<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006082" url="http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Chicken-Corn-Fritters.aspx" time="2012-07-12-22:46" support="1" score="0.006307404331091573" bingtitle="Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe | Taste of Home Recipes" webtitle="Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe | Taste of Home Recipes">
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>... Chicken Dinner Recipes Chicken Main Dishes Chicken Recipes Condiments Corn Recipes Dinner ... They always served Corn Fritters with the chicken in a fast food restaurant I ...</description>
	<body>
		Shop Taste of Home Free Newsletters Digital Editions App Share Your Recipe 
 
 Log In Join Us 
 
 Subscribe &gt; Digital Edition &gt; Give a Gift &gt; Customer Care &gt; 
 
 Recipes 
 Advanced Search Course Ingredients Holidays Top 10 Recipes More... 
 Healthy 
 Recipe Makeovers Healthy Menus Special-Diets Comfort Food Diet Live-Well Healthy Cooking Plus 
 Community 
 Forums Groups Cooks Who Care 
 Videos 
 Playlists Search Videos Submit Videos Taste of Home Videos 
 Cooking Schools 
 About Us Find a Show Meet Our Staff FAQs How to Cook 
 Contests 
 Hide&amp;Seek Sandy’s Wand Carrie’s Carrot Recipe Contests 
 Cookbooks 
 Taste of Home Baking&amp;Desserts Comfort Food Diet Slow Cooker Kitchen Gadgets Healthy Cooking eCookbooks More... 
 Magazines 
 Taste of Home Plus Simple&amp;Delicious Plus Healthy Cooking Plus 
 
 
 My Recipe Box 
 All Saved Recipes Add Personal Recipe My Grocery List My Newsletters 
 
 [X] 

 Home &gt; Recipes &gt; Chicken Corn Fritters 
 Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe 
 Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe photo by Taste of Home Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe 
 Read reviews (2) 
 
 Rate recipe 
 
 I&apos;ve always loved corn fritters, but they weren&apos;t satisfying as a main dish. I came up with this recipe and was thrilled when my husband and our three young boys gave it rave reviews. The chicken and zesty sauce make these a wonderful brunch or lunch entree.
-Marie Greene, Scottsbluff, Nebraska 
 
This recipe is:
 
Contest Winning
 2 
 Rate Print Grocery List Recipe Box Email 
 
 
 [X] 

 [X] 
 Rate Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe 
 Click on stars to rate   
 Would you make this recipe again? 
 Yes No 
 Write a review [X] Chicken Corn Fritters Recipe 
 Prep: 20 min. Cook: 15 min. Yield: 4 Servings 
 20 15 35 
Ingredients

 1 can (15-1/4 ounces) whole kernel corn, drained 1 cup finely chopped cooked chicken 1 egg, lightly beaten 1/2 cup milk 2 tablespoons butter, melted 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 1-3/4 cups all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon baking powder Oil for deep-fat frying GREEN CHILI SAUCE: 1/3 cup butter, cubed 1/4 cup all-purpose flour 1/4 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 1/8 teaspoon garlic powder 1/8 teaspoon ground cumin 1 can (4 ounces) chopped green chilies 1 cup milk Shredded cheddar cheese, optional 
 
Directions

 Place corn in a large bowl; lightly crush with a potato masher. Stir in the chicken, egg, milk, butter, salt and pepper. Combine flour and baking powder; stir into the corn mixture just until combined. In a deep-fat fryer or skillet, heat 2 in. of oil to 375°. Drop batter by 1/4 cupfuls into oil. Fry for 3 minutes on each side or until golden brown. Drain on paper towels; keep warm. In a large saucepan, melt butter over medium-low heat. Stir in flour and seasonings until smooth. Add chilies. Gradually stir in milk. Bring to a boil; cook and stir for 2 minutes or until thickened. Serve with corn fritters; sprinkle with cheese if desired.  Yield:  1 dozen. 
 
 
 

 

 Originally published as Chicken Corn Fritters in Taste of Home August/September 1999, p27
	</body>
</document>
