<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006870" url="http://ninteenpointzerofour.wordpress.com/2011/04/08/no-6-volume-1-chapter-2/" time="2012-07-12-23:51" support="22" score="0.014495192456485544" bingtitle="No. 6 Volume 1: Chapter 2 « 19.04 SECONDS" webtitle="No. 6 Volume 1: Chapter 219.04 SECONDS">
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000352" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001137" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000539" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000039" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000979" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000291" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001105" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>... up garbage and dropping it in the receptacle in its ... The fast food restaurant near downtown was crowded with an ... his shoulder and ran to the station’s exit ...</description>
	<body>
		— 19.04 SECONDS 

To the glory of the Glittering Crux… and to the destruction of the Galactic Pretty Boy!
 
 Home About Comics Penguin Drum Star Driver 00 Archive 
 Magazine Info Official Files Side Stories Novels MSC/Other 
 
 2011/04/08 Anime , No. 6 , Volume 1 18 Comments 
No. 6 Volume 1: Chapter 2
 
I guess my one week estimate was pretty spot-on, lol. This really shouldn’t take quite so long, but I’m pretty distractible. Anyway, on to the chapter:

 

 Previous Chapter : Chapter 1–The Drowned Mouse 

Chapter 2: Quiet Beginnings

Index Case (first discovered instance)
Male. 31 years old. Employed by a biotech firm. Engineer. Dead upon discovery. Legal address…

A man sitting on a bench in the woodland park sighed. How many times had he sighed that day? He sighed and gazed at the head of lettuce in his hands. And then sighed again. 

The head of lettuce had glossy, tightly wound green leaves, it was a first-rate product. He plucked the outermost leaf and ate it.

It had a subtle flavor and a flawless texture. It was a first rate product for sure. And yet, it wasn’t selling.

The lettuce was this man’s product. The man had always been working on bio-engineering perishables, mainly leafy vegetables. He believed that because they were safe, cheap and tasty bio-engineered products, they would solve the supply issues and become a major part of the food supply. He had plenty of confidence. But, when he saw the demand at the market, he’d overestimated things. The man was extremely disappointed. The customers had chosen the field-grown vegetables from the East and South blocks over his bio-engineered produce. The tendency was especially noticeable with leafy vegetables like cabbage and lettuce.

He was told that now his superiors were considering ending production.

Lately, he’d been getting a creeping, prickly pain at the base of his neck. In the past, he was the type prone to getting stress rashes. He would probably end up getting a huge red rash all over his body tonight. He was having nothing but trouble today. He sighed. The lettuce in his hands was heavy.

An electronic sound came from his breast pocket. A young woman’s face appeared on the mini cell phone screen of his ID card.

“I’m with the city information service center. The city infant examination information you requested is ready. To confirm, please enter your citizen registration number…”

The man punched in his citizen number before she finished speaking. Today was the day of his only daughter’s 2nd-year examination. His daughter was a bright and adorable child. He would never say it out loud, but he was secretly expecting her to be certified as top rank.

“Thank you. Your number and finger print have been confirmed. Here are the results.”

His daughter’s name was displayed, followed by tiny numbers.

Weight, height, chest measure, healthiness, nutritional state, developmental state, special ability ranking…They were all graded from A to C, meaning she was completely normal. She’s not particularly developmentally delayed or advanced. That’s all.

He stared at the screen for a while before putting the card back into his pocket. He recalled his daughter’s smiling face.

Oh well.

The man murmured, looked down at the lettuce and laughed. Talent or no talent his daughter was still his daughter. Adorable. Beloved. That was enough.

At that moment, something suddenly occurred to him.

Haven’t I been obsessing over this top rank lettuce? It is most certainly a flawless lettuce. But, didn’t it’s perfection backfire? Perhaps the reason those identically perfect heads of lettuce were for naught was because the consumer kept them at a distance. Contrary to what you might think, perfection puts people off, doesn’t it?

A cleaning robot drew near. It had a silver torso with a round head. It’s two arms stretched out picking up garbage and dropping it in the receptacle in its torso. My lettuce is like that robot. It’s clean and orderly, but it’s too artificial. The vegetables the consumers chose were more unique and natural…

The lettuce rolled out of his hands. He was about to rush to collect it when he raised an eyebrow.

Hm?

His fingers went stiff. His vision suddenly became dim, his breathing labored.

The robot grabbed the lettuce, and paused for a bit. A young man’s voice asked,

“May I dispose of this as garbage?”

The man opened his mouth and started coughing violently. White things came spilling out of his mouth as he coughed. Teeth. His teeth were falling out.

“If it’s okay, I’ll dispose of it.”

The lettuce was tossed into the receptacle and the robot left.

––Hang on, help me…

The man reached out and screamed. His outstretched arms were covered in spots. His body felt heavy. The man staggered and collapsed between the bench and some shrubs.

“Shion, come here.”

It was after 6 p.m. when Shion was called by his colleague Yamase. They were the only people in the park’s management office. They were in charge of managing the three maintenance robots making the rounds in the park. The cleaning robots were much simpler in comparison to the manual labor robots, which were still in the prototype stage in another division somewhere, but they did break down from time to time. Controlling them was annoying too. They couldn’t really determine what was trash and what wasn’t. They were designed to recognize trash and register that with the computer and then automatically clean it up, but they often sent unable-to-identify errors. One such error happened about 30 minutes ago. The image it sent appeared to be a lettuce and Shion himself was forced to make the decision for the machine. Occasionally he’d get things that he wasn’t sure why it considered them garbage, like a baby bird fallen from a tree or a hat with a gaudy feather, but this was the first time it was a lettuce.

“What’s going on?”

He stood behind Yamase who was sitting before the controls.

“Hmm, Walker’s acting weird for some reason…”[ 1 ]

Yamase had given each of the three robots nickname. Walker was the one in question. Today it was working in the far corner of the park. And the one that had picked up the lettuce was Walker.

The screen before him was flashing red to indicate an identification error.

“What’s the image?”

“Yeah, that’s…I don’t know how to say it, but it’s weird.”

“Weird?”

Yamase, 20 years old, was four years older than Shion, but he was rarely quietly confused. Shion liked working here for two reasons: as he was working with machines, he wouldn’t have to talk to other people and he enjoyed his colleague, Yamase’s calm disposition.

“Come on, take a look at it.”

The image on the screen changed.

“Could you bring it into focus a bit more?”

“Sure.”

Yamase’s hands moved frantically. The image came into focus.

“That’s…”

Shion leaned forward and gulped.

Legs?

A pair of trouser-clad legs were sticking out from behind the bench. He could make out a brown shoes too.

“Is he sleeping…?”

Yamase’s voice trembled.

“Lifesigns?”

“What?”

“Expand Walker’s sensor range as far as it’ll go, please.”

Walker had several sensors that could measure temperature, noise, and mass.

Yamase’s voice trembled again.

“Oxygen, body temperature…undetectable. Lifesigns…zero.”

“I’m going to check it out.”

“Oh, I’ll come too.”

They hopped on our bikes, and peddled with all their might. There had been a bike boom the last few years. The statistics department had announced that each citizen owned between one and three bikes. Jogging shoes were flying off the shelves too. It seemed that people were starting to choose to walk and peddle––to use their own bodies––over more convenient vehicles. Although, for a student like Shion, inexpensive, maneuverable vehicles with no energy cost were a necessity, boom or not.

There was a speed limit for bikes inside the park. They sped down the path they’d normally take slowly. Most vehicles have an automatic control and they were designed to engage the breaks automatically if the speed limit was exceeded for a certain amount of time. Bikes were no exception, they had a controller in the hand brake. But, since Shion had an old bike, it didn’t have one. If the transit authority were to find out, he’d be fined, but, right now, he was thankful that he didn’t have to worry about his speed.

It was a quiet spot surrounded by trees. The wind made a pleasant sound as it blew through the trees; Walker had stopped below them. With it’s head tilted slightly, somehow it almost seemed like it was lost in thought.

“Walker.”

Its eyes glowed green in response to Shion’s voice. Shion was petrified after he peered behind the bench.

“Shion, what’s wrong?”

Yamase, who arrived just after him, said in a muffled voice.

That man laid behind the bench as if to conceal himself. His mouth was agape and his eyes open wide. It wasn’t an expression of terror or pain, but more like shock. Like he saw something unbelievable just before he died. That’s the kind of face he had. His hair was completely white and his cheeks were covered in age spots. And deep wrinkles. He appeared to be very old.

––His shirt is unusually flashy for his age though.

Shion thought upon seeing that his shirt was a pale pink.

“Mr. Yamase, please contact the public order department.”

“What? Uh…but…Okay. I’ll do it right now…Hello? This is Yamase from the the park management office….”

Shion tried touching the man’s body with his hand while listening to Yamase’s quivering voice explain the situation. He was in full rigor mortis.

“That doesn’t make sense.”

He muttered unconsciously.

––It’s too soon.

Rigor mortis setting in one hour after death is pretty fast, normally it takes two or three hours. Normally it starts at the jaw and works its way down to the feet. In other words, the man must have died a few hours ago. But, the corpse only found its way here thirty minutes ago. Otherwise Walker would have noticed it. He knew that someone had been sitting on the bench. When he confirmed the lettuce was garbage, Walker’s sensors picked up a person’s lifesigns. He couldn’t be sure if it was the same person though. No, there’s no way it was the same person. There’s no way the body would be in full rigor mortis in just thirty minutes. But then, that would mean someone sat on the bench without noticing the man.

––That’s not possible.

Shion let go of the man’s arm, which felt harder and colder than Walker’s.

There’s no way. If, for argument’s sake, the man died without anyone noticing, Walker would have picked it up. And yet, when Walker sent an unable-to-identify error earlier, there was no corpse here.

It’s almost like the corpse moved. Of course it’s just my imagination. But…Shion ended up grumbling a little more. The area around his chin should be completely stiff, but it’s started to soften. And he could smell a faint sent of decomposition. The man was lying face down and a dark, nearly black, stain was growing behind his ears. It wasn’t there before. At the very least, it was visible to the naked eye. He drew closer for a better look.

“They’re here.”

Shion let out a sigh of relief. The public order department car was quietly, slowly making its way there.

“Tens of minutes ago, he was in full rigor mortis, yet, it’s subsided…There’s no way that could be true.”

Safu said plainly after she swallowed the piece of chocolate doughnut in her mouth. The fast food restaurant near downtown was crowded with an assortment of customers.

“And then, there was that rotten smell, so bacterial decomposition had probably started. There’s no way that could happen. Even if it was summer, rigor mortis would take over 30 hours to set in and subside…right?”

“Under ideal conditions, in summer it takes 36 hours, in winter, three to seven days, in the current climate, about 60 hours. That’s what my textbook says.”

Shion averted his eyes from Safu’s face and brought his cup of black tea to his mouth. He was depressed and tired.

“Was the public order department’s investigation intense?”

Safu peered over at him. Her short hair cut complimented her delicate face and gave her a strange, androgynous charm. Safu was classed as top rank in the 2nd-year examination. She was one of his fellow elite with whom Shion had shared a classroom with for 10 years and now 16, she was one of Shion’s close confidants. Her field of study was physiology and she was leaving for another town as an exchange student soon.

“For now, it’s considered an unnatural death. It’s suspicious, so of course the police interviews were relentless.”

The Safu Shion knew in school was a short and quiet girl. She’s probably the same in the lab. But when she was alone with Shion, Safu laughed and ate a lot and spoke quite a bit in a friendly tone.

Shion finished his black tea and slowly shook his head.

“No, it wasn’t as intense as I’d thought it would be.”

Actually, the public order office’s questioning was handled rather disappointingly quickly. Walker’s data on the corpse had been seized and Yamase and Shion were both asked for their explanations of the situation. Right after Shion’s official address was confirmed to be downtown, near the East block, the public order officer’s tone became more strict, but he was already used to that reaction, do it didn’t bother him much.

“So, why do you look so upset? You look like a troubled young man.”

“Yeah…I’m just stuck on it.”

“The rigor mortis and how fast it subsided?”

“Yeah, that. Just like you said, it makes no sense. It really doesn’t make any sense. No matter how much I think about it, there’s nothing I can come up with that would make rigor mortis set in and subside that quickly.”

“You mean, there weren’t any external conditions like temperature or humidity that could have done it. Without an autopsy, we have no way of knowing if there were any internal factors contributing to it.”

“Internal factors? Like what?”

“Like, if the person was particularly weak to begin with, the rigor mortis would be pretty weak too, it wouldn’t last very long either. I don’t think it wouldn’t be too apparent in someone poisoned with phosphorous or newborn babies either…”

“That man was definitely not a baby.”

Safu whined and glared at Shion.

“I was just throwing out examples. You’re as cynical as ever. Anyway, without any data we won’t know anything.”

“Yeah…”

Shion vaguely nodded his head and unconsciously bit his lower lip. Data, textbooks, manuals…they’re all completely useless at times. Four years ago, everything he believed was true, everything he thought was absolute, was shattered in an instant.

“Shion.”

Safu had brought her hands together as if in prayer and rested her chin on top of them as she gazed at Shion.

“I’d like to ask you something.”

“What? Why are you getting so formal all of a sudden?”

“Why didn’t you take the special course four years ago?”

It was like she could see right through him. He picked at the all-too-sweet apple pie with his hand. The gooey insides spilled out onto the plate.

“Why are you asking all of a sudden?”

“Because I want to know. Objectively speaking, you’re the better student. You pick up and utilize information better than I do. All of your teachers had high hopes for you.

“You flatter me.”

“It’s a fact. The numbers prove it. Do you want me to show you your talent evaluation from four years ago again?”

“Safu.”

There was a bitter taste in his mouth. It was a bitter taste bubbling up from inside him.

“What do you expect to accomplish by asking me that now? Four years ago I was not qualified to take the special course and all my special privileges were revoked. I didn’t decide not to take it. And now, I’m working at the park’s control office to earn my tuition and taking the the manual labor department’s engineering course. And I’ve only made the bare minimum number of classes, so I’m not even sure if I’ll graduate. That’s the truth, or in your words a‘fact.’”

“But how did you lose your qualifications?”

“I don’t want to talk about it.”

“Come on, I wanna know.”

Shion licked the pie crust off his fingers and firmly shut his mouth. He didn’t want to talk about it. Rather, he couldn’t explain it, he just didn’t have the words to explain it so that Safu would understand.

It was actually very simple. The public order office had found out that he’d harbored a VC and let him escape. His mother, Karan thought it was suspicious that Shion had turned off the foreign body detection alarm system in his room. Since the systems in each house were all connected to central control computer in the city hall, it was easy to figure out what happened.

Not one hour after Mouse had disappeared from the room, several men from the public order department came to the house. After that the investigation just went on and on.

You knew he was a VC?

Yes.

But you didn’t report him right away?

Well…

Please answer the question. There’s no hurry so please answer carefully.

Well, he looked about the same age as me and he was really hurt, I was worried…

So you sympathized with a VC, failed to alert the authorities, treated his wound and helped him escape?

That’s what ended up happening, yes.

The head of the public order department’s investigation was named Rashi, he never dropped his gentle tone. He never raised his voice or exercised violence. When investigation ended after a full two days and Shion was released, he even patted him on the shoulder and said,“good work.”But Shion noticed that his eyes never smiled once. Even now, four years later, he still dreamed about those eyes from time to time. Un-smiling eyes staring at him. They were so disconcerting that on those days, he’d wake up drenched in sweat.

Aiding and abetting a criminal. For that crime, Shion was barely punished, but since the judgment and [punitive] action were strikingly lacking, all of his special privileges were revoked.

After the typhoon let up, Shion and Karan were tossed out beneath the dazzlingly clear sky. They had no home or means to make a living. The special ecology course and everything, were farther away than the clouds, far out of reach.

Everything that had been firmly within my grasp until yesterday, until just a short while ago disappeared. Rather than being blown off by a strong wind, the leaves leapt off. That was the first time in my life that I’d ever tasted loss.

No. 6 had no welfare system. Though there was a graduated system of assurances for those authorized to work for the city based on how much they contributed. Shion and Karan were treated as people who could not fulfill their civic duties let alone contribute to the city. They were bottom rank. They were just barely allowed to stay in the city, which meant that they had to give up all their aide and assurances.

The pure elite. Mouse had said so that night, but that’s exactly what it was. I realized for the first time when I was thrown from that pure coffin. No. 6 is a magnificently ordered hierarchical society. The upper and lower ranks are arranged into a perfect pyramid. If you slipped from the upper echelons, it wasn’t easy.

“You’re making a weird face.”

Safu laughed.

“Alright, I get it. If it’s that hard to explain I’ll stop asking.”

“Sorry.”

Shion turned to Safu and made a begging gesture. He was relieved that she’d stopped pressing him for answers. Stating facts is easy. He also thought he wanted to tell Safu about the change happening in his body, he wanted her to ask him about it. But, Shion loosened his grip, it was his current self that felt it was too difficult to explain. He couldn’t understand this strange feeling of regret. He fumed silently at the fragility of his situation, along with a dormant feeling of loss. But, he was thinking about the four years he’d lived through. What would he have done differently if he could turn back time to his 12th birthday? Would he call the public order department? Turn on the alarm system? The answer was always no. Even if he could go back to that night, it would have been the same. He would invite the intruder in along with the wind and the rain. He was perplexed by his confidence in that notion. It’s not like he was particularly satisfied with his current way of life. He still longed terribly for ecology and the rich educational environment, and his life without want, and while we’re at it, the words and looks of encouragement and praise he was surrounded by back then. And yet, he’d still do the same thing. If embracing Mouse lead to his destruction, then he wouldn’t hesitate to chose destruction again. He didn’t regret what he’d done one bit. But he couldn’t explain it. Many typhoons had come since that day. The feeling Shion had upon hearing the rustling of the trees in the wind was not regret, but a sort of nostalgia {herp, bad word choice}. He wanted to see him again.

He didn’t have the confidence to explain that feeling to Safu. He couldn’t say a word.

“Shion, let’s go.”

Safu stood up. The shop had gotten so busy it had gotten difficult for them to hear each other over the noise.

“I’ll walk you to the station.”

“Naturally. You’re not so unrefined as to make a girl go home all by herself.”

“Look who’s talking. You were always really strong despite how thin and short you were. And agile too. I secretly thought you were more suited for martial arts than P.E.”

“I know, right? Even though I was usually really quiet, I had to be careful not to get too worked up. Maybe I’m not suited to being a researcher.”

They followed the street to the station. Since, aside from part of the restaurant district, late night businesses weren’t allowed to operate, in just a few hours there would be almost no foot traffic. Shion lightly pressed [his hand] against Safu’s back. Because Safu’s voice sounded weak.

“Why would someone who passed the selection test and decided to study abroad say something so pitiful?”

Safu raised her head and giggled a bit.

“You’re jealous, aren’t you?”

“Yeah, totally.”

“You’re a little frank.”

”‘Be honest with yourself and be kind to strangers,’it’s sort of my motto these days.”

“Liar.”

“What?”

“You were never jealous.”

They stopped. Safu looked up at Shion, as if challenging him. Just as he was about to say something to her, a strong hand landed on his shoulder from behind.

“Excuse me.”

A man about a head shorter than Shion was standing there, smiling. He was wearing a public order department uniform. It was a subdued two-piece, navy blue garment, but it was made of a special fabric called a‘super fiber.’Ten times stronger than steel, it was plenty effective as a bullet proof vest, and on top of that it was light and breathable. The closer you get to the West block, the number of people in the public order department’s defense section uniforms increased. Shion slowly removed the man’s hand and asked,

“Can I help you?”

“No, I just wanted to ask you something…How old are you two?”

“Sixteen.”

“Both of you?”

“Yes.”

“There’s a curfew in effect, people under the age of 18 aren’t supposed to be out past nine o’clock.”

“I know. But it’s only eight.”

“Shion.”

Safu whispered. She was telling him not to defy the officer. The public order department uniform behind him unconsciously reminded him of the eyes of Rashi, the head of the public order department’s investigation. Rather than standing down, he opposed him.

“Could I see both of your IDs?”

Did he notice Shion’s defiant tone? The man’s smiling face was replaced with an expressionless one as he requested their personal identification. Safu handed him a silver ID card. Shion handed his over in silence.

“Please recite your citizen registration numbers.”

“SSC-000124GJ”

“QW-55142″

He removed the card from the small reader, turned to Safu and gently lowered his head.

“What is a special course student doing here at this hour? You should hurry home.”

“I was just going home…I was heading to the station.”

“I’ll take you to the station.”

“No, need. I’ve got him with me.”

Safu grabbed onto Shion’s arm.

“I’m taking her. That’s why I was walking with her. Let’s go, Safu.”

Shion nearly snatched the cards from the man, took Safu’s hand and started to walk briskly. He looked back after a bit, the short man had been enveloped by the crowd.

“That was surprising.”

Safu was clutching her chest.

“I’ve never been warned by a public order officer before.”

“It happens all the time around here. He’d have been a lot harder on you if it weren’t for that special ID card you have.”

“Really?”

“Really. You’re going to get on a train, but because you have that ID card it’s not a regular car, but a special one that you get to ride. That’s the kind of place this city is. People are discriminated against based on talent, assets, and various other factors.”

“I don’t know if I’d call it discrimination. People are people. Not trash or things.”

“Safu, this isn’t a question of humanity. It’s just an issue of whether you’re a productive citizen or not.”

“Shion…”

“You called me a liar just a bit ago. I wasn’t lying. Of course I’m jealous. You get special treatment and get to research what you like. I’m jealous. Frankly, I might even call it envy. You have everything I don’t.”

Shion let out a deep breath. I said way too much. How rude of me. Petty. Embarrassing. Pitiful. He chastised himself in his mind.

Safu sighed too.

“You’re such a liar.”

“What?”

“Are you deaf? I called you a L-I-A-R. I should have stuck a‘massive’in front of it. You’re just pretending to be jealous of me. Or do you not even realize that you’re lying? You’re such a dense boy.”

“Safu, you know…”

“If you were really jealous or envious of me, you wouldn’t have been able to eat with me. Weren’t you just laughing and eating and talking and cracking jokes like normal?”

“That’s…because even I have pride. I couldn’t let myself do something so lame as to let my jealousy show.”

“Shion, my specialty is the relationship between brain function and behavioral change and hormones.”

“Yeah, I know.”

“I’d be mad if you didn’t. I’ve said it I don’t know how many times. You know, if you were pretending to have a good time while hiding your envy of me, that should be really stressful.”

“Yeah, it was…”

“The thing about stress is, when you feel stressed out, it’s because your adrenal glands have excreted a corticosteroid––or more plainly a steroid hormone––which affects the brain. And consequently your behavior changes.”

“Safu, I said I know. Gimme a break. If I’d wanted a lecture, I’d have asked for one.”

“Listen. You weren’t stressed at all. You’re not jealous of me. Shion, what do you want to do?”

“What?”

“If you wanted to continue researching, fine, be jealous of me. But, you don’t. You said I have everything you don’t, but what do you have? Don’t tell me‘nothing.’A person who has nothing is…No, that’s not right. A person who thinks they have nothing couldn’t laugh like you do. You’d need to be specially trained to have such complete control over your emotions such that they wouldn’t have an effect. You never received such training. I don’t think you’re an especially emotional person. But, I don’t think you have 100% control over them either. Since you were fine talking and laughing with me, it’s because you have surplus emotion.”

“Safu, what you’re saying is just an empty theory. People have complicated emotions. They’re not lab rats. I don’t think you can explain the connection between emotions and actions that simply. It’s conceited to think that there’s a scientific explanation for everything about humanity.”

Safu shrugged. The station building came into view.

“I never took you for a writer.”

“Safu.”

“Then stop talking like a poet. Surplus emotion…in other words aspirations, or dreams. You have those, don’t you. So you don’t need to be jealous of me. Shion, what do you aspire to?”

Aspiration. He mouthed the word silently. It’s a word he hadn’t used in years. It wasn’t bitter or sweet. It slowly permeated his body with warmth.

Aspiration. What do I aspire to?

The future I was promised had crumbled to dust. All I had left was my mother, a job by which I could earn meager compensation and my sixteen year old body. But I knew it wasn’t hopeless.

They entered the station. Shion lived in a district on the boarder of the West block. It served as a buffer zone between the city center and the West block. They called it“Lost Town.”Compared to the quiet in the city center, it was a crowded, chaotic place. Even this building was overflowing with people. It smelled faintly of fried food and alcohol.

“This is fine.”

Safu stopped. A small, winged insect landed on her shoulder. Shion swatted it away and innocently asked,

“Take care. Oh, by the way, when are you leaving to study abroad?”

“The day after tomorrow.”

“The day after tomorrow! Why didn’t you tell me earlier?”

“I didn’t want to talk about it. Speaking of which, aren’t you going to give me a farewell present?”

Safu tilted her chin up.

“Shion, there’s something I want from you.”

“Yeah. But I don’t know if we have time now…”

“Your sperm.”

Safu stared at Shion unblinkingly, and said it. Shion looked down at her, mouth agape.

“Did you hear me? I want your sperm.”

“Uh…what? Safu…. um…”

“Of all the people I know, you’re the best candidate for sperm donor. Don’t you think my eggs and your sperm would produce a superior child? I really want it, Shion. I want your sperm.”

“Do you have the city’s approval for artificial insemination?”

“Getting approval isn’t a problem. Shouldn’t the city be encouraging artificial insemination for people with superior genes and abilities?”

Shion gulped and looked away. A bug crossed his line of sight. As if induced by the sound of those wings flapping, an unpleasant feeling came over him.

“Safu…Maybe I never mentioned it, but I don’t know anything about my father. Not his personality, his genetic makeup, his appearance, or his medical history.”

“I know. But this has nothing to do with your parents. DNA, the human genome, has been 99% decoded. It’s simple to look at what kind of genetic data you have.”

“So, you look at it and…. What if, what if you find something you don’t like?”

“Then…”

“Safu, what are you thinking? Do you think humans are nothing more than the base sequences that make up their DNA? Even if you read my DNA and understand my genetic makeup, you won’t know anything about me. You can’t simply bring a child into––”

“I know a lot about you!”

Safu interrupted with a shout. It was so loud that everyone around them turned to look.

“We’ve been together since we were two years old. I know what kind of person you are, what you like…I know it all. You say you understand…. but you don’t!”

“What?”

Safu mumbled something. He couldn’t understand it. He leaned in a bit.

“I want to have sex.”

Safu’s words reached his ears right away.

“Safu…”

“I don’t need your sperm. I don’t want to be artificially inseminated. I don’t care about having a kid. I just want to have sex with you. That’s all.”

“Um, wait, hang on a minute…Safu, um…”

“Right now.”

Shion took a deep breath. The thick smell of fried food flooded his lungs. The eight o’clock chime sounded.

“Not now.”

“Why? Do you not like me? Are you not interested in sex?”

“I like and am interested in both. But…I don’t want to do it with you right now.”

“You mean, you can’t do it with me?”

“No, my body would probably respond. But, I don’t like the idea. But…That’s why I don’t want to. I don’t want to sleep with you just because I’m aroused.”

“So you mean you don’t have any romantic feelings for me.”

“Yeah. I think of you as a friend.”

“You’re an idiot.”

Safu let out a big sigh.

“You’re still such a child. I mean seriously. Whatever, I’m going home.”

“Safu, two years.”

“What?”

“Your study abroad term is two years, right? I’ll give it to you when you get back.”

“You mean have sex?”

“Yeah.”

“You really are a complete idiot. You must have been raised to be really care-free.”

“Take care. Don’t over do it.”

“I’m gonna put my nose to the grindstone. I’ll try not to go after any other guys though.”

As Safu lightly waved her hand and turned to walk away, she let out a little whine. A little ash-colored creature ran past Safu’s feet and jumped onto Shion.

“Eeew a mouse!”

A little mouse the size of a pinky finger climbed up Shion’s shoulder and sniffed.

“I’m surprised there are any mice in town. But it is pretty cute.”

“He seems to be a pretty friendly fellow.”

The little mouse brought its face close to Shion’s ear. And whispered.

“You’re as big an airhead as ever.”

Electricity ran through his body. That’s what it felt like. When he reached out to grab the mouse, it lept from his shoulder and ran to the station’s exit. It was downtown, but it was unusual for a mouse to be in“Lost Town”which was within the city limits. The sanitation department diligently took care of the extermination of rodents and insects. People weren’t used to mice running between their feet. It caused shrieks and commotion in the crowd.

Just before that, Shion saw ash-colored eyes. It was just for a second. Again, a numbness ran through his body.

“Mouse!”

“Shion, what are you doing?”

“Safu, you can get home from here, right?”

“What are you talking about? Of course I can. I was just about to leave, wasn’t I? What’s wrong? Why are you in such a rush all of a sudden?”

“Sorry.”

When we part, I won’t see her for two years. I have to see her off properly. At least until she disappears into the crowd…She wants to have sex with me, but to me, Safu, is an unshakably important person to me. I can’t part with such an important person like this. I know that. I know that all too well, but I ignored it. My senses returned to me and my body began to move.

Ah, I experienced this four years ago too. My senses told me which road to take.

Running the alarm system. Reporting to the public order department. Rejecting an odd person. I went against all that. The same thing was happening now. I was following my heart.

It was raining outside. The rain that’d just begun to fall, hit my face. There was one face I recognized within the quickly moving crowd.

“Shion!”

Karan opened her eyes when she saw her son come home.

“You’re soaked. Where were you?”

“Out on a walk.”

“In this rain? Where to?”

“The station.”

“Why did you keep walking while getting drenched again?”

“It calms my mind.”

“I give up. You really are care-free.”

Safu had said the same thing. Shion started laughing without thinking about it as she dried his hair. The rain chilled him quickly. Just an old style space heater warmed the room. Karan yawned lightly. It was bedtime already. Karan had opened a hand made bread shop in a corner of Lost Town. It was a small shop without even one proper showcase, but I guess the fragrant aroma that wafted from the shop starting early in the morning drew people in, it was fairly popular. Early to bed early to rise. 9 p.m. was the dead of night to Karan.

“I think I’ll make more butter rolls starting tomorrow. And I’ve made up my mind to try making simple cakes instead of just muffins. What do you think?”

“Cherry cake?”

“Yes, yes! I want to keep it at a price people can afford for a mid-day snack, but I think it should be more expensive than the bread and muffins. A modest commemoration for a special day, that sort of thing.”

“It might work.”

“Right? It’ll feel kind of fun with a bunch of cakes lined up in the shop.”

Shion nodded and left the living room. In this house, they didn’t have the luxury of separate bedrooms. Karan slept in a corner of the living room and Shion slept in a room that had become a store room for the bread shop.

“Shion.”

His mother called and he turned back.

“Did something happen?”

“What?”

“Did something happen that made you need to cool your head?”

Karan continued, not waiting for Shion to answer.

“When you came home, you looked like you wee in a daze. Like you didn’t even realize that you’d been soaked by the rain…And even now”

“Even now?”

“You’re making a face like you’re agitated and lost in thought. Do you need a mirror?”

Shion sighed.

“Someone died in the park today.”

“Really? In the woodland park? I didn’t see anything on the news.”

It didn’t make the news? Does that mean he died of natural causes? It was sudden, but it was explainable. An extremely normal death that didn’t even make the news…. Shion wiped his face.

I guess things like that do happen. The body’s rigor mortis time and that green spot were weird. That isn’t normal. I’d only explained what he looked like when I found him to the public order department. I pretended not to notice the rigor mortis or the mark. I thought that was the best thing to do. I don’t know why though. A voice inside me told me to play dumb, pretend not to notice. It was a voice like the instinct small animals have to hide themselves when they sense enemies near. It was informing me that danger was near.

Look, even I have instincts. I was moved not by reason but by feeling. Even though I turned my back on reason, I readily follow instinct.

Shion took another deep breath. He was having a little trouble breathing.

“So you’re a little agitated?”

“Yeah, I guess. It was the first time I saw a dead body.”

That’s a lie, mom. I saw those eyes again today. I saw Mouse. I had a premonition. I feel like something about to happen. So…

Karan smiled and said good night. It was a calm and gentle smile. He told her good night, and left the living room.

She was still as plump as ever, but his mother looked more youthful than before. It seems like the move from Chronos to Lost Town didn’t bother her at all. She enjoyed making and selling bread with a smile on her face. She wasn’t just putting on a brave face for her son. Karan really didn’t bemoan living here. It was different from the completely provided life in Chronos, but Karan built her life in Lost Town with her own hands. And that’s why I didn’t want to ruin it. I don’t want to do anything that could uproot her life again like what happened four years ago. At the very least, I don’t want to involve her in anything.

He collapsed into bed. He was shivering a bit. His head was pounding. It didn’t stop even when he closed his eyes, all sorts of images appeared inside his eyelids.

A green spot, a rolling lettuce, a pink shirt, Safu’s face.

When she asked to have sex with him.

A small mouse running up his body. And whispering in his ear.

“You’re as big an airhead as ever.”

His body temperature rose. His pulse quickened.

It wasn’t a dream or an illusion. Mouse was definitely in the crowd at the station.

That was a pretty showy entrance.

He tried mumbling,“dumbass.”What are you trying to say, making me believe you appeared like that. What are you trying to do?

Shion awoke on his bed.

Safu is probably unrelated, but I wonder if the body at the park and Mouse have anything to do with each other. Mouse appeared the night I discovered the corpse. Was that just a coincidence? There’s got to be a connection somewhere…

An electronic sound started up. The cell phone in his ID card was ringing. It couldn’t be. There’s no way it could be Mouse. I knew that, but my heart wavered. The fingers holding the card trembled a bit. The two characters that made up Safu’s name glowed on the screen. When he pressed the accept button, the name was replaced with her face.

“Shion, were you already asleep?”

“Oh, no.”

Right, I should have called her. I’ve gotta make up for that half-assed farewell.

“Safu, I’m sorry about earlier. Um,”

“Was it really such an important person?”

“What?”

Safu’s face on the screen was making a bitter smile. It was a beautiful, adult expression.

“I’d never seen you make that face before. Do you know what kind of face you made?”

“No, um, uhh, I made that weird of a face?”

“It was funny. I could never get tired of that. At first you were really surprised, and then…Yes, what was that? Joy, perhaps? Like you were dreaming. Like you were blown away by something. And then you left me alone in the station and ran out. How awful, I mean really.”

“Sorry. I’m really sorry.”

“Don’t worry about it. Oh, so this person, this person who made you make that face, who let me see this completely new expression of yours…. Hey, Shion, the person who made you make that face, who is it? There’s someone you care about so much that you’d run after them in a trance?”

“Yeah.”

I was surprised that I answered in the affirmative so quickly.

“Um, Safu, don’t get me wrong here. I don’t have a lover or anything like that, um, I can’t really explain yet, but, how to put it…”

“This is the first time I’ve seen you confused and unable to explain something too. It’s fine. I don’t mind if there’s someone you like…I guess I’m bluffing a bit. I have a bad habit of acting like I’ll be fine regardless of what happens.”

“I don’t think so at all. Safu, you’re always honest with yourself, aren’t you?”

“Only in front of you.”

Safu continued, making a face as if to say,“you really never noticed?”

“Safu, I really mean it, take care of yourself. When we meet again in two years”

“I love you, Shion. I love you more than anyone else.”

She didn’t even wait for Shion to answer before hanging up. He could hear the sound of the rain. Something was moving in the corner of the room.

“Mouse?”

In this storehouse piled high with flour and sugar, only the sound of rain could be heard. He grasped his knees and sat alone in the dark, listening to the rain. The rain was pouring with no sign of letting up, it continued that way throughout the night.

–––––
[ Original Text ]

 [1] サンポ–I’ve translated the robot’s nickname. This might be a number pun (since there are 3 robots), but without the others it’s hard to say. I don’t think it’s really terribly significant, just that Yamase’s the type of person who nicknames service robots.
 
Share this:
 
 More 
 
 
 
 No. 6 noitaminA 
 ← Previous post Next post → 
 lol, Twitter 

 RT @ yarare_kanrinin : 型月フェス、『Fate/Zero』出演者の集合写真でおじさんの中の人だけテンション上がってるｗｗｗ yaraon.blog109.fc2.com/blog-entry-106… @ yarare_kanrinin 15 hours ago RT @ colonydrop : Dear Parents:&quot;Shojo&quot;=&quot;Unsavory Physical Abuse/Rape-Predicated Relationship.&quot;&quot;Seinen&quot;/&quot;Gekiga&quot;=&quot;Weird Pervert Reveng ... 15 hours ago LOGH TAKARAZUKA OH MY GOD http://t.co/q7s5zNm9 15 hours ago 
 Follow @Good_Haro 
Recent Posts

 Hadaka Shitsuji Fandisk Site Open Status Updates/etc The Basara Movie Penguin News 2 Novel 2 Spoiler Dump 
 
Categories
 Select Category Anime    Code Geass    Gundam 00       Theories    Kuroshitsuji    No. 6       Volume 1       Volume 2    Other    Schell Bullet    Spinning Penguin Drum       Novel          上    Star Driver       Interviews       News / MSC Info       Summaries       Theories / Speculation    Tytania    Winter 09       Slayers Drawfaggotry Hadaka Shitsuji HOMOLUST Other/Msc    Faggotry    Linguistics SF    Babylon 5    Battlestar Galactica    Doctor Who    Dollhouse    Heroes Tech Stuff    Robots tl;dr Uncategorized 
MSC
 H O M O L U S T C H A L L E N G E G E N E R A T O R 
Projects
 Hadaka Shitsuji 15159 of 27767 lines (54.59%) 


 SCHELL BULLET 

 I ADEN ARIBE :
 Prologue | 1 - Rhone Balt | 2 - Shell | 3 - GMa. Ors Break | 4 - Clipper Race | 5 - Blockade Breakthrough | 6 - Life Game | 7 - Schell Battle | 8 - Border Bullet 6.28% II ABRAXAS :
9 - Intermission | 10 - Kill Mark | 11 - Battle Link | 12 - Victor&apos;s Principle | 13 - Orbital Attack | 14 - Survival Strategy | 15 - Operations of Death | 16 - Iconoclasm | 17 - Hide and Seek | 18 - The Missing Link 0% 18 comments 
 wandering-dreamer said: 2011/04/08 18:01 
Very nice and the second chapter of the manga just came out so it’s fun to compare the two. Shion comes off as more like a teenager here (more, angry and such, in the manga he seems a bit bland so far) and there’s a lot more world building in here so far, thanks for the translation! Quick question, is No. 6 just one book or is it part of a series?
 Reply↓ 
 Good Haro said: 2011/04/08 18:48 
It’s a series. There are 8 books. I’m not sure if it’s complete, but it probably is (iirc the last volume came out in 2009).
 Reply↓ 
 wandering-dreamer said: 2011/04/09 17:22 
Ooooo, wonder how many books the anime will be able to cover in just 11 episodes then, unless it runs for two cour like Shiki did then I’m a little worried for it.
 Reply↓ 
 Good Haro said: 2011/04/09 20:40 
At this rate, I kind of feel like they could cover the first book in 2~3 episodes, so they might be able to go through a fair bit of it.
 Reply↓ 
 
 
 Kencana said: 2011/05/08 14:48 
Nice translations. I like Safu’s honesty.
 Reply↓ Bk said: 2011/07/10 14:04 
Safu is a piece of work.

I like her personality with the exception of how she just impose herself onto her childhood friend.

Like‘maybe he doesn’t like you like that,’kind of thing.

I really need to watch the anime too but these translations are a treat. Thanks.
 Reply↓ phat008 said: 2011/07/10 20:06 
Thank you! I couldn’t hold myself back from continuing to read your translations, i really wanted to wait until the 2nd ep comes out to visit again, but i’ve submitted to indulgence. Karan seems very calm and maybe more than meets the eye? And i wonder if Nezumi has some form of special ability to communicate with Shion via a mouse?! Now i can stop, must read the next chapter. Thank you!
 Reply↓ Becca said: 2011/07/19 00:27 
oh this is great!
 Reply↓ Veronica said: 2011/07/22 00:16 
I’m happy to be here!
 Reply↓ odaime said: 2011/07/26 10:09 
LOL I shocked when Safu wants Shion’s sperm frontally. I remember this chapter, it’s episode 2 in the anime. Well, because I prefer the novel than the anime although I follow both of them, I hope you will translate the next chapter as soon as possible. Thanks a bunch anyway!
 Reply↓ AppleSweetRose said: 2011/08/02 01:42 
Thank you sooooooo much for the translations.
You have no idea how much I appreciate it.
Gah, I think you did a good job, because I enjoyed the heck out of it.
Someone gave me your site for the translations and I have never been more grateful.

Thank you!
Fell in love with this by the end of chapter 1 XD
 Reply↓ animaven said: 2011/08/05 05:33 
Safu was so bold in her actions, acutally coming out and saying she wanted to have sex with him. He seemed nonplussed about it, too. Still, he is only 16 years old, but he wants to wait 2 years. He is definitely a good person.
 Reply↓ peebs75 said: 2011/08/07 18:28 
This chapter somehow felt shorter. I could already see a spark of“something”between Shion and Mouse. I’m gonna start on the next chapter right away.
 Reply↓ PaperTiger said: 2011/08/12 09:02 
Hey Ho–
I’ve enjoyed reading so far–just a quick querie / offer if you might be interested:

Would you like me to beta-read and toggle in a word document where the tenses and the perspectives change in the same sentence? I’m just learning Japanese now so I admire you ability to translate in any fashion (one day so shall I be capable) in the mean time I have above par english capacity and would love to help if you would like.
 Reply↓ Dobuchu said: 2011/08/12 12:14 
“Shion turned to Safu and made a begging gesture.”I’m thinking your translating the action of putting a hand in front of the face, or both hands in a praying manner in front of the face. If that’s the case, then that is more of a‘i’m sorry’gesture. I can only guess that’s what you mean, because if not, then I have no idea what a‘begging gesture’is.

That aside. I enjoy the translations so far! I’m waiting for these books to be sent to me currently. I asked for a couple of them from a friend’s relative that works overseas. I’ve been reading too much Ribon lately, it’s time for something with less pictures, ha ha. Keep up the good work and ganbatte!
 Reply↓ Lena Schabsky said: 2011/10/23 17:27 
Lovely second chapter. I wish there was more. Reading this makes me so endlessly happy.^^
 Reply↓ lactuca virosa said: 2012/01/08 14:03 
Someone necessarily assist to make significantly articles I’d state. This is the very first time I frequented your website page and so far? I amazed with the analysis you made to create this actual post incredible. Excellent process!
 Reply↓ Paru said: 2012/03/06 09:46 
Thanx for translating ^^ i was looking online and i found this website..Its really great. Thank you so much n off to reading other vol ^x^
 Reply↓ 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Blogum by WPShower .
 Follow 
 Follow“19.04 SECONDS” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 140 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
