<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006823" url="http://www.complaintnow.com/Fast-Food-Restaurant-Complaints" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="15" score="0.03720430899207179" bingtitle="ComplaintNow.com: Fast Food Restaurant Complaints" webtitle="ComplaintNow.com: Fast Food Restaurant Complaints">
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000857" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000605" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000355" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001485" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Complaints ... waiting 10 min. for the guy in front of us to receive ... and spoke to a woman that took my name and order number a ...</description>
	<body>
		Complain Dialog Box X 
 
 
   
 Home | About | Contact | Help | Login  
 
 
 Complaints Businesses Post A Complaint Category My ComplaintNow 
 

 
 
 
 
 
Fast Food Restaurant Complaints
 

 
 

 SonicDrive-In - Would&apos;nt take order  
 by darkmom , on Jun 29, 2012 
 This happened on a Sonic in Madisonville, Tenn.. I ordered a creamslush for myself and a choc. milkshake for my 84 year old mother. I was told I could&apos;nt order anything with ice cream because it was too hot and would melt. How Rude and Stupid. 


 Hardees - worker  
 by 1traveller , on Jun 17, 2012 
 im writing in regard for my wife,who is employed by hardees booneville ms.this morning sunday she was to go to work at 6am,she was up all nite sick,my wife has never missed or been late for work,and works when called in to work for someone else.today i cal 


 McDonalds - wrong order/ wrong receipt/ bad attitude  
 by esmilie , on Jun 08, 2012 
 Order a large coke, southern chicken sandwich&amp;a quarter pounder. All on the menu board. Paid&amp;was told I&apos;d get receipt with my order. Pulled up and was handed a medium coke I told the guy it was a larger he looked at the receipt and said that&apos;s not w 


 White Castle - Unfinished burgers  
 by Dee1 , on May 16, 2012 
 I always buy the frozen boxes of White Castle Cheeseburgers (8) twin packs. After visiting the grocery store on Saturday 5/12/12, I purchased my usual box and got home and noticed that 3 packages did not have top buns. What&apos;s up with that?

Audrey Cher 


 Taco Bell - Manager don&apos;t give shit  
 by Bigrod29 , on May 12, 2012 
 I came to drive thru and ordered me taco which they got me wrong taco. I was on lunch break and no time but I did call taco bell and spoke with manager what an ass. Hung up on me twice and don&apos;t give shit. My food was cold and wrong ordered and i pay too m 


 Taco Johns - Rude employee at Spencer Iowa Taco Johns  
 by BilboBaggins , on May 11, 2012 
 Spencer Iowa employee named Josh is rude to customers and doesn&apos;t wear gloves when dealing with food and also uses inappropriate language 


 Popeyes Chicken - Given Wrong Information about ingredients  
 by Blessed , on Mar 07, 2012 
 I asked the MANAGER at popeyes what the gravy was made of and she said CHICKEN gizzards ... i asked are u SURE its not pork AS I do NOT eat pork and she said no it was before but now its chicken because not alot of people eat pork ... now my friend who is 


 Taco Cabana - Taco Cabana is Racist!  
 by Bael29a , on Feb 24, 2012 
 I have been visiting the same Taco Cabana location almost every week day in the morning for breakfast on my way to work, never again! The lady who worked the drive through this morning (02/23/2012 at 7:30 AM) is the reason. For some reason every time she w 


 Taco Bell - Rude  
 by codymom , on Feb 23, 2012 
 My son and i went to Taco Bell in Staunton Va we were ordering the lady that was taking the order was so rude. She said some very rude things about me because i was not finished ordering when she thought i was. I paid a item i did not get. I will never go 


 Sonic - Rude Service by Manager&amp;False Advertising  
 by Marvalous , on Feb 15, 2012 
 Purchased a chocolate milk shake and when it came it had whipped cream. I told the person who gave it to me that I did not want whipped cream since it makes me nauseated. She brought a new one and when I got home I realized that it did not taste like choco 


 Wingstop - Worst Employer Ever!  
 by pissed101 , on Feb 04, 2012 
 This is the worst employeer to work for. She leaves pages of threats to employees which usually ruins their day and if they&apos;re mad enough they end up taking it out on the customers. She sits at home and watches you when you work. If you&apos;re not mopping the 


 Dairy Queen - Bad Service  
 by shaebear , on Jan 20, 2012 
 In the drive thru at Sweetwater. My Fiance and I ordered a med. Caramel Moolate and had to repeat several times and waiting 10 min. for the guy in front of us to receive his meal. The young lady ringing us up was still looking for the one button to push so 


 Checkers - Teller Chairs  
 by atoz , on Jan 17, 2012 
 Good Morning to you, I just want to bring to your attention that some of your stores in particular Checkers in Pinetown off ST. Johns need their teller chairs replaced. It is absolutely appalling the condition these chairs are in. I think they must have be 


 Subway - Subway Clerk Threatened Me  
 by babycakesmmd , on Jan 14, 2012 
 My sister and I were ordering from a Subway store on Atlantic off Rock Island. There was to male clerks assisting customers with their orders. One of the male clerks, (he was of Latin culture), shifted to me and my sister. When I and my sister were deliber 


 Dermitage - Lousy Customer Service  
 by dissappointed , on Dec 22, 2011 
 Lousy customer service. I have purchased this item for some time and every time I do, I have issues. It really is NOT worth the trouble. There is no communication, customer service is not helpful, they do not speak English, yet they &quot;understand&quot; everythi 


 Subway - Employees  
 by hondalover , on Dec 14, 2011 
 I recently went to this subway and saw new employees. I noticed that the manager and the new employee were sisters. From what I know it is not right for family to work together while one is a manager. Also the new employee was treated with a lot more respe 


 Dunkin Donuts - Cappuccino Horror!  
 by wooddale , on Dec 05, 2011 
 Can&apos;t make cappuccino to save their soul! Called corporate who was supposed to have the owner call me, manager of store did instead. She told me to come back in and they would make it correctly. I did, they didn&apos;t! When the cappuccino came out as a major 


 White Castle - Poor Management&amp;Falsified Information  
 by nisk , on Nov 27, 2011 
 I had visited the White Castle on MacArthur Rd in Whitehall Pa on Nov 20 2011 and purchasd $54.47 of food. When i got home, some of the food was raw and uncooked. So i called and spoke to a woman that took my name and order number a list of items that were 


 Wendys - Very Rude  
 by dukster , on Nov 06, 2011 
 She did our order wrong, they pretty much called me a liar. Then when I got our order, I ordered 2 chicken sandwiches and 1 spicy chicken and 1 honey chipotle sandwich and they were all wrapped in same paper. I had no idea what was what went back to counte 


 Dunkin Donuts - Store # 338608 Douglas MA  
 by karynvtma , on Nov 01, 2011 
 The community of Douglas was thrilled to have a Dunkin Donuts come our way. Especially thrilled were the poeple of the end of town where there is virtually nothing other than a convenience store. When the shop first opened in our local convenience store al 

 
 
 
 


 Companies In This Category Burger King Holdings Inc. Jack in the Box Inc. Krispy Kreme Doughnuts Inc. Sonic Corp. Wendys Wendys Subway Dunkin Donuts The Columbia Resturant McDonalds Burger King Taco Bell Checkers Duncan Donuts Dairy Queen KRYSTAL Ninety Nine Taco Bell Donut Connection McDonalds McDonalds McDonalds Subway Sandwich and Salad Headquarters PaPa John Pizza Arbys chur chucken McDonalds McDonalds JACk in da box Quiznos Burger King Corporation Fiesta Cafe/Churchs Chicken McDonalds KFC Gourmet on the Go Altanta Mc.Donalds Subway Sandwich Kentucky Fried Chicken Carls Junior Hardees Wendys Old Fashion Hamburgers Williams Chicken KFC burger king resturants Dermitage Dunkin Donuts McDonalds Chick-fil-A Golden Bird Resteraunt Sonic Drive Inn Of Giddings Texas McDonalds A&amp;W fast food Wendys Fast Food Burger King Subway store at Pilot station KFC Oakdale, Ca burger king resturants #2013 Pluck U Taco Bell Hardees Resturants McDonalds Taco Bell McDonalds McDonalds Taco Bell KFC in Syr. N.Y McDonalds Buger King KFC #341 Del Taco Whataburger McDonalds SonicDrive-In Montclair Plaza Foodcourt McDonalds Kentucly Fried Chicken Kentucly Fried Chicken Kentucly Fried Chicken Taco Bell Churches Chicken BISCUITVILLE biscuitville Taco Bell Spangles Taco Cabana Wendys New River Air Station McDonalds dunkin doughnuts Blimpie McDonalds kfc Moby Dick Jack in the Box Popeyes Chicken Happy Wok McDonalds chicken express Jack In The Box 844 McDonalds McDonalds Long John Slivers Taco Johns McDonalds Frizzles Custard Nathans Famous Hot Dog Subway Sandwich&amp;salads; McDonalds Long John Silvers Sonic Drive Inn of Claremore, Ok. Nori Japan McDonalds Subway Hebron CT mcdolnalds soutehern multifood A@W kfc north providence, ri Burger King north providence Subway store #16152 Hardees Burger King Taco Bell Burger King Kentucky Friend Chicken Penn station McDonalds Arbys Roast Beef Restautants McDonalds Kentucky Fried Chickhen El pollo loco McDonalds Taco Bell McDonalds McDonalds Neds Fried Onion Pit Mc Donald Subway Subs Burger King Restaurant #7470 McDonalds Popeyes Chicken McDonalds Burger King Subway at Hayfield Shopping Center, Alex, Va Chicken Express White Castle Burger King Bojangle Checkers Snellville KFC 88 Burgers Crown Fried Chicken Taco Johns Wendys White Castle Subway Wingstop Sonic Taco Cabana 


 Related Categories Bar and Grill Complaints Restaurant Complaints Bakery Complaints Beverages Wineries&amp;Distillers Complaints Catering Complaints Ice Cream Store Complaints Coffee Shop Complaints Restaurant Supplies and Tools Complaints Pizza Restaurant Complaints Specialty Eateries Complaints Cafeteria Complaints Deli Complaints Yogurt Shop Complaints Brewery Complaints 
 
 
 
 Help | About | Contact | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
