<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006830" url="http://www.vrindi.com/default.aspx" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="8" score="0.009694538493504977" bingtitle="Vrindi Inc | Online Food Ordering System | Restaurant Website ..." webtitle="Vrindi Inc | Online Food Ordering System | Restaurant Website Design | Search Engine Marketing Services">
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>... email marketing, 24x7 support, detailed order ... your restaurant website the SEO advantage, credit card ... Multi location, indian fast food restaurant gets online ordering ...</description>
	<body>
		Login | Register 
 
 Sales 1 (877) 987-4634 Ext.1 sales@vrindi.com 
 
 Support 1 (877) 987-4634 Ext.2 support@vrindi.com 
 
 Home RestaurantWave Demos Clients About Us Contact Us Wiki 
 Enter Promotion Code: 
 
 
 Features Competitive Edge Clients Testimonials 
 
 
 Online Ordering Online Payments Interactive Directions Table Reservation Marketing Promotions Website Popularity Multiple Locations All Features 
 
 RestaurantWave can be fully customized for designing restaurant website with online ordering system. This technology is successfully used by Banquet Halls, Cafes, Bar and Caterers websites. RestaurantWave product is customized for Restaurant Online Ordering Solution. Online ordering solution for restaurant is guaranteed to achieve increased revenue and customer satisfaction. A great looking website with well organized restaurant menus, photo gallery, directions, coupons, events promotions are the basic feature of RestaurantWave. The online ordering for Pickup, Delivery, Dine-In, Table Booking or Catering with online payment is guaranteed to increase business revenue and profit. More... 
 
 Increase customer satisfaction and revenue by taking credit card payments online. RestaurantWave works with leading payment gateway&amp;major credit cards, providing highest level security. Each year, more consumers are increasingly making online payments. Do not lose out on these customers and their orders to your competitors. RestaurantWave online ordering Solution is designed by using highest level of security standard, SSL certificate and credit card industry PCI Compliance. More... 
 
 Imagine driving a vehicle on the map to your location for the last few hundred yards. Interactive direction is a technology providing directions online, as given by one person to another. Make your customers find directions to your location, as easy as getting to their home. Your customers can invite their family and friends by Emailing or Text Messaging Directions directly from your website. Reduce your customer service efforts significantly by directing them to your website with confidence. Try it to see the difference. Interactive Directions (c) is vrindi&apos;s copyrighted concept. More... 
 
 Your diners don’t need to be dismayed now for the unavailability of an ambient dining place in their favorite restaurant. Using our Online Table Reservation software, they can book tables in advance at any of your restaurant locations, sitting at their home! Diners can now book tables anywhere in advance. Besides they can also place booking requests for banquets, parties, family functions, wedding ceremonies, etc. Get immediate reservation/booking details on your computer, sent via electronic mail, mobile text message and FAX. More... 
 
 Explore new dimensions of Advertising and Publicity. We provide a threefold solution for all your business campaigning issues. And our solutions ensure that you rule the market! Also get listed on numerous online business and restaurant directories.
 To top it all we provide your restaurant listing on our revolutionary portal for elite restaurants – RestaurantWave! More... 
 
 Get the most out of your web presence with our unique online promotion facilities for your website. Give your business the power of ‘Just-in-Time Promotions’. Make sure that your Offers catch the customers’ attention instantly! Now your customers can know of new announcements regarding lunch/dinner buffets. We design eye-catching flash promos and animations for your website’s home page that change on daily-weekly basis. Get promotional campaigns on telephone, FAX, bulk mail and SMS.
 Offers and Discounts won’t go unnoticed now, and reach your customers timely. More... 
 
 Give your restaurant website the SEO advantage. Our expertise and experience in Search Engine Optimization guarantees your website top rankings in Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs) of Google, Yahoo, AOL and various other organic and inorganic search engines. We leverage your business by providing you a well-placed and highly competitive platform for ‘Search Engine Marketing’. Our research in SEO guarantees you highly accurate, findable and competitive set of keywords that improve Google-Yahoo-friendliness of your website. Get listed among the top 10 of the search results page! More... 
 
 We design websites that enable easy online access for your customers to all your restaurant locations from a single access location. They can now place reservations and orders at anywhere, anytime! Provide your customers the ease to order food, or get bookings at any of your restaurant locations, using the same centralized website.
 They also get road maps and animated driving directions to all the locations. More... 
 
 
 
Vrindi’s ingenious products give you a competitive edge in today’s cut-throat world
 of Restaurant business, marketing and e-commerce, where an Internet presence is
 extremely crucial. Statistically, 45% of consumers aged 25-37 use Internet to find
 restaurant locations and online spending per person has increased by 75% last year.
 In this opportune time, having a restaurant website with Online Ordering facility would greatly leverage your sales! Why not cash on this?

Our websites increase your efficiency in taking orders, while revolutionizing Menu
 Management and the ordering process itself! And the Online Payment feature ensures sure&amp; Highly Secure Credit Card Processing&amp;Transactions .
 Our advanced Search Engine Optimisation will accord your site excellent findabililty
 on Google, Yahoo, etc. And to complement this, you get a three-fold Online Marketing solution, with Yellow Pages listings and Just-In-Time Promotions .
 Using our Interactive Road Map&amp;Driving Directions feature, your customers
 can reach any branch of your Multi-location restaurant. The Website POS Integration streamlines your business, and you also get Monthly Website Traffic Report and 24x7 Web Support . A fully Customized Domain Name&amp;Website , with
 robust Database Hosting Service is just what you need.. Join us, and rule
 the market! 
 Customized Website with Online Ordering for your Restaurant 
 
 Eldorado Diner [More] Sinapis Pizza Rustica [More] La Stella Deli [More] Bulls Head Diner [More] Kickin Chicken Kickin Chicken Restaurant is one of the best Chicken restaurants in Haledon, New Jersey. It serves “fresh&amp;fried” chicken recepies and fast food dishes. The specialties here include Buffalo&amp;Kickin’ Wings, Fish and Chips and Kickin’ Sandwiches. It also offers the facilities of banquet and external catering. They support online ordering at www.kickinonline.com [More] Chutney Mary Chutney Mary and Manor is a fine Indian Restaurant and Banquet Hall in Manmouth, New Jersey (NJ) owned by The Riya Group (www.riyagroup.com). Chutney Mary specializes in authentic Indian and Chinese cuisines. They boast of an exotic Indian food menu and serve one of the best preparations, both vegetarian and non-vegetarian. Chutney Manor’s Indian banquet hall, party halls and corporate meeting halls have top-class catering services including Lunch buffets. They extend Online Ordering, table booking and pick-up facilities at www.chutneymary.us / www.chutneymanor.us [More] S&amp;H Kebab House S&amp;H Kebab House in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (PA) is a family-owned Turkish restaurant. It specializes in serving Turkish, Middle Eastern and Mediterranean cuisines. Chicken and Vegetable Soups, Eggplant Salad Appetizer, Lamb Kebab, Chicken Mushroom sauté, Baklava dessert and Doner Grilled Kebap are some of the best preparations it serves. Live entertainment with Belly Dancing shows on Fridays is its star attraction. It also supports Online Ordering and Delivery ( www.kebabhouseonline.com ) and Banquet&amp;Catering services. [More] Cluck U Chicken Cluck U Chicken is a famous chicken restaurant owned by the Cluck U Corporation, located at Greenview Drive Suite, Laurel, Maryland (MD). It specializes in hot Chicken sauce, Chicken bbq sauce and 911 sauce. It has an exhaustive menu of various sauces it offers. Cluck-U provides the facility of Online Ordering of their specialties. Their merchandise can be ordered at www.shopping.cluckuchicken.com [More] Tiffin Blog Tiffin Blog provides unique solutions for the lunch and dinner needs of their customers. It delivers “Tiffin” on daily, weekly or weekend bases. It specializes in providing home style vegetarian and non-vegetarian Indian food. And what’s more is that the food is delivered to the customers’ door – home or office. The menu changes every month and that is posted on the website www.tiffinblog.com It operates in New Jersey (NJ), Bronx (New York, NY) and Manhattan (New York, NY), preparing Indian food at its fully inspected, approved and licensed professional kitchen, and delivering it in Microwave save containers. The orders can be placed at orders@tiffinblog.com. [More] Simply Fresh Delivered Simply Fresh Delivered is a San Diego based cafeteria and hospital catering house. They deliver high quality, nutritious and healthy food to night shift employees at hospitals. The food is always freshly prepared and they deliver even late in the night. They have an online ordering enabled website ( www.simplyfreshdelivered.com ) and provide Free Delivery service. Fresh Simple Food, Delivered Late Night, when You Need It! [More] Abuja International Abuja International is a fine restaurant in New Jersey that serves authentic Caribbean, West African and American food. It also provides banquet&amp;catering services for birthday parties and weddings. Its specialty is Desserts and Drinks. It can be visited at www.abujainternational.com [More] Flavor Of India Flavor of India in Plainsboro, New Jersey NJ is an exotic Indian restaurant serving the very best of North Indian, South Indian and Indian Style Chinese cuisines. Punjabi and tandoori food, Indian chat dishes, Indian desserts and beverages are their specialities. With plush and ambient interiors, it’s an ideal place to celebrate birthday parties&amp;anniversaries. They serve grand lunch buffets, both vegetarian and non-vegetarian on weekends. They take online orders ( www.flavorfindiaonline.com ) and provide for food delivery and catering services too. [More] Bangkok Degree Restaurant Bangkok Degree situated at Cariappa Marg, New Delhi is an authentic Thai Restaurant&amp;Café. They serve the best Thai Food in Delhi, with Thai Noodles, Som Tam Salad, Tom Yum Soup, Po-Pia Thod Appetizer and Phad Nam Prik Pao being some of their specialties. They serve both vegetarian and non-veg cuisines. They can be visited at www.bangkokdegree.com [More] El Gran Rodeo El Grand rodeo is an authentic Mexican Restaurant and Margarita Place in West Chester, Pennsylvania. They serve all Mexican cuisines of varied flavors, colorful decorations and variety of spices, prepared fresh and in a great ambience. Some specialities are Burrito, Tortillas, Chalupas, Tostados, Frijoles Refritos, Enchilada, Nachos, Sandwiches, Sopapillas, Guacamole, Chile Relleno, Quezo Fundido, Tacos, Tamal, Chicken&amp;Pollo Parrilla Chicken. They have weekly lunch specials, provide catering packages and have an online menu up at www.elgranrodeopa.com [More] Akbar Restaurant Akbar Restaurant serves great Indian food in NJ since 1976,we believe in consistent quality and service to customers. They have well designed banquet halls, courtyard and delicious food is catered to the guest of parties of all types.
 Vrindi&apos;s RestaurantWave solution enabled them to get many online inquiries for our Banquet functionality and Table Reservations. Publishing ongoing events also is a very useful to promote their business. www.akbarrestaurant.com [More] Lovash Indian Cuisine Lovash is the finest Indian Cuisine in Philadelphia, PA(Penssylvenia).It also provides Hukka Room To serve more better they have come up with a repertoire of dishes from the southern part of Indian taking into consideration lots of factors that will help us reach and serve all of you, and give a broader variety to choose from and also take you on a gastronomic tour of India that is our motto and keyword. And more you will be feeling the warmth of Home Cooked food being served to you away from home. Online Ordering at www.lovashrestaurant.com They also take Catering Orders and Online Table Reservation requests. [More] Royal Kamling Royal Kamling serves Indian, Chinese and Thai Cuisine. Royal Kamling Edison, NJ., Food is of Freshest and Highest Quality of ingredients. Most Dishes are prepared according to your preference like Vegeterian, no garlic, with garlic etc. Dine-in and Take-Out. Online Ordering at www.royalkamling.com They also take Catering Orders, Party Trays and Online Table Reservation requests. [More] Taj Tribeca Taj Tribeca serves great Indian cuisine in New York City. They brought the Cuisine of the Taj to the Tribeca area of this metropolis of great diversity, art&amp;culture. They serve the most authentic Awadhi Cuisine to the discerning residents&amp;guests of Tribeca. Vrindi&apos;s RestaurantWave solution enabled them to get many Online Orders and Table Reservations. Taj Tribeca welcomes you to have a unique experience of India through the incredible cuisine of Taj Tribeca presented by master chefs.
 Visit Taj Tribeca at www.tajtribeca.com . [More] Crown of India Since 1990, Crown of India has been offering the full menu of authentic Indian dishes prepared using ingredients of the highest quality. They offer completely remodeled banquet rooms for meetings/conferences/parties. RestaurantWave made it possible to get online order for food and table/banquet reservation.
 Visit www.Crown-Of-India.com . [More] Columbus Gourmet Food Columbus Gourmet Food, located at Upper West Side of New York City known for its fast food and Pizza. Columbus Gourmet’s extensive selection of eclectic offerings and your hunger is sure to be satisfied! Try their catering options for private parties, luncheons, picnics, or office get-togethers. Visit Columbus at www.ColumbusGourmetNYC.com . [More] City Market Cafe City Market Cafe, Located at Upper East Side of New York City known for Specializing in Fresh Fast Food. This chain of New York cafés is a dream lunch destination. Visit City Market Cafe at www.CityMarketNYC.com . [More] Cake Walk Cake Walk Indian Bakery&amp;cafe is located in plainsboro NJ. A unique bakery with the Indian touch was started in India and soon spread all over the world, because of its unique fusion of western and Indian taste in bakery products. Visit Cake Walk at www.CakeWalkOnline.com . [More] Indian Hut Indian Hut also known as Hot Breads of Benslem are located in the heart of Chester County, Pennsylvania. They serve choice of traditional Indian dishes, the fusion of Indian American (Chinese cusine as known to Indians). They also caters for Party. Visit Indian Hu at www.IndianHut.com . [More] Indian Kitchen Indian Kitchen the Indian Style Chinese Cuisine, in Pennsylvania Since 1997. They bring Mumbai street food, South Indian and North Indian Food dishes. They have been creating the tastiest Dishes with the best value for their loyal customers in Pottstown Pike, Pennsylvania area in a clean, comfortable, intimate, family-oriented atmosphere. Visit Indian Kitchen at www.IndianKitchenPA.com . [More] Chaanakyas Chaanakyas Restaurant L.L.C is a Indian Chiness Cusine near Al Qouz, Dubai.Chaanakyas serves you to the exotic Far East and offers a healthy and ethnic dining alternative. Not only does Chaanakyas have a beautiful private dining room, but is available for on-site catering ... let us bring the Tandoori oven to you! Visit Chaanakyas at www.Chaanakyasuae.com . [More] Yummie Solutions Yummie solutions servers Quality Food for Quality People. They deliver food directly to your office/home doors. And you need not pay any extra charges for this service. Visit Yummie Solutions at www.YummieSolutions.com . [More] Pan Asian Bowl PanAsian bowl serve fresh&amp;healthy food with an innovative dining experience, They have expanded their menu to include specialties from Malaysia, Thailand&amp;China. Party lounge providing music&amp;screens of the highest quality, guests can enjoy a more relaxed evening like never before, and all this for an extremely affordable price where quality. Visit Pan Asian Bowl at www.PanAsianBowl.com . [More] Ashoka Indian Cuisine Ashoka Indian Cuisine serves best Indian Food and also provides online ordering and food delivey at Pleasanton CA. Visit Ashoka Indian Cuisine at www.ashokacuisine.com . [More] Golden River One of the Best Restaurant in San Francisco, CA providing a great test of authentic and delicious Hong Kong Style Chinese Cuisines, Dim Sum and Seafood. Visit Golden River Restaurant at www.goldenriversf.com . [More] Daisey&apos;s Diner Daisey&apos;s Diner, brooklyn NY&apos;s best 24x7 diners.Serves healthy food at your place. Provides Free and Fast Delivery. Visit Daisey&apos;s Diner at www.daiseysdiner.com . [More] MichelAngelo&apos;s Pizzeria MichelAngelo&apos;s Pizzeria serves the Finest and Fresh Italian Food in Yonker&apos;s NY. It provides online ordering, catering and VIP club. Visit MichelAngelos Pizzeria at www.michelangelospizzas.com . [More] Famous Famiglia Pizzeria Famous Famiglia Pizzeria serves wonderful, classic italian food and specialty Pizzas. The website is been established with best Restaurantwave features like online ordering, catering, directions etc. Visit Famous Famiglia Pizzeria at www.famousfamigliawp.com . [More] VillaNova E. Villa Nova E. has been family owned and operated for 40 years. They provide Italian favorites and some Villa Nova Originals. They Not only offer a bar and a spacious dining room, but also two catering rooms each with a seating capacity of approximately 140 persons. Visit Villa Nova E. at www.villanovae.com . [More] Only Falafel Only Falafel, a multilocation restaurant, Edison 08820 and in Philadelphia 19103, serves the best food in the town. Mexican Post is their another food court that servers the best mexical food.Visit Only Falafel at www.onlyfalafel.com/ . [More]
	</body>
</document>
