<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006444" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/cookout-restaurant-cary-north-carolina-3008668.html" time="2012-07-12-23:22" support="1" score="0.0021761020337995925" bingtitle="Cookout Restaurant in Cary, North Carolina - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="Cookout Restaurant in Cary, North Carolina - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>... there I had the pleasure to eat at a fast food restaurant called ... I was really impressed with the menu selection and ... All of my food tasted charbroiled. My burger was ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Cookout Restaurant in Cary, North Carolina
 DiamondJewelSpiritHeaven , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Apr 15, 2009 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: North Carolina Caries 
 Flag Close Post a comment When I first moved to the Raleigh, NC area I was staying at a hotel on Walnut St. in Cary, NC. While staying there I had the pleasure to eat at a fast food restaurant called Cookout.
From the outside the restaurant didn&apos;t look like much. It boasted itself to be &quot;the best place for burgers,&quot; so I thought that one day when I was in the mood I would try the place out. I thought right off the bat that they would probably just sell fried chicken and burgers but nothing significant. I usually prefer when I eat out to buy seafood or Chinese or the type of food you can eat with a fork; but sometimes I do get into fast food moods.

One day I was in the mood for something more quick and inexpensive so I decided to try the place out. When I first pulled up to the drive through; I found to my great surprise that the menu had quite a lot of choices. The burgers were described as charbroiled and had many ways that they could be ordered in addition to plain or with cheese. Some of these choices included: Out West Barbecue, Steak Style, Cheddar Style and many more. I tried the Out West Barbecue Style because I love barbecue and bacon. It was delicious.

I was really impressed with the menu selection and literally said &quot;Wow,&quot; out loud. It had a lot of what many people would consider southern specialties like chopped pork with barbecue; or slaw; corn dogs; hot dogs; and slaw dogs. I literally had no idea what I was going to get at first because they had so many things that I liked. They also carry chicken that is prepared by charbroiling or in the deep frier chicken finger style. They have similar chicken choices to the burger choices and you can have your french fries prepared with cajun seasonings, cheese or chili.

They sell milkshakes, standard sodas and a soda I never heard of called cheer wine. They also sell sweet tea like most restaurants in this area. I was curious to try the cheer wine, but must admit that I chickened out. I was really thirsty that day and really didn&apos;t want to buy something I didn&apos;t like. I was also on a daily budget and wouldn&apos;t be able to replace the beverage with anything other than tap water. I do plan to try the Cheer Wine out one day though.

I must say that I was also pleased to see once I received my order that you get a lot of food for your money. My visit to Cookout was well worth the money. The only negative thing I can see is that Cookout only has locations in the Raleigh Triangle Park area of North Carolina. This is not a national chain. If they did decide to expand though without comprimising the quality of the food sold; I think this restaurant would be appreciated all over the country. All of my food tasted charbroiled. My burger was huge to say the least; at least 5 inches in diameter. All of my other food tasted fresh and the restaurant looked clean and well cared for from what I could see. I was very pleased.
 
Published by DiamondJewelSpiritHeaven 

I am a young woman who has many interests. I enjoy writing as a means to share experience,learned knowledge and joy with others.  View profile 
 
 Fast Food Calories: Where to Find Them This article helps you find fast food calorie information in your area and compare meals Fast-Food Survey Results - Where&apos;s Your Beef? Zagat and the Today Show surveyed 5,535 people to find out who has the best fast-food. Dave would have been proud. Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Many fast food restaurants are now offering healthy choices. This means Americans can get their instant satisfaction without receiving a side order of thunder thighs. But, how... Guilt-Free or Almost Guilt-Free Fast Food Meals Fast food doesn&apos;t have to mean &quot;the worst food you could eat&quot;. It is possible to make healthier choices even at fast-food restaurants. Review of Trader Joe&apos;s Grocery Store in Cary, NC Review of the new Trader Joe&apos;s location in Cary, NC. 

 Measuring Portions at Restaurants Top 10 Tips for Healthy Restaura... What Makes a Great Restaurant? 
 
 Auto Sales in Cary North Carolina Triangle Shopping: Computer Stores in Raleigh and Durham, NC Exciting Cookout Ideas Eat Fast Food and Still Be Healthy Fast Food is Everywhere in CA What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? Cookout Restaurants - Fast Food Done Right 
 
 
 
1 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Elena 11/10/2010 
My friend&amp;I have dined at Coquette Brasserie, several times now, especially in the bar area. The food is delicious, moderate prices,&amp;the service is very good as well. The duck confit crepes, lovely moule frites, best frites in the Raleigh. Coquette is a true french brasserie, in beautiful setting. This is our favorite restaurant in North Hills.
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
