<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006579" url="http://articles.dailypress.com/1995-02-27/business/9502270024_1_hampton-roads-newport-news-police-department-drive-through-window" time="2012-07-12-23:30" support="1" score="0.0029999928660953464" bingtitle="Fazoli&apos;s Italian Restaurant To Offer Fast-food Service - Daily Press" webtitle="Fazoli&apos;s Italian Restaurant To Offer Fast-food Service - Daily Press">
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Fazoli&apos;s is a fast-food restaurant serving spaghetti, fettuccine ... &quot;We are monitoring Hampton, and so far we can tell ... Slain Hampton woman had protective order against ...</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt; Collections &gt; Hampton Roads 
Fazoli&apos;s Italian Restaurant To Offer Fast-food Service

Storefront
 February 27, 1995 | By PATRICIA LINEBERRY Daily Press 
A Kentucky company broke ground last week on the area&apos;s first Fazoli&apos;s Italian Restaurant at 11739 Jefferson Ave. in Newport News - next door to the International House of Pancakes and across Jefferson from the Oyster Point business park.

Pasta Isles, owned by Frank Cain of Lexington, holds the local franchise, the chain&apos;s second in Virginia, and plans to open the restaurant in late April or early May.
 
Cain also runs 33 Long John Silver Seafood Shoppes in Illinois, said Frank Massino, operations director for Pasta Isles.

Fazoli&apos;s is a fast-food restaurant serving spaghetti, fettuccine alfredo, pizza, minestrone soup, salads and desserts. The 144-seat restaurant will have self-service drink and condiment stations inside and a drive-through window.

Cain plans to open 10 more franchises in Hampton Roads over the next four years, Massino said. Virginia&apos;s first Fazoli&apos;s opened in August in Christiansburg.

CATCH THE BUS, GUS. Pentran will roll out the welcome mat next week at its new facility in downtown Newport News.

&quot;Our intentions are to start operating buses out of the station March 6,&quot; said Michael Townes, Pentran&apos;s executive director.

The facility, at 34th Street and Washington Avenue, will be equipped with vending machines and newsstands. More important, he said, the Newport News Police Department will occupy 3,500 square feet of office space inside the terminal.

Greyhound Bus Lines, which transferred its Jefferson Avenue operations to Pentran&apos;s new Hampton terminal in December, does not plan to operate out of the Newport News terminal, said Walter Benjamin, Greyhound&apos;s customer service manager.

&quot;We are monitoring Hampton, and so far we can tell that our Newport News customers are coming to Hampton to travel,&quot; Benjamin said.

BROWSING ... Ukrop Super Markets Inc. was named &quot;Grocer of the Year&quot; by the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services for actively promoting Virginia products. Winn-Dixie and Kroger were runner-ups. ... Nottingham Hallmark in Williamsburg Shopping Center will celebrate the grand opening of its newly expanded store Saturday with food and prize drawings.

* Got a tip for StoreFront? Call Lineberry at 247-4734, fax it to 245-8616 or send it to the Daily Press, 7505 Warwick Blvd.
 Featured Articles 
Fireworks in Hampton Roads
 
800 new Green Mountain Coffee jobs coming to Isle of Wight
 
Virginia&apos;s new synthetic marijuana law difficult to enforce
 MORE: 
 Independence Day on the Peninsula moves forward without Fort Monroe celebration 
 
 Virginia&apos;s blue crab season starts with a bang 
 
 Obama to campaign in Virginia next week 
 
 Health insurance check coming for thousands in Virginia 
 
 Newport News launches arrest database for public 
 
 800 new Green Mountain Coffee jobs coming to Isle of Wight 
 Related Articles 
 On The Move 
 October 4, 1993 Crime Report/faces/places 
 June 14, 1990 
 Find More Stories About 
 Hampton Roads Business Park 
 Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Index by Date | Index by Keyword
	</body>
</document>
