<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006932" url="http://forums.radioreference.com/new-jersey-radio-discussion-forum/96470-monmouth-county-taxi-companies.html" time="2012-07-12-23:55" support="1" score="0.0024592625641193023" bingtitle="monmouth county taxi companies - The RadioReference.com Forums" webtitle="monmouth county taxi companies - The RadioReference.com Forums">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>... for any taxi companies in monmouth county mainly ... Why do some people enjoy monitoring fast food restaurant drive ... out of date it is as these taxi cab companies change ...</description>
	<body>
		The RadioReference.com Forums &gt; Regional Radio Discussion Forums &gt; New Jersey Radio Discussion Forum monmouth county taxi companies 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 FAQ Members List Calendar Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 

 New Jersey Radio Discussion Forum Forum for discussing Radio Information in the State of New Jersey. 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Tag Search Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 

   LinkBack Thread Tools Search this Thread Display Modes 
 
  # 1 ( permalink )  02-14-2008, 9:55 AM 
 eclipse3256 Member     Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: ocean county nj Posts: 168 
 monmouth county taxi companies anyone have frequencies for any taxi companies in monmouth county mainly belmar asbury area. Checked various websites including fcc database and can not locate anything. I have seened numerous cabs in those areas with vhf antennas any help would be great! 

 Sponsored links 
      
 
 
  # 2 ( permalink )  02-14-2008, 10:56 AM 
 fineshot1 Member   
 Premium Subscriber   Join Date: Sep 2004 Location: NJ USA (Republic of NJ) Posts: 2,635 
 Dont know if any of these are still valid but give em a try.

152.345B - Able Transportation (Manasquan)
157.605M - Able Transportation (Manasquan)
152.270B - Briggs Taxi Base (Point Pleasant Beach)PL 107.2
157.530M - Briggs Taxi Mobiles (Point Pleasant Beach)PL 107.2
152.435 - Homestead Taxi (Spring Lake Heights)
151.955 - Shore Jitney (Manasquan) __________________
fineshot1
NJ USA 
 
  # 3 ( permalink )  02-14-2008, 12:30 PM 
 Tech792 Member   
 Premium Subscriber   Join Date: Mar 2003 Location: Central NJ Posts: 813 
 Also, when checking the FCC database, a lot of these taxi operations aren&apos;t corporations so the license may be in the proprieter&apos;s name.
Ex. Joe Smith DBA
Atlantic Taxi Co. 
 
  # 4 ( permalink )  02-15-2008, 7:41 AM 
 DJ88 Member     Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Brick Twp., New Jersey Posts: 1,835 
 Here&apos;s a few from Asbury Park that probably make runs into the area you mentioned:
Citi Cab
452.275 - Base&amp;Mobile
Independent Taxi
152.315 - Base
157.575 - Mobile
Supercab
452.0500 - Base&amp;Mobile
Topps Taxi
152.450 - Base
157.710 - Mobile
Vets Cab
152.360 - Base
157.620 - Mobile

Coast Answering - Avon
150.845
Not sure if they still operate taxi cabs or not. They do operate mini buses though.

The frequency listed for Homestead Taxi, above, is the base frequency. Mobile is
157.465

Just a FYI, I don&apos;t know if you&apos;re familiar with the way taxi companies operate or not, but a lot of them use two frequencies; dispatch uses the base frequency and the cabs use the mobile frequency. I was told this is done to prevent the drivers from yaking back and forth with one another. __________________
My Toys:
Uniden BCT15X | Uniden BCD996T | Uniden BCD396T
Uniden BC785D | Bearcat 210XLT 
 
  # 5 ( permalink )  02-15-2008, 2:06 PM 
 242 Member     Join Date: Jun 2006 Posts: 47 
 What is the enjoyment in listening to a Taxi company? 

 Sponsored links 
      
 
 
  # 6 ( permalink )  02-15-2008, 3:26 PM 
 DJ88 Member     Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Brick Twp., New Jersey Posts: 1,835 
 Why do some people enjoy monitoring fast food restaurant drive thrus, Wal Mart, Target, school buses, aircraft and military comms, trains? Personally I have no interest in any of it, but that&apos;s what makes this hobby so versatile. We all have different things we enjoy monitoring and there&apos;s something for everyone. As they say, different strokes for different folks. __________________
My Toys:
Uniden BCT15X | Uniden BCD996T | Uniden BCD396T
Uniden BC785D | Bearcat 210XLT 
 
  # 7 ( permalink )  02-20-2008, 12:28 PM 
 N2ZGE Member   
 Amateur Radio   Join Date: Jan 2007 Posts: 461 
 Monmouth County Taxi Frequencies Here are the frequencies I confirmed myself as of last summer, officially licensed or not:


ASBURY PARK TAXI SERVICES - 152.315, 152.450, 157.575 (may be an input)

LONG BRANCH SHORE TAXI - 159.795

POINT PLEASANT (BRIGGS TAXI) - 152.270

RED BANK YELLOW CAB - 153.680

I can not confirm any for Belmar though. 
 
  # 8 ( permalink )  03-05-2008, 9:11 PM 
 eclipse3256 Member     Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: ocean county nj Posts: 168 
 taxi frequencies thanks for the help anyone have there pl tones alot of RF in this area and hearing other companies from further away 
 
  # 9 ( permalink )  04-28-2008, 5:21 PM 
 NESN Member     Join Date: Apr 2004 Posts: 297 
 LEON&apos;S TAXI Freehold area 151.6850/210.7 with a LOUD ANI tail...... __________________
SIGINT: In God We Trust, all others we monitor. 

 Sponsored links 
 
  # 10 ( permalink )  06-01-2008, 4:53 PM 
 eclipse3256 Member     Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: ocean county nj Posts: 168 
 taxis monmouth/ocean counties I know this was originally posted but if anyone has any more up to date info on taxi companies in either county please share would be greatly appreciated 
 
  # 11 ( permalink )  06-01-2008, 5:43 PM 
 fineshot1 Member   
 Premium Subscriber   Join Date: Sep 2004 Location: NJ USA (Republic of NJ) Posts: 2,635 
 This is my complete list but again I do not know how out of date it is as these taxi cab companies change freqs frequently and also go in&amp;out of business quickly as well.

461.9250 - AAA Taxi DPL 026
152.345B - Able Transportation (Manasquan)
157.605M - Able Transportation (Manasquan)
151.8650 - Apex Taxi Co(TR)
152.270B - Briggs Taxi Base (Point Pleasant Beach)PL 107.2
157.530M - Briggs Taxi Mobiles (Point Pleasant Beach)PL 107.2
152.450B - Monnies Yellow Cab - Toms River
157.710M - Monnies Yellow Cab - Toms River
461.550 - Lincoln Taxi(out of business)
152.450B - Monnie&apos;s Yellow Cab (Toms River)
157.710M - Monnie&apos;s Yellow Cab (Toms River)
157.560 - Aries Motor Transit (Lakewood) (out of business)
153.170 - Laurel Taxi/Leisure Hack (Lakewood)PL 192.8
152.435 - Homestead Taxi (Spring Lake Heights)
151.955 - Shore Jitney (Manasquan)
157.560 - Regnu Taxi/NJ Medical Transport (Lakewood)(out of business)
159.780 - Cedar Bridge Taxi (Lakewood/Brick)(They use one frequency only)
159.870 - Cedar Bridge Taxi (Lakewood/Brick)(They use one frequency only)
159.855 - Latino Express Taxi (Lakewood)DPL 074
159.675 - Bennies Taxi (Lakewood)DPL 025
472.2125 - Price Rite Towing/AA-1 Taxi/Mantoloking Taxi
151.6850 - LEON&apos;S TAXI Freehold area PL 210.7
464.4500 - Taxi Cabs Out Of Jackson(unknown) DPL 072 __________________
fineshot1
NJ USA 
 
  # 12 ( permalink )  06-01-2008, 6:37 PM 
 DJ88 Member     Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Brick Twp., New Jersey Posts: 1,835 
 Here&apos;s the database link for Price Rite Towing/AA-1 Taxi/Mantoloking Taxi:
 http://www.radioreference.com/apps/db/?sid=4920 __________________
My Toys:
Uniden BCT15X | Uniden BCD996T | Uniden BCD396T
Uniden BC785D | Bearcat 210XLT 
 
  # 13 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 12:47 AM 
 countryboy879 Member     Join Date: Dec 2005 Posts: 222 
 would anyone have the freq for either brick or ace taxi? 
 
  # 14 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 5:04 AM 
 fineshot1 Member   
 Premium Subscriber   Join Date: Sep 2004 Location: NJ USA (Republic of NJ) Posts: 2,635 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by countryboy879 would anyone have the freq for either brick or ace taxi? 
 157.5900 - ACE Taxi

i confirmed this with my freq counter

sorry - but i have not figured out brick taxi yet __________________
fineshot1
NJ USA 
 
  # 15 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 4:16 PM 
 GM Member   
 Premium Subscriber   Join Date: Dec 2002 Location: 08817 Posts: 397 
 One of the taxi cab companies in the Belmar area operates on MURS in Base/Mobile mode 154.57000 PL 123.0. I believe that it is the Shore Taxi Co. (may be based near the Boathouse restaurant on 15th Ave&amp;Main St. ??) Another cab co. that always cracked me up was when I was working in Long Branch, and that was the Paramount Cab Co. Those guys really set the standard as far as entertainment goes with Cab companies!! They are also a Base/Mobile type on 151.74500 PL 94.8. (That was back in 2007 though). 

 Sponsored links 
      
 
 
  # 16 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 5:27 PM 
 eclipse3256 Member     Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: ocean county nj Posts: 168 
 don&apos;t think it&apos;s shore they have to big of a fleet. I think i know who it is once u said the location. The guy is cheap lol he&apos;s use cans tied with string if it would work lol 
 
  # 17 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 5:29 PM 
 eclipse3256 Member     Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: ocean county nj Posts: 168 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by fineshot1 157.5900 - ACE Taxi

i confirmed this with my freq counter

sorry - but i have not figured out brick taxi yet 
 










Ace is brick taxi just a different license but same owner they also own nj medical transportation 
 
  # 18 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 7:38 PM 
 countryboy879 Member     Join Date: Dec 2005 Posts: 222 
 do they have a base freq and a mobile freq? 
 
  # 19 ( permalink )  05-03-2010, 7:39 PM 
 countryboy879 Member     Join Date: Dec 2005 Posts: 222 
 whats the pl? if any? 
 
  # 20 ( permalink )  05-09-2010, 9:54 PM 
 countryboy879 Member     Join Date: Dec 2005 Posts: 222 
 anybody?? do they have a mobile freq and base freq?...whats the pl? 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 


 Bookmarks 
 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 Search this Thread 
 Advanced Search 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On Forum Rules 
 
 
 


 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 4:55 PM . 
 
 The Radio Reference Homepage - Archive - Privacy Statement - Top 

 Powered by vBulletin®Version 3.8.2
Copyright©2000 - 2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All information here is Copyright 2012 by RadioReference.com LLC and Lindsay C. Blanton III.Ad Management by RedTyger   
 Copyright 2011 by RadioReference.com LLC Privacy Policy  |  Terms and Conditions 
   
 
 
 LinkBack LinkBack URL About LinkBacks
	</body>
</document>
