<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006247" url="http://www.texasspeeders.com/RestProd/mexican.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:55" support="1" score="0.0015551334580518469" bingtitle="Good Eating Fort Worth Mexican Section - TexasSpeeders.Com ..." webtitle="Good Eating Fort Worth Mexican Section">
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>Mexican food is my food. I love it. ... to see a long line out the door waiting on a table. ... It used to be a fast food restaurant but they closed ...</description>
	<body>
		Ole!
 
Mexican food
 is my food. I love it. When I was a kid, I had plans to marry a beautiful
 Hispanic wife who could cook good Mexican food. So much for dreaming.
 I don&apos;t think I can go a week with out it. So many different versions
 and different tastes. You can&apos;t find one exactly like the other. But
 this makes for great character in the food as well.

La Famalia:
 2720 West 7th Street { West of Downtown }
Phone: 817-870-2002
Eating There Since: 2002
My Stomach Says: Nothing can beat originality!
Service Details: Never a wait, excellent service, the owner
 is there to shake your hand.
More Info:

Everyone has their own opinion of what a great Mexican
 restaurant should be. When it comes to looks, some think it should
 be adobe looking and have sombreros hanging from the walls. Others
 think it should have an exotic setup with a big pool and garden. This
 restaurant is far from looking like those styles. It was a McDonalds before
 it closed down. The owner took it over and brought with him his experience
 of 30 years in the Mexican food industry. You don&apos;t come to a restaurant
 to look, you come to eat, and they have the food for you. They try
 to get away from using any lard and the owner has a personal gripe
 with other restaurant&apos;s chicken. He says that most restaurants use
 shredded chicken that comes out of a bag that is boiled. He dices
 fresh chickens. He brags that his chickens are so fresh that roosters
 come to his restaurant.&quot;You can&apos;t find fresher mexican food.&quot;Their specials are always changing and they are constantly brining
 in new meals with different sauces or different meats, never a boring
 moment to the taste buds. No other restaurant has been this original,
 they usually stick with one type of meal and cook it for years. You
 may not see many sombreros but you will see all the awards they have
 won. They recently won an award for Fort Worth&apos;s Best Salsa. They
 have lunch specials and dinner specials that are pretty inexpensive.
 Come give it a try, they may have that taste you been looking for.

Joe T&apos;s (Joe
 T. Garcia&apos;s): 2201 N. Commerce Street { North Fort Worth }
Phone: 817-6264356
Eating There Since: Forever?
My Stomach Says: I have found the holy grail of re-fried beans
Service Details: Normally a short wait on weekdays and a long
 wait on weekends
More Info:

I have been going to this place for as far as I
 can remember. I can remember the famous Juan Hernandez who started
 his singing career in that restaurant. Yes! They have a group of musicians
 walking around playing music and singing. I think they only do this
 on the weekend in the evenings. This place gets packed. Be prepared
 to see a long line out the door waiting on a table. You have the choice
 of staying in one line that will seat you inside or you can go to
 the patio and be seated somewhere out there. They have a beautiful
 patio. For dinner you have two choices, fajitas or the family dinner.
 The fajitas come to you all at once while the family dinner is served
 in parts and comes on big plates that you serve yourself (just like
 when you are at home). The family dinner starts out with a cheese
 tostada (2 per&quot;family dinner&quot;person) and then tacos (2
 per&quot;family dinner&quot;person). Watch out, your fajita ordering
 people think these items are for them too. Slap their hands! I am
 very territorial when it comes to food. Don&apos;t touch mine. You then
 get a plate with the two enchiladas served on them and a big plate
 of rice, beans, and guacamole for all the family dinner people to
 spoon onto their plate. The beans are ROYAL. I leave this place with
 a dry mouth and the after taste of their beans. Wow, I sleep good
 tonight.

Caro&apos;s: 3505
 Bluebonnet Circle { Mid South Fort Worth, TCU }
Phone: 817-924-9977
Eating There Since: Forever
My Stomach Says: Puffy tacos, puffy nachos, and so good cheese.
Service Details: Good and Fast
More Info:

This place is incredible. Be prepared to be fattened.
 If you are looking for a place for it&apos;s own originality, this is it.
 You come in and seat yourself. Your drink orders are taken and you
 have a chance to look at the menu that was laying on the table. This
 is the home of the puffy taco and chips. They serve the best nachos
 in town. I would suggest the 1/2 and 1/2. This is 6 nachos with cheese
 and 6 with guacamole. These things can start a fight in the family
 on who gets the last one. I am set on the beef enchilada dinner, 2
 with rice and beans. My mom gets the chicken tacos and my girlfriend
 gets the flautas. The rice and beans are made in heaven. Put this
 on your Mexican food&quot;need to eat here&quot;lists.

El Fenix:
 6391 Camp Bowie Blvd. { West Fort Worth }
Phone: 817-732-5584
Eating There Since: 1980?
My Stomach Says: We need to come back on a weekly basis.
Service Details: Good and Fast
More Info:

I have been going to this restaurant for about 20
 years. The have a special on Wednesday where you can get two cheese
 enchiladas, rice, and beans for under 5 dollars. They get so much
 business on that evening that they have to take names and it takes
 about 10 minutes of wait time to get a table. The normal price of
 their meals average at about 8 to 10 dollars. They have expanded their
 menu to include many items like honcho sauce and banana paradise sopapillas
 (have not tried this one ...yet).

Cancun: 7419
 Camp Bowie Blvd. { West Fort Worth }
Phone: 817-696-8810
Eating There Since: 2001
My Stomach Says: Gosh, I like their food.
Service Details: Ready to seat you before you come inside.
More Info:

There is something about this place that I just
 like. It is small. It used to be a fast food restaurant but they closed
 down and Cancun&apos;s took over. I have never had to wait to sit down
 and have eaten a couple of their many choices of dinners on the menu.
 I can&apos;t get past this one dinner. The Cancun dinner is a tamale with
 cheese sauce, a beef enchiladas with chile con carne, a chicken enchilada
 with Swiss sauce, a taco, rice, and beans. It cost about 8 dollars. I have taken
 some friends with me to test this place. Two out of three put this place in their
 top ten list of best Mexican restaurants.


Original Mexican Eats Cafe: 4713 Camp Bowie Blvd. 
 { West Fort Worth }
Phone: 817-738-6226
Eating There Since: 2003
My Stomach Says: There is something about the food, must eat it again.
Service Details: No line, quick seating.
More Info:

First I must forewarn you - The building is hot in 
 the summer and cold in the winter. They do not have good heating or 
 air. So, I have been in the restaurant eating with a jacket on and 
 my date shivering. If you are willing to get over those hurdles, which 
 many of us have, the food is great. I can&apos;t tell you what food item 
 does it for me but there is something that tingles the tastebuds. 
 The place allways has a good amount of people eating but I never recall 
 a line. The waitstaff is good at getting everything you need fast. 
 So the only downfall, when I walk out of the restaurant, may be the 
 temperature.


 !CLOSED! - Miranda&apos;s: 
 3803 Southwest Blvd. { West Fort Worth } - !CLOSED! 
Phone: 817-735-9988
Eating There Since: 2001
My Stomach Says: Not sure, need to try it again.
Service Details: Fast seating, no rushes, decent service
More Info:

Not much I can say here. I have eaten here many
 times and come out at about the same place in thought. There food
 is good but it is not&quot;shazam&quot;, if you know what I mean.
 They serve their chips with the normal cup of hot sauce but also throw
 in a cup of beans. That&apos;s different and I like places that promote
 a different character. I, also, have to say that I am a re-fried bean
 junkie. I think the taste of your re-fried can make or break you. Their
 refried is good but it&apos;s missing something. I can&apos;t quite figure it
 out. It leaves my stomach forgetful. So a couple of weeks down the
 road, it&apos;s saying&quot;hey what did that Miranda&apos;s taste like&quot;.

Uncle Julio&apos;s:
 5301 Camp Bowie Blvd. { West Fort Worth }
Phone: 817-377-2777
Eating There Since: 2000
My Stomach Says: Decent enchiladas, average beans, but
 the Fajitas make up for it all.
Service Details: Slow to get a table and poor customer service
 by management.
More Info:

The only reason this place has not made it to the
 complaints section is because the good food slightly out weighs everything
 else that is poor. Many of my friends and co-workers have voiced their
 opinion to me about how they hate being billed for replacements. In
 example, you order the Fajitas and tell them you don&apos;t want the rice
 and beans. You ask that you trade the rice and beans out for the graded
 cheese and some sour cream. The cheese and sour cream normally are
 an extra charge. The waiter/ress says sure and the person gets what
 they ordered. They are charged both the price of the fajitas (with
 rice and beans) and the price of the sour cream and cheese. Another tidbit
 if information, that you should know, is that when you ask for cheese and
 sour cream with your fajitas, the menu shows you a single charge (&quot;Cheese and Sour Cream&quot;) for the addition
 but when you get the bill, there is a double charge (I guess they really meant Cheese or Sour Cream). I have
 seen people argue with management on this and other issues. Needless
 to say, the customer has lost against management every time or should
 I say management has showed how they really care about their customers.
 Let&apos;s get back to food. The fajitas are probably the best in town.
 They are marinated in something good and cooked to perfection.

 
 
 

 Breakfast American Home Italian     Greek German Oriental Complaints
	</body>
</document>
