<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006650" url="http://host.madison.com/test/webfeeds/personal-finance/march-foreclosure-activity-down-to-near--year-low/article_cf29ba8c-6a27-5ce5-bdee-6159fdd0c223.html" time="2012-07-12-23:38" support="1" score="0.00048111829465696885" bingtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low" webtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low   : Madisondotcom">
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low ... the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place to ... Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are ...</description>
	<body>
		Place an ad WSJ Subscriber services Archives Obituaries More 
 Advertiser Services Legal Notices Email Alerts Mobile Apps Comics Games&amp;Puzzles Contact us 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 Contribute 
 Article Event Photo Video 
 My Account 
 Edit Profile Subscriptions Logout 
 
 89° Partly Cloudy 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 93° 71° Saturday 95° 70° Sunday 91° 72° Monday 94° 75° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home Sites 
 Madison.com Capital Times Wisconsin State Journal 77 Square Sports Prep Zone Daily Cardinal 
 News 
 
Topics

 News Now Local News Wisconsin news Business Nation World Obituaries Photo Galleries 
 
The Latest
 
 Dad charged in 3 daughters&apos; deaths in River Falls 

Wisconsin prosecutors charged a North Dakota man Thursday with killing his three young daughters, who were found tucked in to their beds.
 
 Dean Health Plan expanding to Green Bay market 

Madison-based Dean Health Plan has signed an agreement with Prevea Health and St. Vincent Hospital in Green Bay to offer health insurance thro…
 
Recent

 Another bout of mid to upper 90s coming next week Burn ban extended; 4 state parks prohibiting campfires New scam in town: Solicitor asks for old medications Update: Beltline lane, ramp at Fish Hatchery Road reopened Cops to crack down on US 151 speeders 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 College Preps Packers Brewers Local Recreation Colleges BadgerBeat 
 
The Latest
 
 Lawmakers furious about U.S. Olympic Team&apos;s Chinese-made uniforms 

Members of congress are unhappy with the U.S. Olympic Committee&apos;s decision to dress the U.S. team in Chinese manufactured uniforms.
 
 UW-Whitewater will dedicate athletic complex to former coach 

The University of Wisconsin-Whitewater will dedicate its student athletic complex to Bob Berezowitz during Sept. 22 ceremonies on the UW-White…
 
Recent

 UW football: Badgers continue to show up on latest preseason watch lists Phelps downplays teammate&apos;s comments on work ethic Penn State officials concealed Sandusky&apos;s abuse, report says Gary Engberg: A cool event amid hot days of fishing Packers Insiders blog: Rodgers repeats as NFL’s best player at ESPYs 
 
 Entertainment 
 
Topics

 Food Movies Music Arts City Life TV &amp; Games Events Comics Games &amp; Puzzles Travel People 
 
The Latest
 
 Table Talk: Yeah, I Ate That: The Red Robin Fiery Ghost Burger 

Made with sauce containing the world&apos;s hottest pepper, Red Robin&apos;s newest offering packs some heat.
 
 Recent Obsessions: &apos;Margaret,&apos; Ellen Page, Stomp Rocket 

77 Square staffers share their latest fixations: Week of July 12.
 
Recent

 Surround Sound: La Fete de Marquette brings a taste of New Orleans to Madison Farmers&apos; Market &apos;off the square&apos; due to Art Fair this weekend From the Capitol Square to Door County, art fairs offer atmosphere as well as aesthetics Salud! Small-batch brew hits the big time Spotlight: &apos;Shut Up and Play the Hits&apos; 
 
 Events 
 
Topics

 Submit an Event Books &amp; Readings Clubs &amp; Nightlife Community Kids &amp; Family Lectures Music 
 
The Latest
 
 Queenie&amp;the Bluecats, 5:30 p.m.; Madfork w/ Wild Nothing, Night Moves 

All ages
 
 Big K.R.I.T. w/ Casey Veggies, Big Sant 


 
Recent

 Psalm One, M.I.C., Ted Park, Darius Walker, Qwayz, DJ Pain 1 
 
 Weather 
 Current Conditions Live Radar Forecast Severe Weather Airline Delays 
 Communities 
 Blogs Community Events Celebrations Worship Directory 
 Get It 
 Classifieds Coupons Deals Sell it Madison Newspaper Ads Business Directory Place an Ad 
 CarSoup 
 New Used Certified Sell Research The Shop Dealers Specials Videos 
 Jobs Homes Rentals 
 
 Trending Metered subscription: Questions and answers You asked Madison.com golf guide City salaries 2000-11 John Doe investigation 
 
March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low

March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low
 Print Email 2012-04-11T23:11:47Z March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low The Associated Press The Associated Press April 11, 2012 11:11 pm  •  Associated Press (0) Comments 
LOS ANGELES (AP) — More U.S. homes are entering the foreclosure process, setting the stage for a surge in properties repossessed by lenders this year.

The number of homes that received first-time foreclosure notices rose 7 percent in March from the previous month, foreclosure listing firm RealtyTrac Inc. said Thursday.

That marks the third consecutive monthly increase this year and reflects stepped-up efforts by banks to take action against homeowners who fail to keep up with mortgage payments.

&quot;We&apos;re not out of the woods yet with foreclosures,&quot; said Daren Blomquist, a vice president at RealtyTrac. &quot;There are more batches of foreclosures coming through the pipeline.&quot;

Foreclosure activity, as measured by the number of homes receiving foreclosure-related notices, slowed sharply in the fall of 2010 when claims surfaced that some banks and mortgage servicers were processing foreclosures without verifying documents.

A $25 billion settlement reached in February between the nation&apos;s biggest mortgage lenders and state officials has paved the way for banks to take action on unpaid mortgages, many of which have been in a procedural limbo for months or years. And it&apos;s those homes that could ultimately be foreclosed-upon and end up back on the market.

Foreclosures typically sell at a discount to other homes and can drag down the value of neighboring properties, so the prospect of more foreclosures means it could take longer for home prices in some areas to bounce back.

The U.S. housing market remains weak, even after the best winter for home sales in five years and steady improvement in the job market. Home prices are now back to 2002 levels, according to the Standard&amp;Poor&apos;s/Case-Shiller U.S. home price index.

Rather than a large wave of bank-owned homes crashing onto the market at once, it&apos;s likely the new crop of foreclosures will arrive in smaller waves throughout the year, Blomquist said.

Still, many of the homes entering the foreclosure process now are properties with loans that have gone unpaid for a long time, not instances of borrowers just starting to fall behind. That suggests the possibility that the number of homes at risk of foreclosure could begin to taper off once banks tackle the crop of homes with long-overdue mortgage payments.

&quot;The faster we can move some of these old foreclosures through the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place to recover,&quot; Blomquist said.

At the end of last year, some 1.5 million U.S. homes had mortgages that had gone unpaid at least 90 days, according to Mortgage Bankers Association data.

First-time foreclosure notices, such as warnings of initial default, are the first step in the process that can potentially result in a home being foreclosed upon. Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are paid. Sometimes, a bank will allow that the home be sold for less than what the borrower owes on their mortgage, a so-called short sale.

All told, 101,939 U.S. homes received a first-time notice in March, the biggest monthly increase since October, RealtyTrac said.

Thirty-one states posted a monthly increase in homes with a first-time foreclosure notice. Nevada led the pack with an increase of 153 percent.

Even so, foreclosure activity overall — as measured by the number of properties receiving a notice of default, scheduled for auction or repossessed by lenders — sank in March to the lowest level since July 2007, the firm said.

In all, 198,853 homes received a foreclosure-related notice last month, down 4 percent from February, and down 17 percent from March last year.

Banks took back 55,075 homes in March, down 14 percent from the previous month, and down 25 percent from March 2011.

RealtyTrac expects banks will repossess close to 1 million homes this year. Last year, lenders took back 804,000 homes.

For the first three months of this year, foreclosure activity fell 2 percent compared to the last quarter of 2011 and was down 16 percent from the first quarter of last year, the firm said.

Foreclosure activity in the first quarter fell primarily in states where the courts do not play a role in foreclosures. Among them: Arkansas (79 percent), Nevada (62 percent) and Arizona (21 percent).

In contrast, many states where courts must sign off on foreclosures saw outsized increases foreclosure activity, including Indiana (45 percent), Connecticut (38 percent) and Florida (26 percent).
 View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
More Test stories
 
 
 Fewer auto closings reduce US unemployment claims 
 
 News Summary: US mortgage rates dip to record lows 
 
 Emerging market bonds: 4 things you need to know 
 
 Buffett says general economy slowing this summer 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
 Like us on Facebook and win! 
 
Most Popular
 
 Articles Comments 
 
 UW football: Latham&apos;s pick of Badgers a slam dunk Madison biotech facility expected to close; 179 could lose jobs Fitchburg police probe child&apos;s death in domestic incident; adult in custody Judge blasts &apos;frivolous&apos; lawsuit alleging assault by Sandusky at Camp Randall Middleton woman drowns in Wolf River 
 
 Plain Talk: Sen. Johnson, have you no sense of decency? (67) Supreme Court says local communities can&apos;t set restrictions on factory farms (43) Crime and Courts: Advocates blast city&apos;s proposed downtown panhandling ban (25) Van Wanggaard’s fine whine (19) John Nichols: Paul Ryan wants to blackmail democracy (14) 
 Latest comments 
 Latest Local Offers 
 View More... 
 Looking For A New Rental Home? Apartment Matchmakers will help you today! 

Looking for your next new rental home? Personalized and profes…
 
 $300 OFF Cabintets at HC Cabinets&amp;Design, LLC 

$300 OFF All New Kitchen Orders Until December 31st, 2012!
 
 Yahara Bay Distillery - Tours&amp;Tastings 

Call anytime to arrange group tours and tastings.
 
 Farm&amp;Fleet - Enjoy the great outdoors even more 

Enjoy the Great Outdoors&amp;Save! Sales on tents, sleeping…
 
 LIKE US ON FACEBOOK&amp;BE ENTERED TO WIN A $15 GIFT CARD Clark&apos;s Hooves&amp;Feathers 

Clark&apos;s Hooves&amp;Feathers
 
Featured Businesses
 
 Salons of Distinction 
 
 Gagne Ford LLC. 
 
 Tim O&apos;Brien Homes 
 
 Crestwood Auto Clinic 
 
 Candlin Pet Hospital 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
For Sale

 Carsoup Stuff Homes 
 
Vote!

 Who do you like best of the Republican candidates for U.S. Senate? 
 Loading… 
 Tommy Thompson Eric Hovde Mark Neumann Jeff Fitzgerald I&apos;m not sure 
 View Results 
Win!

 Like us on Facebook and enter to win! WATSKY --A versatile lyricist switching silly&amp;serious with complex and simple. SUMMER NIGHTS! with Wook and Madtown Dubstep DJ Battle. Win free entry! THE GREAT AMERICAN CANYON BAND --&quot;intimate, honest and ethereal&quot; LANGHORNE SLIM&amp;THE LAW --&quot;gospel-infused soul born out of late nights&quot; Jerry&apos;s Hot Picks MULLIGAN MATCH-UP --Your shot at $250 or a free foursome! Win free movie tickets and stay on top of Madison&apos;s movie scene! 
 
Special interests

 Fight epilepsy through music Go Madison! 77 Square dining guide Healing Arts Directory - Spring 2012 Newspaper archives Nursingmatters Order here: I want my TV magazine Sign up for email newsletters 
 
 FEATURES 
 News Sports Entertainment Events Weather Communities Obituaries Games, Puzzles E-mail Archives Blogs 
 GET IT 
 Classifieds Coupons Deals Sell it Madison Newspaper Ads Business Directory Place an Ad Homes Jobs Carsoup Rentals 
 Advertiser Services 
 Download a media kit (PDF) Photoshop Color Settings BW Guidelines Color Guidelines Submit a celebration Legal Notices Submit digital files for ads Place a classified ad for print or online 
 Capital Newspapers 
 Madison.com Wisconsin State Journal Capital Times Sports Wisconsin Prep Zone 77 Square Daily Cardinal Nursing Matters WiscNews 
 
 ©Copyright 2012, madison.com , 1901 Fish Hatchery Rd Madison, WI | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Madison Apartments Madison Attorneys Madison Auto Dealers Madison Auto Parts Madison Auto Repair Madison Beauty Salons Madison Car Rental Madison Dentists Madison Doctors Madison Flowers Madison Hotels Madison Insurance Madison Loans Madison Mortgages Madison Movers Madison Pizza Madison Realtors Madison Restaurants Madison Storage Madison Tax Preparation Madison Travel More Madison… Middleton Apartments Middleton Attorneys Middleton Auto Dealers Middleton Auto Parts Middleton Auto Repair Middleton Beauty Salons Middleton Car Rental Middleton Dentists Middleton Doctors Middleton Flowers Middleton Hotels Middleton Insurance Middleton Loans Middleton Mortgages Middleton Movers Middleton Pizza Middleton Realtors Middleton Restaurants Middleton Storage Middleton Tax Preparation Middleton Travel More Middleton… Waunakee Apartments Waunakee Attorneys Waunakee Auto Dealers Waunakee Auto Parts Waunakee Auto Repair Waunakee Beauty Salons Waunakee Car Rental Waunakee Dentists Waunakee Doctors Waunakee Flowers Waunakee Hotels Waunakee Insurance Waunakee Loans Waunakee Mortgages Waunakee Movers Waunakee Pizza Waunakee Realtors Waunakee Restaurants Waunakee Storage Waunakee Tax Preparation Waunakee Travel More Waunakee… Oregon Apartments Oregon Attorneys Oregon Auto Dealers Oregon Auto Parts Oregon Auto Repair Oregon Beauty Salons Oregon Car Rental Oregon Dentists Oregon Doctors Oregon Flowers Oregon Hotels Oregon Insurance Oregon Loans Oregon Mortgages Oregon Movers Oregon Pizza Oregon Realtors Oregon Restaurants Oregon Storage Oregon Tax Preparation Oregon Travel More Oregon… Cottage Grove Apartments Cottage Grove Attorneys Cottage Grove Auto Dealers Cottage Grove Auto Parts Cottage Grove Auto Repair Cottage Grove Beauty Salons Cottage Grove Car Rental Cottage Grove Dentists Cottage Grove Doctors Cottage Grove Flowers Cottage Grove Hotels Cottage Grove Insurance Cottage Grove Loans Cottage Grove Mortgages Cottage Grove Movers Cottage Grove Pizza Cottage Grove Realtors Cottage Grove Restaurants Cottage Grove Storage Cottage Grove Tax Preparation Cottage Grove Travel More Cottage Grove… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Thank you for reading
You have viewed all free pages in 30 days . Please login or register at this time and enjoy articles free of charge.
 No Thanks 
 
Thanks for visiting
You&apos;re entitled to view free articles every 30 days , and you currently have free articles remaining before being asked to login or register. 
Use your existing host.madison.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with host.madison.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
