<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006987" url="http://community.foodandwine.com/service/searchEverything.kickAction?as=117547&amp;mediaType=blog&amp;sortType=commented&amp;includeBlog=on&amp;d-7095067-p=15" time="2012-07-12-23:58" support="2" score="0.0016711953509530985" bingtitle="Blog posts with the most comments - Food and Wine Community ..." webtitle="Blog posts with the most comments - Food and Wine Community - Inspiration served daily">
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="90"/>
	<description>You constantly find yourself going to each fast food restaurant ... all of which is placed on like this huge trash can ... as all manner of asian staples like rice and condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		F&amp;W Community

 Register or Login 

 Favorites Profile Logout 
 
 2 FREE PREVIEW Issues 
 Tablet Edition | Give a Gift 
 
f&amp;w everywhere
 
 RECIPES&amp;CHEFS WINE&amp;COCKTAILS RESTAURANTS&amp;TRAVEL ENTERTAINING&amp;HOME BLOGS MAGAZINE 

 Events Subscribe 
 Food&amp;Wine’s Daily + Weekly Newsletters Ingredients 
 Beef Chicken Pasta Pork Seafood See All 
 Cuisine 
 American Asian French Italian Mexican See All 
 Dish Type 
 Easy Fast Healthy No-Cook Vegetarian See All 
 Occasion 
 Brunch Cocktail Party Cookout/BBQ Graduation Party See All 
 Best Lists 
 Best New Recipes Best New Chef Recipes Best New Recipe Collections Staff Favorites Recipe Trends 
 More in recipes&amp;chefs Food&amp;Wine’s Wine List Newsletter 
 Wine Spirits Beer Cocktails Mocktails Trends 
 Best Lists 
 50 Best Bars in America Best Value Wines 
 More in wine&amp;cocktails Food&amp;Wine’s Travel Tips Newsletter Best Lists 
 Best Burgers Best Grilled Cheese Best Fried Chicken Best Doughnuts Best Ice Cream Cities 
   
 Best Bed&amp;Breakfasts Best Coffee Bars Best Pie Spots Best Cities for Street Food Best Airport Dining 
 More in restaurants&amp;travel 
 Best Kitchen Design Best Equipment Setting a July 4th Table 
 More in home&amp;design Food&amp;Wine Tablet Edition 
 Recipes Features&amp;Columns Subscribe 
 F&amp;W in Los Angeles, buy tickets 
 2012 Calendar Promotions Sweepstakes F&amp;W Videos F&amp;W Classic 
 New! 2012 Annual Cookbook 
 Magazine Newsletters Books Wine Club Connoisseur Club iPad Edition 
 
 community homepage my profile photos rants and raves members discussions 
 
 add a blog post my blog most recent highest rated most viewed top favorites most comments 
 
 log in join now forgot password 
 advanced Search 
 photo blog member message pages 
 Results 281 - 300 of 650 «Previous 1 2 ... 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 ... 32 33 Next» 
Blog Posts With the Most Comments

 
 Food Stylist Food Stylist 

 From: Palomalorena03 Description: 
Hi out there!!!

Im on my new career path, on becoming a food stylist. I recently Graduated from college with a BA in Hospitality Management concentrating in Marketing. After Graduating i Realize that every job a look up had somethings a like and some that i did not. So i Started a quest on finding a career in food that would have all of my passions (Food, Photography, People, Good Life, ect.) So after researching for days a found FOOD STYLING as a career. And everything i read about it said more and more of the things i like doing. So i decided to move to New York in order to pursue my dream as a food stylist.

 

Any advise???
 Blog post 7 months ago Views: 349 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Giro D&apos; Vino Giro D&apos; Vino 

 From: EncompassLife Description: 
 http://encompasslife.net/2011/11/20/giro-d-vino-a-wine-tasting-and-cycling-extravaganza/ 
 Blog post 7 months ago Views: 306 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Caramelized Chicken Caramelized Chicken 

 From: natalie.sztern Description: 
 

 

 

A fantastic recipe for Broiled Chicken breasts and legs. Great on the BBQ or Grill. Versatile Marinade which produces a caramelized coating, luscious in color and taste.

 

A few of the ingredients can be found in an Asian Grocer - the most difficult to come by will be the Japanese Vinegar and the Yuzu so feel free to substitute for more of the unseasoned rice vinegar or lemon juice squeezed from a fresh lemon: taste for the tartness.

 
 after the first 20 min and time for 1st basting 
 

 

The ginger came from my freezer. WHAT ...your freezer?

 

 

 

 

 

 

Yes, when I get a knob of ginger I like to grate what I need for the recipe and then, for just a few minutes more, I grate the entire knob or hand, as it is called. Then I wrap it sausage shaped onto a piece of plastic wrap and freeze the balance so that I have fresh ginger when I need it and the rest of the knob doesn&apos;t go to waste. As anyone knows, grating Ginger is a b_tch, except when you take it from the freezer.

 

 

 

 
 DONE! 
Grating ginger must have been a punishment invented by the Samurai: before the days of waterboarding.

 

Not only does it take forever - what you reap from that is almost nothing. I use a ceramic grater especially for grating ginger. I also have the microplane grater and either will do.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
 
 Japanese Marinated Chicken Caramelized Chicken     
 Recipe Type: Main Author: Natalie Sztern Prep time: 15 mins Cook time: 90 mins Total time: 1 hour 45 mins Serves: 4 chicken breast on the bone marinated and broiled Ingredients 
 1 1/2 pcs cut up chicken 4 oz Honey Garlic sauce 2 oz Wafu®Original Sesame 4 oz Wafu®Wasabi Edamame 1 tbsp Rooster Sauce (Sriracha) 2 oz Gyoza dipping sauce 2 oz Chinese vinegar 2 0z unseasoned Rice Vinegar 2 oz Yuzu 1 tsp grated ginger 2 tsp garlic, fine chop 
 Instructions 
 Combine all ingredients in large bowl Reserve 1 cup of marinade and set aside Take chicken, at room temperature, and marinate for at least 2 hours or overnight if you wish Set Oven for 375 F Lay Chicken in one layer on baking sheet and pour over the remaining 1 cup of marinade. After 20 minutes of baking, open oven and baste chicken; continue basting ever 15-20 minutes or until chicken becomes caramelized. If the chicken looks ready but has no color then Broil it for 5 min to caramelize. Take it out and let it sit for 10 minutes and serve. 
 Notes 
Depending on your oven and the size of the chicken if they are deboned or bone-in the amount of cooking time may vary. The idea is to get the chicken a deep golden color on top and this happens the more you baste. The basting is for the color.
 
 

 

 

 

 STAY TUNED FOR WAFU CONTEST NEXT WEEK: WINNER WILL WIN THIS: 

 

 

 

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 463 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Traci K talks about the Turkey Traci K talks about the Turkey Diet Plan 

 From: tracik Description: 
 In the latest issue of FitSTyle magazine. They talk about the turkey diet plan 

and &quot; CABERNET&quot; We asked the editor

 What is the plan?

Well as you might say that most are concerned about weight gain during the holidays this plan is simple start to keep on track but enjoy.

 

Can you really lose weight?

It is more about detoxifying plus contributing to moods and stress. So yes it can help with hormonal embalance and stress. And results vary per individual but you could I noticed results.

I slept good and felt relaxed.

 

So what is some of the things can you talk about it?

Well don&apos;t want to give it away but you need to read the latest issue cause it also featured my latest singles and albums coming up plus free stuff ...

 

What is this about and what is this trying to do?

Well help raise money for losses where people like me know of the struggles as an artist or health professional getting the benefits we need and also military familys.

many times I never ever was not with family but the military and recent situations has caused stress amongst us and never really see much of them it really changes and it is sad cause growing up I wasn&apos;t used to that type of abandonment. But a lot of artists , athletes or military families do on tours. The costs and the situations seem to make it harder. 

AHH...we hope that changes for you ...and you deserve it...so what is it about the latest?

 

I am trying to ofcourse get back to life and recover the funds from the losses....so my music is part of the spirits....it also helps with health.,..and of course we deal with relationships during this time.

and my latest singles talk about that.

 

We noticed you other names why? Oh that is the past but keep it from my fitnesss and health days

so I keep it but I go by my original Traci K...or Kochendorfer. 

 

Well you can check out her latest on her facebook and also buy her album 

 

photograph contributed by Shel Spencer( us army)

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 517 Comments: 0 
 
 Cold Somen Noodles With Japane Cold Somen Noodles With Japanese Dipping Sauce 

 From: natalie.sztern Description: 
 

 

 

 

 

On a day when the sun is still shining and it is hot and the beach is staring you in the face and when you sweat in the air conditioning there is one food that screams out to be the choice and that is a salad.

 

Salad is not just lettuce, tomatoe, onion and radishes. Salads come in variables that only is limited by the imagination.

 

I love a Japanese salad; wakame; cucumber marinated with mirin and soy sauce; simple green salad with Sesame Wafu®dressing or Goma-ae; and the infamous Naruto roll which is served usually with a vinegar dressing which is composed of Mirin and Seasoned Rice Vinegar.

 

 

 

 
 
 Naruto refers to a roll (maki) made without rice, that is wrapped in thinly-peeled cucumber instead of seaweed. The roll is named after the city on the southeast coast of Japan where the style originated. The city has a well-known tidal whirlpool (and fishing and the gathering of seaweed are important local industries).“Naruto”means“whirlpool”in Japanese. 
 
 

 

If you have ever sat at a sushi bar watching the Chef cut a cucumber like this, it is an amazing artistry of knife.

 

I was making lunch for‘the girls’one day and I decided on a light salad to serve which included using somen noodles. Somen noodles can be bought in most groceries now but can also be substituted for Soba noodles or Ramen noodles or rice noodles. All these noodles are much thinner than their Italian counterparts like linguine. They also come packaged in serving size. Each bundle is enough for one serving.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

Strain the noodles from their ice bath - then pat dry with a paper towel. Noodles need to be dried or strained very well if they are to take on a sauce or be used in a dip.

 
 Wafu®Wasabi Edamame Japanese Vinaigrette Dipping Sauce 
Wafu®

 

Somen take a literal minute to cook. It is a great dish for a fast meal or a great dish for a cold meal. One can choose any topping from crab meat to mushrooms to lobster and cucumber. You are limited by your creativity and desire.

 

 

 

 **Plates courtesy of Ofra-T Ceramics 

 

 

 

Stay tuned to the contest...
 
 Cold Somen Salad with Dipping Sauce 
 #ratingval# from #reviews# reviews Print 
 Recipe Type: Salad Author: Natalie Luffer Sztern Prep time: 2 mins Cook time: 1 min Total time: 3 mins Serves: 2 or more a cold salad of Somen noodles with a dipping sauce Ingredients 
 Somen Noodles (they are already portioned with thin strips of tape) Grated Japanese cucumber (seeded)** Sliced Scallion with greens Wafu®Wasabe Edamame Japanese Vinaigrette optional - Wakame or Kombu placed in the boiling water 
 Instructions 
 Take a pot of Water and place a small sheet of Wakame or Kombu (dried seaweed) into the pot of water with a teaspoon of salt and bring to boil. When boiling add the Somen Noodles taking off the tape. Carefully time the cooking as these noodles take literally a minute to become soft and once soft they are most definitely cooked. If serving cold, place the noodles in an ice bath. Once the noodles are cold or at room temperature place them on a plate and on top place the grated cucumber, and the scallions. In a separate dish place the Wafu dressing to be used as a dipping sauce for your noodles. Chopsticks are a nice touch 
 Notes 
The prep time is minimal and the portion is controlled by how many pre-portioned noodles you decide to use.

**Seeding a cucumber with a teaspoon is easy, just use the spoon to scrape the inside of the cucumber after having cut it in half. Japanese cucumbers have fewer seeds than the regular ones but Kirby cukes can be substitued.
 Google Recipe View Microformatting by Easy Recipe 2.1.7 
 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 443 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Aspen Food&amp;Wine;Festival Aspen Food&amp;Wine;Festival 

 From: bdelutis Description: 
I am interested in attending this event for the 1st time and wanted to know if others have gone and what their experience was like. I go Aspen every winter to ski but have not been there in the summer. 

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 378 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 salted carmel pie salted carmel pie 

 From: normaj Description: 
I didnt think using a recipe from food and wine would be risky , like so many other sites, etc... was I wrong. The salted carmel pie was the most tasteless thing I ever made, was an

 ingredient left out, are these recipes tested? Very dissapointing!
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 506 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Blog dedicated to Sous Vide! Blog dedicated to Sous Vide! 

 From: siliconvalleysousvide Description: 
Check out my blog dedicated to sous vide cooking!

 www.siliconvalleysousvide.blogspot.com 

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 277 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 A Chocolate Masterpiece A Chocolate Masterpiece 

 From: bylandersea Description: 
 Believe it or not, DNA was the topic of the conversation around the candlelit dining table at the exclusive Allegro Italian restaurant located within the Four Seasons Prague . A decadent orgy of multiple courses, each one a scrumptious blending of the finest, fresh ingredients with a masters touch unfolded. When dessert time arrived, an insatiable desire for chocolate teased our genes. Chef Andrea Accordi , under whose direction the kitchen became the first in the former Eastern Block to be awarded a Michelin star, and his staff arranged a chocolate art presentation at our table. How exotically fabulous.

A white cloth was positioned upon the table amidst an array of nugget-filled containers. An enthusiastic chef drizzled a sweet red liquid in an abstract design which I am told was beetroot sauce, but I would never have guessed. Then, he scattered candied orange and lemon rind around the delicacy, followed by candied kumquats. Rolled pieces of whiskey truffle bonbons were strategically placed as we witnessed awestruck an edible masterpiece sculptured before our eyes.

 

A small rectangular slice of frozen chocolate mousse was added near the center along with a triangular Earl Gray gelato, further garnished by seductive frozen jasmine foam dollops. Delectable spoonfuls of a chocolate hazelnut blend known as a croccantino adorned the whole along with sprinkled pistachio nuts. Lastly, the lively artistic creation was topped off with warm and heavenly chocolate sauce.

Then, each of us leered at each other, laughed, picked up our spoons and scooped to our hearts desire. A fusion of the finest chocolatier and ice cream shoppe enveloped our palate. An indulgence over the top, but wicked fun and a delightfully interactive way to end an elegant evening.
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 570 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Roast Goose Roast Goose 

 From: Thadman63 Description: 
In the earily 1990s (91 or 93) FW ran a December issue and the cover was Roast Goose. The receipes were great and this was my 1st attement at Goose and the one were you parboiled the goose is great. I moved to a new house this past year and in the move I lost several issue of old FW one of them being this issue. If anyone has a copy or the recipes from this issue please post. As I would like to prepare this for Christmas this year.
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 365 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Japanese-style Green Beans/Waf Japanese-style Green Beans/Wafu® 

 From: natalie.sztern Description: Japanese Style Green Beans with Wafu®Ginger Carrot Vinaigrette 
 

 

 

 When boiling Green Beans season water with Kosher salt.
 Let water come to a full boil - then lower the heat to a simmer. Beans should cook at a simmer from 8-10 minutes or until the beans are just starting to become soft. Have ready an ice bath - which is just a bowl with water and ice. This shocks the beans and keeps the color green vibrant. 
 ice water bath 
 

 

 Because I wanted to use the same water for the Bean Sprouts, instead of draining the beans in a colander, I used my Chinese Spider Skimmer to lift the beans and put them into the ice cold water bath. Next I put the water back up to a full boil - placed the Bean Sprouts carefully into the water - then counted to 40 and drained them. They, too, were quickly dunked into a second ice bath bowl to retain their crunch. The residual heat, without an ice bath, could mean the difference between a crunch or a soft sprout. 

 
 Toasting cashews 
 

 Toast the cashews–for this you absolutely must be beside the stove stirring the nuts because their natural oils can burn in a blink. Once you begin to smell the aroma of the nut take off the heat and continue for another 20 seconds to stir allowing the pan to cool down. 

 In cooking Residual Heat can make or break a dish which is why one must always take into consideration the fact that food continues to cook. Which is why meat needs to‘rest’. Microwaving also has residual heat and if you cook a baked potato in a microwave you must count on leaving it alone for another 30-40 seconds to completely cook. 

 Combine ingredients,except cashews and the Ginger Carrot Japanese Vinaigrette, which are placed just prior to serving. Actually I refrigerated it for a good hour. You want this to be a cold salad. I took the Carrot Ginger Wafu® and tilted the bottle for a taste test so that I could know how much ginger to add.... 
 
 It is here that I want to lay a complaint to all those bottlers who think that a top like this... 
 
 
 
 

 is a good top to have placed on your product...ketchup does it, the unmentioned here does it...mustard does it....lemme tell you the way it is: the piece of plastic with the writing that is supposed to be a &apos;TAB&apos; is almost impossible to grab hold of and therefore it is impossible to pull off. All that happens is the consumer has to take a sharp knife or a kitchen scissor and stab-stab-stab-it to death and hope that there is some way we can grab a little more of the cap which BTW is impossible to tear completely off the rim as the glue is so strong it make a clean opening absolutely IMPOSSIBLE!!!!! 
 
 
 Toasting cashews 
 

 

 As I said before, I took the Carrot Ginger Wafu® and tilted the bottle for a taste test so that I could know how much ginger to add. 

 

 

 AMAZING… 

 

 

 

 

 I couldn’t add anything. The taste was so dead on in flavour, including the tang of lemon; there was no way I could elaborate any more. The balance of flavours were Umami. 

 Every taste was there, discernable individually, with even a hint of that lemony tart taste. It was a divine Vinaigrette to be used on its own. 

 Delicious–Delectable–Delightful. 

 

 
 You know it is cold when the ice floats 
 

 

 

 

 

 
 
 Wafu®Japanese Style Green Beans #ratingval# from #reviews# reviews Print 
 Recipe Type: Side Dish Author: Natalie Luffer Sztern Prep time: 5 mins Cook time: 12 mins Total time: 17 mins Serves: 4 Japanese Style Green Beans Ingredients 
 1 lb fresh green beans, washed 1 tsp salt 2 c. mung beans/bean sprouts 1 c corn niblets, drained 1 bunch green shallot/scallions minced with green stems 2 bowls of ice water for bathing both green beans and bean sprouts 1 bottle of Wafu®Carrot Ginger Japanese Vinaigrette 
 Instructions 
 Boil green beans in salted water for 8-10 minutes or until beans are slightly soft but still have substance. Once done, with a large slotted spoon, take green beans out of pot and into an ice water bath. This will shock the beans allowing them to keep their gorgeous green color. Immediately bring the green bean water up to a boil and blanche the bean sprouts just a minute. Place them in a cold water bath as well. Let beans and bean sprouts chill in the fridge or come to temperature in their water baths. They should be room temperature and even cool to cold. Place in a bowl the green beans, the bean sprouts, the corn niblets, and the shallots/scallions. Pour over the Wafu Ginger Carrot Japanese Vinaigrette to taste and until the green beans have the shine of the vinaigrette. *Note: If you do a taste test of the Wafu Ginger Carrot Japanese Vinaigrette and you are someone who likes to tweak a recipe by automatically tweaking a dressing to your preferences - you will find, like I did, the the Wafu Ginger Carrot Japanese Vinaigrette has a perfect balance of flavors. Any other addition is not recommended. I, too, am a recipe tweaker and incredibly I discovered that this is a perfect blend of ingredients and includes an added flavor of lemon just enough to cut the sweetness of the sesame seeds and sesame oil. 
 Google Recipe View Microformatting by Easy Recipe 2.1.7 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

*plates courtesy of Ofra-T Handmade Ceramic plates

 

Stay tuned as I will be giving away a set of the four flavors of these dressings and then you can enter t he contest being run at Wafu® 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 399 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 NOW IT WAS BRANCAIA,TUSCAN, NOW IT WAS BRANCAIA,TUSCAN, 

 From: siddwine Description: 
 

 NOW IT WAS BRANCAIA,TUSCAN, 1 st Nov.’11 

 Prize winning wine producer Brancaia from Tuscan region,Italy are comparatively new in the wine world.The Swiss family,if not‘the only’in the region started in 1982 and shall thus complete their first 30 years, in next.Die hard commitments to quality, an ingrained element of Swiss, took them to heights of achievements within initial years. They witnessed a vertical take off right in 1983 winning the coveted first place, at Chianti Classico tasting.They did not look back thereafter.The brand has been occupying positions within first 100 all these years at major tasting sessions.Few years,within first 10.A laudable achievement. 

 The owners spared no stones and continued with their identity and strongly held principles of‘understanding their clients’and‘understanding their coworkers’immensely.So much so, Martin the present owner who at the tasting session for Press,in Mumbai on 1 st day of Nov.’11 explicitly described the seriousness they involve, taking their front line workers numbering round 55,every alternate year to visit other European cities and tasting their own brands and labels, exactly within an atmosphere their final consumers are subjected to.A unique integration of warmth,sentiment and understanding amongst produce and producers. 

 No wonder the importer Vishal Kadakia of Wine Park also stated, stressing their policy of selecting exporters,only who‘understand and ensure quality to uncompromising height and nothing less’.Cheers!! to such a thought itself. 

 While presenting three exclusive,highly popular Tuscan super classic red wines, selected for the evening,Brancaia Il Blu,Brancaia Tre,(both IGT Rosso Toscana) and Ilatraia(IGT Rosso Maremma Toscana) both declared their robust 2012 plan primarily to educate,make aware,demonstrate and train consumers,sellers,servers including wholesallers and retailers.Grand program indeed.And just the strategy needed for India today while getting up the stairs to know,appreciate and enjoy wines. 

 “Without the very best grapes you do not make top class wines”.Makers of boutique wine Brancaia, with nuances of hand making finesse,attends to soil selection,treatment and nurturing with same gusto as they maintain the vigilance and care over grapes,all the way till wines are bottled and shipped. 

 Brancaia Il Blu is estate’s top wine.It is elegant,complex and full bodied.Dark in color.An ideal mix of Sangiovese(50%), Merlot (45%) and Cabernet Sauvignon(5%).Well matured and aged wine which shall be a grand supplement to meaty,spicy and heavy food.North and Eastern Indian special occasion dinners shall have an ideal companion to their dishes.Less of tannin and full bodied. 

 Brancaia Tre is a blend of Sangiovese(80%),Merlot and Cabernet Sauvignon(20%).Light to dark in color. Leaves a happy taste in mouth and encompasses your feeling with warmth and maturity.Indian vegetarian dishes shall have good pairing,specially 4 states of South India shall have a good accompaniment to their rice and lentil based main dishes.Fish,coconut treated chicken dishes shall marry the label well.Often called as‘baby Tuscan’, appealed to me and shall definitely get a large number of ardent patrons soon in India. 

 The third one Ilatraia ,was another classic to be reckoned with.Darker in color.Top product from their other estate Maremma.A blend very well balanced of Cabernet Souvignon(60%),Sangiovese(30%) and Petit Verdot(10%).Aged for 18 months and then matured for several more, the wine smiles on your palette and goes well with slight flavor of spices.We tried 2004 vintage.And I am sure it shall be one of the selections,a connoisseur shall make. 

 One gets struck by the simplicity of their labels.Something definitely to catch your attention.In spite of large following,huge list of regular buyers and pan European presence with pride and prominence,the group has kept their most simplistic labels same, as they were originally designed in late 80s,last century.Martin confirms the philosophy behind,”no pretension,no show offs,we are simply quality stuck and committed only to serve clients well”.The estates both are under management of Martin Kronenberg for marketing,training and after sales service with Barbara for production and quality assurance. 

 The day we press members met,Martin and Vishal had tasting sessions at two major 5 star hotels, at two different corners of the city.Attending us, the team had to entertain a wine dinner arranged by one of their partner 5 star establishments of the town.A real hectic schedule as they resolved to give their best to their patrons, with understanding from both sides.They have similar plans on a continuous 5 days basis and that too on multi city basis.The 5 star and above establishments they shall cover, include,Olive,Taj Mahal in Mumbai,Taj Mansingh in New Delhi,Leela in Gurgaon and Claridges in Suraj Kund,New Delhi.All within Martin’s 5 days’stay in country.Wine strength?Or Brancaia inspiration? 

   

 Soon after Tuscany&apos;s Sensi and then the group of 50 Italian wine producers under the banner of Gambero Rosso,Italy, presented their best to Mumbai audience,it was now turn of another recognised,widely sought after boutique brand,Brancaia.All from Italy,the largest producer and largest exporter in the world.All took place within a short span of few weeks of October and November 2011.A great time for Indo-Italian wine relation. 

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 370 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Wafu® Wafu® 

 From: natalie.sztern Description: 
 

 

 

 

 

I am not a recipe developer by trade. I love all foods; particularly Japanese food and not just Sushi or Sashimi. I enjoy true traditional foods, either Japanese in nature or pure product.

 

 

 

I always have loved the umami taste –that 5th taste, so recently discovered and named.  I have always known it existed; here in the Paris of the North, that taste was always described it as the‘ Je ne said quoi” . We knew it existed but had no name for it.

 

 

 

 Umami. 

 

Henry and I were pioneers when it came to Sukiyaki, Shabu Shabu and the traditional Japanese-style dishes. While dating, in the middle &apos;70&apos;s as University students), we made Azuma, then near the Lafontaine Park , our go-to date place.  I still remember how it was below street level and in order to enter into the restaurant we had to dip at our knees to avoid the overhanging curtain (noren) .

 

In maintaining my love for Japanese food, it was my own husband who first introduced me to the world of Sushi when it had been introduced to him. We fell in love with Sushi and never looked back. Today I will eat only Sashimi and it must be in the best Sushi Restos in town. When the sliced fish literally melts in your mouth, you know this is the place to eat it, and you know this, also, by the number of people in the restaurant that you can see through its windows.

 

 

 

Anyone who writes a blog has‘virtual friends’. People with common interests and usually proficient in their field which is why you‘follow’them and enjoy what they have to say. If you are like me; you comment all the time. It gives my virtual friends feedback and in the process; albeit slow; one can actually develop friends or contacts.

 

 

 

This is how the next few posts I am writing, came to be.

 

 

 

 The Japanese Food Report is run by esteemed author and Chef, Harris Salat , and ne’er a post goes by where I don’t devour it. I love everything Harris cooks and writes about, because his specialty is Japanese.

 

 

 

 

You can’t love Japanese food without loving Sesame based Salad Dressing. known as Goma-ae.  Most Montrealers will remember the salad dressing of Katsura; it became so popular that they actually sold it by request in two sizes-a lot of years ago. Expensive but so good.

 

 

 

Then, miraculously, and in some stores only, in the 90’s, came a bottled salad dressing which was identical to what Montrealer’s were used to on their Japanese salads. Including (dare I say it)…including the Benihana on Decarie Blvd, where my daughter had a 6th grade birthday party. NOT A GOOD IDEA, because the kid I was least afraid would touch that VERY HOT flat-top, was the kid who did touch it.

 Wafu®is Kosher. ..The Heart and Stroke Foundation gives its seal of approval and the Canadian Food and Drug laws very carefully monitor ingredients and the use of symbols in their labels such Health Check and Peanut free and Kosher symbols. All must be factually verified and inspected especially, but not only, the Kosher Certification .

 

 

 Wafu®i s the Registered name of the Sesame Style Japanese Salad Dressing (goma-ae)I am talking about, that is bottled by Mari&apos;s Foods Inc.  Mari Toyoda was also a pioneer in Montreal&apos;s Sushi scene.  A Chef, herself, by profession in Tokyo, she also is a famed Sushi teacher in Montreal.

 

 Wafu®, once found in specialty food shops, alongside Prime Olive Oils and Balsamic Vinegars; it was costly. I guess Montrealer’s didn’t mind, because soon it became available everywhere. It was and is the‘Go-To’Salad Dressing for my family.

 

 

 

Wafu®is used as a marinade, a dip, a dressing…

 

 
 Wafu Original I use over tossed Salad. 
 

 

Recipes exist all over the net for Japanese Sesame Salad Dressing and I, myself, have made it numerous times; but the effort, the ingredients and the taste is a difficult balance to achieve. The Sesame seeds and the Sesame oil is a hard dance to master as it can become too sweet too quickly. It is also a hard dressing to fix in taste–remember it is that umami taste one aims for.

 

 

 

As with all Japanese cooking, balance reigns supreme. Wafu®is sold in Japanese food stores - the one I go to, Wafu®is virtually the only one sold as ready-made. If memory serves me correctly Miyamoto (Montreal&apos;s first &apos;really Japanese&apos; food store in Westmount, sold the dressing.  Miyamoto has a history all its own - not only Montreal&apos;s first specialty food store for Japanese ingredients it is also known for its quality of products sold and its dedication to Japanese Foods only. It is where, if you can believe it, my husband (the one who cooks spaghetti in cold water before the boil) and I took Sushi lessons - yes I begged and coaxed and finally won for the first and only time ever, when it comes to food.  (This is also the man who almost made a waiter faint when we ate at Commerc 24 in Barcelona) 

 

 
 New flavors of Wafu 
 

Now it comes as Wafu®Ginger Carrot and Wafu®Wasabi Edamame, individual packages for on the go; Wafu®The Original in Lite and it is soon coming out in a ready-made cole slaw to sit alongside Moishe’s. Another Montreal institution who realized the Montreal market had a need.

 

 

 

This I can’t wait for.

 

 

 

Wafu®is superb and over the next few posts I intend to show how it can be used and in recipes so easy to make. Why dedicate posts to Wafu®? I have been fortunate to have been contacted, through Chef Harris&apos;s blog, by Wafu® . It is a product I use, it is a product I love–and it is the product I commented on with regards to the Japanese Food Report. 

 

As far as I can see Wafu®has only room to grow.

In addition please stay tuned to this blog for a give-a-way contest sponsored by Wafu®. One winner will win all 4 flavors of Wafu®Japanese Vinaigrette in Lite, Original, Carrot and Ginger, and Wasabe. Canadian residents only postage paid. Details to follow. Relatives not allowed to participate and you know who you are...so don&apos;t bother. I love y&apos;all anyway....

x

 
 Blog post 8 months ago Views: 410 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Plum kuchen with streusel topp Plum kuchen with streusel topping 

 From: growntocook Description: 
 

Dough

¼l milk, body temperature

40 g fresh yeast

60 g sugar

500 g all-purpose flour

pinch of salt

90 g butter, melted

2 egg yolks

 

Filling:

750 g plums or damsons, halved (or quartered if large), pit removed

 

Streusel topping:

120 g cold butter, cut in 1 cm dice

120 g sugar

200 g all-purpose flour

 

1 egg white

 

To make the dough, mix flour with salt and sugar in a large bowl. Make a wel in the center and pour in the milk in which you have dissolved the yeast. Let it stand for about 10 minutes, or until the yeast bubbles up. Add the melted butter and yolks and mix everything together. The dough is too sticky to mix by hand, so use a wooden spoon to beat it until it becomes smooth and springy to the touch. Gently pressing with your hands, spread the dough evenly on a buttered sheet. Let rise for 30 to 45 minutes in a warm draught-free room. Meanwhile, make the streusel topping: mix butter and sugar in a bowl, then add the diced butter. Using your fingertips, rub everything together until it resembles breadcrumbs. Keep the streusel in the fridge until needed.

Preheat the oven to 180 degrees Celsius.

Top the dough with the plums, cut side up, leaving an edge of about 2 cm. Cover the plums with the streusel. Brush the edges with the egg white. Bake for about 30 min, or until the edges are golden and the topping starts to colour.

 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 367 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Meat Meat 

 From: johnhandaz Description: 
Montreal smoked meat is rare in the US would love to here from a good source on how to perfect this tasty treat at home.
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 285 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 10th Annual Fall Wine Classic 10th Annual Fall Wine Classic at the Richard Nixon Library 

 From: MaryKimberlyCornellOlson Description: 
The Fall Wine Classic brings together over 50 prestigious wineries from all over California and over 500 wine enthusiasts for a wine tasting event like no other. The East Room of the Richard Nixon Library is stunning and provides the perfect sophisticated&amp;elegant venue for our annual event.

Sunday November 6, 2011

2-5 p.m.

tickets: www.fallwineclassic.com 

 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 398 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Head To Tail Dining Head To Tail Dining 

 From: natalie.sztern Description: 
 

 Frozen Beef/Organs 

 Eating Head To Tail is very much in Vogue these days and Zoey can be its Mascot leading the way. Head To Tail ( including the you-know-what) ….

 

My dog, my pup, has allergies. At 22 lbs this BUGG is always scratching or knawing at herself. Part Pug, part Boston Terrier; her breed is called a BUGG but she is nothing but love.

 

 

 
 The very first day we got her. Cute Cute Cute 
 

 

 

Since she was 4 months old she has been suffering and if you combine the two breeds which are notorious for skin ailments, it is no wonder the poor thing suffers. Our Vet has done numerous tests and all we could come up with is that she suffers from‘environmental’allergies. There was nothing to be done but put her either on very expensive medication or on an allergy pill that has a touch of prednisone.

 

Neither were cures.

 

 
 All grown up but still the face of a puppy 
 

 

 My most recent order from Raw Paw . The Pink bowl is used only for Zoey’s food. 

 

 

 

 

 

 It is not mixed in with our dishes. 

 

 

I ran the gamut of trying different foods, toys, any possible product that went into her mouth to alleviate her scratching. Finally I ended up with the Vet’s recommendation of a new food to the Montreal market that was primarily Kangaroo and vegetables. Labeled for dogs specifically with Environmental Allergies.

 

She loved and did well on the food but unfortunately the Canadian Food and Drug Administration found a reason to ban the supply that came into Canada.

 
 Beef Tendons, dried 
 

Zoey hates the winter. So do I.

 

Bundling her up to take her for a walk in winter goes like this…On with the booties and on with the winter coat which goes over the heavily knit turtleneck sweater and then over all of that goes her harness.  By the time she is dressed she looks like a little fat piglet in pink. 

 

And I am in a total sweat.

 

 

 When I am ready to defrost her food it is usually a few smelts which I cut up and then mix it all together. Each portion is at least 1 piece of fish + meat = 60 grams + veggies/yogurt to equal a total of 95 grams per serving. 

 

If I am in a pissy mood I don’t put the booties on which actually look like balloons not yet blown up. They are called Pawz and are supposed to be the best…they are not.

 
 Pawz 
 
 Beef Neck, Large 
 

Open the door…she smells the cold and very reluctantly steps out behind me. If it is not so cold I could coax her down the stairs and then….THEN…she sits her fat ass on the ground and doesn’t move.

 

 

 

 If it is too cold to place that fat ass on the ground then she takes a stance, and no pulling, conniving or treat bribing, will get her more than a foot from the door, where Ms. Piglet promptly does an about-turn and hi-tails it up the stairs.
 
 **all names used to describe Zoey is with her consent and is in no way meant to be construed as cruel - she understands I love her greatly....** 

 
 
 

 The Elk Bone Large 

 

 
 Beef snouts 
 

Keep in mind dressing this dog is worse than dressing my kids in snowsuits. Plus, I also must get into battle gear. I know I am going to lose each and every time I do this and yet I continue to try it all winter long.

 

 

 
 Bison Tails 
 

 

 

 
 Bison Tails come frozen and stay in the freezer for an extra snack and as food 
I ask you…who has who trained…I keep doin’it…

 

 Luckily Zoey is what I term‘dual-energy’.  She is completely paper trained and she will go outside to make but only if it is above 62 degrees F. Anything below and she won’t go out.

 

 

 

 

 

 Dried Chicken feet and pig snout 

 

It makes it great for me but it also makes me lazy; and she gets virtually no exercise. So I take her once a week to puppy daycare just to keep socializing her and because twice a month I have to cut her nails as she can scratch until welts appear and bleed.

Le Pet Spa recommended me to try  Raw Paw who had begun selling human grade raw food for dogs. The products come frozen, or dried and every part of the animal is used. Two weeks on this diet and I was able to reduce her prednisone to a 1/4 pill which was totally great.

 

 

 Clockwise is frozen Bison, dried Lung and Tripe and frozen Smelts 

 

The cost averages out the same; I add my own veggies and Pumpkin (which is good for constipation) and she loves, loves her food.

 

Is it a pain to get this product–NO. Farah delivers the product and the only other thing I have to do is to remember to defrost what the dog needs and to weigh and portion her food for usually 10 days. Then it goes into the fridge and is ready to eat when she is ready.

 

In addition I buy snacks like dried pig snout, or lung, or duck/chicken feet. All dried. Even and dare I say it…Bull Penis. Or any kind of Penis…dried of course. Farah of Raw Paw says it is called  Pizzle - I call it smelly, stinky, gross...and a good thing I already have my children....

 

(the breeders didn&apos;t splurge on any mohels for this head to tail dining...someone stop me please....this is too much fun....)

 

  HOWEVER SINCE THE TITLE OF THIS POST IS ALL ABOUT HEAD TO TAIL DINING I HOPE THAT ALL THE PICTURES HAVE GIVEN YOU AN IDEA OF WHAT IT MEANS IN THE ANIMAL WORLD OF PROVIDING FOR THE RAW FOOD DIET. 

 

It is everything I have shown you: the Bison Tails; the Lung; The Elk Bones; the ground up meat with bones, the Beef Bones....food in its purest form that aboriginally dogs used to eat. In addition to the meat and bones, I add vegetables which include Pure Pumpkin and human grade canned veggies, which I believe should be used only for animals.

 

 

 Yes, this is Pizzle, Penis or whatever you call it and Pig snout on the far right 

 

 
 More Dried Beef Snouts 
 

The raw food diet is a hard sale here in the area I live; but I can truly say I believe wholeheartedly in it.

 

 

It is definitely easier to open a can of kibble or a bag of kibble, surely. Much more difficult to feed one small dog in this manner; but when one gets a dog or cat and sees how they struggle with skin ailments it becomes crystal clear that the Raw Food Diet is the only way to go. Unfortunately it took me two years to find it and it was by fluke because it is not a popular method to feed pets here with; and when you can get hold of it, the cost becomes prohibitive.  Which is why most of the pet stores that sell this food are usually in the areas of Montreal where people would be most apt to buy.

 

 Raw Paw delivers.

 

Raw Paw is not just the food - it is also the service. No, it is just the food. No, it is the service..nope it is THE FOOD

 

If enough people knew of Raw Paw and how decent its prices are and how they will deliver to your door, more of us Montrealers would use them and our pets would be a lot healthier. It&apos;s odd that people will pay up to $60.00 to have their dog bathed but then balk at the cost of good, healthy and aboriginal food with which to feed them.

 
 Dried Lung, Tripe and Other Beef Parts 
Zoey gets at any given meal: a combo of bison, beef which also includes organs and bones ground, sea smelts, veggies and 100% natural Probiotic Yogurt.

 

I had to take away the rawhide toys but she gets a bone or a chicken leg once or twice a day for a treat.

 

 Yes, the chicken legs that our Jewish Grandmother&apos;s used to use to make Chicken Soup and which had been banished and disallowed along with the yellow eggs are now served to the Dog, dried and still looking like the chicken legs I will always remember.

 

Nothing else passes her lips. She is doing fabulously well; although she still suffers I am able, at least, to lessen the prednisone.

 

 

 Dried Lung, dried tripe and a mixed bag of dried goodies 

I thought this would make a good post on the Raw Food Diet for Dogs and so I have taken pictures of what I buy and feed her and the good news is that cost-wise it is the exact same as when I was buying her specialty food from the vet.

 

Lucky is the pet owner who has a pet without any health problems. Lucky is the Vet whose patients have health problems.

 

I could order any kind of the following food:

Halibut, Cod Green Tripe,Beef Neck Bones, Elk Femur, Elk bones XL as Raw Frozen food and then Dehydrated the list is: Beef Snout, Duck/Chicken feet, Chicken Breast, Beef Lung and Liver, Pizzle ( or Petzel or Schmeckel ), a Pig Ear, Trachea 5”/8”and various antlers.

 

 Raw Paw 

514-983-3277

 farah@rawpaw.ca 

 
 &lt;embed /&gt; 
 * this post was written not as a dedicated and paid advertisement for Raw Paw. All my posts that are dedicated to a particular product or retailer are done so strictly because I have made use of it, and loved it or hated it. 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 344 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Americain set to head supersta Americain set to head superstar cast in 2011 Melbourne Cup 

 From: cathyreynolds0706 Description: 
The Melbourne Cup needs very little introduction and the race remains the jewel in the Australian racing crown.

 

The event is the most important sporting and cultural festival in Australia and on Tuesday 1st November, the nation will grind to a halt for a spellbinding renewal of‘the race that stops a nation.’

 

Each year the whole country stops to tune into the two-mile showpiece and it is the most watched five minutes of television Down Under year in and year out.

 

The beauty of the Melbourne Cup stream is that you don’t have to be part of the racing fraternity to become engulfed in the action and a combination of the world’s finest thoroughbreds, mixed with some of the globe’s leading fashions have made the Carnival the most anticipated social event of the year.

 

The first ever Melbourne Cup was run in 1861 and ever since the roll of honour for the great race has been dominated by some of the most famous race horses the world has ever seen. The likes or Phar Lap and Makybe Diva are mentioned in households all over the world every day of the year and their exploits on the track were enough to demand the love and attention of a nation.

 

Will there be a superstar lurking in the field of this year’s race? Last year’s contest was won by French raider Americain and Bart Cummings’sensational So You Think was back in third and it looks likely that there will be another racing sensation to emerge from the pack in 2011.

 

There seems to be an increasing number of challengers from the northern hemisphere tackling the race and Americain will be back, looking to make it back-to-back victories in the Australian feature.

 

The only horse to have done that this century was Makybe Diva who landed the spoils in 2003, 2004 and 2005 and he will have his work cut out running off top weight at Flemington. He is the favourite for the handicap, but with the likes of Jukebox Jury, Lion Tamer, Midas Touch and December Draw all in the field, the opposition to last year’s hero looks formidable.

 

While it is impossible to know what this year’s meeting will bring one thing is for certain: the action is sure to be explosive, exhilarating and thoroughly intriguing. With a superstar cast set to contest the Melbourne Cup and with more than 100,000 fans set to head to Flemington to watch the race live or watch the Melbourne Cup live online , it really will be an event to savour.

 

Click here for more information about Melbourne Cup tips 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 402 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Winning Big at Buffets Winning Big at Buffets 

 From: Adam Bryan Description: 
 

Ahh the buffet…I truly enjoy your all-you-can-eat nature. From your endless selection to your moderate prices, I can always leave you feeling happy and satisfied. I especially love being in your presence in one of my favorite cities in the world, Las Vegas.

 Las Vegas is a city of dazzling lights, elegant casinos, extravagant clubs, and my favorite, world class food. For those with a huge appetite and plenty of time, buffets are the way to go. Buffets can be found in almost every hotel and casino and the food quality can range from casual to gourmet. For those who are willing to spend a little extra for fine dining quality foods in a buffet format, they should check out the buffet at the  Wynn Las Vegas ,  Bellagio Buffet , and the newly opened  Wicked Spoon  at the Cosmopolitan. These buffets provide delicious gourmet food at a premium price. Prices usually range from $20 to $30 for lunch and $35 to $50 a person for dinner. So how do you win big? At most buffets in Vegas, they never close in between dinner and lunch. This then allows hungry customers, such as yourself, to come in just as lunch is about to be over and get lunch prices. Then if you wait for a few minutes, the buffet will start bringing out the dinner meals. So basically, you are getting the same dinner selection, but at half the cost. So the next time you find yourself going to a buffet in Vegas or elsewhere, make sure to go in between lunch and dinner and you will win big! 

For more dining tips like this, be sure to check out  FoodTweet 

 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 323 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 The Gluten-Free Guide to Fast The Gluten-Free Guide to Fast Food Restaurants 

 From: Adam Bryan Description: 
How many times have you gone to a Burger King or McDonalds and never knew what to order since you had no idea what was gluten-free or not? I can tell you from past experiences that I have found myself in this situation countless times. Let&apos;s face it, eating gluten-free at fast food restaurants is very tough and troublesome. There&apos;s no doubt, it&apos;s probably the most daunting task for any gluten-free dieter to go through. Frankly, making a safe and accurate meal decision is the slowest and most inconvenient part of eating fast food. You constantly find yourself going to each fast food restaurant and asking the employees for a breakdown of all their gluten-free products -- a task that can take forever and sometimes seem quite nagging in some eyes. Sound at all familiar?

Thankfully there is a great guide called the &quot;Gluten-Free Guide to Fast Food Restaurants.&quot; In this guide, you will be provide with simple, easy to read lists of gluten free food available on the menus at most major fast food chains. You&apos;ll get listings from Burger King, McDonald&apos;s, Panera Bread, Chipotle, Sonic, Starbucks, Baskin Robins, Noodle&apos;s&amp;Company, Chick Fil A and much more. I even made sure to contact each company for their gluten-free items if they weren&apos;t available on their websites. This means that there were no third parties involved during the creation of this book.

The &quot;Gluten-Free Guide to Fast Food Restaurants&quot; is your way to eat with confidence. To start eating gluten-free now, click  HERE 
 Blog post 9 months ago Views: 1458 Comments: 0 Not yet rated 
 
 Results 281 - 300 of 650 «Previous 1 2 ... 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 ... 32 33 Next» Blog Posts With the Most Comments 
 User-Generated Blogs by KickApps Terms of Service 
 
Terms of Service
 
 
 advertisement The Dish Receive the latest on food, restaurants and trends in this bi-weekly e-newsletter. Sign Up The Wine List Weekly pairing plus best bottles to buy. F&amp;W;Daily One sensational dish served fresh every day. American Express Publishing (&quot;AEP&quot;) may use your email address to send you account updates and offers that may interest you. To learn more about the ways we may use your email address and about your privacy choices, read the AEP Privacy Statement. How we use your email address advertisement 
 
Sections

 Recipes&amp;Chefs Wine&amp;Cocktails Restaurants&amp;Travel Home&amp;Design Blog Magazine 
 
Subscribe

 Subscribe to Food&amp;Wine Give a Gift Subscription Food&amp;Wine Books Get Food&amp;Wine iPad Edition Get F&amp;W Mobile Apps 
 
Clubs&amp;Events

 Food&amp;Wine Connoisseur Club Food&amp;Wine Wine Club Events 
 
F&amp;W Everywhere

 Food&amp;Wine Community Like Us on Facebook Follow Us on Twitter RSS Feeds 
 
Contact

 Customer Service Contact Us Advertising 
 
American Express
Publishing

 Travel + Leisure Departures Travel + Leisure Golf Travel + Leisure Family Skyguide Executive Travel Black Ink 
 Site Map 
 
 View Website Terms and Conditions and Privacy Statement of American Express Publishing Corporation 

Users of this site agree to be bound by the terms of the American Express Publishing Corporation Website Terms and Conditions.

Copyright
 © 1997 - 2012 American Express Publishing Corporation. All Rights Reserved.
 mock rpx login link
	</body>
</document>
