<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006450" url="http://www.semissourian.com/news/local/" time="2012-07-12-23:23" support="1" score="0.00021557421056346386" bingtitle="seMissourian.com: Local News" webtitle="seMissourian.com: Local News">
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>... candidate for the 25th Senate District seat, led ... grocery store shoppers to school principals to fast-food restaurant ... Loretta Schneider wants to talk trash. And the Cape ...</description>
	<body>
		Enlarge text Subscriber login | Subscribe/register now | Subscription help 
 T-storm in Vicinity ~ 88°F   
 River stage: 14.45 ft. Falling 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 Stories Blogs Comments Photos Events Classifieds Marketplace Real Estate Everything Archive since 1918 
 
 Home 
 Subscribe/register Contact Us Terms of Service Media Partners Photo Store Text Alerts Mailing lists Search Browse archives Online Reader Login to post comments 
 News 
 Today&apos;s News Local State Nation Crime Jackson Election Weather Schools Census Flood 2011 All headlines Online Reader Text alerts Email newsletters 
 Sports 
 Today&apos;s Sports High School College Community Professional St. Louis Cardinals Semoball.com Text alerts 
 Business 
 Today&apos;s Business Progress Who&apos;s Who Talking Shop Business Today Photo galleries 
 Features 
 Today&apos;s Features Health Food, Home&amp;Garden Religion Community Schools Honor Rolls Online Games Prom photos 101 Fun Things To Do History Contests 
 Events 
 Calendar Movie Trivia Movie Schedule TV Schedule Celebrity 
 Records 
 Obituaries Births Weddings Engagements Anniversaries Police/Fire Out of the Past 
 Opinion 
 Today&apos;s Opinion Editorials Letters Columns Speak Out Cartoons Forums 
 Blogs 
 Today&apos;s blogs James Baughn Candice Davis Robyn Gautschy Brad Hollerbach Fred Lynch Melissa Miller Scott Moyers Erin Ragan James Samons Sharon Sanders Weather or Not Katherine Webster All blogs 
 Your Stories 
 Your stories Your photos Submit story Submit photo Submit historic photo Speak Out Ride of the Week 
 Photos&amp;Video 
 Photos Video Today&apos;s images Prom photos 
 

 Shopping 
 Marketplace Coupons Circulars View Flyers Today&apos;s Deal 
 Homes 
 Open houses Maps 
 Jobs Classifieds 
 Submit Online Listing Submit Print Listing Upload Flyer View All Listings View Flyers My Listings My Wishlist 
 
 
 Local State Nation Crime Jackson Schools Headlines Online Reader RSS 
 
 
Local News
 Grant to expand Cape-area reading program will be $107,900 (07/12/12) 
 The amount of grant funding the United Way of Southeast Missouri will receive to expand a volunteer-run reading improvement program in area schools this fall was announced Thursday by the Missouri Community Service Commission. Read to Succeed began in Blanchard and Alma Schrader elementary schools in recent years and will be added to Clippard, Franklin elementary schools, as well as Gordonville Attendance Center during the coming school year. ... Answers to Cape graduation rate questions expected at Monday board meeting (07/12/12) 
 Cape Girardeau School Board members will receive answers Monday to questions they recently posed to administrators about the effects an academic and behavioral improvement model has on the district&apos;s graduation rate. Superintendent Jim Welker and assistant superintendent Sherry Copeland told board members at the June 18 meeting of the board they would present data collected thus far on the effectiveness of a professional learning communities model at the high school. ... Caruthersville attack on disabled man spurs anger (07/12/12) 
 CARUTHERSVILLE, Mo. (AP) -- Prosecutors charged teenage girls in the beating of a mentally disabled man, after video of the attack was posted on Facebook and provoked outrage in their southeast Missouri community. The incident happened about two weeks ago in Caruthersville. The video shows the girls punching Louis Crocker, a man known around town as &quot;Cool Breeze&quot; who is mentally disabled and who drinks heavily, according to his family... Locals named to Missouri commission to study disaster recovery (07/12/12) 
 Cape Girardeau native Lt. Gov Peter Kinder will chair a commission to study disaster response that includes Southeast Missouri lawmakers. Kinder, a Republican, was appointed by House Speaker Steven Tilley to chair the commission that will spend several months &quot;assessing the state&apos;s ongoing disaster recovery efforts,&quot; and the level of preparation of state and local government for future disasters, according to a news release from the Missouri House of Representatives communication office... Fire crews battle apartment blaze in Cape Girardeau (07/12/12) 1 
 Firefighters rescued a Cape Girardeau woman from an apartment fire that started just after noon Thursday. Another woman was taken to the hospital. The fire began in a ground floor unit in building H of the apartment complex at 121 E. Rodney. It spread to the upper story... Sales tax collections up for local governments, especially Jackson (07/12/12) 1 
 Cape Girardeau County consumers are spending more again this year, with sales tax collections showing a trend of slow but continued growth that seems to be bucking -- if only slightly -- a dismal national economic outlook. Workers run into bee problem while demolishing Franklin Elementary (07/12/12) 8 
 Demolition crews starting to tear down the old Franklin Elementary in Cape Girardeau on Wednesday encountered a group not quite ready for the school to go. Cape Parks and Rec Day aims to get children involved in recreation (07/12/12) 1 
 Cape Girardeau Parks and Recreation will team with the Southeast Missourian Jr. to help get children involved and interested in recreational activity. The 11th annual Cape Girardeau Parks and Rec Day will be held from 11 a.m. to 3 p.m. July 13 at the Osage Centre. ... Cape Parks and Rec now managing soccer league (07/12/12) 
 A mutual agreement between the Cape Area Youth Soccer Association and the city of Cape Girardeau has led to a changing of the guard for youth soccer in the community. CAYSA has been in charge of youth soccer leagues and recreation tournaments in Cape Girardeau for the past 32 years... Two businesses, church in Cape County burglarized (07/12/12) 2 
 As usual, Revis Reisenbichler walked into the office of his Pocahontas business about 5:45 a.m. Wednesday to prepare for the day. What was not usual was finding his gun safe smashed on the floor. While none of his guns was missing, cash from the previous day&apos;s sales was gone... Bloomfield Street home damaged in fire (07/12/12) 
 No one was home when fire heavily damaged a Cape Girardeau home early Wednesday evening. Shortly before 6 p.m., neighbors reported thick brown smoke coming from the eaves of a home at 1911 Bloomfield St., fire chief Rick Ennis said. Sixteen firefighters in five firetrucks responded and brought the fire under control in about 10 minutes, he said. The fire was primarily in the hidden voids within walls, Ennis said... Jackson chamber hosts annual ag tour (07/12/12) 
 For more than 30 years now, the Jackson Area Chamber of Commerce&apos;s Agri-Business Tour has showcased local farms and manufacturing facilities. More than 100 people took part Wednesday in the annual tour, which included stops at Nordenia USA&apos;s Hubble Creek Plant in the Jackson Industrial Park; Richardet Feedyards in Perry County; and TG Missouri in Perryville... Bloomfield alderman steps down (07/12/12) 
 BLOOMFIELD, Mo. -- The Bloomfield Board of Aldermen accepted the resignation of one of its members in a special meeting Monday night. Steve Larsen, who was elected in April, submitted his resignation in writing, listing only &quot;reasons apparent.&quot;... Annual New Hamburg Picnic set for this weekend (07/12/12) 
 NEW HAMBURG, Mo. -- When asked what makes the annual New Hamburg Picnic so special, event chairman Nathan Dirnberger didn&apos;t have to think long before answering. &quot;It&apos;s just good, small-town fun,&quot; he said. &quot;It&apos;s a good atmosphere, and everybody is always happy.&quot;... Storm causes 2,400 to lose power in Bollinger County (07/12/12) 
 MARBLE HILL, Mo. -- About 2,400 customers were without power Wednesday night in Bollinger County after storms moved through. According to Black River Electric Cooperative, high winds downed several trees when the system moved through about 5:30 p.m... New retail store opening in Marble Hill (07/12/12) 
 MARBLE HILL, Mo. -- Amid concern about upcoming water bill increases and passing bond issues for sewer improvements, the Marble Hill Board of Aldermen received some good news Monday night. Family Dollar Store plans to build a store in Marble Hill, on three acres next to Jay&apos;s Barbecue... Senators ask for disaster declarations (07/12/12) 
 U.S. senators Roy Blunt and Claire McCaskill sent a letter Wednesday to U.S. Department of Agriculture Secretary Thomas Vilsack asking him to grant Gov. Jay Nixon&apos;s request for a primary disaster declaration for 114 counties in Missouri. The request is due to the losses sustained by farmers and ranchers as a result of the extreme drought conditions... Cape man charged with unlawful use of a weapon (07/12/12) 
 A Cape Girardeau man was in custody, charged with a felony and a misdemeanor, after shots were fired in a southside neighborhood early Wednesday morning. Officers responded about 12:15 a.m. to the 900 block of Hackberry Street, after receiving reports of shots fired, said officer Darin Hickey. No injuries reported in Cairo house fire (07/12/12) 
 CAIRO, Ill. -- No one was injured when fire destroyed a Cairo home Tuesday afternoon. Firefighters responded about 3:45 p.m. to a house fire at 427 Union St., said fire chief John Meyer. Marble Hill officials ironing out ordinance on who manages city personnel (07/12/12) 
 MARBLE HILL, Mo. -- An ordinance to transfer authority over city personnel to the Marble Hill board of aldermen did not get a chance to be read at the board&apos;s meeting Monday night. It will take a special meeting in the near future to iron out some differences between the board and Mayor Michael Sowers before all concerned can agree on who can hire, fire and manage city personnel. Kinder files lawsuit accusing Carnahan of bias in ballot wording (07/11/12) 33 
 Lt. Gov. Peter Kinder signaled his intention Tuesday to file a legal challenge to ballot language crafted by Secretary of State Robin Carnahan, calling her wording biased with an aim at skewing the outcome of the Nov. 6 election. The Cape Girardeau Republican was in his hometown Tuesday morning to discuss the lawsuit he planned to file in Cole County later in the day. It was the first of several stops in Missouri that were to include Springfield, Joplin, Jefferson City and St. Louis... Read to Succeed program expanding in Cape, Jackson this fall (07/11/12) 
 Plan A for growing a volunteer-run reading improvement program in local elementary schools is now in action. Read to Succeed, a project of the United Way of Southeast Missouri that until this summer depended on a funding donation from the GRACES Women&apos;s Council, sends around 140 volunteer tutors from the community into two Cape Girardeau School District elementaries to help kindergarten and first-grade students up their grade-level reading skills... Red Cross seeing blood shortage in area during summer (07/11/12) 3 
 The height of summer and winter can be a difficult time to get people to give what the American Red Cross needs to help what many others need to recover from injury and illness. Blood donations to the organization often fall off when the holidays hit -- regular donors often get busy with gatherings, go out of town to visit family and friends, or don&apos;t leave the house as frequently when the weather is too hot or too cold... Morley police chief challenging Walter for Scott County sheriff (07/11/12) 
 In Scott County, challengers for sheriff dropped by half before the race began. Fellow Democrats Ron Merideth and Paul Johnson stepped up to challenge incumbent Rick Walter, but after finding out that he couldn&apos;t run for the office, Merideth dropped out... Document reveals some details on Cape Girardeau office vandalism (07/11/12) 3 
 A probable-cause statement released Tuesday details the moments leading up to vandalism that caused extensive damage to a Cape Girardeau building and the eventual confession by a suspect in the case. Prosecutors charged Travis Henry Fornkohl, 32, with second-degree burglary and first-degree property damage in connection with the June 30 vandalism at the Auburn Park Place office building, 3065 William St... U.S. factory orders increased 0.7 percent in May; local companies see increase, too (07/11/12) 1 
 WASHINGTON -- Companies placed more orders with U.S. factories in May after two months of declining factory orders, demanding more computers, machinery and other equipment that signal investment plans. Still, factory orders are down from the start of the year. And more recent data show manufacturing activity shrank in June for the first time in three years, adding to worries that weaker global growth is weighing on the U.S. economy... Scott County libraries to offer training for e-readers (07/11/12) 
 SIKESTON, Mo. -- Two Scott County libraries have received state grants to better assist patrons with their e-reader devices. The Sikeston Public Library received a federal e-reader Exploration Grant for $1,871, while the Chaffee Public Library received the same type of grant for $1,480... Olive Branch, Ill., woman sentenced for false sexual assault report (07/11/12) 
 An Olive Branch, Ill., woman pleaded guilty Tuesday to disorderly conduct after she filed a false police report, Union County State&apos;s Attorney Tyler R. Edmonds said in a news release. Dea Ann Thompson, 44, accused Illinois State Police officers of sexually assaulting her in February during a state police investigation, Edmonds said in the release. The sexual assault allegation was investigated by the state police Division of Internal Investigation and the Union County Sheriff&apos;s Department... Pair traveling down Mississippi to raise funds for not-for-profit group (07/11/12) 
 Luke Taylor and Craig Loss, and their dog, Jane, head under the Bill Emerson Memorial Bridge on Tuesday morning in Cape Girardeau. Taylor and Loss are making a 2,300-mile trek on the Mississippi River from Itasca, Minn., to New Orleans. They are raising funds for the not-for-profit Local Livelihood, which promotes the growing of specialty coffee as a way for families overseas to make a living. You can follow Taylor, Loss and Jane on their journey at www.canoetothefuture.blogspot.com/ ... Boil-water order issued for Oak Creek subdivision (07/11/12) 
 Cape Girardeau County Public Water District No. 2 has issued a precautionary boil-water order for Oak Creek subdivision near Jackson effective today and continuing until further notice. The water will be turned off for three to four hours, according to a news release from the Cape Girardeau County Public Health Center. While the order is in effect, residents should boil water intended for any type of consumption for at least three minutes... Today is last day to register to vote in Aug. 7 primary (07/11/12) 
 Today is the last day to register to vote in the Aug. 7 primary in Missouri. More information on how to register can be found at www.govotemissouri.com or by calling any county clerk&apos;s office. As of Tuesday, there were 51,996 registered voters in Cape Girardeau County out of a census count of 75,895 total residents, according to the county clerk&apos;s office... Judge says Busch civil case remains in Southeast Missouri (07/11/12) 1 
 ST. LOUIS (AP) -- A judge has ruled that a wrongful death lawsuit against August Busch IV in the death of his former girlfriend will remain in a Southeast Missouri court. Busch, the former chief executive of Anheuser-Busch Cos. Inc., is being sued by the minor son of his girlfriend, Adrienne Martin, who died of a drug overdose at Busch&apos;s home in 2010. Busch has never been charged with any crime in her death... Attorney hired to look into Sikeston&apos;s actions regarding FEMA flood maps (07/11/12) 1 
 SIKESTON, Mo. -- The city of Sikeston has hired a St. Louis lawyer to investigate the possible mishandling of important correspondence regarding the Federal Emergency Management Agency&apos;s new flood plain maps. The city council voted unanimously during a closed meeting July 2 to hire Richard Greenburg of Greensfelder, Hempker and Gale PC. According to the state&apos;s open meeting law, the council is permitted to meet in closed session to discuss certain legal matters... Cape&apos;s old Franklin school coming to an end (07/11/12) 
 Premier Demolition removes the trees surrounding Franklin Elementary School on Tuesday in Cape Girardeau. Demolition of the school is slated to begin today. The old school opened its doors in 1927. The building is being replaced by a new $10 million, 50,000-square-foot Franklin Elementary that will welcome students in August... Repairs set for Cape river bridge (07/11/12) 
 East- and westbound Highway 34/74 in Cape Girardeau County will be reduced to one lane as Missouri Department of Transportation crews make repairs to the Mississippi River bridge between Cape Girardeau and Illinois. Weather permitting, the work will be done from 7:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. daily Monday through July 20. Signs will mark the work zone. Motorists are urged to use caution while traveling near the area... Ramp in Butler County closed for pavement repairs (07/11/12) 
 SIKESTON, Mo. -- The ramp to Route B on eastbound Business U.S. 60 in Butler County will be closed today as Missouri Department of Transportation crews make pavement repairs. Weather permitting, the work will be done from 7 a.m. to 4 p.m. The work zone will be marked with signs. Motorists are urged to use caution while traveling near the area... Highway 77 in Scott County reduced for bridge repairs (07/11/12) 
 SIKESTON, Mo. -- Highway 77 between Route H and County Road 401 in Scott County will be reduced to one lane as Missouri Department of Transportation crews make repairs to the bridge over Interstate 55. Weather permitting, the work will be done from 8 a.m. to 3 p.m. today. The work zone will be marked with signs. Motorists are urged to use caution while traveling near the area... In federal court: Man pleads guilty to conspiring to distribute cocaine (07/11/12) 
 Age: 37 Charges: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of cocaine Sentencing: Scheduled for Oct. 9 Summary: Redd pleaded guilty to conspiring to distribute 500 grams or more of cocaine from May 23, 2011, through June 2, 2011, in Dunklin County, Mo., and elsewhere. During the conspiracy, Redd obtained at least 3 kilograms of cocaine from co-defendant Randy Caruthers and then distributed it to others. Redd now faces a maximum punishment of 40 years in prison and a $5 million fine... In federal court: Arkansas man pleads guilty to drug charges (07/11/12) 
 The U.S. attorney&apos;s office released the following information Tuesday for defendants who appeared before U.S. District Judge Stephen N. Limbaugh Jr. pleaded guilty Residence: Blytheville, Ark. Age: 32 Charges: Distribution of cocaine base and distribution of 28 grams or more of cocaine base... Work wrapping up on one-room Cape schoolhouse (07/10/12) 2 
 Floyd Petzoldt was initially against spending any money to fix up the old Hanover Lutheran School that is owned by his church. Then he took a drive past the 88-year-old one-room schoolhouse along Perryville Road last week and saw how some of the money had been spent... Video, photo show to be part of this year&apos;s Homecomers (07/10/12) 1 
 Jackson Homecomers will kick off its 104th anniversary July 24 with new attractions alongside tried-and-true draws to historic uptown. The event started in 1908, when people gathered to celebrate the completion of the Cape Girardeau County Courthouse and the installation of the memorial for Confederate Army Col. ... Jackson&apos;s Hitt acknowledges American Legion error on campaign materials (07/10/12) 9 
 Missouri House candidate Van Hitt admitted Thursday he has been distributing political materials that incorrectly identify him as a member of the American Legion, a group exclusively reserved for former military personnel who served their country during wartime... Cape County case gets attention on Supreme Court blog (07/10/12) 9 
 A blog dedicated to covering the U.S. Supreme Court has chosen a Cape Girardeau County case that could go before the court as one that asks a noteworthy question. SCOTUSblog selected the case of Missouri v. McNeely as its petition of the day for Friday... Former Carter County sheriff gets 10 years in prison (07/10/12) 1 
 A former Carter County sheriff who admitted stealing firearms that had been seized as evidence will spend the next 10 years in a federal prison, and his former chief deputy will do five years on the same charges after being sentenced Monday in U.S. District Court in Cape Girardeau. Sunday house fire possibly started by Molotov cocktail (07/10/12) 1 
 Police on Monday were searching for the person who started a house fire, possibly using a Molotov cocktail, at an occupied house early Sunday morning. Police responded about 5:20 a.m. to 1425 Cousin St., where residents reported they found the curtain over their air conditioner burning after they investigated a loud noise in their living room, said Cape Girardeau police Sgt. Jason Selzer. A resident and neighbor were able to put the fire out, Selzer said... Child care providers cautious during recent heat wave (07/10/12) 
 With a few happy screams, children took back outdoor play Monday after a seemingly endless heat wave left Southeast Missouri. During the past month, several area child care providers say they&apos;ve had to use extra caution when allowing children to spend time outside. Summertime can pose extra safety risks to children -- and especially susceptible to heat illnesses are those under age 5, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention... Cape County reappoints 2 to library board; reappointment to sewer district board declined (07/10/12) 
 The Cape Girardeau County Commission reappointed two members of the Riverside Regional Library Board on Monday. Joann Hahs and Tom Gross will each serve four-year terms. Kevin Smith declined the commission&apos;s July 2 reappointment to the Cape Girardeau County Sewer District No. ... Woman asks Jackson Park Board for improvements (07/10/12) 2 
 A business owner took her campaign to improve Jackson City Park to a new venue Monday. &quot;Over the past five or so years, the park has gone down, down, down,&quot; Brenda Pfefferkorn told the Jackson Park Board on Monday. Pfefferkorn has owned the Jackson Tender Care Playhouse for 22 years and operates a summer program for children ages 6 to 10. ... Cape Girardeau handicapped-accessible playground vandalized (07/10/12) 5 
 Melaina&apos;s Magical Playland, a handicapped-accessible playground that broke ground at Cape County Park North in March, was vandalized over the weekend. Slides, construction materials, safety panels and musical chimes were damaged, said Andrea Cunningham, playground co-founder. ... Change of judge granted in Cape vandalism case (07/10/12) 
 The man accused of causing hundreds of thousands of dollars in property damage to a Cape Girardeau office building has been granted a change of judges. Travis H. Fornkohl of Cape Girardeau was scheduled for an arraignment Monday in the vandalism of an office building at 3065 William St, that occurred the night of June 30, but Fornkohl&apos;s attorney, Malcolm Montgomery, filed a motion for a change of judges. Judge Gary Kamp granted the motion... Last week&apos;s most read stories 
 Cape Girardeau man charged in office vandalism Vandals cause $500,000 in damage to office building Discipline being considered for Cape Girardeau lawyer Cape Girardeau police chief leaving department Man fatally bitten by copperhead in Carter County, Mo. Document reveals some details on Cape Girardeau office vandalism Drury Southwest is hoping land preparation will draw in businesses 
 
 
 Sections
 News Sports Business Events Features Opinion Records/Obituaries Blogs 
 Shopping
 Classifieds Coupons Homes Marketplace Jobs 
 seMissourian.com
 Search News archives Forums Your Stories Contact Us Terms of Service Media Partners 
 Services
 Subscribe/register Contests Movie Trivia Online Reader Text Alerts Mailing lists Facebook Twitter 
 Submit
 Wedding Engagement Anniversary Letter to the Editor Paid Election Letter Speak Out Event Story Photo Classified ad 
 Shortcuts
 Speak Out Editorial cartoons All headlines Weather Photo galleries Video TV listings 
 
 ©2012 Southeast Missourian
	</body>
</document>
