<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006103" url="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g294450-d817512-Reviews-Cevabdzinica_Zeljo-Sarajevo.html" time="2012-07-12-22:47" support="2" score="0.0029044566378647624" bingtitle="Cevabdzinica Zeljo Restaurant Reviews, Sarajevo, Bosnia and ..." webtitle="Cevabdzinica Zeljo Restaurant Reviews, Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>... cevapcici in the heart of bascarsija in this small fast-food restaurant where you have to wait for a place to sit ... go in&apos;, even if you would have to share your small table ...</description>
	<body>
		Cevabdzinica Zeljo Restaurant Reviews, Sarajevo
 
 Home Sarajevo 
 Sarajevo Tourism Sarajevo Hotels Sarajevo Holiday Rentals Flights to Sarajevo Sarajevo Restaurants Sarajevo Attractions Sarajevo Travel Forum Sarajevo Photos Sarajevo Guide 
 Hotels Flights Holiday Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Europe &gt; Bosnia and Herzegovina &gt; Sarajevo &gt; Sarajevo Restaurants &gt; Cevabdzinica Zeljo 
 
 All 113 Sarajevo Restaurants» 
Cevabdzinica Zeljo
 Kundurdziluk (Bascarsija) , Sarajevo , Bosnia and Herzegovina 4 visitor photos Ranked #7 of 113 restaurants in Sarajevo 57 Reviews Price range: £3 - £5 Good for: Child-friendly, Local cuisine, Cheap Eats Dining options: Breakfast/Brunch, Lunch Spot Restaurant details Good for: Child-friendly, Local cuisine, Cheap Eats Dining options: Breakfast/Brunch, Lunch Spot Update restaurant details Write a Review 
57 reviews from our community
 82% Recommend 
 Excellent 32 Very good 15 Average 8 Poor 1 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 57 reviews sorted by Date Rating Danish first Dutch first English first French first German first Italian first Japanese first Any olliekemp92 Senior Reviewer 9 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “Don&apos;t believe the Hype.” Reviewed 6 July 2012 NEW via mobile 
Lauded as the best cevapi in town, it actually feels a little soulless and the food is very average- tastes a little manufactured. There is much better cevapi to be had, try Ferhatovic, near the great library. Excellent.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 7 more reviews by olliekemp92 for Sarajevo Allen F St-Remy-de-Provence, France 1 review “Lovely!” Reviewed 6 July 2012 NEW 
I was there with my girlfriend and we tried Cevapcici. It was delicious! We really enjoy it!You have to try Cevapcici when in Sarajevo.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? bella201 Reviewer 4 reviews “Must try!” Reviewed 6 July 2012 NEW via mobile 
Cevapcici are Bosnian fast food and they are very delicious and cheap.You cannot visit Sarajevo if you do not visit Zeljo and eat cevapcici.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by bella201 for Sarajevo TiborBH Senior Reviewer 6 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 3 helpful votes “Excellent” Reviewed 4 July 2012 via mobile 
Everyone who comes to Sarajevo should try cevapcici. And the best place to do it is Zeljo. It is not a fancy restaurant with professional staff, but a typical family run place. It is just perfect place to eat Bosnian traditional food. An advice: don&apos;t ask for ketchup or mayonnaise!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 2 more reviews by TiborBH for Sarajevo Carbo1960 Belgrade, Serbia Senior Contributor 28 reviews Reviews in 9 cities 6 helpful votes “Cheap and tasty” Reviewed 1 July 2012 
While wondering Baščaršija, don&apos;t hestate to stop at one of two premisses of this Bosnian-style fast food (both located in the same street paralel to Miljacka river, just behind the City of Sarajevo Museum). A filling portion of tasty mixed grilled meat will set you back for 7 EUR (bread, chopped onions and mustard included). Be prepaired to wait for... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 9 more reviews by Carbo1960 for Sarajevo wingcastles Turin, Italy Senior Contributor 22 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 4 helpful votes “Typical food” Reviewed 21 May 2012 
Former Yugoslavia is a place to go if you&apos;re interested in recent history, not gourmet food. All the food comes from the octoman domination of the past (kebabm baklava, etc) but in this place downtown you can have a sort of wrap with beef sausages, cream sauce and onions that is very very filling and ridicolously cheap. Dont miss it!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 4 more reviews by wingcastles for Sarajevo Maja S Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina Contributor 11 reviews “Mass ćevapi” Reviewed 1 May 2012 
It&apos;s ok and tasty, but you feel like you are in an assembly line in a car factory, you have to eat fast, drink fast, pay fast, because there are always people waiting for a table.
Definitely a Bosnian fast food place.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 10 more reviews by Maja S for Sarajevo Foks M Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina Contributor 13 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 2 helpful votes “The best fast food in town” Reviewed 28 April 2012 
Traditional Bosnian Fast food are Cevapcici, and this is the best pace to try them. If you like that king of food, I guarantee you, you will want to return for more…and more…and more. The service is excellent and you get the food in no time.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 10 more reviews by Foks M for Sarajevo Kristina B Mojstrana Senior Reviewer 6 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “Our first stop!” Reviewed 26 April 2012 
It was our first visit to a restaurant when in Sarajevo and it certainly wasn&apos;t the last! Best cevapcici I have ever eaten!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 4 more reviews by Kristina B for Sarajevo bosnom Luxembourg City, Luxembourg Senior Contributor 32 reviews Reviews in 11 cities 15 helpful votes “For tourists” Reviewed 24 April 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
The place enjoys a nice reputation, which is not justified, as there are many much better places serving this kind of food. It is mostly popular among non-connoisseurs as a matter of fact. However, in spite of being much over-rated, the food they are serving is decent, nothing to be ashamed of. One thing: You don&apos;t, ever, no matter the... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 2 more reviews by bosnom for Sarajevo 1-10 of 57 reviews « 1 2 ... 6 » 
Travellers who viewed Cevabdzinica Zeljo also viewed
 Restaurant Kibe 67 Reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina Dveri 54 Reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina   Karuzo 24 Reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina To Be Or Not To Be 33 Reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina   All restaurants in Sarajevo (113) 
Been to Cevabdzinica Zeljo? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Cevabdzinica Zeljo, register now for free tools to enhance your listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Hotels travellers are raving about...

 Hotel Central 72 Reviews Read reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina Holiday Inn Hotel Sarajevo (formerly Holiday Inn Sarajevo) 69 Reviews Read reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina City Boutique Hotel 55 Reviews Read reviews Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina 
 All hotels in Sarajevo (47) 
Free Sarajevo Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Sarajevo restaurants

 Karuzo Nanina Kuhinja Restaurant Kibe To Be Or Not To Be Franz&amp;Sophie Dveri Kuhinja mala Barhana TORTE i to Cafe&amp;Patisserie Noovi Tavola Restoran Brajlovic Cevapdzinica &quot;SPECIJAL&quot; Pivnica HS Inat kuca Kulin dvor Maroko Vinoteka Pod Lipom 
 
Hotels around Sarajevo

 Hollywood Hotel Sarajevo 3.5 out of 5, 28 reviews Last reviewed 12 Jul 2012 Hotel Hayat 2.5 out of 5, 43 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Hotel Italia 4.0 out of 5, 5 reviews Last reviewed 10 Jul 2012 Hotel Hecco 3.5 out of 5, 35 reviews Last reviewed 10 Jul 2012 Lion Pansion - Hostel 4.5 out of 5, 13 reviews Last reviewed 9 Jul 2012 Art Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 24 reviews Last reviewed 7 Jul 2012 Hotel Europe Sarajevo 3.5 out of 5, 62 reviews Last reviewed 7 Jul 2012 B&amp;B;Divan 4.5 out of 5, 45 reviews Last reviewed 5 Jul 2012 Hotel Sarajevo 3.5 out of 5, 19 reviews Last reviewed 5 Jul 2012 Kandilj Pension 4.5 out of 5, 36 reviews Last reviewed 27 Jun 2012 Motel Europa 4.5 out of 5, 3 reviews Last reviewed 25 Jun 2012 Hotel Hecco Deluxe 4.0 out of 5, 19 reviews Last reviewed 22 Jun 2012 Hostel City Center Sarajevo 4.0 out of 5, 31 reviews Last reviewed 21 Jun 2012 Hotel Astra Garni 3.5 out of 5, 19 reviews Last reviewed 19 Jun 2012 Hotel Octagon 4.5 out of 5, 6 reviews Last reviewed 29 Apr 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Mc Cormick&amp;Schmick&apos;s 3.5 out of 5, 27 reviews Tapella&apos;s 3.5 out of 5, 6 reviews Taberna El Paisa 3.5 out of 5, 6 reviews Country Club Dorado Ranch 3.0 out of 5, 7 reviews Fischbachtal 4.0 out of 5, 5 reviews 
 Hotels 
 Hotel de l&apos;Europe - 10 Arr. in Paris 3.5 out of 5, 189 reviews Last reviewed 7 Jul 2012 Mayview Glory Hotel in Kuala Lumpur 4.0 out of 5, 62 reviews Last reviewed 4 Jul 2012 Sebago Lake Lodge and Cottages 4.5 out of 5, 25 reviews Last reviewed 3 Jul 2012 Kervansaray Lara 3.5 out of 5, 384 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Xuan Yuan International Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 57 reviews Last reviewed 25 Apr 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, holiday rentals, holiday packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, holiday rentals, holiday packages, and lots more! Visit TripAdvisor&apos;s international sites: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Owners | Help Centre | Business Listings | DMO/CVB © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Some photos provided by VFM Leonardo. * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
