<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006532" url="http://killarney-ireland.info/travelogue/killarney.html" time="2012-07-12-23:27" support="1" score="0.0005752324680823928" bingtitle="Killarney by car — Killarney Ireland" webtitle="Killarney by car — Killarney Ireland">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>... back on N71 through the Killarney National Park. ... This is the same number that I saw the entire day on ... cater) to special diets. “I stop in a family fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Subscribe 
 
 Killarney Ireland 

All you need to know for your trip to Killarney including hotels, tourist sites, transport and more
 
Killarney by car

 September 27, 2006 · 0 comments 
 
Don Wiss has a detailed travelogue of his trip to Ireland (June 2006). Of particular interest to you will be the section on Kerry. Don’s travelogue is, admittedly, low on detail about Killarney but its good general purpose reading that will help inform your decisions on where to go (and not) and what to do (and not.)

There are some gems in here such as:
 
 “I drive back on N71 through the Killarney National Park. I stop at all the laybys along the way. As I approach Killarney I pull into the Muckross House . I take a quick picture of it. More of it will have to wait until I return to Killarney for a few days and bicycle around. But while there I count 14 coaches! This is the same number that I saw the entire day on the Ring of Kerry (though half were parked, or I was parked, so I didn’t have to pass that many).” 
 
The alternative title for Don’s trip could be‘gluten-free Ireland’; because Don is celiac (aka coeliac) he maintains a careful diet free of wheat, so he does a great job describing his search for pubs, restaurants and B&amp;B’s that cater (and don’t cater) to special diets.

 
 
“ I stop in a family fast food restaurant and ask what they have. The younger woman says her mother is celiac. (I hear comments about celiac relatives often.) They suggest a restaurant which has no sign. Their alternative suggestion is the Black Rock. I can’t find the one with no sign, so I go to Black Rock. I ask what they have that if gluten-free and dairy-free. She comes back and says only the chicken salad. Often restaurants think we celiacs will be happy eating a salad. I ask what’s wrong with the burgers. She saus it wouldn’t have a roll. Like so what! I start asking what else is cooked on the burger’s griddle. What else is fried with the chips, etc? A fellow replaces her. Was he the manager? After several trips to the kitchen to ask the chef (and a long delay each time) we figure I can have a burger, and the fries will be cooked in their own pan and oil. I ask for medium rare. Nope. They are not allowed to serve them medium rare. The food comes. The burger is well done, but all-in-all a nice meal. I head on’It’s now 2:00. As I leave I see that Ballybunnion has cliff walks, but not in the steady rain!” 
 
Also, of interest is the fact that Don is an avid photographer so his piece mentions lots of places where he stopped to take photos. Don’t miss his rendition of the time he forgot to use his camera in the valley of blooming rhododendrons in Tipperary when his car got stuck in a ditch.

One thing I would add, is that some tourists go a little bit too far in their efforts to capture Ireland in photos . Most often this happens when photographing people. Don tends to cross that border from time to time:
 
 “As I leave the B&amp;B I see an old man along the side of the road, plus the xxx church. So I turn around. I go past the old man and pull into a driveway. It seems he saw me in the distance. He kept looking the other way.”
 
 
I know its a bit of a sensitive subject, but a bit of respect would go a long way. What do you think?
 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name 

 E-mail 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Previous post: Walk Killarney 

Next post: Photography resources 
 
 
Pages

 About this site/Contact Golf and Fishing Horse Riding Kerry Genealogy Killarney Accommodation 
 Bed&amp;Breakfast 
 Killarney Lakes Killarney National Park Killarney Town Killarney Transport Ladies View Killarney Map of Killarney Souvenirs, Gifts and Guides Trails and Guided Walks Weather in Killarney 
 
Recent Visitor Comments

 Elaine Ryan on Kerry Genealogy Tuatha de danann on The Irish–more Spanish than Celtic? Rita on Kerry Genealogy Anonymous on Killarney Town PATRICK O&apos;NEILL on The Irish–more Spanish than Celtic? 
 
Categories

 accommodation Events Genealogy General Ireland Kids Music Special Offers Sporting Event Storytelling Tours&amp;Walks Transport Travelogue 
 
 
 
Search this site.
 
 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 
Get smart with the Thesis WordPress Theme from DIYthemes.

 WordPress Admin
	</body>
</document>
