<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006588" url="http://reetsayseat.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-23:31" support="5" score="0.0029920175520338093" bingtitle="Reet Says Eat" webtitle="Reet Says Eat">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>Reet Says Eat many times over the years at Renaldo&apos;s ... If you get just the right seat, you can peer across the ... SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - A diner at a Wendy&apos;s fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Reet Says Eat
 
 What&apos;s to eat? Shared recipes, music suggestions and, well, you never know what else to help you through your next meal. Take what looks interesting, then post your comments; perhaps you can share your favorites here, too. If there&apos;s a story that accompanies the recipe, real or legend, all the better! 
 
 Sunday, March 11, 2012 
 
 Tweeted from Kay McGowan in Marrakech... 
 Stall #14 Marrakech! I know there are others but I return again and again. The freshest fried fish! To die 4 eggplant twitter.com/curatedworld/s… 
—Kay McGowan (@curatedworld) March 11, 2012 

 Posted by Johnnyk at 4:15 PM No comments: 
 Thursday, March 01, 2012 
 
 Mardi Gras Dinner at Anthony Jack&apos;s... 
 Anthony Jacks Wood Fire Grill Mardi Gras Beer Dinner Thursday, March 8th 2012 6:30 pm Featuring Abita Beer straight from New Orleans 
 Menu 

 First Course 
Shrimp&amp;Craw fish Remoulade
over roma tomato cups
paired with purple haze 
 
 Second Course 
Creole Fried Eggplant
topped with a crab&amp;andouille sausage cream sauce
paired with jockamo ipa 
 
 Third Course 
Blackened Red Fish
over cajun jambalaya topped with a creamy hollandaise sauce
paired with mardi gras bock 

 Fourth Course 
Wood Grilled Pork Tenderloin
over sweet potato mashed&amp;a pecan-molasses glaze
paired with turbo dog 

 Fifth Course 
Bananas Foster Ala Mode
paired with save our shore pilsner 

(860) 426-1487, Reservations are required
 

 Posted by Johnnyk at 6:02 AM No comments: 
 Monday, February 20, 2012 
 
 Live from Daryl&apos;s House - Philly Cheese Steaks... 
 Posted by Johnnyk at 6:44 PM No comments: 
 Sunday, December 25, 2011 
 
 What&apos;s for Christmas Dinner this year? 
 At Thanksgiving dinner, the question of Christmas dinner arose. Stay with the traditional beef tenderloin or try something new? We are, therefore, polling the attendees as to their preferences. Respond in the comments section below. The Reet says she will evaluate, but promises nothing! 

 Beef Tenderloin- It&apos;s what we do. Don&apos;t change anything. Crown pork roast- Time for a change; the BT is getting a bit boring and we need to shake things up a little. Lasagna- Reet&apos;s delicious lasagna has been our Christmas Eve staple; time to bring it to center stage. We can order out Thai the night before. Prime Rib- Ham- Yes, I know we do ham at Easter. Get over it. Seafood- not sure if we would get a consensus on this, but we&apos;re throwing it out there. Hey, I&apos;m a Vegan; what about me! 
 


 Posted by Johnnyk at 5:38 PM 4 comments: 
 Thursday, November 24, 2011 
 
 City Winery opens the Barrel Room... 
 (September 6, 2011) City Winery, which opened in the fall of 2008, has quickly established itself as an innovative brand by uniquely combining the first winery in Manhattan with world-class music programming. With 6 harvests completed (3 from Northern Hemisphere vineyards and 3 spring harvests from south of the equator) more consumers will have an opportunity to taste the high quality of the wine through a unique tap system directly from the cellar below. ( more ) - Reservations are now available: OpenTable.com 
 The Classic! 
 Posted by Johnnyk at 7:11 AM No comments: 
 Saturday, January 01, 2011 
 
 Reet&apos;s &quot;Wake-Up-You-Lazy-Bastard&quot; Breakfast Casserole 
 This casserole is sure to get that lazy, no-good bastard in your life out of bed and bounding down the stairs to start the brand-new day. Maybe he will do something with his life once he&apos;s got a full tummy (probably not).  These are the ingredients you will need, so make that lazy bastard go out and get them:  
 8 frozen hash-brown patties (possibilities include Pattie LaBelle, sans BluBelles; Pattie Hearst, sans Symbionese Liberation Army; Pattie Duke; Peppermint Pattie). You get the picture. 4 cups shredded cheddar cheese 1 lb bacon- cooked, drained, crumbled (in other words, completely demoralized!) 7 eggs 1 cup milk 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon mr. mustard powder (find him in the bedroom with the candlestick) 
 Got &apos;em? Okay, let&apos;s do this: 
 Place patties (all 8 of them, kicking and screaming) in a single layer in a greased 13 by 9 baking pan; sprinkle with cheese and bacon. 
 
 In a separate bowl, beat eggs, milk, salt and mustard powder mercilessly (let all that pent-up anger out!); pour over casserole.   
 
 Cover, then bake in oven at 350 degrees for one hour (careful, if you bake at 360 degrees, you are right back where you started). 
 
 Uncover (no, not you, you idiot, the casserole!), then bake 15 minutes longer until edges are golden and a toothpick inserted in center comes out clean (it&apos;s, like, magic!!!) 
 

 Suggested music: &quot;Morning Has Broken&quot; by the sweet-voiced terrorist Yusuf Islam from his album Teaser and the Firecat . Be careful, though, George W. may send you on a vacation to Cuba for listening. 
 Posted by Johnnyk at 5:22 PM 2 comments: Labels: breakfast 
 Saturday, December 25, 2010 
 
 Nancy&apos;s simple punch (some would say it&apos;s a cheap shot) 
 Ingredients: 1 can Hawaiian Punch
1 small can frozen orange juice undiluted
1 large can frozen lemonade undiluted
1 - 2 liter bottle ginger ale
several scoops sherbert

Prepare:
You are kidding, aren&apos;t you?

Ok, I suppose you should look away while SOMEONE puts some muscle into this roundhouse. 
 Posted by Johnnyk at 8:27 PM No comments: Labels: wine/beer/spirits 
 Friday, December 24, 2010 
 
 Sally Walker&apos;s holiday beef tenderloin... 
 Ingredients: 
 6-8 lb whole tenderloin 2 lb mushrooms butter burgundy wine 
 Prepare: 
 sprinkle with rosemary; rub garlic on top of roast tuck narrow end under (the roast&apos;s, not yours); remove connective tissue (fat) place tenderloin on wire rack in large roasting pan and stick a meat thermometer into the thickest part. roast at 450 degrees for about 45 minutes or to 140 degrees on the thermometer take out of oven and pour 1 cup (or more) burgundy wine over beef to make drippings slice into 1/2 inch thick portions saute&apos; 2 lbs or more mushrooms in 1/2 cup butter; arrange around meat on festive platter and serve the starving masses. ENJOY! 
 important note: check meat sooner if you like it rare (we like it medium-rare) and don&apos;t forget that the roast will continue to cook for 10 minutes after you take it out; also, sometimes I have turned the oven down a bit towards the end. 
 Suggested music: Try a Little Tenderness by Otis Redding - (oh, she may be weary, young girls they do get weary, wearing that same old funky dress): 

   Posted by Johnnyk at 5:24 AM No comments: Labels: entrees 
 Tuesday, July 06, 2010 
 
 Sharie&apos;s tasty 4th of July rack (of ribs)... 
 Cole slaw--just a bag from the store and Cole Farms Old Fashioned Cole Slaw Dressing--at Stop&amp;Shop in the lettuce area.

  Ribs-- 
 
2 tbl brown sugar
1 tbl paprika
1 tsp dry mustard
1 tsp dried oregano
Kosher salt and black pepper
4 lbs baby-back ribs (2-3 racks)
1/2 C Dijon mustard
1/2 C balsamic vinegar
1/4 cup honey



1. Combine the brown sugar, paprika, dry mustard, oregano, 2 tsp salt, and 1/2 tsp pepper to make the rub.
2. Place the ribs on a large rimmed baking sheet. Rub the ribs with the spice mixture and tightly cover the baking sheet with foil. Bake until tender and the meat easily pulls away from the bone. 2-2 1/2 hrs at 275 degrees.
3. Combine the Dijon mustard, vinegar, and honey to make a sauce. Transfer 1/2 cup of the sauce into a small bowl for serving.
4. Grill the ribs on med-high, basting with the remaining sauce and turning occasionally, until just beginning to char, 4 to 5 minutes. Serve with the reserved sauce.

Enjoy!!

Sharon Posted by Johnnyk at 6:27 AM No comments: 
 Saturday, July 03, 2010 
 
 Linda Clock&apos;s Killer Chili 
 Ingredients: 3-4 lb ground beef 1 or 2 onions 1 pepper 2 cans large plum tomatoes 4 tablespoons chili powder large can red kidney beans (include sauce) 1 can chick peas (puree if you like) 
 Prepare: Brown ground beef and drain Saute onions and pepper Add tomatoes Add chili powder Add salt&amp;pepper 
 Cover, simmer for at least 2 hours Add kidney beans and chick peas Add a dash of hot sauce if you dare (yes, dare) 
 Serve with shredded cheddar cheese melted on top Have a glass of water and an ice cold Dixie close by 
 Suggested music: Put on the Iguanas real loud: Posted by Johnnyk at 8:16 PM No comments: Labels: soups/appetizers 
 Monday, March 01, 2010 
 
 You asked for it, Nancy K...... 
 Reet&apos;s Broccoli Soup 

It&apos;s Winter in America (gratuitous Gil Scott-Heron reference), you need something warm and tasty in your tummy while watching your favorite hoops team fail to meet expectations. Whatcha got? Rustle up some Reet&apos;s Broccoli Soup and cuddle up with your honey (or your hubby/wife- it&apos;s your call).

Ingredients:

 6 cups of water (tap is fine, unless you have to impress someone, then get Evian)  2 10-oz chopped broccoli (for those who have seen Dana Carvey&apos;s standup routine , take time out to smirk knowingly; others just move on)   3/4 cup of chopped onion   2 teaspoons of salt 2 teaspoons of white pepa (you feelin&apos; it now? gettin&apos; funky? push it good, push it real good.) 1 teaspoon of garlic powder 8 oz of American cheese 1 cup of milk 1 cup of light cream (I guess that&apos;s the Cream without Eric Clapton, but I could be mistaken) 1/4 cup of butter 1/3 cup of flour 1/2 cup of cold water (wtf? I already have 6 cups of water, you say? Just do it!) 

 Let&apos;s do this! 
Boil the water with the chopped broccoli and onion for ten minutes. You can continue to push it real good while waiting (ooh, baby baby). Then add all seasonings/cheese and stir until the cheese melts (a Northeastern expression akin to &apos;til the cows come home&apos;). Add milk, light Cream (remember, Ginger Baker and Jack Bruce only) and butter.

Now you find out why we needed that extra water. Mix the water with the flour, then very slowly add to the soup mix for texture. When your arm feels like it is falling off, you&apos;re done! Pour into large cup and ease onto the couch. Enjoy! Posted by Johnnyk at 5:32 PM 1 comment: Labels: soups/appetizers 
 Saturday, February 20, 2010 
 
 Sharie&apos;s Spicy Shrimp Cocktail 
 This recipe will warm you up on a cold winter night.   
 Keith likes the spicier version that has Sharie playing a game of &apos;Find the Shrimp&apos; 
 Mix together (mingle/network): 1/4 C catsup 1/4 C lime juice 1-2 tsp. hot pepper sauce 
 Add: 1 pound jumbo shrimp; peeled, cleaned and de-veined ( you&apos;re so de-veined, you probably think this recipe is about you ) 1/2 C chopped plum tomato 1/4 C chopped red onion 1/4 C fresh snipped cilantro 
 Refrigerate for 2-4 hours. Add 2 peeled, chopped avocados. Garnish with a wedge of lime. Serve chilled. 
 
 Suggested music: Try some low country blues from Shrimp City Slim and his band, possibly from their CD &quot;Ancestor Worship: The Boston Sessions 1980-83&quot; Posted by Johnnyk at 2:53 PM No comments: Labels: soups/appetizers 
 Tuesday, January 05, 2010 
 
 That was no hero, that was a Cuban sandwich... 
 It&apos;s got two kinds of pig meat, ham and roast pork, and a slice of white cheese in the shape of New York, so throw on a pickle and pick up your fork, say &quot;el Cubano,&quot; that&apos;s a Cuban sandwich. 


 

 You know you want one! 
Cuban or French sub roll

Chef Maurices special dressing (1 ounce Dijon mustard, 1 ounce mayonnaise, 1 ounce grainy mustard, mixed well)

2 slices Swiss cheese
2 ounces sliced ham
2 ounces sliced pork loin
2 ounces sliced salami
2 pickles, sliced flat, lengthwise

Split the roll two-thirds of the way through lengthwise and unfold. Spread Chef Maurices special dressing evenly on both sides of the bread.

One one side of the bread, layer Swiss cheese, ham, pork, salami and pickles. Fold the top of the bread to make a sandwich.

Place the sandwich in a skillet (coated with butter) on medium high heat for about two minutes per side with a weighted sandwich press. You may use a panini press or George Foreman grill. Or completely cover a large can of soup or vegetables with aluminum foil and use that to press the sandwich. Posted by Johnnyk at 8:27 AM 1 comment: 
 Thursday, December 31, 2009 
 
 Irene Flynn&apos;s American Goulash... 
 Special request of Andy McGowan 

 Ingredients: 

2 lbs. ground beef
peppers/onions in quantities of your taste
2 large cans of tomato soup
1 large can of whole tomatos
1 lb. of elbow macaroni
salt/pepa

 Prepare: 

 brown beef in skillet; set aside  saute onions/peppers in butter; set aside cook macaroni add 1/2 can water per can of tomato soup; warm mixture drain elbows and put into large pan mix in beef, peppers onions; slice whole tomatos into mix pour soup over top bake in oven @ 350 degrees for 1/2 hour 

 Pour a cold beer or a cheap chianti and dive in!  

 Suggested music: American Woman by Guess Who (unless you prefer the updated Lenny Kravitz version) 
 
   Posted by Johnnyk at 4:01 PM No comments: Labels: entrees 
 Jan Dubose&apos;s scandalously good chocolate chip cake 
 Ingredients: 
 
 Duncan Hines Deluxe Yellow Cake Mix (Jan says that if you must make the cake mix from scratch, knock yourself out, but the cake won&apos;t be better than hers)   1 package of instant vanilla pudding   4 eggs 1/2 cup oil (I&apos;m assuming cooking oil here, but let me know) 10 cups water 
 Prepare:   

 blend above ingredients and beat for 2 minutes  add 1 package of mint chocolate chips add 4 oz of jimmies pour into tube pan and bake @ 350 degrees for 1 hour   Slice and serve (not to be confused with a sliced serve).   
 
 Jan suggests a tasteful Victoria&apos;s Secret teddy just in case you&apos;ve got some batter remaining and you&apos;re in a playful mood. Otherwise, stick it in the fridge. 

 Suggested music: The Chocolate Dandies  ( YouTube )  Posted by Johnnyk at 3:03 PM 1 comment: Labels: cookies/desserts 
 Saturday, January 10, 2009 
 
 Gail Lessard&apos;s minestrone with sweet sausage and tortellini... 
 There&apos;s a winter storm acomin&apos;. People are swarming the supermarkets like ants. You decide to rustle up some soup. Good move, make this: 
 First step, gather the goods: 1/3 cup best-quality olive oil 1 lg. yellow onion, cut into thin rings 4 lg. carrots, peeled and thickly sliced 1 fennel bulb, chopped 2 lg. potatoes, peeled and diced 1 green bell pepper, cored, seeded, cut into 1/2 inch squares 3 medium-size zucchini, diced 1.5 cups of diagonally-sliced green beans 1 medium-size green cabbage, shredded 5 cups beef stock 5 cups water 1 one (35 oz.) can Italian plum tomatoes 2 tbsp. dried oregano 1 tbsp. dried basil Salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste Outer rind of 2-inch chunk of Parmesan or Romano cheese 1.5 cup canned cannellini (white kidney) beans, drained 1 lb. cheese-stuffed tortellini 1.5 lbs. sweet Italian sausage (pan fried, drained, sliced) Freshly grated Fontina cheese 
 Take a brief rest, being thankful you had all this shit in the house.
Deep breath, GO! 
 Heat oil in a large stockpot over medium heat. Add onion, saute until transparent (or transgendered, whichever happens first). Stir in carrots and saute 2-3 minutes, tossin&apos; and turnin&apos; occasionally Add the fennel, potatoes, green pepper, zucchini and green beans, sauteing each veggie 2-3 minutes before adding the next (don&apos;t cheat, we&apos;re watching you). When assignment is completed, passed in and graded, stir in cabbage cook 5 minutes more (extra credit). Add the stock, bonds, mutual funds, water, tomatoes with their juice, spices. Bury the Parmesan rind in the middle of the soup (R.I.P.- no calling hours) Heat to boiling, then reduce heat, simmer covered low 2.5 to 3 hours. Stir occasionally. The soup will be very thick (something akin to your understanding of this whole process). Fifteen minutes before serving stir in cannellini beans and tortellini. Raise heat to cook tortellini, continue to stir occasionally. JUST before serving, stir in sausage. Ladle the minestrone into shallow pasta bowls and garnish lavishly with Fontina (no, not THAT Fontina, the stripper you met while hangin&apos; with Plaxico Burriss). 
 
 There, you&apos;ve done it! Pop a cold one and sit in front on that big-screen you bought yourself for Christmas (and hope you didn&apos;t really give Fontina your home phone number). Posted by Johnnyk at 9:21 AM 1 comment: Labels: soups/appetizers 
 Whew, George the Lobster, that was a close one!... 
 NYC eatery grants freedom to lobster centenarian (AP) NEW YORK–A 140-year-old lobster once destined for a dinner plate received the gift of life Friday from a Park Avenue seafood restaurant. George, the 20-pound supercentenarian crustacean, was freed by City Crab and Seafood in New York City. &quot;We applaud the folks at City Crab and Seafood for their compassionate decision to allow this noble old-timer to live out his days in freedom and peace,&quot; said Ingrid E. Newkirk, president of People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals.

PETA spokesman Michael McGraw said the group asked City Crab to return George to the Atlantic Ocean after a diner saw him at the restaurant, where steamed Maine lobster sells for $27 per pound. George had been caught off Newfoundland, Canada and lived in the tank for about 10 days before his release. Some scientists estimate lobsters can live to be more than 100 years old. PETA and the restaurant guessed George&apos;s age at about 140, using a rule of thumb based on the creature&apos;s weight. He was to be released Saturday near Kennebunkport, Maine, in an area where lobster trapping is forbidden.

 Tribute to George: 
 Posted by Johnnyk at 5:18 AM 1 comment: Labels: entrees 
 Thursday, January 01, 2009 
 Thanks for letting us into your kitchen (it&apos;s a little messy, don&apos;t you think?) 

 Happy New Year! Posted by Johnnyk at 6:39 AM 1 comment: 
 Saturday, December 27, 2008 
 
 I guess we&apos;re hosed on these gift certificates!....
	</body>
</document>
