<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006606" url="http://pubsub.com/Yum-Brands-Sweetens-Dividend-Yum-Yum-Restaurant-8LQouNDnAiXS" time="2012-07-12-23:32" support="5" score="0.009326945158794939" bingtitle="Yum Yum Restaurant - PubSub - Home" webtitle="Yum Yum Restaurant">
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000786" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the ... I’ve always cared about what my food looked like. If it doesn’t look good ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Search Real Time Hot Items Topics Help About Login as: Sign up 
 Remember me Your Ad Here 
 

Yum Yum Restaurant
 ( Permalink ) 
 Your Ad Here 
 Yum ! Brands Sweetens Dividend 
 [ Forbes , Most Popular ] ( Forbes.com: News )
 Restaurant chain among several companies to declare shareholder payouts.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Restaurant chain among several companies to declare shareholder payouts. 
 Bullish on Yum Brands 
 [ The Globe and Mail , Canada , Globe and Mail , Starter Kit ] ( The Globe and Mail - Home RSS feed )
Technical analysis shows the restaurant company, whose brands include KFC and Pizza Hut, is set to rise ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-ca   Technical analysis shows the restaurant company, whose brands include KFC and Pizza Hut, is set to rise 
 San Juan Puerto Rico With Kids: Old San Juan 
 [ Travel , Moms ] ( DeliciousBaby.com )
We were invited guests of the San Juan Marriott Resort&amp;Stellaris Casino. The hotel paid for the cost of our air tickets, hotel, activities, and most meals. They did not require that I express a particular point of view. Sunshine! Finally! Lots of it! Of course Everest, the poor sweet boy who I dragged across the ocean to an uncharacteristically rainy Puerto Rico wouldn&apos;t know. He&apos;s sleeping in. Everest sleeps through the morning By the time ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 We were invited guests of the San Juan Marriott Resort&amp;Stellaris Casino . The hotel paid for the cost of our air tickets, hotel, activities, and most meals. They did not require that I express a particular point of view. 

Sunshine! Finally! Lots of it! Of course Everest, the poor sweet boy who I dragged across the ocean to an uncharacteristically rainy Puerto Rico wouldn&apos;t know. He&apos;s sleeping in.
 Everest sleeps through the morning 
By the time he wakes up, I&apos;m in a rush. I want him to experience the beach and the pool, and I need him to eat breakfast. We&apos;re headed to Old San Juan for lunch today, so we don&apos;t have unlimited time. I hustle him into a swimming suit and we race out to the beach. I search for, and find, a server who will bring us breakfast by the pool.
 Beach at the San Juan Marriott Resort&amp;Stellaris Casino 
Everest cannot get enough of the beach - and he thinks that standing with his feet in the ocean as the waves rush in is the funniest, giggliest thing that can happen to you. (we live by a lake, so he sees lots of shoreline, but almost never experiences surf) I wish I had pictures, or video of this, but believe me, standing in the ocean with a squiggly 15 month old in your arms and a precariously balanced 5 year old by the wrist is quite enough for me to manage.
 Everest focuses on digging a hole to China 
Is the beach supposed to be relaxing? Perhaps if my husband were here, or if the kids were a bit older, it would be. Still, we&apos;re having fun, and that&apos;s enough.
 Everest and I slide down the waterslide together 
But never mind, there&apos;s a pool to check out, and a water slide. Everest is normally super cautious, and when I saw the slide, I imagined that he&apos;d never go on it. After watching the other kids splash down the slide a few times, he wants to try it too. Yay for being on a trip with other kids! He slides down with Colleen of TravelMamas the first time, and then someone convinces me to hand off baby Eilan and slide down with him myself. We have a few precious moments alone together, and I&apos;m so surprised that I slide down with my hat on and forget to hold Everest up in the air on impact. Water rushing up his nose isn&apos;t his favorite sensation, and it might be a while before he agrees to go on a water slide again.

But then we&apos;re off again. It&apos;s time to head to lunch. We&apos;re the last ones out of the pool, and I have three bodies to dry off, dress, and bring downstairs to the lobby. Still, we&apos;re somehow the first ones out by the bus - perhaps that&apos;s the advantage of having boys, or perhaps it&apos;s the lack of fussiness that comes with being a sleep-deprived mom of three kids.

Our lunch is in Old San Juan at a restaurant called Raices . Raices is a casual place with servers in old fashioned Puerto Rican dress. It&apos;s been around forever, and it&apos;s a favorite with both locals and servers. The menu is huge, and includes lots of fried items ( yum ) and many varieties of Mofongo (meat with plantains). I&apos;m delighted, but for Everest, even the kids menu is challenging.
 Appetizer platter at Raices Restaraunt in San Juan Puerto Rico 
I have to admit, dealing with picky eating always stresses me out somewhat, but it&apos;s somehow heightened in this situation with several other moms and kids. Somehow (even though there&apos;s no competition expressed or implied) I want, more than ever, for poor Everest to be the perfect traveler - always ready for new experiences and new foods. We compromise on cod fritters (which I sell as fish sticks) and then he tries (and loves) the slightly sweet deep fried corn fritters. Whew, at least I didn&apos;t have to break out my peanut butter packets 

After lunch, we wander around Old San Juan. We&apos;re both hot, and I&apos;m sweating under the weight of a sleeping baby Eilan. I wonder if this area might be best seen on one of the free trolleys that run circuits around the tourist areas. I love the architecture, but most of the businesses cater to tourists, not locals. If you&apos;re not shopping for souvenirs, there&apos;s not much need to look inside the buildings.
 Old San Juan Old San Juan This building must have an interesting history 
Our next stop is Castillo San Felipe Del Morro . We&apos;re going to explore the old Spanish fort (which dates from the 1500&apos;s) and then fly kites on the huge lawn. Everest is more excited about the kids than the fort, but somehow I cajole him through the entry, and we race down stairways, into turrets, and through what seem to him like secret passage ways. The views are spectacular, and though there aren&apos;t any relics here beyond the building itself, a child with a vivid imagination would find material for days of storytelling. Everest isn&apos;t that child, though, he&apos;s interested in how the whole thing is engineered - the stairways, the gutters and the 6 meter thick walls.
 Castillo San Felipe del Morro, San Juan Castillo San Felipe del Morro, San Juan View from Castillo San Felipe del Morro, San Juan 
And then finally, he times out. We slather on sunscreen and head to the front of the fort to fly kites. This feels like the most fun we&apos;ve had together in ages. We&apos;re running, giggling, and laughing. With the heavy winds, our kite is hard to control, and I&apos;ve got the baby, the kite, Everest, and of course I&apos;m on twitter posting pics as we go.
 Everest flying his kite on the lawn at Castillo San Felipe del Morro in San Juan Puerto Rico 
Eventually, the wind is just too much, and the kite gets away from us. Everest and I get burns from the string in the process of trying to rescue it, and Everest is just inconsolable. Everyone tries to calm him down, but he&apos;s tired, he hasn&apos;t had a great lunch, and he&apos;s heartbroken about the loss of the kite.

But Kara, our tireless host, knows just what to do - we&apos;ll march back to the street and buy shave ice (Piragua in Spanish) from a cart! Within moments, Everest&apos;s eyes are dry, and he&apos;s smiling again.
 Piraguas at Castillo San Felipe del Morro, San Juan 
Just look at those kids - as far as they&apos;re concerned, there&apos;s not a thing wrong in the world.

Eventually we make our way back to the hotel, and we have a &quot;mom&apos;s night out&quot; at Ristorante Tuscany , the Marriott&apos;s upscale Italian restaurant while the kids watch a movie with a sitter. The food, and wine are lovely and by the time we&apos;re done everyone is ready to get into bed. With our trip complete, I&apos;ll pack us up in the morning and we&apos;ll fly back to Seattle.
 Doesn&apos;t this look like the perfect antidote to a busy day with the kids? Related Links: 
 City Guide: San Juan Puerto Rico With Kids 
 
 UPCOMING: Learn how to make Gazpacho with Free Demo by Ris Chef, Ris Lacoste, at Georgetown &quot;Social&quot; Safeway SAT, Sept 11th 1:00pm - 2:30pm 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( &quot;Free in DC&quot; Free Events&amp;Things to Do in DC! )
Chef Ris Lacoste hosts Cooking Demonstration at Georgetown&apos;s “Social” Safeway Saturday, September 11th 1:00pm - 2:30pmFree The recently renovated, swank “Social” Safeway in Georgetown has been celebrating since their grand re-opening with “52 Weeks of Events” featuring events each week: chef demos, jazz soloist performances, story telling and more. This week, DC celebrity chef Ris Lacoste of Ris restaurant will appear for a chef demonstration showing guests how t ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   

 Chef Ris Lacoste hosts Cooking Demonstration at Georgetown&apos;s “Social” Safeway Saturday, September 11th 1:00pm - 2:30pm Free 
 The recently renovated, swank “Social” Safeway in Georgetown has been celebrating since their grand re-opening with “52 Weeks of Events” featuring events each week: chef demos, jazz soloist performances, story telling and more. 
 This week, DC celebrity chef Ris Lacoste of Ris restaurant will appear for a chef demonstration showing guests how to prepare a restaurant quality gazpacho at home with Safeway products. Yum ... gazpacho! 
 Georgetown Safeway Chef Station, Seafood dept 1855 Wisconsin Avenue, NW Metro: Circulator bus up Wisconsin Ave from K St or Penn Ave, from Farragut North or Foggy Bottom Metro or take any of the 30 buses south on Wisconsin Ave from Tenleytown Metro 

 
 Foodsday Tuesday: Pepper Season 
 [ Philadelphia, PA , Philadelphia ] ( Phillyist )
Image Credit: John Winkelman Growing up in Texas, it was chili pepper season all year. It wasn&apos;t until I moved to the Northeast that I realized that, in fact, there were certain times of year during which it was nearly impossible to find good-looking jalapeños or poblanos. I&apos;ve spent eight years trying to pinpoint when, exactly, chili season is for this part of the country. On Sunday, on a trip to the Headhouse Square Farmer&apos;s Market, I finally learned: the time is now. Ten dollars got me ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Image Credit: John Winkelman 
Growing up in Texas, it was chili pepper season all year. It wasn&apos;t until I moved to the Northeast that I realized that, in fact, there were certain times of year during which it was nearly impossible to find good-looking jalapeños or poblanos. I&apos;ve spent eight years trying to pinpoint when, exactly, chili season is for this part of the country. On Sunday, on a trip to the Headhouse Square Farmer&apos;s Market , I finally learned: the time is now. Ten dollars got me two pints of some of the most gorgeous peppers—poblanos and Anaheims—I&apos;ve ever seen. Combined with other late-summer produce, some kitchen staples, and one of my favorite starches, the peppers formed the basis for a truly epic side dish that could be eaten hot, cold, or at room temperature.


 Quinoa with Chili Peppers, Zucchini, and White Corn 
One cup quinoa (dry)
One can diced tomatoes with green chiles, strained, liquid reserved
Four zucchini, diced
Four poblano peppers, diced, seeds and membrane removed
Four Anaheim peppers, diced, seeds and membrane removed
Two tablespoons of olive oil (or less)
Four ears of corn, cooked, kernels removed from cob
Five cloves of garlic, minced
Salt and pepper to taste

Measure liquid from canned tomatoes and add water to reach two cups. Combine liquid, quinoa, chopped tomatoes, and salt (if desired) in pot. Bring to a boil, reduce heat, cover, and simmer 10-15 minutes or until liquid is evaporated. Uncover and set aside.

Sauté zucchini with chili peppers in olive oil until zucchini begins to soften and peppers turn translucent, seasoning with salt and pepper to taste. Add corn and garlic, continue to sauté until garlic begins to darken. Remove from heat and combine with quinoa, stirring until mixture is evenly distributed. Serve at desired temperature with the protein of your choice (we used it to accompany a flatiron steak). Save leftovers and eat them cold, straight out of the refrigerator, whenever you need a snack—at least, that&apos;s what I did.

 Quick Nosh 


 The Junior League of Philadelphia is hosting its first Taste of Fall fundraiser early next month, featuring food; beer and wine tastings; cooking demonstrations; and more. Additional information and tickets online . Like food trucks? Like Jose Garces? Then you&apos;re really like what happens when the two converge. Meal Ticket has the scoop. It seems like every neighborhood has a restaurant week of its own these days. Bucking the trend is John Brandt-Lee, chef/owner of Avalon Restaurant in West Chester, who will be offering a NON- Restaurant Week special to his patrons. Just tell your server that you&apos;re not there for Restaurant Week, and get a free cheese plate. Yum ! 


 
 
 A whole week of awesome 
 [ Africa ] ( Afrigator )
Some may say its counting your eggs before they have hatched, others will say it encourages positive thinking, I am going with the latter. In case you are blind, deaf and been living under a boulder, I started Weight Watchers in December last year. My goal to lose 30kgs in one year, it&apos;s been 9 months and this is my week baby, my week to OWN that 30kgs. O . M . GToday I picked up my jeans, and my very first thought was WTF, who am I kidding, who&apos;s jeans are there? These will never fit. They fit ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Some may say its counting your eggs before they have hatched, others will say it encourages positive thinking, I am going with the latter. In case you are blind, deaf and been living under a boulder, I started Weight Watchers in December last year. My goal ... to lose 30kgs in one year, it&apos;s been 9 months and this is my week baby, my week to OWN that 30kgs. O . M . GToday I picked up my jeans, and my very first thought was WTF, who am I kidding, who&apos;s jeans are there? These will never fit. They fit. I can paint my own toe nails and shop in the normal girl section at woolies, for the very first time I can remember since forever my clothes size does not start with an &apos;X&apos; - its the small things really. Anywho, I thought in celebration, because lets face it, this is one mother trucking achievement, or it will be rather, on Thursday. I am going to have a week of 30s, to kick us off;30 things I had to change to lose 30kgsPlanning my meals every day, every meal!Writing down everything I eat, every single thing, ALL OF IT, even the things you would rather forget about, every day!2% milk turned into skim milk you learn to love it, I promiseCoke turned into coke zero, coke lite, tab, sprite zero, Fanta free yes, you learn to love it :)Butter turned into ultra freaking lower than low fat spread, I dont think you can even call it margarine anymoreNo sugar in my coffeeI have become the human embodiment of the Weight Watchers point book, I can probably work out any point score for you at any timeI started going to gym - regularlyI started runningI started to enjoy running. My SSK says running is a lot like banging your head against the wall, it feels AWESOME when you stop.I have had to find and make time to go to gymI go to gym 5 or 6 times a weekI eat so much salad that my middle name should be buggsI make lunch for myself every dayI dont eat pizza, slap chips, regular chips, cake, slabs of chocolate, biscuits, burgers, tart and restaurant pasta unless I specifically have points to burn or am DYING of a craving, even then you only eat half of what you really want to eatI always save points for weekends (Weight Watchers has a bank system when you can carry points over during the week if you dont use them so if you go over on weekends you technically did not fall off the wagon)I make sure I sleep at least 5 - 8 hours a night (true story, sleep deprivation makes it harder to lose weight)I make sure I am in a good head space (true story being emotionally vulnerable makes it harder to lose weight)I have to buy new pants and bras every two months (no jokes, I started off as a size 24, I am now a size 14)I fall off the wagon from time to time, but the difference is now I get back onI have grown to appreciate the uni-boob of a good sports braI need to be in control of my life for at least 6 days out of a week, otherwise the wheels fall off and when that happens all my dedication goes out the window routine baby, routine No snacking! OK so you can snack, but be creative, gum for instance :) gherkins, olives, sugar free jelly and lite custard, coke zero, diabetic biscuits. YUM I actually cant stress that enough, NO (unplanned) SNACKING. The truth is this one is all about will power, if your work place is anything like mine, someone always has pizza, cake, doughnuts, biskies, chocolate, chips bread-rolls and chips, slap chips it never ends! You need to smile sweetly and say no thanks, but in your head you are screaming YES PLEASE PUT IT IN MY MOUTH NOW NOW NOW YOU MOFO! But instead you smile sweetly, and say, no thanks. :)I have bought, well my dad bought me (thanks dad!!), super-duper running shoes, if you are going to be running you cant be messing with fong-kong shoes that will hurt your ankles and kneesYou cant shop hungry, its a rooky mistake, either you fall off the wagon and shove a hotdog (7 points, see point number 7 above - ironically) in your mouth, or you play hard ball and shop in record speed to get home and eat, but then you buy really silly bad things and have to re-shop anyway!I have had to set very clear goals, like my 30kg mark, then every 5kg mark thereafter and make sure people know, that way you become accountableI have to remind myself all the time that half way there is not good enough, its about finishing what you startedI have had to learn how to appreciate and accept compliments people pay me - a lifetime of being overweight teaches to take compliments with a pinch of pity and saltEvery single day makes a difference, every single chip and slice of pizza makes a difference, if you are trying to lose weight and you &apos;cheat&apos; I got news for you sister, you are only cheating yourself. 
 Pizza Party Toy = Yum &amp;Fun 
 [ Shopping ] ( Family Style )
My son, JD, celebrated his third birthday this past Monday! My family and I took him to a friend’s restaurant for dinner and we got the royal treatment, which meant JD got to make a pizza! He had so much fun! Check out this adorable pic of him. Naturally, I needed to find him a ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   My son, JD, celebrated his third birthday this past Monday! My family and I took him to a friend’s restaurant for dinner and we got the royal treatment, which meant JD got to make a pizza! He had so much fun! Check out this adorable pic of him. Naturally, I needed to find him a [...] 
 PM Listage: When to Ask for Substitutions; Top Chef Is Getting Predictable 
 [ New York City, NY , Food , New York City ] ( Eater National )
Inside Tiato, Santa Monica. [Photo: Muy Yum ] · Countdown to Emmys: Feeding 3,600 Guests at the Governors Ball [LAT] · &apos;Bad&apos; Pizza Is Subject of New Domino’s Spot [NYT] · Florida Restaurant Obama Visited Cited For Food Safety Violations ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Inside Tiato, Santa Monica. [Photo: Muy Yum ] · Countdown to Emmys: Feeding 3,600 Guests at the Governors Ball [LAT] · &apos;Bad&apos; Pizza Is Subject of New Domino’s Spot [NYT] · Florida Restaurant Obama Visited Cited For Food Safety Violations... 
 True Confessions: Forbidden Fair-Food Fetishes 
 [ Organic ] ( Simple, Good and Tasty )
Have you noticed a theme at Simple, Good and Tasty (SGT) this week? Nope, it’s not about the salmonella outbreak in factory-raised eggs; Michael Pollan, Bill Marler and John Robbins are doing a good job covering that subject for us. And, no, it’s not about the growing controversy about whether or not to sell flavored milk in school cafeterias; thank you, Renegade Lunch Lady Ann Cooper, for taking care of that one. While we’ve got the big guns out doing the big, food stories, we&apos;re focusing ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Have you noticed a theme at Simple, Good and Tasty (SGT) this week? Nope, it’s not about the salmonella outbreak in factory-raised eggs; Michael Pollan , Bill Marler and John Robbins are doing a good job covering that subject for us. And, no, it’s not about the growing controversy about whether or not to sell flavored milk in school cafeterias; thank you, Renegade Lunch Lady Ann Cooper , for taking care of that one.

While we’ve got the big guns out doing the big, food stories, we&apos;re focusing instead on a topic that’s a bit nearer and dearer to our hearts, and stomachs: food at the Minnesota State Fair.

Wait a minute, you may be saying to yourself, SGT is about local, healthful, humanely sourced food. What’s in the name of Lucia Watson does that have to do with corn dogs, deep-fried candy bars, french fries, and funnel cakes? The answer is, admittedly and unfortunately, not much. As our own Lee Zukor wrote last week , &quot;can&apos;t we put our heads together and come up with new [fair food] offerings that taste great, support our state&apos;s economy, promote our local farmers, and don&apos;t require emergency angioplasty?”

Last year, Rachel Hutton of City Pages wrote &quot; How Minnesota is the State Fair ,&quot; a spot-on account of her search for local food at the state fair. Among her comments: &quot;You&apos;d hardly know that the Great Minnesota Get-Together is run by the State Agricultural Society.&quot; And &quot;Most fairgoers treat the state&apos;s agricultural concerns as they do the fair&apos;s myriad cow pies. And by that, I mean they avoid them.&quot; And, finally: &quot;You could spend an entire day at the fair without eating anything locally grown.&quot;

Still, every August, locavores like myself optimistically drive down Como Avenue in St. Paul, park in a dusty field, and walk up the ramp to the pedestrian bridge with high hopes that this year will be different – that this will the year we find real, Minnesota food at the Minnesota State Fair.

And then there is reality.

 Byron Katie wrote in her book Loving What Is that when you argue with reality, you lose – 100 percent of the time. So in the interest of keeping peace with reality – the majority of the food at the Minnesota State Fair is not from Minnesota, is not humanely raised, is not healthful to humans or the environment – I posed this question to some of the Twin Cities’ most passionate locavores:

“During the Minnesota State Fair, what one food do you know you’re not supposed to eat (it’s bad for you, it’s not local, it’s not humanely raised, etc.) but you have a hard time resisting? And if it’s not fair food, what is it?”

For instance, my forbidden fair food is cotton candy. Always pink. Always on a white, paper cone. I know it’s nothing but processed white sugar, artificial color, and artificial flavor, but when I put that first delicate wisp into my mouth, I can’t wait for the second, the third, and on it goes until I’m actually licking the cone. My nine-year-old daughter, also a cotton candy aficionado – describes it perfectly: “It’s like eating a sweet, pink cloud.”

 My husband &apos;s fair-food fetish is mini donuts. But not just any mini donuts:

&quot;My favorite is the original Tom Thumb by the food building. When perfect, they&apos;re hot and crispy on the outside, and barely cooked on the inside — “medium rare” if such an idea holds for donuts. And it’s important to come prepared with a cup of hot coffee – you don’t want to get the donuts first and let them cool down while you’re ordering coffee. The best fair coffee is at French Meadow, just across the street.&quot;

Lee wrote last week that his biggest food weakness is food he’s never tried before, but that some of the new offerings at this year’s fair – chicken-fried bacon in a gravy boat, pizza with corn-dog topping, and deep-fried bologna on a stock – aren’t exactly what he had in mind:

&quot;I&apos;ve already admitted to a weakness for weird foods, but this stuff isn&apos;t really weird, and it isn&apos;t very creative either.&quot;

What about other local foodies? Do they have a forbidden Fair food that they will admit to eating at the State Fair?

You betcha...

Angelique Chao, writer/blogger, SGT and From Animal to Meat &quot;Deep-fried Snickers. Snickers aren&apos;t exactly local, and I&apos;m not optimistic that the milk in the milk chocolate is sourced from humane, sustainable dairies.&quot;

Jenny Breen, chef and food educator, Good Life Catering &quot;My favorite, decadent, and undoubtedly not PC treat at the fair is the salted-nut roll -- gooey nougat (probably sugar and cornstarch) rolled with nuts – (I prefer cashews, but pecans and peanuts are also available) and then covered in chocolate. None of it fair-trade or sustainably raised, I&apos;m sure, but YUM ! And directly across from there is my other favorite: corn fritters and fried green tomatoes-batter with a few kernels of (likely NOT local) corn, and deep fried, and slices of green tomatoes -- assuredly mass produced -- also deep fried. Double YUM ! Can&apos;t wait to see what others admit to.&quot;

Tracy Morgan, writer and marketing consultant, SGT and Segnavia Creative &quot;Easy. Pronto Pups. Not corn dogs, Pronto Pups. Who knows where a hot dog comes from but I’m guessing it&apos;s not one of those fancy all-beef sorts either way!! Otherwise, I&apos;m disgustingly good when it comes to the fair -- cheese curds, but only 1/2 order max (and they&apos;re local!); caramel apple sundae; corn. That&apos;s about it!!&quot;

R.T. Rybak, mayor , Minneapolis:&quot;Like a lot of people, I develop split personalities at the State Fair. My two favorite foods there are in the Food Building: the gourmet wild rice burger at Wild Rice Specialties, which I follow up with Nitro Ice Cream, which is made on site with liquid nitrogen. I could eat a gallon of that stuff.&quot;

Kristin Boldon, writer/blogger, SGT and Girl Detective &quot;My non-Minnesotan friends are truly horrified by the fair foods I celebrate each year. I excuse them (ahem, OK, maybe rationalize them) by saying it&apos;s once a year, and by having the food guideline of going with a group, always getting a small, and sharing. For the fair, I also do my homework and look for other foodie advice so I don&apos;t get bamboozled into Joe&apos;s random corn dog and cotton candy stand, but am seeking out the things there that might not be healthful, but above all are tasty.&quot;

Jill Grunewald, founder, Healthful Elements and organizer, Minnesota Cooks &quot;Two words: Funnel cake!&quot;

James Norton, founder/editor, The Heavy Table &quot;Deep-fried candy bars are life-destroying abominations that should be wiped from the face of the planet, and are so tremendously unhealthy that even a paid glutton like yours truly avoids them at all costs... except at the Minnesota State Fair. Then, what the hell. Somehow they sneak into the mix.&quot;

Tracey Paska, writer/blogger, Tangled Noodle and SGT&quot;It has got to be the original, deep-fried on a stick food -- the Corn Dog!! Processed meat product, battered in (highly likely) GMO corn, then deep fried. It couldn&apos;t possibly be any worse, but it&apos;s so good! But I have had success resisting. Last year was the first time in ages that I have gone to a county or state fair where it might even be a temptation. And I ate so many other things, I had no room for a corn dog!&quot;

Then there are others who won’t admit to a particular Forbidden Fair food, but they do confess a weakness for other foods that probably would not make Michael Pollan’s “Like” list:

Lenny Russo, owner/chef, Heartland Restaurant , St. Paul&quot;I don&apos;t eat junk food, but at home, what we occasionally do is indulge in prime-grade beef porterhouse or ribeye steaks. I&apos;d say we do that once or twice a year. We know it&apos;s grain-fed, probably not locally raised (but at least from the Midwest), and most likely not humanely produced. At any rate, it is not consistent with how we normally eat or run our lives and our business. I feel pretty guilty when I&apos;m buying it, but not so guilty when I&apos;m eating it. That said, if it went out of existence tomorrow and I could never have another piece of prime beef, I don&apos;t think I would miss it too much.&quot;

Daniel Klein, filmmaker, Perennial Plate :&quot;I&apos;ve brainwashed myself into being pretty good about what I eat, but my girlfriend always buys avocados and I&apos;m very happy that she does. But I guess that isn&apos;t Fair-related, or junk, it&apos;s just from a long way away. The same goes for all the French and Italian cheese we buy. As far as junk goes, I really like Sunchips and will sometimes get them if I&apos;m on a road trip; the waxy Hostess chocolate-cake donuts at gas stations are also a craving. And Coke and Gatorade can be extremely refreshing. The thing is my girlfriend loves cotton candy, cheese puffs, Coke, cinnamon bears, Pop tarts... the list goes on, so I constantly have to be the example and not cave in to her tastes... So, after all that writing, I realize that the big thing that I know I shouldn&apos;t eat, but that I really like, is diner breakfast patty sausages. I try to eat meat only from good sources, but those breakfast sausages are amazing with a little syrup.&quot;

Greg Reynolds, owner, Riverbend Farm &quot;When I&apos;m out, not near any of my usual places of supply, and need to keep going for another hour, I like a Snickers bar. And while we have some great local beers,  Bell&apos;s Two Hearted Ale tastes pretty good.&quot;

Amy Boland, writer/blogger, SGT and Cook &apos;em if you got &apos;em &quot;OK, I know that pork is NOT the other white meat. It is a red meat liberally streaked with (scrumptious) saturated fat. In its most delicious forms, it is also filled with curing agents that are not good for me. But I love it. I have entire friendships based on shared fondness for pork. I wouldn&apos;t say this food is forbidden, but it is certainly not constructive to eat it more than once a week. Which, sometimes, I do.&quot;

Hopefully, the courageous admissions (Deep-fried candy bars! Funnel cakes! Corn-fed steak!) by this esteemed group will be the encouragement you need to face your food fetish – whether it&apos;s associated with the fair or some other event – and accept it as a delicious and satisfying reminder of this reality: we&apos;re all human.

 

 

Shari Danielson is editorial director at Simple, Good and Tasty .You can write to her at shari@simplegoodandtasty.com .

 

 
 
 Yum , Yum 
 [ SciFi&amp;Fantasy Novels ] ( Old Enough to Know Better )
Near our birthdays -- just around the corner -- my wife and I will sometimes go to the dunes, on the Oregon coast, around Florence. We camp at the port RV grounds, walk into town, shop, read, hang out, and eat. Two years back, we discovered Crave&apos;s, which had food to die for. Just as good last year. This year, however, when I got online to make reservations, Crave&apos;s was gone Well crap! But wait -- Now the same spot is occupied by Feast, and happily -- the only thing that changed was the ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Near our birthdays -- just around the corner -- my wife and I will sometimes go to the dunes, on the Oregon coast, around Florence. We camp at the port RV grounds, walk into town, shop, read, hang out, and eat. Two years back, we discovered Crave&apos;s , which had food to die for. 
 Just as good last year. 
 This year, however, when I got online to make reservations, Crave&apos;s was ... gone ... 
 Well ... crap! 
 But wait -- Now the same spot is occupied by Feast , and happily -- the only thing that changed was the name. Same chefs, same food. 
 So we ate. Oh, man! If there was any justice, we wouldn&apos;t have been able to get in; fortunately, though it was busy, we did get a reservation. 
 My wife had for her appetizer a beet salad. I had onion rings, though the onions were amazingly thin. Dianne&apos;s entree was linguini with mushrooms, I had duck breast with cherry sauce. Dessert was a baby cake -- caramelized hazelnuts in a vanilla cream sauce. Best meal in a restaurant I&apos;ve had since, well, the last time we at there. 
 I also had a beer. 
 Total cost? $54. Can&apos;t beat that, truly. 
 If you are on the Oregon coast and you are any kind of foodie, you gotta go there. Really. 
 Associate Manager, Customer Relationship Management 
 [ Jobs , Jobs (not Steve) ] ( Monster Job Search Results )
TX-Dallas, A&amp;W;, KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut, and Taco Bell - together they form YUM ! Brands, the world&apos;s largest restaurant company. More important than our size is our commitment to breakthrough innovation and the success of our employees. From multi-branded stores to our passionate customer mania philosophy and an incredible franchise system, this is one great place to work! So come see what it&apos;s li ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   TX-Dallas, A&amp;W;, KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut, and Taco Bell - together they form YUM ! Brands, the world&apos;s largest restaurant company. More important than our size is our commitment to breakthrough innovation and the success of our employees. From multi-branded stores to our passionate customer mania philosophy and an incredible franchise system, this is one great place to work! So come see what it&apos;s li 
 A Conversation in a Restaurant 
 [ Weight Loss ] ( Escape from Obesity )
My little girl (emphasis on the &apos;little&apos; she is quite thin) has always loved Indian food. Even as a baby, she goo gooed and gaa gaaed her way through a dish of &quot;chicken and rice&quot; (chicken makhani) and gnawed piece after piece of naan bread. When she wouldn&apos;t eat anything else, she&apos;d surely eat that! The Indian restaurant here has a lunch buffet that&apos;s pretty great, and I used to go with my daughter and husband about once a week and eat plate after plate of creamy curry over rice. Love the stuff. ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   My little girl (emphasis on the &apos;little&apos;... she is quite thin) has always loved Indian food. Even as a baby, she goo gooed and gaa gaaed her way through a dish of &quot;chicken and rice&quot; (chicken makhani) and gnawed piece after piece of naan bread. When she wouldn&apos;t eat anything else, she&apos;d surely eat that! The Indian restaurant here has a lunch buffet that&apos;s pretty great, and I used to go with my daughter and husband about once a week and eat plate after plate of creamy curry over rice. Love the stuff. And the naan is to die for: fresh off the Tandoor, steaming hot, crispy and doughy with butter brushed over the top. I cannot even tell you how much food I used to pack away when we went there, but I would estimate that it was 4-5 full plates of creamy stuff on rice, a bowl of salad with dressing, a Mango drink, 8 large circles of naan, and 2 little desserts. After I started blogging and counting calories, I found that I was satisfied with 1-2 plates, focusing on curried veggies but always saving space for a piece of naan.

Today we ran errands. I took my daughter to her gymnastics class and we did some shopping. It was lunchtime and guess where we were? Near the Indian restaurant . My daughter wanted to go there for lunch. We haven&apos;t gone in months (maybe 2 times this year) so I said yes, and off we went. I figured I&apos;d focus on salad and chicken. We sat down to eat, and it went like this:

Me: Mmmm, this chicken is so good. But oh the creamy sauce is rich and fantastic, I could eat it like soup!
Myself: Yeah, I guess it isn&apos;t too bad without any rice. But check out the fried pakoras!
Me: No thanks, that&apos;s off plan. I don&apos;t like fried stuff.
Myself: Don&apos;t like fried stuff?? Who are you trying to kid, lady?
Me: I don&apos;t need it. They never taste that good anyway.
Myself: Those fried donut balls in syrup always taste good!
Me: No sugar. Boy, am I enjoying this chicken! And the salad is fresh and crisp.
Myself: The dressing is off plan! I bet it is high in fat. May as well have a donut ball now.
Me: Nah, I didn&apos;t use much dressing, I will count it as a condiment, it&apos;s fine. Yum , these cucumbers are so good!
Myself: Look at that naan your daughter is eating. Boy that looks yum my.
Me: Yeah it does. But it&apos;s not fresh, it has sat on the buffet awhile. I only really like naan fresh.
Myself: So what? Dip it in the sauce.
Me: Nah,

(enjoyed eating in silence for awhile, getting full)

Myself: Dude! They JUST brought out steaming fresh, hot naan!
Me: Oh, yeah, wow, that looks really good.
Myself: You totally should have a piece.
Me: Well, maybe a small piece. I do LOVE hot fresh naan and I haven&apos;t had any other carbs today.

(went up to the buffet, brought back hot, fresh naan)

Me: Oh, this is nice and chewy and crisp.
Myself: Yeah! Eat more of that! Hurry before other people eat it all! Go back up and get more just in case!
Me: Nah, one small piece is enough.
Myself: No it isn&apos;t!
Me: I am full, and you know what, this naan is not as good as I remembered it. I don&apos;t want anymore.
Myself: HA!!! YOU WENT OFF YOUR DIET!! YOU&apos;RE OFF PLAN!
Me: Hmmmm.
Myself: You screwed up! Failure! Hey, remember those cookies and brownies and stuff at that bakery??
Me: Um, yeah. Yum ...
Myself: Now that you&apos;re off plan, you may as well go there and get something! Just a brownie, a slice of cake, a few cookies...
Me: Maybe. Maybe I will do that. I AM off plan already...
Myself: Yeah, go have what you want and start fresh tomorrow. Today is ruined anyway.
Me: Ruined? No, wait, today is not ruined...
Myself: Yes it is, screw up!
Me: If I went to that bakery I don&apos;t know what I&apos;d get.
Myself: A cookie dipped in chocolate and pecans!
Me: No, actually, those are probably sort of dry and crumbly under the chocolate, and I don&apos;t like that kind of cookie...
Myself: A nanaimo bar, then.
Me: Ugh, no, that&apos;s so sugary and greasy I think it would make me sick.
Myself: That chocolate cup with mousse in it!
Me: Nah, if I get one of those I want to share it with my kids
Myself: A brownie then, or heck, just get 5 things and take a bite of each and only eat the best one!
Me: (sigh) Ya know, nothing there would taste very good anyway.
Myself: Are you NUTS?
Me: I am fine. I had ONE piece of naan the size of a small slice of bread, there is nothing immoral about that.
Myself: Ugh! Shut up, go get a cheesecake!
Me: Nah, I am fine. I really just want to go home.
Myself: Well then just get some dark chocolate!
Me: No, I am okay. I am going home and staying on plan.

(exit, went home, stayed on plan)

 
 Tomato Pickers’ Struggle Coming to a Grocery Store Near You 
 [ Healthcare ] ( AFL-CIO NOW BLOG )
   The fight for justice for tomato pickers is headed to grocery store aisles across the country now that the top three food service companies and the four largest fast-food companies have signed agreements to improve wages and working conditions in the Florida tomato fields. The Coalition of Immokalee Workers (CIW) announced earlier this week that Sodexo, the largest food service company in the nation, had agreed to pay an additional 1.5 cents for every pound of Florida tomatoes it p ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
       

The fight for justice for tomato pickers is headed to grocery store aisles across the country now that the top three food service companies and the four largest fast-food companies have signed agreements to improve wages and working conditions in the Florida tomato fields.

The Coalition of Immokalee Workers ( CIW ) announced earlier this week that Sodexo, the largest food service company in the nation, had agreed to pay an additional 1.5 cents for every pound of Florida tomatoes it purchases, with the extra money going directly to the harvesters.

At least 30,000 immigrant farm workers in Florida pick 95 percent of the nation’s tomato crop between October and June. The workers are demanding safer, more humane working conditions and a penny more per pound of tomatoes picked. Florida tomato pickers earn 45 cents for a 32-pound bucket of tomatoes, a rate that has not changed for three decades.

Sodexo joins a growing list of companies that have signed agreements with CIW, including Aramark , Compass Group North America , Bon Appetit Management Co., Subway , Taco Bell and its corporate parent, Yum ! Brands, McDonald’s , Burger King Whole Foods Market and the Chipotle Mexican Grill restaurant chain.

 

CIW spokesperson Lucas Benitez said:
 
Together with Sodexo and our other partners, we are building a system of real accountability, with tangible consequences for growers who fail to protect farm workers’ basic rights. It is our belief that such accountability, with worker input, will be the foundation for lasting improvements in the industry.
 
The farm workers’ focus now has shifted to the supermarket industry. WalMart, which alone sells 25 percent of all food sold in U.S. grocery stores, along with the Publix , Ahold and Kroger supermarket chains, have tremendous market power in the produce industry. And as an Immokalee press release says:
 
 …with great power comes great responsibility—both for the poverty and brutal working conditions from which they have profited for so many years, and for the work of reforming farm labor conditions in their supply chains that lies ahead.
 
 Tuesday, Lazy Day 
 [ Barbados ] ( Beautiful Barbados )
Tuesday, August 24: Another early rise for me, anyway. I woke up at 8 with the sun streaming in. Made some coffee, wrote a little bit. The gardeners cut down some of the foliage that I liked the other day. Tom likes it better – we can see the sea better again. I liked the jungle feel, though. By the time Tom had finished his morning work we decided to go to breakfast at the new Italian restaurant here. The paperwork said that they were open until 11. Turned out, they were only open un ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Tuesday, August 24:

Another early rise for me, anyway. I woke up at 8 with the sun streaming in. Made some coffee, wrote a little bit. The gardeners cut down some of the foliage that I liked the other day. Tom likes it better – we can see the sea better again. I liked the jungle feel, though.

By the time Tom had finished his morning work we decided to go to breakfast at the new Italian restaurant here. The paperwork said that they were open until 11. Turned out, they were only open until 10, then at noon for lunch. We could have gone to L&apos;Azure but I knew that their buffet ended at 11 and I didn&apos;t want to get all the left-overs so we decided to go shopping instead.

We headed out to Six Roads, near Emerald City and the Chefette from the other night. The highway we usually take had a roadworks sign up so we circled the roundabout again and got off at highway 5 instead. That way to go is a little longer but prettier and goes by the Four Square Rum Distillery. That&apos;s a great place to go for tours and info on the rum process. A bit easier to get to from here than Mount Gay!

We got out to the ABC highway – named for 3 important past politicians from here: Tom Adams, Errol Barrow and Gordon Cummings. Each has his own named section of the road.

Then, along the Spring Garden to Holetown where we were going to another Cave Shepherd for that ellusive bathing suit. They had one – hooray! We also went into a tshirt store where they had a cute dress. They showed both the LP (Local price) and the DF (Duty Free price). Big difference – $24 US DF and $43.50 US LP. Luckily we were able to get the DF price.

From there we headed back home. We tried to take the road that had been closed out of Six Roads and we got close but there was a long detour. Of course, there was just the one detour sign with no further instruction. We did find our way and went just past our place to a newish restaurant called Cutters. Cutter is the Bajan word for sandwich. This restaurant is owned and operated by the husband of someone we&apos;ve known for a long time here at The Crane and its nice to see them doing well.

While waiting for our food, Tom took the opportunity to check his email (as usual!)

I had a flying fish cutter. Yum my! I&apos;ve never heard of any other place in the world that has flying fish. It&apos;s an interesting phenomenon to see, a school of fish flying/gliding through the air, all shimmery. They have a wonderful hot sauce to put on things here, made with Scotch bonnet peppers. I used some – sparingly. Yum ! We actually bought a bottle to take home once but I never used it. Nothing at home seemed like it was suited to the hot sauce like flying fish is.

Back home for a little nap. When I woke up, I started taking pictures of the newly trimmed gallery when I came upon a little rainbow. I took these pictures but within 2 minutes, according to the timestamp, the rainbow was gone.

 

(Click on the image to view all today&apos;s pictures, please. But only if you&apos;re interested!)

Off to Reception to update webpages, blog and so on then we sat outside for a bit and just talked.

This year is nice. No plans (yet), no people to show around, no place we have to be. Just relaxing and being calm. I like this! Usually by now we&apos;d have plans drawn up for the whole time. Where to be on what day, things to do, scheduled conference calls. How nice to leave all that behind for a few weeks and just chill.


I think it&apos;s about time for a bit of “Kristine&apos;s” rum punch now! 
 Helpful Singapore Information (from Andrea) 
 [ Singapore ] ( my life in Singapore )
My friend Andrea has a great blog (click here) with loads of interesting information too .. one of her more popular blog posts was about Helpful Singapore Information. I tried to do a direct posting across, but not possible so here it is as a Copy and Paste: Helpful Singapore InformationThis is intended to be a starting place for those new to Singapore. You will undoubtedly find many more options as you go on your adventures and probably some you like better but we understand what it’s lik ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   My friend Andrea has a great blog (click here) with loads of interesting information too ..... one of her more popular blog posts was about Helpful Singapore Information. 
 I tried to do a direct posting across, but not possible so here it is as a Copy and Paste:


 Helpful Singapore Information 
 This is intended to be a starting place for those new to Singapore. You will undoubtedly find many more options as you go on your adventures and probably some you like better but we understand what it’s like to be clueless for those first few weeks. Some information is from personal experience and some is by recommendation. Feel free to comment with any helpful information you might find and we will update as we make new discoveries.

Ann Maroni – Incredible Real Estate Agent!! http://www.homeequity.com.sg/AnnMaroni.htm 

Money Exchange Rates: http://www.xe.com/ 

American Association links - http://www.aasingapore.com/en/cms/?68 

American Women’s Association – http://www.awasingapore.org/  (really great for local tours and the only reason I joined, honestly)

(even if you’re not American, you might find some of these links helpful) Useful links from AWA site – http://www.awasingapore.org/resources.html 

 www.gothere.sg  – this is incredible for finding your way anywhere and using any form of transportation.

 http://www.singaporesights.com/ 

 http://www.nparks.gov.sg/cms/ 

 http://www.ura.gov.sg/  Urban Redevelopment Authority – This site will give yo info about gov’t housing, parking, and other interesting things about the city of Singapore in terms of building and planning. You can visit the city gallery as well.

 http://www.ura.gov.sg/gallery/mainS4_PlanVisit.html 

 Also, be sure to check the comments on this page. There is a wealth of information down there! 
 Traffic&amp;Parking Info: http://www.onemotoring.com.sg/publish/onemotoring/en/on_the_roads.html 

 Some parking lots are coupon lots. You can purchase coupon books at 7 Elevens and you’ll use these for 30 minute intervals by punching out the date and time you will be there. 

 Postal Service:  http://www.singpost.com.sg/  main page 

 http://www.singpost.com/singpost_01consumer.htm   -consumer page, tells you where post offices are and where SAM’s are. Automated stations to buy stamps and weigh packages. Seems you need a NETS card at these machines. Maybe some take cash but the one we found didn’t. We have a ‘mom and pop’ store in a condo next to us that sells stamps and will mail letters so check your nearby condo’s, it’s very handy!  S$1.10 for a standard letter and S$.50 for a postcard. 

 http://www.singpost.com/quick_services/quicks_03postal_02overseas01.htm  -int’l airmail postage rates 

 Utilities: 
Our agent set up our electricity and water for us so I’m not sure how to go about that. Check with your agent about getting gas canisters changed for water and stove if applicable.

 Starhub : cable/broadband/land lines. You can get a decent package deal. It’s nothing like American cable, though, so do some research online before setting it up.

 M1 : cell phones – great cell phone plans for families to call 3 for free within M1 users. M1 also provides broadband and is cheaper for cell phone customers than Starhub. You might run into a conflict with not having enough cable/broadband ports in your place or ports not in the right place for your set up. Starhub will install more for a fee.

 Singtel : cell phones. Probably the most popular in Singapore.
For about $100 SGD you can get a cheapo phone with a “top up” card. You get a number and a sim card and add minutes to it whenever you need more. After the initial fee you will just pay to top up your card.

M1&amp;Singtel both have an international plan for about $5/month where you can call a prefix and it only uses your minutes to call certain countries and does not charge international calling charges.

Online”garage sales”:
 http://singapore.craigslist.com.sg/ 
 http://singapore.gumtree.sg/ 
 http://classifieds.mocca.com/ 
You can also find items for sale on bulletin boards at many grocery stores.

 Meat: 
 Chicken Man (Mr. Wee) 9139 2189 – Delivers fresh chicken. Minimum order is $30, about 15 butterfly, boneless, skinless chicken breasts. You can get whole chickens and really any parts of the chicken you’d like. He can also get you other meats (no beef) and fruits and vegies if you like. Very nice people and easy to communicate with.

 QB Foods – GREAT place to get frozen sausages, all cuts of beef, pork, fish, etc. and other miscellaneous grocery items. Everything is either fresh or frozen so you can put it right into your freezer. They sell wholesale to stores around Singapore but are open to the public in a small store in their warehouse.

 Ben Foods - Meat, wine, etc. Only open to the public from 10-12 on Saturdays. This is our weekly Saturday stop. Ben Foods also supplies to Singapore stores. The things that are available on the weekends vary as they are clearing for next weeks stock.

 Note about meat : Most thawed meat in stores has come to them frozen and then thawed so you must use it within a few days or cook it up and then freeze it.  Mr. Wee delivers only fresh meat so it can go right into your freezer. Grocery stores will advertise if it needs to be used in 3 days or if it’s fresh. If it’s not clearly marked, I would assume it’s been thawed and you should use it soon.

 Food Delivery: 
 Madrina Pizzaria (no website) 6474 7342 They only deliver to certain areas. Thin crust pizza, fresh ingredients, pastas, salads and desserts. Their large pizza is equivalent to about a US medium and it’s thin crust so they don’t stretch as far. Eat in here too if you can. The atmosphere is nice and quiet and food is much better hot out of the oven. Blk 3 #02-141 Queen’s Road(Farrer Rd). Remember you can look it up on www.gothere.sg .

 Canadian Pizza  - our favorite. Comparable to Domino’s in the US.

 http://www.mcdonalds.com.sg/ 

 http://www.pizzahut.com.sg/  - we didn’t like Pizza Hut’s cheese but they stay in business so they must sell to someone.

 http://www.dominos.com/home/index.jsp  - ahhhh…. a little piece of America brought to your doorstep in less than 30 minutes. If you have one near you, that is. They have only been in Singapore for less than a year so they aren’t serving the whole island yet.

 http://www.pastamania.com.sg/ 

 http://www.hungrygowhere.com/ – find a restaurant by cuisine, location, etc.

 Grocery Shopping: Be sure to have a $1 coin handy. You’ll need this coin in most stores to unlock your shopping cart. You get it back when you return the cart. I personally think this is brilliant!

My newest FAVORITE place for fresh produce and dried good is Pasir Panjang Wholesale Centre . It’s where the locals shop and a real budget booster! I think they’re closed on Mondays. Nuts, dried fruit, dried fish, and any kind of fresh off he boat produce you can imagine. Buy in bulk or in small quantities. Parking is available for cheap and there’s a bus stop right outside of the gate.

 http://www.carrefour.com.sg/  – Compared to Walmart. There’s one at Plaza Singapura and Suntec City. Delivers if you spend over $150. Take cold stuff or things that might melt home with you and set up delivery for the rest. If you purchase before 3pm your goods will be delivered same afternoon, otherwise it will be the next day. Tell them when you check out if you want delivery. You will pay and then go to the delivery counter to fill out a form. Then you walk away. It’s a little awkward at first try but they really do show up with your things.

 http://www.fairprice.com.sg  – One of the main grocery store chains here. I’m told that with both Cold Storage and Fair Price, if they are in a nicer location, the prices are higher because their rent is more. I have found really good bargains at both Fair Price and Cold Storage so it’s worth checking both if you have the time. Our favorite is Fair Price Finest in Bukit Timah Plaza. Convenient parking and it’s a two level store with good prices and most everything you’ll need. There is also a Fair Price Extra in Jurong East Mall. I have not been but I hear it’s great. I think Fair Price delivers but not sure. Check it out, though.

 http://www.coldstorage.com.sg  – The other main grocery store chain. Cold Storage delivers and you can order online. They have specific delivery times and I think you have to spend over $150 or $200 for free delivery. I haven’t used their delivery service yet. Cold Storage is where I would go first if I need something from the US. They tend to cater to expats.

I’m told that most locals shop at NTUC (Fair Price) or go to Malaysia once or twice a month to stock up.

There are local shops called wet markets where you can get fresh fish/meat and vegetables. There is one at China Town, Ghim Moh, Tekka Market in Little India is a really big one. If you don’t want to purchase bulk in the market, there are smaller shops just across the street on Buffalo where you can buy just the amount you need. Still fresh. These are great places to go in the morning and get fresh vegies, fruits and meats. If you find a vendor you like, stick with them. Once they get to know you, they might just save you the good stuff. Even if you don’t like to shop at these you should visit them. Makes for great stories and photos.

My new favorite market is Pasir Panjang Wholesale Market .

There is another big grocery store called Giant . It is referred to as Malaysia’s Walmart. One is in the Bukit Timah area at Turf City (if you go there, be sure to try the Indian Lime Juice at Curry Garden), VivoCity Mall has a really huge store, another at IMM Mall and the other is on the East side of the island, Tampines. They will deliver if you purchase over S$200. Take the cold stuff with you. Some have free parking. One even has a pig organ eatery. Yum ! 


 Mustafa is in Little India. The prices on some items are not much better than the local stores but they have quite a variety of products and are a one stop shop! For sure, buy your dried beans, spices and rice there. So cheap!! Food, health care, toiletries, American products, sporting equipment, clothing, shoes, outdoor equipment, electronics, office/school supplies, appliances, jewelry, etc. If you need something and can’t find it, this is the place to go. Weekends are crazy crowded. Weekdays are much better! They are open 24/7. If you get out on the Farrer MRT station take the C exit , look to your left and you should see the Mustafa sign. Mustafa will only deliver larger electronic items for a $20 fee. (You can get a great henna tattoo in Little India Arcade on the other end of Serangoon closer to Bukit Timah, across from Tekka Market.  Both hands for around S$10. Be sure to check the 2nd level of Tekka Market for clothing and other goodies. ) 

 Phoon Huat:  is an incredible store!! Any type of baking item you need is there. Sugar, flour, sprinkles, pans, disposable containers, frozen fruit, cream cheese by the kilo, shortening, pastry doughs, nuts… You name it and it’s there for a very good price! If you bake, you must go there.

 Malaysia shopping is great as well and pretty easy to get to. Here’s a link to a friends blog who gives you a step by step guide on how to get there.

 Batam, Indonesia - short ferry ride and really easy day trip but recently they changed the tourist visa so it’s not as much of a bargain as it used to be. It’s still a great “date day” or fun day with the girls or even a long weekend.

 Shopping-General: 
 Costume Rentals: Hey, you never know when this will come in handy!
No. 1 Costume Shop
7 Jln Lembah Kallang, Singapore, 339563
6333 9440
Out on the East side of town, Tampines (pronounced tam pu neeze), there is a huge IKEA, Courts Mega Store, and a large Giant store all together. There’s also a Courts in Bukit Timah area and and Ikea on Alexandra (Queensway area). Good place to go to price shop for furniture and electronics and groceries and/or stock up.

 Furniture:   Ikea (very large one with more selection in Tampines, smaller one (but still big) on Alexandra. Prices are very reasonable and some is cheaper than in the US.), Harvey Norman Home, Barang Barang (a bit pricey but nice), I Wanna Go Home (neat store! Cross between Kirkland’s and Pier 1 Imports in US), Courts Mega Store. And of course, the online “garage sales” listed above. There’s a store in Turf City that has some beautiful furniture and will custom make things for you along with many other places around Singapore. We’ll update this as new discoveries are made.

 http://www.justanthony.com/  - larger pieces – huge facility We recently purchased our dream dining table here. Great place!

 http://www.chinacollection.com.sg/ 
Jane’s Art and Crafts – smaller pieces, antiques, etc.
75 Hillcrest Rd, 288948, Singapore
p: 64695920 f: 64688992

 Electronics : Gain, Best, Parasilk, Mustafa, Harvey Norman, Court, Giant. Fu Nan Digital Mall is a good place for electronics and cameras. Sim Lim is where the locals say to go but you will need to know exactly what you are looking for and what it should cost. Bring your bargaining skills to Sim Lim. It is said that the higher you go up in the center, the cheaper the prices will be. This is a good place to get replacement power supplies for the US electronics that you might burn up. You can pretty much find any type of electronic device here. Also, the first hour of parking is free between 5&amp;10 pm on any day including weekends and holidays. If you bring your tv to Singapore from another country you may need to buy a tv license. We purchased our tv’s here so the license comes with them so I’m not sure how that works. Just ask around. Sounds strange, I know, but it’s true.

 Washers : We understand that top loading washers do not heat water. Since most washers do not hook up to hot water supply, the washer needs to heat water so be sure and ask if you are shopping.Also check to make sure what type of washing powder you need. Most front loaders need low suds detergent. 

 DVD players : If you have American dvd’s, you’ll either need to purchase a multi-region player or “region free” player. It is hard to make sure you are getting this because the salesmen tell you “can!” so do your research. We use our PS3 or laptop if necessary for our US dvd’s and bought a multi-region player (recoded) at Parasilk in Holland Village for our extra tv in the guest room. Basically, we were told that if a dvd player has been opened then it will work as this means they have opened it and changed the codes. Goes against everything we’re told in the US but he said NOT to buy a dvd player that hasn’t been opened. Crazy! Some dvd players that are cheaper probably can’t be recoded so be sure to ask. (After being here or several months now, we have found that we prefer to get our movies from the US and either brought over or mailed to us (media postage rate is pretty cheap). Since we watch most movies through our PS3, it’s just better to have American Region movies.) 

 Turf City Mall is a great place to eat, shop and get groceries or even buy a car. :) This mall has quite a mix of quality and inexpensive items. It’s not all that easy to find your way around but you could spend quite a bit of time here and find most of what you might need. Free parking and Wifi!! Try the Indian Fried Rice, a Tissue Prata and an Indian Lime Juice at Curry Gardenn. It’s really good!! The Giant grocery store is at this mall. Fidgets play area is also here and it’s great for younger kids to roam and play and for parents to have a good cup of coffee or snack.

 Novena has two shopping centers right outside of the MRT. Square 2 and Velocity . They connect with each other and it is very convenient to step out of the MRT and right into the malls without having to go outside. Plenty of food and shops to keep you busy for a while. There is a Fair Price at the top of the Square 2 side (Level 4) and a Cold Storage in the Velocity side (Level 1).

 United Square (take MRT to Novena, exit toward United Square) has lots of children’s clothing stores, toy stores, and baby goods stores.  There is also a McDonald’s, Pizza Hut. They are more reasonably priced than Paragon. It connects underground. Pretty easy walk. If you end up missing meat (which we do), Fiesta Brasilia is a great buffet for really good meat and salad bar. It’s a little pricey but for a special outing, it’s worth it.

 City Square is my current favorite mall. It is a new mall in Little India. Take the MRT and come out of the Farrer Park Station right into the mall. Great mall with tons of options and more Western sized items and good prices. And it’s just not as “expat” as others around which I tend to like. The Metro store there is super!

 Queensway shopping center is great for sporting goods but you really need to shop around from store to store. Stores have the same items for different prices. There are all sorts of shops tucked away in corners in this mall so be sure and wander around. When you go there, follow your nose and try the fresh hot waffle with ice cream in the middle. Or even better, kaya. A green jelly/paste that tastes mildly like coconut and vanilla. Oh yum !

 Orchard Rd./Scotts Rd. area is ALL shopping and eating and very crowded on the weekends. It’s pretty much survival of the fittest but you should experience it even if you don’t plan to buy anything. Walk tall and stand your ground with a smile on your face. When you get hot outside, there’s always a cool place to step into.

 Paragon (on Orchard Road) has a small kid’s indoor play area near Toys R Us and lots of kid’s clothing shops. There is a great dumpling place, Din Tai Fung, in the basement food area of Paragon. Din Tai Fung is in our top three favorites.

 Wheelock Place has a lot to do in that area for teens. Borders, Starbucks, movie theater nearby (make reservations online for movies), shopping. This is also in the Orchard area so the malls and food options are numerous and within walking distance.

 Far East and Lucky Plaza are a good if you are more of a bargain shopper and feeling culturally adventurous.

 Tanglin Mall (just off Orchard) has Kindermusik and a Gymboree kid’s play/music center and plenty of neat shops. The Chili’s and Dan Ryan’s are in/near this mall. Dan Ryan’s is supposed to have Dr. Pepper when they don’t run out and they both have free refills which is nice! The Tanglin Marketplace also carries Dr. Pepper( when they have it in stock.)

 Marina Square (Marina Center?) mall has an indoor kids play area close to the Gain Electronics store. There are also quite a few kids’ stores here. It’s a huge mall with lots of eating and shopping options. This one is close to the Singapore Flyer and Esplanade area and the new Helix Bridge which is a beautiful area to explore at night.

 Plaza Singapura is a great mall for strollers! It’s easy to get to by bus or MRT (Dhoby Ghaut). There is a Carrefour there. Also a $2 store called Daiso and a store similar to Hobby Lobby called Spotlight. Spotlight is a great store for craft items and general household items. They have kid’s shops as well as flat ramp escalators and elevators. Very crowded on the weekend but weekday is okay.

 Great World City is a less crowded mall with a good variety of shops, places to eat and coffee. There is also a Cold Storage.

 Ngee Ann City mall is HUGE and it also is near to Wisma Atria . Lots of food options and shopping. Ngee Ann City is a bit pricey. Wisma is more realistic. Bargains can be found just about anywhere if you’re willing to look.

 Kinokuniya –Huge bookstore in the Takashimaya center. It’s in Ngee Ann City mall on Orchard Road. Takashimaya also is a HUGE department store and can find most anything there. Mostly pricey but you can find a bargain. Popular and Borders are other bookstores here. There are also used bookstores around the city for trade in’s or finding that random book that the bigger bookstores might not carry. I know there’s one in Holland Village above Cold Storage. We have also ordered from  http://www.amazon.co.uk/ and the shipping fees and delivery time is very reasonable.

 VivoCity – supposedly the largest mall in Singapore. We went there to eat and did not walk around much. Sensory overload for us. It felt like we were in an American mall. It’s on the water and is very beautiful. You can see Sentosa Island entrance from there and there is space outside for kids to run and play. Again, we were there for dinner and it was beautiful at night time.

 IMM Somerset – the newest mall to date and a great place to shop and eat and convenient to bus and MRT. The Food Republic there is fabulous and there are some neat shops. Prices to please all pocket books can be found.

 Jurong Point – West Coast. Massive mall with a theatre, restaurant s and plenty of shopping to please everyone. STep out of the MRT station and into the mall. Super convenient.

 Parkway Parade – East Coast. Terrific mall with all banks, all major grocery store options and plenty of shops and eateries.

The malls are plentiful here!!! You’ll have to do some searching on your own and find out what you like. There are definitely areas that you can tell cater to wealthy expats and they are more expensive but there are places to shop that don’t cost you an arm and a leg either. They just take a bit more searching sometimes.

Be sure to explore the HDB’s and condo’s near you. Salons, clothings stores, local food, grocery stores and other gems are often found tucked away inside.

 Go to gothere.sg to find all of these locations. 

 Hair cuts: 
 Kids: Junior League Children’s Style Salon. They have one in United Square and one in the Toys R Us at VivoCity. And Fantastic Sams in The Forum on Orchard. Jonathon came recommended.
 Men: Summerview in the Serene Centre (2nd floor, at Bukit Timah and Adam/Farrer Road– above the McDonalds&amp;where Tierney’s gourmet grocery store is. There are a $10/10 minute shops all over town, Plaza Singapura, Holland Village and really all over the country. They do a decent job and is where my husband and son go. If you’re picky, you don’t go there. They pretty much have a universal cut.
 Women:  My daughter and I go to a shop called D’lly ( Sally, 9479 8791) in Pandan Valley Condo facing Holland Road/Ulu Pandan. There are salons tucked away all over the island. As you settle in start asking your new friends where they go. This is how we found D’lly. Other recommendations: Casey’s in the Palais Renaissance on Orchard Road. Comes recommended but hear it’s pricey. Amy Chee was recommended for a good stylist/colorist. There are Toni&amp;Guy shops everywhere but I find them too pricey.

 Trips/Entertainment: 
Movie Theater – http://tickets.cathay.com.sg/index.aspx 

Going to the movie in Singapore – http://www.expatsingapore.com/content/view/1091  This link also has other theaters listed and info about the movie/dinner experience.

 Wild Wild Wet – inexpensive water park compared to US parks. More fun for smaller children but our family of 5 with two older teens really enjoyed it for a couple of hours. This one costs about S$50/family.

 Jurong East Water Park – among others… find one near you. Facilities  and rates, etc.
The Singapore government offers these great water parks that would equal parks in the US for a fraction of the cost of what we would pay in the US. You can go to these water parks for about S$5/family!

 Singapore Zoo – we’ve been told to go in the afternoon/evening when it’s cooler. We’ve also been told that about 5 hours would be a good time to cover the entire zoo.

 Night Safari – nice and we found it worth the money.

You can get package memberships for Zoo/Night Safari/Bird Park, etc. http://www.zoo.com.sg/ 

 Merlion – famous Singapore landmark. City Hall MRT and then start asking where Merlion is.   It’s beautiful and you can find a place to eat on the water and/or enjoy a cup of coffee outdoors or indoors. Very pretty in the evening when everything is lit up. You can also take the Singapore River Cruise from Clark Quay to get a great tour of this area. Beautiful at night time.

 Singapore Flyer – Great! A little expensive but definitely worth it once. Beautiful views even with the current construction. Take your camera.

 Sentosa Island - You can make this a day trip or stay for the weekend. We haven’t been but apparently it’s geared more for tourists.

 http://www.forestadventure.com.sg/  - We haven’t been here yet but it comes recommended.

 Botanic Gardens – a definite must! It’s free to enter the main portion and only $5 for the Orchid Garden which is totally worth it! Go a little later for cooler weather but you might want to take a little mosquito spray. There are food and drink stops within reach and even a hawker center in the park.

 Singapore City Gallery – http://www.ura.gov.sg/gallery/mainS4_PlanVisit.html  Set up by the Urban Redevelopment Authority. If you’re curious about the skyline, buildings, and seeing a “small” scale birds eye view of Singapore, this is your place.

There are many museums to visit as well.

Visit this blog http://millysmix.blogspot.com/ for day trip and outing ideas especially if you have young children. You can do a search so you don’t have to read the entire blog. Another very helpful blog is my friend, Leone’s.  She’s an awesome photographer and has been super helpful in getting me around Singapore and Asia.

Of course, there are endless sights to see in Singapore and nearby! Again, visit www.gothere.sg to find out how to get there. All of these can be found on the internet as well for pricing and hours.

 Vacation spots: 

I will add to this as we take more trips. We have already been to  Bintan, Indonesia (Nirwana Resort) and really enjoyed that. We’ve made it to Batam, Indonesia for a day trip. It’s an easy ferry ride and good for a day adventure. We took an 8 day trip to Pokhara, Nepal which is hands down our favorite so far. Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam for Christmas.  Johor Bahru, Malaysia for a day shopping trip. That’s an easy bus ride over. Bangkok, Thailand was a fun 4 day trip. Budget airlines, Jetstar, Tiger Airways, Silk Air, are always running specials and it’s super cheap to get around Asia and even parts of Australia with them.

Travel from Singapore is very easy and can be done on a tight budget. Before we moved here, we felt it would be a shame if we didn’t go and see the world around us while we were here, so we have just made that a priority for our family. Of course, there’s so much to do in Singapore too. We want to experience Singapore and all it has to offer as well. It’s amazing how much is here for having such small land mass. There are many underground and above ground worlds to explore.

 Churches: I’m going to leave this blank because probably everyone would agree on a good price for a box of cereal but everyone needs to search out churches on their own. I will say, though, that there are some great churches here in probably every denomination and some you may not have ever heard of. The internet is a great place to start and then just start asking around. Ok, I’ll tell you… we go to Redemption Hill Church . 


 Schools: Same as churches. You really will need to dig around for what you are looking for. Our oldest goes to ISS (International School Singapore). And we are homeschooling our youngest. Choose the school that you think is best suited for your children, they are all good in their ways. It seems as if many people move around a bit.

This listing will be updated as necessary. Last update was on June 21, 2010.

There are always a lot of places new to try and not so easy to keep an updated list ..... but the above should help some of the new people that have just arrived for the new year in town.

If you are looking for something in particular, try GOOGLE , if not feel free to email us - we will do our best to help.
 
 THANKS ANDREA!! 

 
 Yarra Valley - The Best Place on Earth..... 
 [ Malaysia , India ] ( Asian Correspondent: Global Feed )
It is early morning here in the Yarra Valley. It is cold outside (about 5 degrees!) and there is a slight mist in the air giving the landscape a picture perfect, fairytale beauty. This is now my home where I have lived for the last 20 years and where my husband Steve Webber and I look after the Yarra Valley winery for our family. The Yarra Valley is located about 40 km north east of Melbourne, which is Australia’s most Southern mainland city. It is Victoria’s oldest wine region, wit ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 

 It is early morning here in the Yarra Valley. It is cold outside (about 5 degrees!) and there is a slight mist in the air giving the landscape a picture perfect, fairytale beauty. This is now my home where I have lived for the last 20 years and where my husband Steve Webber and I look after the Yarra Valley winery for our family. 

 The Yarra Valley is located about 40 km north east of Melbourne, which is Australia’s most Southern mainland city. It is Victoria’s oldest wine region, with over 4000 hectares under vine and one of the most visited wine regions in Australia. There aren’t many vineyard regions where just one hour from the middle of a city you find yourself in a stunningly beautiful landscape. 

 There were just 16 wineries in the Yarra Valley when my family purchased this vineyard in 1987. Steve and I were living in Coonawarra when my brother Darren asked us if we would like to manage the Yarra Valley project with the goal to establish a premium wine brand for the company in a prestigious cool-climate region. 

 By 1990, our Winery&amp; restaurant / cellar door complex had been built to launch the new De Bortoli Yarra Valley label. Today the De Bortoli Winery&amp; Locale Restaurant is one of the premier wine and food attractions in the Yarra Valley with recent accolades including the 2008 and 2009 Best Tourism Winery in the Qantas Australian tourism Awards. More importantly to us though, it is a place that people can come to discover the joy of wine in a very convivial environment. Good food, good company and great wines. Isn’t that what life is about? 

 We can show you why the Yarra Valley is the best place why on earth - watch video 

 If you have been to the Yarra Valley I would be happy to hear of some of your experiences. If not, some of my recommendations are: 

 

 
 Healesville Hotel: a great place for a quick bar meal or for finer dining in the restaurant 
 

 
 Giant Steps Innocent Bystander : big bustling place to enjoy pizza with a glass of wine but my highlight would have to be their very tasty sourdough bread. In the days our restaurant is closed, I&apos;ll often zip ove r to Healesville to buy a loaf or two of their bread. Yum yum . 
 

 
 De Bortoli Cheese Shop: Yeah, I know its ours but this collaboration with Richard Thomas has resulted in beautifully matured cheese which we can offer to visitors. Also Richard and our staff can advise on some pretty interesting cheese and wine matchings too 
 

 
 TarraWarra Museum of Art: The TWMA was built by the Bensen Family some years ago and is a showcase of the Bensen&apos;s contemporary Australian art collection as well as visiting art exhibitions. The architecture of this wonderful building is worth the visit on its own.  
 

 
 Na tskin Dayspa : Well, a girl has to pamper herself every now and again. Situated at Balgownie, Mecure Hotel is the place to go for a manicure or massage or both.   
 

 
 Healesville Sanctuary:   Got kids? Well look no further than this place to while away a few hours. All manner of Australia flora and fauna can be found here and is well worth the visit, even without kids.
 
 
 Balloon Flight : Want to do something a little different? Take a float over the valley and vineyards with Global Ballooning. Memorable. 
 
 

 

 S o why not come and see us sometime, and look at the world through a Rosé-coloured glass! 

 

 

 Cheers, Leanne 

 Follow Leanne on Twitter@DeBortoliWines and visit us at www.debortoli.com.au 

 

 
 

   Pinot Noir Rose on the back deck 
 

 
... 
 A vegan in Paris, part one! 
 [ Vegan ] ( Alltop RSS )
I am excited to announce that my broke college ass ended up in Paris for a whopping two weeks before my semester in the even less-vegan-friendly Prague [Ed.: For more advice on visiting vegan Prague, check out Melisser’s chronicles.] And to every asshole in my life that told me I would have to give up veganism to enjoy Paris: t’es un putain de merde. It’s helpful that I have a two-burner stove kitchenette with the appropriate accoutrements, but I’ve found it easy as hell to eat in lovely ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
I am excited to announce that my broke college ass ended up in Paris for a whopping two weeks before my semester in the even less-vegan-friendly Prague [Ed.: For more advice on visiting vegan Prague, check out Melisser’s chronicles . ] And to every asshole in my life that told me I would have to give up veganism to enjoy Paris: t’es un putain de merde . It’s helpful that I have a two-burner stove kitchenette with the appropriate accoutrements, but I’ve found it easy as hell to eat in lovely vegan(-friendly) restaurant s. Oh, and the baguettes are vegan, and probably the most important food group ever. Here are a few suggestions:

 Saveurs Végét’Halles 
41 rue des Bourdonnais
Open daily 11:30 a.m. to 3 p.m. and 5 to 11 p.m.
Saveurs Végét’Halles ( get it? ) is an adorable little mostly-vegan restaurant in the heart of Paris. The cuisine is described on HappyCow as having an “Oriental feel”, and I agree with that sentiment. For about 18,90€ you can get the dîner formule : an entrée (starter), a plat principal, and a dessert. There’s a cheaper with one fewer dish, but you’re in Paris! Go big or go home. I opted for the salade mixte aux coeurs de palmiers (salad with hearts of palm), assiette légumes vapeur minute (steamed veggies with a tofu chive sauce and some mashed peas), and crumble aux pommes (apple crumble YUM ). Here’s the photos (the lighting inside was mood lighting, not so great for food lighting).

 
The salad was a salad; there isn’t wasn’t any special dressing beyond vinegar and oil, but it was well balanced and full of fresh and yum my veggies. The main course was exactly what I was in the mood for: really filling and satisfying food that feels  healthy. Unfortunately, some of the veggies weren’t steamed properly, especially the carrots. The tofu-chive sauce was delicious, and tasted great with everything on the plate. 

The crumble aux pommes was the star of the meal. I’m definitely one of those bitches who will melt for any apples prepared with cinnamon (gimme that shit over chocolate for V-day any day), and I have to say, as an apple-crisp lover, I’ve never had it accompanied with a raspberry coulis! INGENIOUS. They took two amazing fruits and put them on the same plate. LOVED IT GIMME MORE.

 Le Potager du Marais 
22 rue Rambuteau
Open daily noon to midnight; last seating/reservation at 10:30 p.m.
Le Potager du Marais, which specializes in French cuisine, is definitely one of those fancy-shmancy places you do not go for a casual lunch (like I did). It’s super-tiny with limited seating, so they recommend making reservations (as I went lunchtime, I didn’t bother). My lunch, a plat and dessert, cost 24€. For lunch. For just me. It’s pricey as fuck, but again, GO BIG OR GO HOME. Here’s the rundown on this place: beautiful atmosphere, nice music choices and volume, and a really friendly, eager-to-please waitstaff. You get what you pay for I guess.

I ordered a cassoulet de la mer gratinée aux noisettes (16€), which on the menu was described as a type of casserole with smoked tofu, mashed peas, bits of seaweed, and topped with crushed hazelnuts (to balance out the mushy texture). Flavor-wise, I felt the casserole was a little on the bland side. However, it was so rich and the texture was spot-on, I finished every last morsel. It was also served with an impressive side-salad, with a wide assortment of lettuces and sprouts and perfectly julienned carrots.

For dessert, I got a Tarte Tatin et Chantilly à la crème d’amandes (8€). Arguably the most beautiful looking dessert offered, it fell far short of being yum my. I was expecting a really sweet and rich end to my meal, and instead got a slightly bitter fruit topping with a difficult-to-cut-with-a-fork pastry bottom. I so wish I had gone with the chocolate mousse.

 Le Quartier Juif in Marais 
Rue des Rosiers between rue Vielle du Temple and rue Payenne
 If you are craving some authentic Middle Eastern food and don’t want to pay more than 5€, this stretch of Jewish highway is your place. I got by ordering my falafel in Frebrew, this new pidgin language I started (but not really). I ordered just a plan old pita and falafel, and was assured in two different languages that there was indeed no dairy or eggs in any of the products I was eating. It was soooo yum my, street food at its finest (and a great alternative to Maoz ).

So that’s all for now folks!! More Parisian food porn to come, I promise!

 [all photos by Brianna!] 
 
 Top Chef: Ur Doin&apos; It Wrong (Week 10) 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( DCist )
Whaddya mean I have no idea what I&apos;m doing? Photo from Bravo. Well, we&apos;ve now made it through double-digit episodes in this season of Top Chef. And we&apos;ve done it without resorting to a drinking gameyet. Whatever else one can say about this season, we&apos;ll admit that it&apos;s served up to a lot of classic Top Chef archetypes. Angelo is our villain: cocky, entitled, talented, and with a knack for making everyone hope for him to lose (previous examples include Hung, Stefan and Marcel). Kenny was ou ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Whaddya mean I have no idea what I&apos;m doing? Photo from Bravo. Well, we&apos;ve now made it through double-digit episodes in this season of Top Chef . And we&apos;ve done it without resorting to a drinking game...yet. Whatever else one can say about this season, we&apos;ll admit that it&apos;s served up to a lot of classic Top Chef archetypes.
Angelo is our villain: cocky, entitled, talented, and with a knack for making everyone hope for him to lose (previous examples include Hung, Stefan and Marcel). Kenny was our talented and promising cheftestant who went out early thanks to an executive chef stint on Restaurant Wars (see: Tre and Dale). And then we have Alex. Alex is the contestant that everyone hates. These contestants are never the most talented. Sure, they&apos;ll manage to cook a decent dish at some point, but mostly they survive and advance by being bad, but not the worst. Often, this strategy lands them on the bottom week after week but keeps them in the competition for a while, much to the chagrin of the other chefs (Robin and Lisa are your best previous examples of this phenomenon).

This week&apos;s episode began with pretty much everyone indicating they are ready for Alex to go, most feeling he should have gone last week. Alex himself says that he thinks this is all just people lashing out because Kenny&apos;s gone and they liked Kenny. Oh, Alex. We&apos;re sure you&apos;re right in that people liked Kenny and are sad he&apos;s gone, but we also think they just genuinely don&apos;t like you. One bright spot is Amanda, who says she likes Alex and respects and admires his cooking. Which is fitting since, more often than not, she joins him on the bottom at judges&apos; table.

For this week&apos;s Quickfire, the cheftestants had to cook with a mystery box of ingredients, incorporating every ingredient in the box into the dish. And because this is Top Chef , there&apos;s a twist. As the contestants cook, more mystery boxes showed up with more ingredients that had to be added to the dish. This is also a high-stakes Quickfire, with the winner collecting $10,000. Once that&apos;s announced, we found out from Angelo that his fiancé lives in Russia and he really wants that $10 grand to &quot;get everything worked out with the visa&quot; so he can bring her here. Wow, generally we thought Russian mail-order brides came with free shipping. But seriously though, does $10,000 really equal an automatic visa?

This Quickfire challenge gave the contestants some trouble and had quite a few of them lost. Taking a look at the list of ingredients that the chefs ended up being handed, we&apos;ll concede that this one was tough. Fish, fava beans, hominy, squid, black garlic, ramps, passion fruit, and jicama. Any ideas what to make using all of that? Yep, none here either.

But the most surprising part of the Quickfire was how Angelo, usually all poise and cockiness, just sort of aimlessly wandered through the challenge with no idea what he&apos;s doing and a general sense of &quot;I have no idea what the f*** is happening to me.&quot; And that&apos;s unsettling. We like our Top Chef villains to be extra villain-y and always self-assured. Angelo, you have a role to fill and you need to live up to it.

Tiffany ends up winning the Quickfire, as guest judge Wylie Dufresne chose her flavorful fish stew over Kevin&apos;s crispy rockfish. It&apos;s Tiffany&apos;s second high-stakes Quickfire win, and we&apos;re thinking she&apos;s going to have a pretty awesome wedding now that Top Chef is contributing $20,000 to the occasion.

For this week&apos;s elimination challenge, the chefs engaged in a bit of culinary espionage when they &quot;disguised&quot; a classic dish and head to Langley to serve it to CIA officers and chief Leon Panetta. These kinds of &quot;re-invent a classic&quot; challenges are always fun and a way to see the chefs&apos; creative talents. But we&apos;re a bit worried about this season&apos;s group. They haven&apos;t proven been the most talented creative bunch.

Early on, we saw some problems brewing. Angelo bought frozen puff pastry for his Beef Wellington pizzas. (That worked out so well for other contestants Angelo -- good call!) He wasn&apos;t the only one struggling. Kelly just straight up didn&apos;t know what Kung Pao shrimp is supposed to taste like, so she buys a bottle of pre-made Kung Pao sauce to check the ingredient list. Smart girl. Unfortunately, those smarts fail her a bit when we learned that she doesn&apos;t know how to cook rice at sea level. Kels, we know you&apos;re from Denver, but you&apos;ve visited sea level before, yes?

As the dishes went out, some of them clearly did a better job of handling the challenge than others. Kelly&apos;s Kung Pao shrimp soup went over well, as did Ed&apos;s deconstructed Chicken Cordon Bleu and Tiffany&apos;s fork-and-knife gyro. Other chefs are less successful. Not surprisingly, Angelo&apos;s decision to use frozen puff pastry came back to bite him. It turns out hard and dry, and his dish wasn&apos;t even that well disguised. Alex managed to disguise Veal Parmesan a little better, but his veal was overcooked and his tortellini looked like an afterthought.

In front of the judges, Tiffany won, earning herself a trip to Paris. (Wedding paid for and a honeymoon? Top Chef sure has been good to Tiff.) And, in what surely elicited a sigh of relief from 90% of the contestants and viewers, Alex ended up going home for his poorly executed dish.

But as sad as Alex&apos;s dish looked, we feel like Amanda was ultimately doin&apos; it the wrongest. First of all, her attempt to disguise French onion soup was to make...drumroll...an onion soup with a cheese-covered piece of bread on the side. Sorry, but that is just not going to cut it. There were so many great ways to disguise and have fun with that dish. An open-face cheese sandwich with an onion gravy? Yum . What about a savory bread pudding that incorporates all the flavors of French onion soup? Or hey, what about just anything that isn&apos;t onion soup? Even worse, her poorly disguised onion soup ended up not tasting good to the judges.

Although the judges didn&apos;t agree with us that she was the worst of the worst, the good news is that we get to enjoy her &quot;you&apos;re kidding me&quot; face of shock at judges&apos; table for at least one more week. It&apos;s all about the silver lining.


 
 
 Pizza Hut(R) Makes Global Pizza Delivery 
 [ Tech ] ( IndianWeb2.com - Web 2.0 and Technology Startup News and Reviews )
Pizza Hut� Makes Global Pizza Delivery Pizza Hut� Surprises Savvis, Inc. Employees Around the World PR Newswire — August 19, 2010 DALLAS, Aug. 19 /PRNewswire/ — Today, Pizza Hut will complete a global delivery to five countries totaling more than 900 pizzas. At 11:30 a.m. local time, Savvis, Inc. will reward more than 2,300 global ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 
 
Pizza Hut� Makes Global Pizza Delivery

Pizza Hut� Surprises Savvis, Inc. Employees Around the World

PR Newswire — August 19, 2010

DALLAS, Aug. 19 /PRNewswire/ — Today, Pizza Hut will complete a global delivery to five countries totaling more than 900 pizzas. At 11:30 a.m. local time, Savvis, Inc. will reward more than 2,300 global employees with their favorite pizzas as recognition for all their work.

The pizzas will be delivered to Savvis, Inc. employees in the United States, United Kingdom, Canada, Japan and Singapore.

“We are excited to deliver pizzas to the global office party hosted by Savvis,” said Pat Murtha, Pizza Hut Chief Operations Officer. “Providing Pizza Hut Pizza to these employees world-wide shows our continued promise to surprise and satisfy our customers in unique ways.”

The global delivery marks the largest one-time order the company has completed in its 50-year history, and quite possibly the largest one-time delivery for the entire industry.

“Our employees continue to deliver for Savvis, so we enlisted Pizza Hut to deliver for them and to help us celebrate our successful second quarter on a global scale,” said Jim Ousley, chief executive officer at Savvis.

For more information on Pizza Hut, visit PizzaHut.com or interact with Pizza Hut at facebook.com/pizzahut and twitter.com/pizzahut.

About Pizza Hut

Pizza Hut, America’s Favorite Pizza, delivers more pizza, pasta and wings than any other restaurant . The only pizza company to be named a top ten franchise in 2009 by Entrepreneur Magazine, Pizza Hut began 50 years ago in Wichita, Kansas and today operates nearly 10,000 restaurant s in more than 90 countries. Pizza Hut, Inc. is a subsidiary of Yum ! Brands, Inc. (NYSE: YUM ). To check out what’s new at Pizza Hut visit pizzahut.com.

About Savvis

Savvis, Inc. (Nasdaq: SVVS) is a global leader in cloud infrastructure and hosted IT solutions for enterprises. More than 2,500 unique clients, including 30 of the top 100 companies in the Fortune 500, use Savvis to reduce capital expense, improve service levels and harness the latest advances in cloud computing. For more information, please visit www.savvis.net. 

Media Contact Alexa Robinson 972-338-6839 alexa.robinson@ yum .com @PizzaHut Twitter.com/PizzaHut

SOURCE Pizza Hut

Subject Codes: PC/t.100819113603530, PT/lang.en, PC/ticker, IN/FOD, IN/RST, IN/REA, IN/CPR, IN/ITE, IN/NET, RE/Texas, PC/priority.r, PC/category.f, PC/class.1278, PC/class.1255, PC/WAVO_….r., PC/APT_….r, PC/trade_r, PC/wavo5_r, PC/class.1058, PC/WAVO_t….., PC/APT_t…., PC/state_t, PC/wavo1_t, PC/class.1000, PC/WAVO_..b…, PC/APT_..b.., PC/circuit_b, PC/wavo3_b, PC/DataFeat_natl3, PC/port_32, PC/Billing_IRW, PC/Billing_RWB, PC/Billing_TNW, PC/Billing_US1, PC/1stAcc_137868, PC/bureau_CG, PC/port_01, PC/port_96, PC/port_31, PC/port_19, PC/port_91, PC/contact, PC/website, PC/id_CG52801

Company Codes: NASDAQ-NMS:SVVS, NYSE: YUM 

 
 
 
 175: Morrissey 
 [ Celebrities ] ( FameBall.com - Most Famous Celebrities Right Now )
OMFG! We&apos;ll take that with a side of heart attack, please! Check out the latest reason America is a scary-ass place - a Krispy Kreme Bacon Cheeseburger, which made its debut at the Wisconsin State Fair this summer! The $5 monstrosity - created by Nathan Morrissey of Machine Head restaurant - apparently is a normal cheeseburger with a Krispy Kreme doughnut instead of a bun, and is topped with chocolate-covered bacon and clocks in at about 1,000 calories! YUM ! Can you imagine how q ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   OMFG! We&apos;ll take that with a side of heart attack, please! Check out the latest reason America is a scary-ass place - a Krispy Kreme Bacon Cheeseburger, which made its debut at the Wisconsin State Fair this summer! The $5 monstrosity - created by Nathan Morrissey of Machine Head restaurant - apparently is a normal cheeseburger with a Krispy Kreme doughnut instead of a bun, and is topped with chocolate-covered bacon and clocks in at about 1,000 calories! YUM ! Can you imagine how quickly that shiz sinks to the bottom of your stomach? We&apos;d probably keel over and die after two bites! LOLs! [ Image via Brad Vest .]
 [From: Perez Hilton] 
 Table Talk: Thai Yum tightens its focus 
 [ Asian Food ] ( Inform - Asian Food And Cooking )
The chef and the owners remain the same, but the Federal Hill Thai-American restaurant known as Ten-O-Six is now known as Thai Yum and, as its name ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   The chef and the owners remain the same, but the Federal Hill Thai-American restaurant known as Ten-O-Six is now known as Thai Yum and, as its name... 
 Salmonella Lawsuit Filed by Marler Clark on Behalf of Ohio Victim of Taco Bell Salmonella Outbreaks - Ohio, Illinois, Kentucky, and Wisconsin Lead the Illness Count 
 [ Food Safety ] ( Food Poison Journal )
An Ohio victim of the Salmonella outbreaks linked to Taco Bell filed a food poisoning lawsuit in the Court of Common Pleas of Scioto County, Ohio today. The lawsuit was filed against the food chain parent company Yum ! Brands on behalf of a Scioto county resident by Bill Marler of food safety law firm Marler Clark and by Fred Wendel of the Columbus firm Stewart&amp;DeChant. Two parallel outbreaks of Salmonella have been identified by Centers for Disease Control (CDC), both linked to the Taco Be ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 An Ohio victim of the Salmonella outbreaks linked to Taco Bell filed a food poisoning lawsuit in the Court of Common Pleas of Scioto County, Ohio today. The lawsuit was filed against the food chain parent company Yum ! Brands on behalf of a Scioto county resident by Bill Marler of food safety law firm Marler Clark and by Fred Wendel of the Columbus firm Stewart&amp;DeChant.

Two parallel outbreaks of Salmonella have been identified by Centers for Disease Control (CDC), both linked to the Taco Bell restaurant chain. Salmonella Hartford and Salmonella Baildon--the two outbreak strains--are rare and strong, sickening at least 155 people in 21 states and sending more than 30% of the ill to the hospital. More than 60% of the victims reported eating at Taco Bell.

Tammy Hale purchased food from a Taco Bell in Wheelersburg at the beginning of June. The next day she began to experience gastrointestinal symptoms, which worsened over the next several days until she had to be hospitalized. During her four-day hospitalization, tests revealed that she had been infected with the outbreak strain of Salmonella Hartford. She is still recovering from her illness.

 &quot;Ohio has been hard-hit by these outbreaks,&quot; said food safety advocate and attorney Bill Marler. &quot;Studies show that for every confirmed Salmonella illness in an outbreak, another 38.5 people who are sick don&apos;t visit the doctor or don&apos;t get tested. Using that math, close to a thousand Ohioans have likely been sickened. Many, like Tammy, are still trying to regain their health. At this point in the outbreak, our job is to help them do that.&quot; 
 
 Today&apos;s Menu: DC Restuarant Week, Five Guy, Lobster Truck 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( All News )
Day one of DC Restaurant Week is over. Where did you dine? Did you snap a picture? If so, please send it in. We’re looking for food photos to feature in the “9 Restaurant s” in TBD’s food and dining section. If you want your photo to be featured, please e-mail it to us with the name of the restaurant and dish in the subject line. If you’re looking for suggestions on where to dine and how to get most out of Restaurant Week, check out this post — it includes tips ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Day one of DC Restaurant Week is over. Where did you dine? Did you snap a picture? If so, please send it in . We’re looking for food photos to feature in the “9 Restaurant s” in TBD’s food and dining section. If you want your photo to be featured, please e-mail it to us with the name of the restaurant and dish in the subject line.

If you’re looking for suggestions on where to dine and how to get most out of Restaurant Week, check out this post — it includes tips from food bloggers, foodies, and local restaurant critics and writers. We&apos;re adding to it all the time, so keep the tips, links, and reviews coming.

Where you won’t be dining during D.C. Restaurant Week: Les Halles.
The Washington, D.C., Les Halles closed its doors in 2008, and according to Tim Carman, Travel Channel’s adventurous eater and former chef of New York Les Halles, Anthony Bourdain, is relieved. Read more here .

Speaking of adventurous eating... you can now order red velvet fried chicken in San Francisco. Yes, that’s right. It’s fried chicken coated in red velvet cake batter, served with a side of cream cheese infused garlic mashed potatoes. Yum ?

 VIDEO : How honest is D.C.? Pretty honest, actually. Turns out we’re the second-most honest city, beating out San Francisco, New York, Chicago, and Los Angeles. Honest Tea left bottles of ice-cold tea outside on a hot day with a sign asking people to pay one dollar. Check out what happened... (via We Love DC)

The never-ending burger news continues... last week the news about Shake Shack coming to D.C. shook Twitter into a frenzy . Today, Carman reports that Five Guys won best fast-food burger in the country by Zagat voters in the 2010 fast-food survey . The Arlington-based fast-food chain came out on top over the West Coast favorite, In-N-Out Burger. Rounding out the bottom three were Wendy’s, Burger King, and McDonald’s.

Other Zagat winners include:
• McDonald’s for Best French Fries
• Panera Bread for Best Salads
• KFC for Best Fried Chicken
• Starbucks for Best Coffee
• Chick-fil-A for Best Grilled Chicken
• Ben and Jerry’s for Top Ice Cream/Custard
• Dairy Queen for Best Milkshake

Downtown Bethesda has seen a boom of new restaurant s this summer, including Robert Wiedmaier’s Belgian-inspired Mussel Bar , the Mediterranean Bistro Lazeez , and Vapiano . And it doesn’t end there. American Tap Room is scheduled to open its doors soon too. The contemporary American restaurant featuring an extensive beer list is located on the corner of Woodmont Avenue and Elm Street, in the spot that once held Austin Grill. Also coming to the neighborhood: Food and Wine Co. , a wine bistro that’s taking the former Pizzeria Uno spot at 7272 Wisconsin Avenue and Taylor Gourmet , a sandwich shop that has already seen success at two other locations in the District. (via WBJ )

 Food Truck News 

• Great news: After postponing not once , but twice , the Lobster Truck is finally rolling out today ! On the menu: lobster rolls, shrimp rolls, chips, and Maine root soda

• Looks like it’s going to be a fall launch for the Empanada Truck. Yesterday’s tweet to me said they’ll start serving in early October.

• No love for food trucks? Washingtonian reports that D.C. restaurant s are not happy with the growing number of street food on wheels in the District. Restaurant owners complain of losing business to the food trucks and think it’s unfair that they have to pay rent, fees, and overhead. However, food trucks don’t get off that easily. They’re required to obtain a license, and according to Regulatory Affairs, “there must be a line of customers waiting for a truck to pull over”. One solution for the food trucks and restaurant s to co-exist peacefully would be to create an outdoor food court for the trucks to park in. Another proposed solution would be to prohibit the trucks from parking within 60 feet from a similar food establishment.

 Write-ups and reviews from the food bloggers 

• The Bethesda Foodies dines on snails at Zaytinya 
• I Flip For Food go for a nice meal and great atmosphere at Kramerbooks&amp;Afterwards Cafe 
• Capitol Bites bites into a lobster roll at the Burger Joint 
• “Mark Felt”, the Deepthroat Foodie, was pleasantly surprised at Ping Pong Dim Sum 

 Plan Ahead - Upcoming Food and Drink Events 

• August 16-22 -- DC Restaurant Week 
• August 16-22 -- H Street Eats 
• August 17 -- SouthHampton Beer Fest at Commonwealth
• August 17 - Enjoy bubbly and treats at the outdoor screening of The September Issue (via CityShopGirl )
• August 20 -- DC Beer Week begins
• August 21 -- Chesapeake Crab and Beer Festval 
• August 28 -- DC State Fair 
• September 1 -- Food Blogger Happy Hour at Poste
• Now-September 5 -- The Capital Grill Master Wine Tasting Event 
• September 6 -- Labor Day Street Party 
• September 11 - DC Veg Fest 

 Sweet Deals 

• Free Italian ice at the new Rita’s in Chinatown this week (via Prince of Petworth)
• Free August cooking classes with Chef Michael Kiss (via EveryFoodFits)
http://everyfoodfits.com/2010/08/10/free-august-cooking-classes-with-kiss-the-cook/
• $5 Drink specials all week at Argonaut
• 50% off mimosa brunch at ACKA Cocoa Bar
• TGI Friday’s : Save $5 when you spend $15 (valid through 8/18)
• Starbucks : Buy-one-get-one-free Doubleshot Energy Drink coupon
• Cheesecake Factory : Free slice of cheesecake with $5 donation
 
 Create healthy lifestyle 
 [ Vegan ] ( Alltop RSS )
Create Healthy Lifestyle is the name of the eatery. Went to this place at fortune center and had their Petai fried brown rice. Pretty nice with the chilli added in. $6. This place serves healthy food, organic, no msg If you are not sure about the dish do ask them if they use dairy before ordering. Nearest MRT: Bras Basah and Bugis Last week I went to Lotus vegetarian restaurant for their dishes again. Had the hor fan, which was fairly done. I also had the Penang Char Kway Teow the standard ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Create Healthy Lifestyle is the name of the eatery. Went to this place at fortune center and had their Petai fried brown rice. Pretty nice with the chilli added in. $6. This place serves healthy food, organic, no msg... If you are not sure about the dish do ask them if they use dairy before ordering.
 

Nearest MRT: Bras Basah and Bugis

Last week I went to Lotus vegetarian restaurant for their dishes again. Had the hor fan, which was fairly done.
 

I also had the Penang Char Kway Teow... the standard is still there! Very Malaysianish yum ! A must try. Click here to see the Char Kway Teow picture (note: they don&apos;t serve it with veggies on the top now). 
Click here to see dim sum at Lotus veg. 

Nearest MRT: Novena, Toa Payoh, Lavender, Boon Keng 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 
 Ohio Victim of Taco Bell Salmonella Outbreaks to File Second Lawsuit 
 [ Food Safety ] ( Food Poison Journal )
Ohio, Illinois, Kentucky, and Wisconsin Lead the Illness Count An Ohio victim of the Salmonella outbreaks linked to Taco Bell will file a food poisoning lawsuit in the Court of Common Pleas of Scioto County, Ohio today. The lawsuit will be filed against the food chain parent company Yum ! Brands on behalf of a Scioto county resident by Bill Marler of food safety law firm Marler Clark and by Fred Wendel of the Columbus firm Stewart&amp;DeChant. Two parallel outbreaks of Salmonella have been ide ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
 Ohio, Illinois, Kentucky, and Wisconsin Lead the Illness Cou nt

An Ohio victim of the Salmonella outbreaks linked to Taco Bell will file a food poisoning lawsuit in the Court of Common Pleas of Scioto County, Ohio today. The lawsuit will be filed against the food chain parent company Yum ! Brands on behalf of a Scioto county resident by Bill Marler of food safety law firm Marler Clark and by Fred Wendel of the Columbus firm Stewart&amp;DeChant.

Two parallel outbreaks of Salmonella have been identified by Centers for Disease Control (CDC), both linked to the Taco Bell restaurant chain. Salmonella Hartford and Salmonella Baildon—the two outbreak strains—are rare and strong, sickening at least 155 people in 21 states and sending more than 30% of the ill to the hospital. More than 60% of the victims reported eating at Taco Bell.

Tammy Hale purchased food from a Taco Bell in Wheelersburg at the beginning of June. The next day she began to experience gastrointestinal symptoms, which worsened over the next several days until she had to be hospitalized. During her four-day hospitalization, tests revealed that she had been infected with the outbreak strain of Salmonella Hartford. She is still recovering from her illness.

 “Ohio has been hard-hit by these outbreaks,” said food safety advocate and attorney Bill Marler. “Studies show that for every confirmed Salmonella illness in an outbreak, another 38.5 people who are sick don’t visit the doctor or don’t get tested. Using that math, close to a thousand Ohioans have likely been sickened. Many, like Tammy, are still trying to regain their health. At this point in the outbreak, our job is to help them do that.” 
 
 Bond Trisransri Is at It Again With 2B Asian Bistro 
 [ Miami, FL ] ( Short Order )
When Bond Trisransri opened Mr. Yum , a Thai and sushi restaurant in the middle of Little Havana, in 2009, it seemed about as likely to flourish as escargot in Indiana. However, the success of Mr ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   When Bond Trisransri opened Mr. Yum , a Thai and sushi restaurant in the middle of Little Havana, in 2009, it seemed about as likely to flourish as escargot in Indiana. However, the success of Mr... 
 RSC Staffing Leader 
 [ Jobs , Jobs (not Steve) ] ( Monster Job Search Results )
TX-Dallas, A&amp;W;, KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut, and Taco Bell - together they form Yum ! Brands, the world&apos;s largest restaurant company. More important than size is our commitment to innovation and the success of our employees. From multi-branded stores to our passionate customer mania philosophy to our explosive international growth, this is one great place to work.At Pizza Hut, we recognize that all the ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   TX-Dallas, A&amp;W;, KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut, and Taco Bell - together they form Yum ! Brands, the world&apos;s largest restaurant company. More important than size is our commitment to innovation and the success of our employees. From multi-branded stores to our passionate customer mania philosophy to our explosive international growth, this is one great place to work.At Pizza Hut, we recognize that all the 
 Yum Brands spends $360K lobbying in 2nd quarter 
 [ Seattle, WA , Seattle , Most Popular , Op-Ed (opinion editorial) , College Basketball ] ( The Seattle Times )
Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report. 
 Yum Brands spends $360,000 in second quarter to lobby gov&apos;t on food safety, labor issues 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( Washington Examiner Site Feed )
Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report. 
 Yum Brands spends $360,000 in second quarter to lobby gov?t on food safety, labor issues 
 [ Tech ] ( Gaea Times (by Simple Thoughts) Breaking News and incisive views 24/7 )
 Yum Brands spends $360K lobbying in 2nd quarter WASHINGTON ? Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report. That’s more than double the $150,000 that the fast-food chain spent in the first quarter, and up from the . Original article : Yum Brands spends $360,000 in second quarter to lobby gov’t on food safety, labor issues.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Yum Brands spends $360K lobbying in 2nd quarter WASHINGTON ? Fast-food restaurant company Yum Brands Inc. spent $360,000 in the second quarter to lobby the federal government on food safety and other issues, according to a disclosure report. That’s more than double the $150,000 that the fast-food chain spent in the first quarter, and up from the .... Original article : Yum Brands spends $360,000 in second quarter to lobby gov’t on food safety, labor issues . 
 2010 Chain Restaurant Sales &apos;Pops&apos; 
 [ Finance ] ( pfblogs.org: The Ad-Free Personal Finance Blogs Aggregator )
John Gordon submits:We recently looked for same store sales (SSS) “pops”, where the sales metric trend moved by 10% (1000 bpts) or more from quarter to quarter. And even in the last year or two, there have been a few instances, as seen below (SSS %s): We see yesterday’s MCD impressive same store sales gains (but not a “pop”) that can be traced back to new products (smoothies), discounting (drinks) and sales platforms. And we are watching Dominos (DPZ), that ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   John Gordon submits:We recently looked for same store sales (SSS) “pops”, where the sales metric trend moved by 10% (1000 bpts) or more from quarter to quarter. And even in the last year or two, there have been a few instances, as seen below (SSS %s): We see yesterday’s MCD impressive same store sales gains (but not a “pop”) that can be traced back to new products (smoothies), discounting (drinks) and sales platforms. And we are watching Dominos (DPZ), that got a legitimate sales pop from its new pizza (and a nice follow-on, but not an “pop” in quarter two), and Pizza Hut ( YUM ) got a 17% pop for its $10/any/any price focus (and a decent 8.0% follow on last quarter).Complete Story » ... 
 2010 Chain Restaurant Sales &apos;Pops&apos; 
 [ Economics ] ( SeekingAlpha.com: Home Page )
John Gordon submits:We recently looked for same store sales (SSS) “pops”, where the sales metric trend moved by 10% (1000 bpts) or more from quarter to quarter. And even in the last year or two, there have been a few instances, as seen below (SSS %s): We see yesterday’s MCD impressive same store sales gains (but not a “pop”) that can be traced back to new products (smoothies), discounting (drinks) and sales platforms. And we are watching Dominos (DPZ), that ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
We recently looked for same store sales (SSS) “pops” , where the sales metric trend moved by 10% (1000 bpts ) or more from quarter to quarter . And even in the last year or two, there have been a few instances, as seen below (SSS %s):

We see yesterday’s MCD impressive same store sales gains (but not a “pop”) that can be traced back to new products (smoothies), discounting (drinks) and sales platforms. And we are watching Dominos ( DPZ ), that got a legitimate sales pop from its new pizza (and a nice follow-on, but not an “pop” in quarter two), and Pizza Hut ( YUM ) got a 17% pop for its $10/any/any price focus (and a decent 8.0% follow on last quarter).
 
 Taiwan launches &apos;gasto-diplomacy&apos; drive 
 [ Guardian ] ( News: Main section | guardian.co.uk )
Taiwan becomes the latest country to launch a diplomatic drive based around its national cuisineIt is diplomacy by dim sum, a brand of international relations that relies less on fusty summits than on fine dining.A number of countries have concluded that when it comes to selling their image and their goods to the British public, there is no more effective way to win hearts and minds than through the stomach.Taiwan has become the latest country to launch a diplomatic drive based around its nation ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en-gb   
Taiwan becomes the latest country to launch a diplomatic drive based around its national cuisine

It is diplomacy by dim sum, a brand of international relations that relies less on fusty summits than on fine dining.

A number of countries have concluded that when it comes to selling their image and their goods to the British public, there is no more effective way to win hearts and minds than through the stomach.

Taiwan has become the latest country to launch a diplomatic drive based around its national cuisine. President Ma Ying-jeou has ordered his envoys to start talking the language of food by launching a £20m &quot;gastro-diplomacy&quot; campaign in the UK and elsewhere.

Taiwan&apos;s consulate in London is hoping to make dishes such as &quot;stinky tofu&quot; and oyster omelette the stars of a diplomatic drive to differentiate the country from its giant and sometimes antagonistic neighbour, China, and to end the perception that Taiwan is little more than the mass-production workshop of the world.

It is not alone. The Malaysian government will next month transform Trafalgar Square into a street food bazaar as part of a UK campaign fronted by chef Rick Stein.

South Korea has pushed its culture through a programme of &quot;Kimchi&quot; diplomacy, particularly in the US. Kimchi refers to Korea&apos;s ubiquitous fermented vegetable pickle, and there has been a boom in Korean fast food trucks in California serving kimchi quesadillas.

The ultimate goal for gastro-diplomats is to emulate the success of Thailand&apos;s 2002 &quot;Global Thai&quot; campaign, which increased the number of Thai restaurant s around the world, making pad Thai and tom yum just as familiar a shorthand for Thailand as the hamburger is for America.

Even North Korea is putting its best food forward: a chain of state-owned &quot;Pyongyang restaurant s&quot; has spread to Cambodia, Bangkok, China and Laos, serving dishes such as ice-encrusted noodles and dog-meat soup, while waitresses sing and dance to North Korean songs.

&quot;People feel warm around food,&quot; said Steve Chen, Taiwan&apos;s economic consul in London, over dumplings and bubble tea, a Taiwanese drink featuring chewy black pearls of tapioca and sweet potato starch which he hopes will become a hit with the UK&apos;s coffee drinking set. &quot;It touches your heart, and that is what we want.

&quot;It is completely different to the image we have had as a centre of industrial production. Our most important job was to promote the hi-tech industries, but that is changing and the government in Taipei has decided that the food industry is the most important item to promote, because we need to make clear there is something unique about Taiwan.&quot;

The food shown off by Chen at Old Tree, his favourite restaurant , in Golders Green, north London, is a fragrant fusion of Chinese, Japanese and Vietnamese cooking.

There are hints of a more political intent, and one goal is to use food to ensure the world understands the difference between Taiwan and mainland China. Taiwan is often treated as wayward province by China.

&quot;Taiwan has figured out it can do better outreach work through the kitchen table,&quot; said Paul Rockower, a visiting fellow at the Taiwan Foundation for Democracy, who is studying gastro-diplomacy. &quot;When someone tries a sea-salt latte [a Taiwanese drink] it creates awareness about Taiwanese culture. The Koreans embarked on Kimchi diplomacy partly because their brands weren&apos;t being recognised as Korean – Samsung was being recognised as a Japanese brand.&quot;

Gastro-diplomacy can cause cultural indigestion, however. Old Tree&apos;s menu features a lot of pork, which has sparked complaints from the Jewish community in Golders Green, while Malaysia&apos;s year-long campaign, run by a British PR firm in London, has overwhelmed some food writers who, with five months still to go, have grown tired of being bombarded with offers of rich Malaysian food.

The differences between Israel and Lebanon were exposed earlier this year when a &quot;hummus war&quot; erupted, with both sides vying to prepare the largest bowl of hummus to claim the world record. And during indirect peace talks between Israel and Syria, Syria&apos;s president, Bashir Assad, was rumoured to have had a plate of Damascus hummus delivered to then Israeli prime minister Ehud Olmert.

In 2005, France&apos;s pride in its world-famous cuisine may have cost it the right to host the 2012 Olympics. Jacques Chirac, then president, was reported as criticising British and Finnish food on the eve of the final IOC vote in which Finland had two votes and London was a candidate. &quot;You can&apos;t trust people who cook as badly as that,&quot; Chirac said, according to the newspaper Liberation. &quot;After Finland, [the UK] is the country with the worst food.&quot;

 Stinky tofu anyone? 

 Stinky tofu A form of fermented tofu with – don&apos;t say you weren&apos;t warned – a strong smell. Popular in east and south-east Asia, particularly Hong Kong, Taiwan and China, where it is found at night markets or roadside stands, or as a side dish in lunch bars.

 Bubble tea Otherwise known as pearl milk tea, this sweet beverage created in Taiwan usually contains a tea base mixed with fruit and or milk as well as small tapioca balls or pearls called boba. The tea is shaken to mix the ingredients, creating a foam on the top of some varieties, hence the name.

 Kimchi Korean dish made of vegetables with varied seasonings. There are hundreds of varieties made with a main vegetable ingredient such as napa cabbage, radish, green onion or cucumber.

 Dog meat soup Another Korean speciality, it has been claimed to increase virility. The meat is boiled with vegetables such as green onion, parilla leaves and dropwort, and various spices.
 
 Taiwan Thailand Malaysia North Korea South Korea 
 Robert Booth 
 guardian.co.uk © Guardian News&amp;Media Limited 2010 | Use of this content is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions | More Feeds 
 Le Veneziane Gluten-Free, Gremolata 
 [ Allergies ] ( Please Don&apos;t Pass The Nuts™ )
Trust is the cornerstone of every good relationship; with food allergies, it becomes even more vital. Having friends, partners, dates and restaurant s that you can trust is ideal: ultimately you want to be able to trust everyone in your orbit. Trust with a restaurant is a beautiful thing and like any other relationship, it’s created over time and trial. With a resto though, it involves lots and lots of eating. Nizza has been one of my haunts for the last year, as in I go weekly. I usually ha ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Trust is the cornerstone of every good relationship; with food allergies, it becomes even more vital. Having friends, partners, dates and restaurant s that you can trust is ideal: ultimately you want to be able to trust everyone in your orbit.

 Trust with a restaurant is a beautiful thing and like any other relationship, it’s created over time and trial. With a resto though, it involves lots and lots of eating.

 Nizza has been one of my haunts for the last year, as in I go weekly. I usually have the same dish; I know it, I trust it and I like [ahem, love] it. Every time I go, I remind the manager, the chef and the server of my food allergies. Even though they know them by heart. Recipes change, formulations change, staff changes; it’s my job to remind them of what my needs are.

Last week, GM Benjamin said they had a special of gremolata with pasta [ le veneziane gluten-free pasta for me] and peas and asparagus. I thought, that sounds safe - is it? Trying a new dish or straying away from a safe favorite is scary. It’s starting all over again. And even with a trusted restaurant , with trusted staff and a trusted chef, I do the routine: go over every ingredient and remind them of what my needs are. And I smile, a lot.

Because I’m a regular (tips on becoming a regular here and here ), I find restaurant s are ready and willing to work with me and my milliondy questions.

In this dish, it was fairly straightforwardly delicious: le veneziane gluten-free pasta , the gremolata (which is totally my new favorite thing and I will be making some at home and adding it to everything), grated Parmesan, a little butter, a little GF pasta water and the veg.

 

Totally easy and yum and now I have something new to add to the menu of my faves at this resto.

Do you have the same dish over and over? When was the last time you tried a special or an off-menu item at a trusted restaurant ? What happened? Do tell! 
 BBC hiring for new downtown restaurant 
 [ Louisville, KY , Louisville ] ( WAVE - News )
The Bluegrass Brewing Company has started hiring for their new downtown location at Third and Main Streets near the new KFC Yum ! Center.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   The Bluegrass Brewing Company has started hiring for their new downtown location at Third and Main Streets near the new KFC Yum ! Center. 
 Vegas Vacation! 
 [ Celiac Disease ] ( gluten free betsy )
Hello all! If you&apos;ve noticed the lack of posting, it&apos;s because I was on vacation in Las Vegas. My cousin tied the knot, so my family and I headed out to the desert to be a part of her big day. This was a very exciting trip for me, not because of my cousin&apos;s wedding, but because it was the first &quot;big&quot; vacation I&apos;ve be able to take since 2005!! (Which ironically was to visit the very same cousin in Scottsdale, AZ while she was in college.) I did a lot of research for gluten free restaurant s in th ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
Hello all! If you&apos;ve noticed the lack of posting, it&apos;s because I was on vacation in Las Vegas. My cousin tied the knot, so my family and I headed out to the desert to be a part of her big day. This was a very exciting trip for me, not because of my cousin&apos;s wedding, but because it was the first &quot;big&quot; vacation I&apos;ve be able to take since 2005!! (Which ironically was to visit the very same cousin in Scottsdale, AZ while she was in college.)

I did a lot of research for gluten free restaurant s in the area. I know how to order a meal wherever I&apos;m at, but that usually consists of a salad or plain grilled chicken or meat. I love when I come across a place with gluten free hamburger buns or gluten free pizza. During my vacation homework I was able to find a bunch of places that were gluten free friendly, many with the help of Jennifer Sullivan from the Las Vegas Celiac Disease Support Group .

I found three really great places I wanted to check out, first Sammy&apos;s Wood Fired Pizza for their much talked about gluten free pizza and other gluten free items. I mean, look at that menu, wood fired pizza with Brie cheese and truffle oil!! (Please open a location in Chicago, Sammy!)

Second, Atomic #7 for their gluten free waffle cones! Not just that, their ice cream is organic and vegan! They even have dairy free ice cream in the likes of soy milk, almond milk, rice milk, coconut milk, and lactose free milk. I could definitely go for one of their Out of This World Ice Cream Flavor Combos !

Lastly, I was looking forward to breakfast at The Cracked Egg for some gluten free pancakes! Yum !

Sadly I did not make it to ANY of these restaurant s. All were a cab ride away from the strip where I was staying and with all of the things we had planned (if you are in Vegas, you HAVE to see The Beatles: LOVE Cirque du Soleil show , A-M-A-Z-I-N-G!!) we just didn&apos;t have time to visit venture out to Henderson.

Still, I DID safely enjoy some wonderful food. A huge round of applause to the Hard Rock cafe on the strip. Our server was a total rockstar and was able to answer all of my questions (Do the fries have any sort of flour or batter coating? Are they fried in the same oil as the breaded items?) After we placed the order, my sister and I ran to the ladies room to wash our hands. When we returned a man with a killer mullet was chillin&apos; at our tables taking to the rest of the family. When I sat down, I found out he was the manager and came to discuss &quot;who&apos;s got the gluten allergy&quot; He wanted to know how sensitive I was and that they are doing everything they can to prevent cross contamination in the kitchen. Wow...that was really nice. I order this piece of deliciousness:

 
A Grilled Granny Smith Apple with Provolone Burger. No bun, but bursting with lots of flavors, seasoned beef, tart granny smith apples, salty crunchy bacon, caramelized onions, and melted provolone cheese. And of course those yum my just potato fries. It was every bit of amazing as it sounds. After we finished and my brother polished off an Apple Cobbler dessert, the general manager stopped by to make sure everything was to our satisfaction and encouraged us to visit the rest of the cafe/museum. We headed up to the third floor were I came across MC Hammer&apos;s legendary hammer pants. They were definitely too legit.

 
For brunch the next day, some of the family hit the buffet, but my sister and I headed over to Serendipity 3 in Caesars Palace. I&apos;d been the original New York location years ago (and I loooove the movie - John Cusack *swoon*) so I was super excited to see one in Vegas! We decided to split an appetizer and then go all out with the ice cream desserts. We ordered nachos with grilled chicken (they came with beef, black beans, cheese, guacamole, pico di gallo, and sour cream) and then used our coupon for a free frozen hot chocolate. So much food, we couldn&apos;t even make it through the nachos. Everything was phenomenal and we so desperately wanted to return for those sundaes we promised ourselves (didn&apos;t happen - next time!)

 

 
Prior to The Beatles: LOVE show, we dined at The Range in Harrah&apos;s . A typical steakhouse, luckily because they were not very knowledgeable on food allergies. I asked my questions and after being reassured that the au gratin potatoes were safe, they arrived topped with bread crumbs (well I thought maybe they&apos;d be ok since they were an upscale restaurant ). When asked if they came without breadcrumbs, I was told they were already prepared with them. Um...ok. I had grilled asparagus and garlic potato wedges instead. Tasty! Unfortunately some of the other members of my family didn&apos;t have the greatest experience either (under cooked fish that tasted very fishy...not fresh at all. Then again we were in the desert, couldn&apos;t exactly catch it that morning.)

 
 
The following morning, Jimmy Buffet&apos;s Margaritaville at the Flamingo sounded about right after a long night out. Excellent choice indeed. Perfect hash browns and a SoCal omelet filled with fresh avocado, bacon, and jack cheese. I could have eaten it for every meal.

 
 
The wedding dinner followed later that day. No pics, but tons of amazing (and waaay too much) food at NOVE Italiano . My cousin winked at me as the food came around, she already took care of mine and my mom&apos;s meals. When I told the server I was gluten free and if anything could be prepared without the glutens, he already had the heads up. I was able to eat a lot of the items served family style, but a special salad came around sans croutons. Three different gelatos finished off the meal. Upstairs in the Palms celebrity suite, cupcakes filled the table. Gluten galore, but after a few cocktails I ate a Hershey kiss off the top of one and licked a tiny bit of frosting off. I bet they were good.

 
 
The last day of the trip we ate at Caesars Palace again, this time at Augustus Cafe . I had a wonderful Cobb Salad. Free of gluten, filled with flavor.

 
So there you have it. A gluten free Vegas success story. If you head out there, I highly recommend all of these places. Maybe you&apos;ll be lucky enough to hit up the three restaurant s I mentioned at the beginning of the post. If you do, let me know how they were!

 Did any of you guys vacation this summer? Where was your favorite gluten free meal? 
 Our Day Out with Lays Chip Trips! 
 [ Shopping ] ( Everything Up Close )
July has been a crazy busy month for us. So, this month, we combined our Lays Chip Trip with some wedding planning. We decided to start off our day with lunch at our local Subway Restaurant , then head off to meet with our photographer (Amber Bond Photography) at our venue, Pineridge Hollow (a beautiful country-style venue in Birds Hill Park), for some photo planning. Before meeting at our venue, Jay and I decided to stop in at Subway to grab a bite to eat. I&apos;ve always loved Subway because o ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
July has been a crazy busy month for us. So, this month, we combined our Lays Chip Trip with some wedding planning. We decided to start off our day with lunch at our local Subway Restaurant , then head off to meet with our photographer ( Amber Bond Photography ) at our venue, Pineridge Hollow (a beautiful country-style venue in Birds Hill Park), for some photo planning.

 Before meeting at our venue, Jay and I decided to stop in at Subway to grab a bite to eat. I&apos;ve always loved Subway because of their healthier choices and lack of fried foods. I generally make it a meal and add a couple of White Chocolate Macadamia Nut cookies (my favorite), which kind of conteracts the healthy sandwich, but either way, I love it (we all deserve a treat once in awhile)! My fiancé chose the Spicy Italian Sub - as usual, and I decided to go with a sub I haven&apos;t had in awhile, the Sweet Onion Chicken Teriyaki (oh so yum )! Since I&apos;ve been tried to eat healthier and lose a bit of weight before the wedding (at the end of this month...ekk), I started off with a 9-grain sub bun and loaded it with lots of fresh veggies...and of course, I only got a 6&quot;.

 Because of Lays Chip Trips, we were also able to get $5 off our meal with the $5 gift card I redeemed for online with my Lays Chip Trip Points. This gift card is only 30 points on the Lays Chip Trips Website and it is great to have on hand for the sporadic lunch out. Unfortunately, you can only redeem for one $5 Subway voucher per Lays Chip Trips Account. But, if you pair up the voucher with their daily specials (meals for only $5), you get a free meal (all you have to pay for is tax).

Short and simple day but none-the-less it was a good one! Since it was a super hot (and humid) day, I was happy to get home to our nice air conditioned house. I have a couple of other trips in mind for this month including a trip to the Manitoba Museum (they have a music themed exhibit on right now that I&apos;m looking forward to), a day out at O Roseau , and an afternoon of mini-golf.

 To find out more about the Lays Chip Trips Program, please visit my original post on the Lay&apos;s Chip Trip Summer Campaign . 

Finally, Lay&apos;s Chip Trips has partnered with the Canadian Tourism Commission (CTC) to allow Canadians to discover great spots in their provinces and across the country. The CTC has created a website called Local&apos;s Know that has ideas for your summer outings, as well as special offers. So, if you are looking for something to do with the remainder of your summer, I encourage you to check out the CTC Local&apos;s Know Website .

 Disclosure - I am participating in the Lay’s® Chip Trips program by Mom Central on behalf of Frito Lay Canada. I received Lay’s® Chip Trips points and a gift card to off-set my trip costs to facilitate this post. The opinions on this blog are my own. 

 
 Conference update 
 [ Romance Novels ] ( Carol Burnside&apos;s Road to Publication )
Met with agent - she requested full. Met with Harlequin editor - she requested partial. Went to several workshops and took notes. Met an online CP that I&apos;ve critiqued with about 6 yrs. Saw another online CP again this year. Saw a lot of my chapter mates from Georgia Romance Writers. Had lunch at Big River with two editors from Belle Books who are also chapter mates and terrific ladies. Ate at Cat Cora&apos;s restaurant , Kozzina&apos;s twice for breakfast - Yum ! In the morning, it&apos;s back home to my hubby. ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Met with agent - she requested full.
Met with Harlequin editor - she requested partial.
Went to several workshops and took notes.
Met an online CP that I&apos;ve critiqued with about 6 yrs.
Saw another online CP again this year.
Saw a lot of my chapter mates from Georgia Romance Writers.
Had lunch at Big River with two editors from Belle Books who are also chapter mates and terrific ladies.
Ate at Cat Cora&apos;s restaurant , Kozzina&apos;s twice for breakfast - Yum !

In the morning, it&apos;s back home to my hubby.
Next week I start requested revisions on a full with Red Sage and finish plotting out my next book. 
 Score a Slice at The Cheesecake Factory For Half Off Today 
 [ Noodles , Food ] ( YumSugar )
In honor of National Cheesecake Day, The Cheesecake Factory is pulling out a few sweet stops. Today only, guests can get their fix of the chain&apos;s 30-plus flavors for half off. In addition to varieties like red velvet and white raspberry truffle, the restaurant is also offering a new flavor, Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter Chocolate Cake Cheesecake, at the promotional price and donating 25 cents of each slice to charity. So if you love your cheesecake studded with peanut butter cup chunks and layered with ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
In honor of National Cheesecake Day, The Cheesecake Factory is pulling out a few sweet stops. Today only, guests can get their fix of the chain&apos;s 30-plus flavors for half off.

In addition to varieties like red velvet and white raspberry truffle , the restaurant is also offering a new flavor, Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter Chocolate Cake Cheesecake, at the promotional price and donating 25 cents of each slice to charity. So if you love your cheesecake studded with peanut butter cup chunks and layered with fudge cake and caramel, today&apos;s your lucky (and guilt-free) day.

I&apos;m pretty sure Mr. Yum will be dragging me to the San Francisco location for a bite of his favorite - the simple-yet-classic plain version. What will you be ordering?

 Source 
 
 KFC&apos;s Parent Company Conquers the World 
 [ Small Business ] ( The Global Small Business Blog )
What&apos;s mightier or bigger than McDonald&apos;s? KFC&apos;s parent company, Yum ! Brands, which also owns Pizza Hut and Taco Bell, has earned the exclamation mark on which it insists as the world&apos;s largest restaurant company -- is poised to grow fast in China, Russia and India. With 37,000 restaurant s in 110 countries, Yum ! even eclipses that more famous icon of American colonization, McDonald&apos;s, to rank as the world&apos;s largest restaurant chain in terms of numbers of outlets.Read more here. Illustration cr ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   What&apos;s mightier or bigger than McDonald&apos;s? KFC&apos;s parent company, Yum ! Brands , which also owns Pizza Hut and Taco Bell, has earned the exclamation mark on which it insists as the world&apos;s largest restaurant company -- is poised to grow fast in China, Russia and India. 
 With 37,000 restaurant s in 110 countries, Yum ! even eclipses that more famous icon of American colonization, McDonald&apos;s, to rank as the world&apos;s largest restaurant chain in terms of numbers of outlets. Read more here .

Illustration credit here .

Posted by: The Global Small Business Blog 
 Fitch affirms rating on Yum Brands, upgrades outlook 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( Washington Examiner Site Feed )
Fitch Ratings on Tuesday affirmed several its rating on Yum Brands, Inc., given the company&apos;s recent operational and credit improvements. And it upgrading its rating outlook to &quot;positive&quot; from &quot;stable&quot; for the restaurant chain.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Fitch Ratings on Tuesday affirmed several its rating on Yum Brands, Inc., given the company&apos;s recent operational and credit improvements. And it upgrading its rating outlook to &quot;positive&quot; from &quot;stable&quot; for the restaurant chain. 
 snapping a slice of life 
 [ Photography ] ( Shutter Sisters )
Confession: The only thing I love more than eating food is photographing food. Is it just me or does anyone else do this? Sometimes I will plate a meal so that it looks pretty even though it’s going to be in my belly in two seconds. I’ve always cared about what my food looked like. If it doesn’t look good, I usually don’t want to eat it. As an artist, I&apos;m always on a hunt for color, texture, and light. Food provides all three of these things on one plate! This week, I&amp;rsq ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   
  

Confession: The only thing I love more than eating food is photographing food.

Is it just me or does anyone else do this?

Sometimes I will plate a meal so that it looks pretty even though it’s going to be in my belly in two seconds. I’ve always cared about what my food looked like. If it doesn’t look good, I usually don’t want to eat it. As an artist, I&apos;m always on a hunt for color, texture, and light. Food provides all three of these things on one plate!

This week, I’m inviting everyone over for a Slice of Life Tuesday Visual Potluck! Slice of Life Tuesday is a weekly photo challenge in which I provide a theme for inspiration and ask people to share photos from their everyday lives. For me, it has provided a way to stay creative and find the beauty in ordinary moments. And really, what could be more “everyday” than eating? It’s something we all have in common. We all have to eat. And those three square meals a day (or 6-12 in my case) provide ample opportunity for us to pull out our cameras.

So let’s feast! Cook up some of your most delectable, delicious, yum -tastic meals, and share a photo that will make our stomachs growl. If you don’t usually cook, try your hand at photographing your meal at a restaurant .

At one time, I thought about becoming a food photographer and spent a lot of time flipping through my fair share of food magazines, studying and ogling over the delicious photos. Through my studies, I discovered a few simple tricks that can help capture food at its best.

1. View your plate as art. Take your time plating the food. Think about composition and the rule of thirds . The same concepts that apply to art apply to plating your food.

2. Color. Color. Color. The camera loves color. Colorful food sets off triggers in our brains that say &quot; Yum ! I want what she&apos;s having!&quot; In addition, think about ways to bring color and texture into the background. Use napkins and tablecloths to contrast and enhance the food.

3. More is more. When it comes to photographing food, the more full the plate is, the more scrumptious it looks. Photograph the overflowing bowl of food before you serve it on plates. Or put more on your plate than you plan on eating. Sometimes, art wins out over practicality!

4. Find the light. If you cook in a kitchen with fluorescent lighting like I do, don&apos;t be afraid to move the food to a different location. I photographed the couscous salad in the photo above outside on my deck. If you don&apos;t have a deck, bring the food to a window that lets in lots of natural light or find a place in your home that is lit with warm light. You can sometimes find me in the living room with my camera and my breakfast because that was where the best light was at that moment.

5. Take a bite. If you look at any food magazine, most of the photos show the food as it’s being cooked or mid-meal. This is where the &quot;slice of life&quot; philosophy really helps. Use your food to tell a story. Take food photos that look like real life. If you normally have a fork on your plate, put a fork on your plate. If you want to take a bite, take a bite!

Above all else, enjoy the food! Before your meal gets cold, put down the camera and pick up the fork!

Bon appétit!

 Image and words courtesy of Honorary Sister / Guest Blogger Darrah Parker . You can find her on her blog where she hosts Slice of Life Tuesday . You are invited to share your Slice of Life with her at the Slice of Life Tuesday Flickr Group . 
 
 Credit Suisse boosts earnings forecast for Yum , says refranchising could boost results 
 [ Washington, D.C. ] ( Washington Examiner Site Feed )
An analyst said Monday that operating profits at Yum Brands Inc. may climb if the restaurant chain accelerates the sale of more of its restaurant s to franchisees.
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   An analyst said Monday that operating profits at Yum Brands Inc. may climb if the restaurant chain accelerates the sale of more of its restaurant s to franchisees. 
 Cold Southwestern Corn and Shrimp Soup: Quick, Easy&amp;Summery for Souper (Soup, Salad&amp;Sammie) Sundays 
 [ Food ] ( Kahakai Kitchen )
Although we get corn throughout the year here, summer always seems like the best time to enjoy it. I was looking for a new and different cold corn soup recipe and came across this one from Martha Stewart in a &quot;60 days of Summer&quot; feature on her site. I liked the additions of shrimp, avocado and cherry tomatoes and how quick and simple it was to prepare, although I did take a few extra minutes to lightly blanch, drain and cool some fresh, local Kahuku corn instead of using frozen. The corn, lime, ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Although we get corn throughout the year here, summer always seems like the best time to enjoy it. I was looking for a new and different cold corn soup recipe and came across this one from Martha Stewart in a &quot; 60 days of Summer&quot; feature on her site. I liked the additions of shrimp, avocado and cherry tomatoes and how quick and simple it was to prepare, although I did take a few extra minutes to lightly blanch, drain and cool some fresh, local Kahuku corn instead of using frozen. The corn, lime, tomatoes and avocado are all locally grown. 
 
 You can find the recipe on the Martha Stewart website here. 
 Everyday Food says, &quot; Using frozen corn and shrimp saves a lot of time in this no-cook soup. &quot; 
 
 Cold Southwestern Corn and Shrimp Soup Martha Stewart&apos;s Everyday Food ,June 2007 ( Serves 4 ) Prep Time 20 min / Total Time 20 min 
 4 packages ( 10 ounces each ) frozen corn kernels, thawed ( I used fresh corn ) 
1 cup low-fat yogurt
1 cup milk ( I used unsweetened rice milk ) 
1/3 cup fresh lime juice ( from 2 or 3 limes )
1 teaspoon ground coriander
pinch cayenne pepper
1 lb cooked frozen shrimp, thawed, roughly chopped, reserving 4 whole shrimp
Coarse salt and ground pepper
1 cup grape tomatoes, halved
1 avocado, halved, pitted, peeled, and diced

In a blender, working in two batches, puree corn, yogurt, milk, lime juice, coriander, and cayenne. Strain through a fine-mesh sieve into a large bowl, pressing to extract as much liquid as possible; discard solids. Stir in chopped shrimp, and season with salt and pepper.

 Serve garnished with tomatoes, avocado, and reserved whole shrimp.

 
 Notes/Results: Cold and creamy with a nice, light flavor--a little sweet, a little tangy and a bit of spice ( I used a large pinch of cayenne. ) I think the fresh local corn adds a lot of flavor and sweetness but if it isn&apos;t available I am sure the frozen will work fine. I made just a half batch, used a low-fat Greek yogurt and since I didn&apos;t have milk in the house, I added unsweetened rice milk. ( If you wanted to make it all non-dairy you could use a soy or other dairy-alternative yogurt. ) I tried this soup freshly made and it was good, but even better after a few hours in the refrigerator so the flavors had a chance to blend. Fast, simple and pretty, a small bowl makes a great starter to a summer meal like tacos, or something from the grill. I would make this again. 
 

 
 Let&apos;s visit the Souper Sunday kitchen and see who is here this week:

My friend girlichef wrote herself into our latest Cook the Books selection &quot; The School of Essential Ingredients &quot; and made a gorgeous bowl of Mexican Pozolé inspired by the novel. She writes ( very lyrically ), &quot; As sure as she’s sitting there, her soul is already in the kitchen…gathering, prepping, simmering the ingredients that will turn into an earthy, comforting bowl of Pozolé…she can almost feel the heat creeping up her face after she scoops up a big bite with a broken piece of tostada…the cooling garnishes giving the ultimate in contrast of flavors and textures. &quot; Read more about the book and her delicious soup on her post! 
 

 Next we welcome a couple of new faces to Souper Sundays. The first is Deepti from the blog A Hint of Spice , who joins us from Charlotte, North Carolina. Deepti has a bowl of the classic Chinese Hot and Sour Soup to share; full of veggies, spices and other good stuff. She says to &quot; Enjoy your soup with Spring rolls or egg rolls. &apos;njoy!!! &quot; Thanks for joining us this week Deepti!

 

Our second new face is Reshmi from the blog A Feast to the Eyes and Stomach , blogging from Germany. Reshmi says, &quot; Ezogelin Soup is another common soup in Turkish cuisine, the main ingredients being Bulgur and red lentils. It is also the most frequently cooked soup in my home. Bulgur wheat, rich in fiber and protein has interesting natural weight-loss benefits. The origin of this soup is attributed to Ezo, the bride from Gaziantep, the sixth largest city in Turkey. &quot; Welcome Reshmi! 
 
 
 The talented Janet from The Taste Space is back this week with a colorful Carrot Soup with Ginger and Lemon . Janet says, &quot; I love soups. I gravitate to the heavy, one-pot meal soups in the winter and to the fresh, light soups in the summer. This is one of my favourite carrot soups as it simple to make, healthy and has such complex flavours with tomato, lemon and ginger. This is not your typical carrot soup. It is bright and summery, all in a bowl! Creamy without any cream.. such bliss! &quot; 
 
 
 Resourceful Zibi from Fresh Slowcooking has a creamy, flavorful Tomato Shorba soup to share this week and says, &quot; My tomato shorba was inspired by a disappointing restaurant visit. I decided to use my slow cooker to prepare the tomato shorba I expected. I cooked fresh Roma tomatoes in a broth containing roasted cumin and coriander seeds, a hint of dried chilis and then softened it with a splash of coconut milk. An easy soup that’s full of deep, satisfying flavours. &quot; 
 

 Lee Ann from Mangos, Chili and Z made a bright and refreshing Watermelon and Feta Salad and says, &quot; I found this recipe a couple of years ago, tweaked it a bit and now it’s my “take everywhere all Summer long” dish. I love a sweet and salty combination. When I was in my 20′s and didn’t care what I ate, I used to pile potato chips on top of a candy bar to get my sweet-salty fix…ah, those were the days. Let’s address a healthier combination, how about sweet watermelon, salty olives and creamy feta. I think you’ll find it addictive and a real crowd pleaser. &quot; Yum ! 
 

 My pal Kim from Stirring the Pot has both a salad and a sandwich to share this week. About her salad she says, &quot; I used a recipe for Chopped Salad from Mark Bittman&apos;s How To Cook Everything Vegetarian. The base of the salad calls for Romaine, chopped celery, chopped carrots, chopped red onion, and chopped bell pepper. Bittman&apos;s chopped salad also calls for cucumber but I left it out and chose to add blanched and chopped green beans, chopped hard-boiled egg, chopped radishes, chickpeas, and boiled and chopped new potatoes. I sprinkled the salad with sunflower seeds and topped it with a homemade creamy Italian dressing. It was delicious! &quot; 
 
 For her sandwich, Kim tried Ellie Krieger&apos;s Ellie&apos;s Better Burger with Green Olives and says, &quot; Ellie&apos;s burger is flavored with coarsely chopped green olives, parsley, and cumin. Not only is this a unique combination of flavors, it is delicious. The olives give the burger that briney, salty flavor while adding some extra texture and the cumin gives the burger a nice smoky flavor. I served my burger on a whole wheat bun with lettuce, sliced red onion and mayo. I loved this burger. I loved it so much that I ate 2 of them! &quot; 
 
 Some lovely soups, a couple of fresh and fabulous salads, and a juicy burger! Thanks to everyone who joined in this week. If you have a soup, salad or sandwich that you would like to share--just click on the Souper Sunday logo on the side bar for all of the details on how to join in. 
 Have a wonderful week! 
 Best Money Tips: How to Make Green French Fries 
 [ Finance ] ( pfblogs.org: The Ad-Free Personal Finance Blogs Aggregator )
Welcome to Wise Bread&apos;s Best Money Tips roundup. Today, we give you a recipe for green french fries, the secrets of self-made millionaires, and ways to save on the putting green! Top 5 Articles Green French Fries — Stuck with extra zucchini? Perhaps you just need a crispy way to get your kids to eat veggies? This recipe reminds me of restaurant French fried Green Beans — but with a different member of the green family! ( yum .) Dinner A Love Story via Mom Advice 8 Reasons you SHOULD Us ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Welcome to Wise Bread&apos;s Best Money Tips roundup. Today, we give you a recipe for green french fries, the secrets of self-made millionaires, and ways to save on the putting green! Top 5 Articles Green French Fries — Stuck with extra zucchini? Perhaps you just need a crispy way to get your kids to eat veggies? This recipe reminds me of restaurant French fried Green Beans — but with a different member of the green family! ( yum .) Dinner A Love Story via Mom Advice 8 Reasons you SHOULD Use Coupons — We’ve heard the ol’ back and forth between people who clip and those who don’t. This rebuttal to a recent Yahoo! article is very clever, and a great read for those on both sides of the fence. Mommy Snacks 12 Secrets of Self-Made Millionaires to Help You Simplify Your Finances — Are your money processes getting complicated? Take a moment to ... 
 Cleveland *Did* Rock! 
 [ SciFi&amp;Fantasy Novels ] ( Mindy Klasky - Fun Smart Blogging )
And now, I&apos;m back from Cleveland, having enjoyed a *fantastic* long weekend away. (When I posted, asking for restaurant recommendations, I still wasn&apos;t sure when I&apos;d be going; it turns out that our plans came together much more quickly than expected!) Cleveland is about a 6-hour drive from here. Unless one stops in Breezewood, PA, for lunch. Then, Cleveland is about a 7.5-hour drive. Do not stop in Breezewood. Ever. Under any circumstances. Really. You&apos;ll thank me. We made reservations ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   And now, I&apos;m back from Cleveland, having enjoyed a *fantastic* long weekend away. (When I posted, asking for restaurant recommendations, I still wasn&apos;t sure when I&apos;d be going; it turns out that our plans came together much more quickly than expected!)

Cleveland is about a 6-hour drive from here. Unless one stops in Breezewood, PA, for lunch. Then, Cleveland is about a 7.5-hour drive. Do not stop in Breezewood. Ever. Under any circumstances. Really. You&apos;ll thank me.

We made reservations at the Intercontinental Suites, the most reasonably priced hotel near University Circle. When we arrived, though, we found that they had no rooms (likely, because they are a suites hotel in the middle of a gigantic hospital complex - families that had intended to check out with loved ones on Friday found themselves staying over the weekend for additional medical treatment.) The Suites upgraded us to a room at the Intercontinental proper, a luxury hotel a few blocks away. They maintained our great room rate and parking rate, so we felt like we&apos;d won the jackpot!

The main reason for our trip to Cleveland was to visit the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame (including the special exhibit about Springsteen.) I am a *total* stranger to music; it&apos;s never been a big part of my life, but it&apos;s hugely important to Mark. For our car trip, he prepared a 10.5-hour playlist, with songs by R&amp;R HoF inductees. By the time we arrived, I was educated! ::grin:: We spent an entire day at the museum - arriving at 10, when it opened, and leaving at 9, when it closed. (We took a brief break for lunch off-site, while we waited for afternoon crowds to clear, but otherwise, it was all-Hall-of-Fame, all-the-time. I found the most interesting bits to be the drafts of songs, especially songs that I knew, to see how they&apos;d changed over time, along with the Rolling Stone exhibit (the magazine, not the plural band), including snarky correspondence between the publisher and Hunter S. Thompson. All in all, a fine visit.

On Sunday, we went to the Cleveland Museum of Art. The museum is in the midst of a *huge* expansion and construction project. Having managed one small law library&apos;s transition during construction, I was *amazed* by how well the museum has set up its functioning during construction. Engaged docents directed traffic, clever displays showed the intended final museum, and the vast majority of the artwork was available for viewing. The collection reminded me a lot of the Minneapolis Institute of Art - every major time period and school of art is represented, and some artists are well-represented, without a gigantic collection of any single school. The entire museum was free, which was a wonderful surprise!

Along the way, we indulged in many of the restaurant recommendations received here - Trattoria in Little Italy, Tommy&apos;s on Conventry (once for a late dinner, and another night for fruit shakes - yum !), Mint Cafe for Thai... We tried to get into Melt Bar and Grilled on Cedar on Sunday night, but the wait at 7:30 p.m. was 1.5 hours - too long for us! We ate breakfast at Yours Truly in Shaker Heights, before heading home yesterday morning.

All in all, a fantastic getaway weekend, where the main attractions exceeded our expectations. We feel like we have things left over for a future-tense visit back to Cleveland!

Mindy, settling back into work... 
 Manager, International Tax 
 [ Jobs , Jobs (not Steve) ] ( Monster Job Search Results )
KY-Louisville, Yum ! Brands, Inc. is the world&apos;s largest restaurant company with more than 33,000 restaurant s in over 100 countries and territories and more than 840,000 employees worldwide. Four of our restaurant brands - KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut and Taco Bell - are the global leaders of the chicken, quick-service seafood, pizza and Mexican-style food categories respectively. A&amp;W; Restaurant s is the lon ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   KY-Louisville, Yum ! Brands, Inc. is the world&apos;s largest restaurant company with more than 33,000 restaurant s in over 100 countries and territories and more than 840,000 employees worldwide. Four of our restaurant brands - KFC, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut and Taco Bell - are the global leaders of the chicken, quick-service seafood, pizza and Mexican-style food categories respectively. A&amp;W; Restaurant s is the lon 
 #95067 - Tofu&amp; Yum Yum Sauce 
 [ Food ] ( TasteSpotting )
Tofu Yum Yum -easy&amp;delicious restaurant style Asian craving more? check out TasteSpotting ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   

Tofu Yum Yum -easy&amp;delicious restaurant style Asian...

craving more? check out TasteSpotting 

 
 Breaking Down the Restaurant Industry, Monopoly Style 
 [ Finance ] ( pfblogs.org: The Ad-Free Personal Finance Blogs Aggregator )
Jefferson Starship submits: The purpose of this piece is to take a look at the middle class restaurant industry as a whole and use an entertaining analogy to offer a way of comparing different companies within the sector.I have developed a list of 22 companies that fall into this category throwing out some for various reasons (i.e. Ark Restaurant s (ARKR) for being to upscale and Krispy Kreme (KKD) for having a negative price to earnings ratio). This industry has been broken into sub-categories, ...
 [details] [close] received 1 year ago  published 1 year ago  lang: en   Jefferson Starship submits: The purpose of this piece is to take a look at the middle class restaurant industry as a whole and use an entertaining analogy to offer a way of comparing different companies within the sector.I have developed a list of 22 companies that fall into this category throwing out some for various reasons (i.e. Ark Restaurant s (ARKR) for being to upscale and Krispy Kreme (KKD) for having a negative price to earnings ratio). This industry has been broken into sub-categories, including breakfast, fast order pizza, traditional restaurant s, fast food burger joints, fast food restaurant hybrids, coffee places, and Yum ! ( YUM ) because of their diversification.Complete Story » ... 
 Your Ad Here ©2010 Something Simpler Systems Inc. ( contact ) Categories [ close ]
	</body>
</document>
