<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006940" url="http://www.articlesbase.com/law-articles/attorney-questions-and-answers-1277233.html" time="2012-07-12-23:55" support="3" score="0.004294575952109793" bingtitle="Attorney questions and answers - Free Articles Directory | Submit ..." webtitle="Attorney questions and answers">
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Upon waiting for my order at a well known fast food restaurant, an employee referred to me a ... comes to settling issues such as divorce and child support ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Online Articles Directory 
 Why Submit Articles? Top Authors Top Articles FAQ AB Answers 

 Publish Article 
 
 Login Login via Register 

 Hello My Home Sign Out 
 Email 
 Password 
 Remember me?
 Lost Password? 
 Home Page &gt; Law &gt; Attorney questions and answers 
Attorney questions and answers
 Posted: Sep 28, 2009 |Comments: 0 | Views: 207 | 
 What charecteristics should I look for in a good paralegal? I&apos;m filing chapter 7 and I need a good paralegal. 
I live in the Los Angeles area. Does anyone out there know of a good paralegal specializing in bankruptcies who could help me out? I&apos;m not sure why you would want a paralegal. A paralegal is technically an attorney&apos;s.

 What decisions must an in-house attorney make after their company is sued, but before a trial team is hired? 
I want to know as much as possible about initial lawsuit decision making within corporations. What are the basic obligations of an in-house corporate ligation attorney? How do they assess the risks associated with a given lawsuit prior to discovery?.

 What do you do when a lawyer dumps you for questioning the bill? 
My divorce was final Sept last year. The bill came in the mail. Next came a letter from the state attorney general stating the division of property order was rejected because my lawyer used the wrong form. I sent a letter objecting to the invoice to.

 What does &apos;pursuant to&apos; mean? 
In reference to a paragraph in a contract written by an attorney addressing how real estate commissions were to be paid, the attorney said the commission shall be paid by the Seller on the first $13,250,000.00 of the Purchase Price pursuant to a separate agreement with the Seller. ??djective 1. proceeding after; following (usually.

 What does the grant letter of administration means? 
Its what my attorney wants from me,its something to do with my uncle&apos;s will,he passed away and in order for me to get his will,his attorney needs some documents from me and so he told me that i need to get a grant letter of administration or something about The Administration.

 What happens at a disposition hearing in a criminal case? 
you mean deposition? This is when either the prosecutor or defense attorney asks a witness or the person charged questions about what happened. Everything said is on record and is used as evidence in the case. - Dispostion is usually used in civil matters/child protection courts. This is.

 What happens if your ill parent will not sign the Power of Attorney form? 
Unfortunately, my mum is showing strong signs of dementia. In order to provide for her future, we were hoping that she would sign the enduring power of attorney form. As she lives on her own, we are worried that she will find it difficult to.

 What happens when someone refuses to comply with a subpoena? 
What are the normal consequences? (.if there are any) If the subpoena is signed by an attorney only, a motion will be made for an order to compel. You will be ordered to comply with the subpoena and likely to pay the costs of making the motion as well..

 What if someone shoots at a burglar in their house, but the bullet goes thru the wall and kills the neighbor? 
Are they liable? Not to sound like an attorney, but the answer does depend on the intent and motives of the shooter. In most states, a homeowner has a duty to retreat even before he can use deadly.

 What if the harasser is an attorney in a law firm? 
my daughter works in a law firm and get harrassed everyday by this one attorney.yesterday he held a file in his hands while insisting that something was missing out of it but refused to let her see the file to review before she could answer him. he just.

 What is a binding arbitration? 
My daughter was in a car accident almost 2 years ago, she was a passenger in her friends car. The person who hit them was found at fault however for him it was a fatal accident. My daughter just received a letter from her attorney advising the man&apos;s insurance co. would like to hold. 
 What is a medical agent? and what are legal aspects of appointing a medical agent? 
To make medical decisions and sign consent forms when you cannot do so for yourself. A &apos;medical power of attorney&apos; if you will. The person that acts on your behalf - your husband, children, siblings - should not be a professional who is.

 What is a Power of Attorney? 
A power of attorney is a document that evidences the creation of a relationship between two people who are designated as the &apos;principal&apos; and the &apos;agent&apos;. The principal designates the agent in the document, and the agent is authorized to act on the principal&apos;s behalf--to stand in the shoes of the principal--for.

 What is an executor of an estate? 
While an executor is responsible for ensuring the clauses in the decedent&apos;s will are carried out, they are also responsible for ensuring that the estate is properly handled and settled with respect to taxes and required filings. Generally, an executor will hire an attorney to assist him or her (referred to.

 What is Power of Attorney? 
we live in tennessee and my girlfriend and i are in a same sex relationship. we are raising a child together who is one month old now. what rights if any would i have regarding the child if she was to give me general power of attorney? the bioloigical father of the child has.

 What is the average hourly fee for an attorney in Los Angeles? 
Is $520/hr high for a wrongful termination case? Where can I find this information online? It doesn&apos;t matter where you are $520 is way high. Senior VP for a major company charged with securities fraud well that would be about right. A divorce with say 50 million.

 What is the difference between a general power of attorney and special power of attorney? 
A general power of attorney means you can pretty much sign for the other person for anything. A specific power of attorney limits that power to specific issues, such as for a real-estate purchase or medical decisions. - A general power attorney gives.

 What is the difference between a lawyer and an attorney? 
There is no difference. Some people just prefer one name over the other. - No difference: regardless of what you call them, they&apos;re cretins that contribute nothing worthwhile to our society. -RKO- 04/17/07 - Those are just two names for the same thing. - Well they are the.

 What is the difference between ethics and morals? 
Ethics are connected to a set of legal principals. Whereas morals are tied to social laws and concepts. Example: An attorney can be sanctioned for ethical lapses. A person with a morals does not behave in such a manner. - Ethics is near London, dont know where Morals is. -.

 What is the Miranda admonishment? 
The Miranda warning includes the following rights: 1. The right to remain silent; (anything the suspect says can be used against him/her; 2. The right to an attorney and to have the attorney present during questioning; 3. The right to appointed counsel if cannot afford an attorney; and 4. With that understanding of.

 What is the most effective way to get an attorney to represent a plaintiff &apos;pro bono&apos;? 
i am not trying to be flippant to your answer, since i hear this question so many times over. pro bono work is available in death penalty cases and some high profile civil rights violations. so to answer your question, there simply.

 What is the procedure of defensive asylum in sixth circuit? 
after taken fingerprints what next? http://www.usdoj.gov/eoir/efoia/newudms/.attorney http://www.berdklauss.com/?page_id=14. - Do NOT go to court without an attorney!! Your chance of receiving asylum without an attorney is about 1 in 40. Send me an email: mtp@mail.utexas.edu . I am a law student and have represented.

 What is the proper procedure in securing an attorney for slaunder issues? 
names and contact numbers for reference We can&apos;t answer this unless we know where you are. In my state, you can call the state bar office for referrals. - Slander is a hard thing to prove in court. Make sure you have your proof before you start..

 What is the statute of limitations for a felony in utah? 
Depends on the felony. Why? What did you do? - Yeah.Why? What are you planning to do? - http://www.justice.state.ut.us/.attorney - This is a question that is best put before an attorney. I would suggest contacting a criminal attorney in your area and asking him/her..

 What is the web site i can print free legal forms? 
i need to print a child support contempt form http://www.legalzoom.com/attorney Reviews of &apos;e-lawyering&apos; sites: http://online-legal-forms-review.toptenr. - there is no such site. you can preview forms for free, but all cost money. have your attorney do the form to ensure it is filled.

 What kind of a lawsuit can a person bring against the DA or The court for an injustice case? 
Charging someone for a crime under penal code P.C. 290 because the district attorney mentioned &apos;Well he thought of it&apos; What kind of a lawsuit can this person bring up against the district attorney&apos;s office, and also against that court.

 What kind of lawyer do I need to evict a tenant? 
I need to hire a lawyer to evict a tenant for non payemnt of rent. What kind of lawyer do I need? Do I need a real estate lawyer? what&apos;s the average fee to process the case? Thanks There is a specialized attorney that specializes in this type.

 What must be included in an opening statement for a trial? 
I have to write an opening statement for a mock trial. I was wondering what I have to include in it. What are the general requirements for all opening statements? I&apos;m a defense attorney. 1. Opening short statement of case theme. (&apos;This is a case about ____________ (greed,.

 What should i do? while having my tubes untied the nurse stuck herself and bled inside me. can i sue? 
they tested us both for diseases during my surgery but what if something shows up later? How do you know this? Did the nurse admit it? Sounds to me like you need to talk to a LOCAL malpractice attorney.

 What type of attorney do I need to file a discrimination lawsuit against a reputable food restaurant? 
Upon waiting for my order at a well known fast food restaurant, an employee referred to me a racist word in spanish not knowing I spoke and understood the language. I was devastated to know that he was a manager and used.

 What type of lawyer should I seek if I want to dispute charges from my previous landlord? 
My previous landlord is trying to collect on &apos;property damages&apos; that are exceedingly outrageous. What type of attorney should I seek in order to challenge these charges? Dear Friend, I can understand your problem. I will suggest you to take help from.

More Attorney questions please visit : LawFreeFAQ.com 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.articlesbase.com/law-articles/attorney-questions-and-answers-1277233.html &quot; lawfaq - About the Author: 


LawFreeFAQ.com

 
Questions and Answers
 Ask our experts your Law related questions here... Ask 200  Characters left 
 
 Why should we hire you interview question and answer ? 
 
 Why should we hire you questions and answers ? 
 
 Can i get an exhaustive list of questions and answers to ask from a customer looking for an e-commerce site 
 
 Rate this Article 1 2 3 4 5 vote(s) 0 vote(s) Feedback Print Re-Publish Source:   http://www.articlesbase.com/law-articles/attorney-questions-and-answers-1277233.html 
Article Tags:

 attorney 
 
 
Related Articles
 
Latest Law Articles
 
More from lawfaq
 
 
 Power Of Attorney - General Power Of Attorney: The Basics 
 
A power of attorney is a legal document. You use it to give someone the power to act for you. You are the principal. He is your agent. The person acting for you is also known as your &quot;attorney-in-fact.&quot;Two types of powers of attorney are the general power of attorney...
 By: Rex Bush, Doctor Of Jurisprudence, Attorney At Law l Law l Jul 21, 2009 l Views: 856 
 Charlotte Personal Injury Attorney - Hiring Advice 
 
A detailed summary on things to consider when deciding on a personal injury attorney in Charlotte NC.
 By: Charlotte Attorney l Law &gt; Personal Injury l Jun 03, 2009 l Views: 189 
 What Requires a Tax Attorney 
 
Even though the IRS would really like you to reckon that tax laws and regulations are monochrome, they truly are not. A tax attorney is aware of this and will make certain that those numerous hues of gray function for your benefit by utilizing loopholes and a finer, present comprehension of tax laws and regulations
 By: Tax Attorney l Finance &gt; Taxes l Sep 30, 2010 
 Franchise Attorneys and Franchise Consultants: Critical Evaluation Questions to Ask 
 
Evaluating franchise attorneys and evaluating franchise consultants can seem a daunting task. But the firm a company selects to assist its entry into franchising, refine existing franchise efforts or make franchise opportunity investment decisions will have profound consequences. While asking for a list of references is one approach (and when is anyone ever dumb enough to provide a bad reference?) there are more objective criteria that are not dependent on selectively disseminated information.
 By: Kevin B. Murphy, Franchise Attorney, MBA - Mr. Franchise l Business &gt; Ask an Expert l Jul 25, 2008 l Views: 707 l Comments: 2 
 Looking For A DUI Attorney? Here Are Some Steps! 
 
One night you&apos;re out enjoying your time with some friends and decide to have a few drinks too many, and you decide that you want to ride in the car while intoxicated, then you get arrested for driving under the influence on a night where you didn&apos;t expect it, then it is important that you look for a Firm that has known and outstanding
 By: Seattle DUi Attorney l Law &gt; Health and Safety l Jul 18, 2011 
 A Dallas Family Attorney Knows the Nuances of Family Law 
 
There are so many attorneys out there that have plenty of in-depth knowledge and experience when it comes to settling issues such as divorce and child support as there are also many family issues that arise where the assistance of a Dallas family attorney must be sought.
 By: Attorney in Dallas l Law l Mar 03, 2011 
 Defining a Successful Attorney-Client Relationship 
 
A successful attorney-client relationship means more than just a winning case. To ensure success, make sure the relationship you have with your attorney meets these qualifications.
 By: Brooke Haley l Law l Jul 10, 2012 
 Why Everyone Should Make a Will 
 
Your last will and testament, everyone should have one but you would be surprised at the large percentage of people who do not even consider making any preparations for when they have gone. In 2011 it was estimated that around 70 percent of UK adults had not written a will of any sort.
 By: Chris Smith l Law l Jul 08, 2012 
 Seeking Out the Services of a Criminal Attorney 
 
It is never a small thing or a having a laugh matter when you are billed with a criminal activity.
 By: Ryan Andrews. l Law l Jul 07, 2012 
 Get Compensation With Personal Injury Attorneys For Moreno Valley From The Party Responsible 
 
The personal injury attorneys for Moreno Valley will file the compensation for you and will also fight on behalf of your case and ensure that your losses are compensated.
 By: samvega l Law l Jul 06, 2012 
 Do You Need a Child Custody Attorney? 
 
Your lawyer can help you decide if mediation is the best way of working out a settlement in your case, and if it is, he or she can help you find a mediator who is qualified and fair.
 By: George Patel l Law l Jul 05, 2012 
 Attorney Questions&amp;Answers 
 
During a deposition what does the wrod&apos;Form&apos;mean?
After the Plaintiff&apos;s attorney asks the Defendent a question and the Defendent&apos;s Attorney says&apos;Form&apos;what does that mean? The attorney that says&apos;Form&apos;is objecting the question. Even though the defendant must answer the question, the attorney is reserving the right to object to and question that particular testimony.
 By: lawfaq l Law l Mar 31, 2010 
 Legal Questions&amp;Answers 
 
This question is for people that say pot is bad and morally wrong.?
Many people say pot is very bad for you because its a illegal drug and breaking the law. What about Salvia, this drug is perfectly legal in the United States and still gets you high. Since this drug is legal, their would be nothing wrong with.
 By: lawfaq l Law l Mar 31, 2010 
 Case Law Q&amp;a 
 
why should judges make law?
advantages and disadvantages of judges making law when is case law being made? uses of judicial review how can case law benefit others? how can case law meed the needs of people? Judges don&apos;t make the law, they interpret it. It is the duty of the legislature, who is independent of the judiciary, to.
 By: lawfaq l Law l Mar 31, 2010 
 Lawyers Faq 
 
Do legal aid lawyers work for the state?
And if so, if you needed to use a legal aid attorney to help you appeal for disability - would they really be on your side or the states? Legal Aid does not work the for the State. However, public defender&apos;s do. Public defenders are still expected to be adversarial to.
 By: lawfaq l Law l Mar 31, 2010 
 Attorney Q&amp;a 
 
Can you call the police and file a report about your attorney&apos;s malpractice? I want to know if you can call the police and report about your attorney doing malpractice on your case such as refusing to turn your money in client&apos;s trust fund after dateline of your demand and so much things, but that&apos;s the most important thing.
 By: lawfaq l Law l Mar 16, 2010 
Discuss this Article
 Author Navigation 
 My Home Publish Article View/Edit Articles View/Edit Q&amp;A; Edit your Account Manage Authors Statistics Page Article Widget 

 My Home Edit your Account Update Profile View/Edit Q&amp;A; Publish Article 
 Author Box lawfaq has 75 articles online Contact Author Subscribe to RSS Print article Send to friend Re-Publish article Articles Categories All Categories Advertising Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive Beauty Business Careers Computers Education Finance Food and Beverage Health Hobbies Home and Family Home Improvement Internet Law Marketing News and Society Relationships Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports and Fitness Technology Travel Writing Law Bankruptcy Copyright Criminal Cyber Law Health and Safety Immigration Intellectual Property Internet Law National, State, Local Patents Personal Injury Regulatory Compliance Trademarks Need Help? 
 Contact Us FAQ Submit Articles Editorial Guidelines Blog 
 Site Links 
 Recent Articles Top Authors Top Articles Find Articles Site Map Mobile Version 
 Webmasters 
 RSS Builder RSS 
 Business Info 
 Advertising 
 Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the Terms Of Use and Privacy Policy | User published content is licensed under a Creative Commons License .
 Copyright © 2005-2012 Free Articles by ArticlesBase.com, All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
