<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006542" url="http://www.career.vi/employee/Cooks,_Restaurant_G___D_Seafood_2077.html" time="2012-07-12-23:28" support="5" score="0.014578834586739602" bingtitle="Cook(Cooks, Restaurant) @ St. Thomas | Apply for this job at Career.vi" webtitle="Cook(Cooks, Restaurant) @ St. Thomas | Apply for this job at Career.vi">
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>... Seafood)Detail:Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant ... Read food order slips or receive verbal ... orders to customers at windows, counters, or tables.</description>
	<body>
		Follow Us On   
 
 22677 Job Applications For 3765 Total Jobs Posted By 709 Companies 
 
 
 
 
 
 Username*:  Password*:  Remember Me   Forgot Password or Username? 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 
 

 
 All Cities St. John St. Croix St. Thomas Jost Van Dyke Virgin Gorda Anegada Tortola     Or click here for advanced search   
 
 
 
      Keywords Location All Cities St. John St. Croix St. Thomas Jost Van Dyke Virgin Gorda Anegada Tortola Job Category Career Level Doesn&apos;t Matter Accounts Advertising Analysis Architects Business Development Chemist Clerical/Admin Client Services Communication and Media Corporate Affairs Creative Customer Service Customer Support Data Entry Database Administrator(DBA) Design Doesn&apos;t Matter Education Engineering Executive Mangement Financial Services Food Services General Management Hardware Human Resource Import and Export Information Technology and Automation Intern Judicial System Legal Affairs Maintenance Management Consulting Manufacturing Marketing Media - Electronic Media - Print Medicine and Health Networking Operations Planning and Development Procurement and Supply Chain Product Development Product Management Production Project Management Public Relations Purchase Quality Assurance (QA) Researcher Retail Sales Service Quality Software Development Summer Internship Supply Chain Management Systems Analyst Telemarketing Training Travel/Airlines Web Development Writer Other - Select One - Entry Level Student (Undergraduate/Graduate) Experienced 

 (Non-Manager) Manager Executive (SVP, VP, Department Head, etc) Senior Executive (President, CEO, CFO, etc)   Experience Salary   Doesn&apos;t Matter Fresh 1 Year 2 Years 3 Years 4 Years 5 Years 6 Years 7 Years 8 Years 9 Years 10 Years 11 Years 12 Years 13 Years 14 Years 15 Years More than 15 Years Doesn&apos;t Matter More than 5,000 More than 10,000 More than 20,000 More than 30,000 More than 40,000 More than 50,000 More than 100,000 More than 150,000 More than 250,000 Job Type   Doesn&apos;t Matter Permanent Part Time Full Time Contract Internship Volunteer Show jobs with salary information only.     Search Results Display Options  Sort search results by:    Relevance   Date View jobs updated within: Doesn&apos;t Matter Last 1 Day Last 2 Days Last 7 Days Last 30 Days Last 60 Days 
   Close Advanced Search 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 Cook - ONET Job Title: (Cooks, Restaurant) 
 Industry: Full-Service Restaurants 
 
 Apply for this job: Note to Employer: 
 Select Your Resume: - Select One - Customer Service finance Schuster Resume TYSHANNA PHILLIPS PDF Resume Brittani Belange resume Dependable multi-tasking Individual Ms.Foy Resume Updated Resume Urbeensier J-Febres Nikisha Charles Cherene Watson seans resume Archer--Summer Employment--Internship Diarra Thomas KiahMuller Employment Archive 2012 Resume annazar&apos;s Resume VWiltshire Resume OR Upload your Resume   
 
 
 Already a member? Sign In | Register 
 
   Job Details 
 Back to Job Listing   
 
 
 Job Title:   Cook ONET Job Title:   Cooks, Restaurant Industry:   Full-Service Restaurants Job Type:   Permanent Job Shift:   First Shift (Day) Job Location:   St. Thomas Minimum Education:   High School Diploma Career Level:   Experienced 

 (Non-Manager) Maximum Experience:   3 Years Work Permit:   Virgin Islands (US) Required Travel:   Not Required Apply By:   Apr 30, 2011 

 
 
 Job Description: 


 Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited menu. Duties of the cooks are limited to preparation of a few basic items and normally involve operating large-volume single-purpose cooking equipment. 
 


 Skills Required 

 
 
 Clean food preparation areas, cooking surfaces, and utensils. Cook the exact number of items ordered by each customer, working on several different orders simultaneously. Maintain sanitation, health, and safety standards in work areas. Measure ingredients required for specific food items being prepared. Operate large-volume cooking equipment such as grills, deep-fat fryers, or griddles. Read food order slips or receive verbal instructions as to food required by patron, and prepare and cook food according to instructions. Verify that prepared food meets requirements for quality and quantity. Wash, cut, and prepare foods designated for cooking. Clean, stock, and restock workstations and display cases. Order and take delivery of supplies. Schedule activities and equipment use with managers, using information about daily menus to help coordinate cooking times. Serve orders to customers at windows, counters, or tables. Take food and drink orders and receive payment from customers. 
 
 


 Company Information More jobs from this company   Company Name: G&amp;D Seafood
 Company Description: 
 Restaurant 
 
          
 Confirm Are you sure you wish to see the number of people competing for this job. Note: This will use &apos;1&apos; credit from your account within 24 hours? Show No LEARN MORE Confirm Job Agent feature will require &apos;5&apos; credits per Job Agent Set up. Are you sure you wish to set up Job Agent? 
       No         Yes    Learn more about job agent   
 
 
 Career Post Home Headlines Career Tips Employer Insight Career Growth Job Market Ask the Experts 
 
 Jobs By Location St. John St. Thomas St. Croix Tortal Anegada Jost Van Dyke Virgin Gorda 
 
 Career.VI About Career.VI Job Market in VI Media Privacy Policy by TRUSTe Site Map Terms and Conditions Company Listings FAQs Contact Us Partnership RSS 
 
 Discussion forum    Common Questions to ask the Interviewer    How to Handle Difficult Interview Situations    Common Interview Questions    The Importance of Research    Self Confidence 
 
 
 
 
 
 Powered By 
 International Business Development | New Business Development | Economic Development Authority | Reduce Taxes | Career Assessment | Career Guidance | Career Mapping | Career Management Copyright 2012 Career.VI
- Top Virgin Islands Jobs - All Rights Reserved.
Reproduction of material from any Career.VI pages without permission is strictly prohibited.
	</body>
</document>
