<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006250" url="http://www.inquisitr.com/140947/white-castle-connoisseur-martin-kessman-sues-fast-food-chain-over-booth-sizes/" time="2012-07-12-22:56" support="5" score="0.01759493113574722" bingtitle="White Castle Connoisseur, Martin Kessman, Sues Fast Food Chain ..." webtitle="White Castle Connoisseur, Martin Kessman, Sues Fast Food Chain Over Booth Sizes">
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>... pounds and says that he has no problem using airline seats or finding a place to sit ... that could accommodate a person that merely wanted to sit down and eat his meal.”</description>
	<body>
		HOME NEWS 
 Business Media Industry Politics 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 Celebrity News Movies Music TV 
 TECHNOLOGY 
 Gadgets Green Tech Mobile Start-Up Social Media 
 SPORTS 
 Baseball Basketball Football Hockey Racing Soccer Summer Olympics 
 HEALTH SCIENCE GAMING LIFESTYLE 
 Fashion Shopping 
 WORLD FUNNY 
 Pics Videos 
 SUBSCRIBE 
 Full RSS Feed Daily Email Twitter Facebook Technology Feed Gaming Feed News Feed Sport Feed Entertainment Feed Funny&amp;Strange Feed World Feed Lifestyle Feed 
 
 
   White Castle Connoisseur, Martin Kessman, Sues Fast Food Chain Over Booth Sizes
 Posted: September 12, 2011 
 

Martin Kessman loves his White Castle. But according to a new lawsuit filed by the White Castle connoisseur, it is impossible for a man of his size to enjoy a White Castle meal inside the restaurant. Why? Because White Castle doesn’t have booths big enough to accommodate the restaurant’s overweight customers.
 
This, according to Kessman, violates the civil rights of fat people.

Kessman says that the Americans With Disabilities Act is:
 
“applicable, not only to me, but to pregnant women and to handicapped people. I just want to sit down like a normal person.”
 
The 64-year-old stockbroker weighs in at 290 pounds and says that he has no problem using airline seats or finding a place to sit at other fast food chains. But White Castle uses stationary booths, which apparently, are not one size fits all.

Kessman wrote a letter to White Castle in 2009 when he finally got fed up from banging his knees and squeezing in his gut as he sat at a White Castle booth. Kessman wrote:
 
“As I looked around the restaurant, I saw that there were no tables and chairs that could accommodate a person that merely wanted to sit down and eat his meal.”
 
According to the New York Post, White Castle sent back a few condescending letters, a few coupons for some sliders (cheese not included) and a hollow promise to make larger booths.

Kessman said:
 
“They sent me specs and everything, about how the booths were going to be enlarged and made comfortable for people with a little more weight. So two and a half years went by, and nothing was done.”
 
Kessman is suing the burger chain for bigger chairs and unspecified damages.

So should White Castle be required to provide seating for obese people? My guess is that the majority of White Castle patrons, like Martin Kessman, have a few extra pounds around their waists. It’s probably in White Castle’s best interest to give them a place to sit.

 Category: Odd + Funny 
 Tags : civil rights , martin kessman , obesity , white castle 
 Posted: September 12, 2011 
By Dan Evon
 
 More Posts By Dan Evon 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
Comments

 
21 Archived Responses to“White Castle Connoisseur, Martin Kessman, Sues Fast Food Chain Over Booth Sizes”

 Jeremy Clodfelter 
 Sep 12, 2011 
 
I fit in the seats just fine at 375 come need money please.
 Chris Rathbun 
 Sep 12, 2011 
 
the way i see it is this man is right my girlfriend was just recently pregnant with twins and we went to white castles cause thats what she was craving and she could not sit down in the booth they only have booths nw at white castles they should have tables and chairs also not everybody like sitting at a booth some can sit at a booth so stop being hatred and understand this mans and my concerns
 Jaime Sanchez 
 Sep 13, 2011 
 
He shouldn&apos;t be suing WC they should be charging him to put in a larger seat just like the airlines.
 Joe FatthenFitnow Leonardi 
 Sep 13, 2011 
 
I was in his shoes at one point in my life, but I never expected the world to change for my bad choices. http://fatthenfitnow.wordpress.com/2011/09/13/i-was-martin-kessman-2/ 
 Andrea Disanferdinand 
 Sep 13, 2011 
 
I think Mr. Kessler should ponder the idea that once you can&apos;t squeeze your body into a booth, perhaps White Castle (and similar fast food restaurants) isn&apos;t the sort of place he needs to be eating in.
 Chris Mason 
 Sep 13, 2011 
 
The very fact some asshole judge will probably allow this to proceed is a major part of what is wrong with our judicial system. When you choose to be that weight you live with the consequences.
 Lee Kairis 
 Sep 13, 2011 
 
The mentality that he is suing under&quot;Americans with Disabilities Act&quot;is pretty disturbing. I guess he sees himself as a victim who should take no responsiblity for what got him there in the first place
 Joshua Kohler 
 Sep 14, 2011 
 
Fuck this guy. He&apos;s a shining example of what&apos;s horribly fucked up about our legal system / civil lawsuits in this country.
He can have his picture taken next to the dickheads that sued because coffee is apparently served hot, and the McDonalds that didn&apos;t refuse service to an overweight kid who&apos;s granny sent him there with money twice a day.
 Jacob Hathcock 
 Sep 14, 2011 
 
Look if you have to&quot;squeez your gut&quot;into a booth that&apos;s a friendly way of saying your way to fat and for you to lose some fuckin weight….Try for just once to be a decent human being and EARN your money the old fashion way….WORK…stop being lazy and trying to steal money from a person who had an idead (although an unhealthy one) it was still a idea that made THEM rich not you, quit riding their coat tail.
 Jessi Carlsen 
 Sep 14, 2011 
 
wow
 Jacob Hathcock 
 Sep 14, 2011 
 
Chris Rathbun not really agreeing with u, ur girlfriend wasnt fat becaise she was eating fast food and double fisting 1/4 pounders SHE WAS PREGNANT and with twins (congrats by the way) this guy isnt he is LAZY…I do however agree that they probably should put in some tables…however it is their restaraunt and their choice on who they want to accomodate…i mean really are you going to change the furniture in your own home because a&quot;fat&quot;person came by and said they couldnt fit in ur chair???
 Christopher Fox 
 Sep 15, 2011 
 
Only in America! What a stupid, lazy, self-entitled, fat piece of shit!
 April Arroyo-Monroe 
 Sep 15, 2011 
 
This is just beyond pathetic, sad and embarassing…
 Adam Gadberry 
 Sep 15, 2011 
 
he&apos;ll sue…and not win
 Adam Gadberry 
 Sep 15, 2011 
 
but will settle….
 Jervis Hill 
 Sep 20, 2011 
 
Do some exercise!
 Joann Hill 
 Sep 20, 2011 
 
Do you remember the Prince Castle in LaSalle? We used to go there very rarely but I do remember that they had square hamburgers and the shakes were called On In A Million. Bonehead Locke used to come to the movies with a huge bag of burgers from there that he ate watching the show. LOL.
 Jervis Hill 
 Sep 21, 2011 
 
Joann Hill Pauly Weber used to go there because he was I love with Carol, who worked there. I didn&apos;t care for her–I liked JoAnn Ficeck (sp.)?
 Joann Hill 
 Sep 21, 2011 
 
Carol who?
 Heather Johnson 
 Mar 23, 2012 
 
Sorry, but being grossly overweight is rarely a legitimate disability. Stop eating all the fast food, lose a few pounds, and then you&apos;ll fit in the booth. Us normal-sized people don&apos;t want to sit in ginormous booths just so fat people can comfortably sit down and get fatter.
 Heather Johnson 
 Mar 23, 2012 
 
Sorry, but being grossly overweight is rarely a legitimate disability. Stop eating all the fast food, lose a few pounds, and then you&apos;ll fit in the booth. Us normal-sized people don&apos;t want to sit in ginormous booths just so fat people can comfortably sit down and get fatter.
	</body>
</document>
