<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006371" url="http://employmentagency.jobamatic.com/a/jobs/find-jobs/q-Order+Selector" time="2012-07-12-23:14" support="4" score="0.021304062227400004" bingtitle="Order Selector Jobs - Employment Agency" webtitle="Order Selector Jobs - Employment Agency">
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="57"/>
	<description>This is an Order Picking Packing ... food products for a fast food restaurant ... During down times, the Order Selector also performs the duties of bagger and/or cashier.</description>
	<body>
		Order Selector jobs
  Subscribe to RSS Feed Post a Job Only $29 for 30 days Keywords Location   Exact within 5 miles within 10 miles within 15 miles within 25 miles within 50 miles   
 
 Posted Job Title Company Location 
 Looking to hire? Post your job today! 
 Featured Job Postings from the Web Jul 09 Order Selector Pick N&apos; Save Milwaukee, WI 
 Order Selectors(Part-time) Headquartered in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Roundy&apos;s Supermarkets, ... opportunities available for warehouse order selectors in our distribution center... more 
 Jun 13 Piece Picker Order Selector CSI Health Somerset, PA 
Piece Picker/ Order Selector Price and pack merchandise in trays to fill orders for shipment to stores. Ability to read, write and count accurately. Ability to work in seasonally... more 
 More Job Postings from the Web Jul 12 Warehouse order selector Phoenix Personnel Byron Center, MI 
Pick orders from pick ticket. Operate forklift to pick orders. Pack and ship orders
 

 
Previous forklift experience, must pass warehouse test, drug screen required Lift up to... more 
 Jul 10 Warehouse Order Selector Kroger Co Ohio 
Ohio is currently hiring for Warehouse Order Selectors. Earn a Great Salary with Excellent Benefits!!!

* Starting pay at $12.50/hr
* 6 Month Retention Bonus
* Earn up to... more 
 Jul 10 Warehouse Order Selectors Future Force Personnel Florida 
Companies in the Miami area is seeking Order Selectors. We are a Drug-free Workplace ... May complete requisition forms to order supplies from other plant departments. more 
 Jul 10 Order Selector - Freezer C&amp;S Wholesale Grocers York, PA 
used and the selector hears the item in the order to be picked from the slot. In other ... production and safety standards.
* Read an Order Sheet or use a headset to find... more 
 Jul 09 Order Selector Animal Supply Company Washington 
1 ORDER SELECTOR OVERALL

To ensure that Animal Supply Co. is Delivering Success to our ... to read Tote Packs, customer order labels, and all other shipping... more 
 Jul 06 Now Hiring Order Selectors !! Department of Workforce Services West Valley, UT 
Now Hiring Order Selectors!! nbsp; If you are looking for a Career with potential for ... company. We are currently hiring full time Order Selectors to start immediately!... more 
 Jul 06 Warehouse Order Selector Andrews Corpus Christi, TX 
JOB DESCRIPTION TITLE: Warehouse Order Selector JOB FAMILY: Warehouse ANDREWS DISTRIBUTING ... INNOVATIVE CUSTOMER FOCUS Warehouse Order Selector Warehouse Core Competencies... more 
 Jul 06 Order Selector AmeriCold Logistics Virginia 
services in the U.S., is seeking Order Selectors to join the team at its Salem, Virginia facility.

Primary Responsibilities:

Prepare and load voice template into Talkman unit... more 
 Jul 05 Night Order Selector U.S. Foodservice Fife, WA 
pallet, labeling the selected cases with the order labels and using Voxware Voice ... Minimum six months experience working with manual order selection/ order filling systems,... more 
 Jul 05 Warehouse Order Selector -Night Shift Performance Food Group Lebanon, TN 
with a company that really delivers!

The Selector position will perform the following duties:

 Selects grocery products to accurately fill customer orders.
 Safely operates... more 
 Jul 03 Order Selector Econofoods Bloomington, IN 
but not limited to, reading and interpreting order forms and selection labels. Basic ... to ensure such equipment is in good working order .

*
Reports damaged and/or out-of-stock... more 
 Jul 03 Warehouse Order Selector Food Services of America Billings, MT 
requires a valid Driver License Night Order Selector Job Fair: July 12th at 6:00pm ... schedule of driver. Label each customer order and review order for completion. Must... more 
 Jul 01 IL Warehouse Order Selector - Full-Time or Part-Time Dot Foods Mount Sterling, IL 
Warehouse Order Selector Department: Dry, Freezer&amp;Refrigerated Warehouse
Location: Mt ... the English language

Job
: Warehouse Order Selector Schedule
: Full-time

Primary... more 
 Jun 28 Industrial Athletes/ Order Selectors NEW HIGHER STARTING RATE! Manpower Fort Wayne, IN 
in how to make things better. As a full-time Order Selector for our client, Fort Wayne&apos;s ... today. Background check and drug screen required. Order Selector , Forklift,... more 
 Jun 26 Warehouse Order Selector Core-mark International Minneapolis, MN 
throughout our facility:

- Cooler Order Selector - Completes Product Inventory ... lift 50 lbs constantly.

- Single cell Order Selector -
Retrieves order from scanner and... more 
 Jun 22 Order Selector Davis Companies Marlborough, MA 
 Order Selector Order Selector Pay: $11-11.40 hr Marlborough, MA Contract to Hire Handling ... up. Person is given an order , will pick order from correct area using bar code system... more 
 Jun 21 WAREHOUSE- ORDER SELECTOR Adecco Austinburg, OH 
Warehouse- Order Selector - Associates will drive self powered pallet jacks. The order ... size. Associates must be able to use audio selector equipment and working in varying... more 
 Jun 20 ORDER SELECTOR Nash Finch Company Jessup, MD 
but not limited to, reading and interpreting order forms and selection labels. Basic ... to ensure such equipment is in good working order . AReports damaged and/or out-of-stock... more 
 Jun 14 Order Selector /Frozen Food (11081) Frozen/Grocery Warehouse (DIS) Safeway Auburn, WA 
This position is an entry level warehouse worker responsible for selecting and palletizing cases of merchandise for shipment from the frozen food warehouse to the retail grocery... more 
 Jun 12 Order Selector Recruit Gaap Albuquerque, NM 
The Distribution industry is seeking an Order Selector for the Albuquerque, NM area. Recruit GAAP seeks someone who can successfully perform the following scope of... more 
 Jun 12 Order Selectors Staffmark Oklahoma City, OK 
Northeast side warehouse/distribution center seeking 1st and 2nd shift order selectors ... Prior experience in warehouse/ order selecting required... more 
 May 20 2nd Shift Order Selector Belcan Franklin, IN 
Reads shipping order and/or picking order to determine items to be moved, gathered, or dis ... places product items on pallets according to order fill instructions or special... more 
 Mar 30 Warehouse Associates, Order Selectors , Quality Auditors, Forklift Automation Personnel Services Fairburn, GA 
Needed: Warehouse Associates, Order Selectors, Quality Auditors, Forklift Operators (with ... reconciliation Experience driving a Man-up Order Selector is a plus. Experience in WMS... more 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next&gt; 
 Jobs by 
 
Refine your search:
 
 
Title

 Order Selector Warehouse Order Selector Warehouse Incentive Selector Delivery Driver/warehouse Teammate Selector Selector Night Part-Time Selector, Night Warehouse Selector Warehouse Worker Order Selectors See More » 
 
Company

 Harris Teeter C&amp;S Wholesale Grocers Performance Food Group U.S. Foodservice C&amp;S Wholesale Grocers Dot Foods US Foods Aerotek C&amp;S Wholesale Foods See More » 
 
Job Type

 Full-time Part-time Contract Permanent Temporary Internship Seasonal See More »
	</body>
</document>
