<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006404" url="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/ShowTopic-g147262-i230-k5059681-Meal_prices_in_and_around_Coconut_Court_and_taxi_s-Barbados.html" time="2012-07-12-23:16" support="1" score="0.00021248354087796616" bingtitle="Meal prices in and around Coconut Court and taxi&apos;s - Barbados ..." webtitle="Meal prices in and around Coconut Court and taxis - Barbados Message Board - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>... questions and offering advice on topics like &quot;Meal ... is also in Hastings where the four of you can eat ... of you.The kids will love Chefette, our local fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home Barbados 
 Barbados Tourism Barbados Hotels Barbados Holiday Rentals Flights to Barbados Barbados Restaurants Barbados Attractions Barbados Travel Forum Barbados Photos Barbados Guide 
 Hotels Flights Holiday Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
Barbados
 
 Barbados Tourism Barbados Hotels Holiday Rentals Flights to Barbados Barbados Hotel Deals More On Barbados Restaurants Things to Do Travel Forums Photos Videos Barbados Deals Hotel&amp;Air All Travel Offers Travel Guide 
 Free Newsletter 
Interested in Barbados ?

We&apos;ll send you updates with the latest deals, reviews and articles for Barbados each week.
 
Recently Reviewed Hotels in Barbados 
 
 Accra Beach Hotel&amp;Spa 370 Reviews Last reviewed 12 Jul 2012 #17 of 37 hotels in Christ Church
 Sunswept Beach Hotel 114 Reviews Last reviewed 12 Jul 2012 #2 of 2 hotels in Holetown, Barbados
 Butterfly Beach Hotel 640 Reviews Last reviewed 9 Jul 2012 #14 of 37 hotels in Christ Church
 Cobblers Cove 167 Reviews Last reviewed 10 Jul 2012 #10 of 104 hotels in Barbados, Caribbean
 Tamarind by Elegant Hotels 428 Reviews Last reviewed 8 Jul 2012 #1 of 1 hotels in Paynes Bay, Saint James
 All Seasons Resort Europa 211 Reviews Last reviewed 6 Jul 2012 #1 of 1 hotels in Sunset Crest, Barbados
 Mango Bay Resort 607 Reviews Last reviewed 6 Jul 2012 #1 of 2 hotels in Holetown, Barbados
 Magic Isle Beach Apartments 66 Reviews Last reviewed 5 Jul 2012 #16 of 97 speciality lodging in Barbados
 South Beach Hotel 79 Reviews Last reviewed 4 Jul 2012 #19 of 37 hotels in Christ Church
 Almond Beach Village 1,703 Reviews Last reviewed 3 Jul 2012 #1 of 3 hotels in Speightstown
 Tropical Winds Apartment Hotel 18 Reviews Last reviewed 21 Jun 2012 #2 of 4 hotels in Saint Philip, Barbados
 Rostrevor 155 Reviews Last reviewed 11 Jun 2012 #15 of 37 hotels in Christ Church
 Legend Garden Condos 48 Reviews Last reviewed 20 May 2012 #23 of 104 hotels in Barbados, Caribbean
 Royal Westmoreland 34 Reviews Last reviewed 4 May 2012 #11 of 23 hotels in Saint James, Barbados
 Maresol Beach Apartments 17 Reviews Last reviewed 27 Apr 2012 #60 of 104 hotels in Barbados, Caribbean
 
 Explore the world! TripAdvisor has reviews and information on over 400,000 locations, including: Travel Destinations 
 Sri Lanka Bled hotels 
 Hotels 
 Residence Hotel Bad Fallenbach Sahara Beach in Monastir Beales Hotel Hatfield Racz Hotel&amp;Thermal Spa in Budapest Stone Mountain State Park Holiday Inn London - Regent&apos;s Park El Plantio Golf Resort in Alicante Marina Corfu Majorca 
 
 Home 
 Caribbean Barbados Forums 
 
 
Barbados Forum: Meal prices in and around Coconut Court and taxi&apos;s
 
Hotels travellers are raving about...

 Beach View 268 Reviews Saint James, Barbados Read reviews Hilton Barbados 823 Reviews Saint Michael, Barbados Read reviews Turtle Beach by Elegant Hotels 1,120 Reviews Dover, Barbados Read reviews 
 All hotels in Barbados (104) Top questions about BARBADOS 
   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=230&amp;g;=147262&amp;faqid;=946&amp;qid;=2899 When is the best time to visit?   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=230&amp;g;=147262&amp;faqid;=946&amp;qid;=2898 How do I get to Barbados? 
 BARBADOS Itineraries 
   ABS:ForumItinerary?action=detail&amp;i;=230&amp;g;=147262&amp;id;=330 Day trips: Beach   ABS:ForumItinerary?action=detail&amp;i;=230&amp;g;=147262&amp;id;=331 Weekend trips: Night Life 
 Collected by our Destination Experts Babiface 1,328 forum posts BBDSBEAUTY 1,008 forum posts BGIWorldTraveller 8,765 forum posts butterflysue1 2,355 forum posts footychick 2,023 forum posts forestred 1,281 forum posts glittergirl85 974 forum posts InBarbados 1,897 forum posts kirimist 3,049 forum posts LittleMissRed 1,782 forum posts LoisInsiderTips 1,456 forum posts Scary 5,502 forum posts Sunniebgi 3,334 forum posts uktripfan 1,687 forum posts 
 Members who are extremely knowledgeable about this destination and answer travellers’ questions frequently. Free Barbados Guide 
Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.
 Grab it and Go! Beyond destination forums 
 Air Travel 
 › See all Which Barbados hotels are on sale?
	</body>
</document>
