<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006649" url="http://brandsandtags.com/List_of_Slogans.html" time="2012-07-12-23:38" support="2" score="0.003603119418304615" bingtitle="Catchy, creative slogans and taglines" webtitle="Catchy Slogan | Creative Slogan Examples | Clever Taglines">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>The wins of change ... (Fast food restaurant slogan / tagline) Rever Computer ... facility located at highest point in county) Consler Performance Line</description>
	<body>
		brandsandtags.com:  Memorable names, meaningful taglines and slogans.  Branding and positioning that differentiates you from the crowd.   Your Subtitle text 
 Branding&amp;Slogans/Home Brand Names / Examples Slogan Examples $477 Slogan Ideas Pack Branding Articles 101 Great Meeting Themes Company Logo Design Bio&amp;Experience The REAL Voice Talent 101 Best Slogans List 
 Watch our Video on How to Create a Meaningful, Catchy Slogan or Clever Tagline   Recently Created Meaningful, Catchy Slogans and Clever Tag Lines 
 royaltyfreeroads.com
 Get there faste r  
(For web site providing professional photos of highways and travel destinations)

furniture.ie
 Dream it. Find It. Love It! 
(Web site slogan and corporate tagline)

Atlas Pools and Recreation
 Water. Wellness. Wonderful!
 (Pool and spa dealer)

 
Sentinel Lighting Systems
 Lighting That Outperforms 
(Commercial lighting system)

The Dorman Real Estate Services
 The art of real estate, the science of success 
(Slogan for realtor and real estate company)

The Lancaster School
 Engaging minds, empowering success 
(K-12 school tag line)

 Vestopia Real investors, real money, real-time . (Web site and corporate positioning)
 
 Northwest Community Association NWCA: Building a better Northwest, one block at a time 
(Non-profit organization tag line)

 Sovereign Wealth Management 
Expertise for changing time s (Investment advisor advertising slogan ) 

 Christian Mission to Egypt Good works, good words–a cross-cultural Christian outreach 
(Non-profit organization)

 Annual Meeting Theme for Company with Recent Acquisitions The wins of change (Conference and meeting theme) 
 
 How a Meaningful Slogan or Tagline Can Advance Your Brand Positioning 

 A meaningful identity takes your brand name further and makes it more powerful. If you&apos;re Rever Corporation, maker of a notebook computer with a built-in projector, prospects may think it&apos;s just another laptop PC. They don&apos;t know what makes it different and better. 
 When you position the notebook with the advertising slogan, &quot;The first notebook computer with an 8-foot screen,&quot; you&apos;ve instantly created differentiation and immediately added greater perceived value. Your sales prospect thinks: &quot;What are they talking about?,&quot;and wants to learn more. Now the value of this brand&apos;s appeal has been taken to a higher level, thanks to meaningful positioning. 
 If you&apos;d like to create a new or improved brand name or company, product or service slogan or tag line, call or e-mail. Chuck Ingersoll. 585.746.2320. 
 E-mail me 
 
 
 5 Keys to a Great Advertising Slogan
 
 1) Avoid self-aggrandizement 
Instead of saying &quot;Nobody makes a better fran-o-stat than Acme,&quot; consider what&apos;s in it for the prospect/customer. &quot;Get there faster,&quot; my strapline for Royalty Free Roads&apos; web site, provides a benefit for the person searching for stock photos of highways and locations. You&apos;re all about (or should be all about) offering advantages to the customer, and your advertising slogan should communicate this.
 
 2) Remember that emotion trumps rationality 
Rationale appeal: &quot;The most accurate gun sights in the world.&quot; Emotional appeal: &quot;Choose Wisely, Live Longer,&quot; a product slogan I created for LaserMax gun sights. The emotional appeal is significantly more powerful and memorable.
 
 3) Don&apos;t be afraid of an extra word or three 
Today, as noted branding expert Al Ries notes, many companies use short positionings, such as Fidelity Investments &quot;Turn Here.&quot; What does this corporate endline really convey? And couldn&apos;t almost anyone use this wording? It&apos;s hardly unique to Fidelity. Then consider &quot;What happens in Vegas stays in Vegas.&quot; It&apos;s far more emotive and &quot;sticky.&quot; Don&apos;t be afraid to add a few more words, it may make your clever slogan more meaningful, targeted and resonant. 
 4) Achieve resonant congruent differentiation 
Speaking of resonant, strive to ensure that your ad slogan meets these three key criteria: 1) Resonant, meaning that it is aligned with your essential brand messaging, so that a prospect says, &quot;Yeah, that&apos;s important to me.&quot; 2) Congruent, consistent with the qualities and values personified by your brand. 3) Differentiated, stating why you aren&apos;t like everyone else, but how you are  different and better. 
 5) Extend your brand essence
 Consider whether your proposed tagline enhances and amplifies your Unique Selling Proposition (USP): your number #1 selling point and differentiator.

Can one creative slogan or clever tagline do it all? It would be very difficult. But keying on at least one of these critical aspects of brand positioning and strategy will help you hone your messaging to create a more effective brand strategy.
 
 Get 10 powerful, meaningful, creative slogans for just $477 with our Slogan Ideas Pack. As a branding strategist, slogan writer and tagline creator, I can provide you with the choices you need to select the perfect positioning.  Learn more . 
 
 
 List of Slogans and Tag Lines Created by Chuck Ingersoll and brandsandtags.com 
 
 St. Luke’s Catholic Schools
 A higher degree of education 
(School slogan)

Program for Eye Care Practitioners
 Making your practice perfect
 (Conference theme and program identity for optometrists)

In-Genius
 The genius is in the details
The genius is in the programming.
The genius is in the software 
(Hardware and software system)

 
Bud&apos;s Hot s: We&apos;ve got the hots for you
 (Tagline for fast food restaurant)

Rever Computer
 The first notebook computer with an 8-foot screen 
(Laptop computer positioning)

Catholic University MBA Program
 Come back to get ahead
 (For college MBA degree promotion)

KODAK Processing
 Everything you need from start to photofinish 
(Photofinishing service)

LaserMax
 Street smart, dead certain 
 Choose wisely, live longer 
(Laser gun site products sold to police departments and individuals)

Greater Rochester Housing Partnership
 Because home is a better place 
(Non-profit organization)

Bausch&amp;Lomb Predator Sunglasses
 Stalk the Sun
 (Product name and ad slogan for Ray-Bans)

Transcat Calibration Services
 Better by every measure
 (Industrial products and services)

 
 Jazz 90.1 
 Take Jazz Further 
 (Public radio station) 

Central Trust
 The Bank with Human Interest 
(Bank)

Centenium
 Space and design in motion
 
 Sylvan  
 Balanced for Business 
 
 Reunion  
 Yesterday’s Mood, Today’s Spirit  

 Oxford  
 Quietly dignified, artistically graceful  
(Naming architecture and series of four slogans for line of high-end office furniture)

Garlock
 What have you got against Garlock? 
(Industrial gaskets)

RERO
 Dependability, delivered 
(Industrial distributor) 
 
WYLF Radio
 Laugh. Cry. Remember. 
(Music of your life radio station)

Hambleton Plaques&amp;Displays
 First Impressions That Last 
(Plaque manufacturer and distributor)
 
Fairport Crew Club
 Help Us Keep Both Oars in the Water 
 Help Us Keep Our Boats Afloat 
(School sports team)

Waterson Canal Cruises
 Life In the Past Lane 
(Cruise line positioning)

Sentinel 
 Lighting That Outperforms 
(Tagline for commercial lighting system)

Brecker County Community College
 Start Here. Go Anywhere. 
(College)

Golf Course
 Rochester’s High Point for Golf 
Golf course located at highest point in county) 
 
Consler Performance Line
 Nobody Filters Out More Problems 
(Filter manufacturer)

NitroPlus Membrane
 A Breakthrough, Not a Breakdown 
(Membrane used in biology and AIDS research testing)

Lawson Optical Distributors
 Making Your Practice Perfect 
(Eye care products meeting theme)

Walker Outdoor Displays
 It’s not the media, it’s the motion 
(Mobile billboard company)

Get It Straight Wet/Dry Flat Iron
 Straighten up and dry right! 
(Air dryer and straightener)

Circuit Board Assembly Firm
 We TCB for PCB
 (Industrial slogan)

 Note: some of these tagline and advertising slogan examples included here do not list a company, but simply describe the company in generic terms. This is to protect the client identities of branding agencies that contract with me as a branding strategist and slogan writer. 


 
 
 
 
 
Slogan Creator | Company Brand Names | Business Taglines Creation | Company Logo Design | Catchy Slogans Examples | Tagline Ideas | Creative Tagline | Clever Tag Lines | Sales Meeting Themes
 Copyright . Chuck Ingersoll. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
