<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006379" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/303002" time="2012-07-12-23:15" support="1" score="0.002236932647868012" bingtitle="Best way to remove burned oil stains from stainless frypan? - Not ..." webtitle="Best way to remove burned oil stains from stainless frypan? - Not About Food - Chowhound">
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>Getting odors out of tupperware/plastic containers? ... Did you ever work at a fast food restaurant? [moved from Food ... » Videos » Don&apos;t Throw Away Pea Pods » In ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; Not About Food Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
Best way to remove burned oil stains from stainless frypan?
 
I&apos;d use EasyOff, but I heard that&apos;s not good to use, although I don&apos;t know why. What product would best remove these burned oil stains on my stainless frypan?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Yahi on Mar 11, 2006 07:17 PM 
Updated on Nov 16, 2008

 17 Replies 
 
 
I think you might try sprinkling the spots with baking soda and spraying them lightly with water (I suggest spraying because too much water just washes the soda away). Or you can just make a paste of soda and water and spread it on the spots. Leave it a while (several hours, but not until the water dries and only the powder remains), then scrub with the plastic side of your sponge. Let us know how this works. My son-in-law once burned canola oil onto my stainless frypan and worried that it would never come off, but it did eventually just with routine washing.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Marsha on Mar 11, 2006 07:52 PM 
 re: Marsha 
We&apos;ve had great success with baking soda on our stainless steel-aluminum pans. I didn&apos;t have any Barkeeper&apos;s Friend around (and wasn&apos;t sure if it&apos;s enviro-friendly or not) so I pulled out the ubiquitous (in my house)baking soda. I had to do some scrubbing, but it worked like a charm.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Laurella on Mar 15, 2006 01:00 PM 

 
 
I&apos;ve had good results with Dawn Power Dissolver. Making a paste with Barkeepers Friend can also be effective.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Ruth Lafler on Mar 11, 2006 10:31 PM 

 
Barkeeper&apos;s Friend together with vigorous scrubbing with a steel wool pad always work for me.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RGR on Mar 11, 2006 11:39 PM 

 
Easy Off or Down Power Dissolver will be best and no scrubbing and sratching. What you don&apos;t want to use either product on is annodized aluminum, like Calphalon. It will ruin the surface.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Candy on Mar 12, 2006 11:38 AM 
 re: Candy 
I always use no-fumes oven cleaner on my stainless&amp;enamel pots or glass baking dishes&amp;casserols. It works beautifully&amp;doesn&apos;t scratch them.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Taralli on Mar 13, 2006 10:28 AM 
 re: Taralli 
Was looking for something else entirely and came across my brochure for All-Clad. With reference to cleaning the interior,&quot;DO NOT USE [their caps] oven cleaners or cleansers with chlorine bleach. DO NOT USE steel wool.&quot;As for the exterior:&quot;We do not recommend using steel wool, steel scouring pads or harsh detergents. Nylon scrubbing pads are safe to use.&quot;
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By JoanN on Mar 13, 2006 01:18 PM 
 re: JoanN 
Just saw the warning on the web; however, have found oven cleaner to work just fine so far. I usually set the pans outside on newpaper, spray copiously, let sit&amp;rinse w/warm water&amp;soft cloth. If sc doesn&apos;t get everything, I go over with nylon net ball or reapply oven cleaner&amp;do it again.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Taralli on Mar 14, 2006 11:25 AM 
 re: Taralli 
Now why would All-Clad recommend against using oven cleaner if it&apos;s just stainless? Do they think it will eat away at it and get down to the Al core or something? I don&apos;t see why I shouldn&apos;t use oven cleaner, which works quite well.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Yahi on Mar 14, 2006 11:55 AM 
 re: Yahi 
Can&apos;t answer that question; the brochure doesn&apos;t say. What it DOES say is&quot;Use a fine powder cleanser with water to form a paste. Apply paste using a soft cloth. Rub in a circular motion from the center outward. Wash in hot soapy water, dry immediately.&quot;

Sounds to me like they&apos;re recommending Barkeeper&apos;s Friend which, purely coincindentally, is what I use anyway.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By JoanN on Mar 14, 2006 12:17 PM 


 
 
 
 
 
If you are very, very careful (it&apos;s nasty stuff) AND if you can find it DIABLO CARBON KLEEN -&quot;Removes baked-on Grease&amp;Carbon from Metal surfaces, Brick&amp;Glass!&quot;This stuff always works but I don&apos;t use it on my anodized Calphalon. It works great on SS Wolff Range and SS and Al cookware.

I buy this wonder stuff at a restaurant supply store in 1 gallon cans for $39.15 +tax. They also have it in 1 quart cans.

Use gloves and eye protection to protect from splatter!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By sel on Mar 12, 2006 04:01 PM 
 re: sel 
&quot;If you are very, very careful (it&apos;s nasty stuff)...Use gloves and eye protection&quot;

I like to have clean and sparkling cookware but there&apos;s a point where one should stop. Having dangerous, industrial chemical products in the home is a very bad idea. If Barkeepers Friend doesn&apos;t get it perfect, don&apos;t worry, it&apos;s a kitchen after all, not a museum. Better to live with a few stains than risk harming yourself or others.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By BluPlateSpec on Mar 13, 2006 11:40 AM 

 re: sel 
I believe Diablo Carbon-Kleen and another product called Sokoff are forms of some buffered acid cleaners.

I have used both with great success and you are correct in the use of protection. I got some splatter on my upper wrist and it hurt like like the dickens.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RShea78 on Nov 16, 2008 09:05 PM 

 
 
Barkeepers Friend is what you need.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Tugboat on Mar 13, 2006 08:06 AM 
 re: Tugboat 
Works for me everytime. If the grease is really baked on (a la Zuni chicken), I sometimes pre-soak the pan in hot water mixed with detergent, then use Barkeeper&apos;s Friend.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By emily on Mar 13, 2006 10:55 AM 

 
 
TOOTHPASTE! So far i tried colgate whitening and crest pro health, with lots of elbow grease and a scrubby sponge....! Takes awhile, but seems to work and is healthier than oven cleaner plus you can have clean teeth after meals now (j/k) !
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By limesparks on Nov 16, 2008 05:58 PM 
 re: limesparks 
Hey, not so fast in giving oven cleaner (lye) a bad reputation! (LOL) I love Pretzels (pate fermente), so please see link below.

 http://www.thefreshloaf.com/recipes/p... 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RShea78 on Nov 16, 2008 09:09 PM 

 
 
 «Back to the Not About Food Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 Removing Oil Stains From Fabric - Any foolproof methods? (55 replies) 1 HELP......fingers are burning from cutting jalapenos. Remedies? (108 replies) 2 Getting odors out of tupperware/plastic containers? (28 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 78 

 Do you ever dance in the grocery... 

28 minutes ago
 
 3 

 Grocery Store Mark Up 

40 minutes ago
 
 295 

 2012 Confessions 

about 2 hours ago
 
 151 

 Plastic Grocery Bag Ban - what... 

about 2 hours ago
 
 212 

 Crazy supermarket check-out... 

about 2 hours ago
 
 105 

 So WHY were we forced to sit... 

about 3 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 DIY Projects See All 41 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana » Supertaster Daily: Whole Grain Beefaroni 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Blue Cheese and Chive Compound Butter 
 
 »Blogs » Quirky in Queens: Panorama of My Silence-Heart Café » All&apos;Angolo: Tasty Italian Pasta in LA&apos;s Koreatown » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County 
 
 »Discussion » What dish do you cook that people just rave about? » Let&apos;s talk soft serve » Where can I get the best French Dip sandwich in NYC? » Visiting LA. Restaurant recs? (Dietary restricitons) » Leather Strop » Nice, romantic restaurant for anniversary with girlfriend. 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;Best way to remove burned oil stains from stainless frypan?&quot;
	</body>
</document>
