<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006675" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/recent-comments/f/229/24208/Caribbean.html" time="2012-07-12-23:39" support="1" score="0.0020528985835521272" bingtitle="Recent reviews of Myrtle Beach Caribbean Restaurants | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Recent reviews of Myrtle Beach Caribbean Restaurants | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>My food was obviously ... with two soft drinks and no alcohol was 86.00 with tip. We would have been better off spending 1/3 that amount at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In   
 Choose a city:    Charleston     Charlotte     Hampton Roads     Los Angeles     New York     Research Triangle     South Carolina       More Cities... Urbanspoon Myrtle Beach Home &gt; Myrtle Beach &gt; Caribbean  &gt; 

Recent user reviews of Myrtle Beach Caribbean Restaurants


 Key West Grill Do not dine at the Key West Grill. 
by Dalton Alford ( 2 reviews )
 July 11, 2012 - The food was not good. The prices were high. That is all. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Jules , Lexington
 ( 24 reviews )
 July 04, 2012 - This was our favorite dining experience of our whole vacation!! Kids loved entertainment and balloon making! Everyone enjoyed the great music and dancing! It is a long wait but do much to do around the Area to occupy the time. The food is incredible!! They give you tons! Awesome family experience! 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Tim Goyette , Treasure Coast
 ( 76 reviews )
 July 03, 2012 - The decor is definitely Key West style. We had a couple of appetizers during their happy hour and washed them down with cold Coronas. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Tim Goyette , Treasure Coast
 ( 76 reviews )
 July 03, 2012 - Same great food at all of his locations. We love the Cheeseburger in Paradise. Free entertainment for the kids as there are so many things to look at... this location has a hurricane that mixes up margaritas in a giant blender. Where&apos;s my lost shaker of salt? 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Heather , Buffalo
 ( 2 reviews )
 June 26, 2012 - Came here for a light lunch while on vacation. It&apos;s a popular spot, the menu choices are adequate and the portions are large. I ordered the crab corn chowder and sadly it came out cold. I sent it back and their second try was at least a proper soup temperature but somewhat thick and lumpy. It tasted good though and I enjoyed the fun decor once i came to terms with the fact that it isn&apos;t meant to be a sophisticated culinary experience. FYI, the nachos passing by looked amazing coulda the enough to feed a small country!!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Bobby , Daytona Beach
 ( 5 reviews )
 June 24, 2012 - The girl working the front reception/check in was a BI?@() ! She wants to count a table of four with a child as a table of five. A wait for a table of four was 45 minutes. A wait for a table of 5 was 1:45. Yeah. Like the food is that good. Luckily we had the drinks we wanted at the bar. This place&apos;s service sucks and the prices are that of all other margaritavilles&apos;s have bigger glasses for the same price. Don&apos;t fall for the tourist trap. Great atmosphere. Crappy prices and service. 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise mobile review 
by Jordan Knipper ( 4 reviews )
 June 13, 2012 - The atmosphere is very family oriented. Food is good. Recommend the onion strings. Most meals are under ten dollars 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Olivia ( 3 reviews )
 June 08, 2012 - The food was good but expensive for what it was. $20 for a plate of Mac and cheese is a little high. Our waitress was rude but the guy on stilts was friendly and made our dinner more enjoyable. The environment was very fun. 
 | Not helpful 
 
 Fire Island Grille mobile review 
by Leighanne ( 11 reviews )
 June 03, 2012 - Great service. Restaurant decoration based on the scooby doo movie. Expensive kid menu. Food was very good I ate the pulled pork sandwich. We would eat here again. 
 | Not helpful 
 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Seafood Mac&amp;Cheese by Karen Kovach Thomas Wright ( 8 reviews )
 May 24, 2012 Mushroom-seafood appetizer was great. Pink Cadillac margarita was way too sweet for me. But the seafood Mac n Cheese was huge and delicious. Expensive dinner! $40.00!!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill Terrible, Just Terrible 
by Woody Walls , Wilmington
 ( 1 review )
 May 21, 2012 - Made a quick trip to Myrtle Beach with the family today before the crazy season starts with my job. The gang was hungry so we decided on Key West Grill. I usually steer clear of these types of restaurants in heavy tourist areas like Broadway at the Beach since they are notorious for being big on appearance and fall way short on food and service. As we were walking to our table my son and wife said they didn&apos;t have a good feeling about the upcoming experience, but I talked them into staying anyway. I should have listened to them! The menu was pretty typical and had very little&quot;Island&quot;or&quot;Caribbean&quot;influence save the choice of plantains with your sandwich. The menu pricing would suggest that they better hit a homerun with the food and service, but they struck out on all attempts. The server arrived and gave the standard robot like greeting running through the specials and the fact that all of their fish was caught locally or in International waters! You don&apos;t say...where else would it be caught? Your bathtub? I seriously don&apos;t think he took a breath, probably because he needed the cadence of the words to regurgitate the script he had memorized. This always turns me off in a restaurant. What happened to genuine simple and attentive service with personality? Our drink order was taken and the drinks arrived in plastic Coke cups. Didn&apos;t the server just tell me that one of the specials was $50?! Something doesn&apos;t add up here...you have the nerve to offer a $50 special and serve me a drink in a plastic (OK, polycarbonate) cup? After perusing the menu we decided to keep it simple. My sons ordered the&quot;steamed&quot;shrimp to share and my wife and I each ordered a Cuban sandwich. The server brought a piece of bread on a wooden cutting board and 4 bread plates (3 of which were clean!). The bread came with Land o Lakes butter cups. Did I mention that the bread plates were melamine (yep....plastic!). Enter the food delivery...oh boy! The shrimp arrived in a bowl with no side plates or anywhere to put the shells when peeled, I had to ask the server to bring plates for my sons. Then my son tells me they are cold and asked didn&apos;t the menu say steamed? Yep, why not call it shrimp cocktail or say steamed and chilled? The bowl with the shrimp had a half cup of water in it and not a piece of lemon in sight...pretty standard in most restaurants. Trying to find something positive, I looked at my wife&apos;s plate and noticed that her fries looked good, especially since my sweet potato fries were almost burned! We each got an ounce of Ketchup in a plastic cup! One bite of the sandwich and I was almost irate...it was dry with two pickle slices and pretty bad. The pork roast on it was almost like jerky and had no seasoning, it was just terrible. When the server came to check and asked if everything was alright, I told him yes....Just Alright, he walked away without comment- FAIL! We suffered through and got the check. I paid the bill and asked for the manager. When the manager arrived I was surprised that it was the same person I had seen throughout our meal standing at the bar chatting with the staff. Guess I shouldn&apos;t have been with the way the experience had been. No wonder the place is terrible! He did the usual...what&apos;s the issue? He seemed a little taken back when I told him he should be embarrassed to charge for the food my family experienced. He asked what we had and when I told him the Cuban and about the pork I was amazed at his response! He said.&quot;Yeah, we&apos;re working on that, it&apos;s been an issue.&quot;!!! At this point I lost it on him...you mean to tell me that you know you have an inferior product, yet you continue to serve it and charge for it? I told him he needed to go to the kitchen and tell them not to serve another Cuban sandwich until he was sure it was fixed! At that point, I got up and left with the manager still standing at the table dumbfounded. I am in the Food and Beverage business and have been for years and never write reviews, because I have been the recipient on some I felt were unwarranted, but this restaurant deserves every bad review they get! Save your money, save your time and aggravation and skip the meal at Key West Grill. Shame on them for preying on tourists and charging outrageous prices for subpar food and service 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by B K , Colorado Springs
 ( 9 reviews )
 May 02, 2012 - $16 for 6 coconut shrimp, which were a 7/10 at best. The wait staff was friendly enough, but if you&apos;re searching for something other than a VERY loud, cheaply decorated, touristy themed restaurant, don&apos;t bother. 
 | Not helpful 
 Mama Rue&apos;s Blues Garden Restaurant&amp;Lounge mobile review 
by Jon , San Diego
 ( 3 reviews )
 April 25, 2012 - Diamond in the rough Great food-fresh and tasty Nothing like it in Myrtle Beach Go for it 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by John Mezz ( 12 reviews )
 April 24, 2012 - Food is average, they have a wide selection of margaritas, and the atmosphere is fun. Fish tacos were a pleasant surprise and they even have a gluten free menu. 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise Average 
by Sarah B ( 4 reviews )
 April 22, 2012 - The food is not that great (try Margaritaville-they have better) but we continued to go for the drinks! They have gotten rid of a ton of drink menu items though, so although they have a lot-their cool drinks like the Key Lime Pielada and the Tootsie Roll are gone. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Great Burgers 
by Sarah B ( 4 reviews )
 April 22, 2012 - The selection is good and the burgers (what we ate) were fantastic. Lots of drink choices and a fun atmosphere. The staff is nice although they are often very busy. On a weekend be prepared to wait a bit or to be seated on the covered patio-which isn&apos;t bad at all. We enjoyed it immensely. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Kaitlyn ( 1 review )
 April 11, 2012 - Absolutely amazing. Calamari was fantastic and loved the stuffed shrimp. My husband ordered a steak medium and they brought it out rare. Just before we were going to complain we both took a bite and it was delicious! 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise mobile review 
by Stephen Watkins , Missouri
 ( 3 reviews )
 April 03, 2012 - Burger was good and the onion rings were excellent. 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise mobile review 
by Debbie Walker ( 1 review )
 April 02, 2012 Great gluten free ribs and fries. Manager came to our table to let us know everything was prepared separately. Great food and service! 
 | Not helpful 
 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by Joshua ( 2 reviews )
 March 29, 2012 - Great place and good atmosphere. Drinks are awesome... Prices are reasonable 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Loved it 
by Chris , Jacksonville
 ( 36 reviews )
 March 24, 2012 - Atmoshere was awesome and food was incredible. Definitely need to return. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Fun atmosphere! 
by NikkieLynn ( 25 reviews )
 February 02, 2012 - You go to Margaritaville for the amazing atmosphere. The food tends to be better when they are busier for some reason. In the summer, we like to sit out on the back deck on the water and listen to the guitar player - but inside rocks when the band is playing. Just don&apos;t sit in front of the speakers like I did. It&apos;s worth the wait in the summer. But the drinks are on the weaker side. They are more sweet than anything, but refreshing none the less. Don&apos;t go there in the hopes to get drunk and eat an amazing meal. Go there to grab a pretty good burger or savory sandwich and enjoy the atmosphere around you. 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise Gluten Free Paradise :-) 
by Gina , Portland
 ( 3 reviews )
 January 16, 2012 - I Loved my GF Experience at Myrtle Beach Cheeseburger in Paradise. I had the BBQ Grilled Chicken w/ bacon and swiss on their very own GF BUN. It was a normal sized soft bun with a white crumb, the taste was great! The wait staff was pleasant, patient and knowledgable about their GF menu. The manager of the restaurant came to our table and introduced himself, asked which one of us was GF and then described the safety measures they had taken to make sure I had a completely safe GF dining experience. I was so pleased to know what great lengths they had taken to make sure that I was comfortable dining at their establishment. FIVE STARS 
 | Not helpful 
 Mama Rue&apos;s Blues Garden Restaurant&amp;Lounge Food made with love 
by Nancy ( 8 reviews )
 January 09, 2012 The food is outstanding. You can tell everything is made from scratch and with love. The fish in butter sauce, jerk pork and chicken, steamed dumplings, and Howlin&apos; Wolf are super! We were there on a Tuesday, so don&apos;t know about the smoke issue...but we will be back for live blues and St. Patrick&apos;s day. 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Dabney Varner Porter ( 1 review )
 January 02, 2012 The food was excellent (crab cakes and calamari), service was great, nice atmosphere, great children&apos;s menu. We would go back again. 
 | Not helpful 
 Fire Island Grille We go all the time! 
by terri ( 1 review )
 November 05, 2011 - I live in Jersey and we are down here 5 times a year. We love Fire islands food as well as the staff. The bad reviews.....wow! They couldn&apos;t have eaten at the same place. Great atmosphere, good food, great drinks and a good time for our money! 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 Bingy&apos;s Jamaican Restaurant mobile review 
by jason ( 1 review )
 October 31, 2011 - This is the best food I&apos;ve ever had the jerk chicken is amazing and the sauce you get is soon good. Try the beef stew its really good. I love the rice and peas and the portions are huge and cheap 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Crap 
by Bellajocko , Morgantown
 ( 80 reviews )
 October 27, 2011 - I only got french fries, but they were terrible, frozen, crap. The show where there is a hurricane, the ceiling starts swirling and then a huge blender fills up and makes a margarita was interesting, the baby loved it. 
 0
 / 1
 people recommend this review | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise mobile review 
by Nicole Campbell , Fayetteville
 ( 3 reviews )
 October 23, 2011 - We were looking for a great burgere joint to recover after the mini marathon and this place was perfect. The fries were crispy and nicely seasoned. I had the burger of the day (Chesapeake bay burger) and it was really good. Definitely coming back when we visit again. 
 | Not helpful 
 Mama Rue&apos;s Blues Garden Restaurant&amp;Lounge Home 
by Lee Crawford ( 1 review )
 October 22, 2011 You walk in the door at 4 PM, right when it opens, and you try their signature and secret-ingredient Howlin Wolf, talk to Mama Rue about everything from the blues to sailing in the Keys, eat Chef Eric&apos;s steamed pork dumplings, proceed to talk to Chef Eric about Jamaica, stay for hours, listen to the best blues harmonica player on the SC coast, and leave feeling like you&apos;ve made it. Home. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Jarodbeauofmarcie ( 3 reviews )
 September 28, 2011 - Went at beginning of off season. At two pm we were only ones there. Has friendly server and food was great, if slightly expensive. 
 | Not helpful 
 Bingy&apos;s Jamaican Restaurant JERK CHICKEN by Billy ( 1 review )
 September 03, 2011 - The best jerk chicken I have ever had was in Atlanta, not anymore! Just the right amount of spice and flavor... Excellent! 
 | Not helpful 
 Icey Pastry Productions Awesome Cakes for Myrtle Beach Special Occasions!! 
by jelllo_2001 ( 1 review )
 August 18, 2011 - I have had the pleasure of enjoying the wonderful cakes of Icey Pastry Productions. I even trusted them for my 40th birthday cake. They also made my favorite cake which has been hard for me to find. It was a replica of my wedding cake- a strawberry amaretto cake with cream cheese/butter cream icing. Irvin the owner was very gracious. I have also had the pleasure of tasting his jerk chicken and caribbean side dishes topped off with some refreshing Island iced tea. It reminded my husband of his grandmother&apos;s...perfect!! I was a bit apprehensive of ordering such a special cake long distance, but Irvin and his professionalism has made helped to make my day more than perfect. I would trust him for birthday cakes, wedding cakes, or any of your other catering needs!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Drew , Greenville
 ( 50 reviews )
 August 06, 2011 - The calamari is the best I have ever had. Excellent service, too! 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Paige ( 3 reviews )
 August 06, 2011 - Soooo good! Hands down the best calamari I have ever had! Go 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Joseph , North Carolina
 ( 7 reviews )
 July 28, 2011 - Good food and service but not sure it was worth the money. It cost me $80 for two sodas one appetizer one ribeye and a pasta dish. It was good but not $40 per person good 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Kathy V ( 3 reviews )
 July 26, 2011 - Save your money! My husband&apos;s burger was raw! Rest of the meals were edible but were really not worth it at all! Way over priced! 
 | Not helpful 
 Fire Island Grille mobile review 
by Rebecca ( 3 reviews )
 July 25, 2011 - Yuck. Service is insanely slow. My food was obviously sitting around for ages. 
 | Not helpful 
 Fire Island Grille mobile review 
by Jacob Cuglewski ( 2 reviews )
 July 24, 2011 - Other than my sisters food being under cooked. The service was prompt and refilled my drink 5 times. Food was quickly delivered and delicious. 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise Bummer 
by Tim Adkins , Lexington
 ( 36 reviews )
 July 14, 2011 - With all the great places to eat, we picked one of the worst in Myrtle Beach ! My Blue Burger, the special of the day was supposed to have Blue Cheese, sauteed onions and spicy mayo. When I got it , it only had a few onions in the middle on the bun. Was the guy making it on drugs ? Anyway the place was rundown and I can&apos;t believe we wasted our time here ! 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by K.A. ( 26 reviews )
 July 12, 2011 - Loud, poor quality food, and sticky tables. You decide. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville mobile review 
by hungaryhungaryhippo , Lexington
 ( 18 reviews )
 June 20, 2011 Atmosphere fun, food mediocre. Go for a drink, but don&apos;t waste your money eating here. It COULD be a really great place but it&apos;s about making a $ off tourists and not about good food. Sad to say, but this is a poor choice to dine 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill Not At All Worth It 
by victor29576 ( 8 reviews )
 June 20, 2011 - We chose Key West Grill because it was the only restaurant my hungry kids could get into without a wait and that should have clued us in about what we should expect given that the surrounding restaurants had patrons standing outside of the doors waiting to get in. We were seated quickly - in fact, the seater almost ran to the table without so much as a&quot;please follow me.&quot; The server took at least 10 minutes to acknowledge us after we were seated and didn&apos;t get around to our drink orders for some time after that. The food came out reasonably fast BUT the medium rare prime rib turned out medium well and the server didn&apos;t have a clue what was wrong when we pointed out that there was hardly any red in the meat at all. We sent it back (something that I have NEVER done before) and it came back medium and not medium rare but we dipped it in tasteless aujus and ate the meat which had little flavor at all. Others at our table ordered cheese pizza (a relatively simple and safe bet), fried shrimp, and shrimp and grits. The pizza was ok, the fried shrimp batter was over spiced and the shrimp overcooked, and the shrimp with grits were marginal. Overall, the cost for one adult and three children with two soft drinks and no alcohol was 86.00 with tip. We would have been better off spending 1/3 that amount at a fast food restaurant. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville Average Food, High Energy Atmosphere 
by Sue Bee , Maryland
 ( 16 reviews )
 June 19, 2011 - I have eaten here three times over the last 4 years. The food is average or good for the price. The only menu items I would rate as excellent are the Volcano Nachos, Taco Salad (surprisingly tasty!), Coconut Shrimp and the salmon entree. The cheeseburger is dry and tasteless. The chicken tenders from the kids menu are pretty good, real chicken, not dry at all. The frozen raspberry margarita is fabulous. The house margarita is only average. It was served to me warm this last visit, it melted the ice and watered down my drink, yuck. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Carolinas Doc , Florence
 ( 1 review )
 June 14, 2011 - Prices way too high for the quality. Waitstaff looked liked they were on prison work release, however, the service was good. Portions way too small and my potato was undercooked. I will never go back, too many other quality options in Myrtle Beach 
 | Not helpful 
 Cheeseburger In Paradise Yuck 
by Mrs. B , Columbus
 ( 5 reviews )
 June 13, 2011 - If you want fried food and crazy expensive drinks then this is the place for you. If you are trying to eat a bit healthy then RUN AWAY! Our salad and salmon were terrible but the baskets of fried pickles we saw when walking out looked interesting. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill Not a Good Value 
by Skip Dodson , Columbus
 ( 62 reviews )
 June 11, 2011 - Prime Rib and Baked Potato--$25, and the beef didn&apos;t have much flavor. That was it; didn&apos;t include appetizer, or salad or vegetable, or drinks, or desert. It did include bread, butter and water. Atmosphere is nice, but we weren&apos;t impressed. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by Sahvohn , Fayetteville
 ( 7 reviews )
 June 07, 2011 - Food was dry and overcooked. Drink was not mixed well. Disappointed. 
 | Not helpful 
 Jimmy Buffett&apos;s Margaritaville just ok 
by Heather Sayne Walker , Memphis
 ( 17 reviews )
 May 13, 2011 my family and I have gone here three times. Everytime we go it is very busy and there is almost always a wait. You would think that meant it was great, but alas no. I believe it is always so jam packed because of the novelty of the place. I went there last year because I wanted a cheeseburger. I though surely if this man sings a whole song about a cheeseburger then surely he wouldn&apos;t slap his name on a bad one. Boy was I wrong. My burger was dry an flavorless a true disappointment. We decided we were not going to waste or time/money going there this year on vacation for two reasons. The poor food quality and also ever 30 minutes they do a&quot;show&quot;where they blast&quot;margaritavilla&quot;over the speakers and the make a huge margarita in this 6 ft blender. I honestly thought that would freak my 7 month old daughter out. 
 | Not helpful 
 Key West Grill mobile review 
by DerrickRose1 ( 1 review )
 April 21, 2011 - Do NOT go. the food is average and prices outrageous Serving size is very small Please Don&apos;t go 
 | Not helpful 
 

 See more recent reviews 


 Home &gt; Myrtle Beach &gt; Caribbean  &gt; 
 Careers | Add Restaurant | Contact Us | Blog | Go Mobile | About Us | Terms of Service | Privacy | FAQ   Get Urbanspoon on the iPhone Partner Sites: Ask Answers | Life123 | Bloglines | Citysearch | Insider Pages | MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
