<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006674" url="http://advancesufficiency.wordpress.com/2010/11/10/la-times-fast-food-restaurants-market-too-heavily-to-kids-a-report-finds/" time="2012-07-12-23:39" support="12" score="0.032037857290844816" bingtitle="LA Times: Fast food restaurants market too heavily to kids, a ..." webtitle="LA Times: Fast food restaurants market too heavily to kids, a report findsCenter for MoralityEthics News Study">
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000338" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="103"/>
	<description>Burger King, Fast food, Fast food restaurant, Happy Meal, Kelly ... The information doesn’t put fast food ... Letter Tray on Bangkok Post’s “Ex… Franklyn ...</description>
	<body>
		thaiintelligentnews 
 
 Center for Morality&amp;Ethics News Study 
 
 Yale Club on Moral Life Human Rights Guardian UK: The Poor gives more than the rich Social Justice&amp; America Archives RSS Feed 
 
 Burger King , Fast food , Fast food restaurant , Happy Meal , Kelly D. Brownell , Los Angeles Times , McDonald&apos;s , Yale University 


LA Times: Fast food restaurants market too heavily to kids, a report finds
 In Uncategorized on November 10, 2010 at 9:29 am 

By Jeannine Stein, Los Angeles Times 

9:30 AM PST, November 8, 2010
 
 
 
It’s no secret kids like fast food. And fast food likes kids–so much so that some companies have ramped up their marketing efforts in the past couple of years, says a new report released Monday from Yale University’s Rudd Center for Food Policy&amp;Obesity .

The report details findings on fast food marketing and nutrition information, based on examining the marketing endeavors of 12 large national fast food chains. Researchers also looked at data on nutritional information in more than 3,000 children’s meal combos and 2,781 menu items.

The information doesn’t put fast food companies in the best light. For example, the report found that (shocker) unhealthful foods reign on menus. Out of 3,039 likely meal combinations, a dozen met nutrition standards the researchers set for preschoolers, and 15 met the criteria for older children. Sugar and saturated fat make up at least 30% of the calories of items bought by kids and teens.

The report is also critical of how some fast food restaurants don’t make healthful options more obvious. It found that although most establishments have at least one nourishing side dish and beverage for their children’s meals, these are hardly ever offered as an alternate choice. And despite advertisements that show healthful options, the report finds that French fries are served with kids’meals 86% of the time, and soft drinks at least 55% of the time.

Exposure to fast food advertising is escalating, according to the report. In 2009 preschoolers saw 56% more ads for Subway, 21% more ads for McDonald’s and 9% more ads for Burger King , compared with 2007. Children age 6 to 11 saw even more: 59% more ads for Subway, 26% more for McDonald’s and 10% more for Burger King.

The report also found that African American kids and teens are exposed to at least 50% more fast food ads than their white counterparts.

“Our results show that the fast food industry ‘s promises to market less unhealthy food to young people are not enough,”said study co-author Kelly Brownell , director and co-founder of the Rudd Center, in a news release.“If they truly wish to be considered partners in public health, fast food restaurants need to drastically reduce the total amount of marketing that children and teens see for fast food and the iconic brands that sell it.”

The Rudd Center isn’t the only organization becoming fed up with fast food restaurants marketing to kids. Last week the board of supervisors in San Francisco voted to ban Happy Meals and similar restaurant items that come with a toy and have disproportionate amounts of fat, calories and sodium. Another vote may be necessary to make the ban final.

Related Articles

 Study finds fast-food chains targeting children () “American Food Policy: Toxic, Starting With Children, Especially From Poor Families”and related posts (downwithtyranny.blogspot.com) Fast-food restaurants target U.S. kids, study shows (reuters.com) Fast-food restaurants target US kids, study shows (reuters.com) San Fran to ban toys in some fast food kids meals (dailycaller.com) San Fran to ban toys in some fast food kids meals (seattletimes.nwsource.com) San Fran to ban toys in some fast food kids meals (sfgate.com) Health Buzz: Fast Food Restaurants Increase Ads Aimed at Kids (health.usnews.com) Of Over 3,000 Kids’Meal Combinations, Only 12 Seen As Healthy For Preschoolers (medicalnewstoday.com) Study: Kids’Fast Food Options Rarely Healthy (abcnews.go.com) 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. ▶No Responses 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 « Before Seeking Alpha: Morality Investing&amp; China November 10, 2010 After NYT: Company Accused of Firing Over Facebook Post November 10, 2010 » 
 
 
BLOG OPERATES FROM INTERNET REPRESSED THAILAND
 
 
Join the Blue Ribbon Online Free Speech Campaign! 
 
 Humanity Bridge 

Error: Please make sure the Twitter account is public .
 
 Philosophy 

 Plutocracy Watch: Tax Edition July 12, 2012 Nussbaum Interviewed about Religious Intolerance... July 12, 2012 Roubini, Prohpet of Doom on the Economy, Suggests Hanging Bankers May be in the Offing... July 12, 2012 What areas of philosophy are most important for a strong PhD program? July 11, 2012 Informative interview with Scanlon July 11, 2012 Gottlieb on Romano July 10, 2012 The usefulness of useless knowledge July 10, 2012 Bill Gates&apos;s Attack on Public Education July 10, 2012 Per Student Value of University Endowments...or the rich are even richer than you thought! July 10, 2012 Experimental Philosophy page... July 9, 2012 In the midst of all the chatter about the healthcare decision... July 9, 2012 Why the Affordable Health Care Act Was Clearly Constitutional Under Existing Precedents July 9, 2012 &quot;Philosophy needs to be relevant&quot;: 18th-Century Edition July 9, 2012 A note to prospective advertisers July 9, 2012 APA&quot;Best Practices&quot;in Journal Publishing July 8, 2012 3AM Magazine is Back... July 6, 2012 How philosophy came to enjoy the highest place in the universities July 6, 2012 More Creationist Mischief...with the Loch Ness Monster July 6, 2012 Waldron on the Regulation of Hate Speech July 5, 2012 3AM Magazine Having Technical Difficulties... July 5, 2012 
 
 Religion and Morality 

 Taking a Break from Blogging – But Still Very Much in This Fight February 21, 2009 
 
 
 
BLOG OPERATES FROM INTERNET REPRESSED THAILAND
 
 
Join the Blue Ribbon Online Free Speech Campaign! 
 
 Thai Intelligence News 

 ASEAN Defense: Thailand orders 2 more Black Hawks as Black Hawk readied to rescue Constitutional Court judges July 12, 2012 Justice: Thai Rath reports 416 MPs&amp;Senators “Opinioned” not to accept Thai Constitutional Court order July 12, 2012 ASEAN Defense: Thai army chief “You have two years to fight&amp;settle differences with AEC looming” July 11, 2012 Justice: With link to Abhisit&amp;Yellow Shirts, Thai anti corruption network accuses Yingluck of corruption July 10, 2012 Politics: How far will an “Insane” Constitutional Court go as Thaksin’s family in Thailand threatened July 10, 2012 Diplomacy: USA’s Hillary invite Yingluck to meet on “Friday 13th” when Thai court verdict announce July 9, 2012 Diplomacy: Thai opposition says “As a Black Person” Obama Should Better Understand “Justice” in Thaksin visa July 7, 2012 Diplomacy: The 43rd Anniversary of Thai USA “Friendship Road” sparks debate about “Ugly Americans” July 7, 2012 Journalism: Reuters&amp;Bloomberg probably in “Shock” by head of Thailand’s largest conglomerate, CP July 7, 2012 Journalism: Reuters&amp;Bloomberg probably in “Shock” at Wall Street Journal&amp;AP Thai reports July 6, 2012 Diplomacy: Thaksin gets “Visa” to enter USA&amp;how Wall Street Journal reports events in Thailand July 6, 2012 Justice: Abhisit meets “Secret Club” head with links to Constitutional Court, ahead of ruling July 5, 2012 ASEAN Defense: Thailand choosing new airforce chief with decision on U-Tapao “ASEAN Air Evacuation Hub” pending July 4, 2012 ASEAN Defense: Drug dealers pushing “Ice” to the younger Thai generation as “Diet&amp;Beauty” suppliment with a “Kick” July 4, 2012 Justice: Leak video shows Abhist&amp;Constitutional Court judge favor amending Thai Constitution, in past July 3, 2012 Economics: “Defeat Thinking” at Thailand’s Central Bank&amp;Thailand Developmental Research Institute July 3, 2012 Justice: Key witness wife, in case to topple Yingluck at Constitutional Court, works at Constitutional Court July 3, 2012 Justice: Human Rights Watch (HRW) Thailand senior researcher says Constitutional Court “Abusing Power” July 2, 2012 Competitiveness: A Thai homeless, at Bangkok’s richest district, could teach Thais a few thing about “Corruption” July 1, 2012 Competitiveness: USA on offense against China for Thailand’s fruit market hurt Thai producers July 1, 2012 
 
 Bangkok Post (Class System) 

 What next after judicial deja vu? July 12, 2012 Korkaew comes under fire July 12, 2012 Protest drags traffic to a halt July 12, 2012 Police brace for red-shirt trouble July 12, 2012 Business concerned over post-verdict situation July 12, 2012 PM asks all parties to accept the court&apos;s verdict July 12, 2012 MP an embarrassing liability for the government July 12, 2012 Spaniard kills self while on Facebook July 12, 2012 IMF chief predicts Asia will weather euro crisis July 11, 2012 This very fishy business July 11, 2012 King pardons US man jailed for lese majeste July 11, 2012 Phuket land in&apos;critical&apos;shape July 11, 2012 Korkaew threatens to seize judges July 11, 2012 Clinton wants more studies on Mekong dam July 11, 2012 US citizen jailed for royal insult pardoned July 11, 2012 Rights lawyer wins Somchai Neelaphaijit Award July 11, 2012 Student, teacher fight clip goes viral July 11, 2012 PM denies she&apos;ll meet US execs in Cambodia July 10, 2012 Not such a capital idea July 10, 2012 PM denies she&apos;ll meet US execs in Cambodia July 10, 2012 
 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

 

 
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.com 
 
 
 
BLOG OPERATES FROM INTERNET REPRESSED THAILAND
 
 
Join the Blue Ribbon Online Free Speech Campaign! 
 
Copy Right Note:
 This blog is a study center for academic-non commercial purpose&amp;thus we cut and paste resources for research. Sources please inform the center if such a practice violates copy-right. 
Global Hits
 
 website counters 
Incept: 7/2010

 15,264 hits 
 
Categories
 Select Category Uncategorized  (270) Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Bangkok Post: On-Line suicide spark Thai concern over web-cam Washington Post: Ending child marriage helps communities across the developing world Washington Post: FTC proposes new guidelines for collecting debt from dead people Washington Post: Environmental justice issues take center stage Mail UK: David Cameron cancels his Christmas holiday to Thailand to avoid sending‘wrong message’in age of austerity AFP: Hundreds of foetuses found in temple AFP: UK author jailed for book on Singapore hangings The Nation: The Money&amp;Media Election Complex Washington Post: The Death of Real News The Star: Massacre of tigers continues Care2: DREAM Act to Get A Vote During Lame Duck Session Care2: Ozone Depletion is Leaving Whales Sunburned Care2: Wanted–Only Young, Pretty Women Need Apply In Chengdu NYT: Company Accused of Firing Over Facebook Post LA Times: Fast food restaurants market too heavily to kids, a report finds 
 
Top Posts

 Bangkok Post&apos;s &quot;Excellent Expose&quot; on clubs that sell &quot;Boy&quot; sex to women CNN: Gallery-Mercy and hope in the slums of Pattaya Women&apos;s sex work past and her new life problems CBS: Long Island Man Arrested For Defending Home With AK-47 The Mail: Would this girl have captivated the world if she hadn’t been a beauty? Kawker: Vladimir Putin Reaches Limit of Badassery By Shooting Whale with Crossbow Social Justice&amp;America 
 
Recent Comments

 Round Kitchen on Bangkok Post’s Opinion:… pkvadmin on Women’s sex work past an… Letter Tray on Bangkok Post’s“Ex… Franklyn Boyte on Washington Post: Dispute over… Round Mirror · on The Mail: Would this girl have… 
 
Top Clicks

 None 
 
 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .
Theme: DePo Masthead by Automattic .
 Follow 
 Follow“Center for Morality&amp;Ethics News Study” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
