<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006074" url="http://www.recyclingfactsguide.com/recycling-cooking-oil/" time="2012-07-12-22:45" support="1" score="0.0015325671852521483" bingtitle="Recycling Cooking Oil | A Key To Solving The Emerging Energy Crisis" webtitle="Recycling Cooking Oil | A Key To Solving The Emerging Energy Crisis">
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... the nation’s oil dependence dramatically, available at every fast food restaurant. ... Where before restaurants had to pay to get rid their waste oil, the tables have ...</description>
	<body>
		Recycling Facts Guide Protect Your Environment 

 
You are here: Home » Oil Recycling » Recycling Cooking Oil May Hold The Key 
 
Recycling Cooking Oil May Hold The Key
 
It may surprise you that there is a massive, but largely untapped fuel energy resource that holds the potential to reduce the nation’s oil dependence dramatically, available at every fast food restaurant. What is it? A genuine energy alternative can be made by recycling cooking oil. Not only is it a clean burning fuel, but it is more efficient than any fossil fuel.

Why is cooking oil relevant to the state of energy consumption and the rising price at the pumps? The obvious point is that the economy is an interdependent system. When you have high fuel prices, the costs of other merchandise also rise to compensate for transportation and freight costs. Regardless of whether it is gasoline or diesel, the costs are rising and the need for better fuel alternative is an ever present concern in the minds of consumers.
 
Recycling Cooking Oil
 
This is where recycling cooking oil becomes relevant. You’ve probably been hearing news reports or reading articles in magazine articles discussing the topic of biodiesel. What you may not know is that often biodiesel is processed by recycling cooking oil such as you would find at your local McDonalds. The waste material in the form of fat and vegetable oil can be converted to environmentally friendly biodiesel.

Biodiesel made by recycling cooking oil is not just a concept fuel alternative. It has been tested and proven to offer better savings and arrest the urgency of the developing energy crisis. The reason that this option is not being pursued is tied up in a lack of investment in the technology needed to make it viable on a larger scale.

Yet, cooking oil based biodiesel is beginning to look more appealing than it has in the past. Where before restaurants had to pay to get rid their waste oil, the tables have turned and now many of these same restaurants are charging substantial amounts for their waste oil. Companies that specialize in the conversion process that includes recycling cooking oil and creating new biodiesel are cropping up every month. The potential for the big fast food chains to get in on the act and cash in on the emerging market is huge.

Recycling cooking oil and using in this way represents some of the creative ideas that may revolutionize the energy markets and provide a roadmap to achieve energy independence in the United States and transform oil usage in the world at large. This type of imaginative work is what it is going to take to achieve results. Perhaps, you could get in on the ground floor of this developing market and reap the benefits of this innovative fuel resource.
 
Help Us Spread The Word.. Share It!

 Share on Twitter Share on Google+ Share on Facebook Share on LinkedIn Share on Buffer Pin It! 
 
Subscribe
 
Subscribe to our e-mail newsletter to receive updates.
 
Related Posts:
 
 What Are Some Prominent Oil Recycling Companies In Texas Used Oil Filter Recycling: A Quick Reference To Home Disposal Interesting Facts about Recycling Plastic and Glass Bottles What Does It Take To Heat Your Home By Recycling Oil Some Interesting Facts About Motor Oil Recycling 
 ← Creating Effective Oil Recycling Slogans Cashing In On The Recycling Fast Food Oil For Fuel Trend → 
Newsletter
 Join our newsletter and receive our exclusive Special Report
 Email Address * 
 First Name 
 * = required field 
Our strict privacy policy keeps your email address 100% safe and secure.
 
eBooks
 
 Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Terms Of Service | Sitemap 
Copyright©2012 Recycling Facts Guide
 });
	</body>
</document>
