<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006774" url="http://www.fairplaygames.com/gamedisplay.asp?gameid=4370" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="1" score="0.00035353367913546505" bingtitle="Fair Play Games - Change! - Discounted Board Games and Card Games ..." webtitle="Fair Play Games - Change! - Discounted Board Games and Card Games - Cheapass Games - James Ernest">
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>Just to name a few items on blowout, we have Pirate ... Welcome to Frieday&apos;s, the Fast Food Restaurant of the Damned. ... The game comes with 50 cards, which represent bills ...</description>
	<body>
		Reward Point System 
Earn Points for each order
Earn Points for each Rave 
Redeem for Cash on next order Huge selection of
discounted
 boardgames
and card games 
 
 Home | Games | Customer Service | Contact Us | General Information | Customer Raves | Interviews | Game Bits | Newsletter        Settlers | Axis&amp;Allies | Card | Children | Party | 2 Players | Abstract | Blowout | Advanced Search   

  Find All Products Games   Sign In     New Account  Gift wrapping
starting at $1.00  Gift Certificates in
$5.00 increments View
Shopping Cart 
 
 
 
 Change! 


 
 
 (Click to view full size) 
 Manufacturer: Cheapass Games    Visit their site Designer: James Ernest 
 Brian Snoddy Time: 30 Minutes Categories: Card Game 
 
 
 Availability: Unavailable  
 Notify me when available Our Price:  $4.95
 Reward Points : 495 
 Notify me if this item goes on sale     This item is currently NOT available. When and if it becomes available, we&apos;ll update the availability message accordingly.   
 
 
 From the Publisher... 
Welcome to Frieday&apos;s, the Fast Food Restaurant of the Damned. This is Change!, the third game set at this place. And Change isnt just one game, its three different change-making games in one. The game comes with 50 cards, which represent bills in denominations of 1, 3, 5, 7, and 10.

Game 1: Make Your Own Change Night. In this one, youre all trying to score extra cash off a Zombie whos a little dim. If he hasnt got exact change for you, hell give you more money than you gave him. Who can get the best deal? For 2-6 players, 30 minutes.

Game 2: Boneyard. There are buckets of money on the table, and its a silent auction to grab them. Your bids fall back into the buckets, and the first player who can get far enough ahead wins. For 4-8 players (the more the better!), 20 minutes.

Game 3: Diminishing Returns. Simple, elegant, and the best of the set. Players start with the same collection of bills, and play money into a common pot until all but one player is out. Its a version of the old Cheapass standard, Fight, played with bills in denominations of 1, 3, 5, 7, and 10. For 2-3 players, or 2-6 players with a second deck; 10 to 30 minutes.

All three games are clever and strategic; and considering the price (a dollar each), how can you possibly go wrong?

You Need: A score pad

 Read 
 more information at the Board Game Geek website 


 Products that other customers purchased when purchasing this item. 
 
 Fluxx (v4.0) 
 
 Bohnanza Expansion-La Isla Bohnita 
 
 Agora 
 
 Cube Farm 
 
 Manila 
 
 Lord of the Rings: The Confrontation Deluxe Edition 
 
 Wits&amp;Wagers : 2nd Edition 
 
 Bull Spit card game 
 
 Gift Trap (GiftTrap) 1st Edition 
  

 Customer Raves - Write your own Rave about this game! 
 (Click on a person&apos;s name or game group to see other raves by the same person or group. 

 
 
 
 Shopping Cart 
 
 Empty 
 
 

 
 
 Wish List 
 
 To create a wish list, Login to your account or create an account.
 Login or Create an Account View Expanded Wish List 
 
 
 


 Home | Contact Us | About Us
	</body>
</document>
