<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006864" url="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=24936" time="2012-07-12-23:50" support="3" score="0.00399632527462015" bingtitle="Milkshakes Fail to Fix Slow Service at Diner | The Emory Wheel" webtitle="Milkshakes Fail to Fix Slow Service at Diner | The Emory Wheel">
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>It was refreshing to eat at a fast food restaurant where the table wasn’t sticky and the menu ... the name Steak’n’Shake doesn’t really do the food selection ...</description>
	<body>
		| About the Wheel | Advertise | Contact Us | Donate Welcome, Guest [ login | register ] 
 
 
 
 Home News Editorials Sports Arts&amp;Living Entertainment Advertise Blogs Photos Business Center Student Elections 
 
 home | arts&amp;living 
 
Milkshakes Fail to Fix Slow Service at Diner
 By Steven Stein Posted: 01/28/2008 
 
 Welcome to 1950s Bizarro World.

The shakes are cold, the burgers hot and the skinny fries sizzling, but that ain’t Chuck Berry pouring out of the jukebox. And that isn’t June Cleaver serving your food.

It’s Steak’n’Shake, the venerable fast-food/diner hybrid. And in the most eagerly anticipated arrival since the Dalai Lama, it’s finally come to Emory.

For months we grudgingly chowed down on Wendy’s and Quiznos as we stared longingly at the corner of La Vista and North Druid Hills, waiting for the arrival of our fast food Valhalla. Two weeks ago, the pearly gates, er, glass doors finally opened.

Was it worth the wait? Let’s put it this way: Don’t expect to find Arnold’s Drive In. Or service that merits the designation “fast” food.

You walk in and become part of a mass of human bodies that could hardly be called a line. This is Steak’n’Shake’s system for organizing diners. After 10 to 15 minutes of bumping and jostling, we were escorted to our table.

It was refreshing to eat at a fast food restaurant where the table wasn’t sticky and the menu wasn’t covered with God knows what. But we only had a few moments to savor the cleanliness. That’s when we met Sir Walter.

Sir Walter, as his name plate informed us, was our server, a feature that distinguishes Steak’n’Shake from its fast food brethren. (“So does this mean he’s been knighted?” one amused customer asked.) Even if your server is royalty, don’t expect speedy service.

To be fair, signs informed hungry customers that this was a training period, and that half of the proceeds went to the Girl Scout Council of North Georgia. But for the amount of time we were waiting, they could have at least thrown in some samosas.

Still, slow service seems to be a problem plaguing the Steak’n’Shake. Message boards are brimming with complaints, and the company just reported a first-quarter loss, sending stock prices into a tailspin.

In other words, be ready to order immediately. If not, you may have to wait another 10 minutes before you can flag down your waiter.

If you do have time to study the menu, you’ll realize the name Steak’n’Shake doesn’t really do the food selection justice. There are all kinds of non-cow related items, including a spicy chicken sandwich, a fish fillet and six different kinds of chili.

But to go to Steak’n’Shake for the first time and not order, well, a steakburger and a shake is sacrilegious.

Forty-five minutes later, we finally came face to face with the vaunted steakburger. A steakburger is the result of a bunch of different steak cuts grounded together. It is disappointingly small and, to be honest, doesn’t taste all that different than a regular burger. The fries are the size of toothpicks and about as tasty, and the onion rings are mediocre at best.

The lone saving grace is the milkshake. We stuck with the basics — chocolate and vanilla, with a cherry on top — and couldn’t have been happier.

Two-thousand three-hundred and sixty-three calories later, and $20 poorer, we were unsure how we felt about the experience.

The service is too slow and the prices are too high to qualify as fast food. But the quality isn’t up to diner standards.

Steak’n’Shake seems to be caught in the murky middle ground between fast food restaurant and diner.

So stay away from the food, savor the shakes and make sure to stop in once, if only to meet Sir Walter.

 — Contact ­ Steven Stein 

 
 disclaimer | privacy policy 





Top Stories

 Summer News Update: Wine Bar Opens in Village; Professor Named Poet Laureate; Healthcare Sued for Missing Patient Records Judge Places Charges Against Arrested Protesters on the Dead Docket Andrew Allen, 23, Passionate and Dedicated Emory Nursing School, VA Center Launch Health Care Research Program Summer News Update: Protesters Arrested on Campus; New Emory Point Businesses; New Dean of Campus Life Appointed Songwriter Paul Simon to Give 2013 Ellmann Lectures 


Related Stories

 Student Choreography Inspires with EDC’s Showcase Awards Night Celebrates Student Writing Slam Poets ‘Push The Art Forward’ Fabulous Friday TEDxEmory Thinks Outside the Box This Interfaith Initiative is Sweet Music to the Ears 
 Most Read Most Read Latest Latest Most Commented Most Commented 
 No articles at this time 
 
 
 Summer News Update: Wine Bar Opens in Village; Professor Named Poet Laureate; Healthcare Sued for Missing Patient Records 
 
 Judge Places Charges Against Arrested Protesters on the Dead Docket 
 
 Andrew Allen, 23, Passionate and Dedicated 
 
 Emory Nursing School, VA Center Launch Health Care Research Program 
 
 
 No articles at this time 
 The Emory Wheel 

 Archives of Past Issues About The Emory Wheel The Emory Wheel Staff Advertising Place a Classified Ad 
 Helpful Links 
 Emory University Emory Report 
 
 Home | News | Editorials | Sports | Arts&amp;Living | Entertainment | Advertise | Place a Classified Ad | Register | Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Wheel Alumni Website 

 Copyright©2007 The Emory Wheel
ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
 Red Clay Interactive Web Design Company
	</body>
</document>
