<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006952" url="http://www.wate.com/story/14679089/fine-dining-and-fast-food-restaurants-suffer-in-health-inspection-scores" time="2012-07-12-23:56" support="5" score="0.0178784484732136" bingtitle="Fine dining, fast food restaurants receive low inspection scores" webtitle="Fine dining, fast food restaurants receive low inspection scores">
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>Fine dining, fast food restaurants receive low health inspection scores ... Below 70 is considered &quot;unsanitary,&quot; and this fine dining restaurant that ...</description>
	<body>
		Fine dining, fast food restaurants receive low health inspection scores
 Member Center: 
 Create Account | Log In Manage Account | Log Out 
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 Health Source Focus 6 Summer Camps and Beyond 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 Health Source Summer Camps and Beyond Focus 6 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 Health Source Summer Camps and Beyond Focus 6 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 Health Source Summer Camps and Beyond Focus 6 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 Health Source Focus 6 Summer Camps and Beyond 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes 
 
 Health Source Summer Camps and Beyond Focus 6 6 Around Town East Tennessee Obituaries 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Fine dining, fast food restaurants receive low health inspection scores
 Posted: Thursday, May 19, 2011 3:23 PM EST 
 
 Food for Thought More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurant Scores 

 Restaurant Scores 
 The inspection scores reported here are accurate at the time of this report. To check the latest scores, visit the Tennessee Department of Health website . The inspection scores reported here are accurate at the time of this report. To check the latest scores, visit the Tennessee Department of Health website . More &gt;&gt; 
 Don Dare 

 Don Dare 
 6 On Your Side reporter Don Dare reports on the latest restaurant inspections by the Knox County Health Department every Thursday on 6 News at 6:00. Each week, 6 On Your Side reporter Don Dare checks the latest restaurant inspections by the Knox County Health Department. Find out which restaurants flunked and which are the cleanest every Thursday More &gt;&gt; 
 
By DON DARE 
Food for Thought Reporter

KNOXVILLE (WATE) - You may be surprised when you see some of the restaurants that did poorly this week in their health inspections.

 Lowest Scoring Restaurants: 

 The Orangery, 5412 Kingston Pike - Grade: 59 

Below 70 is considered &quot;unsanitary,&quot; and this fine dining restaurant that features French cuisine didn&apos;t come close to that.

The inspector reported finding a rotten onion in a storage bin.

She said she watched a kitchen worker wipe his hands on a dirty rag, then prepare tomatoes without washing his hands first.

What&apos;s more, the dishwasher temperature wasn&apos;t hot enough. The proper temperature is 165 degrees to clean dishes, not 143 degrees.

Also, when the inspector checked the microwave oven, it was dirty inside and out.


 Mexico Lindo, 462 Cedar Bluff Rd. - Grade: 61 

Here the inspector found personal medicine stored with food. It should have been in either a locker or purse to prevent any surprises.

Also, water was dripping in the walk-in cooler from the ceiling onto food.


 Copper Cellar, 7316 Kingston Pike - Grade: 63 

Hamburger meat wasn&apos;t being stored cool enough. The proper holding temperature is 41 degrees or lower.

Individual patties of butter were left out were at room temperature of 71 degrees. They should have been at 41 degrees.

Finally, mold and mildew were seen inside the ice machine.


 Gatti&apos;s Pizza, 7664 Oak Ridge Hwy. - Grade: 64 

The inspector reported finding flies buzzing around in the kitchen.

He also ordered five pizzas thrown out because they weren&apos;t hot. They were sitting out at 62 degrees.


 Oscars, 1840 W Cumberland Ave. - Grade: 64 

Here the inspector found kitchen equipment dirty. He also writes there was a plumbing problem.


 Salsarita&apos;s, 5224 Broadway - Grade: 65 

The inspector watched an employee handle a trash can as debris was brushed from it, but then the employee didn&apos;t wash his hands as he went back to work in the kitchen.


 3 Spoons Frozen Yogurt, 1710 Cumberland Ave. - Grade: 67 

Employees weren&apos;t sanitizing their yogurt machine properly.


 Cancun, 4409 Chapman Hwy. - Grade: 68 

A condenser in the walk-in cooler was dripping water onto chicken and other meat. A toilet in the ladies wasn&apos;t working.


 Other low scores: 

 Savelli&apos;s Deli, 3055 Sutherland Ave. - Grade: 69 Oskies Sports Grill, 155 West End Ave. - Grade: 69 

 This week&apos;s high scores: 

 Creative Cakery, 7780 Oak Ridge Hwy. - Grade: 97 Firehouse Subs, 119 Brooklawn St. - Grade: 95 McDonald&apos;s, 7402 Strawberry Plains Pike - Grade: 93 Pizza Hut, 5701 Western Ave. - Grade: 92 
 
 
 More Knox County News More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Jury gives Knoxville man lesser charge in shooting death of girlfriend 

 Jury gives Knoxville man lesser charge in shooting death of girlfriend 
 A Knoxville man was found guilty Thursday of a lesser charge of reckless homicide in the shooting death of his girlfriend. More &gt;&gt; A Knoxville man was found guilty Thursday of a lesser charge of reckless homicide in the shooting death of his girlfriend. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hundreds wait for hours to see Olympic swim team 

 Hundreds wait for hours to see Olympic swim team 
 Hundreds of people lined up in the rain on the University of Tennessee campus early Thursday for a chance to watch the U.S. Olympic swimming team practice.
 More &gt;&gt; Hundreds of people lined up in the rain on the University of Tennessee campus early Thursday for a chance to watch the U.S. Olympic swimming team practice.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 Knox County man arrested while doing yard work in the nude 

 Knox County man arrested while doing yard work in the nude 
 A Knox County man was arrested Wednesday after he was seen naked working in his yard. More &gt;&gt; A Knox County man was arrested Wednesday after he was seen naked working in his yard. More &gt;&gt; 
 UT phone app helps gardeners identify pests, problems 

 UT phone app helps gardeners identify pests, problems 
 Tennessee home gardeners can now tap their smartphones for help to care for their landscapes and stay on track with seasonal chores. More &gt;&gt; Tennessee home gardeners can now tap their smartphones for help to care for their landscapes and stay on track with seasonal chores. More &gt;&gt; 
 Nashville Calhoun&apos;s closes doors after 25 years 

 Nashville Calhoun&apos;s closes doors after 25 years 
 A chain based in Knoxville has one of it&apos;s restaurants closed in Nashville. More &gt;&gt; The Calhoun&apos;s Restaurant on White Bridge Road in Nashville has closed its doors for good. The location had been open for 25 years.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 Knoxville store shut down for alleged synthetic drug sales 

 Knoxville store shut down for alleged synthetic drug sales 
 A Knoxville convenience store was shutdown Wednesday after investigators said synthetic marijuana was being sold at that location.
 More &gt;&gt; A Knoxville convenience store was shutdown Wednesday after investigators said synthetic marijuana was being sold at that location.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 Dispute leaves DirecTV subscribers without channels 

 Dispute leaves DirecTV subscribers without channels 
 DirecTV customers may notice they have fewer channels. A dispute has caused Viacom to pull some their channels from DirecTV. More &gt;&gt; Satellite distributor DirecTV is in a dispute with Viacom, which owns 17 channels no longer available.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 Four candidates vie for newly-created Knox County House seat 

 Four candidates vie for newly-created Knox County House seat 
 With no Democrat in the running, the upcoming Republican primary will decide the race. The four men running for the 89th House seat all come from different backgrounds and experiences.
 More &gt;&gt; With no Democrat in the running, the upcoming Republican primary will decide the race. The four men running for the 89th House seat all come from different backgrounds and experiences.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 Two Knox men arrested on child sex charges 

 Two Knox men arrested on child sex charges 
 Two Knox County men were arrested Wednesday morning on sex charges involving children. More &gt;&gt; Two Knox County men were arrested Wednesday morning on sex charges involving children. More &gt;&gt; 
 Efforts underway to save Knoxville&apos;s old South High School 

 Efforts underway to save Knoxville&apos;s old South High School 
 The historic building at Moody Avenue and Tipton Street has become a blighted property, but plans are in the works to save the structure.
 More &gt;&gt; The historic building at Moody Avenue and Tipton Street has become a blighted property, but plans are in the works to save the structure.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 
 
 Stay in Touch Stay in Touch More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Discuss and Share 

 Discuss and Share 
 Facebook 
 WATE Blogs 
 Photos and Video 
 Send a News Tip   More &gt;&gt; 
 Follow 6 News 

 Follow 6 News 
 Twitter 
 Email Alerts 
 RSS Feeds 
 Mobile News   More &gt;&gt; 
 
 All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WATE. All Rights Reserved.
For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
