<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006734" url="http://www.payscale.com/research/US/Employer=McDonald&apos;s_Corporation/Hourly_Rate" time="2012-07-12-23:44" support="9" score="0.023041045312225006" bingtitle="PayScale - McDonald&apos;s Corporation Employer Wages, Hourly Wage Rate" webtitle="PayScale  - McDonald&apos;s Corporation Employer Wages, Hourly Wage Rate">
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001065" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>Pay can vary greatly by location. To view local data, take the PayScale survey. ... Combined Food Preparation and Serving Worker, Including Fast Food: $7.55</description>
	<body>
		Create an account Log in 
 
 INDIVIDUALS EMPLOYERS 
 
 My Salary Reports Career Research 
 Research Center Salary Calculator GigZig Cost of Living Calculator 
 Blogs 
 The Salary Reporter Ask Dr. Salary Salary Stories Compensation Today 
 Special Features 
 The PayScale Index Data Packages Infographics 
 Education 
 Degree Research College ROI Report College Salary Report 
 Find Jobs 
 Find Jobs 
 
 
 
 
Hourly Rate for McDonald&apos;s Corporation Employees
 Updated: 3 Jul 2012 
 Browse the Index   |   United States    (Change Country) 
 
 
 Salary Hourly Rate Bonus Vacation Weeks Popular Tallies More 
 Commute Time Commission Profit Sharing 
 
 
 
 United States » Employer Name » McDonald&apos;s Corporation Overview » McDonald&apos;s Corporation Hourly Rate Find Out Exactly What
YOU Should Be Paid Get a more precise salary
range for your exact position. 
 Job Title Country State City Experience 
 Check salary info for your own job Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation Hourly Rate Range by Job 
 Job (Number Reporting) National Data ( ? X All compensation data shown are gross, national 10th to 90th percentile ranges. Pay can vary greatly by location. To view local data, take the PayScale survey . ) $0 $7 $14 $21 
 
 
 [-] Cashier (34) 
 $7.20 - $9.01         

 
 [-] Cashier (34) 
 

 Hourly Rate $7.20 - $9.01         Learn more about this career 
 
 
 [+] Assistant Manager, Fast Food (15) 
 $8.91 - $13.83         

 
 [+] Assistant Manager, Fast Food (15) 
 

 Overtime $13.41 - $21.76         Hourly Rate $8.91 - $13.83   Learn more about this career 
 
 
 [+] Fast Food Worker (14) 
 $7.12 - $8.62         

 
 [+] Fast Food Worker (14) 
 

 Hourly Rate $7.12 - $8.62         Learn more about this career 
 
 
 [+] General Manager, Restaurant (13) 
 $7.77 - $19.39         

 
 [+] General Manager, Restaurant (13) 
 

 Hourly Rate $7.77 - $19.39         Learn more about this career Compare Employers for this Job Title 
 
 See more jobs for McDonald&apos;s Corporation 

 Country: United States | Currency: USD | Updated: 3 Jul 2012 | Individuals Reporting: 361 
 
  Add to your site  |  Share | 
 
 Job Listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation Jobs
 
 
 Posted 
Job Title
 Company 
Job Location
 Jan 24 
 Global Marketing Director - 6408 MB / SS 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation Oak Brook, Illinois Over-see creative approvals in partnership with McDonald&apos;s Legal

Partner with the Global Marketing teams... competitive creative and McDonald&apos;s creative around... Indeed Jan 22 
 Director, Global Menu Strategy 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation Oak Brook, Illinois the Department:

For McDonald&apos;s, one of the most... Accountabilities:

In addition to following McDonald&apos;s policies and procedures, principal accountabilities... Indeed Jan 17 
 Design Director - E-Commerce Platforms 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation Oak Brook, Illinois Description: 
 McDonald&apos;s Worldwide Concept and... marketing, operations, and management.

Working at McDonald&apos;s requires a global mindset and empathy for... Indeed Jan 19 
 Marketing Manager 
 McDonald&apos;s Roseland, New Jersey McDonald?s policies and procedures, principal accountabilities include, but are not limited to:Leadership- Maintains and strengthens the McDonald&apos;s brand... Indeed 
 Previous Next 
 jobs by 
 Search for more jobs: 
 
 Compare Employers :
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation Portillo&apos;s Chilis Bar and Grill Job Satisfaction ( ? X The job satisfaction stars show how satisfied employees are with their job at a particular employer, relative to other employers. For example, when all five stars are highlighted, that doesn&apos;t mean all employees at that employer are &quot;Extremely satisfied,&quot; but it does mean a significant majority are &quot;Extremely satisfied&quot; compared to workers at other employers. ) Extremely satisfied Highly satisfied Highly satisfied Work Stress ( ? X The work stress thermometer reflects the intensity of stress experienced by employees on the job at a particular employer, relative to other employers. For example, when the arrow on the thermometer indicates &quot;Extremely Stressful,&quot; that doesn&apos;t mean all employees at that employer feel that their job is &quot;Extremely stressful,&quot; but it does mean a significant majority find their job to be &quot;Extremely stressful&quot; compared to workers at other employers. ) Highly stressful Extremely stressful Highly stressful Job Flexibility ( ? X The job flexibility scale (with options including Not flexible, Somewhat flexible, Flexible, Highly flexible, Extremely flexible) indicates an employer&apos;s typical flexibility regarding schedule as reported by employees and as compared to other employers. For example, if the text shown is &quot;Not flexible,&quot; that doesn&apos;t mean all employees at that employer feel that the employer is &quot;Not flexible,&quot; but it does mean a significant majority feel that their employer is &quot;Not flexible&quot; compared to workers at other employers. ) Highly flexible Highly flexible Highly flexible Typical Benefits unavailable Vacation Weeks 1.4 Weeks 2.3 Weeks 1.5 Weeks Gender Breakdown 
 49% 51% 
 
 50% 50% 
 
 21% 79% 
 Years Experience Breakdown 
 1-4 5-9 
 
 1-4 10-19 
 
 &lt;1 1-4 5-9 
 Popular Perks Free beverages , 401(k) , Paid holidays&amp;vacation 401(k) , Free beverages , Life insurance / disability 401(k) , Free beverages , Paid holidays&amp;vacation Job Satisfaction ( ? X The job satisfaction stars show how satisfied employees are with their job at a particular employer, relative to other employers. For example, when all five stars are highlighted, that doesn&apos;t mean all employees at that employer are &quot;Extremely satisfied,&quot; but it does mean a significant majority are &quot;Extremely satisfied&quot; compared to workers at other employers. ) Extremely satisfied Highly satisfied Highly satisfied Typical Benefits unavailable Popular Perks Free beverages , 401(k) , Paid holidays&amp;vacation 401(k) , Free beverages , Life insurance / disability 401(k) , Free beverages , Paid holidays&amp;vacation 
 [-] Collapse [+] Expand 
 Key Statistics for
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Salaries and Jobs
 
 
 Gender 

 Female 49%   Male 51% Hourly Rate: $7.75 - $10.41 $7.90 - $9.82 
 
 Years of Experience 

 
 
 Less than 1 year 
 6% 
 1-4 years 
 43% 
 5-9 years 
 23% 
 10-19 years 
 17% 
 20 years or more 
 11% 
 
 
 Top Degrees 
Hourly Rate
 

 Bachelor&apos;s Degree $7.25 - $13.91 Associate&apos;s Degree $7.86 - $14.90 High School Diploma Not enough data GED or High School Diploma Not enough data Bachelor of Science (BS / BSc), Finance Not enough data 
 See more degrees 
 Work Stress 

 Extremely stressful Highly stressful Stressful Somewhat stressful Not stressful 
 
 
 Special Reports 
 Apple vs. Amazon: Top Tech Employers Compared 
What&apos;s unique about people who work in tech and which companies offer them the best pay and benefits? PayScale reviews stats on Facebook, Google, Microsoft and more. More Special Reports » Which jobs, cities and industries are seeing wages recover post-recession? Track the latest compensation trends with The PayScale Index Q2 2012 results. » Do Employers &quot;Like&quot; Social Media? [infographic] » Should you ask for a raise? [infographic] » College Tuition ROI : Will your education pay off? » Are you a tech rock star? Here&apos;s where to find the best startup IT jobs . 
 Company Locations for
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 
Popular McDonald&apos;s Corporation Locations

 
 
 
 
Company Locations By Popularity
 1. Mesa, Arizona 2. Louisville, Kentucky 3. Panama City Beach, Florida 4. Toledo, Ohio 5. Santa Clara, California 6. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 7. Raleigh, North Carolina 
 
 Mesa, Arizona (AZ) #1 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Mesa, Arizona. Louisville, Kentucky (KY) #2 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Louisville, Kentucky. Panama City Beach, Florida (FL) #3 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Panama City Beach, Florida. Toledo, Ohio (OH) #4 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Toledo, Ohio. Santa Clara, California (CA) #5 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Santa Clara, California. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (PA) #6 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Raleigh, North Carolina (NC) #7 Most Popular Location for this Company See job listings for McDonald&apos;s Corporation in Raleigh, North Carolina. 
 More Charts for
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Jobs
 
Related Charts for 
 Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation

 Median Hourly Rate by Years Experience - Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation Median Hourly Rate by City - Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation Median Hourly Rate by State or Province - Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation 

 
Most Popular Job for 
 Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Median Hourly Rate Charts 

 Cashier Assistant Manager, Fast Food Fast Food Worker General Manager, Restaurant Restaurant Manager Cook, Fast Food Fast Food Manager 

 More  
Most Popular Years Experience for 
 Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Median Hourly Rate Charts 

 Less than 1 year 1-4 years 5-9 years 10-19 years 20 years or more 

 More  
Most Popular City for 
 Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Median Hourly Rate Charts 

 Mesa, Arizona Louisville, Kentucky Panama City Beach, Florida Toledo, Ohio Santa Clara, California Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Raleigh, North Carolina 

 More  
Most Popular State or Province for 
 Employer: McDonald&apos;s Corporation
 Median Hourly Rate Charts 

 California Pennsylvania Georgia Florida North Carolina Ohio Michigan 

 More  Subscribe to Our Newsletter Salary and career advice to put you a step ahead. 
 
 Thanks! We&apos;ll send you a welcome newsletter as soon as we can.

In the meantime, check out our research center.
 
Looks like your email already exists in our database.
Please log in here .
 
You are already logged in.
 
 
 Follow Us On:       
 Employers Compensation Software Request a Demo Get a Free Report Read Customer Success Stories Download Whitepapers Employees&amp;Job Seekers Personal Salary Report Blogs Career Research Job Listings Special Features Our Company About PayScale Announcements Jobs at PayScale Management Team PayScale In the News Terms of Use Privacy Policy Methodology Publisher Tools Contact Us ©2000- PayScale, Inc.
All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
