<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006304" url="http://www.peiweiblog.com/food/caramel-chicken-stock-velveted/" time="2012-07-12-22:59" support="10" score="0.03477525640908664" bingtitle="Caramel Chicken, Stock Velveted… | Pei Wei Blog" webtitle="Caramel Chicken, Stock Velveted|  Pei Wei Blog">
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000136" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="146"/>
	<description>When you order your Caramel Chicken stock velvet ... stock velveted or steamed is something all cashiers ... quality napkins I have seen in a casual fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home About the Pei Wei Blog Photos Order Online Contact Us 

 Posts Comments 
 Pei Wei Blog East of Usual® 
 Jun 23 
 
Caramel Chicken, Stock Velveted…

by Joe in Flavor Tourism , Food , Vietnam 
 
 To Stock Velvet or Not to Stock Velvet…. 

That is often the question when ordering Pei Wei. When we were out in Phoenix for our culinary meeting and livestream event, I learned an interesting tidbit about Pei Wei’s new Caramel Chicken, between ordering Wok Fried vs Stock Velvet. Stock velvet has not only less fat but building the sauce in the wok isn’t the same as when the protein is fried.

Plus when your dish arrives stock velvet you can amuse your friends and say, “is this velvet? This is beautiful!” Ok back on track…

Let’s start with the health aspect first. When you order your Caramel Chicken stock velvet, it will have 35% less fat than the same wok-fried dish. The way to achieve that health difference is that that protein is poached in a vegetable stock made fresh throughout the day. Some may argue the texture is different while others just prefer that crunch you get from the wok fried. Regardless, you can’t argue with the numbers!

If you’re not worried about counting grams of fat, the flavor difference between the same entrée prepared two different ways is striking. The stock velvet dish is very lively on the palate capturing more of the highs and lows of the sauce&amp;aromatics. The reason for this is that the oil used to cook the protein in the wok becomes a coating on the tongue and other flavor receptors in your mouth. The wok chef will need to add more firepower to get the same flavor effect. Personally I think, you’ll be able to taste a broader range of flavors with a stock velveted Caramel Chicken and possibly enjoy it more. And  having less fat doesn’t hurt either.

So here’s my Pei Wei challenge for all of you…when it comes time for Carmel Chicken, order one entrée stock velveted and the other in its traditional style. Taste them both side by side and see if you can taste a difference. It’s the best way to really get an idea of how very different the two can be. Who knows you may even start ordering all your entrees in a new way!

I’d love to hear if anyone has a preference one way or another. Drop me a note in the comment section to let us know where you fall – To Stock Velvet or Not to Stock Velvet.

 Joe Campagna is the Chicago Food Snob. A former restaurant General Manager, Server and Chef you can find him on twitter @chifoodsnob. You can reach him through email at chicagofoodsnob@hotmail.com . Joe is retained as a compensated blogger by Pei Wei Asian Diner. 
 
Tags: Caramel Chicken , Stock Velvet 
 
93 Responses to“Caramel Chicken, Stock Velveted…”

 
From Mothermary:

Okay . . . is this Caramel chicken GF or not? Is there soy sauce in the caramel sauce? If this franchise belongs to PF Chang’s, as I keep hearing, why don’t they substitute the San J wheat free soy sauce in other sauces? Thankfully they do have the little packets which is VERY helpful. Anyway, I love going to Pei Wei, just wish there were more GF options. Unfortunately, this GF thing isn’t a life style choice so, no cheating for me!
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 4:15 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

The Caramel Chicken is NOT gluten free, regardless of preperation. We are also owned by the same parent company that owns P.F. Chang’s.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:08 PM # 
 
From krista c.:

This is the best news since paper napkins…Thank you so much, but please make sure the people at the cash register know about this, sometimes when I order new things or specials..they have no idea what I am talking about.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 4:31 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Ordering your dish stock velveted or steamed is something all cashiers should know. It is a standard part of our menu training.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:10 PM # 
 
From Christine:

Yes, they should all know but I ALWAYS have problems ordering it. I have gotten to ordering only online so I can place my order correctly. Please, please educate your staff 

PS, Thai Dynamite is GREAT stock velvet!
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 3:13 PM # 
 
 
From Lizzy T.:

To stock velvet! I’ve been ordering the Kung pao chicken stock velvet for years! It tastes better especially if you don’t eat fried food often. You can order any chicken dish stock velvet. I’ve never had a problem with the cashiers not knowing but I always ask if I can please have the chicken steamed/stock velvet? They should all know!
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 4:52 PM # 
From Tiffany:

Is there ANY WAY to make it gluten free??? Carmel chicken (and Pei Wei) were my FAVORITE until my diagnosis a few months ago. I LOVE IT!!!!!!!!!
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:21 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Unfortunately, the Caramel Chicken is not available as a GF dish. The sauce contains gluten.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:55 PM # 
 
From Tiffany:

Well, you guys do a great job with the GF sweet and sour chicken! Thanks!
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 6:30 PM # 
 
 
From Karch:

What’s the difference between ordered a chicken dish stock velvet vs steamed? Is steamed less fat than stock velvet?
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:47 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Stock Velvet&amp;steamed are the same thing. We say both terms because some cashiers know it as both.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 5:56 PM # 
 
From Lane:

I’m assuming other proteins can be“stock velveted”…right?
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 6:53 PM # 
 
From Cristina:

You can stock velvet all the proteins. They are a bit more hesitant with the steak, but they will. I would just ask them to steam it“well done”
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 9:14 PM # 
From PeiWei :

That is correct!
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:21 AM # 
 
From nolie:

How in the world do you order“stock velvet”online? After seeing this email, I tried and found the phrase NOWHERE in the‘order online’process. I eventually (though not easily) found a way to order my chicken“steamed”. Is there an easier way?

By the way, I’ve had dinner now and the Caramel Chicken was terrific steamed.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 7:09 PM # 
From Sarah Bryant:

Can any dish be ordered stock velvet? Specifically the Pad Thai? That’s my favorite, but I try not to eat it too often because it doesn’t taste very healthy (i.e. it tastes WAY too good =P ).

And I too would like to know how to order stock velvet online.
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 7:29 PM # 
 
From Cristina:

The Pad Thai is already cooked stock velvet unless you order steak. If you do order steak, you may request it Stock Velvet. I do not know how to order S.V. online though, sorry 
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 9:16 PM # 
From PeiWei :

Sarah, any dish can be ordered stock velvet. However, the Pad Thai is already prepared in that manner.
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:20 AM # 
 
From Joyce:

I have been ordering it like this for a long time, but I didn’t know there was a name for it! I have stopped eating fried food, and I avoid oil as much as possible. When I order meals, I ask for it to be made with“no oil”and I just assumed it was steamed.

I have however got puzzled looks sometimes from the cashiers. Next time I will try saying stock velvet!

Thank you PeiWei for having this option!
 Posted on June 23, 2011 at 9:42 PM # 
From denice becker :

hi, eat at your restaurant twice a week, each week. don’t you have frequent diner cards to reward loyal customers.
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 6:00 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Denice, while we have tested a rewards card in select restaurants, we do not currently have one available.
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 7:12 AM # 
From Tracy N.:

I have a Pei Wei rewards card. It gives you a free meal after you purchase 10, and you can keep track of it online. Why do they tell you they don’t have them?
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 9:56 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Tracy, our rewards card is not available at all our restaurants. It is only available in our California and Nevada restaurants
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:16 AM # 
 
From Eric:

We also eat at Pei Wei often, and love it! We moved from California to Virginia and were VERY disappointed to find out the rewards card does not work outside of California and Nevada. What’s the plan? Will you have it in other areas soon? I recommend starting with Virginia!!
 Posted on July 7, 2011 at 7:34 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Eric, the Rewards Card is testing in CA&amp;NV. Right now, there are no plans to expand it outside those two states.
 Posted on July 7, 2011 at 8:13 AM # 
 
 
 
 
From tami murphy:

What is the total calories for the Kung Pai Chicken on brown rice, (entire Portion) also what is the lowest calories entree that Pei Wei offers?
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 6:59 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Tami, our complete nutritional info is available to download at http://www.peiwei.com/menu .
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 7:14 AM # 
 
From Rita:

Which version has less sodium content?
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 4:48 PM # 
 
From Rita:

Scratch that.. I found it on your nutrition download !
 Posted on June 24, 2011 at 4:51 PM # 
 
From c121592:

Does the Caramel Chicken contain any Fish products (in a sauce needed to marinate, etc.)?
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 8:50 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Yes, the Caramel Chicken contains fish sauce.
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 12:55 PM # 
 
From Helen:

I did not know you used fish oil in the Carmel Chicken. I hate the taste and smell. What is on your menu without fish oils?
 Posted on June 29, 2011 at 3:40 PM # 
 
 
From Stacy:

I think it’s funny that you’re touting healthy“caramel”chicken. How about leaving out the sugar?
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 8:53 AM # 
From Carla:

I, too, am curious as to whether the Caramel Chicken is made with any fish sauce. When I had it recently, I thought I detected a very slight fishy taste, which I did not care for. I have previously asked Pei Wei employees to recommend entrees that contain no fish sauce, (oyster sauce, for example) and it seems that there are very few available. Can you please tell me which entrees are completely fish-free? Thanks!
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 9:37 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

The Caramel Chicken sauce does have some fish sauce in it.
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 12:54 PM # 
 
From nolie:

Dear Pei Wei. Please answer my post from Thursday…

How in the world do you order “stock velvet” online? After seeing this email, I tried and found the phrase NOWHERE in the ‘order online’ process. I eventually (though not easily) found a way to order my chicken “steamed”. Is there an easier way?

By the way, I’ve had dinner now and the Caramel Chicken was terrific steamed.

Posted on June 23, 2011 at 7:09 PM #
 Posted on June 25, 2011 at 1:57 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Nolie, I apologize for missing your post. To order Stock Velvet, click the steamed protein button online. They are the same thing.
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:16 AM # 
 
From jessica:

Would love to try it but I did not get my BOGO coupon. when I tried to sign up for it I got a message that my email was already in the system
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 9:57 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Jessica, I looked up your account, and it appears your email was in the system. However, there was a data issue on our end. I have corrected the mistake for future emails and offers.
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:19 AM # 
 
From Tracy N.:

I am VERY excited to know about this option! There are so many yummy dishes I don’t order because they are fried. Thank you for sharing this! I can order all kinds of dishes now! LOVE Pei Wei!!
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 10:00 AM # 
From Maxine:

I eat at Pei Wei regularly. My kids love it. This is the first time I’ve heard of the term stock velvet. I’m always watching my weight and fat content and try to order the most healthiest items you have, but now I can have more to choose from now that I now this“Stock Velvet”term. By the way, I love your napkins! They are the thickest highest quality napkins I have seen in a casual fast food restaurant. Even my kids talk about them!
 Posted on June 27, 2011 at 11:47 AM # 
From Jess:

Any chance we can get the nutritional information for Caramel Chicken? I know it says 35% less fat, but what does that mean in numbers? Thanks!
 Posted on June 29, 2011 at 7:48 PM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Jess, our complete nutritional info, including Caramel Chicken, can be downloaded from our website.
 Posted on July 7, 2011 at 8:16 AM # 
 
From Jan:

Thank you for the velveting……please make this an option on all your selections. I work near your store and would eat there more often if the fat was reduced on your options. I cook with the broth when I stir fry and the flavors are much more lively and fresh!! MORE MORE MORE MORE PLEASE!
 Posted on July 1, 2011 at 10:06 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Jan, stock velvet is available on all Pei Wei dishes. Some are already prepared that way.
 Posted on July 7, 2011 at 8:15 AM # 
 
From angie :

I recently tried the caramel chicken liked it but decided it would be an occassioal order cause it seemed fatty. Had I known i had the option of“stock velvet or whatever”i might be a frequent eater! why didnt the cashier give me the option or at least have it on the menu?????
 Posted on July 3, 2011 at 5:07 PM # 
From Mark:

Couldn’t you use San J soy and arrowroot as the thickener to make the carmel chicken velvet a gluten free dish?
 Posted on July 6, 2011 at 4:44 PM # 
From Christopher:

Very saddened about Pei Wei. I introduces hundreds of friends to try Pei Wei. They received a free coupon to try the new Carmel Chicken via the internet. I did not receive a free coupon. Unbelieveable to have hurt one of your most valuable customers. When I discussed the matter with the Manager at your Royal Oak Michigan location on Woodward, het turned me off. I had such a bad experience talking with him that he turned me off from suggesting Pei Wei to other friends and family. He wouldn’t even give me a store number that I could contact corporate. Thanks. Customer Service is Key to Longevity.
 Posted on July 10, 2011 at 8:01 AM # 
 
From PeiWei :

Christopher, the Caramel Chicken offer was sent out exclusively to those who were signed up for our emails by Wednesday, June 8. I looked up your email address, and it appears that you signed up just past the deadline on June 10. I’m sorry for the confusion or any mix up.
 Posted on July 11, 2011 at 3:00 PM # 
 
From suzanne w :

I tried the Caramel Chicken Stock Velvet style..yum ! Of course Lemon Pepper Chicken will always be my all time favorite.
 Posted on July 19, 2011 at 5:46 AM # 
 «Older Comments 
Blog Topics

 China Flavor Tourism Food Japan Korea Recipe Recipes Thailand Travel Vietnam 
 
 Photos on flick r 
 
©2012 Pei Wei Asian Diner, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
 
 View Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
