<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006511" url="http://www.oldbaldycwrt.org/pastmeetings.html" time="2012-07-12-23:26" support="1" score="0.0003878553636926949" bingtitle="Old Baldy Civil War Round Table -- Past Meetings" webtitle="Old Baldy Civil War Round Table -- Past Meetings">
			<query id="001031" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Bill Hughes: US General Hospital at Beverly, NJ: March ... to discuss the future of the Old Baldy Round Table. ... shopping center, complete with gas station and fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		&gt;Home &gt;About Us &gt;Member Profiles &gt;Past Meetings &gt;Newsletters &gt;Archives &gt;Events 
 
 
Past Meetings

 Date Speaker Topic June 14, 2012 Kerry Bryan A Salute to Old Glory: The Story of the American Flag May 10, 2012 multiple Old Baldy Goes to South Jersey April 12, 2012 Arlene Harris John Fulton Reynolds: Duty, Honor, Sacrifice March 8, 2012 Rich Jankowski Renovations Needed for Old Baldy February 9, 2012 Hugh Boyle The Women in Lincoln&apos;s Life January 12, 2012 Don Wiles Gettysburg... Hallowed Ground in Bronze and Stone December 8, 2011 Jane Peters Estes A Christmas Past November 10, 2011 Herb Kaufman Creating the Gettysburg Address October 13, 2011 Phil Lechak Camp Letterman, Gettysburg: 80 Acres for 121 Days September 8, 2011 Craig Schoeller Battle of the Bulge—Imprisonment August 11, 2011 Old Baldy members Show and Tell July 14, 2011 Mike Wunsch Abraham Lincoln&amp;the Great Central Sanitary Fair June 9, 2011 Craig Schoeller WWII Battle of the Bulge, based on his personal experience May 12, 2011 Jack Lieberman Life and Civil War Achievements of Capt. Percival Drayton April 14, 2011 Bill Hughes US General Hospital at Beverly, NJ March 10, 2011 Dick Simpson Wilson&apos;s Creek, August 10, 1861 February 10, 2011 Stephen Wright and
Hugh Boyle Abraham Lincoln Program January 13, 2011 Roger Arthur The Secession Crisis December 9, 2010 Stephen Wright and
Michael A. Cavanaugh Battle of Fredericksburg and Defense of Gen. Burnside November 11, 2010 Sid Copel Civil War Spies&amp;Guerillas October 14, 2010 John Nagy Invisible Ink, Spycraft of the American Revolution September 9, 2010 Jim Heenehan Colonel Ira Grover, 7th Indiana Volunteer Infantry: The True Story of his Court-Martial and Acquittal July 8, 2010 Jerry Carrier Meet John Hay—A One-Man Historical Presentation June 10, 2010 Ed Root General Butler&apos;s 1862 Tenure in New Orleans May 13, 2010 Herb Kaufman A People at War: American Jewry and the Civil War April 8, 2010 Mike Burkhimer The Reports of the Lincolns’ Political Partnership Have Been Greatly Exaggerated 

 Meeting of June 14, 2012

   Kerry Bryan Old Glory   

Kerry Bryan on&quot;A Salute to Old Glory: The Story of the American Flag&quot;

Having needed some 40 years to recover from the effects of a really BAD high school history teacher, Kerry Bryan discovered a love of historical research just a few years ago while taking graduate courses at the University of Pennsylvania. Her Civil War epiphany occurred when she went as a spectator to the 145th Gettysburg Battle reenactment in 2008 because her brother had come up from North Carolina to participate as a Union soldier. She began reading about the Civil War and hasn’t stopped since! Kerry has been a member of the Old Baldy Civil War Round Table since July, 2009, and belongs to numerous other local historical institutions and societies.

Since the meeting fell on June 14th, which is Flag Day, Kerry prepared a PowerPoint presentation called “A Salute to Old Glory: The Story of the American Flag.” Kerry gave a great presentation on the History of flags and of our flag—what the flag has meant to this country. Ours is the only country that has a “Flag Day” and a “Pledge of Allegiance” to that flag. She talked about the design of the first American flags and a little on the “Betsy Ross” story. The choice of colors, stars, stripes and the overall design and its migration into what it looks like today and what it means to its patriots today. The history of our flag actually incorporates the history of the people of this country.

 Meeting of May 10, 2012

 Dr. Jack Pesda 

&quot;Old Baldy Goes to South Jersey&quot;

The Old Baldy Civil War Round Table of Philadelphia held its May 10th meeting at Camden County College. The main purpose was to inform the area about the Old Baldy Civil War Roundtable of Philadelphia. The purposes of the Roundtable are to help educate people in the Civil War era and to preserve the battlefields, artifacts, and the history of the area and its citizens who took part in that era. Rich Jankowski and Bill Hughes gave talks on the history and aims of the round table. Dr. Jack Pesda of Camden County College gave a presentation on the college and what they are doing to educate people on the Civil War era and the how the college may work with the round table. The college has offered us use of a meeting room and will help spread the word about our round table, which will help us to attract new members. The July meeting is now scheduled to be held at Camden County College on Wednesday, July 11th at 7:15PM (note change to Wednesday).



 Meeting of April 12, 2012

 

Arlene Harris on&quot;John Fulton Reynolds: Duty, Honor, Sacrifice&quot;

Arlene D. Harris spoke in the first person as Catherine F. Reynolds, the sister that John F. Reynolds was closest to through-out his life. Starting with his early life and education, this presentation showed how what Reynolds learned and accomplished shaped the Code of Honor he would live and die by and how truly dedicated and valuable to his country he was.

Arlene provided information on her background: Born in New Jersey of Pennsylvania parents, in 1953. I am a lifelong student of American History. After years of studying early and late Native American wars and then the American Revolution I decided to get into the American Civil War in the mid 1980&apos;s. After finding I had more than a passing interest in John F. Reynolds, and why, I decided to center my studies and research on him. My found connection goes back to 1987. My husband Steve and I have been involved in Civil War living history as Henry and Kate Reynolds Landis since 2000. We belong to: Friends of Lancaster Cemetery, the General Meade Society of Philadelphia, the 98th Pennsylvania Volunteer History Organization, the Confederation of Union Generals based in Lancaster, Pennsylvania and the GAR Museum and Library of Philadelphia. We constantly do events in connection with these organizations. I gave three lectures on Major General Reynolds in 2010, two in 2011, and this will be the third year participating in Victorian Day for the Lancaster Cemetery, speaking at John Reynolds&apos; grave-site as Kate Reynolds as one of the stops on the cemetery tours all that day. To me I feel the most important thing we do is that we have complete adoption of the grave of John F. Reynolds and the entire Reynolds family plot which we landscape and care for year round. Being an art major, my John F. Reynolds connection has brought me back to my artwork and an oil portrait of him is in the works.

 

 Meeting of March 8, 2012

 

Rich Jankowski on&quot;Renovations Needed for the Old Baldy CWRT&quot;

Our March meeting was to discuss the future of the Old Baldy Round Table. Fifteen folks showed up for the discussion. We had received 4 emails and 1 phone message from those unable to be there in person. Bill Hughes gave a brief account of the events in the last several months including the Board Meeting. The email and phone comments were shared with the audience. Herb Kaufman gave an account of our financial situation [which is good without dues collection]. Several members made their comments about their time with the Round Table and the Pine Street Museum. Discussion included Center City, the Union League, the aging of the membership, the need to publicize, and possible alternatives.

In the past it had been proposed to find another location as a possible solution to draw more folks. Since more than half of our regular attendees at the meetings are coming from New Jersey, Bill Hughes pursued some locations to possibly hold a meeting there. He made contact with Jack Pesda at the Center for Civic Leadership and Responsibility at Camden County College. Pesda agreed to host a meeting if we continued the Round Table, to see if there was interest on the New Jersey side. Other members from New Jersey pledged to assist Bill in getting the word out about the meeting. Just like folks reluctant on coming to Center City there is a fear of crossing the bridge, although it is very convenient. At this meeting after explaining the history of the Old Baldy Round Table, current members could testify to the ease of taking the Speed Line into the City and getting to the Union League. This effort would be to reach people not currently in a Philadelphia group [Meade, GAR, Laurel Hill, Union League, etc]. Other members are invited to seek alternate locations that could draw new members. Additional suggestions were to not meet over the summer, try more round table discussions and contacting local residents.

After everyone had the opportunity to comment, it was decided to hold the April meeting at the Union League, try the May 10th meeting at the College in New Jersey and collect dues for this year—please submit them to Herb. It is hoped that these actions will generate interest in our group because something different, outside the normal actions, needs to be done to grow our Round Table. Thank you to all who provided their input on this very important issue because it is your Round Table.

 Meeting ofFebruary 9, 2012

 Mary Lincoln Sarah Bush Hugh Boyle 

Hugh Boyle on&quot;The Women in Lincoln&apos;s Life&quot;

Hugh Boyle gave us a look into the women who were in Lincoln&apos;s life and who helped toinfluence and mold who he was, what he thought, his desires, and also his melancholy. How his White House years were filled with the influence of strong, opinionated women. His presentation was superb with all the knowledge that Hugh has on Lincoln. It is always a pleasure to have Hugh visit us at Old Baldy.


 

 Meeting of January 12, 2012

 

Don Wiles on&quot;Gettysburg... Hallowed Ground in Bronze and Stone&quot;

On Thursday, January 12th OBCWRT member Don Wiles demonstrated both his graphic artist&apos;s eye and his historian&apos;s knowledge when he presented&quot;Hallowed Ground in Bronze and Stone,&quot;a slide show/talk featuring samples from his prodigious collection of photographs of Gettysburg Battlefield monuments, accompanied by Don&apos;s exposition. Don&apos;s excellent photographs manage to capture not only the careful details and artistry of the monuments, but also the spirit and ideals that they represent. Equally impressive is Don&apos;s expertise: he has spent many years walking, studying, and photographing the Gettysburg battlefield. His presentation was indeed a taste of a connoisseur&apos;s private collection; it was monumental in every sense of the word.


 Meeting of December 8, 2011

 

Jane Peters Estes on&quot;A Christmas Past&quot;

Jane Peters Estes has been a living historian and active member of various Delaware Valley region historical organizations for almost 30 years. She shared some of her expertise with members of OBCWRT on December 8th when she presented&quot;Christmas Past,&quot;a delightful overview of the origins of many of our Christmas traditions, ranging from the hanging of stockings to trimming the tree. Jane&apos;s presentation particularly highlighted Christmas customs of the Civil War era and offered many insights, some of them surprising. The program was an early yuletide gift to all who attended.

Jane has had articles published in Civil War Lady Magazine , Citizen&apos;s Companion Magazine , Philadelphia Bride MagazinUe , and People Magazine .

Jane&apos;s many programs and presentations include: Civil War Nurses, Fashions of the 1860s, Grave Matters (Victorian Mourning Customs), Wedding Customs and Traditions, Women&apos;s Lifestyles of the 1860&apos;s, Vivandieres, Pets of the Past, and The Battle of Gettysburg: Where Were the Women?

 Meeting of November 10, 2011

 

Herb Kaufman on&quot;Creating the Gettysburg Address&quot;

Herb Kaufman addressed the myth of Lincoln writing the Gettysburg Address on a small piece of paper on a train from Washington to Gettysburg. Herb pointed out the 272 words of Lincoln&apos;s Address that had their foundation in the Declaration of Independence. He explained looking into Lincoln&apos;s mind and examining his prior speeches and comments and determining how they impacted his thoughts for November 19, 1863. Herb further pointed out that Abraham Lincoln was one of our nation&apos;s most thoughtful and measured presidents. That he rarely made comments that didn&apos;t have a specific point, nor did he write a speech without giving it the most deliberate thought. The ideas and concepts that stand behind what has become his most famous and quoted speech could hardly have been attributed to a two hour ride on a train.

 Meeting of October 13, 2011

 

Phil Lechak on&quot;Camp Letterman, Gettysburg: 80 Acres for 121 Days&quot;

When the Army of the Potomac and the Army of Northern Virginia left the Gettysburg environs on July 4, they left behind almost 21,000 wounded soldiers. These men were distributed over the countryside in roughly 160 locations. Casualties of this magnitude overtaxed the available resources immediately. Camp Letterman—the first of its kind, a large General Tent Hospital—was constructed. It occupied 80 acres on the site of the George Wolf Farm, on a hillside just one mile out of town on the York Pike, and existed for a period of 121 days.

Using period accounts, original photographs, and current maps Licensed Battlefield Guide Phil Lechak brought this often overlooked and underappreciated site to life. Although today this location contains only two historic markers, a hotel, and a shopping center, complete with gas station and fast food restaurant, we took an imaginary walking tour around the grounds and experienced where soldiers healed from the ravages of war.

Phil Lechak became a Licensed Battlefield Guide at the Gettysburg National Military Park in November of 2005. At his retirement from the U. S. Postal Service in January of 2007, following an almost 37 year career, Phil and Donna, his wife of 33 years, moved to Gettysburg. Now a Full Time LBG, Phil has led multiple tours across these historic Hospital grounds for many groups and was a presenter at the 2010 13th GNMP Biennial Seminar—The Aftermath and the End of the Campaign.


 

 Meeting of September 8, 2011

 

Craig Schoeller on&quot;Battle of the Bulge—Imprisonment&quot;

Due to an emergency cancellation by the scheduled speaker, Tom Moran, this month Craig Schoeller, OBCWRT member, presented the rest of his story on surviving the&quot;Battle of the Bulge&quot;during World War II. Craig&apos;s story had previously gone from his enlistment to a replacement in the 35th Division of the Third Army in the area of Bastogne, Belgium, when the German Army made its final push to break through the American Lines. The second part of his story was about his capture and imprisonment in a German Stalag.

 Meeting of August 11, 2011

Old Baldy Members present&quot;Show and Tell&quot;

Old Baldy Members and Guests presented a&quot;Show and Tell&quot;of their Civil War interests, artifacts, projects, books, photos, battlefield trips, seminars, ancestors, etc.

 

 Meeting of July 14, 2011

Mike Wunsch on&quot;Abraham Lincoln&amp;the Great Central Sanitary Fair&quot;

 

Local speaker-historian Michael Wunsch portrayed Executive Chairman John Welsh of the Great Central Sanitary Fair, and presented Abraham Lincoln&amp;the Great Central Sanitary Fair, Philadelphia, June 1864.

The talk featured a brief overview and history of the United States Sanitary Commission, the growth of the local Aid Society and Sanitary Fair movements, as well as the Great Central Sanitary Fair itself, a huge commission fund-raising event held on the grounds of Logan Square from June 7 to June 29, 1864. It concluded with one of the true highlights of Philadelphia&apos;s immense and important home-front activities, President Abraham Lincoln&apos;s visit to the&quot;great fair,&quot;and our city at-large on June 16, 1864.

Mr. Wunsch, a resident of Philadelphia, is a graduate of Northeast High School and La Salle College. He is a member of the Delaware Valley CWRT, G.A.R. Museum&amp;Library, and the Lincoln Forum, and currently serves as the Secretary of the General Meade Society of Philadelphia, an educational non-profit group devoted to Major General George G. Meade&apos;s memory and service to the nation. Mr. Wunsch has been researching and speaking on this topic for nine years, and has spoken at area venues including the GAR Museum&amp;Library and the Union League, and Civil War Round Tables in Gettysburg, Cape May Court House, NJ, and before the Bensalem Historical Society.

 Meeting of June 9, 2011

Craig Schoeller on&quot;Battle of the Bulge&quot;

 

Craig Schoeller gave a great talk on his life and the time he spent in the Battle of the Bulge in World War II. Craig&apos;s story went from his enlistment to being in action as an infantry replacement in the 35th Division of the Third Army. His story was about his combat, his wounding, his friends, and his capture. As we heard of his experiences, we received a better appreciation of what young men and women went through to protect our freedoms. Craig corrected us on the term used in the previous newsletter—that he was an American Hero. In fact, he said the heroes were among the ones who didn&apos;t come home to continue their lives but had given up those lives for America. Craig volunteered to come back and give us a talk on his captivity in a German prison camp. It was great to have Craig back from his recent injury. We are very lucky to have a gentleman like Craig as a member of Old Baldy.


 Meeting of May 12, 2011

 Jack Lieberman Capt. Percival Drayton 

Jack Lieberman on&quot;Life and Civil War Achievements of Capt. Percival Drayton&quot;

Jack Lieberman gave a great presentation on little-known Captain Percival Drayton, USN, and his brother Brigadier General Thomas Fenwick Drayton, CSA. This family situation became&quot;brother against brother.&quot;Percival had enlisted in the Navy in 1827 and served up to and into the Civil War. His career reflected the history of the Navy through its early years. He was stationed at the Philadelphia Navy Yard when the Civil War started. He was given command of the USS Pocahontas and took part in the Port Royal action in November 1861. During this battle he actually fired on troops of his brother who was in command at the time. He was promoted to Captain and assigned to Admiral Farragut&apos;s Squadron and took command of his flagship USS Hartford . He was in command as the fleet attacked Mobile Bay. When the war ended he lived in Philadelphia and died of a twisted bowel obstruction and buried in Philadelphia. A great presentation and a great turnout. Jack will always be welcomed back.

Jack P. Lieberman, Captain, USN (Retired), is a native of Cheltenham, PA. He received his B.S. Degree in accounting from Villanova University in 1965. Following graduation, he received a commission as an Ensign in the U.S. Navy and served during Vietnam as a Gunnery Officer aboard USS San Marcos (LSD-25). Attaining the rank of Captain, he was Commanding Officer of various units and Chief of Staff Officer during Exercise Rainbow Reef in the Indian Ocean, a convoy training exercise, preceding Operation Desert Shield/Desert Storm. Upon release from active duty, the U.S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, MD, called upon him to work with applicants and Congressional staffs, as a Blue and Gold Officer. In addition, he accepted a position as an Internal Auditor with Atlantic Richfield Oil Company (ARCO), which utilized his management, organizational and financial skills in a corporate setting. Jack is also graduate of the Naval War College, Newport, RI, and is currently Vice President of the Philadelphia Council, US Navy League.

 Meeting of April 14, 2011

 Bill Hughes Clinton Waggoner, Surgeon in charge of Beverly Hospital Statue originally in Beverly Cemetery Nurse
Georgeanna Woolsey 

Bill Hughes on&quot;US General Hospital at Beverly, NJ&quot;

William Hughes, a member of Old Baldy, spoke on the history of the U.S. General Hospital at Beverly, New Jersey, during the war. The hospital, which was located at the site of a former civil war rendezvous camp, was in operation 1864-1865. Through much research, Hughes put together an interesting description of what it took to organize and operate this type of military hospital. His book traces the hospital&apos;s roots and the people who shaped it including: the dedicated surgeons and nurses, the brave yet gravely injured and sick soldiers, the employees who took advantage, and the community that rallied around both staff and patients. It also touches on the origins of the Beverly National Cemetery, which holds over 40,000 military burials beginning during the Civil War. We heard from actual soldiers&apos; letters written home from the hospital. Both the hospital and cemetery have connections to similar sites in the Philadelphia area.

William E. Hughes is a graduate of Pfeiffer University in North Carolina, with a Masters degree in Education from West Chester University, a retired teacher of 38 years, and current local school board member. He is currently secretary of the Old Baldy Civil War Round Table in Philadelphia and has written several articles for their newsletter. He has also published The Civil War Papers of Lt. Col. Newton T. Colby of the 107th New York Regiment, his great-great-grandfather.


 Meeting of March 10, 2011

 

Dick Simpson on&quot;Wilson&apos;s Creek, August 10, 1861&quot;

Historian Dick Simpson presented a program on&quot;The Battle of Wilson&apos;s Creek&quot;, the first major battle west of the Mississippi. In early August 1861, Confederate Brigadier General Benjamin McCulloch&apos;s army was camped at Wilson&apos;s Creek, Missouri, while Union Brigadier General Nathaniel Lyon&apos;s men were camped 12 miles away in Springfield, Missouri.

On the night of August 9, both sides had developed plans of attack on the opposing camp, but rain forced the Confederates to forgo the assault. At dawn the next day, Lyon led his army into battle. The attack caught McCulloch off guard, driving his army back. For more than five hours the battle raged on&quot;Bloody Hill&quot;.
 At about 9:30 a.m., Lyon, who had been wounded twice already, was killed while positioning his troops. Command fell to Major Samuel Sturgis, who ordered a withdrawal to Springfield at about 11 a.m., his ammunition nearly exhausted.

 Meeting of February 10, 2011

 Steve Wright Hugh Boyle 

Stephen Wright and Hugh Boyle on&quot;Abraham Lincoln Program&quot;

What a great night! This year in honor of Lincoln&apos;s birthday, Hugh presenting a short program entitled:&quot;Congressman Lincoln: 1847 to 1849&quot;and Steve explored Lincoln&apos;s formative years in New Salem. What a great evening with two Lincoln scholars. We were given insight into a period of influence on young Mr. Lincoln at New Salem and the ambition of Lincoln in Illinois as the shrewd politician. We always enjoy Hugh and Steve, but the two together made for one of our outstanding programs.


 Meeting of January 13, 2011

 Roger Arthur 

Roger Arthur on&quot;The Secession Crisis&quot;

&quot;The Secession Crisis&quot;traced the events that led to the attempt to break up the Union. Why did the Southern states believe they were better off out of the Union? What justification did they have? What did the government do or attempt to do to assuage the sectional crisis? What caused the final rift? Why would they fire on the flag?


 Meeting of December 9, 2010

 Stephen Wright Mike Cavanaugh 

Stephen Wright on&quot;Battle of Fredericksburg&quot;and Michael A. Cavanaugh on a Defense of Gen. Burnside

Noted as being one of the most one-sided battles of the Civil War, the battle of Fredericksburg is also remarkable in that Union casualties were more than twice those suffered by the Confederates and the armies at Fredericksburg represented the largest number of armed men ever to confront each other for combat during the war.

Following the battle, both General Burnside and President Lincoln came under harsh criticism for the defeat at Fredericksburg. Radical Republican Senator Zachariah Chandler wrote,&quot;The President is a weak man, too weak for the occasion, and those fool or traitor generals are wasting time and yet more precious blood in indecisive battles and delays.&quot;Pennsylvania Governor Andrew Curtin visited President Lincoln after touring the ravaged battlefield. The period following the battle of Fredericksburg was one of the darkest for the sixteenth President. He said of it,&quot;If there is a worse place than hell, I am in it.&quot;

For this program, Steven Wright presented a short PowerPoint presentation on the Battle of Fredericksburg, followed by another short program by Michael A. Cavanaugh putting forward author William Marvel&apos;s defense of Major General Ambrose Burnside as commander of the Army of the Potomac from his book on Burnside. Afterward, an old fashioned Civil War Round Table discussion of the controversy ended a very interesting and educational night.

 Meeting of November 11, 2010

 John S. Mosby Sam Davis 

Sid Copel on&quot;Civil War Spies&amp;Guerillas&quot;

Dr. Sidney Copel is a clinical psychologist who is now retired. He received his undergraduate and graduate training at Temple University. He was for many years the Administrator of the Psychological Clinic at the Devereux Foundation where he ran one of the biggest programs of its kind in the country. After leaving Devereux he went into private practice until his retirement in 1995.

Over the years Dr. Copel has published books in his field, lectured on mental health topics, and served as a consultant to schools, clinics, and police departments. He was for a time also a consultant in selection of player personnel for the Philadelphia Eagles, Denver Broncos, and Los Angeles Rams. He has been interested in the Civil War and reading about it since childhood.


 

 Meeting of October 14, 2010

 John Nagy His book 

John Nagy on&quot;Invisible Ink, Spycraft of the American Revolution.&quot;

John&apos;s presentation on gathering and transmitting military information during the Revolutionary War was very intriguing. The sophistication of codes designed for use to conceal information in letters is still being used today. They used alphabet matrices, cut out masks placed over written groups of words and words themselves that have different meanings. John showed us how sophisticated intelligence information was transmitted in colonial times. John is greatly welcome to come back even though his presentations are of another time period.

Mr. John Nagy, of Mount Laurel, New Jersey, is a founder and current president of the American Revolution Round Table of Philadelphia. He received his BA from Saint Francis University, Loretto, Pennsylvania, where he is now a Scholar in Residence. John received his MMS from Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, New Jersey. John is a consultant for the William L. Clements Library at the University of Michigan on espionage and also an expert in antique documents. He was the source of information used in the very popular web page &quot;Spy Letters of the American Revolution&quot; from the collections of the Clements Library.

Released in December 2009, his book Invisible Ink: Spycraft of the American Revolution is based on two decades of primary research. John has appeared on the History Channel, C-Span, and local educational TV and is the subject of a one hour interview on the Pennsylvania Cable Network. He maintains a very busy speaking and book signing schedule at colleges, universities, historical societies, Revolutionary War reenactments, etc. His current speaking schedule is available here . John&apos;s book, Rebellion in the Ranks—Mutinies in the American Revolution , won the American Revolution Round Table of Philadelphia&apos;s&quot;Thomas Fleming Book Award&quot;for the best book on the American Revolution published in 2007. On his Revolutionary War expertise, the eminent historian David McCullough, author of John Adams and 1776, wrote&quot;John Nagy, fellow historian and Revolutionary War scholar extraordinaire!&quot;

 Meeting of September 9, 2010

 Colonel Ira Grover Jim Heenehan 

Jim Heenehan on&quot;Colonel Ira Grover, 7th Indiana Volunteer Infantry: The True Story of his Court-Martial and Acquittal&quot;

July 1, 1863, Emmitsburg, MD. – The higher the sun rose in the sky that morning, the more impatient Col. Ira Grover became with his regiment&apos;s overdue relief. Finally, at 10 a.m., he ordered his 7th Indiana to move north to rejoin the main army. On the march, Grover heard that fighting had broken out at Gettysburg and quickened the pace. Arriving that evening, his men were posted to Culp&apos;s Hill.

Historians note that Grover&apos;s decision had two results. First, it saved Culp&apos;s Hill from being captured by Edward&quot;Allegheny&quot;Johnson&apos;s division later that night. Second, it resulted in Grover being hauled before a court martial just after the battle and charged with leaving Emmitsburg, MD without orders. Or did it?

Jim discussed the court martial—including the fact that it had nothing to do with his departure from Emmitsburg. He explained how historians confused Grover&apos;s court martial with his July 1 march, the events leading up to Grover&apos;s court martial, his unusual but successful defense, and, of course, how the 7th Indiana saved Culp&apos;s Hill that first night of July.

Jim Heenehan has been a member of Old Baldy for ten years. Jim has been an attorney for the United States Environmental Protection Agency since 1978. He has written several articles for various Civil War publications, the most recent being his piece on the Philadelphia Brigade at Pickett&apos;s Charge for The Gettysburg Magazine .

 Meeting of July 8, 2010

 Jerry Carrier John Hay 

Jerry Carrier on&quot;Meet John Hay—A One-Man Historical Presentation&quot;

John Hay (1838–1905) was a unique figure in the history of the United States. No other statesman was so close—both personally and politically—to both Abraham Lincoln and Theodore Roosevelt.

As a young man, Hay was one of Lincoln&apos;s White House secretaries. He was not only a trusted aide, but their personal relationship was like that of father and son.

Late in his life, Hay was secretary of state under Roosevelt. Again, their relationship was more than professional. The two men had a lifelong friendship, which began when Roosevelt was 12. Roosevelt&apos;s father (also named Theodore) had worked closely with Hay on Army-related matters during the Civil War.

In addition to his relationship with two Presidential icons, Hay had a remarkable career of his own. He was not only a statesman and diplomat, but also a highly successful poet, journalist and historian. Perhaps no other figure in the nation&apos;s history was such a luminary in both politics and literature.

Jerry Carrier is a longtime journalist who, after his retirement from the Philadelphia Daily News in 2001, launched a second career as an actor. He has a variety of credits in both theatrical and on-camera performances. In addition, he is an avid student of Civil War history. He is vice president of the Delaware Valley Civil War Round Table and teaches several courses about the war at Manor College near Philadelphia.

In preparing this one-man show, Jerry found much in common with John Hay. Both men were born in Indiana, and both were employed by major newspapers. In fact, Jerry grew up just 35 miles from Hay&apos;s birthplace.

John Hay left a legacy of letters, diaries, articles and books, rich with witty and colorful observations about his own life and about Lincoln, Roosevelt and other figures. This wealth of material has made it possible to present Hay&apos;s life story as Hay himself would have told it. Wherever possible, the words in this presentation are Hay&apos;s own. The presentation runs approximately 40-45 minutes, leaving ample time afterward for questions from the audience.

 Meeting of June 10, 2010

Ed Root on&quot;General Butler&apos;s 1862 Tenure in New Orleans&quot;

 Ed Root The&quot;Beast&quot;of New Orleans 

Ed Root&apos;s program of General Benjamin Butler explored one of those historic characters who never fails to elicit strong opinion. He was both reviled as a criminal and scalawag and praised as a patriot in his own time. Today, he is most often one of the answers to questions about the Civil War&apos;s most inept officers. Ed&apos;s presentation was very fair and balanced (like Fox News!). Butler was not as bad as historians have made him out to be. There were the usual stories, some of which were quite humorous. Lots of new information. Ed is always welcomed back to Old Baldy.

Ed Root retired as a business analysis after 34 years from Phillips Van-Heusen Corporation. An advocate for many years of American Civil War historic preservation, a Past President of the Civil War Round Table of Eastern PA, Ed has also served on the Boards of the Civil War Library and Museum in Philadelphia and the Gettysburg Battlefield Preservation Association. He is the co-author with Jeffrey Stocker of Isn’t This Glorious – The 15th, 19th and 20th Massachusetts Volunteer Infantry Regiments at Gettysburg’s Copse of Trees. The book garnered the Bachelder-Coddington Award for Civil War in 2006. He served on the Stage II jury, which selected the winning design of the Flight 93 National Memorial in Somerset County, Pennsylvania in 2005. Ed has served on the Board of Directors of the Families of Flight 93, Inc., including a term as Board President. Additionally he has served on numerous committees within either the Families of Flight 93 organization or the larger Flight 93 Memorial partnership. Ed lives in Coopersburg, PA with Nancy, his wife of 41 years.

 Meeting of May 13, 2010

 

Herb Kaufman on&quot;A People at War: American Jewry and the Civil War&quot;

Our own Herb Kaufman presented us with another of his excellent programs. “A People at War: American Jewry in the Civil War.” He gave us examples of how the War split Jewish families as it did other families in America—Brother fighting brother. How Jewish families in the South supported the Southern cause as did the Jewish families in the North supported to keep the Union together. He spoke on Jewish soldiers (7) winning the Medal of Honor for their bravery in the Union Army. The bravery of Jewish soldiers in the Confederate Army. That there were some Regiments that were made up of almost entirely Jewish soldiers because of the communities were they were organized. He touched on Grant&apos;s famous General Order No. 11. The eventual role of Jewish chaplains (a very few) in the Army. Jewish women doing their part for the causes in becoming nurses and spies. One of the most prominent Jewish-Americans in the Civil War period was Judah R. Benjamin, Secretary of War in the Confederate government. Another, Moses J. Ezekiel, a VMI cadet, who after the war became a world renown sculptor and designed the Confederate Memorial at Arlington National Cemetery and is buried at the base of that memorial. In Herb&apos;s research he had found very few books written on Jewry in the Civil War. Herb never stops to amaze us with his programs on educating us on his Civil War knowledge.

 Meeting of April 8, 2010

 

Mike Burkhimer on&quot;The Reports of the Lincolns’ Political Partnership Have Been Greatly Exaggerated&quot;

Mike Burkhimer gave us an excellent program on the Political Partnership of the Lincolns. He spoke on Lincoln&apos;s political experiences before the marriage to Mary. That Abe had already established his political knowledge. He discussed how many modern authors have been writing on the abilities of Mary to guide Abe in his politics. He has done a tremendous amount of research and has found no evidence of Mary writing or rewriting Abe&apos;s speeches and helping him make political decisions that effected his government. Lincoln would ask people their opinions on varying subjects, but he would follow his own feelings and ultimately make the decisions. The consensus of the program was that Abe was his own man and Mary was the First Lady of the White House. Mike is an excellent and knowledgeable speaker and will be welcomed back anytime.
 
 
©2012 Old Baldy Civil War Round Table. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
