<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006778" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Tucson/Taco-Bell_851" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="1" score="0.0023863073825103756" bingtitle="Taco Bell - Fast Food Restaurant Tucson, AZ 85716" webtitle="Taco Bell - Fast Food Restaurant  Tucson, AZ 85716">
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>Taco Bell is a Fast Food restaurant located at ... The evening cashier just stares at you until ... and occasionally worst) things to eat in New York and review fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Taco Bell
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(520) 320-7554

 http://tacobell.com/ 
 AZ &gt; Tucson &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Taco Bell listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Taco Bell to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Taco Bell
 Taco Bell is a Fast Food restaurant located at 3455 E Grant Rd in Tucson, AZ 85716. Taco Bell has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Taco Bell
 
 
 
All Reviews for Taco Bell


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Taco Bell:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Tweets from Taco Bell
 @CumberMyBatchs A really talented bean burrito.
 about a minute ago.   Reply 
TacoBell @HollyGrande @Mamie24 Absolutely.
 2 minutes ago.   Reply 
TacoBell @SteveJankowski1 We heard they&apos;re on tour far, far away.
 3 minutes ago.   Reply 
TacoBell @1DMustaches Oh yeah. It exists.
 4 minutes ago.   Reply 
TacoBell @DreaAlGhul Your mission today is to go to Taco Bell and try #DoritosLocosTacos .
 4 minutes ago.   Reply 
TacoBell 
Taco Bell Tips
 the new bacon ranch flatbread chicken sangwich is perdy dang tasty!
 
Ted G. Gotta love my Taco Bell in the late hours.
 
Mandi L. Best food ever!
 
Ryan G. This is the most awful taco bell in town, the drive thru is always 20 min late at night, they never have their shit together.
 
Michael L. Customer service is not awesome. The evening cashier just stares at you until you say something, then she mumbles.
 
Courtney J. 
Taco Bell News
 Downtown Italian spot moves uptown the restaurant reopens as Gloria’s Italian Restaurant, near Lumina Station. The new 7037 Wrightsville Ave. location, in a long-shuttered Taco Bell next door to Harris Teeter, will offer New York Pasta House favorites like shimp fra diavolo and veal ... Taco Bell: We&apos;re more than &apos;food as fuel&apos; Brands&apos; Taco Bell chain, which must compete with fast-growing Mexican casual dining restaurants such as Qdoba ... declined last week to talk about the new product or the company&apos;s 2012 plans. But in New York earlier this month, Taco Bell CEO ... Altering the experience: Taco Bell wants to be more than &apos;food as fuel&apos; Brands’ Taco Bell chain, which must compete with fast-growing Mexican casual dining restaurants like Qdoba ... declined last week to talk about the new product or the company’s 2012 plans. But in New York earlier this month, Taco Bell ... Yum! Brands Bulls in Charge New York, December 27th ... YUM), owns and franchises quick-service restaurants worldwide. The Company develops, operates, franchises and licenses a worldwide system of restaurants, like Pizza Hut, KFC, and Taco Bell. Yum! Brands is currently trading ... See Ya, 2011: A Look Back at Our Top Posts of the Year Of course, we did more than name the tastiest (and occasionally worst) things to eat in New York and review fast-food items ... it&apos;s going to be a whole lot harder to remember. 10. Remember Taco Bell&apos;s Beefy Crunchy Burrito? It came out last January ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Taco Bell - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Taco Bell is an American chain of fast-food restaurants based in Irvine, California. A subsidiary of Yum! Brands, Inc., which serves American-adapted Mexican food. Taco Bell® | Think Outside The Bun The official site of Taco Bell featuring our fast food nutrition guide, Taco Bell locations, franchise information, and career opportunities. Taco Bell® | Restaurant Careers Want to start a career at Taco Bell? We need talented people to make sure all the Taco Bell tacos we serve are delicious! Learn more about our opportunities. Taco Taco - Yorkville - New York, NY Category: Restaurants Mexican Mexican. 1726 2nd Ave (between 89th St&amp;90th St) New York, NY 10128 Neighborhoods: Yorkville, Upper East Side (212) 289-8226 Terry Kimball Arrested: Taco Bell Customer Calls 911 When ... Terry Kimball Arrested: Taco Bell Customer Calls 911 When Restaurant Refused Service 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 99° 
Fri
 
 81° - 108° 
Sat
 
 81° - 109° 
Sun
 
 79° - 102° 
 
Address
 
Taco Bell

3455 E Grant Rd

Tucson, AZ 
 
85716
 
Telephone
 (520) 320-7554 
Taco Bell
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Taco Bell Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Melting Pot Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Granite Kitchen&amp;Bath Incorporated 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Blackjack Pizza 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Church&apos;s Chicken 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wendy&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wendy&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Covington Fine Arts Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Mos Gallery Fine Framing 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Alexandra Jump Animal Portrait 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Arizona Repertory Singers 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Artseye 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Tucson Art Museums Galleries 
See all Tucson ATMs 
See all Tucson Restaurants 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Taco Bell Coupons 

 Taco Bell Tucson 

 Taco Bell Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Tucson Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
