<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006089" url="http://thesaurus.com/browse/lunch+counter" time="2012-07-12-22:46" support="2" score="0.015386655989794048" bingtitle="Lunch counter Synonyms, Lunch counter Antonyms | Thesaurus.com" webtitle="Lunch counter Synonyms, Lunch counter Antonyms | Thesaurus.com">
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>short-order restaurant: Synonyms: cafeteria, canteen, deli, delicatessen, diner, dog wagon, drive-in restaurant, fast-food restaurant, hamburger ... lunch counter, lunch ...</description>
	<body>
		Added to Favorites Sign Up Log In Introducing a cool
new way to learn! Dictionary Thesaurus Word Dynamo Quotes Reference Translator Spanish Related Searches Lunch counter sit... Woolworth&apos;s lunch... First president Diner lingo Freedom riders Chicago 7 Montgomery bus bo... Ku klux klan Restaurant lingo Civil rights move... Affirmative actio... Black panthers Nearby Words lump it lump sum lump together lumped it lumped together lumping it lumping togethe... lumpish lumps it lumps together lumpy luna lunacy lunar module lunatic lunatic asylum lunatic fringe lunatic-fringe lunch lunch bucket wo... lunch counter lunch meat lunch wagon lunch-bucket wo... lunch-counter lunch-meat lunchbucket wor... luncheon luncheon meat luncheonette lunches lunchmeat lunchroom lunchtime lune lunette lunette window lung lunge lunge at lunged at lunch counter ProPoints® Plan 2.0 www.weightwatchers.de/ProPoints Jetzt für nur 5 € pro Woche fit in den Sommer: Starten Sie noch heute! Thesaurus.com Free Toolbar Dictionary.com Look Up Lunch counter Instantly. Faster Page Loads With Fewer Ads. Ads 
 Main Entry: lunch counter Part of Speech: noun Definition: short-order restaurant Synonyms: cafeteria, canteen, deli, delicatessen, diner, dog wagon, drive-in restaurant, fast-food restaurant, hamburger stand, hot-dog stand, ice-cream parlor, quick-lunch counter, sandwich shop, snack bar 
 
 Main Entry: diner Part of Speech: noun Definition: casual restaurant with varied menu Synonyms: Automat, bistro, booth, café, canteen, chuck wagon, coffee shop, concession , dump *, eatery, eating house, facility , fast-food outlet, greasy spoon, grill, hash house, ice-cream parlor, lunch counter , lunch wagon, lunchroom, mess hall, quick-lunch, saloon, sandwich shop, snack bar, tearoom 
 * = informal/non-formal usage
 
 Main Entry: snack bar Part of Speech: noun Definition: place for buying snacks Synonyms: buvette, cantina, concession, concession stand, drive-in, fast-food restaurant, hamburger stand, hot-dog stand, lunch counter , sandwich bar, sandwich shop 
 Roget&apos;s 21st Century Thesaurus, Third Edition
Copyright©2012 by the Philip Lief Group.
 Cite This Source Search another word or see lunch counter on Dictionary | Spanish Is LUNCH COUNTER messing up your project? Writing Dynamo instantly improves word choice, redundancy and grammar. START NOW Upgrade to Ad-free Premium Membership! Style guide 
 Confusing words 
 Word of the Day Free tools 
 Blog 
 Games Partners: Word Bloglines Citysearch The Daily Beast Ask Answers Ask Kids Life123 Reference Sendori Dictionary.com, LLC. Copyright©  2012 . All rights reserved. About Privacy Policy Terms of Use API Careers Advertise with Us Contact Us Help 
 Please Login or Sign Up to use the Favorites feature 
 
 Please Login or Sign Up to use the Recent Searches feature 
 FAVORITES RECENT
	</body>
</document>
