<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006241" url="http://www.hwcmalaysia.com/2009/04/model-cars-take-centrestage.html" time="2012-07-12-22:55" support="5" score="0.0032151185229330574" bingtitle="Hot Wheels Collectors Malaysia: Model cars take centrestage" webtitle="Hot Wheels Collectors Malaysia: Model cars take centrestage">
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>DON’T be surprised if someone asks for your receipt ... after the Shell Ferrari limited edition model cars ... recent interview at their weekly meeting at a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
Link
 
 Main Page Forum Facebook 
 
 Upcoming Event: 

Weekly - Friday 10:00PM SS15 McD drive through. Location Map 
 
4.03.2009
 
 Model cars take centrestage 
 Posted by Toycarsmy at 9:30 AM . Labels: HWCM 
 
DON’T be surprised if someone asks for your receipt at the petrol station the next time you pump petrol.
 
Chances are the person is after the Shell Ferrari limited edition model cars and that is what Hot Wheels Cars Malaysia (HWCM) Club co-founder Desmond Raja Lakshmana, 22, paid his brother to do—wait at petrol stations to pounce on customers for receipts.

This sometimes spurs other customers, who may initially have no interest in collecting model cars, to keep the receipts and buy the cars themselves after seeing the hype.

This frenzy is due to Shell’s annual Shell Ferrari limited edition model cars, in conjunction with the upcoming Ferrari F1 fever for the third time.

Proud owners: Model car owners admiring their collection at their weekly meeting at the SS15 McDonald’s.

Customers are able to buy the cars for RM6.90 when they purchase a minimum of RM40 worth of Shell V-Power Racing or at RM8.90 for other regular petrol.

At a recent interview at their weekly meeting at a fast-food restaurant in SS15, HWCM members revealed their enthusiasm for model cars and the length they went to obtain the limited edition Ferrari model cars.

Telco engineer Shakz Faizal, 29, was the proud owner of three sets (one set has seven pieces, hence 21 pieces in total) of the Shell Ferrari collection the day it was launched.

“There’s a sense of satisfaction. I had the help of my friend who owns a bus company to fill three buses worth of petrol,”he said, adding that his aim is to collect five sets.

The members meet there every Friday at 10pm to exchange the latest news about model cars and trade collections.

While the club was only founded by Desmond and Yeo Chin Pang, 31, on Jan 11 this year, Hot Wheels fans have long existed and formed small groups to share their passion.

“Previously, the members were scattered, with websites linking them to each other. The HWCM brings everyone together and strengthens the hot wheels community in Malaysia.

“For some, the Shell Ferrari collection is a stepping stone (that introduces them to the world of model cars),”said Desmond, an apprentice with Mercedes Benz.

The club now has over 160 members, who come from diverse backgrounds, occupation,

race, age (10 to 56-years-old) and even has an international network of members,

from as far away as America.

The youngest member Joshua Lim, 10, nicknamed“The Encyclopedia”has an impressive collection of over 900 car models.

“I can remember the models once I see it on the poster. I can also remember the range of colours that a design has,”said Lim who gets his information from books and magazines. According to Jo Huang, the senior accounts manager of Ogilvy Public Relations Worldwide, which handles the Shell account, Malaysia is the first country in the world to see the 2009 Shell Ferrari car models.

This is because of the massive sales in Malaysia and the HWCM members are one of Shell Ferrari model cars most avid group of supporters.

“Members not only collect a single set of the Shell Ferrari cars but multiple sets for future value and trading,”she said.

The members also voiced out their suggestions for functions they’d like to see in future Shell Ferrari collections such as die cast (metal), lights and doors that can be opened.

To know more about the club, log on to www.hwcmalaysia.com, which is updated three to five times a week.

Taken from StarMetro Friday 3 April 2009, Thanks to Jo Huang, ING YEEN and HWCM Members .
 
 
 Reactions: 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home 

 
 
About HWCMalaysia
 HWCM, HWCMalaysia created by a group of people who do more than just collecting Hot Wheels.

It exist to enable collectors to discuss, share knowledge, experience and trade with other Hot Wheels enthusiasts in Malaysia over a common platform.

So, join us now!!!
 
Contact Us
 demonicle(at)hwcmalaysia(dot)com
cpyeo(at)hwcmalaysia(dot)com
 
Subscribe To HWCM
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
Site Translation
 
 中文 Bahasa 
 
Shortcuts
 
 Message Boards 2009 Lineup 2008 Catalog 2007 Catalog HWC Vietnam (New) 
 
Categories
 
 2008 First Edition (2) 2008 Hot Wheels (5) 2009 Ferrari Racer (4) 2009 First Edition (2) 2009 Hot Wheels (6) 2009 Mystery Cars (1) 2009 New Models (1) 2009 Segment Series (2) 2009 Track Stars (1) 2009 Treasure Hunts (1) 2010 First Editions (2) 7eleven promo (1) Color Shifters (3) Contest (4) Custom Hot Wheels (8) Diorama (2) Error Hot Wheels (1) Event (7) Field Report (4) Gathering (1) GiveAway (1) H0 (1) Hot Wheels 1:50 (1) Hot Wheels ConnectCars (1) HWCM (9) Photo Gallery (32) Shell-Ferrari (1) 
   
Collectors&apos; Blog
 
 Where Car Lovers Congregate POS of the Day 12 hours ago Little hobby center 1:64 Pagani Huayra 3 days ago art of toys MY new H 5 months ago scale me down!~ custom works : A story of a scooter and a chopper!~ 7 months ago Gee&apos;s Garage Collection: Hot Wheels&apos;09 Corvette ZR1&amp;Ford Mustang Fastback 1 year ago Car Die-Cast Collector Ipoh Custom Hotwheels Time Attack Cusco Honda Civic Si 1 year ago hotwheels every where.. a custom project by danielh 2 years ago DA&apos;s Collection My Satria Neo 3 years ago Toy Cars Collector Malaysia Increased price to RM6.90 3 years ago 1.0 Hand Powered Cars 41 Willys Hot Rod 3 years ago 
 Show 5 Show All 
Blog Archive
 
 ► 2010 (2) 
 ► March (1) 
 Hot Wheels Race World Challenge 
 

 ► January (1) 
 Custom Hot Wheels DeLorean 
 
 

 ▼ 2009 (68) 
 ► December (4) 
 HWCM 4th Race Day - 18th December A Very Cool Back Slider 2010 New Hot Wheels promotion at Tesco Custom HW&apos;65 Volkswagen Fastback 
 

 ► November (1) 
 HWCM 3rd Race Day - Results! 
 

 ► September (1) 
 HWCM 3rd Race Day 
 

 ► August (2) 
 New variants to be released HWCM 2nd Race-Day 
 

 ► July (4) 
 Latest TRU Promo 7Eleven Promotion Jusco Contest Custom Hot Wheels Greased Lightning 
 

 ► June (1) 
 Custom Hot Wheels Sir Ominous 
 

 ► May (2) 
 More Pics from the Swap Meet! Swap-Meet session at Central Park One Utama (30th ... 
 

 ▼ April (11) 
 Photo Gallery : Custom Evolution X Photo Gallery : 24/Seven Photo Gallery: More Civics Shell Ferrari&amp;Hot Wheels Ferrari Winner for Exclusive H0 Car Giveaway Contest: Hot Wheels Giant Colouring Contest Photo Gallery: Sinclair&apos;s Civic Collection Photo Gallery: Custom Evolution X Exclusive H0 Car Giveaway Model cars take centrestage Photo Gallery: Prabha&apos;s Garage 
 

 ► March (9) 
 Wave Identification 101 by Demonicle Cawan Super Haul Photo Gallery: Civic Maniac! Hot Wheels Error Collection Custom Dodge Van by Eight Custom made Ferrari Garage by Rikmun Photo Gallery: VW Fast Back Photo Gallery: Shelby GT500 by Kurz Photo Gallery: Mini Collection from .::Ones&apos;s Gara... 
 

 ► February (11) 
 Color Shifters -&apos;77 Dodge Van Photo Gallery: Aquarium&quot;Showcase&quot; New Stocks Arrived Work In Progress Photo Gallery: 72 duster by hwcustomizer Photo Gallery: 2003 FE HKS Altezza Photo Gallery: Mitsubishi Eclipse Concept by Sincl... Photo Gallery: HWCM TunerZ Club by Rikmun HWCM Gathering 23rd January 2009 Larger Hot Wheels 2009 Poster Photo Gallery: Nasty accident happened today on th... 
 

 ► January (22) 
 Happy Chinese NewYear 2009 Photo Gallery: Ferrari Club by Sinclair 
 
 
 
Followers
 
 Hot Wheels Collectors Malaysia ©| Hot Wheels Collectors Community Malaysia | Copyright 2009

Disclaimer: The information provided on this site is a courtesy of HWCMalaysia.com. While we try to keep the information on our site as accurate as possible, we disclaim any implied representation about its accuracy, completeness, or appropriateness for a particular purpose. 

You assume full responsibility for using the information on this site, and you understand and agree that HWCMalaysia.com is neither responsible nor liable for any claim, loss, or damage resulting from its use. 

All pictures are copyrights to HWCMalaysia community, Logo and Trademark of Hot Wheels is owned by Mattel Inc.
	</body>
</document>
