<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006308" url="http://dailysavings.allyou.com/2011/01/04/2011-chick-fil-a-calendar-contest/" time="2012-07-12-22:59" support="14" score="0.014545524459439204" bingtitle="2011 Chick-fil-A Calendar Contest | Daily Savings From All You ..." webtitle="2011 Chick-fil-A Calendar Contest  | Daily Savings From All You Magazine">
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>I keep all the items I receive and if I need a gift ... When dining out at a fast food restaurant we try to “supersize ... score gift cards for restaurants from credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Coupons Contests and Giveaways 
 Grocery Challenge 
 Discount Codes Budget recipes Money-Saving Tips What’s on sale Free stuff 
 «Previous Entries Next Entries » 
 2011 Chick-fil-A Calendar Contest 
 Jan 04 2011 
 UPDATE: The contest entry period has ended. Thanks for all the great tips and good luck to all the entrants. Winners will be notified by e-mail. 

Do you have a great tip for eating out on a budget?

Share your best advice on eating out and saving for a chance to win one of ten 2011 Chick-fil-A calendars—each is full of more than $20 in Chick-fil-A food and beverage coupons.

 

Here is how you can enter:

First, “like” All You magazine on Facebook .

Second,  leave your most creative tip for saving money when dining out in the comments below.

Our editors will be judging your tip on creativity, newness of tip, appropriateness and savings value. The contest begins today, January 4  at 12:01 PM EST and all entries are due by tomorrow. January 5 at 11:59 AM EST.

The winners will be notified by email by Friday, January 7, 2011. For official contest rules, click here .
 January 4, 2011 by dailysavingsfromallyou Comments (226) | Print PREVIOUS Burt’s Bees Gift Set from Target: Deal of the Day NEXT Easy Frittata: Budget Recipe of the Day 
COMMENTS (226) 
 Add comment 
 Susan Vaughn | January 4, 2011 at 12:08 pm | 
Use duct tape to remove any unwanted fuzz on your clothes.
 Kara | January 4, 2011 at 12:09 pm | 
My biggest tip…and one I learned from my own parents…is to drink water. The prices that restaurants charge for beverages is absolutely crazy. If you drink water, you will save $1.50 to $3.00 per person. That really adds up! If you don’t like plain water, ask for lemon. It will give the water a nice flavor.
 Carissa | January 4, 2011 at 12:09 pm | 
I look for coupons on Facebook and restaurant Web sites and also check out their specials or value menus.
 Jennifer Barrow | January 4, 2011 at 12:10 pm | 
Always drink water you save so much money! Also, we hit the kids eat free nights and we use our Coupon Saver books for coupons to our favorite resturants
 Jane Sandona | January 4, 2011 at 12:10 pm | 
spray Pam on stuck on price stickers for easy removal
 Sonya Rottero | January 4, 2011 at 12:10 pm | 
I order myself a kid meal.
 Marcia | January 4, 2011 at 12:10 pm | 
Look for local restaurants who offer free kids meals to determine where to go for dinner!
 angie | January 4, 2011 at 12:11 pm | 
My Best Advice to save when eating out is to choose places that offer coupons. coupons are the best way to Save and to have a Good meal like with the Chick fil A Calender and coupons.
 Dianne | January 4, 2011 at 12:11 pm | 
Get your calendar and you can save“mooney”
 Michelle | January 4, 2011 at 12:12 pm | 
coupons, drink water, look for places that have certain days kids can eat for free
 Karen Rivera | January 4, 2011 at 12:12 pm | 
I like to check the websites of my favorite restaurants. Some of them have e-mail clubs that send you coupons. Some of them will give a free meal or entree coupon just for signing up. I wait until a couple of days before we want to go out to eat, then I sign up. Also, if we take the kids, we try to go to a restaurant where the kids eat for free.
 Kathy | January 4, 2011 at 12:12 pm | 
We do several things. (1) We drink water. (2) we use coupons. Whether it’s a coupon run in the Sunday paper (IHOP runs Buy One Get One free entree coupons, so we can eat for the price of 1 dinner), or a coupon I get in email for belonging to a restaurants email club, if it’ll save us money, we use it.
 Olivia | January 4, 2011 at 12:13 pm | 
Always use coupons!! When ordering something big..share it with who ever is with you!! Sometimes one meal is big enough for two!!
 Autumn Peeper | January 4, 2011 at 12:13 pm | 
We do several things–always drink water, no appetizers or desserts unless there’s a coupon, split meals where appropriate and go to places on“kid’s night”when kids eat free or for discounted prices. I almost always split a meal with someone so 2 for the price of 1 is always a good deal! Just ask for an extra plate! 

PS–The Chick-Fil-A calendar is so fun! Cute pictures and great coupons!!
 Gloria Kerrigan | January 4, 2011 at 12:13 pm | 
The way I save money eating out is to join all the restaurant loyalty clubs and birthday clubs. Typically you get a free meal on your birthday, and with the loyalty clubs you periodically get great coupons. For example, with Ruby Tuesdays loyalty club called So Connected, you get a buy one get one free entree! Also, having 2 children I try and visit restaurants one kids night when one or both get a free meal with the purchase of an adult meal.
 Erica Ditommaso | January 4, 2011 at 12:14 pm | 
We had twin girls in July 2007 and with our 2 yr old we’ve difinitely had to make changes with 5 mouths to feed! We have started couponing and have saved a lot of money! But, my piece of advice would be to order water instead of soda or bring water bottles and use restaurant.com and only eat out at when you have a coupon and on days where kids eat free!
 Elisha Nestor | January 4, 2011 at 12:14 pm | 
I Google everything before I buy it on line. It will give you a list of all the different websites that carry that product, and all the prices. Combining that with coupon codes from RetailMeNot, I save hundreds on gifts for Christmas, Birthdays, etc-and get people what they want for so much less!
 Regina Ammons | January 4, 2011 at 12:15 pm | 
In order to eat out on a budget I do the following. ALWAYS have a coupon, bring a drink from home or order water. I tend to go out to eat with my Mom on the weekends. I get good deals at Groupon.com and between that and any coupons I can find for a certain place we normally can eat for less than $5.00 that’s 2.50 a piece! 
 Krystal | January 4, 2011 at 12:15 pm | 
Always use coupons and go on family night where kids eat free 
 Julie | January 4, 2011 at 12:15 pm | 
Purchase gift certificates from Resaurant.com at 60-80% off. You can get $25 worth for $2-$4. Often times you can find codes for additional savings on these certificates on the blog time2saveworkshops.com
Also drinking water and not ordering desserts or appetizers helps to keep the cost down.
 Connie James | January 4, 2011 at 12:15 pm | 
Grab a friend. Find a coupon for a BOGO meal. Split the ticket. Each of you eat for 1/2 price and have a nice time catching up. I love my friends!
 Rhonda B | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
I look all over the internet for restaurant coupons and look for in-store restaurant specials. Always use dollar menu for lunch.
 kristeen martin | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
Help remove pet hair and static from your carpet during winter months by adding 2tsp. of liquid fabric softener to a spray bottle with water, spritz on your carpet wait for it to dry and vacuum. You will be surprised at how much hair comes up. And it freshens the carpet.
 Traci Funk | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
My tip is to always check on-line for coupons before leaving your house to go out and eat. You will be surprised to find percentage off coupons or free appetizer coupons–also drink water—its free!
 Vicki Hendricks | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
Portions are soooo large that my husband and I often share a meal! Plus, we use coupons and seek out“specials”. Sometimes eating out can be cheaper than cooking at home!
 dana | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
I have a couple of ideas…one use your points from debit cards or places that give points to earn free gift cards…share with your spouse…most restaurants give WAY to much food…so split it…costing less and less calories(which most of us do not need anyway)
 Candy M | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
Drinking water has already been mentioned, but that’a a huge money saver. We also have our 7 year old share off one of our plates. We always ask the wait staff if it is okay. Sometimes we may pay a small sharing charge ($2-3), but even that is less than most children’s meals. She eats better food (most everything on a kids menu is fried or battered), I eat less (which helps control my weight) and she gets exposed to new tastes, versus the inevitable fried chicken strips and French fries that the menu offers.
 Assia Mihova | January 4, 2011 at 12:16 pm | 
Surround yourself with the right colors for creativity. Black, which represents the unknown, is a stimulant to the release of feelings and thoughts. Violet is the color of creativity, and purple the color of passion. Red is creation itself, passion, energy, and stamina. Orange encourages playfulness and vitality, and yellow stimulates the mind. Choosing a little of several of these colors in each of your rooms will greatly enhance your creative energy in anything and everything in your life.
 Jen B | January 4, 2011 at 12:17 pm | 
I have my girls share a meal whenever possible.
They are too old to order from the kids’menu, but an adult meal is much too large for them. They have their soup or salad (as one usually comes free with the meal, it’s just a matter of purchasing a second one, much less expensive than ordering an actual meal for the second child) and then they share an adult entree and even then, they just barely manage to finish it.

I also encourage drinking water as opposed to soda, but do allow it on occasion as a special treat.
 Brittni Roberts | January 4, 2011 at 12:17 pm | 
I use Google Translate to translate Spanish language websites that have coupons! Like http://www.quericavida.com/ I joined the website and received a box of coupons and full size products!
 Brandi | January 4, 2011 at 12:17 pm | 
My advice is to order off the appetizer menu, not the entree. Appetizer usually cost less and have just as much food as the entrees.
 Nancy A. | January 4, 2011 at 12:17 pm | 
My husband and I have two boys (3 1/2 and 15 mos.) and we bring their sippy cups with us and a back up juice box that we can add some of our water to. We only ever order water when eating out that can save almost $5 dollars on a bill and when ordering food we never order appetizer or dessert just a larger portion of food and an extra plate for each of the kids. Also, if you have a local resturant that has free chips or bread that would serve as an appetizer. BTW we love Chick-fil-A!!! Thanks for letting us share our tips!
 Kaye | January 4, 2011 at 12:18 pm | 
Use coupons and compare sale prices some stores will honor other stores ads. always make a list before going to grocery store and be flexibel if an item is on sale and use it frequently go ahead and buy it.
 Darcy Rice | January 4, 2011 at 12:18 pm | 
We use coupons, take advantage of kids eat free nights, drink water and we save lots of money this way.
 Kristen | January 4, 2011 at 12:18 pm | 
They are many ways we save money at restaurants with our family of seven. We use coupons and look for groupons at restaurants we like. It is important to know the kids eat free restaurants. When at a restaurant we share meals and drink water. Just drinks can add up to over 10.00 for our family.
 b wagner | January 4, 2011 at 12:18 pm | 
USE COUPONS!
 Tammy | January 4, 2011 at 12:18 pm | 
Use mobile phone and sign up for text alrerts if they have them, Use coupons or order family sizes so everyone can eat and be full and lots of left overs!
 Rachel | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
I do lots of the above things but I also buy discounted certificates either through restaurant.com or things like groupon/livingsocial/etc. For the restaurant.com I usually get $25 ones for $2 or less ($10 regular price, 80% off codes come out every month and 90% codes 1-2 times per year) then you have to spend $35 and add tax and tip but for our family of 4 when we still look at menu prices before ordering, we are usually getting enough food to be stuffed and take home a whole other meals worth for about $20.

With groupon/livingsocial/etc, we get $25 certificates for $10 or similar. Then still go during lunch to get cheaper prices and order water w/ lemon to stretch our“$25″(really $10) further.
 Julee | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
For a perfectly frosted cake:

Lightly frost cake and place in freezer until frosting is firm, then add a second layer of frosting over the firm layer. This eliminates the problem of crumbs and makes for a perfect finish.

Here’s some other tips on frosting the perfect cake:
For one layer cakes, turn the cake upside down before icing so that the top is perfectly flat and even.

For icing two cake rounds or squares: place a layer of frosting on the top of one round, then place the other round upside down on top for a perfectly flat top. If the cake rose high and uneven in the middle when baking, you may need to slice a bit off across the top to lay it flat.
 Carrie | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
My mom says I have champage tastes and a beer budget- as such whenever I search for designer clothes on ebay I try different spellings of the designer names. Thanks to this trick I scored a pair or“tori”burch shoes for 40.00- they usually sell for over 100 even on ebay!
 Connie Mize | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
Always listen to your elders, they have alot of experience and advice for the younger ones.
 Lisa Gary | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
Like so many have said–drink water, not sodas–saves a bundle. But also be sure to talk to your waiter/ess. Ask about any special, mention what items you were thinking about, but didn’t know if you would like, many times they will be bring you a sample or appetizer size of that item. USe coupons–but don’t forget to tip on the full amount. Many waitstaff work for for about $2.00/hour and count on tips to make even min. wage.
 Robyn | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
When a new product comes out that you would like to buy–don’t purchase right away..watch the item for 3 weeks and learn what a good price is for it or look for it on sale…and pairing with a coupon takes your money even further!
 Connie | January 4, 2011 at 12:19 pm | 
When you can combine multiple deals and be smart about what you eat, you will always save money. I like to get a coupon, find a place that offers half off at happy hour (then go on a tuesday so my kids aren’t surrounded by too many drunks! HA!), drink water and if possible order a lunch portion (I don’t need all those calories anyway!). One note–I will always leave a bit extra for tip. The wait staff still has to work just as hard to bring you your free cup of water and your discount meal. It is good karma and I figure I am saving money anyway! 
 Sarah | January 4, 2011 at 12:20 pm | 
I would say order water. Also, portions are a lot bigger so order two meals, depending on family size, and split them. Also, many magazines or newspapers run coupons that can be used at local resturants. I would also say look for special days like“kids eat free on Tuesdays”.
 Alexis H | January 4, 2011 at 12:20 pm | 
I always use coupons! I also buy gift cards for half price from a site similar to Resturaunt.com
 Amanda | January 4, 2011 at 12:20 pm | 
aside from coupons, the $1 menu, and kids eat free, we purchase kids meals which these days are as much as a combo, order and share, or just order a sandwich and share the fries…the portion sizes on fries these days are a bit much at most places. Also been known to take in my kids cups pre filled from home. We have 4 kids (6, 3, 1, and 6 wks.) so frugality when eating out is of great importance. Thanks for the opportunity for the calendar.
 Jennifer Coble | January 4, 2011 at 12:21 pm | 
I watch out for coupon and freebie sites online and sign up. These freebie samples make great gift baskets! I keep all the items I receive and if I need a gift I put coupons and items I have collected in a pretty basket with a bow and I have a nice housewarming present or gift for a new mom.
 alice sims | January 4, 2011 at 12:22 pm | 
I like to use coupons that offer one free meal with the purchase of a meal and two drinks or meals under $10 if you dine before 4:00 p.m. Some of our favorite restaurants have two can dine for $20 with appetizer and dessert shared.
 Karen Perea | January 4, 2011 at 12:22 pm | 
We do a lot of what the other people have said…..we drink water, we eat appetizers as meals, we share, we look for when kids eat free, look in Entertainment book, coupon, restaurants.com. Another tip that I have not seen is when they offer deals on gift cards (for example around Christmas time) where when you buy so many you get another one free or reduced value. I give gift cards as gifts to out of town family and those free giftcards give us free food later in the year. I also check the price of giftcards at places like Sam’s Club since sometimes I can get $30 worth of giftcards for $25 or less and then I combine that with a coupon, kids eat free, ordering water etc to make it all go further.
 Joan Summers | January 4, 2011 at 12:22 pm | 
Taking Shop Smart, Save Money! seminar CouponCarol.net–Carol Runyans- couponcarol@bellsouth.net with a donation of canned goods was one of my best investments yet to finding savings and great resources like“All You!”. Thanks Carol!!!
 Julie | January 4, 2011 at 12:23 pm | 
My whole family is signed up for birthday clubs (and anniversary too). We get tons of free food! The coupons are usually good for 2-4 weeks. Our three birthdays are spread out, so we get three months of free deals!
 Sherri Hays | January 4, 2011 at 12:23 pm | 
Fill a spray bottle half full of rubbing alcohol, then a quarter of the way with hydrogen peroxide and finish it with tap water. Shake and then you have a cleaner for most anything…also great for plastic containers to get rid of the smell of foods like chili, taco sauce or spaghetti, pet potty accidents on the carpet (lifts the smell out as well), an all around natural cleaning product!
 Annmarie W. | January 4, 2011 at 12:23 pm | 
Skip the appetizers and dessert! And we often use gift certificates bought on restaurant.com. Or 1/2 price coupons from the Entertainment book!
 Kelly | January 4, 2011 at 12:23 pm | 
Go out for lunch instead of dinner! Lunch specials are usually cheaper and leftovers can be for dinner. I also order kids meals at fast food places and the smaller portion helps to resist overeating. A BYOB local joint with a coupon is usually a great option, as well.
 Jennifer White | January 4, 2011 at 12:24 pm | 
We always check online before going out–and tips I’ve gotten from ALL YOU has already saved us a ton of money!
 Shay Farnsworth | January 4, 2011 at 12:24 pm | 
I research before I go out. Check the prices of the place, see what specials they have, coupons, and kids meals.
 Bonnie | January 4, 2011 at 12:25 pm | 
We always make good use out of the“Entertainment Book”coupons–plus the purchase supports local fundraisers (school, church, etc)…or I wait and buy one half way through the year for a great discount. Most of the coupons are BOGO.

The other thing that helps us save is to pack up some of the dinner. This is especially nice at places like Ruby Tuesday where we usually get the Minis plus Salad Bar…fill up on the salad bar and have the minis and side dish for another meal. It’s like getting 2 meals for one! They’ll even bring it out already boxed if you ask! At other places, just pack up half of your dinner right away. It’ll keep you from overeating too!
 Sherri Hays | January 4, 2011 at 12:25 pm | 
Should have read the comment for the contest, sorry about the previous post…my tip for savings on eating out is sign up for e-clubs in restaurants. They are always sending coupons for savings for 2 for meals, $$ off, free appetizers, etc. And don’t forget the birthday clubs!!! Free meals usually on your birthday and free stuff on your anniversary too!
 Tammy Huffaker | January 4, 2011 at 12:25 pm | 
We only eat out at restaurants with coupons! Simple, I know, but it works for us!
 Carrie | January 4, 2011 at 12:25 pm | 
We do one or a combo of several things:

First, I always clip coupons from restaurants we frequent regularly and keep them in a zipper pouch in my purse. This way, I have my coupons handy if we decide to eat out while we are already out. I do have to purge the coupons frequently, but those are the only coupons I keep in there so it doesn’t take very long.

Next, we don’t order soft drinks–the cost is crazy and not worth it for us. We will get a soft drink if a coupon requires it or we are eating at a fast food place and order a value meal, but we never“upsize”. We also stay away from appetizers and desserts, unless we have a coupon!

Third, with the huge portions restaurants serve today, we will usually split a meal and order an extra side. If an entree is normally $12, we’ll pay an extra $3 for a side and we’ve spent $15 total vs. $24 = $9 savings!! Some people will say that they would go ahead and order 2 entrees and just take half home for another meal tomorrow, but I have found that most restaurant leftovers don’t re-heat that well. I would rather save the money.

Fourth, if possible, we will try to order from the kid’s menu. It’s difficult because we don’t have any children so this usually only works with fast food places when ordering to-go.
 Rachel Sm | January 4, 2011 at 12:28 pm | 
we use all the tips already mentioned however, we also use restaurants.com. they have saved us a ton of money also. you can buy certificates for $5 and save $25 on meals.
 Marty | January 4, 2011 at 12:28 pm | 
I try and use coupons whenever possible. Always cut them out of the local paper on Sunday, you never know when you might want to try a new place,and having a coupon makes it even better.
 alice | January 4, 2011 at 12:29 pm | 
My daughter is a college student. Our Chick-fil-A has college day. Buy one get one free. She and a friend will split the cost. They both save money and eat a good meal at Chick-fil-A.
 Tammie Bobo | January 4, 2011 at 12:29 pm | 
I sign up 4 coupons on the web, in the store, and on my phone, if available. I also do surveys 4 extra savings. I also sign my son up 4 kids clubs of available. Check the restaurant 4 family nites or kids eat free d
 Deanna | January 4, 2011 at 12:31 pm | 
Facebook and Twitter have become huge sources for discounts. Friend or join the group of the restaurants you like and you will see exclusive discounts. Sometimes the chefs themselves comment which is pretty cool!
 Tammie Bobo | January 4, 2011 at 12:34 pm | 
I sign up 4 coupons on the web, in the store, and on my phone, if available. I also do surveys 4 extra savings. I also sign my son up 4 kids clubs of available. Check the restaurant 4 family nites or kids eat free deals. Also watch 4 special deals during certain hours and/or certain days. Sign up 4 free food on ur birthday. Use restaurant.com 2 get cheaper gift certificates. SpliTting a meal especially when u have a coupon or gift card is smart 2. I always leave my restaurant savings in my car so they r always near. Some restaurants have daily specials as well
 Carol Hall | January 4, 2011 at 12:34 pm | 
Eating out is not a spur of the moment thing anymore. It is planned and thought out by my searching for the best deals. If you go to a restaurant website and signup, they will send you coupons for special deals! And always drink water!
 Ami Williamson | January 4, 2011 at 12:35 pm | 
With a large family(9), it is important to save money when we eat out. So, in addition to drinking water (a $15+ savings) we share sides of“less healthful”items such as fries and onion rings, sometimes desserts, and usually skip appetizers. We use coupons and use loyalty, birthday clubs, and kid’s nights. We also swap portions, say half a piece my this for some of your that. With these practices we save money and, perhaps the biggest eating out blunder-ourselves from overeating.
Ps I really hope I win the calendar!
 Susan | January 4, 2011 at 12:35 pm | 
The newest cost saving tip I’ve learned for dining out is great for families with kids between kids meals&amp;adult meals. Most resturants that offer a senior menu will allow you to order from it for a child that’s not quite big enough for adult sized portions. For my ten year old son the senior portions are perfect&amp;also offer something besides chicken nuggets and fries. My daughter also likes salad&amp;baked potatoes when we are out; often I’ve been able to order that from the lunch menu even after lunch hours. I’ve saved a lot using these tips while dining out recently; hope they help someone else save a bundle too!
 John S | January 4, 2011 at 12:35 pm | 
Of course drinking water is the most obvious way to cut back on eating out. Me and my will also split an entrée. As you get older the meals seem to get larger. This way we get 2 for 1 without using a coupon and we both get to enjoy a great dining out experience.
 neenah | January 4, 2011 at 12:37 pm | 
We save money several ways eating out…some of which have already been mentioned, but can’t help the timing. 1. order water instead of a soft drink. 2. sign up for birthday clubs on various restaurant websites 3. of course, use coupons 4. my 5 year old can’t eat an entire meal himself, so I share a meal with him, just ask for an extra plate 5. purchase meal certificates from Restaurant.com 6. check receipts from restaurants (they often offer discounted future meals or even a free item for taking their online survey) 7. always check the value menu first we purchase at least one coupon book from our area school system—If we are taking the meal home, we will go 2 or 3 different places to use multiple coupons, then we are also saving on soft drinks by using what we already have.
 Marcia M Cason | January 4, 2011 at 12:37 pm | 
Save half of your meal to take home for another day! Portions are usually too large anyway so eat less, be healthier AND save money!
 Debbie | January 4, 2011 at 12:41 pm | 
my best tip is to order water to drink, which saves from having to pay for the sodas that you can drink at home. Also, only order what you are sure you are gonna eat.
 Lenise | January 4, 2011 at 12:42 pm | 
Sometimes when we eat out, I will order a regular meal–like a hamburger plate and then for a few dollars more, add on a salad bar. I will fill up on the salad bar and take my hamburger home for tonight’s dinner or tomorrow’s lunch, pretty much like getting 2 meals for one price!
 Melissa | January 4, 2011 at 12:42 pm | 
My kids are still small, 4 and under, so when we do go out, I order one regular meal for them and 2 extra plates. It feeds all three kids well without spending the extra money on those‘kids meal’entree’s.
 Bethany | January 4, 2011 at 12:43 pm | 
I like to find deals on Restaurant.com. You can find 80% off of gift certificates. I can get a $25 GC for $2!!!
 Sheryl | January 4, 2011 at 12:43 pm | 
I keep an extra expandable coupon file in the glove box with restaurant coupons in it. This way, when we decide to eat out last minute, we already have all our coupons with us!
 Monica | January 4, 2011 at 12:43 pm | 
always be on the lookout for coupons to restaurants. they come in the mail in the newspaper…all over even the restaurants websites. You can also check menus online to figure how much you can save vs how much to spend. just make sure you plan it and it will all workout =)
 Regina | January 4, 2011 at 12:45 pm | 
Eating off the dollar menu when we go out ot fast food restraunts helps alot, and if we go to a nice place we eat an appetizer to fill up and then order from the kids menus and drink water with Lemon in it.
 Carrie | January 4, 2011 at 12:46 pm | 
Another thing I have done in the past is work as a mystery shopper. There are tons of companies to sign up for, and the more shops you do the better shops you will be offered. We ate out for free at several pretty nice restaurants. The catches are that you sometimes have to pay up front (rarely given gift certificates), sometimes they want you to order specific things or go at specific times (drinks at the bar, appetizer/dessert/specials), and you have to give a VERY detailed report of your experience (which can be a little time consuming). However, everything is explained before you sign up for the job so there should be no surprises.
 Shantaye | January 4, 2011 at 12:48 pm | 
I use coupons every where I go that my friends and family joke about it. I love to save my hard earned money but still be able to get out and enjoy time with them. Ususally a couple of my friends and I would each order an appetizer and we would share to have a variety. We usually get one cocktail and some water because we bring drink packets to flavor the water. In the end at most for dinner we would spend maybe 15 a piece, if that and of course that’s before the coupon which could lower my oop.
 Carolyn | January 4, 2011 at 12:48 pm | 
Order appetizer for your meal or if you order a full meal eat 1/2 and take the rest home for lunch the next day. This way you get 2 meals for the price. Coupons of course and water or one drink per person especially if the restaurant charges by the glass.
 Rachel | January 4, 2011 at 12:49 pm | 
My husband and I often order a larger meal and share it, rather than each of us getting our own meal. And when we have coupons for a free dessert or free appetizer, we can share a smaller (less expensive) and save a little more.
 Karie | January 4, 2011 at 12:49 pm | 
I love coupons! One might say I am addicted! I look all over for them…I am fans with different places on Facebook, I get them in the mail, I sign up on my favorite websites for birthday coupons, I get them in the newspaper, I always buy the entertainment book….I always tell my husband and friends that unless I have a coupon we can’t go…I always get a good laugh but I am the one laughing–all the way to the bank!
 jessica | January 4, 2011 at 12:50 pm | 
I usually bring my own drink to fast food establishments whenever I eat inside. I will buy a 2 liter at a convenience store and ask for ice cups. 
 Glenda D | January 4, 2011 at 12:51 pm | 
Share meals with our children and alwas drink only water with lemon.
 Kathy | January 4, 2011 at 12:51 pm | 
Don’t eat out. I save tons that way!
 Teresa C. | January 4, 2011 at 12:52 pm | 
I love using applicatons (apps) on my Droid X. I use a free app called The Coupons App which focuses in on my location and shows me nearby specials. For example, I could pull up the screen and show it to the clerk at Quiznos to get a free soup with my sandwich today! I also use an free app called Kids Eat Free when dining with my 4-year old. It also uses my location to show me nearby specials for kids. I still use some“old school”tips too. I always buy a local Citipass book and a Smartcard for our area. Both offer many buy one/get one deals and discounts.
 Terry Sizemore | January 4, 2011 at 12:52 pm | 
The best way to save money when dining out is by coupon stacking.It is very budget friendly. Plan to dine at a kid friendly restaurant that has a“kids eat free night”(most restaurants have a limit of 2-3 children per promotion)–this is generally with the purchase of an adult dinner.Use a buy one get free coupon for the adult meal.This saves you from the“water only”plan and a family of 4-5 can dine for the cost of 1 meal!
 Belinda Sherley | January 4, 2011 at 12:53 pm | 
One thing I always do is look for coupons before we go! I like to find two for one deals. You can eat well and only pay for one person! If I don’t have coupons I’ll go somewhere with a value menu. Now a days every resturant has a value menu. You can check out menus and deals on the resturant’s website.

You might also consider getting a salad. Not only is it healthy, it’s affordable too!
 Linda | January 4, 2011 at 12:54 pm | 
I’m single and rarely get to go out to dinner let alone with a friend. What I do is use a“buy one, get one”for myself. I get the second one as a take out for a later meal. Frequently I don’t finish the first so I get at least three meals out of the deal.

For instance…when Chili’s or TGI Friday’s has the Two for $20 deal you get an appetizer (to“share”) and two meals. I eat the appetizer and some of the meal and bring everything else, not eaten, home.

I get at least three meals for $20 plus tax and tip. I usually drink water anywhere…rarely soda (at all) and sometimes I treat myself to sweet tea.
 tracie kelley | January 4, 2011 at 12:55 pm | 
always order small drinks (free refills) or drink water&amp;we always try to go somewhere we have coupons that we can use to eat out or go when they have kids nights/buffets or any kind of“deals”we also buy the cards from our local football boosters/band boosters/etc&amp;utilize the savings on those cards!
 Noel | January 4, 2011 at 12:56 pm | 
You can order a large platter for 2 adults and split it, order water to save on soft drinks and you can even bring those little flavor packets or add lemon&amp;sugar for free lemonade, if you have kids then go on a night when kids eat free, restaurant.com has gift certificates that go on sale for 70-90% off, coupons that come in the mail, coupons in newspaper, and you can buy Entertainment Books that have coupons, and sign up for your favorite restaurants fan club on the internet&amp;facebook and they send you coupons and notify you of specials.
 Amie | January 4, 2011 at 12:58 pm | 
My family gets 2 meals. My husband and I share a meal and the kids share a kids meal. It saves us a lot of money and it’s a lot closer to the portions that we should be eating anyway!
 Emily | January 4, 2011 at 12:58 pm | 
My husband and I will often get a take-out meal from one of our favorite restaurants. The portions are usually so large that we will each get 2 meals from a single entree.
 shelia | January 4, 2011 at 12:59 pm | 
I save my Kroger rec,s. There are always good restraunt coupons on the back. Also much cheeper to dine at lunch. Usually 11 am to 2 pm.
 Tiffany Greene | January 4, 2011 at 1:00 pm | 
Try to look for local events. There are so many community groups and churches that hold spaghetti dinners, fish fries on Friday, pancake breakfasts. Not only can you feed your family cheaply (often with home cooked meals) but you also help support their causes, so it’s a win-win for everyone.

.
 Terri Anderson | January 4, 2011 at 1:01 pm | 
I agree, drink water!! Also, we go out and eat a late lunch instead of dinner…..lunch menus are cheaper at most sit down restaurants and no lines!
 Mylinda | January 4, 2011 at 1:02 pm | 
My husband and I save money when eating out by drinking water. To add a little flavor, I go to the dollar store and purchase packs of lemonade powder mix. I always keep a box of the packets in the car and in my purse. You can really save a lot of money by not paying out $2+ for each beverage. One time the waitress came back by the table and noticed the not as clear water. She said,“Did you put something in the water? I was afraid I had brought not so clear water to you!”We got quite a hoot out of that.
 Bonnijean Marley | January 4, 2011 at 1:02 pm | 
We have several strategies. First we choose a restaurant in the right price range. Sometimes we use coupons from an book or their website. And as several people have already posted, drink water. If everyone in our family drinks water, the savings will pay for one person’s meal.
 Kathy Martinez | January 4, 2011 at 1:04 pm | 
To save money when dining out, we always do several things. First, we look to see if we can get a 50% deal through Restaurants.com, Groupon, or LivingSocial. Then, we look on the particular restaurant’s website to sign up for their frequent diners’plan and their birthday club. Next,we scan the Internet for any coupons or coupon codes and/or look through newspaper advertisement inserts/magazines for coupons and deals. We buy savings cards from local students’fundraisers and promotional items from the restaurants. We use the cumulative visit rewards cards issued by the restaurants. We also fill out the survey from the back of the server’s card or the receipt at the end of our meal to be entered into a sweepstakes/giveaway or to receive a coupon on the upcoming visit. We also share appetizers and desserts, not only to save money but also calories.
 Ann Marie | January 4, 2011 at 1:06 pm | 
I agree with most of the comments above, drinking water saves money, coupons, and kids eat free nights. I like to use coupons when restaurants are having a special on certain foods and that helps lower my bill a lot, because if it is already a discounted price then you use a coupon, you are saving more money. I keep my coupon book in my car in case we make a quick stop for fast food, they’re on hand. Also if you write some restaurant’s and let them know how much you enjoy their food they sometimes will send you free coupons or very good discounted coupons. Love it!
 Nicole Koch | January 4, 2011 at 1:07 pm | 
1.) Order water as your drink&amp;ask for several lemon wedges. Squeeze the lemon juice into your water. Add a packet of sugar or sugar substitute&amp;you have instant lemonade for free! 
2.) Split your entree with another person you’re dining with. Most entrees are huge&amp;much more than we should be eating.
3.) Consider ordering side dishes. A couple side dishes may cost less than an entree.
4.) Check for coupons, specials or“kids eat free”days!
 Tabitha | January 4, 2011 at 1:09 pm | 
I always search the web for coupons of any type, then I check their facebook page. And when we get there, we never buy drinks (water always unless it is in the AM then I can’t resist the coffee), and stay away from appetizers and desserts.
 Toni | January 4, 2011 at 1:09 pm | 
Split a meal, use coupons, eat off childrens menu.
 Deborah Finley Henry | January 4, 2011 at 1:10 pm | 
On March 9,2010 had Gastric Bypass,one thing I really enjoyed was going to eat the salads,that was something that helped me and side salad was my daily favorite
 brandy feeney | January 4, 2011 at 1:11 pm | 
Get your meal to GO. You can still use coupons and don’t have to buy drinks. YOu even save on tipping. The best part is you have the comfort of home.
 Alecia | January 4, 2011 at 1:13 pm | 
Split a meal with your child. Ask for an extra plate and save the cost of a child’s meal, there’s always enough to share.
 Lisa | January 4, 2011 at 1:13 pm | 
When going out to eat, we make sure we do a combination of the following to save money while enjoying a meal out with the family. We make sure we have coupons and/or reward card in hand, when possible drink water, eat dessert at home or share a dessert, share meals, use gift certificates when available, use Restaurant.com gift certificates, ask for a refill on a drink and then ask for it to go, eat half your meal and bring home leftovers for another meal and make sure you ask for more bread to take home to enjoy with our leftovers.
 Krystal P | January 4, 2011 at 1:14 pm | 
Sign up for birthday clubs, but don’t use your real birthday. Use other months, that way you get offers at other times of year.
 Jennifer | January 4, 2011 at 1:16 pm | 
1. Drink water, we never pay for drinks when eating out.
2. Go to places with the value menus.
3. If going to a bigger sit down restaurant try to go on a night htey have a specil. Alot of places have 2 for 1 deals on Tuesdays, kids eat free on other nights etc.
4. Sign up for the birthday clubs if they have them. It could mean free appetizer to free meal on your birthday.
5. I also sign up for their email clubs&amp;they send coupons via email often.
6. We purchase a Entertainment book&amp;use those coupons often.
7. Sometimes if it’s a big entree we’ll get one and split it between two people.
 pat cipolla | January 4, 2011 at 1:19 pm | 
Always look for and clip coupons before going out. You can save pretty good
 Kelly | January 4, 2011 at 1:20 pm | 
We choose one weeknight to eat out, then we use local coupon books, (usually sold for fund raisers through schools), or coupons from the resteraunt’s website. I also fill out comment cards and am diligent filling out surveys online and on the bottom of receipts. It’s a win-win, eating out only once a week, we can splurge with an appetizer or desert.
 Rhonda Hall | January 4, 2011 at 1:23 pm | 
My husband and I ordered the biggest meal then just add a sandwich or a salad and one dessert.. and split the big meal and he gets the soda and I just order a glass of water (sine I cut out all caffiene)..
 judy henry | January 4, 2011 at 1:24 pm | 
The“drink water”idea is a biggie, it saves you tons during a year. I also take my little kids (sort of) sippie cups with their juice. Also, the appetizer menu is the best deal at any restaurant, for adults and kids. And though this isn’t really saving money, do make sure you tip the waitstaff IF they are worth it! These people live on tips, they don’t even make minimum wages.
 Sherry Ballard | January 4, 2011 at 1:25 pm | 
I order ice tea w/no ice and a cup of ice on the side so I can dilute it and I get 3 drinks for the price of one.
 Jean A. | January 4, 2011 at 1:25 pm | 
If you have kids, go to places that offer free kids meal with a purchase of adult meal. Ihop is a good place to go for that. Denny’s sometimes has the offer too.
 Kary Browning | January 4, 2011 at 1:27 pm | 
we get coupons off resturant.com to get deals for $25 off $35. We also order water and share meals. The kids also share when possible. One other thing we do is go to resturants that give bread or chips to fill up some so we don’t have to get as big of meal.
 Floyd | January 4, 2011 at 1:30 pm | 
Always order water, as previously stated, especially when having to pay for a family of 5. Use the Entertainment book, not only for coupons, this allows you to try places you haven’t been before. Order lunch portions. The biggest way to save when going out to eat…..drop the kids off with their grandparents 
 Deanna A | January 4, 2011 at 1:37 pm | 
Drink water. Use coupons. Sign up for loyalty programs. Buy from Restaurant.com. Share meals. Get a part time job serving and get discounts as an employee. I work part time at Carrabbas and I get 50% off at my Carrabbas and also 20% off at Outback, Bonefish Grill and others in the chain! Restaurant portions are usually huge, so after ordering ask your server for a carry out container right away and save half for another meal!
 Isabel Acosta | January 4, 2011 at 1:38 pm | 
One of the things we do most is use coupons. my husband will ask where do you have a coupon from before we decide to go out to eat. I also sigh up for email newsletters from all the restaurants that we like. I get several coupons or specials emailed right to me each month. Its really fun when you get freebies for your birthday at several restaurants.
 Janet | January 4, 2011 at 1:38 pm | 
Get the new 2011 Chick-fil-A calender/coupon book. And they also accept multiple coupons.
 momma bruce | January 4, 2011 at 1:39 pm | 
My entire family loves Chic Fil A!!! Morning, Noon&amp;Night, what more could one ask for!! Yummy!
 Dorinda Miller | January 4, 2011 at 1:40 pm | 
Take wipes to clean the highchairs and table.
 momma bruce | January 4, 2011 at 1:42 pm | 
My creative tip is to get emails from all restuarants, especially Chic Fil A. My almost son in law works at a company and on the free Chic Fil A sandwich day every year, his entire shift of people dress up like cows and go to the restuarant. Lovin’Chic Fil A. Another great tip is to use the new Group on specials that CBS Local news offers almost every city. You can get a $50 meal for only $20 to $25. Superb idea!
 Kelly F. | January 4, 2011 at 1:43 pm | 
Of course drinking water anytime you eat out will save you approximately $2.00 per person. Adding a lemon wedge will definitely help with the tasteless drink, plus lemon helps with digestion…can’t beat that! But on top of drinking lemon water my best suggestion would be sharing a meal with someone you love. Not only are your eyes too big for your stomach most of the time but it also helps on the calorie intake where most meals average 1000-1500 per plate when eating out. Most places will allow you to do this as long as it’s not an all you can eat place, which I usually avoid. One last but not least suggestion would be that using a bogo coupon will also cut way back on your eating out bill tremendously.
 Rosemary | January 4, 2011 at 1:47 pm | 
Plan ahead when dining out. Look for specials, coupons or contests for reducing out of pocket costs.
This also allows you to leave a larger tip for your server.
You can order water with your meal instead of a costly beverage.
Take any leftovers home, sometimes there is enough for another meal for later.
 Haley O. | January 4, 2011 at 1:50 pm | 
When dining out at a fast food restaurant we try to“supersize”a meal and split it between the three of us. If that is not enough, we’ll order something off the $1 menu.
At nicer restuarants, we sometimes order from the appetizer menu. It sometimes has the same items in larger quantities for less money. (And we can split an entree for a bit more variety.) **Even when trying to save money, never skimp on the tip!**
 Debra Smith | January 4, 2011 at 1:57 pm | 
Coupons coupons coupons…and if you don’t have any..check the websites for coupon downloads. Another great way to save is to upsize a meal or add to a entre and share it. They usually give you more than enough for 2 people. Plus if you are counting calories it’s a better way to cut back.
 Paula Plunk | January 4, 2011 at 2:02 pm | 
I always drink water, it’s free and drinks are high!
 PAM BARBEE | January 4, 2011 at 2:02 pm | 
On of my best ways to save when eating out is to use restaurant.com gift certificates. You can sometimes buy a $25 gift certificate for $2. The gift certificates never expire&amp;you can change them for other restaurants if you change you mind about where you want to use it. There are restaurants in every state&amp;even in Washington, DC. So you can use them for your vacation plans also. Unfortunately, Chick-fil-A does not offer gift certificates on this site. I always try to eat where I have a coupon or gift certificate for. Ordering water is also a way to save on your bill. Instead of paying $2 a person for a tea or cola, you can save that money or maybe once in awhile splurge&amp;get dessert.
 Emily | January 4, 2011 at 2:03 pm | 
Always drink water and try to go out to eat at lunchtime when portions and prices are smaller! If we go out at dinner, then hubby and I split a meal amongst ourselves or with the kids.
 Lindsay H | January 4, 2011 at 2:04 pm | 
order water! not only is it healthier for you, it’s free! We also use resources like restaurant.com , entertainment book, restaurants websites&amp;follow daily specials on restaurants twitter accounts.
 Kina harrell | January 4, 2011 at 2:05 pm | 
My best advice would be to first check to see if they have a kids eat free deal. Then of course go through your coupons and stretch your dollars as far as possible. It’s always great to be able to eat out as a family and not feel like it’s a strain on the budget. Make sure you check out coupons.com and also put restraurant coupons in your search engine. God Bless and have a great day everyone. 
 Olivia Torain | January 4, 2011 at 2:08 pm | 
Group On website for your city often has fantastic deals. Also, coupons! I receive them online and in the mail. Always search and sign up for email from your favorite places or places you’ve been wanting to try out. Often they will send you coupons via email or text.
 Connie H | January 4, 2011 at 2:09 pm | 
Stack your deals. Get a coupon and then go on a special day, some restaurants we go to have“chicken sandwiches are BOGO on mondays”or“pizza night on Tuesdays”or the best way is pay what you weigh kids days, I have skinny kiddos!
 Lori S. | January 4, 2011 at 2:11 pm | 
Some restaurants have a daily special. Order from it. Divide it in half and box it up as soon as you get it. Now you’ve got another meal ready for tomorrow. Drink water. Eat an apple at home before you leave so you’re not tempted to over-order.
 Amanda Bricker | January 4, 2011 at 2:12 pm | 
My kids loved veggies when they were toddlers. Now they are all going through a phase where at least one of them dislikes the vegetable served for dinner each night. So I decided to make a game of it. After they get home from school I announce the vegetable being served that night and they get online to find one interesting fact about that vegetable. At dinner, they read their fact and the family chooses the most interesting one. The winner picks the after-school snack served the next day. They are all eating their veggies so much better!
 stephanie | January 4, 2011 at 2:13 pm | 
We split meals (good for keeping calories in check too!), we drink water, go when there are promotional meal deals, and when kids meals are free. I would love the calendar!
 Roberta Moore | January 4, 2011 at 2:13 pm | 
My husband and I like chicken strips. We always share a salad and a chickens strip plate, and usually use a coupon too. That way 2 people can eat for the price of 1, or even less if we have a coupon. We order 1 beverage and 1 glass of water and share. We sometimes even have enough left over to bring home a“doggy”bag!
 Beth | January 4, 2011 at 2:14 pm | 
We try to eat out on the nights that our favorite restaurants have kid specials.
 Theresa T | January 4, 2011 at 2:14 pm | 
I split a meal with a friend or my child. I order a side salad and drink water. This cuts calories and saves money!
 kathleen yohanna | January 4, 2011 at 2:16 pm | 
We bought a discount card as a fundraiser for our church. We check which restaurants honor the card and go there. Some places give a 20% discount on the whole check. We sometimes go out to eat early so that we can order off the lunch menu, which is often cheaper than the dinner menu. My friends know that we enjoy eating out so they buy me gift cards to certain restaurants. They have now given me a nice gift and I have a big discount on my meals. They can buy these at face value from my husband’s club which gets a certain percentage of the sales, which in turn they give back to the community. So everyone wins. I like Haley’s advice about tipping on the full amount before your discount.
 Kimberly Pomatto | January 4, 2011 at 2:22 pm | 
Serving sizes are too large at restaurant! A good way too save money is to split a meal with a friend or loved one. Most portion sizes are made to serve 2 to 3 meals and are served to one person. This will not only help out on the pocket book it will help out on the waistline too. Also if you are by yourself order a kids meal it is an appropriate portion size and the toy may just make you feel like a kid again!
 Michelle | January 4, 2011 at 2:23 pm | 
I always look for coupons on sites lite retailmenot.com or groupon.com. I found groupon through a promo from All You and love them. Even searched the town I was going to for the holidays and got some deals. And of course the resturant site itself, some will offer free items just for joining a club which is free.
Another good way to save is to eat lunch insead of dinner. The lunch portion is usually large and is priced less.
I too base tip on amount prior to discount.That is great advise, your tipping on service and it should be on the total not the discount price.
 Kelly E | January 4, 2011 at 2:23 pm | 
We order water and use coupons, from mail, newspaper, internet, Restaurant.com, entertainment book. We also ask for gift cards for special occasions so it can be FREE!
 Chris Cree | January 4, 2011 at 2:34 pm | 
We eat out at lunch instead of dinner at resturants with lunch menues. This way we still get to eat out but not at full price. We also NEVER order soda.
 Charlotte | January 4, 2011 at 2:36 pm | 
The best way to save money eating out anytime is to drink Water! Drinks really add up on your bill. When you drink water you can appreciate the flavor of your food better and save money!
 Ashley C | January 4, 2011 at 2:45 pm | 
When going out to eat the portions are sooo huge and many times we feel so full that we either forget to grab a take home bag or just leave the food there because the sight of even being tempted by one more bite makes us wanna throw up lol (i too have overate LOL) the best tip i have is to make the most of your money. Many times places will over free bread or chips and we fill up on those before the meal even gets there. Drink water ( IT’S FREE) and Split a meal with a friend. Usually there is more then enough for both and spliting a 8 dollar meal is cheaper then spending 16 on two meals : )
 Patricia Hill | January 4, 2011 at 2:46 pm | 
Order from the Kid’s menu if they will let you.
 Madeline | January 4, 2011 at 2:47 pm | 
My tip for saving money while eating out is to share an entree. Some entrees are large enough that two people can eat one. The portions are sometimes too much for one. So, by sharing it, you are no eating too much, and therefore, no“doggy”bag to take home.

Also, I use coupons whenever I can.

I also use points (from My Points, etc.) to buy gift cards to use in restaurants.
 Jennifer | January 4, 2011 at 2:53 pm | 
While eating out I typically either use coupons or other type of savings, such as deal mobs or a weekly site where you can get half off gift certificates. Either that or ordering off the kid’s menu always works too. Another great way to save money is to order water to drink. It’s good for you, and you don’t pay $2 or more for a soda or something that you could get so much cheaper from the grocery store.
 Liz | January 4, 2011 at 3:13 pm | 
We share meals with our kids, drink water, use coupons, and look for discount nights with the kids. And, to save money on gas while eating, we pre-buy gift cards from our grocery store. For every $50 in gift cards we spend, we get .20 off per gallon. So, if we are already going to eat out–why not save on gas on the way there! The way gas prices are now…you can’t afford it otherwise!!!!
 Sharon S. | January 4, 2011 at 3:19 pm | 
At restaurants that serve big portions, my husband and I order an extra side salad and then one entree to split. Many restaurants serve bread, also, so we leave feeling plenty full!
 kristi vandergriff | January 4, 2011 at 3:26 pm | 
I always look through the mail for coupons, which are on a lot of flyers we get. The best bang for my buck has been one of the local fundraising books where there are a lot of B1G1 half off–top that with the kids eat free nite and it is a great deal! These coupons last over a year and also allows us to try different restaurants.
 Alisa | January 4, 2011 at 3:28 pm | 
Planning is the key to saving money when eating out.
1) Never go when you are starving. You will order more.
2) Split a meal and decided to do it before you get there.
3) Order water. It is free and healthier
4) Got kids? Go on kids eat free nights.
5) Restaurant.com, Groupon, dailydeals from Roanoke.com all great ways to get more and pay less
6) Sign up for all loyalty and birthday clubs. There are free meals to be had.
7) Make a dessert ahead of time and plan to eat it when you get home. Less temptation to order expensive desserts at the restaurant.
8) If you are eating at Chick-fli-a…get a calendar. Eat month you get something free. Let one adult get the free item and the other adult orders a sandwich and large fries to split This will cost you about $6.00. That is a good price for two to eat. If you have a child go on the kids night and they get a craft and free ice cream. If you are ordering the Grilled Chick-fil-a sandwich ask for no tomato and lettuce and this will save you about 30 cents.
 Melanie Snipes | January 4, 2011 at 3:34 pm | 
We use restaurant.com coupons for many places. We order water and go out on kids eat free nights. We NEVER eat out without a coupon though.
I also enter sweepstakes regularly and use winning giftcards to pay for our meals out.
 Bethany M | January 4, 2011 at 3:36 pm | 
My best tip is I drink water and so does my daughter. Still working on getting hubby to do that. Second is, my daughter and I share a meal. So I eat less and we spend less.
 Gail B | January 4, 2011 at 3:37 pm | 
To save money order water nd a appetizer. Usually plenty of food if you pick the sampler order . Try to go to resturants that like families to come.
 Kim B | January 4, 2011 at 3:42 pm | 
Sharing a meal with a loved one is also a great way to save on your bills. Some restaurants offer large or smalls on their dishes so order the large and ask for two plates. If you have a small child who isn’t going to be eating a lot, share your meal with them or order a side dish to feed them. At many restaurants you can order sides of pasta or potatoes and for a small child that side will be plenty for them. Sides are much cheaper than the children meal and less goes to waste.
 erika | January 4, 2011 at 3:43 pm | 
always bring the water/can soda (whichever one your family drinks)a can soda bought from the supermarket(like when we buy the 24 packs : ))is sometimes more than half the price you’d pay for it at the restaurant !

also look for coupons !

and when eating at places that offer refill like taco bell , mcdonalds , burker king etc, always gt the‘small’soda because you can always get up and refill it and that will say you n ire than youd guess !

never drink a smoothie or a milshake while you wait for food cuz you’ll be full faster and by the time the food arrives , you will no longer be as hungry !

and last but not least….

if the leftovers are a good portion of your meal , take them home , they can be your snack later on during the day !

that saves money too 
 Jennifer | January 4, 2011 at 3:52 pm | 
I always use a coupon and order water.
 Lori | January 4, 2011 at 4:08 pm | 
Coupons, water, dollar menu, kids eat free nights.
 Cheryl Donigan | January 4, 2011 at 4:18 pm | 
It’s just my husband and I now, so we check out the coupons (if there are no coupons, we don’t go) before we go and see what the best deal is. We look for the“main course”items for B1G1 free. We purchase a medium fries and split it (we shouldn’t have so many fries anyways). Water. If we feel like it, we split a salad too.
 Tiffany | January 4, 2011 at 4:19 pm | 
Decide how much money you want to spend each month on eating out and put that amount of cash in an envelope. Then just use the cash. It’s amazing how much more thought you put into ordering when you know you’re paying with cash instead of putting the bill on your card. It’s also really nice when at the end of the month you realize you haven’t eaten out as much as you thought so you get to splurge. We’ve been using this system for about a year. It takes a little getting used to but we went from over spending on eating out, to staying on budget every single month!
 Darlene | January 4, 2011 at 4:20 pm | 
My husband and I share a meal. There is usually plenty for us both and we save on calories too!
 Wendy Cappos | January 4, 2011 at 4:30 pm | 
Use coupons, look for the best meal deal, and save all your loose change regularly&amp;use that to pay for it, loose change adds up fast!!
 Glenn | January 4, 2011 at 4:30 pm | 
Always look at the back of your restaurant (and even grocery) receipts. Often there is a number to call to complete a survey of your dining experience. At the end of the survey, you are given a code to write on the ticket. Return it to the restaurant for a free sandwich, meal, whatever they offer!
 Heather | January 4, 2011 at 4:32 pm | 
Try ordering an appetizer instead of main course, they are usually nearly half the cost of an entree. If that is not an option, we look for restaurants with huge portions, and bring home the extra to stretch our dollar. Some places we can get 3 meals out of one entree portion! Find a place that does family-style (Maggiano’s is one), and see if they will let you take home extras. If you finish what they bring the first time, they will bring a refill at no cost, and you can take all of that food home. This can be a great way to make your money go farther!
 Kathy | January 4, 2011 at 4:33 pm | 
Use restaurant.com to buy gift certificates. You spend a fraction of what you would normally pay…sometimes as much as 80% off! If you can’t get a certificate, look for restaurants that offer special deals for families. Many restaurants offer“buy an adult meal get a child’s meal free”. Children don’t eat that much, so it’s easy to share food with them or just order side dishes. Coupons are a great option too. Many restaurants offer them on their websites. Last, but not least, get water instead of soda or tea, and go to restaurants that have dollar menus!
 Corey M. | January 4, 2011 at 4:38 pm | 
Saves you pounds and money! Decide to eat half of what is on you plate, and take home the rest.

(A note to earlier poster: Even if you have water with a lemon, don’t put the peel in the water after you squeeze it. Most places, the servers grab lemon slices from a jar and their germs are all over the peel).
 Caanan | January 4, 2011 at 4:47 pm | 
If I’m going to a fast food establishment and am not completely starving, I’ll usually get a kids meal. Cheaper than a sandwich, fries and a drink (or water), and it’s less food. Sure, you can go without fries and just drink water, but this way I get a few fries that are the reason I went there in the first place.
 Melody | January 4, 2011 at 4:48 pm | 
My tip actually has to do with Chick-fil-A! We have one at our local mall and it just happens to be my fav restaurant!! It can be a little expensive, so their calender coupons help a lot. My money saving tip requires a little money up front, but totally pays off in the end! Most Chick-fil-A restaurants offer a special in November and December where you receive a free calender with a purchase of a $20 gift card! I purchase 10 and get 10 FREE calenders! That’s a big savings! Since I visit the mall at least one a week, I combine my coupons and the gift cards I purchased (plus any promotions they are offering), to pay for my meals! This past year, I ate there once a week, plus several weekends with the family, only using the gift cards and coupons I purchased earlier! That’s a huge savings!! You can stay on budget and eat delicious food!! 
 Donna J | January 4, 2011 at 4:51 pm | 
I always check for coupons–Restaurant.com has great certificates at low cost and yes they do work. You can search by zip code and get $25 Certificates for $4.00 or less. They are cheaper at the end of the month and don’t expire.
 Karen | January 4, 2011 at 4:59 pm | 
My tips:

Share meals, use coupons, and always, always, ALWAYS go to Chick-fil-a!!!!!!
 Ann Black | January 4, 2011 at 5:03 pm | 
Since we are senior citizens now and don’t eat as much as when we were younger, we often divide the large plates of food that most restaurants offer to prevent wasting food as well as helping financially. Sometimes we drink water too inplace of the high cost drinks and find it healthier also.
 Suzanne | January 4, 2011 at 5:05 pm | 
We go out to eat one days restaurants have free kids meals, like Firehouse. (Buy 1 combo receive 2 free kids meal on Wed and Sun) We drink water when need be. I also sometimes order Kids meals myself. It is usually enough and is cheaper. I will also save up free meal coupons.
 Sue E | January 4, 2011 at 5:09 pm | 
Sign up for the birthday club, many restaurants offer these and you can get free desserts, appetizers, etc. Pare the freebies with discount coupons, nights with free kids meals, and order water instead of tea and/or sodas. Eat dessert at home, it’s much cheaper and more enjoyable.
 Brenda Smith | January 4, 2011 at 5:10 pm | 
Patronize restaurants that offer free kids’meals (or $.99 meals) on Tuesday nights.
 cindy | January 4, 2011 at 5:14 pm | 
coupons in the paper are really great mostly they can get you a free dinner or a discount which helps with the server tip I have found that the military.com deal site helps for those who can use it.restaurant.com doesn’t have much in my area but if you are a discover rewards member they have gift cards at discount rates using rewards for most of the big chains. signing up at your favorite restaurant websites gets you emai coupon specials year round and on birthdays and anniversarys
 michelle | January 4, 2011 at 5:31 pm | 
I always use coupons or go on a kids night. if it’s fast food i’ll split my meal w/my daughter&amp;order an extra sandwich.
 VickieCouturier | January 4, 2011 at 5:41 pm | 
My best tip when dining out is to drink water,its free an natural,an refills are free too,saves bunches when you have several dining,an I join the places websites for discount coupons to eat

vlbelk(at)hotmail.com
 kim | January 4, 2011 at 5:41 pm | 
our family does several things in order to save while dining out. first, we typically avoid restaurants that have meal servers…which cuts out the extra 18% on the top of your meal for a tip. we drink water with our meal. we frequent restaurants that offer coupons, free kids meals, or are otherwise reasonably priced. we also use certificates from restaurant.com (only when they are offering them at 80% off, or more) and again…try to find restaurants that don’t have servers for the certificates we buy. we also always make sure to stop eating when full and take home our leftovers. there is usually enough left for lunch the next day!
 mary | January 4, 2011 at 5:47 pm | 
we become web members of our fav restaurants to utilize their special/ secret members only discounts.
 Pat | January 4, 2011 at 5:51 pm | 
In addition to ordering water, using coupoins, and sharing meals, my husband and I look for sit-down restaurants that have great ambience, but a low price. That way we can have both a good meal and an opportunity for quality time together.

We order from the“kids of all ages”menu. It is all we really need to eat. If money is really tight when ordering fast food, we get one“combo”meal”plus another sandwich. Then we share the drink and fries.
 Brandi | January 4, 2011 at 5:51 pm | 
Before I go out to eat, I check the restaurants near where I live. Sometimes they have a website which offers special offers or promotions and I can find a good deal.

Also, instead of ordering a fancy (expensive) dessert, I’ll take sugarless gum. After the meal, I can get the sweet taste without the price or the extra calories!
 Dawn | January 4, 2011 at 5:54 pm | 
Instead of eating in at a restaurant, avoid buying a drink and take the food home. Drinks at home are free. At some restaurants that offer larger portions, share the meal with another person. If there are leftovers, take them home for a meal the next day. Having coupons and birthday offers are great, such as a free dessert.
 Janet L | January 4, 2011 at 5:56 pm | 
A lot of times my husband and I decide what restaurant we are going to eat at before we leave our house. So I will take a minute to look at the restaurant’s website to see what their specials are and a lot of times they will have coupons for free appetizers or desserts sometimes even free meals. Also, most restaurants have a website where you can sign up to receive their e-newsletters or e-mails. Almost every week I recieve coupons in my inbox for free appetizers, desserts and free meals.
 Ellen Matos | January 4, 2011 at 6:11 pm | 
I always check for coupons on the internet before going out and keep a folder at home for newspaper and mailed coupons.
 Lori S | January 4, 2011 at 6:16 pm | 
I haven’t seen this tip mentioned yet, which surprises me. Many restaurants now offer bonus cards when you buy a gift card for the holidays (like a $5 bonus when you buy $25). I often buy gift cards to my favorite places as a“gift”to myself, since I know I’ll be eating there anyway in the next year, so I get bonus money just for spending some in advance. The best deal I’ve seen this holiday season was a $15 bonus for buying $50 at Ruby Tuesday (30% extra for your money vs. the usual 20% offered by other restaurants).
 brittany wilson | January 4, 2011 at 6:21 pm | 
I use city deals and I also always look for coupons in the happenings book.
 Elizabeth N. | January 4, 2011 at 6:28 pm | 
We always look for coupons (Entertainment Book, mailers, on websites) and try to split entrees when we can. I also order off the kids’menu if they’ll let me–smaller portions and smaller prices!
 Carrie | January 4, 2011 at 6:54 pm | 
We drink water alot when we go out to eat as well as using coupons. Also, the new trend with some sit down restaurants are meals with 3 mini sandwiches and fries. Instead of ordering my son a child’s meal and then a sandwich for myself, I will just order a mini sandwich meal for us to share. The bill ends up a little lighter and so do I as my son eats most of the fries.
 lisa simmons | January 4, 2011 at 7:17 pm | 
1) we check for coupons then decide where we will eat and what we will eat before hand
2) we order water and I always have crystal light in my purse, I can’t eat or drink 30 min before or after a meal so I always order water and it sits, so hubby has an extra glass with crystal light
3) we split a meal for the 2 of us
4) we don’t eat desserts
 Bev | January 4, 2011 at 7:42 pm | 
We always look for the“early bird”specials and go out during the week rather than the weekend. Since my husband is a senior, he always gets the senior discount and of course, we have learned never, ever order a cocktail, drink water–drink a cocktail at home! We also use coupons and buy restaurant.com vouchers. It is fun to see how much money you can save.
 Dawn Langis | January 4, 2011 at 8:17 pm | 
food courts in the malls often make it difficult and expensive to choose different meals at various vendors when we have our young grandchildren along. And, most of the foods gets wasted.

Now, I pack peanut butter and jelly for everyone (even Pop) and either take our own drinks along or bring cups and buy the largest drink and we share.

Before we leave, they can have a treat. Everyone is happy
 Donna | January 4, 2011 at 8:27 pm | 
My friends and I go to fast food places, each buy different dollar menu items, then share. We each get“tapas”, mini bites of different items, and makes for a fun lunch, and not the same ole boring stuff.
 Kim | January 4, 2011 at 8:43 pm | 
i use all the tips to save money. coupons, coupons, and more coupons. Share entrees, Happy Hour, etc.
 Kim | January 4, 2011 at 8:48 pm | 
Don’t hit the concession stand at your kids sports games! The best tip for saving money at ball games is to boil a pack of hotdogs at home, pour the boiling water in a large insulated mug, and put the cooked hot dogs in the mug. Pack buns, and packs of ketchup&amp;mustard. You will save bunches of money, go to your car and eat at half time. Don’t forget a cooler of drinks.
 Sharon Fisher | January 4, 2011 at 10:09 pm | 
The best way to save money when eating out is to not go when you are starving….try to eat a little bit of something and wash it down with a large glass of water. Wait 20 minutes for your stomach to recognize that it is not empty and that way you will not over order and waste money.
 Ally Frey | January 4, 2011 at 10:28 pm | 
My advice? Use coupons and always get a doggie bag. Portions are always much bigger than what you need so take it home and eat it for lunch the next day. This way you are really getting two meals for the price of one!
 Beverly C. | January 4, 2011 at 10:39 pm | 
I collect coupons from the mail and the paper. I get coupons off of the internet. I purchase an Entertainment Book each year after they go on sale. I join restaurants’Birthday clubs. (Some actually give you a free burger.) I purchase gift cards during the Christmas season when some restaurants offers you $5 or $10 dollars to purchase a $25 gift card. I purchase Groupon coupons and restaurant.com certificates.
 Jessica K. | January 4, 2011 at 11:05 pm | 
My advice is to subscribe to restaurant (Chili’s, TGIF, Ruby Tuesday, Chick-Fil-A) newsletters and they always enclose coupons or free appetizers or dessert ones. They will also let you about special family nights. In 2010, chick-fil-a offered free chicken sandwich to those dressed in Team Jerseys another event was for those dressed like Cows. I found out about those by subscribing.
 Angela P. | January 4, 2011 at 11:16 pm | 
My advice is to get gift certificates off of restaurants.com, you can find great deals on this site. Drink water when you go out to dinner and buy one dessert and share it. Or you can go get dollar menu at a fast food restaurant and take it home.
 L D Rushing | January 4, 2011 at 11:28 pm | 
Take your restaurant coupons to work and share them with a co-worker. A buy one get one free is an excellent way to save money during lunchtime. Also, sign up online with all the restaurants you love to get additional coupon savings.
 Christina L. | January 4, 2011 at 11:34 pm | 
Look for BOGO coupons for your fave restaurants and if you have kids, look for restaurants that allow kids to eat for free. We always buy an Attractions book for $25 each year. This is a book sold locally that is full of BOGO coupons and other discount coupons for hundreds of local restaurants and retail stores. We…also clip coupons that are sent in the mail as well as from magazines and newspapers. You can also find plenty of online coupons if you are into printing coupons from your computer.
 Barbara Platt | January 5, 2011 at 12:04 am | 
Sign up for emails from restaurants and use the coupons for free appitizers and desserts. You also get discounts for meals.
Some places even let kids eat free with the purchase of an adult meal.

Or go to all you can eat buffets.
 Whitney Hogge | January 5, 2011 at 12:14 am | 
I was going to share a lot that has already been talked about…
~Restaurant.com
~The Entertainment Book/Attraction

But some of the best spots are the most inexpensive like going on a date with your sweetie to Costco to get a Hot Dog and a Coke for a $1.50. Also Chick-Fil-A has (in my area on Wednesdays)a night that Kids eat Free and you can all go out as a family.

One last idea–is Plastic Jungle. It is a website where you can go and buy discounted gift cards for Restaurants of your choice. So you can buy a $50 card for around $35. You can also sell any gift card you have that you want cash for, at this site.
 Heather W | January 5, 2011 at 1:54 am | 
My 11-year-old daughter and I clip restaurant and snack bar coupons frequently. I have also signed us up for email rewards programs for child-friendly establishments in our area. However, many times in the past when we were out on an unexpected errand or spur-of-the-moment day trip, our coupons got left at home, doing us no good at all. To solve this problem, I put all the coupons in a large manilla envelope. This envelope stays in our car. When I clip or print new coupons for the envelope, these go immediately in my purse. Once we’re in the car again, my daughter adds the new coupons and removes any that have expired. I cannot tell you how much money we have saved just by ensuring that the coupons are with us when we need them.
 chastidy | January 5, 2011 at 2:21 am | 
Order water to drink and we eat where kids eat free. And we use coupons 
 Kathy M. | January 5, 2011 at 2:47 am | 
I order food items that have ingredients which are costly for me to buy at the supermarket, yet fair in price on the menu. I am able to savor and enjoy the experience. I save lower cost ingredients for home cooked meals, which saves me money. Spice is the variety of life!
 David Chaille | January 5, 2011 at 3:23 am | 
I totally disapprove of Chik-Fil-A’s ultra right wing politics. They can keep their calendar!! I am boycotting this fast-food joint.
 Bev S. | January 5, 2011 at 4:22 am | 
The best way for me to save money when I go out is to have someone else pay for it! 
 maria encinas | January 5, 2011 at 6:18 am | 
We are a family of 6 with 4 teenagers. Ways we save money are by sharing meals. We order 2 or 3 meals, split the drink, and fries and sometimes the sandwich and add to it by ordering off the $1 menu if we need to. We have saved a ton of money this way.

Another thing we do when we go to restuarants is we go when the lunch menu pricing is still on, the prices are lot cheaper (sometimes even more than half that of dinner. Then for dinner we make a desert at home or if we have a coupon we go out for just a desert later on.

Also, coupons, water, and joining on facebook or websites for savings. Compare pricing and do not rule out those little“hole in the wall places”“mom and pop”places they sometimes have better deals than even McDonalds. You need to do your homework.
 angela | January 5, 2011 at 6:20 am | 
Give your kids a small allowance and teach them how to budget at an early age so that they can learn the value of a dollar.
 LISA BLUMENSTEIN | January 5, 2011 at 6:34 am | 
# 1 tip drink water. It saves 2.00 to 3.00 per person. This also saves on the tip you have to leave because you’re bill will be cheaper. I always carry a drink for the kids just in case it does not come with the meal. I always have snacks with me for the kids so they don’t get to hungry and order extra food like appatizer when we will get plenty of food with our meal. Coupons and days when they run specials help also. I also share meals with the kids or split a meal with someone. Always bring left overs home they make a great snack or lunch for the next day.
 Deborah Kallgren | January 5, 2011 at 6:55 am | 
Make use of the Web! Check out restaurants’websites and sign up for their emails. They often will email coupons and alert you to deals. If you provide your birthday, they will often email you a coupon for a free meal or appetizer. Find restaurants on Facebook and“like”them—they like to reward their fans with deals!
 Becky | January 5, 2011 at 7:17 am | 
Alot of restaurants have‘specials’certain days of the week. Educate yourself on the specials of your favorite go to place (ex. Popeyes–Tuesday, 99cent potpies). Eat the‘special’items on the discount days better yet, split it with a friend, and better yet if possible walk to the restaurant and back! You will be saving money, eating a more approiate serving size AND getting exercise in one experience.
 Jessica King | January 5, 2011 at 8:01 am | 
I always go to places that have some sort of special or coupons. You can fnd all kinds of deals&amp;coupons online!
 heather c | January 5, 2011 at 8:10 am | 
Use coupons or discount codes. Sign up for restaurant texts, emails, etc and use them! Don’t forget to check groupon and livingsocial for deals, as well!
Check during the holidays for gift card deals. Sometimes, if you buy a certain denomination of gift card, you get an additional gift card for yourself. Why not buy yourself some gift cards? If you buy a $100 gift card and get a $25 gift card for doing it, that’s like getting 25% off your bill!
Eat out during lunch. Sometimes the portions are just right, and the prices are, as well.
 patricia white | January 5, 2011 at 8:44 am | 
always use coupons, even if it is little amounts, it adds up!
 Tina N. | January 5, 2011 at 9:22 am | 
My husband and I dine out often, because we travel a lot. We find many coupons we use from tourist guides and other coupons local magazines from the supermarket. Every little bit helps. I also enter sweepstakes and I have won a few gift cards that I have been able to use in restaurants, as well. Also, my husband usually gets water with his meal, and we will often share a dessert, instead of paying for two desserts.
 Kim Kenty | January 5, 2011 at 12:12 pm | 
would love to win a Chick-fil-A calendar! My son and I love to eat there when I take him to his regular doctor appts.

To save money when eating out, I look for a value combo meal, a value menu to order from, or a special deal that the place is running!

THANKS.

I think I entered on the wrong page the first time!
 Stacy T. | January 5, 2011 at 4:16 pm | 
First of we never go out to eat unless we have coupons or a gift card. Second you can usually score gift cards for restaurants from credit card rewards, or several of the points based programs out there like Mypoints.
 Wendy T | January 9, 2011 at 1:01 am | 
My husband and I were at I-Hop this week where we frequent often because of the Kids Eat Free, I realized we should just order one coffee for the two of us. They leave a pot on the table and we can just take a turn drinking our cup while the other drinks their free water.
 
 
ADD YOUR COMMENT Cancel reply 
 The rules: Keep it clean, and stay on the subject - or we may delete your comment. If you see inappropriate language, e-mail us . An asterisk ( * ) indicates a required field. 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

 
 
 

 
 
 Save More with Daily Savings 
Sign up to receive updates with new deals and blog content become available.
 sending... 
 
   Facebook Twitter 
 
 
 Stretching a Buck Coupon Cravings Hip2Save Skimbaco Food Bargain Briana 
 See All More on ALL YOU 
 8 ways to spend less Lower your medical bills Save by paying your bills online Easy cupcake recipes 9 ways to earn money from home 
 Daily Savings Blog Archives 
 ﻿ All You 
AllYou.com

 Main Coupons&amp;Deals Food Budget Home Style for Less Diet&amp;Fitness Community Site Map 

Favorites

 Grocery Circular Roundup Sweepstakes&amp;Giveaways Daily Savings Blog Newsletters 

Popular Topics

 Free Samples Easy Appetizers Cheap Meals Cookies Grocery Store Coupon Policies Easter Crafts 

Magazine

 Subscribe to the Magazine Magazine Customer Service Where to Buy All You Affiliate Program Tablet Edition 

Learn More

 About Us Frequently Asked Questions Contact Us Advertise With Us From our Sponsors 

Community

 Become a fan of AllYou on Facebook Follow AllYou on Twitter Pinterest 
 
 A part of the MyRecipes Network Copyright©2012 
 Time Inc. Lifestyle Group.
 
 All Rights Reserved. Use of this site constitutes acceptance of our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy ( Your California Privacy Rights ). Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
