<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006169" url="http://5starcampgrounds.com/rainbow-lake-rv-park/" time="2012-07-12-22:51" support="3" score="0.004349612817920916" bingtitle="Rainbow Lake RV Park llc | 5 Star Campgrounds | RV Park Listings ..." webtitle="Rainbow Lake RV Park llc | 5 Star Campgrounds | RV Park Listings and Reviews">
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>... coupled with a variety of grocery, fast food, restaurant ... and children’s play area, picnic tables, barbecue area. Porter Park ... top (9,902 feet) is accessible by car ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 Privacy Policy 
 Add/Modify Campground Advertise Contact Us Help Us Improve 
 
Rainbow Lake RV Park
 
 Information Campgrounds near Rainbow Lake Campground Address: 2245 S 2000 West, Rexburg, ID, 83440 
 Rainbow Lake RV Park Western Wings Birds&amp;Clays RV Park Sheffield House RV Park Mountain River Ranch RV Park Jessen&apos;s RV Park Heise Hot Springs RV Camp 7 N Ranch Campground Snake River RV Park&amp;Campground 
 Phone Number: (208) 356-3681 Website: Rainbow Lake Campground Latitude   43.7942     Longitude   -111.81982     Campsite Information
 A green check-mark signifies service is available Site Quantity: 60 Pad Type: Gravel, Grass Price: $20 Night, $120 Week, $450 Month Quality: Good Campground / Average Value Electric 50 Amp Water Sewer Big Rig Access Tents Allowed Pull-thrus Group Area Handicap Access Waterfront Access Telephone Cable TV Amenities
 A green check-mark signifies service is available Store Laundry Pool Hot Tub Pet Friendly 55+ Park Game Room Playground Cabins Dump Station LP Gas Wi-Fi Customer Ratings of Rainbow Lake Campground GD Star Rating 
 loading... Select your Star rating above in each Category and Click &quot;Submit Your Rating&quot; Write a Review of your Visit of Rainbow Lake Campground. .   
Rainbow Lake Campground Details


 Rainbow Lake RV Park and Campground is the #1 Rated and Reviewed RV Park in Eastern Idaho and is just $20.00 a night for full hookups (unlimited). Rainbow Lake RV Park is close to Yellowstone National Park, Grand Teton National Park and Sun Valley. Rainbow Lake RV Park is just a few minutes from:  BYU Idaho, Yellowstone Bear World, an hour from beautiful Island Park, Henry&apos;s Lake , renowned Jackson Hole Wyoming and some of the Nation&apos;s best golf courses .

 Rainbow Lake has a 3/4 mile walking/nature path around the lake.  You may see creatures such as fish, otter, beaver, muskrat, moose, elk, raccoon, and two resident eagles.  One Bald Eagle and one Golden Eagle. Rainbow Lake RV Park is a quiet, well-located campground just off Hwy 20 Exit 332. Rainbow Lake Campground is convenient to shopping areas, schools, museums, historical sites and city parks. Located in Madison County, Rainbow Lake Campgroun d residents enjoy close proximity to BYU Idaho, Yellowstone Bear   World,Greater Yellowstone&apos;s only drive-through wildlife preserve. *We are within driving distance of a variety of outdoor pursuits such as fishing, hunting, hiking, bird watching and golfing. Our residents enjoy an onsite Laundromat, updated, showers, full hookups and free Internet access. Rainbow Lake Campground offers the convenience of being within a short drive to the major area events and attractions and welcomes RV’ers to our Park, whether for the long or short term. All sites pull-thru with Full hookups. Showers/Restrooms ·Free WiFi internet· Laundromat! · Dumpsters on site · Dump station on site · Bagged ice available for $2.00 per bag · Daily, weekly, monthly rates available · Cash, checks&amp;Credit Cards accepted 60 sites, 60 PullThru&apos;s, 50&apos; long, 30 amps All daily, weekly and monthly rates quoted above are all inclusive. Our guests enjoy power, water and sewer connections at each site as well as complimentary WIFI, use of facility restrooms, showers and nature path around lake. We have 50 pull thru sites and rarely get booked so reservations are normally not necessary, however Reservations are accepted through email or the contact form located on the “contact us” page of our web site. Big Rigs are welcome we can accommodate any size RV you have. We are working on upgrading several sites to 50-amp electricity but currently offer 30 amp hookups only. Discounts: We have made our rates affordable to pass the savings onto you.  At Rainbow Lake RV our rates are currently at or below most discount group or membership clubs so Passport America, Good Sam or any other discount memberships or discounts are no longer accepted. At Rainbow Lake RV Park we are trying to fully incorporate self registration in an effort to reduce operating and overhead costs which allows us to pass the savings onto our guests. Depending upon when you arrive, there may or may not be a host to greet you at the entrance.  In the event that there is not a host at the entrance or close by, please utilize our self-check in/registration form near the entrance.  You will have the option of submitting cash, check or credit card for payment.  There will be a laminated instruction sheet at the check in area. Our current rates for the 2011 season are $20.00 per night unlimited, $125.00 per week or $450.00 per month.  The all rates night include; water, sewer, 30 amp electricity and complementary Wi-Fi. We are currently in the process of making huge strides in improving our facilities and services. When you pull in you will see that all of our sites are pull-thru with the majority of them measuring 100 feet by 20 feet, fully capable of accommodating most recreational vehicle sizes and attachments. You will also enjoy new restrooms, showers and laundry facilities. We sincerely hope you enjoy your stay and ask this of you, if you see something we can improve please tell us. If you find your stay satisfactory, please tell everyone!!! 


Recreation near Rainbow Lake Campground


 Visit the Teton Flood Museum in Rexburg to relive the event. If you&apos;re visiting in August, don&apos;t miss the Idaho International Folk Dance Festival, a week-long event featuring the best dance groups from Europe, Asia, South America and the South Pacific. Rexburg is home to BYU-Idaho, a quiet private college with tree-lined campus streets and an ambiance going back to 1888. South of Rexburg, visit Yellowstone Bear World, Greater Yellowstone&apos;s only drive-through wildlife preserve. Enjoy seeing grizzly bear, black bear, gray wolves and many other North American wildlife all in their natural habitat. Experience Yellowstone&apos;s past with close-up views of these magnificent animals. Guided tours are available. An adventure you won&apos;t want to miss. ELEVATION: 4,865 Feet JANUARY (Coldest Month) 10.0º F POPULATION: 22,000 JULY (Hottest Month) 83.4º F CHAMBER OF COMMERCE / TOURIST INFORMATION CENTER: Open daily 9:00 a.m. – 4:00 p.m. – in association with the Cotton Tree Conference Center – Stop in for information about things to do and see in and around the area. Free local maps and brochures. AIRPORT: Lighted, paved runway, 4,200 feet with parking area, main hanger and shop with major and minor repairs, charter service, rentals and flight instruction. 80, 100 LL, jet A fuel available. 27 private hangers. CAMPING: Beaver Dick Park is located west of Rexburg, off State Highway 33 right after crossing the Henry’s Fork. Named in honor of an area pioneer, the park features children’s playground equipment, camping sites, picnic area and a dock. Twin Bridges, located south of Rexburg along the Archer Highway, has shaded picnic and camping facilities in a woodland setting. Information on many locally owned RV parks is available at the Chamber Office. CLUBS AND ORGANIZATIONS: Available in Rexburg are Rotary, Lions, Kiwanis, Soroptimists, American Legions, Veterans of Foreign Wars, Senior Citizen, Pink Ladies, Daughters of Utah Pioneers, Sons of Utah Pioneers and other civic clubs. IDAHO CENTENNIAL CAROUSEL: This 1926 Spillman Engineering Carousel was renovated in 1990 to commemorate Idaho’s 100th birthday. It has 12 newly carved horses and 26 repaired horses along with repaired chariots. Music is by Stinson Band Organ Company in Ohio. The organ runs on a paper roll, providing the old-fashioned original sounds. It is one of approximately 170 antique wooden carousels still existing in the United States. The carousel is housed in a new building at Porter Park. IDAHO INTERNATIONAL DANCE AND MUSIC FESTIVAL: Rexburg is the home of the Idaho International Dance and Music Festival. Each year, during the last week in July and the first week in August, dance teams from all over the world come to Rexburg. This festival is internationally acclaimed and is known as one of the finest dance and music festivals in the world. MADISON COUNTY FAIRGROUNDS: Home of the annual Whoopee Days and Madison County Fair with display buildings, arena, chutes and a new grandstand. RECREATIONAL ACTIVITIES: Skateboarding at Clair Boyle Skate Park, snowmobiling, swimming, water slide, bicycling, hiking, walking, camping, golfing, tennis, and racquetball are just a few of the many activities available in Rexburg. A wide selection of fishing streams and lakes are within easy access. REXBURG: Rexburg has many fine physicians, dentists, and a full-service hospital available. This, coupled with a variety of grocery, fast food, restaurant, gas stations, pharmacy and department stores, helps to meet any need that residents and visitors of Rexburg may have. REXBURG NATURE PARK: The Nature Park is a 15-acre park located near the fairgrounds on the west side of Rexburg. The park was created to provide an area for joggers and cyclists to exercise. Fishing ponds area available for everyone, one pond has been designated for children under 12 years of age, with special attention to the needs of handicapped individuals. POINTS OF INTEREST: Smith Park—Tennis courts, baseball diamonds, locomotive, gazebo and children’s play area, picnic tables, barbecue area. Porter Park – Tennis courts, baseball diamonds, carousel, waterslide, sand volleyball, covered picnic areas. BYU-IDAHO: Brigham Young University-Idaho, accommodates approximately 13,500 students per year. The university has an indoor and outdoor walking/jogging track, beautiful gardens, arboretum, large library and several fine arts theaters. BYU-Idaho is open to the public. SUNBIRD PROGRAM: Rexburg has the privilege of hosting approximately 1,800 Sunbirds (retired Seniors from the hot southern states) each year. The Sunbirds are invited to participate in the University Continuing Education Program, use the University Resource Library and their recreational facilities. TETON DAM FLOOD MUSEUM: Come visit the museum to find out more about the history of Rexburg. Many historical and educational displays. YELLOWSTONE BEAR WORLD: See bears and other animals roaming in a natural habitat. Drive through THEIR world for close-up encounters with these delightful, fun filled animals. 

 THINGS TO SEE AND DO NEAR REXBURG 

 BIG SPRINGS: This is where the Henry’s Fork of the Snake River rises to the surface. The springs are full of trout… but for looking only. Located about 65 miles north of Rexburg (5 miles east of Mack’s Inn). CAVE FALLS / BECHLER MEADOWS: The southwestern corner of Yellowstone can only be accessed through Idaho, via east of Ashton. The scenic, 28-mile drive leads to Cave Falls on the Fall River. CIVIL DEFENSE CAVES: Located about 30 miles northwest of Rexburg, look for the sign a few miles past the sand dunes. CRATERS OF THE MOON NATIONAL MONUMENT: This strange land was created, not by meteors, but by volcanoes and flowing lava. The desolate land is only 100 miles southwest of Rexburg. Visions of the moon only 1½ hours from Rexburg. GRAND TETON NATIONAL PARK: 100 miles east of Rexburg, the towering Tetons with Jenny Lake nestled beneath are one of the most magnificent sights in North America. Visit Teton Village and Jackson Lake and return over the fantastic mountain pass to Rexburg within 90 minutes. HARRIMAN STATE PARK: Known as the “Railroad Ranch”, the Park and surrounding Targhee National Forest comprise a 16,000-acre wildlife refuge. Located 18 miles north of Ashton, fishing is allowed and tours are offered. HENRY’S LAKE: A shallow lake known for producing big trout catches. Henry’s Lake is surrounded by lush meadowland and the towering Sawtooth Mountain Range. Located 60 miles northeast of Rexburg. HOT SPRINGS: Hot springs are operated commercially year round. One is at Green Canyon east of Rexburg off Highway 33; the other is 20 miles southeast of Rexburg at Heise and is reached via the Archer Highway. IDAHO FALLS LDS TEMPLE: The Temple itself is closed to the public, but there are guided tours of the grounds, located right by the falls…and visitors are welcome. Visitor’s center is located on the grounds. ISLAND PARK RESERVOIR: This lake, formed from the Henry’s Fork of the Snake River, is home of the infamous Island Park Rodeo…July 4th. It’s a beautiful lake surrounded by lodgepole pines, with fantastic fishing, located 60 miles north of Rexburg. JACKSON WYOMING: Located only 90 miles east of Rexburg, Jackson is the southern entrance to the Grand Teton National Park and a summer retreat for artists, artisans and actors. Visit the national elk refuge, go on a float trip, visit the ski resort, or ride the tram, winter or summertime, to over 10,000 feet. JEFFERSON COUNTY RECREATION LAKE: This Lake is located south of Rexburg off U.S. Highway 20. The man-made lake offers swimming, boating, picnic spots and a softball field. JOHNNY SACK CABIN: 65 miles north of Rexburg at Big Springs, this famous cabin is on the National Register of Historic Places. It has a visitor center and is open for tours during the summer. LAVA HOT SPRINGS: Soda Springs: Located 100 miles south of Rexburg on the Portneuf River, these springs contain more minerals than any other hot springs in North America. The 22 minerals in the baths at the resort are claimed to have medicinal powers. MESA FALLS SCENIC BYWAY: Highway 47 east of Ashton as been designated a scenic route. The highlights are Upper and Lower Mesa Falls, where the Henry’s Fork of the Snake River plunges through a deep, rocky canyon over 114’ and 65’ drops. The upper falls can be reached via a well-maintained road. The lower calls are accessible via a tail only. Located about 35 miles north of Rexburg. Excellent viewing area from the Upper Falls. MOUNT SAWTELLE: The top (9,902 feet) is accessible by car during the summer, affording a spectacular view of three states and Yellowstone National Park. Wildflowers are abundant on Sawtelle. SAND CREEK WILDLIFE MANAGEMENT AREA AND RESORT: Located 17 miles north of St. Anthony at the end of the Sand Creek Road, the Wildlife Management Area offers a close-up view of sand hills, cranes, swans and an occasional moose and deer. Campgrounds are available, excellent fishing. SKI RESORTS: Grand Targhee Ski Resort and Kelly Canyon Ski Resort: At most, one hour from Rexburg. Needless to say, skiing is a popular sport in this area. In the summertime, just visiting the resorts and riding the lifts to the tops of the peaks can be exhilarating. ST. ANTHONY’S SAND DUNES: Located just 15 miles north of Rexburg is Idaho’s miniature Sahara, one-to-five miles wide and 35 miles long. The sand dunes are 10 to 100 feet high and are particularly beautiful when the sun sets over them. SUN VALLEY-KETCHUM: One of America’s foremost ski resorts, Sun Valley takes on a whole new dimension in the summertime with ice skating, golf, swimming, horseback riding, and tennis…not to mention Sun Valley Village. Located 150 miles west of Idaho Falls, about 3½ hours from Rexburg. TETON DAM SITE: Site of Teton Dam can be reached 15 miles northeast of Rexburg on Highway 33. The paved road is marked and informational signs tell the story of the 1976 Teton Dam flood. YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK: The first of the national parks, Yellowstone was discovered and explored in 1808 by John Colter, formerly of the Lewis and Clark expedition. Only a few of the spectacular attractions are: Old Faithful, the Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone, Devil’s Grotto, Yellowstone Lake, and Mammoth Hot Springs. The park’s west entrance, West Yellowstone, is a frontier town located 75 miles north of Rexburg…just over one hour away. 


Directions to Rainbow Lake Campground


 Take Highway 20, exit 332. From exit 332 turn West on University then immediately South on 12th Street. Go South on 12 th Street 1.5 miles and look for Rainbow Lake RV Park on the Right. 

 If your going South on Hwy 20: 

 Take exit 332 and turn right onto University Blvd. Turn left onto 12th Street. 

 If your going North on Hwy 20: 

 Take exit 332 turn left onto University Blvd. Turn left again onto 12th Street. 

 
Photo Gallery

 Rainbow Lake RV Park | Rexburg, ID Rainbow Lake RV Park | Rexburg, ID 
 
 
Video Gallery
 . 
 
 Tweet 
 Rainbow Lake RV Park , 4.7 out of 5 based on 1 rating 
 You can follow any responses to this RV Park/Campground through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 
 Guest Reviews 
 
 Comments 
 
One Response to Rainbow Lake RV Park 

 Reply 
We recently stayed at rainbow lake and were extremely impressed with the helpful and friendly nature of the owners/managers. There was no one at the office when we arrived but there was a sign that said self register and pick your own site. We did just that and a little while later the owner comes up not to ask if we registered or payed but to see if we would like a picnic table or if there was anything we needed. We not only registered but stayed a few days because we were so impressessed with the area and the laundry/restroom facilities. We were allowed to take up two spaces and though we were close to the highway we hardly noticed since the trees are large and mature. Everything is on your honor rather than coin operated. We loved our stay and plan to stay again next year.
 GD Star Rating 
 loading... Dee Anderson    October 11, 2011 at 2:03 am 
 Click on a tab to select how you&apos;d like to leave your comment 
 WordPress Twitter Facebook Google 
 Login Login Login 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Search 5 Star Campgrounds
 Loading 

 
Search by Location
 within 5 10 25 50 Miles of 
 

 
 
Recent Reviews

 Joy Anthony on Help Us Improve Danielle on Nason Creek Campground L.M. on Bidwell Canyon Campground Buffalo Bob&apos;s RV Park on Buffalo Bob’s R.V. Park lee davis on Bow and Arrow Campground 
 

 
Pages

 About 
 Contact Us Privacy Policy 
 Add/Modify Campground Advertise Campsite Definitions Help Us Improve Marketplace 
 
Popular Subjects
 California State Park Campgrounds in Alaska Campgrounds in Alberta Campgrounds in Arizona Campgrounds in California Campgrounds in Canada Campgrounds in Colorado Campgrounds in Florida Campgrounds in Indiana Campgrounds in Kansas Campgrounds in Maryland Campgrounds in Mesa Campgrounds in Minnesota Campgrounds in Myers Campgrounds in Nebraska Campgrounds in Nevada Campgrounds in New Brunswick Campgrounds in New Jersey Campgrounds in New Mexico Campgrounds in New York Campgrounds in North Carolina Campgrounds in Ohio Campgrounds in Ontario Campgrounds in Pennsylvania Campgrounds in South Dakota Campgrounds in Texas Campgrounds in Tucson Campgrounds in Utah Campgrounds in Washington Campgrounds in Yuma Casino Camping Coast to Coast Classic Coast to Coast Deluxe Escapees Club Good Sam Jellystone Park KOA Nebraska State Park news Ohio State Park Passport America Pennsylvania State Park Resort Parks International Resorts of Distinction Washington State Park 
Sign up for our mailing list.
 First Name : 
 Last Name : 
 Email Address : 

 


 
 Copyright©2012 5 Star Campgrounds | RV Park Listings and Reviews . All Rights Reserved.
 Site Developed by Ballyhoo4U
	</body>
</document>
