<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006398" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Order_of_the_Straight_Arrow_(King_of_the_Hill)" time="2012-07-12-23:16" support="3" score="0.013905201389413155" bingtitle="List of King of the Hill episodes - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia" webtitle="List of King of the Hill episodes - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>To pay off her credit card debts, Luanne signs up to be a roller derby girl. ... Bobby convinces the student council to put on a carnival, and he is put in charge ...</description>
	<body>
		List of King of the Hill episodes 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia (Redirected from The Order of the Straight Arrow (King of the Hill) ) Jump to: navigation , search 
 This article needs additional citations for verification . Please help improve this article by adding citations to reliable sources . Unsourced material may be challenged and removed . (June 2012) 

This is a list of episodes of the Fox animated television series King of the Hill . The series was originally broadcast from January 12, 1997, to May 6, 2010.

 
Contents
 
 1 Seasons 2 Episodes 
 2.1 Season 1: 1997 2.2 Season 2: 1997–1998 2.3 Season 3: 1998–1999 2.4 Season 4: 1999–2000 2.5 Season 5: 2000–2001 2.6 Season 6: 2001–2002 2.7 Season 7: 2002–2003 2.8 Season 8: 2003–2004 2.9 Season 9: 2004–2005 2.10 Season 10: 2005–2006 2.11 Season 11: 2007 2.12 Season 12: 2007–2008 2.13 Season 13: 2008–2009; 2010 
 3 References 
 

 [ edit ] Seasons 
 See also: King of the Hill DVDs 
 
Season
 # of
Episodes Originally aired Prod. line DVD releases 1 12 1997 4Exx R1: July 1, 2003
R2: March 13, 2006
R4: March 15, 2006 2 23 1997 – 1998 5Exx R1: November 11, 2003
R2: March 13, 2006
R4: May 23, 2006 3 25 1998 – 1999 3ABExx R1: December 28, 2004
R2: August 28, 2006
R4: September 26, 2006 4 24 1999 – 2000 4ABExx R1: May 3, 2005
R2: January 15, 2007
R4: June 20, 2007 5 20 2000 – 2001 5ABExx R1: November 22, 2005
R2: February 26, 2007
R4: April 23, 2008 6 22 2001 – 2002 6ABExx R1: May 2, 2006 7 23 2002 – 2003 7ABExx -- 8 22 2003 – 2004 8ABExx -- 9 15 2004 – 2005 9ABExx -- 10 15 2005 – 2006 AABExx -- 11 12 2007 BABExx -- 12 22 2007 – 2008 CABExx -- 13 24 2008 – 2010 DABExx -- 

 [ edit ] Episodes 

 No. = Overall episode number # = Episode number within the season 

 [ edit ] Season 1: 1997 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 1 1 &quot;Pilot&quot; Wes Archer Mike Judge &amp; Greg Daniels January 12, 1997  ( 1997-01-12 ) 4E01 When a baseball hits Bobby in the eye during a Little League game, the resulting black eye and Hank&apos;s short temper (from dealing with a teenaged Mega-Lo-Mart clerk) cause a social worker to suspect Hank of child abuse . Meanwhile, Hank&apos;s friends, cuckolded conspiracy nut Dale Gribble , down-and-out Army barber Bill Dauterive , and fast-talking womanizer Jeff Boomhauer , try to fix Hank&apos;s truck, while Luanne Platter moves in with the Hills after her trailer trash parents get sent to jail over a domestic disturbance.  2 2 &quot;Square Peg&quot; Gary McCarver Joe Stillman January 19, 1997  ( 1997-01-19 ) 4E02 Peggy is mortified and tongue-tied when she finds out she has been chosen to teach the middle school&apos;s sexual education class.  3 3 &quot;The Order of the Straight Arrow&quot; Klay Hall Cheryl Holliday February 2, 1997  ( 1997-02-02 ) 4E03 Hank, Bill, Dale, and Boomhauer take Bobby and his friends on an Order of the Straight Arrow camping trip where the men send the boys on a snipe hunt...and Bobby ends up killing a whooping crane . Meanwhile, Peggy sneaks out to buy special shoes for her large feet.  4 4 &quot;Hank&apos;s Got the Willies&quot; Monte Young Johnny Hardwick February 9, 1997  ( 1997-02-09 ) 4E05 Hank is worried that Bobby does not have a role model in life—and things get worse when Bobby accidentally hits Hank&apos;s idol, Willie Nelson (voiced by Nelson himself) with a golf club during a day on the green.  5 5 &quot;Luanne&apos;s Saga&quot; Pat Shinagawa Paul Lieberstein February 16, 1997  ( 1997-02-16 ) 4E04 When Buckley breaks up with Luanne and Luanne goes on a days-long crying jag, Hank sets out to find Luanne a new boyfriend (guest-voiced by Mando Navarro) in forty-eight hours—which backfires when Hank sees Luanne with Boomhauer.
Chuck Mangione also guest stars.  6 6 &quot;Hank&apos;s Unmentionable Problem&quot; Adam Kuhlman Mike Judge&amp;Greg Daniels February 23, 1997  ( 1997-02-23 ) 4E07 Hank&apos;s ongoing constipation causes great concern for Peggy and, much to Hank&apos;s embarrassment, everyone else in Arlen.  7 7 &quot;Westie Side Story&quot; Brian Sheesley Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger March 2, 1997  ( 1997-03-02 ) 4E06 Hank&apos;s attempt to be neighborly with the new Laotian family next door is sorely tested when his new neighbor treats him rudely, and even more so when Dale leads him to believe that his neighbor served him hamburgers made from dog meat.  8 8 &quot;Shins of the Father&quot; Martin Archer Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland March 23, 1997  ( 1997-03-23 ) 4E08 Hank&apos;s brash, sexist father, Cotton Hill, crashes Bobby&apos;s 12th birthday party—and stays over the Hills&apos; house, which does not sit well with Peggy when Cotton&apos;s misogyny begins rubbing off on Bobby.  9 9 &quot;Peggy the Boggle Champ&quot; Chuck Sheetz Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger April 13, 1997  ( 1997-04-13 ) 4E09 Hank&apos;s promise to coach Peggy at the Texas State Boggle Championship is jeopardized when his buddies try to lure him away to the Ninth Annual Dallas Mower Expo. Meanwhile, Bobby and Luanne freak out when they leave a condensation ring on the new coffee table, but their efforts to fix it cause even more trouble.  10 10 &quot;Keeping Up With Our Joneses&quot; John Rice Jonathan Collier &amp;Joe Stillman April 27, 1997  ( 1997-04-27 ) 4E10 When Hank catches Bobby smoking a cigarette in a gas station bathroom, Hank punishes him by making his son smoke an entire carton, but the plan backfires when Bobby, Hank, and Peggy all become addicted.  11 11 &quot;King of the Ant Hill&quot; Gary McCarver Johnny Hardwick&amp;Paul Lieberstein May 4, 1997  ( 1997-05-04 ) 4E13 After telling Dale never to spray insecticide on his lawn again, Hank&apos;s expensive new lawn becomes mysteriously infested with fire ants.  12 12 &quot;Plastic White Female&quot; Jeff Myers David Zuckerman May 11, 1997  ( 1997-05-11 ) 4E11 Bobby is invited to his first boy/girl party, and Peggy is horrified when she discovers him playing Spin the Bottle with one of Luanne&apos;s plastic beauty school heads.  

 [ edit ] Season 2: 1997–1998 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 13 1 &quot;How to Fire a Rifle Without Really Trying&quot; Adam Kuhlman Paul Lieberstein September 21, 1997  ( 1997-09-21 ) 5E01 When Bobby displays a talent for target shooting, Hank signs up for a father–son fun shoot competition—only to discover a buried childhood memory is still sadly affecting his aim.  14 2 &quot;Texas City Twister&quot; Jeff Myers Cheryl Holliday September 28, 1997  ( 1997-09-28 ) 5E02 Hank must save Peggy and Luanne from a tornado after he regrets not showing remorse for throwing Luanne out of the house and moving her back to the trailer that she moved out of after her mother tried to kill her father. Rated TV-PG-DL.  15 3 &quot;The Arrow Head&quot; Klay Hall Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger October 19, 1997  ( 1997-10-19 ) 5E04 Peggy&apos;s excitement over finding Indian artifacts in the front yard distresses Hank when a condescending university professor tricks Peggy into letting him dig in the Hills&apos; yard. Rated TV-PG-DL.  16 4 &quot;Hilloween&quot; John Rice David Zuckerman October 26, 1997  ( 1997-10-26 ) 5E06 Hank goes to war with a litigious Evangelical Christian woman (voice of Sally Field ) bent on banning Halloween and indoctrinating the kids by inviting them to a hell house . Rated TV-PG-DL.  17 5 &quot;Jumpin&apos; Crack Bass (It&apos;s a Gas, Gas, Gas)&quot; Gary McCarver Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland November 2, 1997  ( 1997-11-02 ) 5E03 Hank finds himself facing possible jail time after mistakenly buying crack cocaine to use as fish bait. Rated TV-PG-DL.  18 6 &quot;Husky Bobby&quot; Martin Archer Jonathan Collier November 9, 1997  ( 1997-11-09 ) 5E05 Hank is determined to save his son from humiliation after Bobby decides to model for a husky boy clothing line. Rated TV-PG-DL.  19 7 &quot;The Man Who Shot Cane Skretteberg&quot; Monte Young Johnny Hardwick November 16, 1997  ( 1997-11-16 ) 5E07 Hank, Boomhauer, Bill and Dale face off in a paintball war against the teenage members of a garage band (guest-voiced by the members of Green Day ).  20 8 &quot;The Son That Got Away&quot; Tricia Garcia Jim Dauterive November 23, 1997  ( 1997-11-23 ) 5E08 Bobby, Connie and Joseph run away to &quot;The Caves&quot;, where &quot;half of Arlen&apos;s unplanned pregnancies begin,&quot; after each of them gets in trouble at school for disrupting class. Rated TV-PG-DL.  21 9 &quot;The Company Man&quot; Klay Hall Jim Dauterive December 7, 1997  ( 1997-12-07 ) 4E12 
When a new housing development is in need of a propane supplier, Buck instructs Hank to show the owner, an obnoxious Northerner who acts like a Southerner, a good time. However, Hank is none too thrilled to learn that this will require him to act like a cowboy stereotype . Rated TV-PG-DLSV.

 Note : This episode is included on the Season 1 DVD set due to its production code.  22 10 &quot;Bobby Slam&quot; Chris Moeller Gina Fattore December 14, 1997  ( 1997-12-14 ) 5E10 Hank is delighted when Bobby announces he is joining the school wrestling team, but Peggy is mortified when she learns her son must first wrestle Connie in order to make the team. Rated TV-PG-L.  23 11 &quot;The Unbearable Blindness of Laying&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Paul Lieberstein December 21, 1997  ( 1997-12-21 ) 5E09 In this first Christmas episode, Hank is psychologically shocked into blindness after accidentally catching a glimpse of his mother and her new Jewish boyfriend (voiced by Carl Reiner ) having sex on Hank&apos;s kitchen table.  24 12 &quot;Meet the Manger Babies&quot; Jeff Myers Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger January 11, 1998  ( 1998-01-11 ) 5E12 Hank faces a dilemma of Biblical proportions when Luanne asks him to portray God in a live TV broadcast of her Christian puppet show, which is scheduled to occur during Hank&apos;s beloved Super Bowl party.  25 13 &quot;Snow Job&quot; Adam Kuhlman Cheryl Holliday and Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland and Jim Dauterive February 1, 1998  ( 1998-02-01 ) 5E11 During a snow storm, a shaken and confused Hank becomes disillusioned about his life and career after discovering that Buck Strickland does not use a propane stove in his house and doesn&apos;t even share Hank&apos;s passion for propane.  26 14 &quot;I Remember Mono&quot; Wes Archer Paul Lieberstein February 8, 1998  ( 1998-02-08 ) 5E13 While updating files at Arlen High School, Peggy learns that Hank&apos;s two-week absence from classes during their high school days was due to mononucleosis , not a back injury, and is crushed that what was a romantic story of young love is now a lie. Rated TV-PG-DL.  27 15 &quot;Three Days of the Kahndo&quot; Lauren MacMullan John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky February 15, 1998  ( 1998-02-15 ) 5E15 Kahn&apos;s misreading of an advertisement for a Mexican time share results in him, Hank, and Dale getting trapped in Mexico. Rated TV-PG-DL.  28 16 &quot;Traffic Jam&quot; Klay Hall Johnny Hardwick February 22, 1998  ( 1998-02-22 ) 5E14 
When Hank and Kahn collide with each other&apos;s cars, they are both forced to attend traffic school courses taught by a raunchy black comedian (voiced by Chris Rock ), who begins mentoring Bobby in the art of stand-up. Rated TV-PG-DL.

 Note : Originally, Buddha Sack&apos;s name was to be &quot;Busta Nut&quot;, but the FOX censors objected. The name was then changed to Busta Sack, but this name was also rejected by the FOX censors. [ citation needed ]   29 17 &quot;Hank&apos;s Dirty Laundry&quot; Shaun Cashman Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger March 1, 1998  ( 1998-03-01 ) 5E16 While purchasing a new dryer, Hank discovers that his credit is bad, thanks to a video store clerk who accuses Hank of renting a pornographic video and never returning it.  30 18 &quot;The Final Shinsult&quot; Jack Dyer Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland March 15, 1998  ( 1998-03-15 ) 5E17 After losing his driver&apos;s license, Cotton moves in with Dale and plots to steal Antonio López de Santa Anna &apos;s wooden leg from a museum to use as a bargaining chip with the DMV. Rated TV-PG-DL.  31 19 &quot;Leanne&apos;s Saga&quot; Tricia Garcia David Zuckerman April 19, 1998  ( 1998-04-19 ) 5E18 Luanne&apos;s alcoholic mother is released from prison and starts dating Bill, whom she begins to abuse. Rated TV-PG-DLSV.  32 20 &quot;Junkie Business&quot; Cyndi Tang-Loveland Jim Dauterive April 26, 1998  ( 1998-04-26 ) 5E19 Strickland Propane&apos;s new employee (whom Hank hired because he preferred a man over the qualified woman who applied) turns out to be a drug addict who uses a legal trick that frees him from responsibility on the job and from being fired. Rated TV-PG-LS.  33 21 &quot;Life in the Fast Lane – Bobby&apos;s Saga&quot; Adam Kuhlman John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky May 3, 1998  ( 1998-05-03 ) 5E21 Bobby gets a job as a concession boy at the Arlen race track, where he discovers that his boss is a mildly retarded sociopath (voice of David Herman ). Hank pays very little attention to Bobby&apos;s horror stories until he witnesses the mistreatment firsthand. Meanwhile, Boomhauer is given the chance to drive the pace car in an upcoming race. Seven-time NASCAR Winston Cup Series champion Dale Earnhardt, Sr. guest appears in the episode. In real life, Earnhardt Sr. never won a NASCAR race held in the state of Texas during his career.  34 22 &quot;Peggy&apos;s Turtle Song&quot; Jeff Myers Brent Forrester May 10, 1998  ( 1998-05-10 ) 5E22 When Bobby is misdiagnosed with attention deficit disorder (after eating too much sugary cereal and disrupting class), Peggy quits her job as a substitute teacher and becomes a stay-at-home mom, but soon realizes that she needs a hobby for her newfound time and begins taking guitar lessons. Rated TV-PG-DL.  35 23 &quot; Propane Boom &quot; (Part 1) Gary McCarver Norm Hiscock May 17, 1998  ( 1998-05-17 ) 5E23 
Part one of two. Strickland Propane experiences discontinuation from business after the wholesale of economical propane from Mega Lo Mart, rendering Hank unemployed and forcing him to collude in a plot to disrupt a publicity stunt.
 Note : Sometimes, this and &quot;Death of a Propane Salesman&quot; are aired as an hour-long episode.  

 [ edit ] Season 3: 1998–1999 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 36 1 &quot; Death of a Propane Salesman &quot; (Part 2) Lauren MacMullan Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland September 15, 1998  ( 1998-09-15 ) 5E24 Conclusion. The aftermath of the propane explosion from part one leaves Hank suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder around propane, a now bald Luanne repressing her grief for Buckley (who was the only casualty in the propane explosion) by becoming a Sinéad O&apos;Connor -esque activist, and Bobby worried about death.  37 2 &quot;And They Call It Bobby Love&quot; Cyndi Tang-Loveland Norm Hiscock September 22, 1998  ( 1998-09-22 ) 3ABE01 Bobby falls in love with a 14-year old classmate (guest-voiced by Sarah Michelle Gellar ), but soon learns that love hurts when the girl confesses that she only wants a platonic friend. Meanwhile, Hank, Dale, Bill, and Boomhauer become attached to a couch that was thrown out in the Hills&apos; yard.  38 3 &quot;Peggy&apos;s Headache&quot; Chris Moeller Joe Stillman October 6, 1998  ( 1998-10-06 ) 5E20 Peggy gets hired to write for the Arlen Bystander , but the stress of a new career leads her to require treatment from John Redcorn—and she soon discovers that John Redcorn had an affair with Nancy and is Joseph&apos;s biological father. Rated TV-PG-DL.  39 4 &quot;Pregnant Paws&quot; Chris Moeller Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger October 13, 1998  ( 1998-10-13 ) 3ABE02 
While Hank is busy trying to breed Ladybird, Dale decides to add a little excitement to his life by enrolling in a 4-hour bounty hunter training course.
 Special Guest Voice : William H. Macy   40 5 &quot;Next of Shin&quot; Jeff Myers Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland November 3, 1998  ( 1998-11-03 ) 3ABE05 After Hank learns his sperm count is low, his mood worsens when Cotton shows up boasting that his new wife Didi is pregnant.  41 6 &quot;Peggy&apos;s Pageant Fever&quot; Tricia Garcia Norm Hiscock November 10, 1998  ( 1998-11-10 ) 3ABE07 Peggy enters the Mrs. Heimlich County Beauty pageant in hopes of winning a truck, but quickly discovers that she is not fit to compete with the other contestants.  42 7 &quot;Nine Pretty Darn Angry Men&quot; Shaun Cashman Jim Dauterive November 17, 1998  ( 1998-11-17 ) 3ABE08 
While shopping at the mall on the Friday after Thanksgiving, Hank, Dale, Bill, Kahn, and Boomhauer are invited to be part of a focus group for a new mower (with Cotton as an uninvited guest), Luanne goes ice skating to forget about Buckley, and Peggy falls asleep at a shoe repair shop after tearing her loafer.
 Special Guest Voice : Billy Bob Thornton   43 8 &quot;Good Hill Hunting&quot; Klay Hall Joe Stillman December 1, 1998  ( 1998-12-01 ) 3ABE04 Hank takes Bobby hunting in order to initiate him into the mysteries of manhood. However, everything goes wrong when Hank discovers that it is too late for him to get a hunting license.  44 9 &quot;Pretty, Pretty Dresses&quot; Dominic Polcino Paul Lieberstein December 15, 1998  ( 1998-12-15 ) 3ABE10 In this second Christmas episode, Bill becomes more depressed than usual. Hank, Dale, and Boomhauer decide to watch Bill in case he threatens to commit suicide , but when Hank yells at him for being a burden, Bill&apos;s depression turns into delusion when he begins dressing in drag and impersonating his estranged wife, Lenore.  45 10 &quot;A-Firefighting We Will Go&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland January 12, 1999  ( 1999-01-12 ) 3ABE11 In a Rashomon -style story, Hank, Dale, Bill, and Boomhauer tell their own versions of their day as firefighters after getting arrested for burning the firehouse to the ground. Meanwhile, Peggy pulls a groin muscle and Bobby helps her recover.  46 11 &quot;To Spank with Love&quot; Adam Kuhlman David Zuckerman January 19, 1999  ( 1999-01-19 ) 3ABE03 Peggy gains a reputation as an abusive disciplinarian when she spanks Dooley for humiliating her during class.  47 12 &quot;Three Coaches and a Bobby&quot; Chris Moeller Johnny Hardwick January 26, 1999  ( 1999-01-26 ) 3ABE12 Hank gets his hard-knocks former high-school football coach to take on guidance of Bobby&apos;s football team, but the plan falls apart when Bobby joins the soccer team headed by a politically correct coach (voiced by Will Ferrell ). Meanwhile, Hank realizes that his former coach is a lot more erratic than he remembers.  48 13 &quot;De-Kahnstructing Henry&quot; Klay Hall Paul Lieberstein February 2, 1999  ( 1999-02-02 ) 3ABE14 Hank accidentally gets Kahn fired after revealing one of Kahn&apos;s top secret plans for his company. Kahn eventually abandons his family, leaving Hank to fix the mess.  49 14 &quot;The Wedding of Bobby Hill&quot; Jack Dyer Jonathan Collier February 9, 1999  ( 1999-02-09 ) 3ABE09 
To teach Bobby and Luanne a lesson in playing pranks, Hank orders Bobby to marry Luanne after Bobby takes her birth control pills.
 Special Guest Voice : Matthew McConaughey   50 15 &quot;Sleight of Hank&quot; Jeff Myers Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger February 16, 1999  ( 1999-02-16 ) 3ABE15 Peggy is chosen to be a magician &apos;s assistant, but angers Hank when she will not tell him the secret behind one of his tricks.  51 16 &quot;Return to La Grunta&quot; Gary McCarver Jon Vitti February 23, 1999  ( 1999-02-23 ) 3ABE06 Luanne gets a job as a drink girl at a resort called &quot;La Grunta&quot;, where the golfers sexually harass her. Meanwhile, Hank goes to La Grunta to swim with the dolphins—and gets molested by one of them.  52 17 &quot;Escape from Party Island&quot; Gary McCarver Jonathan Collier March 16, 1999  ( 1999-03-16 ) 3ABE16 
Hank reluctantly drives his mother and her friends to Port Aransas to shop for glass miniatures, but things get even worse when Hank and the rude old women are trapped on the island by college-age spring break revelers.

 Guest voices : Phyllis Diller , Uta Hagen , Pauly Shore and Betty White .  53 18 &quot;Love Hurts and So Does Art&quot; Adam Kuhlman John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky March 23, 1999  ( 1999-03-23 ) 3ABE13 An X-ray of Hank&apos;s colon from &quot;Hank&apos;s Unmentionable Problem&quot; winds up as the main attraction in an art museum. Meanwhile, Bobby is diagnosed with gout after eating chicken livers at a recently opened &quot; New York &quot; style deli.  54 19 &quot;Hank&apos;s Cowboy Movie&quot; Shaun Cashman Jim Dauterive April 6, 1999  ( 1999-04-06 ) 3ABE18 Hurt by Bobby&apos;s negative views of his hometown, Hank tries to get the Dallas Cowboys to move their training camp from Wichita Falls to Arlen. However, his promotion video for Arlen is ruined by his wife&apos;s and his friends&apos; incompetence.  55 20 &quot;Dog Dale Afternoon&quot; Tricia Garcia Jon Vitti April 13, 1999  ( 1999-04-13 ) 3ABE22 After Dale annoys his friends by gloating over his new mower, he goes insane when they steal it as part of a prank.  56 21 &quot;Revenge of the Lutefisk&quot; Jack Dyer Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger April 20, 1999  ( 1999-04-20 ) 3ABE19 
Bobby accidentally burns down his church after getting sick from eating lutefisk , but Cotton gets blamed for it due to his sexist attitude towards the church accepting a female pastor.
 Special Guest Voice : Mary Tyler Moore   57 22 &quot;Death and Texas&quot; Wes Archer John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky April 27, 1999  ( 1999-04-27 ) 3ABE20 Peggy visits a convict who tricks her into thinking he was a former student and uses her as a cocaine mule.  58 23 &quot;Wings of the Dope&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Johnny Hardwick May 4, 1999  ( 1999-05-04 ) 3ABE21 Hank Hill gets a trampoline for his yard, where Luanne begins seeing the spirit of her dead boyfriend, Buckley, who tries to guide her to do something better with her life than attend beauty school. The episode also contains the song Life in a Northern Town by English Rock group The Dream Academy .  59 24 &quot;Take Me out of the Ball Game&quot; Tricia Garcia Jon Vitti May 11, 1999  ( 1999-05-11 ) 3ABE17 Hank is picked to coach the company&apos;s softball team, spurring friction between Peggy and Hank.  60 25 &quot;As Old as the Hills (part 1)&quot; Adam Kuhlman Norm Hiscock May 18, 1999  ( 1999-05-18 ) 3ABE23 Part one of two. Fearing that they may be getting too old to be &quot;cool&quot;, Hank and Peggy spend their anniversary sky-diving, which comes to an abrupt end when Peggy&apos;s parachute malfunctions and she crashes onto a field. Meanwhile, Bobby struggles with taking his pregnant step-grandmother Didi to the hospital when her water breaks.  

 [ edit ] Season 4: 1999–2000 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 61 1 &quot;Peggy Hill: The Decline and Fall (part 2)&quot; Klay Hall Paul Lieberstein September 26, 1999  ( 1999-09-26 ) 3ABE24 Conclusion. Peggy struggles to regain her strength following her skydiving accident. Meanwhile, Bobby delivers Cotton&apos;s son (whom Cotton names &quot;Good Hank&quot;) but gets overwhelmed when neither Cotton nor Didi embrace new parenthood.  62 2 &quot;Cotton&apos;s Plot&quot; Anthony Lioi Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger October 3, 1999  ( 1999-10-03 ) 4ABE01 Cotton takes over Peggy&apos;s physical therapy in exchange for help getting a burial plot in the Texas State Cemetery , but Peggy discovers a discrepancy about Cotton&apos;s service in the Army during World War II.  63 3 &quot;Bills Are Made to Be Broken&quot; Jeff Myers John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky October 24, 1999  ( 1999-10-24 ) 4ABE02 Bill&apos;s high school football record is broken unfairly, and (largely at Hank&apos;s insistence) he tries to get back on the field to set things right.  64 4 &quot;Little Horrors of Shop&quot; Adam Kuhlman Kit Boss October 31, 1999  ( 1999-10-31 ) 4ABE03 Buck Strickland insists that Hank take two weeks off from Strickland Propane, and Hank begins teaching wood shop at Tom Landry Middle School , and becomes so popular that Peggy grows envious of him. However, Hank gets in trouble for violating the school&apos;s zero-tolerance policy on weapons when he asks his students to bring in tools from home.  65 5 &quot;Aisle 8A&quot; Allan Jacobsen Garland Testa November 7, 1999  ( 1999-11-07 ) 4ABE04 Kahn and Minh go to Hawaii for Kahn&apos;s job and asks Hank to take care of Connie, who&apos;s excited that she will be staying with Bobby, but becomes emotional and mean-spirited when she gets her first period , leaving an extremely uncomfortable Hank to both deal with the unstable Connie and have to explain &quot;the birds and the bees&quot; to Bobby (who has no idea why Connie is so emotional).  66 6 &quot;A Beer Can Named Desire&quot; Chuck Austen &amp;Chris Moeller Jim Dauterive November 14, 1999  ( 1999-11-14 ) 4ABE05 
Hank wins an Alamo Beer contest for a chance to win a million dollars by throwing a football through a one-foot hole in a giant Alamo Beer can, while Bill visits his eccentric Cajun relatives in Louisiana.
 Guest voices : Don Meredith , Meryl Streep , The Dixie Chicks ( Martie Maguire , Natalie Maines , and Emily Robison ).  67 7 &quot;Happy Hank&apos;s Giving&quot; Martin Archer Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland November 21, 1999  ( 1999-11-21 ) 4ABE08 The Hills plan to fly to Montana for Thanksgiving, but are stranded with their neighbors at the airport by a snowstorm.
 Amanda Mealing guest stars.  68 8 &quot;Not in My Back-hoe&quot; Shaun Cashman Paul Lieberstein November 28, 1999  ( 1999-11-28 ) 4ABE06 Drew Carey guest stars as a man who befriends Hank Hill after the two discover that they are very much alike. Meanwhile, Bill and Dale steal Hank&apos;s backhoe and take it to a pet cemetery, with disastrous results.  69 9 &quot;To Kill a Ladybird&quot; Wes Archer Norm Hiscock December 12, 1999  ( 1999-12-12 ) 4ABE07 Dale and Ladybird may have contracted rabies from a raccoon Bobby befriended.  70 10 &quot;Hillennium&quot; Tricia Garcia Johnny Hardwick December 19, 1999  ( 1999-12-19 ) 4ABE10 As Christmas approaches, Hank gets irritated over everyone panicking about the supposed technological apocalypse that will purportedly happen on January 1, 2000, due to the Y2K computer date glitch—but soon finds himself trying to safeguard his family after a propane shortage.  71 11 &quot;Old Glory&quot; Gary McCarver Norm Hiscock January 9, 2000  ( 2000-01-09 ) 4ABE09 Peggy writes a school essay for Bobby, and they both catch fire for it by a vengeful English teacher who accuses them of plagiarism . Meanwhile, Hank and his friends try to get rid of an oversized American flag.  72 12 &quot;Rodeo Days&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Jon Vitti January 16, 2000  ( 2000-01-16 ) 4ABE11 When the rodeo comes to Arlen, Bobby tries his hand at cattle roping; when he fails miserably, he takes his career in the other direction, choosing to become a rodeo clown , much to Hank and Peggy&apos;s dismay.  73 13 &quot; Hanky Panky &quot; (Part 1) Jeff Myers Jim Dauterive February 6, 2000  ( 2000-02-06 ) 4ABE13 Part one of two. When Buck Strickland and his wife Miz Liz separate, and Buck dumps his secretary/mistress Debbie Grund, Hank ends up getting seduced by Miz Liz — and Debbie Grund ends up dead and in the dumpster behind Sugarfoot&apos;s Barbecue, which Peggy has been granted proprietorship of.  74 14 &quot; High Anxiety &quot; (Part 2) Adam Kuhlman Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland February 13, 2000  ( 2000-02-13 ) 4ABE14 Conclusion. As Peggy&apos;s experiment as the owner of Sugarfoot&apos;s (renaming it Peggy&apos;s Sugarfoot&apos;s) goes awry, Hank talks to Buck&apos;s computer-geek/stoner roommate — and, as a result of unwittingly trying a cannabis joint he offers him, becomes a suspect in the murder of Debbie Grund. NOTE: On Adult Swim, this episode is rated TV-14.  75 15 &quot;Naked Ambition&quot; Anthony Lioi Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger February 20, 2000  ( 2000-02-20 ) 4ABE12 After a day of swimming at the river, Bobby accidentally walks in on Luanne naked. When Joseph hears the story, his imagination runs wild and he wants to see her nude too — until Connie catches them peeping. Meanwhile, Dale and Bill try to break Boomhauer out of an insane asylum in Houston .  76 16 &quot;Movin&apos; On Up&quot; Klay Hall Garland Testa February 27, 2000  ( 2000-02-27 ) 4ABE16 Fed up with Hank&apos;s demands, Luanne moves out of the Hills&apos; den — and into a house with a trio of even more aggravating college-aged deadbeats.  77 17 &quot;Bill of Sales&quot; Dominic Polcino Paul Lieberstein March 12, 2000  ( 2000-03-12 ) 4ABE15 Peggy reluctantly recruits Bill into a pyramid scheme and is pleasantly surprised by his superb sales abilities, but she&apos;s surprised when her for-once sincere praise for him leads to him being unable to sell anymore.  78 18 &quot; Won&apos;t You Pimai Neighbor? &quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky March 19, 2000  ( 2000-03-19 ) 4ABE18 Bobby undergoes tests to find out if he is the reincarnation of the Buddhist Lama Sanglug, much to Hank&apos;s discomfort.  79 19 &quot;Hank&apos;s Bad Hair Day&quot; Gary McCarver Jon Vitti April 9, 2000  ( 2000-04-09 ) 4ABE19 After Hank&apos;s barber is forced to retire on account of the scarcity of business, Hank gets a haircut on the Army base from Bill, and puts Bill out of the job after lodging a complaint to the government about a $900 bill for the tonsorial procedure.  80 20 &quot;Meet the Propaniacs&quot; Shaun Cashman Kit Boss April 16, 2000  ( 2000-04-16 ) 4ABE17 While working for Hank during the summer at Strickland Propane (instead of going to an acting camp), Bobby, some Strickland co-workers, Dale, and Luanne form a sketch comedy troupe called The Propaniacs.  81 21 &quot;Nancy&apos;s Boys&quot; Tricia Garcia Jonathan Aibel&amp;Glenn Berger April 30, 2000  ( 2000-04-30 ) 4ABE20 Nancy breaks off her adulterous affair with John Redcorn after going on a date with Dale and falling in love with him all over again.  82 22 &quot;Flush with Power&quot; Allan Jacobsen Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck May 7, 2000  ( 2000-05-07 ) 4ABE22 Arlen&apos;s City Council forces Hank to install low-flow toilets against his wishes when a drought hits town. Hank&apos;s anger leads him to join the local zoning board, which he discovers is rife with corruption.  83 23 &quot;Transnational Amusements Presents: Peggy&apos;s Magic Sex Feet&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Jonathan Collier May 14, 2000  ( 2000-05-14 ) 4ABE21 After admitting her real shoe size during a night of bowling, Peggy feels ashamed of her big feet—until a self-proclaimed &quot;foot doctor&quot; makes Peggy an Internet star on a foot fetish website.  84 24 &quot;Peggy&apos;s Fan Fair&quot; Jeff Myers Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland May 21, 2000  ( 2000-05-21 ) 4ABE23 While attending a Nashville music festival with Hank and the guys, Peggy claims that Randy Travis stole lyrics from a song she wrote years ago.  

 [ edit ] Season 5: 2000–2001 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 85 1 &quot; The Perils of Polling &quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Jim Dauterive October 1, 2000  ( 2000-10-01 ) 5ABE02 When Hank takes Luanne to an election fair, Hank meets George W. Bush and shakes his hand, only to discover that Bush&apos;s handshake is weak, giving Hank doubts about having voted for him. Meanwhile, Luanne becomes infatuated with Communist candidate Robert Parigi. Rated TV-PG-DL  86 2 &quot; The Buck Stops Here &quot; Michael Dante DiMartino Norm Hiscock November 5, 2000  ( 2000-11-05 ) 5ABE01 Bobby becomes a golf caddy for Buck Strickland, who takes him along for the ride on a gambling junket. Hank and Peggy are disturbed when Buck&apos;s habits rub off on Bobby. Brad Renfro guest stars. Rated TV-PG-DL.  87 3 &quot;I Don&apos;t Want to Wait for Our Lives to Be Over...&quot; Adam Kuhlman Paul Lieberstein November 12, 2000  ( 2000-11-12 ) 4ABE24 With Bobby&apos;s 13th birthday approaching, Joseph comes back from summer vacation having grown six inches. Bobby is upset that everyone still treats him like a little kid, and Joseph is being driven crazy by the onset of puberty . Meanwhile, Hank tries to build coffins for himself and Peggy.  88 4 &quot; Spin the Choice &quot; Allan Jacobsen Paul Lieberstein November 19, 2000  ( 2000-11-19 ) 5ABE05 Despite Hank&apos;s promise to let him carve the turkey this year, Bobby boycotts Thanksgiving after receiving history lessons from John Redcorn that expose the shameful history behind it. Meanwhile, Peggy creates a pointless new game called &quot;Spin the Choice&quot; when everyone gets sick of playing Boggle with her every year.  89 5 &quot; Peggy Makes the Big Leagues &quot; Dominic Polcino Johnny Hardwick November 26, 2000  ( 2000-11-26 ) 5ABE04 Peggy substitute-teaches at Arlen High School, but arouses the enmity of nearly all (including Hank and her fellow teachers) when she gives the school&apos;s unacademic football star (guest voiced by Brendan Fraser ) a failing grade.  90 6 &quot;When Cotton Comes Marching Home&quot; Tricia Garcia Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland December 3, 2000  ( 2000-12-03 ) 5ABE03 Cotton moves to the VFW , and wants to march in the Veterans Day parade, but his boss denies him the time off from his degrading restroom attendant job.  91 7 &quot;What Makes Bobby Run?&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck December 10, 2000  ( 2000-12-10 ) 5ABE07 When Bobby becomes the school mascot, the &quot;Landry Longhorn,&quot; he is deemed a coward after he runs away from a traditional half-time beating by the opposing team&apos;s band.  92 8 &quot; Twas the Nut Before Christmas &quot; Jeff Myers John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky December 17, 2000  ( 2000-12-17 ) 5ABE08 In the third Christmas episode, Bill&apos;s holiday loneliness leads to him opening a &quot;Christmas village&quot; in his yard, but things get out of hand when he takes on a twenty-something petty criminal as a surrogate son.  93 9 &quot;Chasing Bobby&quot; Anthony Lioi Garland Testa January 21, 2001  ( 2001-01-21 ) 5ABE10 Peggy takes Hank to see a tearjerking movie about a father and son&apos;s relationship, and mistakes Hank&apos;s crying as evidence that his subconscious knowledge that he needs to spend more time with Bobby, but Hank is actually upset about his truck breaking down.  94 10 &quot;Yankee Hankee&quot; Adam Kuhlman Kit Boss February 4, 2001  ( 2001-02-04 ) 5ABE06 Hank&apos;s application for a &quot;native Texan&quot; license plate leads him to the utterly shocking news that he was born in a women&apos;s bathroom at Yankee Stadium in New York City , while Cotton and his cronies hatch a hare-brained scheme to assassinate Cuban dictator Fidel Castro .  95 11 &quot; Hank and the Great Glass Elevator &quot; Gary McCarver Jonathan Collier February 11, 2001  ( 2001-02-11 ) 5ABE12 On a daytrip to Austin for Bill&apos;s 40th birthday, Hank moons the former Governor of Texas, Ann Richards , leading Bill to take the blame and eventually enter a relationship with her. Bill&apos;s time with her leads to a fateful encounter with the last person he would ever see again: his ex-wife, Lenore. Meanwhile, Peggy and Bobby try hamburgers grilled on a charcoal-powered barbecue for the first time — and run afoul of Hank&apos;s none-too-subtle loyalties when he discovers their stockpile of charcoal briquettes upon returning.  96 12 &quot; Now Who&apos;s the Dummy? &quot; Dominic Polcino Johnny Hardwick February 18, 2001  ( 2001-02-18 ) 5ABE14 Bobby acquires a ventriloquist &apos;s dummy named Chip Block, which dredges up childhood anxieties for Dale. Meanwhile, Hank becomes overly attached to Chip due to the dummy&apos;s &quot;knowledge&quot; of sports.  97 13 &quot; Ho Yeah! &quot; Tricia Garcia Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck February 25, 2001  ( 2001-02-25 ) 5ABE15 
Tammi (guest voiced by Renee Zellweger ), a prostitute from &quot;The OKC&quot; ( Oklahoma City, Oklahoma ) hires on at Strickland Propane, moves in with the Hills, and encourages Peggy to add spice to her own life. Things heat up when Tammi&apos;s ex-pimp Alabaster Jones (guest voiced by Snoop Dogg ) comes to Arlen and mistakes Hank for a pimp trying to steal Tammi away from him.

 Note : On FOX, this episode was rated TV-14 for suggestive dialogue (D), making it the first King of the Hill episode not to carry a TV-PG rating. On Adult Swim, this episode is rated TV-PG for suggestive dialogue (D) and offensive language (L).  98 14 &quot; The Exterminator &quot; Shaun Cashman Dean Young March 4, 2001  ( 2001-03-04 ) 5ABE09 Dale is forced to quit the exterminating business after learning that the cumulative effect of on-the-job exposure to poisons may kill him before he turns 50 years old, so he accepts a position at an adhesives company called &quot;Stik Tek&quot; (formerly Stik Co.), where his job is firing other employees.  99 15 &quot; Luanne Virgin 2.0 &quot; Adam Kuhlman Kit Boss March 11, 2001  ( 2001-03-11 ) 5ABE16 When Luanne reveals to Hank that she is no longer a virgin (after her latest boyfriend breaks up with her), Hank puts Luanne in the church&apos;s &quot;born-again virgin&quot; program, where Luanne meets a sexually insecure man (guest-voiced by Owen Wilson ) and Peggy confesses that she had sex with a man (who turned out to be a homosexual) before she met Hank.  100 16 &quot;Hank&apos;s Choice&quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Jon Vitti April 1, 2001  ( 2001-04-01 ) 5ABE11 When it turns out that Bobby is allergic to Ladybird, he ends up living in Ladybird&apos;s luxurious new doghouse while Ladybird continues living in the household. The arrangement is enjoyed by all parties until Hank and Peggy discover that their neighbors are mocking them as a result. Bobby then uses a perfect combination of medication pills to cure his allergy and everything goes back to normal.  101 17 &quot;It&apos;s Not Easy Being Green&quot; Jeff Myers John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky April 8, 2001  ( 2001-04-08 ) 5ABE18 When the local quarry is going to be drained for a landfill, Hank must pretend he is interested in environmental issues in order to keep a secret from Boomhauer.
Guest stars Paul Giamatti as Mr. McKay.  102 18 &quot;The Trouble with Gribbles&quot; Shaun Cashman Jim Dauterive April 22, 2001  ( 2001-04-22 ) 5ABE19 When Nancy turns 40, the television station replaces her with Luanne, who is much younger. This leads to Nancy telling Dale that she wants a facelift. Dale plans to pay for it by filing suit against the makers of his favorite brand, Manitoba Cigarettes (&quot;Manitoba is the brand to smoke, you&apos;ll enjoy it toke for toke...&quot;), claiming that second-hand smoke has made his Nancy unattractive. This results in Dale being both counter-sued and estranged from Nancy.  103 19 &quot;Hank&apos;s Back Story&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland May 6, 2001  ( 2001-05-06 ) 5ABE17 Hank finds out his back problems are caused by &quot;diminished gluteal syndrome&quot; (a condition that has worn down Hank&apos;s hindquarters and put pressure on his spine), and attempts to come to terms with wearing a prosthetic posterior while preparing to compete in a lawn-mower race.  104 20 &quot; Kidney Boy and Hamster Girl: A Love Story &quot; Gary McCarver Garland Testa May 13, 2001  ( 2001-05-13 ) 5ABE22 Bobby pretends to be a high school student with a kidney disorder that stunted his growth, and helps the student body win a radio station contest, with No Doubt performing at the high school prom as the prize.  

 [ edit ] Season 6: 2001–2002 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 105 1 &quot; Bobby Goes Nuts &quot; Tricia Garcia Norm Hiscock November 11, 2001  ( 2001-11-11 ) 5ABE24 
After getting attacked at a slumber party by Chane Wassonasong, Hank lets Bobby sign up for a boxing class at the YMCA , but Bobby ends up taking a women&apos;s self-defense course, where Bobby is taught to attack his aggressors by kicking them in the groin. This results in him kicking Hank in the groin.
 NOTE: This is the first episode of KOtH to be digitally colored instead of cel-painted. No other episode would be digitally colored until &quot;Ceci N&apos;Est Pas Une King of the Hill&quot;, when the series went digital for the rest of the series&apos; run.  106 2 &quot; Soldier of Misfortune &quot; Anthony Lioi J.B. Cook December 9, 2001  ( 2001-12-09 ) 6ABE02 Dale is running for re-election as the Arlen Gun Club president, but his chances seem to be shot when he accidentally discharges his gun. To give Dale his confidence back, Hank pretends to be &quot;Mr. Big&quot;, answers Dale&apos;s ad in Soldier of Fortune magazine, and assigns Dale to pick up a briefcase. But Dale bungles the job, and nearly gets his friends killed by his opponent at the Gun Club.
 Gary Busey guest stars as Mad Dog.  107 3 &quot;Lupe&apos;s Revenge&quot; Allan Jacobsen Dean Young December 12, 2001  ( 2001-12-12 ) 5ABE13 Peggy takes the school Spanish club on a field trip to Mexico, and ends up in trouble for kidnapping a Mexican girl named Lupe thanks to Peggy&apos;s horrible comprehension of the Spanish language . Meanwhile, Hank finds himself the object of the affections of a female police officer (voice of Kathy Bates ), who keeps pulling him over for various reasons in order to spend time with him.  108 4 &quot; The Father, the Son, and J.C. &quot; Tricia Garcia&amp; Cyndi Tang Loveland Etan Cohen &amp;Dean Young December 16, 2001  ( 2001-12-16 ) 6ABE04 While Hank is building a Habitat for Humanity house for Buck Strickland, Buck promotes him to manager of Strickland Propane. In the excitement of the moment, Hank emotes and declares, &quot;I love you&quot; to Mr. Strickland. This causes Cotton to grow incredibly angry with Hank. Peggy&apos;s attempts to bring father and sons together only throws gasoline onto the fire. They get into an altercation, which must be solved by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter .  109 5 &quot;Father of the Bribe&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Dean Young January 6, 2002  ( 2002-01-06 ) 6ABE06 Kahn tries to bribe Bobby to break up with Connie. Connie and Bobby decide to pretend to break up so they can get the money. When a schoolteacher thinks Connie may be depressed after Connie writes a note that reads &quot;I&apos;m so bored, I could kill myself&quot; (which was a response to a dull lecture), her parents try to push her and Bobby back together. After endless double dates with the parents, they become tired of each other, and decide to break up, to Kahn&apos;s horror. Meanwhile, Dale hosts a pirated radio show.  110 6 &quot;I&apos;m With Cupid&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland John Altschuler&amp;Dave Krinsky February 10, 2002  ( 2002-02-10 ) 6ABE09 Following the events from the previous episode, Bobby seems fine in regards to his breakup with Connie and the upcoming Valentine&apos;s Day . However, when he is left home alone while Peggy and Hank go out, Bill depresses Bobby by suggesting that Bobby blew his only shot at true love. Hank then asks Boomhauer to give Bobby advice on women, only for that advice to be alternately confusing and repellent.  111 7 &quot;Torch Song Hillogy&quot; Anthony Lioi Emily Spivey February 17, 2002  ( 2002-02-17 ) 6ABE12 Peggy nominates Bobby to carry the 2002 Winter Olympic Torch through Arlen, but Hank wins the honor—and bungles it.  112 8 &quot;Joust Like a Woman&quot; Dominic Polcino Garland Testa February 24, 2002  ( 2002-02-24 ) 6ABE03 
Peggy works as a cleaning wench at a Renaissance Faire, where her boss ( Alan Rickman ) refuses to give his female workers equal pay and benefits.
 Laura Dern also guest stars as one of Peggy&apos;s colleagues.
NOTE: This episode originally contained a short scene in which King Phillip sees two teen boys at the fair and yells to them, &quot;We wage war on France on the morrow!&quot; after which one boy says to the other, &quot;That is so gay.&quot; After several suicides related to anti-gay bullying made the news in late 2010 (and heightened public concern about the issue), this scene was cut out of repeats on Adult Swim. As of February 9th 2012, the scene was added back into the episode.  113 9 &quot;The Bluegrass Is Always Greener&quot; Tricia Garcia Norm Hiscock February 24, 2002  ( 2002-02-24 ) 6ABE14 
Connie and the guys form a bluegrass band and head to Branson, Missouri , against Kahn&apos;s wishes.
 Note: Vince Gill provided Boomhauer&apos;s singing voice. Also, Charlie Daniels and Yakov Smirnoff makes guest appearances.  114 10 &quot;The Substitute Spanish Prisoner&quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Etan Cohen March 3, 2002  ( 2002-03-03 ) 5ABE21 After handing back tests to her class, Peggy is dumbfounded when Dooley asks her to explain the answer to a question. To restore her self-confidence, Peggy takes an Internet IQ test and discovers that she qualifies for &quot;genius&quot; status, but discovers that the IQ test is a scam when she blows Hank&apos;s retirement fund on a diploma. She then plans a risky counter-con against the scam&apos;s organizer (voice of Jeff Goldblum ) to get everyone&apos;s money back.  115 11 &quot;Unfortunate Son&quot; Anthony Lioi Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck March 10, 2002  ( 2002-03-10 ) 5ABE20 Cotton&apos;s VFW is in dire straits as members are dying and the veterans are behind on their propane bill, so the VFW moves to Hank&apos;s house, but the inclusion of Vietnam War veterans angers Cotton and the WWII vets and leads to an increasingly dangerous situation.  116 12 &quot;Are You There God? It&apos;s Me, Margaret Hill&quot; Gary McCarver Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin March 17, 2002  ( 2002-03-17 ) 6ABE07 Peggy must pretend she is a nun after she gets a job at a Catholic school .  117 13 &quot;Tankin&apos; It to the Streets&quot; Monte Young Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland March 31, 2002  ( 2002-03-31 ) 6ABE10 After Bill finds out the Army subjected him to a secret medical experiment called &quot;Operation Infinite Walrus&quot; that left him fat and balding, he gets drunk and steals a tank, leaving his friends to try to save him from life in prison. Meanwhile, Peggy and Bobby try to win a free ice cream sundae at the Mega Lo Mart.  118 14 &quot;Of Mice and Little Green Men&quot; Shaun Cashman Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin April 7, 2002  ( 2002-04-07 ) 6ABE08 When Hank and Dale find they have more in common with each other&apos;s sons than their own, Dale finally concludes that Joseph isn&apos;t his biological son — and then moves to the wild conclusion that Joseph is actually the offspring of an alien .  119 15 &quot;A Man Without a Country Club&quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Kit Boss April 14, 2002  ( 2002-04-14 ) 6ABE11 Hank is asked to join the exclusive all-Asian Nine Rivers Country Club , enraging a highly envious Kahn, but Hank isn&apos;t aware that the club wants him because they need a Caucasian member in order to host high-profile PGA tournaments.  120 16 &quot;Beer and Loathing&quot; Dominic Polcino Etan Cohen April 14, 2002  ( 2002-04-14 ) 6ABE13 Peggy lands a job at Alamo Beer, which is a dream come true for Hank—until the new batch of beer makes everyone sick and she&apos;s forbidden from telling the truth about what happened.  121 17 &quot;Fun with Jane and Jane&quot; Adam Kuhlman Garland Testa April 21, 2002  ( 2002-04-21 ) 6ABE15 Luanne and Peggy unwittingly join a cult disguised as a college sorority. Meanwhile, Hank and his buddies try to find a place to hide Buck Strickland&apos;s emus after being ordered to kill them.  122 18 &quot; My Own Private Rodeo &quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck April 28, 2002  ( 2002-04-28 ) 6ABE16 Dale and Nancy renew their wedding vows, and Nancy invites Dale&apos;s father, a gay man whom Dale detests for supposedly trying to win Nancy&apos;s affections away from him, to the ceremony.  123 19 &quot;Sug Night&quot; Adam Kuhlman Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck May 5, 2002  ( 2002-05-05 ) 6ABE05 Hank freaks out when he has a dream in which he sees himself and Nancy Gribble grilling hamburgers naked.  124 20 &quot;Dang Ol&apos; Love&quot; Gary McCarver Dean Young May 5, 2002  ( 2002-05-05 ) 6ABE17 Boomhauer falls in love with a woman who wanted only a one-night stand (voice of Laura Linney ), which crushes Boomhauer now that he feels like the many women he has seduced in the past, while Bill recovers from losing that woman and finds advice that helps his friend.  125 21 &quot;Returning Japanese&quot; Allan Jacobsen&amp;Anthony Lioi Kit Boss&amp;Etan Cohen May 12, 2002  ( 2002-05-12 ) 6ABE20 Part one of two. Cotton wants to return to Japan to apologize to the widow of a soldier he killed, and Peggy arranges to bring the family along. Hank is shocked to discover that Cotton actually had an affair with the widow and fathered another son.  126 22 &quot;Returning Japanese II&quot; Klay Hall Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck May 12, 2002  ( 2002-05-12 ) 6ABE21 Conclusion. When Cotton&apos;s Japanese son, Junichiro, renounces his Hill ancestry, Cotton declares his own personal war on Japan by deciding to spit in the Japanese emperor &apos;s face.  

 [ edit ] Season 7: 2002–2003 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 127 1 &quot; Get Your Freak Off &quot; Tricia Garcia Garland Testa November 3, 2002  ( 2002-11-03 ) 7ABE01 Hank takes Bobby and his friends to a music concert but is dismayed to see Bobby and a friend dancing inappropriately to boy band music, so he tries to make Bobby&apos;s adolescence more wholesome. Meanwhile Peggy, Nancy and Minh try to decide who is the best-looking out of Hank, Dale, Boomhauer, Kahn, Bill and John Redcorn.  128 2 &quot; The Fat and the Furious &quot; Allan Jacobsen Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck November 10, 2002  ( 2002-11-10 ) 7ABE03 Bill becomes a competitive eater after downing Hank&apos;s entire platter of hot dogs during a barbecue, but his dreams are soon crushed when Dale (who thinks competitive eating is degrading) beats him.
Guest stars include: Jeff Garlin , Pamela Anderson and Kid Rock .  129 3 &quot; Bad Girls, Bad Girls, Whatcha Gonna Do &quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Kell Cahoon&amp;Tom Saunders November 17, 2002  ( 2002-11-17 ) 6ABE19 Connie&apos;s criminal cousin, Tid Pau (voiced by Lucy Liu ), becomes Bobby&apos;s science project partner and makes him an unwitting accomplice in creating a drug lab.
 NOTE : In the original airing, Tid Pau calls Bobby a &quot;pig fucker&quot; (with &quot;fucker&quot; bleeped out). In all reruns, the word was changed to &quot;pig farmer&quot;.  130 4 &quot; Goodbye Normal Jeans &quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Kit Boss November 24, 2002  ( 2002-11-24 ) 6ABE01 Peggy becomes jealous of Bobby when he uses his Home Ec. class cooking skills in the Hill kitchen.  131 5 &quot; Dances with Dogs &quot; Anthony Lioi Norm Hiscock December 1, 2002  ( 2002-12-01 ) 7ABE02 Bobby and Hank use Ladybird to compete in a dog dancing contest. Meanwhile, Bill is tricked into buying an ill-tempered Rottweiler from an animal shelter.
 Scott Hamilton guest stars.  132 6 &quot;The Son Also Roses&quot; Dominic Polcino Dan Sterling December 8, 2002  ( 2002-12-08 ) 6ABE22 Bobby becomes a rose grower when he tires of doing the Landry football team&apos;s laundry and recruits the help of two cannabis cultivators to help him win a contest.  133 7 &quot;The Texas Skillsaw Massacre&quot; Shaun Cashman Alan R. Cohen&amp;Alan Freedland December 15, 2002  ( 2002-12-15 ) 6ABE18 The Hills are forced to live with the Gribbles after Dale digs a tunnel underneath the Hills&apos; kitchen, and the inspector declares the Hill house uninhabitable until the necessary repairs are done. Things get worse when Hank is sentenced to take anger management classes after accidentally cutting one of Dale&apos;s fingers off with a circular saw (which Dale recovers from when his finger is sewn back on).  134 8 &quot;Full Metal Dust Jacket&quot; Adam Kuhlman Dan McGrath January 5, 2003  ( 2003-01-05 ) 7ABE04 Peggy takes over the lease of a bookstore, but when the bookstore&apos;s business plummets, she allows Dale and his gun group to sell firearms at the store.  135 9 &quot;Pigmalion&quot; Dominic Polcino Jonathan Collier January 12, 2003  ( 2003-01-12 ) 5ABE23 Luanne becomes involved with the psychotic owner (voiced by Michael Keaton ) of a pork processing plant who wants Luanne to be just like the woman on the company logo.
 NOTE : This was originally supposed to air as a season-six episode (even though it has a season 5 production code), but was pulled for a while, presumably for its violent, disturbing content.  136 10 &quot;Megalo Dale&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland J.B. Cook January 12, 2003  ( 2003-01-12 ) 7ABE05 Dale is hired to exterminate at the Mega Lo Mart, but it turns out the &quot;pest&quot; is Chuck Mangione , the Mega Lo Mart spokesman.
 Topher Grace and Danny Masterson also make guest appearances.  137 11 &quot;Boxing Luanne&quot; Michael Dante DiMartino Dean Young February 2, 2003  ( 2003-02-02 ) 7ABE07 To prove to men that she is more than just a pretty face and a sexy body, Luanne becomes a boxer, but soon learns that the boxing she has done was foxy boxing, and that every fight she won had been fixed.  138 12 &quot;Vision Quest&quot; Dominic Polcino Etan Cohen February 9, 2003  ( 2003-02-09 ) 7ABE09 John Redcorn is worried about how Dale is raising Joseph, so he gets Hank to take Joseph on a &quot; vision quest ,&quot; but Dale is the one who gets a vision and mistakenly believes that he is a native American.  139 13 &quot; Queasy Rider &quot; Wes Archer Kit Boss February 16, 2003  ( 2003-02-16 ) 7ABE10 Hank and Peggy try to fix their strained marriage by buying a motorcycle and immersing themselves in the biker lifestyle.  140 14 &quot;Board Games&quot; Boowhan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin March 2, 2003  ( 2003-03-02 ) 7ABE08 Peggy, Nancy, and Minh run for school board against each other after Tom Landry Middle School cuts all after-school programs out of the budget.  141 15 &quot;An Officer and a Gentle Boy&quot; Gary McCarver Dan Sterling March 9, 2003  ( 2003-03-09 ) 7ABE06 Hank sends Bobby to Cotton&apos;s old military academy , where Cotton tries to break the boy&apos;s spirit.  142 16 &quot;The Miseducation of Bobby Hill&quot; Tricia Garcia Tim Croston&amp; Chip Hall March 16, 2003  ( 2003-03-16 ) 7ABE11 Bobby becomes a salesman at Strickland Propane (although Hank doubts his ability, citing his inexperience) and uses underhanded tactics from Joe Jack to sell more grills. Meanwhile, Dale builds a Larry Walters -inspired flying lawn chair and tests it out on Bill, who ends up battered, bruised, and lost in Mexico.  143 17 &quot;The Good Buck&quot; Allan Jacobsen Alex Gregory&amp;Peter Huyck March 30, 2003  ( 2003-03-30 ) 7ABE13 
Buck becomes a born-again Christian (courtesy of Luanne) after his wife divorces him, but Hank is worried that Buck only wants Luanne for sex. Meanwhile, Bobby hides out from his track coach and makes friends with two old ladies at Hotel Arlen&apos;s restaurant during tea time.
 NOTE: On FOX, this episode was rated TV-G (making it one of two King of the Hill episodes that do not have the TV-PG rating [&quot;Ho Yeah&quot;, originally rated TV-14, is the other]). On Cartoon Network, the episode is rated TV-PG for suggestive dialogue (D).  144 18 &quot;I Never Promised You an Organic Garden&quot; Adam Kuhlman Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May April 13, 2003  ( 2003-04-13 ) 7ABE14 Peggy takes over the organic garden at the school, but she is caught using pesticides on the garden.  145 19 &quot; Be True To Your Fool &quot; Anthony Lioi Dan McGrath April 27, 2003  ( 2003-04-27 ) 7ABE12 When Hank gets his head shaved (after Bill gives Hank, Dale, and Boomhauer lice), he discovers a tattoo in the back of his head he got as a teenager during a drunken night out. Meanwhile, Bill makes friends with a bullpen of prisoners at the county jail.  146 20 &quot;Racist Dawg&quot; Michael Dante DiMartino Kit Boss May 4, 2003  ( 2003-05-04 ) 7ABE17 Hank hires an African-American repairman (guest-voiced by Bernie Mac ), whom Ladybird attacks, prompting the town to think that Hank and his dog are racists.  147 21 &quot;Night and Deity&quot; Gary McCarver Garland Testa May 11, 2003  ( 2003-05-11 ) 7ABE16 After Bill attracts pigeons to the alley, Dale must work with an attractive female exterminator (voice of Janeane Garofalo ), who makes Nancy jealous.  148 22 &quot;Maid in Arlen&quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Dan Sterling May 18, 2003  ( 2003-05-18 ) 7ABE18 Bill and Laoma, Kahn&apos;s mother, enter into a romantic relationship that Kahn works overtime to sabotage.  149 23 &quot; The Witches of East Arlen &quot; Matt Engstrom Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin May 18, 2003  ( 2003-05-18 ) 7ABE20 Bobby gets involved with a group of post-adolescent geeks who are into tarot cards and witchcraft. David Cross guest stars.  

 [ edit ] Season 8: 2003–2004 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 150 1 &quot; Patch Boomhauer &quot; Anthony Lioi J.B. Cook November 2, 2003  ( 2003-11-02 ) 8ABE01 Jeff Boomhauer&apos;s brother Patch (voiced by Brad Pitt ), is getting married to a woman whom Jeff has always been in love with, opening old wounds between the two.  151 2 &quot;Reborn to Be Wild&quot; Dominic Polcino Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May November 9, 2003  ( 2003-11-09 ) 8ABE02 Fearing that Bobby is succumbing to bad influences, Hank makes him join a local church youth group. Bobby discovers that the group consists of cool punks (guest voiced by the band members of Sum 41 [ 1 ] ), including their tattooed pastor, i.e. &quot;Pastor K&quot;, who worship God through skateboarding and rock . Hank approves of Bobby&apos;s newfound interest in religion, but disapproves of the way the group treats Christianity as a fad. Meanwhile, Hank&apos;s friends (and Kahn) start a club called &quot;The Last Meal Club&quot;, where they come up with what meals they would like to eat before they die.  152 3 &quot;New Cowboy on the Block&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Dean Young November 16, 2003  ( 2003-11-16 ) 7ABE15 A washed-up former Dallas Cowboys player moves into the neighborhood, and no one, not even Hank, can admit that he is a jerk—until the man starts harassing Hank.  153 4 &quot; The Incredible Hank &quot; Wes Archer Dan Sterling November 23, 2003  ( 2003-11-23 ) 8ABE04 Hank takes Bobby to the doctor to get him some testosterone supplements to boost his energy, but Hank becomes the one who sorely needs a testosterone boost. Meanwhile, Bobby faces his fear of showering after gym class.  154 5 &quot;Flirting with the Master&quot; Anthony Lioi Norm Hiscock November 30, 2003  ( 2003-11-30 ) 7ABE22 The actor who plays TV&apos;s &quot;Monsignor Martinez&quot; invites Peggy to Mexico City to tutor his children for an English language exam. Meanwhile, Luanne takes on Peggy&apos;s duties at home.  155 6 &quot;After the Mold Rush&quot; Dominic Polcino Kit Boss December 7, 2003  ( 2003-12-07 ) 7ABE19 When Hank&apos;s house sustains minor water damage, a man from the insurance company sets out to get rich by determining that the Hill household is infested with mold .  156 7 &quot;Livin&apos; on Reds, Vitamin C and Propane&quot; John Rice Dan McGrath December 14, 2003  ( 2003-12-14 ) 8ABE05 Hank needs to take some antique furniture to his mother in Arizona, so he rents an 18-wheeler and takes Bobby on a road trip (with Dale, Bill and Boomhauer stowing away). Meanwhile, Peggy and Luanne try to write a Christmas novelty song.  157 8 &quot; Rich Hank, Poor Hank &quot; Tricia Garcia Etan Cohen January 4, 2004  ( 2004-01-04 ) 7ABE21 
Bobby thinks Hank is secretly a rich miser after hearing Peggy talking about Hank&apos;s new $1000 bonus, and Bobby and Joseph steal Hank&apos;s emergency credit card to go on a shopping spree.
 NOTE : This is the final episode to use traditional cel animation. Every episode after this is digitally colored.  158 9 &quot;Ceci N&apos;Est Pas Une King of the Hill&quot; Tricia Garcia Etan Cohen January 25, 2004  ( 2004-01-25 ) 8ABE03 
When Hank asks Peggy to design an art piece for Strickland Propane, she creates the &quot;Probot,&quot; a statue made out of propane tanks. Her sculpture is rejected by the city board, but picked up by an art dealer from Dallas. Unfortunately, Peggy finds out that the dealer presents her to the public as an uneducated hillbilly. Meanwhile, Dale starts wearing a suit of armor and uses his newfound invincibility to insult people without consequences.
The episode won an Annie Award for writing. [ 2 ]   159 10 &quot;That&apos;s What She Said&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin February 8, 2004  ( 2004-02-08 ) 8ABE06 A new employee named Rich (voiced by Ben Stiller ) becomes popular around Strickland Propane for telling lewd jokes, but Hank thinks this is a breach of sexual harassment laws. Meanwhile, Dale is forced by Nancy to give up cigarettes, so he takes up chewing tobacco instead.  160 11 &quot;My Hair Lady&quot; Allan Jacobsen Wyatt Cenac February 15, 2004  ( 2004-02-15 ) 8ABE09 Luanne and Bill both get jobs at the hippest hair salon in Arlen called &quot;Hottyz.&quot; But in order to keep his job, Bill must pretend to be a homosexual . Meanwhile, Hank&apos;s elderly barber has a hard time staying in business.  161 12 &quot;Phish and Wild Life&quot; Matt Engstrom Greg Cohen February 22, 2004  ( 2004-02-22 ) 8ABE10 Hank takes Bobby and the guys on a fishing trip, where they vow to eat only what they catch. A very hungry Bobby befriends the campers next to them, who are a group of hippies . After they feed him half of a hamburger bun, Bobby starts to eat with them. The hippies run out of their supply, and come to Bobby for repayment.  162 13 &quot;Cheer Factor&quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Christy Stratton March 7, 2004  ( 2004-03-07 ) 8ABE07 Peggy volunteers to help with the school cheerleading squad, in order to get them to learn some cheers to motivate the football team. Up until now, the squad is only concerned with winning the dance competitions and trophies from other schools. When Peggy gets the crowds behind the team, the school principal replaces the current coach with Peggy...who takes it too far.  163 14 &quot;Dale Be Not Proud&quot; Anthony Lioi Jonathan Collier March 14, 2004  ( 2004-03-14 ) 8ABE11 When NHRA driver John Force needs an organ transplant, Dale is the only one who can save him. Hank encourages Dale to ignore his fear of hospitals and give up his kidney to save Force. Dale reluctantly agrees, but only if Hank takes his place being Dale for the day, a task that consists of outlandish duties.  164 15 &quot;Après Hank, le Deluge&quot; Gary McCarver Kit Boss March 21, 2004  ( 2004-03-21 ) 8ABE08 When flood threatens the town, the Arlenites gather in the communal shelter: the Tom Landry gym. Meantime, the kids go wild in the yearbook office, Peggy regresses, and Dale schemes to build an ark to float his family to safety.  165 16 &quot;DaleTech&quot; Dominic Polcino J.B. Cook March 28, 2004  ( 2004-03-28 ) 8ABE12 Dale starts a security company called &quot;DaleTech&quot;, but his business is threatened by Cotton, who has become a new local auxiliary police officer.  166 17 &quot;How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Alamo&quot; Brian Sheesley Christy Stratton April 18, 2004  ( 2004-04-18 ) 8ABE14 Hank tries to teach Bobby about the Alamo after discovering that the new history textbooks in school contain revisionist history. Meanwhile, Peggy and Luanne mail out a paper cut-out boy named Flat Stanley to be passed around America.  167 18 &quot; Girl, You&apos;ll Be a Giant Soon &quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Dan McGrath April 25, 2004  ( 2004-04-25 ) 8ABE16 Luanne tries to help Hank protest against a grilling contest when it is revealed that the contest does not allow propane grills. Meanwhile, Peggy tries to visit a house where a famous murder took place, but the real estate agent is only letting in potential buyers.  168 19 &quot;Stressed for Success&quot; Tricia Garcia Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May May 2, 2004  ( 2004-05-02 ) 8ABE13 Bobby joins the school&apos;s Quiz Bowl team because of his extensive knowledge of pop culture , but he becomes stressed out by the pressure.
In the final credits this episode is dedicated to the memory of John Ritter . Kelly Clarkson and Ben Stein also guest stars.  169 20 &quot;Hank&apos;s Back (a.k.a.) The Unbearable Lightness of Being Hank&quot; Robin Brigstocke Aron Abrams &amp; Gregory Thompson May 9, 2004  ( 2004-05-09 ) 8ABE15 When Hank suffers a back injury at work and none of his doctors can fix it, he tries the healing powers of yoga . At first, he finds it a little too wacky, but thanks to the help of Yogi Victor ( Johnny Depp ), he realizes that it actually works. However, Hank&apos;s insurance company uses this to prove that Hank is taking unfair advantage of his workers&apos; compensation. Meanwhile, Peggy fights to keep the old Pink&amp;White market open.
 Angela Bloomfield and Marg Helgenberger also guest voice.  170 21 &quot; The Redneck on Rainey Street &quot; Gary McCarver Jim Dauterive May 16, 2004  ( 2004-05-16 ) 8ABE17 Connie is turned down for admission to a prestigious summer school after filling its quota of Asian kids. Realizing that working hard and overachieving will never help them get ahead in life, Kahn and Minh decide to give up and live like beer-drinking, El Camino-driving rednecks, which nearly drive them to homelessness when they stop making payments on their house. Bob Hoskins guest stars.  171 22 &quot;Talking Shop&quot; Anthony Lioi Garland Testa May 23, 2004  ( 2004-05-23 ) 8ABE20 Despite Hank&apos;s wishes for Bobby to take auto shop, Bobby takes peer counseling so he can give advice to vulnerable teenage girls. Meanwhile, Hank finds a wrecked car for Bobby to fix, thinking that he signed up for auto shop.
Guest stars include Alyson Hannigan , Laura Prepon , and Lindsay Lohan .  

 [ edit ] Season 9: 2004–2005 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 172 1 &quot; A Rover Runs Through It &quot; Tricia Garcia Dan Sterling November 7, 2004  ( 2004-11-07 ) 8ABE22 The Hills travel to Montana to visit Peggy&apos;s mother. There, they find out the family is losing the ranch to Henry Winkler because of high property taxes.  173 2 &quot;Ms. Wakefield&quot; Allan Jacobsen J.B. Cook December 19, 2004  ( 2004-12-19 ) 9ABE05 When an elderly stranger, Ms. Wakefield (voice of Marion Ross ), visits the Hill residence during Christmas, Hank is thrilled to show her his house since it was also her childhood home. However, when Ms. Wakefield announces that she wants to die in their house, Hank and Peggy want nothing more than for her to leave, despite her bothersome insistence.  174 3 &quot; Death Buys a Timeshare &quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Etan Cohen January 16, 2005  ( 2005-01-16 ) 8ABE18 Cotton inherits $10,000 from the will of his friend Topsy, and goes to Mexico, with Bill in tow, to buy a timeshare . Feeling lonely after the death of his friend, Cotton gets suckered in by tales of the timeshare development&apos;s owner, O&apos;Kelly, and decides to buy—even though Americans cannot own land in Mexico. Meanwhile, Peggy, Bobby and Dale search for a pool to swim in.  175 4 &quot; Yard, She Blows! &quot; Allan Jacobsen Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin January 23, 2005  ( 2005-01-23 ) 8ABE19 Peggy is jealous that Hank always gets complimented on his yard, so she starts a garden in the front yard. When that plan fails, she puts Winklebottom the garden gnome in their front yard, which drives Hank insane.  176 5 &quot; Dale to the Chief &quot; Anthony Lioi Garland Testa January 30, 2005  ( 2005-01-30 ) 9ABE02 When Dale reads Joseph the Warren Commission Report, he notices the absence of a discrepancy in the positioning of the local landmarks, decides that the U.S. government must be right about who assassinated John F. Kennedy (and thus, their official version of every story he had previously written off as part of some conspiracy is in fact completely factual) and turns his government-hating, right-wing mania into even more insufferable, flag-waving patriotism. Meanwhile, Hank discovers a mistake on his driver&apos;s license and is sent through a boatload of red tape in order to fix it—a task made all the more onerous when Dale reports Hank as a threat to America&apos;s national security.  177 6 &quot; The Petriot Act &quot; Robin Brigstocke Christy Stratton February 13, 2005  ( 2005-02-13 ) 9ABE06 When Hank agrees to take in a soldier&apos;s pet, he gets Duke, a vicious, mean-spirited cat, against Hank&apos;s wishes. Hank takes Duke to visit Dr. Leslie (voice of Jason Bateman ), a veterinarian who runs a battery of tests and presents Hank with a bill for several thousand dollars.  178 7 &quot; Enrique-cilable Differences &quot; Dominic Polcino Greg Cohen February 20, 2005  ( 2005-02-20 ) 9ABE12 Hank&apos;s co-worker Enrique is having marital problems, and starts spending all his time with Hank. Meanwhile, Bobby tries to unblock the Fox network from the Hills&apos; TV.  179 8 &quot; Mutual of Omabwah &quot; Dominic Polcino Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May March 6, 2005  ( 2005-03-06 ) 9ABE03 When Hank forgets to mail his insurance payment, Hank and Bobby must protect themselves from any accidents until their insurance can be re-activated in 36 hours. Meanwhile, Dale decides to raise bees, Bill and Boomhauer discover the joys of deep-frying, and Peggy and Luanne get stuck at a rest stop when Hank asks them not to drive uninsured.  180 9 &quot;Care-Takin&apos; Care of Business&quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Dan McGrath March 13, 2005  ( 2005-03-13 ) 9ABE01 When the Tom Landry Middle School football team has to forfeit a game due to poor field maintenance when the caretaker goes senile, the booster club resolves to replace the school&apos;s elderly groundskeeper, Smitty, and Hank resolves to help him keep his job by secretly doing upkeep on the field. Meanwhile, Luanne starts dating a redneck named Lucky (first seen in &quot;The Redneck on Rainey Street&quot;), much to Peggy&apos;s dismay.  181 10 &quot; Arlen City Bomber &quot; Boohwan Lim&amp;Kyounghee Lim Jonathan Collier March 27, 2005  ( 2005-03-27 ) 9ABE07 To pay off her credit card debts, Luanne signs up to be a roller derby girl. Peggy gets in on it too and uses borrowed money to make improvements on the team, sinking both Luanne and Peggy deeper into debt.  182 11 &quot; Redcorn Gambles with His Future &quot; Matt Engstrom Etan Cohen April 10, 2005  ( 2005-04-10 ) 9ABE09 Hank is in charge of organizing the Strickland Family Fun Day. Meanwhile, John Redcorn and his band &quot;Big Mountain Fudgecake&quot; are having trouble finding a venue to play their music. Acting on Hank&apos;s advice, John Redcorn uses his land to open a casino so his band can have a place to play.  183 12 &quot; Smoking and the Bandit &quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland Dan McGrath April 17, 2005  ( 2005-04-17 ) 9ABE10 When Arlen bans smoking in all restaurants and bars, Dale becomes the rebellious &quot;Smoking Bandit&quot; to impress Joseph. Meanwhile, Peggy decides to tail the &quot;Bandit&quot; and unmask him.
 Tone Lōc guest stars.  184 13 &quot; Gone with the Windstorm &quot; Yvette Kaplan Wyatt Cenac May 1, 2005  ( 2005-05-01 ) 9ABE08 When Channel 84 hires a new meteorologist , Irv Bennett, Nancy and her less-than-accurate weather reports are left out in the cold. Meanwhile, Bobby tries to fight back against a bully who constantly scares him at school.  185 14 &quot; Bobby on Track &quot; Tricia Garcia Aron Abrams &amp; Gregory Thompson May 8, 2005  ( 2005-05-08 ) 9ABE13 Upset with Bobby&apos;s habit of giving up what he starts (after Bobby does not complete the miles needed to run for a charity race), Hank puts Bobby on the school&apos;s track team, but soon learns that the coach only wants Bobby as a &quot;Stick&quot; so he can push the other team members to do better.  186 15 &quot; It Ain&apos;t Over &apos;til the Fat Neighbor Sings &quot; Julius Wu Etan Cohen May 15, 2005  ( 2005-05-15 ) 9ABE19 Bill joins an all-male chorus (based on the Dallas-based men&apos;s chorus the Vocal Majority ) who end up using Bill and forcing him to blow off his appointment to cut the general&apos;s hair at the Army base. Meanwhile, Peggy and Bobby get caught up in a game of Pong .  

 [ edit ] Season 10: 2005–2006 

The majority of episodes in this season are leftover episodes from the 8ABE and 9ABE production line. The AABE production line (much like The Simpsons &apos; 3G production line for seasons eight and nine) is a short-lived line and only lasts for five episodes (four airing this season and the fifth airing as a leftover episode next season).

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 187 1 &quot; Hank&apos;s on Board &quot; Allan Jacobsen Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin September 18, 2005  ( 2005-09-18 ) 9ABE14 Hank fears he is being shunned when his friends go on a vacation without him. Meanwhile, Bobby saves up his money so that he can buy a metal detector .  188 2 &quot; Bystand Me &quot; Dominic Polcino Kit Boss September 25, 2005  ( 2005-09-25 ) 8ABE21 When the Arlen Bystander newspaper gets a new editor, Peggy gets a job writing a household hints column (even though Peggy does not know any household hints). Meanwhile, Hank makes Bobby get a paper route.  189 3 &quot; Bill&apos;s House &quot; Robin Brigstocke Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May November 6, 2005  ( 2005-11-06 ) 9ABE15 Bill turns his house into a rehabilitation center for alcoholics, and enlists Hank&apos;s assistance when the task gets out of hand.  190 4 &quot;Harlottown&quot; Tricia Garcia Aron Abrams &amp; Gregory Thompson November 20, 2005  ( 2005-11-20 ) 9ABE04 Peggy and Hank protest when Arlen&apos;s city manager wants to open a Museum of Prostitution and host the Adult Video Awards.  191 5 &quot;Portrait of the Artist as a Young Clown&quot; Anthony Lioi Christy Stratton&amp;Garland Testa December 4, 2005  ( 2005-12-04 ) 9ABE16 Bobby goes to clown college and becomes a classical clown, but no one likes his new act except Bobby himself.  192 6 &quot;Orange You Sad I Did Say Banana?&quot; Adam Kuhlman Dan Sterling December 11, 2005  ( 2005-12-11 ) 9ABE11 Upon being told that he is too Americanized and called a &quot;banana&quot; (the Asian equivalent to an Oreo [a black person who acts white]), Kahn vows to return to his Laotian roots.  193 7 &quot;You Gotta Believe (In Moderation)&quot; Yvette Caplan Kit Boss January 29, 2006  ( 2006-01-29 ) 9ABE17 Hank invites a softball team to compete against his own team of misfits, to raise money to save Tom Landry Middle School&apos;s baseball team.  194 8 &quot;Business Is Picking Up&quot; Matt Engrstrom Dan Sterling March 19, 2006  ( 2006-03-19 ) 9ABE18 Hank tries to get Bobby interested in working as a propane salesman during Tom Landry Middle School&apos;s Career Day, but when Joseph beats him to the punch Bobby shadows a young, handsome man (voice of Johnny Knoxville ) who makes his living picking up animal (and human) waste.  195 9 &quot; The Year of Washing Dangerously &quot; Cyndi Tang Loveland &amp;Ken Wong J.B. Cook March 26, 2006  ( 2006-03-26 ) 9ABE20 Kahn buys the local car wash as part of a plan to get rich, and Hank finds himself working for his disrespectful, money-obsessed neighbor when Buck takes a stake in the business as well.  196 10 &quot;Hank Fixes Everything&quot; Ronald Rubio Kit Boss April 2, 2006  ( 2006-04-02 ) 9ABE21 Buck Strickland hires the guys from the reality show American Chopper (who voice themselves) to perform at Strickland Propane in order to win a price war with Thatherton Fuels, then gets into a price fixing conspiracy with the other propane companies in Arlen which attracts the government&apos;s attention — centered on Hank.  197 11 &quot; Church Hopping &quot; Robin Brigstocke Jim Dauterive April 9, 2006  ( 2006-04-09 ) 9ABE22 When the Hill family finds out that their pew of many years has been given away to another family at church, they abandon their staid Methodist church and come about to worship at a new megachurch .  198 12 &quot;24 Hour Propane People&quot; Robin Brigstocke Aron Abrams&amp;Gregory Thompson April 23, 2006  ( 2006-04-23 ) AABE01 When Buck gets banned from his favorite strip club, he focuses on making Strickland Propane a &quot;fun&quot; place to work, which sits well with everyone but Hank.  199 13 &quot; The Texas Panhandler &quot; Ronald Rubio&amp;Ken Wong Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May April 30, 2006  ( 2006-04-30 ) AABE02 Instead of getting a real job, Bobby (who has become disenchanted with gainful employment) and Joseph discover that they can make more money, and look cooler, by hanging out on street corners and begging for money.  200 14 &quot; Hank&apos;s Bully &quot; Kyounghee Lim J.B. Cook May 7, 2006  ( 2006-05-07 ) AABE03 Hank gets bullied by a boy named Caleb. Meanwhile, Dale and Peggy enter a taxidermy competition.  201 15 &quot; Edu-macating Lucky &quot; Adam Kuhlman Silvert Glarum&amp;Michael Jamin May 14, 2006  ( 2006-05-14 ) AABE04 Lucky asks Peggy to help him get his GED in the hopes of improving his chances of marrying Luanne. Peggy agrees to help him study for the test, but is torn between her wish to help him and her wish to keep him away from her niece. Then Luanne has an announcement...  

 [ edit ] Season 11: 2007 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 202 1 &quot; The Peggy Horror Picture Show &quot; Kyounghee Lim Christy Stratton January 28, 2007  ( 2007-01-28 ) BABE02 Peggy, feeling a bit unfeminine because of her masculine clothes and size-16 feet, befriends Carolyn, who views Peggy as the epitome of womanhood. Hank is thrilled that Peggy finally has someone else to talk to about her girl problems, but discovers that Carolyn is a drag queen who thinks Peggy is one too.  203 2 &quot;serPUNt&quot; Robin Brigstocke Greg Cohen February 11, 2007  ( 2007-02-11 ) BABE01 When a python Lucky gives to Bobby as a gift gets into the toilet, Hank calls on Tommy (guest-voiced by John Goodman ) and Rollo at Animal Control for help. But instead of taking care of the problem, they make the city believe that the problem is worse than it is in order to get higher salaries, causing panic.  204 3 &quot;Blood and Sauce&quot; Tricia Garcia Dan McGrath February 18, 2007  ( 2007-02-18 ) BABE03 Bill calls a reunion of all the Dauterives due to feeling lonely. After amassing a giant barbecue it is found out that Gilbert, his cousin, is the only other Dauterive.Due to such good tasting food, people want to buy the recipe, however Gilbert will not let Bill whore out the Dauterive family.  205 4 &quot;Luanne Gets Lucky&quot; Ken Wong Jonathan Collier March 25, 2007  ( 2007-03-25 ) BABE04 Lucky neglects Luanne when he becomes obsessed with retrieving a walnut stump his grandfather found, so Luanne accepts a 15-year-old&apos;s invitation to the senior prom.  206 5 &quot;Hank Gets Dusted&quot; Michael Loya Kit Boss April 1, 2007  ( 2007-04-01 ) BABE05 Hank is devastated when Cotton&apos;s Cadillac is given to Hank&apos;s cousin Dusty (voice of ZZ Top &apos;s Dusty Hill ), but when Dusty and his bandmates show up at Hank&apos;s house to play practical jokes for a reality show taping, it is more than Hank can bear.  207 6 &quot; Glen Peggy Glen Ross &quot; Tony Kluck Jim Dauterive April 22, 2007  ( 2007-04-22 ) BABE06 Peggy is fired from The Arlen Bystander and begins a new career as a real estate agent. Meanwhile, after Dale buys a set of titanium golf clubs at a police auction, he gives the clubs to Hank, who does not want them after learning they were used as a murder weapon.  208 7 &quot;The Passion of Dauterive&quot; Anthony Chun Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May April 29, 2007  ( 2007-04-29 ) BABE07 Bill searches for meaning in his life after surviving a roof collapse, leading to a relationship with Reverend Stroup.  209 8 &quot; Grand Theft Arlen &quot; Ronald Rubio Sanjay Shah April 29, 2007  ( 2007-04-29 ) BABE08 Hank protests against a new school program that lets failing gym students play video games—and becomes addicted to Pro-Pain , a Grand Theft Auto knockoff centered on propane and featuring Hank as the protagonist. Meanwhile, Bobby trains for the Presidential Physical Fitness Test.  210 9 &quot;Peggy&apos;s Gone to Pots&quot; Robin Brigstocke Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh May 6, 2007  ( 2007-05-06 ) BABE09 Peggy tries to reach the pinnacle of real estate success by selling houses in the exclusive neighborhood of Arlen Heights, but she winds up selling kitchen supplies for a scam company. Meanwhile, Dale comes face-to-face with Rusty Shackleford, the man whose identity he often uses.  211 10 &quot;Hair Today, Gone Tomorrow&quot; Kyounghee Lim Christy Stratton May 13, 2007  ( 2007-05-13 ) BABE10 Nancy turns to her mother (voiced by Rue McClanahan ) for help when the stress of home life and unresolved feelings for John Redcorn cause her to lose her hair. Meanwhile, Dale takes a ride with Kahn&apos;s delinquent nephew in a souped-up racecar during the vernal equinox and thinks he has traveled through time.  212 11 &quot;Bill, Bulk and the Body Buddies&quot; Tricia Garcia Blake McCormick May 20, 2007  ( 2007-05-20 ) BABE11 Bill meets a body builder named Dirk who agrees to help him train for an upcoming Army physical, but when Bill starts working out with Dirk and his two meathead buddies, Bill develops a bad attitude and alienates his former friends ( Randy Savage guests as one of the bodybuilders).  213 12 &quot; Lucky&apos;s Wedding Suit &quot; Julius Wu Jim Dauterive May 20, 2007  ( 2007-05-20 ) AABE05 When Lucky wants to give Luanne the expensive wedding that she desires, he sues Dale with a frivolous lawsuit after having an accident on the job. Rated TV-PG-L 
NOTE: This episode was originally scheduled to be King of the Hill&apos; s final episode (explaining why the AABE production line is so short and why this episode contained many secondary characters). [ 3 ]   

 [ edit ] Season 12: 2007–2008 

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 214 1 &quot; Suite Smells of Excess &quot; Michael Loya Dave Schiff September 23, 2007 BABE13 When the guys take Bobby to a University of Texas football game their hijinks land them in a VIP box suite, where Hank is mistaken for a former player of the opposing Nebraska Cornhuskers , and is asked to call a crucial play for the team.  215 2 &quot; Bobby Rae &quot; Ken Wong Tim Croston&amp; Chip Hall September 30, 2007  ( 2007-09-30 ) BABE12 Bobby feigns interest in activism when he goes after the heart of a real student activist, who protests the installation of soda machines in the school (and the funds from said soda machines being used to pay for the teachers&apos; vacation).  216 3 &quot;The Powder Puff Boys&quot; Ronald Rubio Christy Stratton October 7, 2007  ( 2007-10-07 ) BABE16 Hank encourages Bobby to be a part of the school&apos;s Powder Puff team (a team where boys dress in drag and impersonate female cheerleaders). However, the boys learn that Peggy and the PTA are trying to put a stop to the tradition.  217 4 &quot; Four Wave Intersection &quot; Anthony Chun Judah Miller&amp;Murray Miller October 14, 2007  ( 2007-10-14 ) BABE15 Arlen is hit by a heat wave and Hank takes the kids to the water park. Unfortunately, they have to tangle with a group of surfer bullies to enjoy the &quot;Endless Wave.&quot; Meanwhile, Boomhauer, who is usually cool, winds up embarrassing himself, and Bill becomes known as the famous &quot;Heat-Waver&quot; when he begins to stand on the side of the highway and wave to motorists.  218 5 &quot; Death Picks Cotton &quot; Tony Kluck Judah Miller&amp;Murray Miller November 11, 2007  ( 2007-11-11 ) BABE14 While at a Japanese restaurant, Cotton suffers a war flashback and ends up getting hospitalized after falling on the grill, where Peggy learns that Cotton may not have long to live. [ 4 ]   219 6 &quot;Raise the Steaks&quot; Robin Brigstocke Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh November 18, 2007  ( 2007-11-18 ) BABE17 After buying tough, unsavory steaks at the Mega-Lo-Mart, Hank, at Appleseed&apos;s suggestion, visits the town co-op in search of better meat. After falling in love with the delicious organic food, Hank becomes a co-op volunteer and co-owner.  220 7 &quot;Tears of an Inflatable Clown&quot; Tricia Garcia Erin Ehrlich November 25, 2007  ( 2007-11-25 ) BABE19 Bobby convinces the student council to put on a carnival, and he is put in charge of it, but a dour so-called &quot;diversity expert&quot; comes to school and nearly puts the kibosh on Bobby&apos;s plan by making everything politically correct. Meanwhile, Dale, Bill and Boomhauer try to get a reluctant Lucky to the hospital when he injures himself.  221 8 &quot;The Minh Who Knew Too Much&quot; Kyounghee Lim Dan McGrath December 9, 2007  ( 2007-12-09 ) BABE18 Minh joins the Arlen Gun Club to learn skeet shooting, a skill she hopes will make an exclusive country club want her and Kahn as members. Meanwhile, Hank tries to solve the mystery of who&apos;s been discarding trash in his trash cans.  222 9 &quot;Dream Weaver&quot; Ken Wong Jennifer Barrow December 16, 2007  ( 2007-12-16 ) BABE20 Nancy wants Dale to get a new job since he is not making any money, so he and Hank go on a &quot;vocation vacation&quot; to learn basket weaving. Meanwhile Peggy, Kahn and Bill try to achieve Internet stardom by creating a wacky viral video.  223 10 &quot; Doggone Crazy &quot; Michael Loya Dave Schiff January 6, 2008  ( 2008-01-06 ) CABE01 The Hill&apos;s dog, Ladybird, goes on a rampage, breaking things all over the house and later biting Hank&apos;s hand. After Ladybird is put on a list of vicious dogs, the veterinarian suggests that Hank takes her to a dog spiritualist.  224 11 &quot;Trans-Fascism&quot; Kyounghee Lim Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh February 10, 2008  ( 2008-02-10 ) CABE02 When the Arlen City Council bans the sale of foods containing trans fats, Sugarfoot&apos;s Restaurant goes out of business. Hank, who feels the ban is an infringement on freedom, encourages Strickland to fix things. Strickland&apos;s solution to the problem is to sell his delicious, trans-fatty foods on a lunch truck so he can evade the law.  225 12 &quot;Three Men and a Bastard&quot;
&quot;The Untitled Blake McCormick Project&quot; Ken Wong Blake McCormick February 17, 2008  ( 2008-02-17 ) CABE03 Bill becomes involved with a single mother, Charlene, who once had an affair with John Redcorn, and, like Nancy Gribble, has a half-Native American child who, like Joseph Gribble, is oblivious to her biological father&apos;s identity.
NOTE: This episode was titled &quot;Untitled Blake McCormick Project&quot; on the FOX broadcast, presumably because the censors did not want to use a swear word in the title.  226 13 &quot;The Accidental Terrorist&quot; Robin Brigstocke Tim Croston&amp;Chip Hall March 2, 2008  ( 2008-03-02 ) CABE04 Hank finds out his car salesman has been tricking him into paying more than he should when purchasing a car, and gets tangled in a botched plan cooked up by two college-aged activists.  227 14 &quot;Lady and Gentrification&quot; Anthony Chun Judah Miller&amp;Murray Miller March 9, 2008  ( 2008-03-09 ) CABE05 Peggy inadvertently ruins Enrique&apos;s life when she sells a house in Enrique&apos;s neighborhood to a hipster (voiced by Dax Shepard ) who invites his hipster friends over to live in the same neighborhood. Meanwhile, Hank is asked to speak at Enrique&apos;s daughter Inez&apos;s Quinceaños celebration.  228 15 &quot;Behind Closed Doors&quot; Tony Kluck Christy Stratton March 16, 2008  ( 2008-03-16 ) CABE06 Tom Landry Middle School holds an emergency community meeting when a child (Dooley) goes missing in Arlen. Relationship expert Stephens Davies is invited to speak at the meeting and makes an example of Peggy by questioning her parenting skills, prompting Peggy to become stricter in her parenting.  229 16 &quot;Pour Some Sugar on Kahn&quot; Tricia Garcia Sanjay Shah March 30, 2008  ( 2008-03-30 ) CABE07 Kahn&apos;s father-in-law, General Gum, visits the Souphanousinphone family. The General gives Kahn a hard time and makes him feel like a failure. Kahn becomes depressed until he stumbles upon a Laotian karaoke bar where he becomes a star singing &quot;The Morning After&quot;.  230 17 &quot;Six Characters in Search of a House&quot; Ronald Rubio Erin Ehrlich April 6, 2008  ( 2008-04-06 ) CABE08 Peggy, a passionate realtor, finds a great home listing that she must sell within two weeks. One catch, though, the home is currently occupied by the strangest family in Arlen. Peggy does not feel they are visually appealing enough to get the home sold in time, so she decides to bring in a &quot;Hollywood&quot; family to sell the home.  231 18 &quot;The Courtship of Joseph&apos;s Father&quot; Michael Loya Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May April 13, 2008  ( 2008-04-13 ) CABE09 Joseph becomes the star quarterback at Tom Landry Middle School, and gives the school hope that they&apos;ll actually win this year. A wealthy prep school offers Joseph to play for their school instead. Joseph wants to stay at Landry, but Dale wants him to take the cash offering. Dale realizes that his family does not fit in the upper-class lifestyle and tries to raise money to pay back the school&apos;s exclusive contract.  232 19 &quot;Strangeness On a Train&quot; Kyounghee Lim Jim Dauterive April 27, 2008  ( 2008-04-27 ) CABE10 Depressed over her botched birthday parties, Peggy schedules a 1970s-style murder mystery party on a train, but when Dale ruins the surprise, thanks to Luanne&apos;s discovery of what her role is, a new mystery crops up—after Hank and Peg have sex in the train bathroom.  233 20 &quot;Cops and Robert&quot; Ken Wong Dave Schiff May 4, 2008  ( 2008-05-04 ) CABE11 When Hank accidentally steals another man&apos;s wallet (thinking that the man pickpocketed him), the man begins exacting his revenge on Hank. Meanwhile, Bobby gets sentenced to spend the day with the school security guard after being framed for throwing a soda can at him and Dale attempts to get a job at a Hooters -esque restaurant called &quot;Bazooms&quot; by citing sexual discrimination if he is not hired. Paul Sorvino guest stars.  234 21 &quot;It Came From the Garage&quot; Robin Brigstocke Blake McCormick May 11, 2008  ( 2008-05-11 ) CABE12 Hank and Bobby get in some father/son bonding time when Hank dumps the old team of Dale, Bill and Boomhauer to help Bobby in a boat-building competition. During the building process, Hank gets spooked by bats that invade the construction garage, forcing Bobby to do the building all alone.  235 22 &quot;Life: A Loser&apos;s Manual&quot; Anthony Chun Dan McGrath May 18, 2008  ( 2008-05-18 ) CABE13 Luanne&apos;s father/Peggy&apos;s brother Hoyt (voiced by Johnny Knoxville ) returns to Arlen to stay with the family. Once he arrives, Peggy reveals to Hank that Hoyt (previously mentioned as being an oil rig worker) is in truth a no-good ex-con and that she created the lie of him being an oil rig worker to allow Luanne to believe that she has at least one law abiding parent. Hoyt attempts to corrupt Lucky (who has recruited Hank in order to get him his driver&apos;s license and other forms of ID after he confesses to Luanne that he has none) and forces him to take the fall when Hoyt is arrested for possessing drugs. Peggy and Hank must then unite to save the day, by getting Hoyt arrested and getting Lucky to recant his confession.  

 [ edit ] Season 13: 2008–2009; 2010 

Beginning with the episode &quot;Lucky See, Monkey Do,&quot; King of the Hill is now shown in 720p high-definition . This is also the final season of King of the Hill . 20th Century Fox Television initially ordered 13 DABE [ 3 ] production episodes, but decided to keep the show in production for four additional episodes (DABE14-DABE17). However, the network only aired the last of those four episodes (13 total for that production season), and confirmed it would not air the remaining four unaired episodes (DABE13-DABE16) in prime time, opting instead for syndication. These episodes premiered between May 3 and May 6, 2010, on local stations and premiered on Cartoon Network &apos;s Adult Swim line-up between May 17 and May 20, 2010, followed by the series finale (DABE17, &quot;To Sirloin With Love&quot;) on May 21, 2010.

 No. # Title Directed by Written by Original air date Prod.
code 236 1 &quot; Dia-BILL-ic Shock &quot; Ronald Rubio Sanjay Shah September 28, 2008  ( 2008-09-28 ) CABE16 Bill, unwilling to change his sugary eating habits, is diagnosed with diabetes by a mean-spirited doctor who tells him that he is going to lose his legs. After deciding to use a wheelchair (which he really does not need), he is befriended by a rugby player named Thunder, who teaches him how to be independent, but their friendship is strained when Thunder realizes Bill is not really disabled.  237 2 &quot; Earthly Girls are Easy &quot; Matt Engstrom Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh October 5, 2008  ( 2008-10-05 ) CABE17 A local paper plans to run a story about Strickland Propane illegally dumping old propane tanks into the river. Hank suggests the company go green, and when the ladies of Arlen hear of the eco-efforts made by the company, Dale decides to help out Strickland with their carbon off-sets to garner the attention of the girls. To impress the ladies, Mr. Strickland organizes an earth benefit concert that goes wrong.  238 3 &quot; Square-Footed Monster &quot; Kyounghee Lim Jerry Collins October 19, 2008  ( 2008-10-19 ) CABE18 After Hank and the guys fix up the recently deceased Dotty Dwyer&apos;s house, Dotty&apos;s nephew sells the house to Ted Wassonasong. But when Ted has construction workers tear down the home to make way for a &quot;McMansion&quot;, the Hill family and the rest of the neighborhood visit the City Council to protest the construction.  239 4 &quot; Lost in MySpace &quot; Tony Kluck Judah Miller&amp;Murray Miller November 2, 2008  ( 2008-11-02 ) CABE14 To boost business, Strickland Propane creates a MySpace page despite Hank&apos;s bad feelings about the idea. Mr. Strickland gives Donna full responsibility over the page, but she fills it with personal information about the employees, leading to conflicts throughout the office. Meanwhile, Dale rents a pig to hunt truffles , loses it, and has to borrow Ladybird in order to track it down.  240 5 &quot; No Bobby Left Behind &quot; Tricia Garcia Tim Croston&amp; Chip Hall November 9, 2008  ( 2008-11-09 ) CABE15 To raise the school&apos;s grade point average as part of the No Child Left Behind program, Bobby and Joseph are put into a &quot;special needs&quot; class, which irks Hank, who believes his son&apos;s mediocre grades are from lack of trying.  241 6 &quot; A Bill Full of Dollars &quot; Steve Robertston Dan McGrath November 16, 2008  ( 2008-11-16 ) CABE19 After losing money in the stock market , Peggy, Minh and Dale decide to study an average man (Bill) in order to find out what sells among people like him.  242 7 &quot; Straight as an Arrow &quot; Robin Brigstocke Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May November 30, 2008  ( 2008-11-30 ) CABE20 When Bobby decides to become a member of the Order of the Straight Arrow (even though it was established that Bobby is already a member according to the season one episode &quot;Order of the Straight Arrow&quot;), Hank decides to get involved as well, but when he bumps heads with the Arrowmaster, who happens to be a new resident of Arlen, this stirs up trouble with Peggy, who has volunteered to serve as the Welcome Wagon representative for the town.  243 8 &quot; Lucky See, Monkey Do &quot; Kyounghee Lim Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh February 8, 2009  ( 2009-02-08 ) DABE01 When Peggy plans a baby shower for Luanne, Lucky invites his sister Myrna and her children to the party. Myrna has conflicting parenting information to give Luanne, and is described by Peggy as a &quot;modern mother&quot;. After a scuffle between Myrna and Peggy on where to birth the baby, Luanne decides to do it &quot;her way&quot; and take Peggy&apos;s advice about going to the hospital to give birth. Meanwhile, Bill goes to Arizona to find a woman who he is attracted to after speaking with her at his favorite fast-food restaurant.
 NOTE: This is the first episode of the series to air in 720p high definition .  244 9 &quot; What Happens at the National Propane Gas Convention in Memphis Stays at the National Propane Gas Convention in Memphis &quot; Ronald Rubio Jim Dauterive February 15, 2009  ( 2009-02-15 ) DABE02 When Buck Strickland is invited to the National Propane Gas Convention as the newest inductee into the Propane Hall of Flame, he asks Hank to accompany him. Although Hank is honored, he quickly realizes his primary responsibility will be babysitting Buck and preventing him from getting into trouble. Hank&apos;s job is made that much more difficult when Buck meets his illegitimate son Ray Roy (guest voice Diedrich Bader ) at the convention and stays out late carousing with him.  245 10 &quot;Master of Puppets&quot; Tony Kluck Blake McCormick March 1, 2009  ( 2009-03-01 ) DABE03 When Hank and Peggy forget to pick up Bobby at the mall, Bobby begins using emotional blackmail to get them to do whatever he wants. Meanwhile, Dale emulates Survivorguy (a parody of Survivorman ) by camping out in the backyard.  246 11 &quot;Bwah My Nose&quot; Jeff Myers Judah Miller&amp;Murray Miller March 8, 2009  ( 2009-03-08 ) DABE04 During a football game practice for an upcoming rematch, Bill breaks Hank&apos;s nose. After trying to live with the injury, Hank reluctantly gets plastic surgery... and becomes hung up on his looks.  247 12 &quot;Uncool Customer&quot; Tricia Garcia Christy Stratton March 15, 2009  ( 2009-03-15 ) DABE05 After Peggy finds out that she is not cool, she befriends one of Arlen&apos;s most glamorous and coolest moms in an effort to learn how to be cool. Bobby finds himself enchanted by her daughter. Hank finds a restaurant that sells delicious meatloaf sandwiches, but cannot get used to its seating arrangements.  248 13 &quot;Nancy Does Dallas&quot; Michael Loya Tony Gama-Lobo&amp;Rebecca May March 22, 2009  ( 2009-03-22 ) DABE06 Nancy moves to Dallas after landing a job as a reporter for a metropolitan news station and back-stabs her way to the top. Meanwhile, Dale conducts a hare-brained experiment by turning the house into an igloo.  249 14 &quot;Born Again on the Fourth of July&quot; Ken Wong Erin Ehrlich April 19, 2009  ( 2009-04-19 ) DABE07 Hank gets involved in a neighborhood war over Independence Day decorations, and Bobby discovers that his apathy over neighborhood pride is what&apos;s tearing the neighborhood apart.  250 15 &quot;Serves Me Right for Giving General George S. Patton the Bathroom Key&quot; Steve Robertson Tim Croston&amp;Chip Hall April 26, 2009  ( 2009-04-26 ) DABE08 Hank receives a special delivery of his recently deceased father&apos;s personal belongings, including a list of bizarre final requests—one of which calls for Hank to flush Cotton&apos;s ashes in the toilet of a bar once used by General George S. Patton. Meanwhile, Dale and Bill bicker over an empty beer can Dale discarded in Bill&apos;s yard and will not pick up.  251 16 &quot;Bad News Bill&quot; Ronald Rubio Dave Schiff May 3, 2009  ( 2009-05-03 ) DABE10 When Hank tries to be realistic about Bobby&apos;s below-average baseball abilities, he is vilified by Bobby&apos;s over-enthusiastic Little League coach, who only wants to set Bobby up for disappointment. Meanwhile, Bill is hired as the head of the baseball field&apos;s snack counter.  252 17 &quot;Manger Baby Einstein &quot; Kyounghee Lim Sanjay Shah May 10, 2009  ( 2009-05-10 ) DABE09 While adjusting to her new career and life as a mom, Luanne resurrects her Manger Baby puppets and, with help from John Redcorn, starts a series of direct-to-DVD educational shows, but risks selling out when the franchise grows stale and other entertainers line up to take her place. Meanwhile, Dale writes a children&apos;s book about a lost bullet wanting to get home to find its gun.
 NOTE: Final appearance of John Redcorn.  253 18 &quot;Uh-oh, Canada&quot; Tony Kluck Jerry Collins May 17, 2009  ( 2009-05-17 ) DABE11 When Boomhauer decides to house-swap with the Huskins, a Canadian family, for the duration of the summer, Hank and the Rainey St. regulars find themselves putting up with the neighbo(u)rs from hell. Meanwhile, Boomhauer romances a French-Canadian woman. Mira Sorvino guest stars.  254 19 &quot;The Boy Can&apos;t Help It&quot; Jeff Myers Dan McGrath September 13, 2009  ( 2009-09-13 ) DABE12 Bobby becomes quite the ladies&apos; man when several girls in his class consider him a potential date for the Homecoming dance, but Hank is worried that Bobby is being used. Meanwhile, Hank and the guys try to put together the ultimate homeless person&apos;s shopping cart.  255 20 &quot; To Sirloin with Love &quot; Kyounghee Lim Jim Dauterive, Tony Gama-Lobo, Rebecca May&amp;Christy Stratton September 13, 2009  ( 2009-09-13 ) DABE17 Series finale. Hank discovers that Bobby has a talent for inspecting and distinguishing cuts of meat, and puts Bobby on a meat-inspecting team run by Heimlich County&apos;s community college.  256 21 &quot; The Honeymooners &quot; Tricia Garcia Paul Corrigan&amp;Brad Walsh May 3, 2010  ( 2010-05-03 ) 
May 17, 2010  ( 2010-05-17 ) ( Adult Swim ) DABE13 Hank is shocked when his mother announces she is marrying a man she has only known for a few weeks. Soon after, the newlyweds celebrate by purchasing an RV and heading to Hank&apos;s. When Hank&apos;s mom and new stepdad have a heated argument, she takes off with the RV and Hank is left to rescue his mother once again.  257 22 &quot;Bill Gathers Moss&quot; Michael Loya Aron Abrams&amp;Gregory Thompson May 4, 2010  ( 2010-05-04 ) 
May 18, 2010  ( 2010-05-18 ) (Adult Swim) DABE14 Bill decides to take in roommates, and Hank fears it will lead to disaster. Meanwhile, Bobby and Joseph go ghost hunting at their school.  258 23 &quot;When Joseph Met Lori, and Made Out with Her in the Janitor&apos;s Closet&quot; Ken Wong Sanjay Shah May 5, 2010  ( 2010-05-05 ) 
May 19, 2010  ( 2010-05-19 ) (Adult Swim) DABE15 After getting into an argument with Joseph about the girl he has been dating, Dale attempts to give Joseph the &quot;sex talk&quot; but fails to, and takes a test claiming he has &quot; dementia &quot; leading to him joining a mental home, but then realizes he has to get out before Joseph and Lori go &quot;all the way&quot;.  259 24 &quot;Just Another Manic Kahn-Day&quot; Steve Robertson&amp;Jack Perkins Jennifer Barrow May 6, 2010  ( 2010-05-06 ) (final episode)
May 20, 2010  ( 2010-05-20 ) (Adult Swim) DABE16 Hank advises Kahn not to pick up his medication at the pharmacy, until he realizes that Kahn needs his medication to curb his manic-depression. Meanwhile, Bobby tries to find the humor in a &quot; Raymond J. Johnson, Jr. &quot; comedy record after his parents and other adults claim it is funny.  

 [ edit ] References 
 
 ^ &quot;&quot;King of the Hill&quot; Reborn to Be Wild (2003)&quot; . http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0620295/ . Retrieved 2009-11-03 .   ^ 32nd Annual Annie Award Nominees and Winners (2004) ^ a b &quot;King of the Hill Originals still on Tap for next Season&quot; . thefutoncritic.com . April 30, 2009 . http://www.thefutoncritic.com/news.aspx?id=8068 . Retrieved 2009-04-30 .   ^ tv.com; &quot;Death Picks Cotton&quot; 
 
 
 
 v t e 
 King of the Hill General 
 Episodes DVDs Soundtrack Arlen, Texas Guest stars 
 Characters 
 Hank Hill Peggy Hill Bobby Hill Cotton Hill Dale Gribble Boomhauer Bill Dauterive 
 Related topics 
 Beavis and Butt-head 
 
 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List_of_King_of_the_Hill_episodes&amp;oldid=501675209#Season_1:_1997 &quot; Categories :
 Lists of American animated television series episodes King of the Hill episodes 
 Hidden categories:
 Articles needing additional references from June 2012 All articles needing additional references All articles with unsourced statements Articles with unsourced statements from January 2011 Episode list using the default LineColor 
 
Personal tools

 Create account Log in 
 
Namespaces

 Article Talk 
 


 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to Wikipedia 
 
Interaction
 
 Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact Wikipedia 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Cite this page 
 
Print/export
 
 Create a book Download as PDF Printable version 
 
Languages
 
 Français Italiano Русский 
 
 This page was last modified on 11 July 2012 at 05:48.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License ;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc. , a non-profit organization.
 Contact us 

 Privacy policy About Wikipedia Disclaimers Mobile view
	</body>
</document>
