<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006663" url="http://www.wvec.com/home/Manufacturer-bringing-800-jobs-to-Isle-of-Wight-Co-132773208.html" time="2012-07-12-23:39" support="1" score="0.0004994510260699425" bingtitle="Green Mountain Coffee Roasters bringing 800 jobs to Isle of Wight ..." webtitle="Green Mountain Coffee Roasters bringing 800 jobs to Isle of Wight Co. | 
                WVEC.com Norfolk - Hampton Roads">
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>... packs for its Keurig® Single-Cup ... job losses, and this project will put ... Customer in Norfolk fast food restaurant robbed; Police say woman stole credit card from Walmart ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip Navigation. Jump to Side Bar. 
 Return to the homepage 
 Search 
 
 Norfolk, VA Forecast 7-Day Interactive Radar 

80°

Partly Cloudy
 
 Home News MyCity Weather Traffic Sports Entertainment Video Community Marketplace Eagle Cam Login 


 Business: Location: 
 Auto Dealers Auto Repair Bar Carpet Cleaning Child Care Chocolate Coffee Dentist Doctor Florists Furniture Golf Course Gym Hair Salon Hotels Insurance Jewelry Landscaping Locksmith Movers Pizza Plumbing Realtor Remodeling Storage Browse all» 
 by MojoPages 
 
 Home 
 
Print
 
 print 

Email

 Email this article 

Share

 Tweet Share 

Share!
 X Digg Delicious MySpace LinkedIn StumbleUpon Newsvine Reddit 
 
 
Green Mountain Coffee Roasters bringing 800 jobs to Isle of Wight Co.
 
Associated Press/ WVEC.com
 
Posted on October 28, 2011 at 11:39 AM

Updated
 Friday, Oct 28 at 5:22 PM
 
Related:

 Green Mountain Coffee holding job fair in Suffolk today add to reading list 
 
Gallery

 

 See all 3 photos» 
 

ISLE OF WIGHT -- Vermont-based Green Mountain Coffee Roasters, Inc. is coming to Isle of Wight County.

Gov. Bob McDonnell said Friday that the company, a leader in specialty coffee and coffeemakers, will establish a production and distribution facility in Windsor. It will invest $180 million over the first five-years of operations.

The company has agreed to purchase a 330,000-square-foot building on a 64-acre parcel of land in the Shirley T. Holland Intermodal Park in Windsor to house coffee roasting, grinding, flavoring, and packaging of its single-serve portion packs for its Keurig®Single-Cup Brewing System.

Within five years, it is estimated the new facility will have as many as 800 employees. Average salaries will be $40,000 a year. Green Mountain Coffee plans to invest $180 million over the next five years.

The region suffered a huge economic blow in 2009 when International Paper closed its mill in Franklin, eliminating 1,100 jobs.

Judy Begland, president and CEO of Opportunity Inc., which is a workforce development organization, hopes it will turn things around for a lot of locals.

&quot;We&apos;re very excited that many of the people that were maybe displaced from that closure might have opportunities here,&quot;Begland said.

McDonnell said in a statement,&quot;The region continues to rebound after experiencing devastating job losses, and this project will put 800 Virginians back to work.&quot;

Jon Wettstein, a Green Mountain vice president, credited Virginia&apos;s&quot;appealing business incentives&quot;and labor force in selecting the Isle of Wight location.

The governor is excited to report the great news.

&quot;This investment is of the size that really I believe will be transformational for Isle of Wight, and by all the smiles on your faces, you believe that to be true,&quot;stated McDonnell.

Wettstein concluded,&quot;Up there in Vermont, we hear so much about Virginia is for lovers. One day, we hope one day some would say Virginia is for coffee lovers.&quot;

Green Mountain operates production and distribution centers in California, Massachusetts, Tennessee, Vermont, Washington and Canada. 

 
   
 
Print

 print 

Email

 Email this article 

Share

 Tweet Share 

Share!
 X Digg Delicious MySpace LinkedIn StumbleUpon Newsvine Reddit 
 
 
 
 Next article Presidential visit will temporarily shut down ORF on Friday 
 
 
Home Video

 
 Newport News Weather and News 

 Newport News Police tracking down federal fugitive add to reading list   
 
 Virginia Beach Weather and News 

 Rudy Giuliani rallying support for Romney in Va. Beach add to reading list   
 
 Local News 

 Searchers in Dare Co. look for clues to missing Ohio woman add to reading list   
 
 Featured Videos 

 Bull shark strikes as fish is reeled in add to reading list   
 
 Hampton Roads, Virginia Weather 

 WEATHER: The heat is coming back add to reading list   
 
 Community 

 Adopt-a-thon marks Norfolk SPCA&apos;s 120th year add to reading list   
 
 Virginia Beach Weather and News 

 Thousands line up for tickets to see President Obama on Friday add to reading list   
 
 News 

 Volunteers to tackle fishing line dangers in Va. Beach lakes add to reading list   
 
 News 

 Americans step up credit card use sharply in May add to reading list   
 
 More Video 
 Sign Out Profile 
 
 Mobile RSS Feeds Special Offers Newsletters Twitter Facebook Weather Weather Text Alerts 
 
Video

 
 Newport News Weather and News 

 Newport News Police tracking down federal fugitive add to reading list   
 
 Virginia Beach Weather and News 

 Rudy Giuliani rallying support for Romney in Va. Beach add to reading list   
 
 Local News 

 Searchers in Dare Co. look for clues to missing Ohio woman add to reading list   
 
 Featured Videos 

 Bull shark strikes as fish is reeled in add to reading list   
 
 More Video 
Most Popular

 Most Viewed Most Emailed 
 
 Va. Beach father dies protecting son on jet ski Thousands line up for tickets to see President Obama on Friday Police seek two more suspects in 4th of July boathouse beating Update: 3 more arrests made in Poquoson marina assault Mother charged after 2-year-old found wandering Suffolk trailer park 
 
 Shots fired at Newport News apartment complex Va. Beach father dies protecting son on jet ski Courtland man writes book, &quot;How to Live Without a Pancreas&quot; Thousands line up for tickets to see President Obama on Friday 
 More&gt;&gt; 
 Home News MyCity Weather Traffic Sports Entertainment Video Community Marketplace Eagle Cam 
 WVEC.com 757-625-1313 (phone) 757-628-5855 (fax) news@wvec.com 
 Search 
 
 Contact Us Employment Advertising Terms Of Service Privacy Policy UPDATED: Privacy Policy 
 
© 2009-2012 WVEC Television, Inc., a subsidiary of Belo Corp. All Rights Reserved.

Powered by Broadcast Interactive Media .
	</body>
</document>
