<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006745" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20070102123631AA1dlm0" time="2012-07-12-23:44" support="1" score="0.0022034707743971444" bingtitle="What is the official name for a fast food restaurant worker ..." webtitle="What is the official name for a fast food restaurant worker? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="110"/>
	<description>A Fast Food Restaurant Worker. I know what your thinking, your ... If you&apos;re asking for a resume I would say counter ... They are standing waiting for you to place your ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 bungle bill Member since: 28 November 2006 Total points: 148 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What is the official name for a fast food restaurant worker?

 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 by hobbit Member since: 04 October 2006 Total points: 575 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 unemployed musician?

student? 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 29% 4 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What is the official… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United Kingdom 
 
 Other Answers (1 - 30 of 36)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by HERBS Member since: 29 December 2006 Total points: 396 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 illegal immigrant 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by MANC&amp;PROUD Member since: 14 September 2006 Total points: 12,766 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Greasy tosser! 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by man with the golden gun Member since: 01 September 2006 Total points: 4,400 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 MACCHIPS 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 7% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Pink n Wise Member since: 01 September 2006 Total points: 1,775 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 A MUG! 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by James K Member since: 10 October 2006 Total points: 407 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 khan 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Antoine F Member since: 27 November 2006 Total points: 7,543 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 A Fast Food Restaurant Worker. I know what your thinking, your thinking that since they work at the restaurant, they must have special names, likeRallly&apos;s for example may have racers as their employee (not really). 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by po h Member since: 03 January 2007 Total points: 161 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 LOSER 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Teddy Bear Member since: 06 December 2006 Total points: 6,223 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 A&quot;Guest Service Representative. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by cavwife Member since: 29 June 2006 Total points: 1,578 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If you&apos;re asking for a resume I would say counter attendant or fast food customer respresentative 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by AL IS ON VACATION AND HAS NO PIC Member since: 08 November 2006 Total points: 5,012 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Team Member 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by chris a Member since: 19 August 2006 Total points: 1,801 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 food service worker and the one who feeds your lazy a$$ when you don&apos;t want to cook. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 7% 1 Vote 
 6 people rated this as good 
 by bowsling... Member since: 27 September 2006 Total points: 1,211 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Burger Flipper 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Modern Major General Member since: 31 December 2006 Total points: 39,504 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Humanities Graduate 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by 90210 aka Hummer Lover Member since: 09 July 2006 Total points: 10,550 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Geek 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by jenzi_e Member since: 28 June 2006 Total points: 760 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 team member
manager 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by monkey#1 Member since: 22 December 2006 Total points: 402 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 some1 who couldn&apos;t find a better job (ha,ha,ha)lol 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by grumpcoo... Member since: 06 September 2006 Total points: 13,736 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 catering assistant. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Barbie Member since: 19 November 2006 Total points: 17,848 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 it*s better than sitting at home being a bum ! don*t knock it till you try it ! i raised a child working at fast food ! 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by talula Member since: 20 June 2006 Total points: 507 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 USUALLY DIM :-/ 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by mrbush Member since: 15 February 2006 Total points: 6,258 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 All of the answers mentioned above. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 21% 3 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by King Kong Jr. Member since: 16 April 2006 Total points: 1,465 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 A parolee. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by The Dictator Member since: 08 May 2006 Total points: 137 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 A student, a thick sh1t,or an asylum seeker.As u can see there are 3 different names. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by LostVega... Member since: 27 December 2006 Total points: 3,045 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 UNDERACHIEVER!
I haven&apos;t met a fast food worker with brains.
Because, if you work in this kind of industry you didn&apos;t look too hard for a job.
Just a heads up.
Nordstroms pays stock people $10 to start,
which requires the same brain power.
Which is better than the minimum wage Taco Bell pays. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by LL Member since: 14 December 2006 Total points: 600 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 EXPLOITED 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 7% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by k_nntang Member since: 11 November 2006 Total points: 2,324 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 People who has no life. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by champagn... Member since: 19 November 2006 Total points: 36,238 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 a dumb spotty kid 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Christopher P Member since: 08 November 2006 Total points: 1,494 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Which one do you mean? There are quite a lot of people working in fast food outlets. The one in the kitchen is probably the chef. I think those standing behind the counter have similar titles to those in a cafe or a restaurant. They are standing waiting for you to place your order so waiter or waitress is the most likely official title. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by untanuta Member since: 12 October 2006 Total points: 5,641 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Team Member!!! 
Source(s):
 I work for a very well known Pizza Chain!! 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by mukyon1 Member since: 15 October 2006 Total points: 1,616 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 SLAVES. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Tessa&amp;Morgan♥* Member since: 02 January 2007 Total points: 118 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 a fast food restaurant worker idiot!! 
Source(s):
 my momma and joe dadda 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 
 
Go to Page

 1 2 Next&gt; 

36 results
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Fast food workers: You ever screw up some customer&apos;s food in… Why do fast food workers just stare at you? people are mean to fast food workers? Why do people (The average person) have little respect for… What&apos;s a good name for a fast food restaurant? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
