<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006947" url="http://couponing.about.com/cs/aboutcouponing/a/themeparksave.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:55" support="1" score="0.0013638546083778486" bingtitle="Theme Parks - Theme Park Savings - Coupons and Bargains - The ..." webtitle="Theme Parks - Theme Park Savings">
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>You can ease the financial anguish of visiting an amusement park this summer by ... Airline Specials &amp; Last Minute Online Savers; Frequent Flyer Programs; Rental Car ...</description>
	<body>
		Money 
 Coupons / Bargains Search 
 Coupons / Bargains Grocery Coupons&amp;Local Deals Couponing 101 Online Deals 

 Share 
 Free Coupons / Bargains Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Theme Park Savings 

Find Summer Vacation Discounts

By Donna L Montaldo , About.com Guide
 See More About: 
 disney world six flags busch garden 
 
You can ease the financial anguish of visiting an amusement park this summer by prudent shopping for ticket bargains.

 Disneyworld has many online vacation packages that have good discounts on rooms and discounted or free ticket packages. They also offer similar discounts to local visitors with special passes at about half the regular price.

Larger theme parks such as Six Flags and Busch Gardens offer memberships that include substantial savings on food, lodging, and entrance fees. You may also want to consider purchasing &quot;Season Passes&quot; to help cut costs. These passes allow for multiple visits and other conveniences such as early entrance for parking and exclusive ride times.

A lot of parks are offering seasonal discounts through national restaurant chains, fast food eateries, pizza places, soda cans and online sites. Keep your eye out for cross-promotions offered by several of the parks.

Other good resources for discounts on lodging, restaurants, and theme park admission include organizations such as AAA and other similar travel clubs. If driving to your destination, don&apos;t forget to browse the brochures located at the Welcome Centers along the highways. Not only will you find tremendous savings, but also letting the kids browse through them is an excellent source of entertainment for the duration of the drive.

Most hotels offer complimentary travel magazines, which include cutout savings coupons for local activities. Also prior to your trip, make a call to your destinations Chamber of Commerce or Tourist Center. They often will forward &quot;visitor packages&quot; full of coupon savings and discounted entrance passes. And finally, one of the best ways to find out the best deals available is too make a direct call to the Promotions division of the park that you plan to visit. Not only will they inform you of the best savings opportunities, but they can also provide you with a list of special activities going on during your visit.

 More: Don&apos;t Take a Vacation From Savings While Planning Your Vacation 
Suggested Reading

 Airline Specials&amp;Last Minute Online Savers Frequent Flyer Programs Rental Car Discounts 
 
Suggested Reading

 Hotel Coupons Restaurant Coupons Outlet Malls Offer Coupons Galore! 
 
Find the Perfect Vacation Clothing

 Clothing - Women Clothing - Men Clothing - Kids 
 Related Articles 
 Theme park vacation deals- ways to get discounts and savings at theme parks Theme Park Discounts - Save Money with Theme Park Discounts Petrified Forest National Park - Money Saving Tips for Visiting Petrified F... Carlsbad Caverns National Park - Money Saving Tips for Visiting Carlsbad Ca... Legoland California Water Park - Water Park at Legoland California 
 
 Donna L Montaldo 
Coupons / Bargains Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Related Searches theme park admission island water park national restaurant chains soda cans ticket bargains cross promotions Explore Coupons / Bargains Must Reads 
 Where to Find Coupons Outlet Mall Shopping Bargain Shoppers Quiz Coupon Directory Free Ecourse - Couponing for Beginners 
 Most Popular 
 Stores That Double Coupons Abercrombie Fitch Outlets Adidas Outlet Stores Brita Coupons Free Grocery Coupons 
 See More About: 
 disney world six flags busch garden 
 By Category 
 Couponing Basics All Online Coupons Free Printable Coupons Shopping Tips Apparel Deals Computer Deals Baby, Toy Deals Beauty&amp;Health Deals Entertainment Bargains Outlet Malls Restaurant&amp;Pizza Coupons Travel Deals Yard Sales, Auctions Grocery Savings 
 Coupons / Bargains 
 About.com Money Coupons / Bargains Travel Deals Theme Parks - Theme Park Savings 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
