<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006154" url="http://franklin.thefuntimesguide.com/2009/10/wolfgang_puck_express.php" time="2012-07-12-22:50" support="35" score="0.09004310114887669" bingtitle="Wolfgang Puck Express In Cool Springs - A Review - The Fun Times ..." webtitle="Wolfgang Puck Express In Cool Springs - A Review - The Fun Times Guide to  Franklin/Nashville, TN">
			<query id="001140" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001485" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000448" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000951" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001297" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000099" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>Like a fast food restaurant, the counter does have a menu board ... you receive a plastic tent with your order number on it ... I never go without ordering a cup of the ...</description>
	<body>
		Franklin/Nashville, TN 
 
 Fun Things To Do Restaurants&amp;Food Shopping&amp;Business Local Celebrities Franklin / Nashville Basics 
 Home&gt; Home &gt; Travel &gt; Restaurants&amp;Food &gt;Wolfgang Puck Express In Cool Springs–A Review 
Wolfgang Puck Express In Cool Springs–A Review
 
 As far as I know, Franklin’s Wolfgang Puck Express is a one-of-a-kind restaurant in this area. It’s gourmet food served fast. They call it&quot;fast-casual meals.&quot;

Wolfgang Puck Express takes the best qualities from fast food and gourmet dining and merges them.

I have been going for years now, and I have always had consistently great food served in minutes. 
 
 
 Here’s my review of Wolfgang Puck Express in Cool Springs, in case you’re thinking about going… 

 

 
 Placing Your Order 

When you go in, Wolfgang Puck Express in Cool Springs has a really different set up.

First, you place your order and pay at the counter.

Like a fast food restaurant, the counter does have a menu board above the cashier’s head, but unlike a fast food joint, it also has a flat screen TV playing images of Wolfgang Puck himself preparing meals.

 There is also a cooler in front of the cashier stocked with mineral water, wine, and beer.

After ordering, you receive a plastic tent with your order number on it to display on your table.

The dining area is very open and has a high ceiling. The colors are warm and the style is contemporary.

The kitchen is in the back and is open. There is even a counter with chairs surrounding it, if you prefer to watch the cooking.

After waiting only about 5 minutes, a waiter finds your number and brings your food. So it’s not McDonalds fast, but much better than the typical fine dining wait.

 
 

 How’s The Food? 

 The best part is the food! It really is gourmet, and there is a wide variety to choose from.

On the menu , they offer:
 
 salads soups sandwiches pastas pizzas classic entrees with fish, chicken, and more 
 
I never go without ordering a cup of the Butternut Squash soup. It’s great! I also like the Chinois Chicken Salad, Margarita Pizza, and Pesto Chicken Sandwich.

My husband and son always get the same thing when they go: barbeque chicken sandwich and macaroni and cheese, respectively.

Lucky for us, the price is not gourmet. It’s quite affordable:
 
 Salads are $8 Sandwiches are $7 Pastas are under $11 Individual pizzas are $8 Classic entrees are under $14 
 
 
 

 Kid-Friendly Dining 

Besides the food, another reason that I like Wolfgang Puck Express is because it’s kid-friendly . It is on our list of 2-year-old approved places—which means it’s just loud enough to not feel uncomfortable if it happens to get loud at our table.

Plus, you can get in and get out pretty quickly. We are not the only ones that feel this way, since I do see a lot of young families there. (But then again we do go early, around 5:30.) I have seen plenty of after work people drop in too.

 
 

 What About Tipping? 

 The one thing that was confusing to me with the merging of the 2 dining types is the subject of tipping.

Yes, you have a waiter, but they don’t take your order or bring a bill. They just bring the food to your table and then check on you.

So I asked about this. The cashier told me that you can tip at the counter when you pay and the entire staff shares it, although I got the impression that it’s optional. So, I decided to tip when I paid at the counter, but just a couple bucks, much less than the typical 18 percent.

 
 

 Location, Location, Location 

 Wolfgang Puck Express is located in a great area of Cool Springs. It’s in the same shopping area as Bed Bath and Beyond , right in between Starbucks and Carrabbas .

The address:
553 Cool Springs Blvd.
Franklin, TN 37067

You can even call ahead and pick up your meal. Their phone number is (615) 771-9066.

Here’s another review of Wolfgang Puck Express in Cool Springs.
 
 Related Posts 
 Learning Express Toy Store In Cool Springs Royal Thai Restaurant In Cool Springs Boscos In Cool Springs - Great Food&amp;Good Beer! Franklin, TN Restaurants: These Are The Best! 
 Lindsy 

I live in Franklin with my husband and our toddler son. I enjoy writing about our experiences visiting places in Franklin, Cool Springs, and the Brentwood area.

 More Posts 
 Filed Under: Restaurants&amp;Food , Travel Tagged With: restaurant reviews Loading 
Get Fun Things To Do in Nashville Via Email
 Enter your email address:

 
 
 Most Popular This Week 
 Best Places To See Celebrities In Nashville Franklin, TN Restaurants: These Are The Best! Alan Jackson&apos;s House... Living Like Royalty In Franklin, Tennessee! Best Places To Shop For Building Materials&amp;Home Decor Items In The Nashville Area My Tribute To Sara Evans... Nashville Area Spraygrounds Are FREE Water Parks&amp;Fun For All Ages! 
 Return to top of page 
 
Copyright©2012 The Fun Times Guide to Franklin/Nashville, TN · Privacy Policy · About · Contact · Advertise
	</body>
</document>
