<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006197" url="http://thehappyhousewife.com/real-life/cracker-barrel-valentines-gift-basket-giveaway/" time="2012-07-12-22:53" support="1" score="0.0015594548532615348" bingtitle="Cracker Barrel Valentines Gift Basket Giveaway" webtitle="Cracker Barrel Valentines Gift Basket Giveaway">
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>... love not having to wonder what might be in my food ... I usually order chicken and dumplins with an extra ... meal for the same amount I would spend at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Journal Kids Fun Tips Military 
 Making it in the Military Military Commissary Deals 
 Disney Archives 
 
Cracker Barrel Valentines Gift Basket Giveaway
 January 29, 2012 
Since this week I’m celebrating my four year blogging anniversary I thought it would be fun to host some giveaways!

I know you are going to love this first giveaway sponsored by Cracker Barrel. Just typing the name makes me hungry for their delicious cornbread, but I digress.

I have this awesome Valentine’s gift basket to give to one reader.

 

Included in the gift basket are Valentine’s Day treats, tidbit plates, mugs, and lots of other fun products from Cracker Barrel’s Old Country Store. You can check out all of Cracker Barrel’s Valentine’s Day treats on their website and enter to win this gift basket for yourself!

Divide up all the goodies in this gift basket to give as gifts or give yourself a little gift this Valentine’s Day! 

 To enter the giveaway leave a comment sharing what you love about Cracker Barrel. For additional entries you can follow Cracker Barrel on Twitter or “Like”them on Facebook . Please leave an additional comment for each extra entry.

 Giveaway ends January 31, 2012. 
 
 
 Tweet 
 
 This post may contain a link to an affiliate. See my disclosure policy for more information. 
 
Comments

 Wendi S says: January 29, 2012 at 6:44 pm 
I love the food…and the cozy fireplace 
 Kristy B says: January 29, 2012 at 6:53 pm 
We don’t have a cracker barrel near us, but I love the idea of the front porch rockers and old country store plus good food!
 Jenny says: January 29, 2012 at 7:14 pm 
The mac and cheese!
 maria says: January 29, 2012 at 7:36 pm 
I love their carrots.
 Darla says: January 29, 2012 at 7:37 pm 
Cracker Barrel has excellent food plus a fun country store–what’s not to love?!!
 Kris says: January 29, 2012 at 7:55 pm 
I love the fireplace inside..warm&amp;comfy. Also the chicken and rice on Saturdays is really good!!
 Kris says: January 29, 2012 at 7:56 pm 
I already like Cracker Barrel on Facebook!
 Julie says: January 29, 2012 at 8:32 pm 
I love their pancakes!
 Serenity says: January 29, 2012 at 8:34 pm 
I LOVE Cracker Barrel!!!! While in training in Arkadelphia, Arkansas I ate at Cracker Barrel for three meals a day for 6 weeks! It was the only decent restaurant in town and I STILL love it after consuming so much of it 
 Yvonne says: January 29, 2012 at 8:34 pm 
We live in CA and we don’t have a cracker barrel, but every time we go to Arizona to visit my brother, we also stop there to eat.
 Yvonne says: January 29, 2012 at 8:35 pm 
I follow cracker barrel on fb.
 Barbara says: January 29, 2012 at 8:57 pm 
I love their cinnamon apples and country fried steak.
 Barbara says: January 29, 2012 at 8:58 pm 
I already follow Cracker Barrel on Facebook.
 Barbara says: January 29, 2012 at 8:59 pm 
I already follow Cracker Barrel on Twitter.
 Parker says: January 29, 2012 at 9:02 pm 
I love the reliability and consistency of Cracker Barrel! And, of course, the country store.
 Annette says: January 29, 2012 at 9:03 pm 
We love Cracker Barrel because they always can handle our large family (including two babies!) with grace.
 Annette says: January 29, 2012 at 9:04 pm 
Following Cracker Barrel on Twitter.
 Lora @ my blessed life says: January 29, 2012 at 9:04 pm 
Well, there are LOTS of things I love about Cracker Barrel, but probably the thing I love the most is their Hashbrown Casserole!!
 Annette says: January 29, 2012 at 9:05 pm 
Liked Cracker Barrel on Facebook
 Lora @ my blessed life says: January 29, 2012 at 9:06 pm 
I *liked* their FB page!
 Lora @ my blessed life says: January 29, 2012 at 9:07 pm 
I’m following them on Twitter now:)
 stephanie says: January 29, 2012 at 9:13 pm 
I love Thursday’s daily special: turkey plate. Pair that with the hashbrown casserole, dumplins,&amp;pinto beans and YUMMY!!
 Elise Arango says: January 29, 2012 at 9:31 pm 
I love Cracker Barrel! There country store is super cute and I covet their rocking chairs every time I go!
 Courtney says: January 29, 2012 at 9:34 pm 
I love their biscuits and apple butter!! Mmmm….
 Courtney says: January 29, 2012 at 9:35 pm 
I liked them on Facebook.
 Diana says: January 29, 2012 at 9:36 pm 
I LOVE that you can“rent”a book on cd from one Cracker Barrel and then return it at another…it’s great for those road trips…Breakfast at one CB and lunch or dinner at another CB! What a genius idea!
 Tania S. says: January 29, 2012 at 9:39 pm 
Love the corn muffins, reminds me of the cornbread my grandfather used to make.
 Tania S. says: January 29, 2012 at 9:40 pm 
Following Cracker Barrel on Twitter.
 Tania S. says: January 29, 2012 at 9:40 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on Facebook.
 Heather H says: January 29, 2012 at 9:43 pm 
I love their fried okra!
 Piper says: January 29, 2012 at 9:47 pm 
We love the fireplace–the boysbget so excited to warm their hands and smell the smoke and listen to the crack and pop of the wood–it is such a cheery sound 
 Piper says: January 29, 2012 at 9:49 pm 
Liked on Facebook 
 Kristen says: January 29, 2012 at 9:51 pm 
BISCUITS!! Omigosh, do I love Cracker Barrel biscuits…..
 Kristen says: January 29, 2012 at 9:52 pm 
I like‘em on Facebook!
 crystal m says: January 29, 2012 at 10:14 pm 
My favorite thing about Cracker Barrell is that it is where my husband and I went on our first date!
 Joanne says: January 29, 2012 at 10:21 pm 
I like having something to do while you wait at Cracker Barrel…checkers outside, golf tee game inside.
 Lizzy says: January 29, 2012 at 10:39 pm 
I love the atmosphere there! Every one is friendly and it makes me feel like I am at home, even if I am traveling!
 Lizzy says: January 29, 2012 at 10:46 pm 
I like Crackel Barrel on Facebook!
 Lizzy says: January 29, 2012 at 10:46 pm 
I follow Crackel Barrel on twitter.
 Angela from Sunny San Diego says: January 29, 2012 at 11:01 pm 
I LOOOVE Cracker Barrel. I had never been to one let alone heard of one til I married a southern boy in 1999. Lived in Alabama for 6 years and fell in love with Cracker Barrel and all the yummy delights they have. I could spend all day looking around in the store and have purchased many things there. I love Cracker Barrel so much that last weekend a few girlfriends and I drove THREE HOURS from San Diego, CA to Yuma, AZ to eat at Cracker Barrel. Now if that isn’t dedication I don’t know what is. I LOVE the sweet tea, corn muffins, spiced apple butter and their hasbrown casserole. Delish!!!!
 SalBug says: January 29, 2012 at 11:15 pm 
I love everything there! But if I have to say one thing, it would be the mac&amp;cheese.
 Steph says: January 29, 2012 at 11:32 pm 
Love the breakfast, and family style seating
 Steph says: January 29, 2012 at 11:38 pm 
I also“liked”them on FB
 Delanna Lynch says: January 30, 2012 at 12:01 am 
Totally love not having to wonder what might be in my food–straight forward, down-home, nothing exotic kinda food! 
 Delanna Lynch says: January 30, 2012 at 12:02 am 
Liked them on FB!
 Charity says: January 30, 2012 at 12:20 am 
Chicken and dumplings…and their shirts! 
 Charity says: January 30, 2012 at 12:21 am 
Liked on FB!
 L larson says: January 30, 2012 at 12:37 am 
Love the home-style cooking! Always fun to shop before or after eating.
 Solducky says: January 30, 2012 at 3:19 am 
Their food is awesome (my Dh LOVES their pancakes) and their store is so lovely to browse.

soluckyducky at gmail dot com
 Solducky says: January 30, 2012 at 3:20 am 
I like Cracker Barrel on FB as sarah linette
soluckyducky at gmail dot com
 Solducky says: January 30, 2012 at 3:21 am 
following them on Twitter as @DuckyBunny
soluckyducky at gmail dot com
 Ashley Currin says: January 30, 2012 at 6:40 am 
I love their homecooked food—and the fact that the prices are so reasonable!
 Ashley Currin says: January 30, 2012 at 6:43 am 
Liked Cracker Barrel on Facebook, as well!
 Lawanna says: January 30, 2012 at 6:53 am 
I haven’t been to one in awhile, but on warm days I like to sit outside on their rocking chairs while waiting for a table.
 Andrea says: January 30, 2012 at 7:36 am 
I love the entire menu of comfort food…But I have never been in the country store…Looks like I would loooove that too!
 Stephanie says: January 30, 2012 at 7:38 am 
I love the clean restrooms at Cracker Barrel!
 Shanna says: January 30, 2012 at 7:45 am 
The rockers, the store, the grilled chicken tenderloin. YUM!
 Shanna says: January 30, 2012 at 7:46 am 
I liked them on FB!
 Brenda H says: January 30, 2012 at 8:23 am 
The first thing I love about Cracker Barrel is their food!! LOVE that they serve breakfast food all day. And, the country store items are always fun to browse through too!
 carrie c says: January 30, 2012 at 9:05 am 
i love their store! i could always find something to buy….their food is great too, and always consistent.
 carrie c says: January 30, 2012 at 9:06 am 
“liked”them on fb
 Jordin says: January 30, 2012 at 9:43 am 
The hashbrown casserole! And everything else about it. 
 Shelly Sawicki Lash Neuhouser says: January 30, 2012 at 9:45 am 
Love the great food at Cracker Barrel and it is always fun to shop in the store.
 Kari says: January 30, 2012 at 9:45 am 
I love their fried chicken!
 nora fraser says: January 30, 2012 at 9:46 am 
I love Cracker Barrel and all their food! Breakfast food is the best food of the day as far as I am concerned.
 Hollie says: January 30, 2012 at 9:46 am 
Hashbrown casserole. Yum!
 Shelly Sawicki Lash Neuhouser says: January 30, 2012 at 9:47 am 
I like Cracker Barrel on facebook
 Shelly Sawicki Lash Neuhouser says: January 30, 2012 at 9:47 am 
I follow Cracker Barrel on twitter

@mneuhouser
 Mona says: January 30, 2012 at 9:47 am 
My husband discovered he liked fish after XX years at a Cracker Barrel. How fun that place is and something for EVERYONE. Thanks.
 Barbara Gallier says: January 30, 2012 at 9:48 am 
It’s my go-to place for the candied Jordan almonds for my husband!
 Leah says: January 30, 2012 at 9:48 am 
Whats not to love about cracker barrel. Its all so yummy!
 alizabeth says: January 30, 2012 at 9:48 am 
My husband and I just made a special 1 hour trip to the nearest Cracker Barrel for our anniversary dinner! We love the ambiance, the fireplace, the worn wooden floors….It is how I want my home to feel, comfortable, familiar like visiting an old friend and always being welcomed. We love their rockers and cannot wait for the day we can buy some for our porch…their food is delicious and we have always had good service..
 alizabeth says: January 30, 2012 at 9:49 am 
Liked them on Face Book too!
 Becky Milstead says: January 30, 2012 at 9:49 am 
I LOVE their chicken&amp;dumplings and biscuits on a cold day. Yum!
 Angel M says: January 30, 2012 at 9:50 am 
We love Cracker Barrel! The Uncle Herschel’s breakfast is my favorite and who can turn down the yummy fried apples? My boys love to sit in front of the fireplace and play checkers.
 Jen Flinn says: January 30, 2012 at 9:50 am 
My favorite part about Cracker Barrel is that EVERYTHING is delicious and we always have excellent service when we go. Also, I bought my favorite purse, ever, at the Country Store.
 Becky Milstead says: January 30, 2012 at 9:50 am 
I like Cracker Barrel on facebook 
 Jen Flinn says: January 30, 2012 at 9:50 am 
I liked them on Facebook.
 Jen Flinn says: January 30, 2012 at 9:51 am 
I follow them on twitter.
 Becky Milstead says: January 30, 2012 at 9:51 am 
I am following Cracker Barrel on twitter 
 Angela says: January 30, 2012 at 9:52 am 
I love the hashbrown casserole best!
 Jess B says: January 30, 2012 at 9:53 am 
I love the antique feel and store there! Not to mention the food is awesome! Thanks for the giveaway! FTM rocks!
 Jess B says: January 30, 2012 at 9:53 am 
Liked on FACEBOOK 
 Bobbi Jo C says: January 30, 2012 at 9:54 am 
We don’t have a cracker barrel near us, but when we travel south it is our choice of places to eat. I love the chicken and dumplings and most breakfast items. Yum, just thinking about it makes me hungry!!!
 Angie says: January 30, 2012 at 9:54 am 
Oh, we LOVE Cracker Barrel! It is the favorite for ALL of our vacations. Their food is the best and the shopping is awesome! They always have the awesome stuff!
 Julie says: January 30, 2012 at 9:54 am 
It has been a few years since I’ve been; however I remember good food with a warm atmosphere. The memory definitely has me ready to go back. 
 Kylie says: January 30, 2012 at 9:56 am 
My family loves just about everything about Cracker Barrel!
 Phyllis says: January 30, 2012 at 9:57 am 
I love their chocolate cobbler and the dumplings!!!!!!!!!!! I love to shop there too!
 Kristi G. says: January 30, 2012 at 9:58 am 
I’ve never tried Cracker Barrel so I don’t know how it tastes but would love to try it! 
 Danielle says: January 30, 2012 at 9:59 am 
I no longer live by a Cracker Barrel. I lOve everything about them! Food, store, atmosphere. Best pancakes ever!!
 Hemda Mercer says: January 30, 2012 at 9:59 am 
Wow, this isnt easy there are so many things to love about Cracker Barrel of course the food is good. I also love the fire place. I love the fact that so many of my friends love it too. I love running into other families and than end up sitting next to each other. I love the games on the table, I love how it feels like your at home with all the great country living. I love the gift shop and especially the CLEARANCE ISLE!
 Debra says: January 30, 2012 at 10:00 am 
We LOVE Cracker Barrel! The Chicken and Dumplings and the hashbrown casserole are delicious!! YUM!! We moved to Washington state 1 1/2 years ago…they do not have any Cracker Barrels!!! We should have checked all their locations before moving!!! We sure do miss that wonderful Southern Cooking!!
 Hemda Mercer says: January 30, 2012 at 10:00 am 
I love the rockers!
 Hemda Mercer says: January 30, 2012 at 10:01 am 
liked them on fb
 Becky b says: January 30, 2012 at 10:01 am 
I love their chicken and dumplings!
 Becky b says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
i liked them on fb!
 Crystal O says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
I love the homecooked food, the fireplace and the little toys they have on the tables for the children to enjoy! I absolutely adore the store also, it always has so many cute things.
 Erica says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
I love Cracker Barrel’s breakfast! Pretty much any of it. 
 Christa B says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
I love Cracker Barrel…but we don’t have them out here in California. The food is yummy and I love the country store.
 Erica says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
I follow you on FB.
 Anissa says: January 30, 2012 at 10:02 am 
Oh this is hard to choose. I guess I love the amazing Christmas decorations they have and especially the clearance of those ornaments. Love that they have the all veggie plate so I can have my carb overload of mac&amp;cheese and fried okra and hash browns. It is a fun and great place to visit and eat at! Oh, almost forgot the rental books on tapes that you can return at your next CB, this is great for road trips!
 Jan Johnson says: January 30, 2012 at 10:03 am 
The food!
 Martha says: January 30, 2012 at 10:04 am 
I too LOVE Cracker Barrels cornbread!!! I usually order chicken and dumplins with an extra order of cornbread! My hubby and I love the Peg Board game that’s always out on the table and we love to look or shop in the store!

Going to“like”their facebook page now!

Thanks for doing this! Hope I win!
 Brandy says: January 30, 2012 at 10:05 am 
Being able to get a taste of home when I am not home in NC! Oh, and their Biscuits 
 Crystal O says: January 30, 2012 at 10:05 am 
I liked Cracker Barrel on fb
 Karen says: January 30, 2012 at 10:05 am 
I love the hashbrown casserole.
 Michele says: January 30, 2012 at 10:07 am 
Never been to a Cracker Barrel but it looks and sounds like a wonderful place to eat! I’ve never heard anything bad!
 Emily says: January 30, 2012 at 10:11 am 
I love the food, the decor, the atmosphere. I love the friendly staff, the rocking chairs. It’s Southern goodness all the way around.
 LeAnn says: January 30, 2012 at 10:16 am 
I love their biscuits and jelly, and of course the gift shop
 LeAnn says: January 30, 2012 at 10:17 am 
I“liked”Cracker Barrell on Facebook
 Kristen says: January 30, 2012 at 10:18 am 
I love the food! Some many different kinds, that it is hard to choose when you eat there!
 Connie Beard says: January 30, 2012 at 10:18 am 
I love to look around the store before being seated. I haven’t eaten there in several years, but I love their fried apples!
 Jennifer maldonado says: January 30, 2012 at 10:19 am 
I love their cozy atmosphere and biscuits with gravy!!!
 Jackie Huvane says: January 30, 2012 at 10:20 am 
I like the quick, reliable service when I am on a road trip.
 Betty says: January 30, 2012 at 10:21 am 
I love Cracker Barrel. It has good old fashioned cooking. Love it!!
 Diana Walker says: January 30, 2012 at 10:21 am 
The food is WONDERFUL and the store is FANTASTIC!!
 Casey says: January 30, 2012 at 10:27 am 
I LOVE Cracker Barrel! I love going there after church for their Sunday fried chicken. And I love everything in their store!
 Casey says: January 30, 2012 at 10:27 am 
I like Cracker Barrel on FB.
 Donna says: January 30, 2012 at 10:29 am 
love their biscuits
 Donna says: January 30, 2012 at 10:29 am 
liked them on facebook
 Sue says: January 30, 2012 at 10:32 am 
I love eating by the fireplace. I love the country atmosphere.
 Hannah S. says: January 30, 2012 at 10:37 am 
I have never been there but it sounds really amazing!!
all country and every thing!!
 Maria says: January 30, 2012 at 10:39 am 
They alwasy have what I want.
 Terri Gossage says: January 30, 2012 at 10:42 am 
Their biscuits are the best—slathered in butter of course!
 Jacqueline says: January 30, 2012 at 10:42 am 
I love the memories I have of sharing time with family and friends there. One of my favorite memories is of our youngest daughter“teaching”her Great Aunt to play checkers there.
 Beth says: January 30, 2012 at 10:43 am 
They have a GREAT kid menu and I LOVE their pancake mix!!
 Dawn says: January 30, 2012 at 10:44 am 
When I was pregnant, I craved their lima beans…which only some stores have them on Saturdays. I also love their french toast for breakfast in the afternoon. By the way, they have an amazing gift shop.
 Amanda says: January 30, 2012 at 10:45 am 
When I was a kid (in the 1990s) my parents use to travel down south just for Cracker Barrel food. There was none near us in New Hampshire. I loved the drive down and we would go to 3 or 4 Cracker Barrels the entire trip. Now I take my family occasionally and it still brings back fun family vacation memories.&lt;3
 Melessa says: January 30, 2012 at 10:47 am 
Chicken and dumplings!
 Teri says: January 30, 2012 at 10:52 am 
I love any place I can shop and eat at the same time!!! Seriously though I
love their cornbread muffins and had their fried fish the other night and it was
delicious!
 Blair @ The Straightened Path says: January 30, 2012 at 10:52 am 
What a FUN giveaway! I love all the old timey yet unique gifts they have in their shop. I also enjoy going to eat there with my parents as there is something for everyone. Gotta love those rocking chairs to wait in as well!
 Darlene Mitchell says: January 30, 2012 at 10:52 am 
I like Cracker Barrel too.They have great food!
 Blair @ The Straightened Path says: January 30, 2012 at 10:52 am 
I now like Cracker Barrel on Facebook. 
 The Happy Wife/Danielle Garcia says: January 30, 2012 at 10:53 am 
I love the homemade flavor to their food.
 The Happy Wife/Danielle Garcia says: January 30, 2012 at 10:53 am 
I follow Cracker Barrel on Twitter (The_Happy_Wife)
 The Happy Wife/Danielle Garcia says: January 30, 2012 at 10:54 am 
I like Cracker Barrel on facebook.
 Tiffany Miner says: January 30, 2012 at 10:55 am 
Their hash brown casserole! I so wish we had a Cracker Barrel where we live!
 Beki says: January 30, 2012 at 10:57 am 
I love the chicken and dumplings!! Yummy!
 Gena in Texas says: January 30, 2012 at 10:57 am 
It makes you feel at home. Love the food and the country store! Need to get back to one soon and rock in those awesome rocking chairs!
 Gena in Texas says: January 30, 2012 at 10:58 am 
I liked them on FB!
 Elizabeth says: January 30, 2012 at 11:01 am 
I love being able to look at fun things while I wait for a table!
 Melis in Wis. says: January 30, 2012 at 11:02 am 
The farmhouse atmosphere…and the dumplings! Yum!
 Elizabeth says: January 30, 2012 at 11:02 am 
I“like”Cracker Barrel on facebook.
 cindy says: January 30, 2012 at 11:04 am 
I love the ability to rent audio books on the road and return them on the road. Not to mention the fantastic selection of sweets!
 Renee says: January 30, 2012 at 11:09 am 
I love the huge fireplace inside, especially on those really cold days, the yummy foods and the rocking chairs on the front porch.
 Tearza says: January 30, 2012 at 11:09 am 
I love Cracker Barrel. They don’t have any up in Pennsylvania so when I moved down here to Texas it kinda reminded me a bit of the small deli we used to go to. They had a nice warm fireplace and delicious home cooking food. Also my first Christmas with my fiancee, his church had a raffle and I won a breakfast basket with their pancake mix and coffee and it was so good to have a taste of it in our home I would love to win this!
 Tammie says: January 30, 2012 at 11:10 am 
I like their Chicken&amp;Dumplings! YUMMY! 
 Tearza says: January 30, 2012 at 11:11 am 
I also liked Cracker Barrel on FB under (Tearza Smith)
 Sherri says: January 30, 2012 at 11:12 am 
Love the food, it’s all good and the old time candies in the store. Lots of fun things to look at while you wait.
 Cindy J says: January 30, 2012 at 11:13 am 
Thanks for your blog It is one of my favorites! Ok, I love Cracker Barrel’s country fried steak. Yummy. I love that you can go there and shop for nostalgic candy, toys, etc. Fun place.
 Cindy J says: January 30, 2012 at 11:14 am 
I follow Cracker Barrel on FB.
 Sarah says: January 30, 2012 at 11:21 am 
I love the food esp pecan pie soooo good plus the old fashioned candy dont forget sitting in the rockers playn games
 Sarah says: January 30, 2012 at 11:21 am 
Liked em on fb too!
 paula says: January 30, 2012 at 11:22 am 
We love Cracker Barrel because we get to visit with family out of state in a fun enviornment and eat yummy food!
 Sue D says: January 30, 2012 at 11:22 am 
I like their food, the decor and atmosphere and the rocking chairs.
 Teresa Matz says: January 30, 2012 at 11:23 am 
Love the food, atmosphere and the store. We don’t have one close by so this would be a fun treat 
 Gail says: January 30, 2012 at 11:24 am 
Their comfort food and the fun things you can find in their gift shop!
 Robin in New Jersey says: January 30, 2012 at 11:25 am 
I love their chicken potpies. But you can only get them on Wednesday at lunch time. 
 Kelly Pitt says: January 30, 2012 at 11:26 am 
I love their bisquits!!!!
 kathleen says: January 30, 2012 at 11:27 am 
i have never had cracker barrel but would love to try them.
 dee johnson says: January 30, 2012 at 11:28 am 
We have a family tradition in the fall of all 6 of us going to Cracker Barrel and enjoying a great big delicious country breakfast. We often do this before/after we go apple picking. It holds such fun memories of the kids playing checkers, shopping, and rocking away by the big fire. The pancakes are MY favorite, the buttery crisp edges with a sweet syrup topping….oh, I wanna go NOW!
This set would sure be a delightful valentine gift! Thanks for sharing it with us!
 Tara H says: January 30, 2012 at 11:31 am 
Growing up we only went to Cracker Barrel on trips so I love stopping there when we now take our family on trips! I love the chicken and dumplings!
 Terri says: January 30, 2012 at 11:32 am 
Great food…great atmosphere….and a fun shop for breaks on road trips! 
….. liking them on Facebook now!…..
 Satha Vorwaller says: January 30, 2012 at 11:33 am 
I love the food!
 Lauren says: January 30, 2012 at 11:34 am 
I love ALL things Cracker Barrel!!! But I do really love that you can shop and eat all at the same place!
 Lauren says: January 30, 2012 at 11:37 am 
I always get their Chicken and Dumplings! Yummm…Now we have to go there tonight!!! I also love that while you wait, you can rock on the porch, or you can shop!! I love Cracker Barrel! (I liked Cracker Barrel on Facebook.)
 Marija says: January 30, 2012 at 11:40 am 
Everything! 
 Rachel Dow says: January 30, 2012 at 11:53 am 
What’s not to love about Cracker Barrel? The food, the staff, the music, the atmosphere, did I mention the food? ;o) I would love to win this gift basket! Who wouldn’t?!
 Rachel Dow says: January 30, 2012 at 11:54 am 
I“liked”Cracker Barrel on FB!
 Amy says: January 30, 2012 at 12:00 pm 
Hashbrown Casserole…Yum!!!
 Amy E. says: January 30, 2012 at 12:04 pm 
I LOVE their ham and hashbrown casserole. I also love sitting by their cozy fireplace when it’s cold outside.
 Amy E. says: January 30, 2012 at 12:05 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on facebook, of course! 
 Amy says: January 30, 2012 at 12:06 pm 
Love that you can shop and eat all in one place!
 Valerie says: January 30, 2012 at 12:16 pm 
I love the breakfast!!
 amanda says: January 30, 2012 at 12:17 pm 
Playing games at the table reminds me to focus on my kids a little more.
 Cindy says: January 30, 2012 at 12:18 pm 
I will confess….I actually like their store even more than the food! I know, how can that be, but it is true. They have the most unusual and cute stuff and I love to browse the store…after I have eaten OF COURSE!
 Jana says: January 30, 2012 at 12:18 pm 
I love the atmosphere in Cracker Barrel. My kids love to play the peg game and munch on those yummy biscuits while we wait on our order.
 Amber W. says: January 30, 2012 at 12:19 pm 
I love their coffee and pecan pancakes!
 Amy B says: January 30, 2012 at 12:26 pm 
I like their roasted chicken…yum!
 Hailey says: January 30, 2012 at 12:30 pm 
Pecan pancakes are my favorite!!!!
 Stacie Fontinell says: January 30, 2012 at 12:30 pm 
We don’t have a cracker barrel. But it sure looks good!
 Cathy Keeling says: January 30, 2012 at 12:31 pm 
I love their home style atmosphere…everything from the food, to games at the table, decor, and their gift shop!
 Cathy Keeling says: January 30, 2012 at 12:32 pm 
I follow Cracker Barrel on facebook.
 Kristina Best says: January 30, 2012 at 12:42 pm 
I love everything about Cracker Barrel…The family friendly is awesome!
 Amy Johnson says: January 30, 2012 at 12:45 pm 
I love the Cracker Barrel!! Everything is wonderful, but my favorites are the Hashbrown Casserole and the Fried Apples–YUMMY !!! I also love their country store 
 Kisti Huffman says: January 30, 2012 at 12:47 pm 
I love their concern for good service. Our local restaurant gave us a free meal (all 4 of us) plus gave us an additional gift card for anything we wanted on our next meal (for 4). They had been especially busy and had messed up part of our order. The manager was great at making sure we were taken care of.
 Kisti Huffman says: January 30, 2012 at 12:48 pm 
I just“liked”Cracker Barrel. 
 Angie V says: January 30, 2012 at 12:50 pm 
Love the Cracker Barrel, has become a vacation must when we travel to Florida from Ohio. There is one in Georgia we always stop at. Love the staff and the ability to everyone have choices to eat what they want. Love walking though the shop and seeing what all is new. Always find a clean restroom which is wonderful when traveling.
 Angi says: January 30, 2012 at 12:51 pm 
I love that I can feed my family a nutritious meal when we are out and about, AND it doesn’t cost much more than fast food.
 Angie V says: January 30, 2012 at 12:52 pm 
Thanks for allowing us to enter this wonderful giveaway. I also follow them on FB 
 Carmen at Old House Kitchen says: January 30, 2012 at 12:55 pm 
I love the down-home country feel about the Cracker Barrel! Yee haw!
 Andrea D. says: January 30, 2012 at 12:56 pm 
I love the Cracker Barrel. I love their store the most and the variety of stuff that they have in it.
 Andrea D. says: January 30, 2012 at 12:58 pm 
I am a facebook fan of Cracker Barrel. Thanks for the chance to enter.
 Michelle says: January 30, 2012 at 1:07 pm 
I love the country store, the yummy food, and the cozy fireplace. And what other restaurant serves chicken livers? Yum!
 Amy C. says: January 30, 2012 at 1:12 pm 
When we lived in Arizona&amp;it was impossible to find sweet tea, we knew we could always find some at Cracker Barrel! Made me feel like I wasn’t quite so far away from home!
 Mom24jewels says: January 30, 2012 at 1:13 pm 
I love their gift shop, although it can be pricy, they do have good sales. Their food is good too.
 Amy C. says: January 30, 2012 at 1:13 pm 
Oh, and we also love shopping in their little store–the old timey candies, Christmas ornaments, small toys for road trip treats, etc. Great stuff in there! 
 Mom24jewels says: January 30, 2012 at 1:13 pm 
“like”them on facebook.
 stacy says: January 30, 2012 at 1:19 pm 
I’ve never been to one before but have heard the food is delicious. Would love to win the basket!
 Jitka says: January 30, 2012 at 1:19 pm 
I love their biscuits and crackers:)
 Kristy says: January 30, 2012 at 1:30 pm 
I love browsing through the country store!
 Brandi says: January 30, 2012 at 1:32 pm 
I love that when we travel we can almost always count on finding a CB to have a meal! Yum!
 Linda B. says: January 30, 2012 at 1:44 pm 
I love the blueberry pancakes!
 Jackie Brown says: January 30, 2012 at 1:44 pm 
we love the b’fast coming home from vacation
 Jackie Brown says: January 30, 2012 at 1:44 pm 
i like, i mean love CB on fb
 Kristy says: January 30, 2012 at 1:45 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on FB.
 katie says: January 30, 2012 at 1:59 pm 
I love their pancakes and the syrup for them!
 KathyM says: January 30, 2012 at 2:00 pm 
I love their country store and the little games on the tables to keep the kids busy while we wait for our food!
 Kristin says: January 30, 2012 at 2:07 pm 
Our whole family loves Cracker Barrel! Xoxox YUMMY!
 Rachel says: January 30, 2012 at 2:10 pm 
Love Cracker Barrel. Would love to win.
 Rachel says: January 30, 2012 at 2:10 pm 
I am a fan of Cracker Barrel on Facebook.
 Shonda says: January 30, 2012 at 2:27 pm 
Ohhhhhhh, I LOVE Cracker Barrel–my favorite thing is that we can take the family out for a“homecooked”meal and I don’t have to do any of the work! I also love to browse through the shop while we wait.
 Sheila says: January 30, 2012 at 2:32 pm 
I like browsing the little store they have.
 Amber S says: January 30, 2012 at 2:59 pm 
Fried okra! 
 Amber S says: January 30, 2012 at 3:00 pm 
Liked them on facebook.
 jen n says: January 30, 2012 at 3:12 pm 
love it all!
 jessie says: January 30, 2012 at 3:15 pm 
Chicken and rice–the Saturday special–is my absolute favorite!
 Mindy says: January 30, 2012 at 4:00 pm 
Love Cracker Barrel! When we lived in California, where there are no Cracker Barrels, my friend and I kidnapped our husbands and made them drive 2 1/2 hours to Arizona to take us to one! 
 Mindy says: January 30, 2012 at 4:02 pm 
I“liked”Cracker Barrel on Facebook. 
 Jamie says: January 30, 2012 at 4:03 pm 
I love the yummy food at Cracker Barrel and all the fun items in their store.
 Wendy Rozema says: January 30, 2012 at 4:05 pm 
I love the atmosphere&amp;my favorite food there are their pancakes&amp;their amazing syrup!
 Jamie says: January 30, 2012 at 4:06 pm 
I am following Cracker Barrel on twitter. @rangersbraves
 Jamie says: January 30, 2012 at 4:06 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on facebook. Jamie L. H.
 Dorothy says: January 30, 2012 at 4:37 pm 
love cracker barrell’s atmosphere and hashbrown casserole:) We go there to eat breakfast on the way to our family mountain trip every October. It is an awesome tradition!
 Delina OLeary says: January 30, 2012 at 5:16 pm 
I love the sweet tea, chicken sandwiches and the toys they sell. 
 Delina OLeary says: January 30, 2012 at 5:18 pm 
I’m following them on twitter now! Thanks!
 Kassie says: January 30, 2012 at 6:09 pm 
The more I got to thinking about why I like Cracker Barrel the longer my list. I love the country store and all of the fun knick-knacks you can play with while you’re waiting for your table, the delicious bacon (but let’s be honest, when is bacon not delicious), I even like the odd vintage family photos that are all over. Like their fb 
 Carol says: January 30, 2012 at 6:15 pm 
My husband and I love their breakfast menu. We usually even order breakfast for dinner! We love the fireplace and country decorations….and enjoy looking around the gift shop.
 Mona says: January 30, 2012 at 8:00 pm 
I“liked”Cracker Barrell on FB:-)
 Colleen G. says: January 30, 2012 at 8:49 pm 
The shopping!!!
And the food is very good too.
-Colleen G.
 Ginger says: January 30, 2012 at 9:15 pm 
Their four or six vegetable plate. Yum!
 Sue Randazzo says: January 30, 2012 at 9:25 pm 
I love Cracker Barrel because it’s the only place I can find Moon Pies!
 Suki says: January 30, 2012 at 9:36 pm 
I love shopping in the Country Store while waiting for a table, eating yummy food, then shopping again before leaving!
 SamanthaR says: January 30, 2012 at 10:01 pm 
I love the ambiance at Cracker Barrel!
 Tina W says: January 30, 2012 at 10:14 pm 
I love how great the food is and that there’s always something to keep my 6 littles entertained!
 Marge says: January 30, 2012 at 10:22 pm 
I love the hashbrown casserole with Ham and the gift shop. thanks
 Judith says: January 30, 2012 at 11:00 pm 
Cracker Barrel…A place where you don’t have to get all duded up to enjoy down home cooking. Sort of like home without the dirty dishes.
 Judith says: January 30, 2012 at 11:02 pm 
I liked Cracker Barrel on FB.
 Heather says: January 30, 2012 at 11:05 pm 
I love the atmosphere in the Cracker Barrel stores.
 Heather says: January 30, 2012 at 11:07 pm 
I liked Cracker Barrel on Facebook
 Constance Crocker says: January 30, 2012 at 11:13 pm 
I’ll try to make a list: the stewed apples, the chicken livers, the breakfast plates, the antiques hung on the walls, the unique gifts in the store, the“southern”atmosphere, the candy, the biscuits, the fried okra, the friendliness of the employees, the game on each table, and, of course, the rocking chairs and checkers. I sure hope I didn’t forget anything.
 meagain2 says: January 30, 2012 at 11:20 pm 
I love the gift shop almost as much as the food
 Valerie says: January 30, 2012 at 11:45 pm 
I so love Cracker Barrel. We as a family love playing the games as we wait for our favorite biscuits or cornbread muffins. Personally my favorite meal is the chicken n’dumplings. Yum! I also love the kids clothes–my mil buys the holiday outfits for my girls and they love‘em.
 Bridget Harrison says: January 30, 2012 at 11:50 pm 
First off, what’s not to love?? But really I LOVE LOVE LOVE their Sunday Fried Chicken!! YUM
 Bridget Harrison says: January 30, 2012 at 11:51 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on Facebook!
 Marsha H. says: January 31, 2012 at 12:23 am 
I have never been to a Cracker Barrel, so I have no idea, but I have certainly heard good things from people who have gone there to eat.
 Marsha H. says: January 31, 2012 at 12:25 am 
I follow Cracker Barrel on facebook.
 Davina Prill says: January 31, 2012 at 3:08 am 
We actually just went there a few days ago for my moms birthday. The food is good but I love the store. I like how it has all the old country stuff and mixed gadgets and fun items along with the awesome selection of candy. I cant think of anything that I don’t like. 
 lisa cacho says: January 31, 2012 at 3:32 am 
Having no CB nearby I can only love the idea of CB–porches, country food, country people, hospitality. We are actually planning a drive to our nearest which is 5 hours away!
 lisa C says: January 31, 2012 at 3:33 am 
I am a fan of CB on facebook…
 Jessica says: January 31, 2012 at 4:18 am 
I love the rustic feel of cracker barrel and also the maple syrup!
 Jessica says: January 31, 2012 at 4:20 am 
I like cracker barrel on facebook
 Jessica says: January 31, 2012 at 4:20 am 
I follow cracker barrel on twitter @jfong1130
 Michelle says: January 31, 2012 at 5:38 am 
I like the rocking chairs!
 Karen says: January 31, 2012 at 6:35 am 
I like their biscuits.
 Kathy T says: January 31, 2012 at 7:21 am 
I LOVE those rockers and after about 20 years STILL hope to get one, one day.
 Lori says: January 31, 2012 at 7:29 am 
I enjoy their cornbread and sitting in the rockers while I wait to be seated! Someday I know I’ll have one of those rockers!!
 MichelleH says: January 31, 2012 at 8:40 am 
I love their salty ham and their awesome pancakes.
 Adela Terrazas says: January 31, 2012 at 9:14 am 
Love Cracker and Barrel food
 Adela Terrazas says: January 31, 2012 at 9:19 am 
I follow Cracker and Barrel on twitter
 Kelly T says: January 31, 2012 at 9:34 am 
I love there chicken n dumplings and there baby carrots. Plus all the old stuff hanging from the ceiling and on the walls is so neat to look at.
 mandi says: January 31, 2012 at 9:46 am 
I love the seasonal displays! They have unique gifts and I currently don’t have one where I live, but I stop at the one three hours away when I get that way!
 Monica says: January 31, 2012 at 3:15 pm 
THe thing I love most about Cracker Barrel is the peg game on the tables….good, clean competition (then there is the breakfast food!)
 Tina W says: January 31, 2012 at 3:36 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on Facebook.
 sunnie says: January 31, 2012 at 4:39 pm 
I have never been there id like to though!
 sunnie says: January 31, 2012 at 4:41 pm 
I like them on facebook
 Stacy C says: January 31, 2012 at 6:58 pm 
I love the food,but my kids love playing checkers by the fire.
 Pat Mickel says: January 31, 2012 at 7:00 pm 
I love their meatloaf and also the liver when they have it. I Also like the little store to browse in.
 Pat Mickel says: January 31, 2012 at 7:00 pm 
I liked them on Facebook.
 Jacqueline says: January 31, 2012 at 7:01 pm 
I LOVE cracker barrel! The food is amazing for my entire family, reasonable prices, and I love shopping after I get a belly full!
 christine says: January 31, 2012 at 7:01 pm 
I love the whole place!! The store is fun with all the old time candies and toys. The food is amazing!! I dont think I have oredered something there and not liked it! My favorite meal to get there is the country fried steak with gravy! So delicious!!
 alisha kever says: January 31, 2012 at 7:02 pm 
I LOVE shopping while my hubby pays the bill!
 Bridgett says: January 31, 2012 at 7:02 pm 
Their rocking chairs!
 christine says: January 31, 2012 at 7:02 pm 
I already like them on facebook!!
 Chelsee Bendtsen says: January 31, 2012 at 7:03 pm 
I love their pancakes with apple butter! Love Cracker Barrel
 Rhonda Barnett says: January 31, 2012 at 7:03 pm 
Oh my, I love wandering around the little store, looking at all the stuff hanging on the walls, the cozy seating/atmosphere, the biscuits and coffee. How do you choose just one thing? lol Ok, if I had to pick one, it’s the atmosphere.
 Chelsee Bendtsen says: January 31, 2012 at 7:03 pm 
Liked CB on FB
 Carrie Blackburn says: January 31, 2012 at 7:03 pm 
We love love love the country store and all the neat stuff to be found there. Of course, the fried okra never hurt a soul. 
 christine says: January 31, 2012 at 7:03 pm 
And now I follow them on twitter! 
 Chelsee Bendtsen says: January 31, 2012 at 7:04 pm 
LIked on Twitter
 Michelle says: January 31, 2012 at 7:04 pm 
We love the family atmosphere.
 Rhonda Barnett says: January 31, 2012 at 7:06 pm 
Liked Cracker Barrel on facebook!
 amy p says: January 31, 2012 at 7:07 pm 
what is not to love about cracker barrel they have so much great food love the dumplings , shrimp , apples and the list goes on and on….one of my favorite places to eat and shop their little store they have such cute things….
 Hannah says: January 31, 2012 at 7:07 pm 
I LOVE the cornbread and the cozy atmosphere!
 Amanda Gillenwater says: January 31, 2012 at 7:09 pm 
Just went there today! My favs are the ability to eat healthy country cooking, the checker boards, and the cozy fireplace. Thanks for hosting this giveaway!
Amanda
 Kristy says: January 31, 2012 at 7:21 pm 
I love Cracker Barrel b/c even if there is a wait you get to walk around their wonderful store or go outside if it’s nice and rock in their rocking chairs. Very nice!
 Kristy says: January 31, 2012 at 7:21 pm 
I like them on FB!
 Ryan A. says: January 31, 2012 at 7:23 pm 
I Love everything about Cracker Barrel! From their amazing food to their wonderful gifts! 
 Elizabeth McBride says: January 31, 2012 at 7:23 pm 
I love all their food. I love playing the game with the triangle and golf tees.
 Heather Patenaude says: January 31, 2012 at 7:24 pm 
I used to work there, they are a great company to work for!
 Heather Patenaude says: January 31, 2012 at 7:25 pm 
I liked them on FB as well!!
 Heather Patenaude says: January 31, 2012 at 7:26 pm 
I also followed them on twitter…so that should be three entries!

I am hosting a marriage conference and this would be a fun giveaway 
 kelly c says: January 31, 2012 at 7:27 pm 
their breakfast served all day–a fave. 
 LEAH says: January 31, 2012 at 7:29 pm 
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE, LOVE, LOVE ME SOME YUMMY TO MY TUMMY CRACKER BARREL! MMMMMMMMmmmmmmm! Makes me smile just thinking about it! It’s my absolutely FAV place to go eat on Friday Nights! It’s for sure the BOMB DIGGITY! 
 Kenda says: January 31, 2012 at 7:30 pm 
Love the home cooking!
 Robin says: January 31, 2012 at 7:33 pm 
The front porch! We love to eat there for breakfast.
 Robin says: January 31, 2012 at 7:34 pm 
I liked them on Facebook.
 Joyce McKnight says: January 31, 2012 at 7:36 pm 
I love their cornbread!!
 Tonya says: January 31, 2012 at 7:38 pm 
Great home cooked breakfasts and I love it in the winter when they have a fire in the fireplace during the meal. Fun, cute gifts in their gift shop, too.
 Rawny R. says: January 31, 2012 at 7:38 pm 
I love the atmosphere!
 Alisa Dellinger says: January 31, 2012 at 7:39 pm 
I love going Cracker Barrel on long road trips. Who doesn’t love country cookin and sweet tea. I craved chicken and dumplings my entire pregnancy.
 Christine S. says: January 31, 2012 at 7:40 pm 
I think the gift shop is the best part about Cracker Barrel! They have wonderful pancakes with fruit toppings too!

Christine in OH
 Kara says: January 31, 2012 at 7:45 pm 
Cracker Barrel Biscuits!!!!!!
 Jonathan says: January 31, 2012 at 7:46 pm 
I love the fireplace and checkers!! Dinner and games with my wife is always fun!
 BCamp says: January 31, 2012 at 7:48 pm 
We love the fried chicken breast special on Sunday!! Yum!
 Clair Herrera says: January 31, 2012 at 7:48 pm 
Love it all!! Cracker Barrel is a favorite for my family! The breakfast is great!
 Linda @ Linda&apos;s Lunacy says: January 31, 2012 at 7:50 pm 
What’s not to love about Cracker Barrel?! I love the family friendly atmosphere, the home style cooking and the gift shop!
 Linda @ Linda&apos;s Lunacy says: January 31, 2012 at 7:51 pm 
I follow Cracker Barrel on Twitter.

@LindasLunacy
 Linda @ Linda&apos;s Lunacy says: January 31, 2012 at 7:51 pm 
I like Cracker Barrel on Facebook.
 michelle says: January 31, 2012 at 7:53 pm 
Love, love, love Cracker Barrel,, especially when they clearance their childrens clothes. My family loveseating out there on family night.
 Whitney says: January 31, 2012 at 7:55 pm 
I LOVE their peach topping for their pancakes!
 Dauvy Ngy says: January 31, 2012 at 8:07 pm 
I LOVE. Cracker barrel’s has brown casserole, their blackberry jam they serve, country fried steak, pretty much a lot I really love their store at Fall and Christmas time
 Chris says: January 31, 2012 at 8:13 pm 
I have never tried cracker barrel because we do not have them in California. I really want to try them.
 Chris says: January 31, 2012 at 8:21 pm 
I liked cracker barrel on facebook
 Lorea says: January 31, 2012 at 8:25 pm 
Everything! Whats not to love?? Apples, hashbrown casserole, the list goes on and on.
 Beth says: January 31, 2012 at 8:42 pm 
I love Cracker Barrel’s fried apples! They are the perfect side for everything from pancakes to pork chops. Yum!
 Nancy Humphrey says: January 31, 2012 at 8:47 pm 
One word…Pancakes!!!!
 Stacy Constable says: January 31, 2012 at 8:48 pm 
I love the store, all the old candies we used to love when we were kids!!
 janna martinez says: January 31, 2012 at 8:49 pm 
I love thier menu. I like the variety of menu. MY personal feelings is your never leave hungry.
 Rachel says: January 31, 2012 at 8:52 pm 
I love Cracker Barrel because of the memories I have of them, not to mention the great food! It was were we stopped to eat just a few hours after I became a wife, on the way to our honeymoon! Ahh…memories…sweet…
 Linka Conkle says: January 31, 2012 at 9:00 pm 
I love the gift shop! There’s not one thing in there that I don’t want! Cracker barrel is like a trip to grandma’s!
 veronica says: January 31, 2012 at 9:04 pm 
I love the comfy atmosphere!
 shelley says: January 31, 2012 at 9:15 pm 
I love Sunday chicken dinner!! And the lima beans. Cracker Barrel is the best!!
 Lisa Smith says: January 31, 2012 at 9:26 pm 
I LOVE the chicken and dumplings and the rocking chairs!
 Jenny says: January 31, 2012 at 10:02 pm 
I love their blueberry pancakes, biscuits and gravy, and the cozy atmosphere.
 Sue says: January 31, 2012 at 10:39 pm 
Their food is great and the atmosphere makes it all come together!
 Lydia says: January 31, 2012 at 10:47 pm 
I love everything about Cracker Barrel!!! The best roast beef dinner I have ever had! I’m drooling just thinking about it now…Hot, tender, juicy beef with onion gravy, mashed potatos, sweet corn and fried okra. Plus the hot biscuits with butter and strawberry jam. Yum!!!! My all time favourite restaurant for good ole home cooking 
 Beth says: January 31, 2012 at 10:47 pm 
I love their little girl clothes and their old fashioned candy. They have great gifts!
 Lydia says: January 31, 2012 at 10:48 pm 
Liked on Facebook 
 Lydia says: January 31, 2012 at 10:49 pm 
Following on Twitter 
 Karen B says: January 31, 2012 at 11:12 pm 
I just love their chicken fried chicken with mashed potatoes&amp;the white gravy. Thanks for the giveaway, hope I win 
 Erica Bunce says: February 1, 2012 at 9:26 am 
I love that I can feed my family a good meal for the same amount I would spend at a fast food restaurant.
 LadyVampire says: February 1, 2012 at 10:26 am 
I like the friendly service and great products at Cracker Barrel.
 LadyVampire says: February 1, 2012 at 10:27 am 
Following Cracker Barrel on Facebook as Aprille Shadowspeak.
 LadyVampire says: February 1, 2012 at 10:27 am 
Following Cracker Barrel on twitter as @LadyVampire2u.
 LAMusing says: February 2, 2012 at 12:42 am 
I love the food and the prices! Sadly they no longr have one in Southern California 
 tyb4 says: February 2, 2012 at 7:10 am 
I love Cracker Barrel!! Some other gift ideas can be found at http://thingsyoubuyfor.com/valentinesday/ 
 Annette says: February 2, 2012 at 10:31 am 
I LOVE their“front porch”and my DD loves their“games”.
 Nicole says: February 2, 2012 at 5:59 pm 
In addition to the food, our family likes the cute games, toys and books they can get at the store.
 
 
Search Real Life
 

 
Support Our Sponsors
 
Books I’m Reading
 
 SuperFoods Rx: Fourteen Foods That Will Change Your Life 
 All New Square Foot Gardening: Grow More in Less Space! 

 Heaven at Home: Establishing and Enjoying a Peaceful Home 
 Seeing and Savoring Jesus Christ 
 





 
Our Story

 How I Came to Know the Long Haired Hippy How to Have a Frugal Wedding My First Attempt as The Happy Housewife The Summer in Which I Became Frugal and Long-Haired Hippie ate Meat Why I Should Have High-Tailed it Out of the Apartment Complex Why You Should Never Let Long Haired Boys Take Your Daughters to the Airport 
 
Blogs I Read
 
 Life in rough draft—by Amy Scott. 

 Confessions from a recovering pride addict 
 
 A Familiar Path 

 Random thoughts 
 
 Challies Dot Com–Informing the Reforming 

 How Many Hours Can I Work? 
 
Tweet Tweet

 @mygomom awesome! Looking forward to seeing you again. It&apos;s been a while. #sbsummit #savvyblogging about 32 mins ago How do you keep your pets safe in the summer heat. #KOACampfire http://t.co/FD3ULDrL about 2 hours ago You know I&apos;ve heard opera is the new.... um... new.... I got nothin. @ErikDiNardo @SavingLifestyle about 2 hours ago http://twitter.com/happyhousewife 
 
 HOME | CONTACT | ADVERTISING&amp;PR | DISCLOSURE | PRIVACY POLICY ©2008–2012 TheHappyHousewife.com. All rights reserved. | Design by Joy @ Five J&apos;s Design
	</body>
</document>
