<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006498" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/156/944878/restaurant/Piedmont-Triad/Jams-Deli-Greensboro" time="2012-07-12-23:25" support="2" score="0.004600155510107727" bingtitle="Jam&apos;s Deli - Greensboro | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Jam&apos;s Deli - Greensboro | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>It is setup like a fast food restaurant, you place your order and pay up front, and they call you when your order is ready. ... of booths available, so seating is ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Piedmont Triad » Greensboro » Jam&apos;s Deli 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Charleston Charlotte Hampton Roads Los Angeles New York Research Triangle Richmond More... 
 
Jam&apos;s Deli
 
(336) 547-0771
 Greensboro 5707 W Friendly Ave 
 Greensboro , NC 27410 See all 3 reviews Cuisine Sandwiches/Subs Menu $ Under $10 per entree Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   31 people have voted 93 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Kabuto Japanese Steakhouse 84% $$$ Greensboro - Steakhouse, Japanese, Sushi 1617 Stanley Rd 
 
 La Fiesta Mexican Restaurant 81% $ Greensboro - Mexican 1312 Bridford Pkwy Ste 103A 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Diner reviews are sorted by relevance

 April 26, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Cain ( 39 reviews ) It&apos;s just ok. The food isn&apos;t spectacular...just ok. Their claim to fame is that you don&apos;t tip the servers, which isn&apos;t enough to bring me back. October 1, 2011 Load Of Choices Here by QuakerHeel ( 496 reviews ) This place has been around for at least 25 years, in the same location, across from Guilford College - don&apos;t know if has been under the same ownership for that entire time. It is setup like a fast food restaurant, you place your order and pay up front, and they call you when your order is ready. There is not a lot of ambiance here, the interior is a little dark and worn, but it is charmingly funky. There are a number of booths available, so seating is not an issue. The parking lot is small and there are a number of businesses in the immediate area, so parking can be a problem at lunch peaks, but not so much at night. And there are front and back entrances. This is basically a soup, salad, and sandwich place, with the sandwiches being the real stars, although the other two are good as well. Great Club, Reuben, Italian Sub, Steak&amp;Cheese, Buffalo Chicken (you gotta try this one) and something they call a Zan-wich - pastrami, pepperoni, swiss cheese, and spicy mustard on... more» This place has been around for at least 25 years, in the same location, across from Guilford College - don&apos;t know if has been under the same ownership for that entire time. It is setup like a fast food restaurant, you place your order and pay up front, and they call you when your order is ready. There is not a lot of ambiance here, the interior is a little dark and worn, but it is charmingly funky. There are a number of booths available, so seating is not an issue. The parking lot is small and there are a number of businesses in the immediate area, so parking can be a problem at lunch peaks, but not so much at night. And there are front and back entrances. This is basically a soup, salad, and sandwich place, with the sandwiches being the real stars, although the other two are good as well. Great Club, Reuben, Italian Sub, Steak&amp;Cheese, Buffalo Chicken (you gotta try this one) and something they call a Zan-wich - pastrami, pepperoni, swiss cheese, and spicy mustard on rye - really nice. Also have burgers, hot dogs, fries pasta salad,house made potato chips (nice), and onion rings. Sandwiches come with choice of chips, curly fries, potato salad, or pasta salad - all at around $6.50, so these prices are reasonable. None of the sides are huge, but adequate. Reasonable, except for the hot dog, which is $4.95, again with a choice of sides. They do use a large wiener, but that still is a little pricey for a single dog. They do have a Double Dog plate that is 2 hot dogs&amp;a side for $5.25, so that second dog is only a buck. The hot dog is a pretty good one. They do offer beer, if you are so inclined. October 9, 2010 Mobile review by Tyler ( 23 reviews ) Good food, but nothing spectacular. To sum up in one word: dull. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Jacob Chandler Steak and cheese... 
 View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Boston Market 84% $ Greensboro - Fast Food, American Chinese Kitchen Restaurant 95% $ Greensboro - Chinese Elizabeth&apos;s Pizza 85% $ Greensboro - Pizza, Italian, Sandwiches/Subs McDonald&apos;s $ Greensboro - Burgers, American Hardee&apos;s $ Greensboro - Burgers, Fast Food 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 jams deli greensboro jams deli jams deli greensboro nc jams deli greensboro nc hours jams deli hours 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
