<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006455" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Restaurant-Franchises---A-Tasty-Business-Opportunity&amp;id=6843570" time="2012-07-12-23:23" support="4" score="0.00680742608797146" bingtitle="Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity" webtitle="Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity">
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>The fast food restaurant typically offers counter service and a ... an individual the right to develop and own a number ... com is a free, comprehensive franchise selection ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Business » Franchising Bob Richman 
 Platinum Author |   93 Articles 
 Joined: March 3, 2008 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity

 By Bob Richman 
 
There are many restaurant franchises located throughout the country and even the world. Opening your own restaurant can be exciting, scary and a wonderful investment. Restaurants offer a great way to make money as well as provide people with something that they need, food. There are several types of restaurant franchises from which to choose.

 Full Service Restaurants 

A full service restaurant typically offers complete table service. This includes service personnel, such as hosts and hostesses, as well as a wait staff. The full service restaurant is a good choice for investors that have a higher investment range. This is because the start up costs for a full service restaurant is typically higher than a casual or fast food restaurant.

 Fast Food Restaurants 

The fast food restaurant typically offers counter service and a drive through option. Pizza places that offer delivery and carryout options are considered fast food restaurants as well. These types of restaurants are also referred to as quick service restaurants or QSR within the industry.

The fast casual restaurant is a slight variation on the fast food restaurant. The fast casual restaurant will typically offer a higher quality menu than the typical quick service restaurant. Fast casual restaurant franchises will often have a more nutritional menu than the standard fast food restaurant.

 Franchise Programs 

There are several franchise programs available for individuals looking into purchasing a restaurant franchise. The first type is the single unit franchise. This is a great option for individuals that plan on being very hands on in the operation. The single unit franchise is typically an owner operator style of business, where the owner also functions as the manager or operator of the business. It should be noted that single unit franchises are not typically offered for some of the more established brands of restaurant franchises as it is not a very efficient franchise model.

The multi-unit franchise offers an individual the right to develop and own a number of the restaurant franchise within a specific area. The owner works less in the day to day operation and focuses on running many units more efficiently. The biggest benefit of the multi-unit franchise is the financial gains produced through owning multiple units.

The other type of major franchise program that is an option is the master franchise. This type of franchise allows the individual or group to purchase the rights to develop a specific territory, which is most often a major region or market. The owner is then allowed to sell parts of the territory to new franchisers. Essentially the master franchise owners are &quot;sub-franchisors,&quot; splitting the roles and the responsibilities, the franchise fees, and the royalties, with franchisors.

Owning a master franchise can be extremely beneficial financially. This is because in the beginning it is possible to run a master franchise from a small office and with few employees. Developing the area for the restaurants will be a large part of the job, but once you sell the franchise, the individuals will be your only customers to deal with.
 
To view additional franchise opportunities and profiles for 1,500+ franchises , please visit FranchiseGenius.com.

FranchiseGenius.com is a free, comprehensive franchise selection resource, with 1,500+ franchise opportunities summarized. Franchise Genius is used by prospective entrepreneurs to research franchises in all industries and price ranges.
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Bob_Richman 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Business: Franchising 
 Bob Richman 
 Email Address: Subscribe Franchising Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 A Complete Guide For Restaurant Real Estate Investments What Are the Top 10 Types of Franchise Opportunities? 10 Master Franchise Opportunities For the Motivated Businessman 6 All-Important Features Top Franchise Businesses Possess Success with a Fast Food Franchise What Is The Right Franchise Business For You? Keys to the Kingdom of Franchising Brand Warfare is More of a War than You Think Home Base Network Marketing Why Only the 5% Succeeded ? 5 MLM Secrets to Perfect Recruiting in Any Network Marketing Business, Just Released! 
 
Recent Articles

 Buy A Franchise Know About The Best Ways For Capital Raising Some of the Most Profitable Franchises Aren&apos;t What You Expect in a Restaurant Discover Why a Graphic Design Franchise Is a Great Business to Own Starting a Printing, Advertising, and Marketing Franchise Could Be a Shrewd Move Why a Digital Printing Franchise Makes Sense for the Entrepreneur Watch Out for the Franchisor &quot;Swat&quot; Team What Is Franchising Driving Into the Current Marketplace? Intellectual Property Monetization Is More of a Moral Issue Reinvent Your Business Goals With the World&apos;s Top Franchises 
 
Submitted On January 26, 2012. Viewed 69 times. Word count: 506.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Richman, Bob &quot;Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity.&quot; Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity .
 26 Jan. 2012 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Restaurant-­Franchises-­-­-­A-­Tasty-­Business-­Opportunity&amp;id=6843570 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Richman, B. (2012, January 26). Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Restaurant-­Franchises-­-­-­A-­Tasty-­Business-­Opportunity&amp;id=6843570 Chicago Style Citation: 
Richman, Bob &quot;Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity.&quot; Restaurant Franchises - A Tasty Business Opportunity EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Restaurant-­Franchises-­-­-­A-­Tasty-­Business-­Opportunity&amp;id=6843570 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
