<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006977" url="http://health.wikinut.com/Vegetarian-Fast-Food%3A-Three-Restaurants-That-Do-It-Well/_qq5eeyi/" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="12" score="0.042294855395916715" bingtitle="Vegetarian Fast-Food: Three Restaurants That Do It Well" webtitle="Vegetarian Fast-Food: Three Restaurants That Do It Well">
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001101" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000850" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>This isn’t your typical fast- food restaurant. You walk up to a counter to order where you ... They even label which items are vegetarian on their menu board. If you’re ...</description>
	<body>
		Vegetarian Fast-Food: Three Restaurants That Do It Well

 By Kristie Leong MD , 4th Feb 2011 | Follow this author | RSS Feed | Short URL http://nut.bz/_qq5eeyi/ 
Posted in Wikinut &gt; Health &gt; Diet&amp;Nutrition 

If you&apos;re out on the road and need to eat vegetarian fast, where do you go? Here are three fast-food restaurants that have healthy vegetarian options.
 
 Healthy Vegetarian Fast-Food Options Boston Market Subway Restaurant Panera Bread Other Vegetarian Fast Food Options The Bottom Line? 
 
Healthy Vegetarian Fast-Food Options

If you’re committed to eating a vegetarian diet, you probably already know that vegetarian fast- food options are in short supply. Most fast-food restaurants cater to meat-eaters and the closest thing they have to vegetables are French fries. If you’re looking for quick vegetarian that’s also healthy, look no further than these fast-food restaurants that offer healthier vegetarian fast-food selections. If you’re vegan, some of these options may not be for you, so ask if they contain eggs or dairy products.
 
Boston Market

Not every city has a Boston Market, but if yours does, you’re in luck. This isn’t your typical fast- food restaurant. You walk up to a counter to order where you see the food displayed in a big glass case. Even better, they offer a variety of meatless side dishes including steamed vegetables, green beans, cinnamon apples, sweet corn and garlic dill new potatoes.
If you’re feeling a little more decadent and you need some vegetarian comfort food, you can enjoy the squash or sweet potato casserole or their macaroni and cheese. They also have an array of salads, although choose carefully, some of them contain meat.
 
Subway Restaurant

This is a super quick vegetarian fast food option, and most cities are fortunate enough to have this popular sub sandwich chain. One option they offer is the make-your-own salad. They lay down a layer of lettuce and you choose the veggies you want on top. You can also order a veggie sub or ask them to customize one just for you. Some locations also offer a veggie burger on a sub bun. If you’re pressed for time and want to do healthy vegetarian, do it at Subway.
 
Panera Bread

Panera Bread makes it easy to order healthy vegetarian fast food. It’s more of a fast-casual eatery rather than a true fast food restaurant. You order at the counter and sit down at one of their comfy tables and wait for them to call your number.
The good news is they have lots of vegetarian options including entrée salads, but ask them to hold the meat. They have a vegetarian soup option every day, usually a garden vegetable or black bean. They even label which items are vegetarian on their menu board. If you’re not vegan, they offer a Mediterranean vegetable sandwich and a tomato and mozzarella sandwich.
Their Café Classic salad is completely meatless, and you can order a fruit cup to finish off the meal. Enjoy it with a cup of coffee with soy milk. How’s that for vegetarian?
 
Other Vegetarian Fast Food Options

Burger King has a veggie burger made with a Morning Star Garden Veggie patty, which you can enjoy with fresh apple fries and a side salad. Burger King offers more vegetarian items than most of their fast food competitors who only offer side salads.
 
The Bottom Line?

If you’re in a rush, look for one of these healthier vegetarian fast food options when you’re on the road, and you can eat vegetarian without having to default to French fries.

References:
Panera Bread website
Subway Restaurant website
Boston Market website
 
Tags

 Fast Vegetarian , Fast-Food Vegetarian , Fast-Food Vegetarian Options , Vegetarian Fast , Vegetarian Restaurants 

Meet the author
 Kristie Leong MD 
I&apos;m a family physician with a strong interest in disease prevention and alternative medicine. I&apos;m particularly interested in how diet plays a role in disease prevention. Hope I can inspire someone to lead a healthier life. :- 
Share this page
 
 Delicious Digg Newsvine Reddit StumbleUpon Twitter 
 
 Mark Gordon Brown moderated this page.
If you have any complaints about this content, please let us know 
 
Comments
 
 Mark Gordon Brown 
 4th Feb 2011 ( # )

My wife and I are not vegetarians but do try to make meat free choices rather often. thanks for this list. I think only Subway is near us.. and that being 45 minutes away!

 Reply to this comment 
 
 Denise O 
 16th Feb 2011 ( # )

I sure do miss our boston market we use to have, I agree a lot of choices there. I am the same as Mark and his wife, I try to eat more grains, fruits and veggies than meat.
Darn good tips.
Thank you for sharing.:)


 Reply to this comment 
 Add a comment 
 Your name Your email address Your comment 
 Username Can&apos;t login? Password 
Wikinut is an online publisher for the masses. You write pages, we publish them online and pay you 50% of advert revenue. Find out more 
 
 Join Wikinut now 
 
Wikinut search
 
Wikinut options

 Help Contact us 
 
Similar pages
 Fast Food Addiction
 vidhyaprakash Wanna go slim without cutting your favourite foods?
 Ravitejatadimalla Has Red Meat Received a Bad Rap?
 Jerry Walch Gluten-Free Banana Split Cake Recipe
 Mackenzie Have a Flat Belly by Enjoying Your Food
 strawberrytreats Female Diet and Nutrition
 dharmesh523 How to Reduce Weight
 hem Best and worst dry dog foods for dogs
 Yasin and Matei Vegetarianism a way of life or a way to live
 johnnydod Why to be a Vegan
 Yasin and Matei Reasons why people struggle to lose weight - Isabelle Bataglin
 IsabelleBataglin Lot of benefits with the tea
 yugasini 
Featured pages
 What is Couvade syndrome
 flavaria Wanna go slim without cutting your favourite foods?
 Ravitejatadimalla Healthy Attitude
 vidhyaprakash The Wisdom to Say &quot;No&quot; - A New Thought for July 12th
 Peter B. Giblett Meaningful Use 2 and PHR (Patient Health Records) Part II
 Benter Adede Warning: The Worse TB Outbreak in 20 Years
 Jerry Walch Chromotherapy: Turquoise Color
 avery sandiego Gluten-Free Banana Split Cake Recipe
 Mackenzie Impacted Wisdom Teeth
 EarnMoneyWeb Sacred Heart medical Diet
 lydear Hetro-homo Sexuality
 LOVERME Have a Flat Belly by Enjoying Your Food
 strawberrytreats 
Similar tags
 Fast-Food Vegetarian Fast Vegetarian Vegetarian Restaurants Vegetarian Fast Fast-Food Vegetarian Options 
Page categories

 Star pages Wikinut Health 
 Alternative Medicine Diet&amp;Nutrition Drugs&amp;Medicines Exercise&amp;Fitness First Aid General Health Health Clubs&amp;Spas Home Remedies Mind&amp;Spirit Youth&amp;Beauty 
 
 
This website is owned and operated by Wikinut Ltd, registered number 07040100 in England and Wales.

©2009 Wikinut Ltd - Terms of use - Privacy policy - Wikinut Ltd does not guarantee the accuracy of any user-authored content.
 Error : You must have Javascript enabled to use Wikinut.
	</body>
</document>
