<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006087" url="http://www.ciao.co.uk/sr/q-mc+donald%21s" time="2012-07-12-22:46" support="1" score="0.005111563350852694" bingtitle="MC Donald!s - Prices, Offers &amp; Tests of MC Donald!s" webtitle="MC Donald!s - Prices, Offers&amp;Tests of MC Donald!s">
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Via Aurelia, 00165 Rome, Italy ... Your credit card will not be charged until we ship the ... It?s not the sort of place you would want to ...</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 
 Browse by category 
 Appliances 

 Books 

 Cameras 

 Cars 

 Computers 

 Electronics 

 DVDs 

 Music 

 Phones 

 Travel 

 More 
 
Ciao - for people with opinions

 
 Latest reviews Write a review 
 
 Latest questions Latest videos 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS Shopping Offers Reviews ALL RESULTS &gt; Shopping &gt; Results for &quot;MC Donald!s&quot; 
Shopping»
 
 
 Results on ciao.co.uk Results in online shops Special Offers 
 

 1 - 8 of 8 results for &quot;MC Donald!s&quot; sort by: Popularity | Price | Rating | Date 
 
 
 McDonald s 
 
(+) No strict dress code, cheap food, always open. (-) Not the healthiest ... more 
 (+) No strict dress code, cheap food, always open. (-) Not the healthiest or cleanest places to eat. (*) (On Ciao since: 06/2000)
... less 
 




 
 
 User reviews (177) 
 
 Food&amp;Drink &gt; Food&amp;Health &gt; Chain Restaurants 
 
 Mc Find DE - McDonald s / Mc Caf Store Locator 
 Mc Find DE - McDonald s / Mc Caf Store Locator (iPad Application)
 
App from BulletBee - Genre: Navigation (On Ciao since: 12/2010)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Software &gt; iPhone Apps 
 
 McDonald&apos;s , Castletroy S C, Limerick 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, American Restaurant - Address: Castletroy S C, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, American Restaurant - Address: Castletroy S C, Dublin Road, Limerick (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Limerick &gt; Limerick Restaurants 
 
 McDonald&apos;s , Frascati S.C., Blackrock 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, American Restaurant - Address: Frascati S .C., ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, American Restaurant - Address: Frascati S .C., Blackrock (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Other Destinations in Ireland &gt; Ireland Restaurants 
 
 McDonald s Mundsburg, Uhlenhorst, Hamburg 
 
Fast Food Restaurant - Mundsburger Damm 71, Ecke Winterhuder Weg, 22087 ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant - Mundsburger Damm 71, Ecke Winterhuder Weg, 22087 Hamburg, Germany (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Germany &gt; Hamburg &gt; Hamburg Restaurants 
 
 Chantra, Neuhausen, Munich 
 
Thai Restaurant, Restaurant&amp;Bar - Nymphenburger Str. 154, (Hinter ... more 
 Thai Restaurant, Restaurant&amp;Bar - Nymphenburger Str. 154, (Hinter Mc - Donald ` S Am Rotkreuzplatz), 80634 Munich, Germany (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Germany &gt; Munich &gt; Munich Restaurants 
 
 McDonald&apos;s ( S -Bahnhof Sternschanze), Hamburg 
 
Fast Food Restaurant - S -Bahnhof Sternschanze 20357 Hamburg (On Ciao ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant - S -Bahnhof Sternschanze 20357 Hamburg (On Ciao since: 02/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Germany &gt; Hamburg &gt; Hamburg Restaurants 
 
 Mc Donald S Development Italy Inc., Rome 
 
Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Via Aurelia, 00165 Rome, Italy (On Ciao ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Via Aurelia, 00165 Rome, Italy (On Ciao since: 02/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Italy &gt; Rome &gt; Rome Restaurants 
 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members
 
 1 




 
Offers»

 1 - 10 of 13 results for&quot;MC Donald!s&quot; Show all results sorted by: Popularity | Price 

 
 The Estuarine Ecosystem (Tertiary Level Biology S .) (2nd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky 
The Estuarine Ecosystem (Tertiary Level Biology S .) (2nd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky
 

Pages: 225, Edition: 2nd, Paperback, Kluwer Academic Publishers


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Temporarily out of stock. Order now and we&apos;ll deliver when available. We&apos;ll e-mail you with an estimated delivery date as soon as we have more information. Your credit card will not be charged until we ship the item.... £ 35.00 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon books 
 The Estuarine Ecosystem: Ecology, Threats and Management (Oxford Biology) (3rd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky 
The Estuarine Ecosystem: Ecology, Threats and Management (Oxford Biology) (3rd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky
 

Pages: 224, Edition: 3, Paperback, OUP Oxford


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 24 hours... £ 33.20 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon books 
 The Estuarine Ecosystem: Ecology, Threats and Management (Oxford Biology) (3rd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky 
The Estuarine Ecosystem: Ecology, Threats and Management (Oxford Biology) (3rd Edition) - Donald S . McLusky
 

Pages: 224, Edition: 3, Paperback, OUP Oxford


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.80 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 27.94 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace books 
 PROFESSIONAL CONSTRUCTION MGMT: Including CM, Design-construct, and General Contracting (McGraw-Hill series in construction engineering and project management) 
PROFESSIONAL CONSTRUCTION MGMT: Including CM, Design-construct, and General Contracting (McGraw-Hill series in construction engineering and project management) - Donald S . Barrie
 
 
Covers subjects that are studied in introductory overview course on construction management. This work focusses on organizational approaches to project...... more 
 Covers subjects that are studied in introductory overview course on construction management. This work focusses on organizational approaches to project management, and the related planning and control systems. It also includes business aspects of the industry, with a section on the business methods in professional construction management.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 9 to 11 days... £ 45.59 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon books 
 PROFESSIONAL CONSTRUCTION MGMT: Including CM, Design-construct, and General Contracting (McGraw-Hill series in construction engineering and project management) 
PROFESSIONAL CONSTRUCTION MGMT: Including CM, Design-construct, and General Contracting (McGraw-Hill series in construction engineering and project management) - Donald S . Barrie
 
 
Covers subjects that are studied in introductory overview course on construction management. This work focusses on organizational approaches to project...... more 
 Covers subjects that are studied in introductory overview course on construction management. This work focusses on organizational approaches to project management, and the related planning and control systems. It also includes business aspects of the industry, with a section on the business methods in professional construction management.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.80 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 38.57 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace books 
 Michael Mcdonald: This Christmas Live In Chicago 
Michael Mcdonald: This Christmas Live In Chicago
 
 
DVDs Xbox 360 Games Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games PSP Games Games PC Bluray DVDs Xbox 360 Games CDs Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games Games PC Blu-ray PSP Games...... more 
 DVDs Xbox 360 Games Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games PSP Games Games PC Bluray DVDs Xbox 360 Games CDs Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games Games PC Blu-ray PSP Games Nintendo DS Hardware Wii Hardware PS3 Hardware Xbox 360 Accessories Xbox 360 Hardware Nintendo DS Accessories PSP Accessories Multi-Grammy Award winner Michael McDonald has had a hugely successful career over four decades with firstly Steely Dan, then with the Doobie Brothers and finally as a solo artist. This festive concert was filmed in high definition in Chicago in 2009. It combines traditional and original Christmas songs featured on Michael s two Christmas albums bookended with classic tracks from both his solo career and his time with the Doobie Brothers. Michael McDonald  s distinctive husky, soulful voice is perfectly suited to this material, which he delivers with sincerity on the more thoughtful songs and with a real panache on the fun numbers. This DVD makes a perfect addition to anyone s Christmas collection. Tracklist: 1) Introduction 2) It Keep
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £0.00 
 Availability :  available £ 13.49 Visit Shop  &gt; ebay 
 Michael Mcdonald: This Christmas Live In Chicago 
Michael Mcdonald: This Christmas Live In Chicago
 
 
DVDs Xbox 360 Games Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games PSP Games Games PC Xbox 360 Games CDs Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games Games PC Blu-ray PSP Games Nintendo DS...... more 
 DVDs Xbox 360 Games Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games PSP Games Games PC Xbox 360 Games CDs Nintendo DS Games PS3 Games Games PC Blu-ray PSP Games Nintendo DS Hardware Wii Hardware PS3 Hardware Xbox 360 Accessories Xbox 360 Hardware Nintendo DS Accessories PSP Accessories PSP Hardware Multi-Grammy Award winner Michael McDonald has had a hugely successful career over four decades with firstly Steely Dan, then with the Doobie Brothers and finally as a solo artist. This festive concert was filmed in high definition in Chicago in 2009. It combines traditional and original Christmas songs featured on Michael s two Christmas albums bookended with classic tracks from both his solo career and his time with the Doobie Brothers. Michael McDonald  s distinctive husky, soulful voice is perfectly suited to this material, which he delivers with sincerity on the more thoughtful songs and with a real panache on the fun numbers. This Blu-ray makes a perfect addition to anyone s Christmas collection. Tracklist: 1) Introduction 2) It
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £0.00 
 Availability :  available £ 15.49 Visit Shop  &gt; ebay 
 This Christmas - Live In Chicago - Dvd - Item 
This Christmas - Live In Chicago - Dvd - Item
 
 
New Page 2 New Page 2 New Page 2 100000&apos; s of Brand New DVD&apos;s, Music Cd&apos;s, Vinyl, Books and Video Games For all formats at Great Prices! DVD&apos;S VIDEO...... more 
 New Page 2 New Page 2 New Page 2 100000&apos; s of Brand New DVD&apos;s, Music Cd&apos;s, Vinyl, Books and Video Games For all formats at Great Prices! DVD&apos;S VIDEO GAMES MUSIC CD&apos;S THIS CHRISTMAS - LIVE IN CHICAGO - DVD DVD Reviews Product Description Multi-Grammy Award winner Michael McDonald has had a hugely successful career over four decades with firstly Steely Dan, then with the Doobie Brothers and finally as a solo artist. This festive concert was filmed in high definition in Chicago in 2009. It combines traditional and original Christmas songs featured on Michael s two Christmas albums bookended with classic tracks from both his solo career and his time with the Doobie Brothers. Michael McDonald s distinctive husky, soulful voice is perfectly suited to this material, which he delivers with sincerity on the more thoughtful songs and with a real panache on the fun numbers. This DVD makes a perfect addition to anyone s Christmas collection. English / NO Title: THIS CHRISTMAS - LIVE IN CHICAGO - DVD Format: DVD Publisher:
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £0.99 
 Availability :  available £ 18.95 Visit Shop  &gt; ebay 
 This Christmas - Live In Chicago - Blu-ray - Item 
This Christmas - Live In Chicago - Blu-ray - Item
 
 
New Page 2 New Page 2 New Page 2 100000&apos; s of Brand New DVD&apos;s, Music Cd&apos;s, Vinyl, Books and Video Games For all formats at Great Prices! DVD&apos;S VIDEO...... more 
 New Page 2 New Page 2 New Page 2 100000&apos; s of Brand New DVD&apos;s, Music Cd&apos;s, Vinyl, Books and Video Games For all formats at Great Prices! DVD&apos;S VIDEO GAMES MUSIC CD&apos;S THIS CHRISTMAS - LIVE IN CHICAGO - Blu-ray Blu-ray Reviews Product Description Multi-Grammy Award winner Michael McDonald has had a hugely successful career over four decades with firstly Steely Dan, then with the Doobie Brothers and finally as a solo artist. This festive concert was filmed in high definition in Chicago in 2009. It combines traditional and original Christmas songs featured on Michael s two Christmas albums bookended with classic tracks from both his solo career and his time with the Doobie Brothers. Michael McDonald s distinctive husky, soulful voice is perfectly suited to this material, which he delivers with sincerity on the more thoughtful songs and with a real panache on the fun numbers. This Blu-ray makes a perfect addition to anyone s Christmas collection. English / NO Title: THIS CHRISTMAS - LIVE IN CHICAGO - Blu-ray Format
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £0.99 
 Availability :  available £ 22.33 Visit Shop  &gt; ebay 
 The Piltdown Men Ride Again - Piltdown Men 
The Piltdown Men Ride Again - Piltdown Men
 
 
1- McDonald &apos; s Cave 2-Brontosaurus Stomp 3-Piltdown Rides Again 4-Bubbles In The Tar 5-The Great Impostor 6-Goodnight Mrs. Flintstone 7-Gargantua...... more 
 1- McDonald &apos; s Cave 2-Brontosaurus Stomp 3-Piltdown Rides Again 4-Bubbles In The Tar 5-The Great Impostor 6-Goodnight Mrs. Flintstone 7-Gargantua #2 (unreleased) 8-Fossil Rock 9-Gargantua 10-Agricultural Twist (unreleased) 11-A Pretty Girl Is Like A Melody 12-Big Lizzard 13-Flint Stomp (unreleased) 14-Night Surfin&apos; 15-Tequila Bossa Nova 16-Sentimental Journey (stereo unreleased)FIELDS, Ernie&amp;Orchestra 17-Birmingham Jail (stereo unreleased) 18-Adam&apos; s Rip (stereo unreleased) 19-Green Green (stereo unreleased) 20-Leap A Frog (stereo unreleased) 21-St. Louis Blues 22-Theme From &apos;Liles Of The Field&apos; 23-Swanee River (stereo) 24-I&apos;ll Cry Instead (stereo unreleased) 25-In The Mood (stereo unreleased) 26-Chloe (stereo) 27-Swingin&apos; DrumsMAY, Billy&amp;Orchestra 28-Drum Village (part 1)PALMER, Earl 29-Drum Village (part 2)
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 24 hours... £ 11.49 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon.co.uk 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members

 Show all results 
 
Related tags for MC Donald!s»
 mc 100 mc 3 mc michael mc how to mc mc d mc queen mc co mc donalds mc sports 
Reviews»

 
 McUnhealthy 

 Advantages: cheap, widely available, quick
 Disadvantages: unhealthy, dubious ethics


.... 

Inside: Walking in you are hit by bright lights and the strong smell of food. All McDonalds seem to have a white tiled floor. The seats are plastic and quite hard. It?s not the sort of place you would want to spend too much time in, indeed, I avoid sitting inside whenever possible. The clientele where I live seem to be mainly gangs of townies dressed in their ?bling bling.? Not the most pleasant place to eat in.

Ethics: McDonalds is keen to stress how much it supports community programmes etc. There has in fact been a lot of literature about rain forests being destroyed, farmers in South America being paid very badly and lots of environmental damage. McDonalds however denies all claims. It is interesting to note that McDonalds spends more than $2 million a year in Public Relations costs. They also happen to sue a lot of people. Many...

 Katieshaz 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of McDonalds 
 
 McDonald Junkie Around the World 

 Advantages: Full meal at reasonable price
 Disadvantages: Full of calories and cholesterol


...I was a McDonald&apos;s kid. Well, not really, but I must state that a proportion of my teenager life and pocket money were spent in McDonald&apos;s.
 
Here, I would like to give a description of some of the interesting features of McDonald&apos;s around the world. I always believe that a worldwide restaurant or fastfood chain should cater to the local tastebuds and in this area, McDonald&apos;s has gone a long way to doing that.
 
I have visited Singapore several times now. It is a tiny Southeast Asian island country. Here, McDonald&apos;s face a tough local market where the variety, authenticity and scrumptious Southeast Asian cuisine beats McDonald&apos;s hands down. Here, McDonald&apos;s has been extremely innovative in catering to the local consumption requirements. The locals seems to have their specific requirements. First, beef and pork are not highly...

 petitesquirt 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of McDonalds 
 
 FRIGHTENING EXPERIENCE AT McDONALDS 

 Advantages: No Strict Dress Code!
 Disadvantages: Service, Cleanliness, Atmsosphere


...I&apos;m not a huge fan of McDonalds but my two children seem to regard it as a treat so we go every once and awhile. History, menus, etc can all be found in other reviews so I would like instead to share with you my most recent, unpleasant and frightening experience.

I arrived at the McDonalds restaurant in the Meole Brace area of Shrewsbury at around 5pm on a Friday before Xmas with my son, then aged 10 yr. and my daughter 4yrs. The restaurant is situated in quite a pleasant retail park about 2 miles from the centre of Shrewsbury. There is ample parking and the surrounding gardens have matured to make the exterior of the restaurant quite attractive.. There are tables outside should you wish to sit in the cold or have a smoke. The exterior of the building itself is of typical McDonalds design - perhaps now rather dated and in need...

 inycon2 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of McDonalds 
 
 
 About Us - 
 Jobs
 - 
 Advertise with Us
 - 
 Press
 - 
 Become a Partner
 - Ciao Quality Seal Ciao Deutschland - Ciao France - Ciao Italia - Ciao España - Ciao Nederland - Ciao Sverige Site Index - Ciao Charts - Most searched products - Data Protection 
 ©2012 Shopping Guide GmbH
	</body>
</document>
