<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006350" url="http://www.forbes.com/sites/jesscollen/2012/04/10/aol-youve-got-patents/" time="2012-07-12-23:03" support="1" score="0.0012987267197755354" bingtitle="AOL -- You&apos;ve got patents! - Forbes" webtitle="AOL -- You&apos;ve got patents! - Forbes">
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>... techniques for salting French fries in a fast food restaurant ... decades which have passed, courts have put ... The Credit Card Is The New App Platform; Home; Business</description>
	<body>
		FREE TRIAL ISSUE Help | Connect | Sign up | Log in 
Log in with your social account:
 
Or, you can log in or sign up using Forbes.
 
 New Posts +30 posts this hour Most Popular 5 Types Of Innovators Lists Best Places For Business Video Highest-Paid Actors 
 
 Jess Collen , Contributor 

Trademark, patent, copyright, social media, privacy&amp;advertising law.
 Follow Following Unfollow 
 Entrepreneurs 

 | 

4/10/2012 @ 2:28PM | 846 views

AOL -- You&apos;ve got patents!
 0 comments, 0 called-out + Comment now + Comment now 
&quot;You&apos;ve Got Mail&quot;starring Meg Ryan and Tom Hanks
 
It is morning. I sit at my desk. I switch on my monitor. I am expecting some critical emails from overseas which should be my wake-up call for the day. I wait for the phone line to clear before I can dial out to connect because my wife was on the phone. Creeping across my screen fresh from my 256k dial-up connection , I am expecting to hear those famous words: “You’ve got mail!” I am the only man in America still on dial-up. I wait and wait. I am Tom Hanks in You’ve Got Mail .

Then I wake up.

You remember the movie You’ve Got Mail , the 1998 remake of the old Margaret Sullavan and James Stewart movie, The Shop Around the Corner , released in 1940. The remake starred Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan , with Hanks an owner of a big book store chain, and Meg Ryan, who runs a local book selling boutique called “The Shop Around the Corner.”
 
Priceline.com
 
So back in the real world I click on my iPad, and the news tells me that AOL had sold off much of its patent portfolio, and is licensing the rest, to Microsoft . When AOL was the — well, Microsoft — of Internet portals, it invested voluminously in technology patents. Of course, what it didn’t do is develop heavily in the means of transmission, and before long (maybe not too long, but eventually) a portal like AOL, which due to the magic of your home telephone allowed you to be part of the World Wide Web, was lost to the telephone and cable carriers who were already wired and investing more to bring broadband internet to our doorsteps. Companies like AOL and Walker Digital ( Priceline ) became famous think tanks for every product and method imaginable, employing computer telephony and digital access to accomplish every mean feat. And then patenting them.

 

What seems like a nice little cash pile for investors (exceeding one billion dollars) may well be less than meets the eye. It means that Microsoft has the right to either own or use without further payment to AOL every piece of technology which AOL has invented. Why would they do that? Well, I don’t even have the slightest insight into the depths of AOL’s patent portfolio. But big patent owners are very keen on acquiring patents or the rights to patents not only for those inventions that they see as diamonds in the rough (who knows? AOL’s portfolio may be full of these) but also and especially for defensive purposes. It all happens through the magic of cross-licensing. Company number one sues company number two for patent infringement. Company number two puts its own patents through the filter and comes up with a whole slew of patents as if that company wanted infringing. If you’re going to sue me, well, I’ll sue you back. So eventually, we enter into an entente. You can use mine and I can use yours, and at least we can keep out everyone else.

I’m going through this process right now with clients where we are analyzing their portfolio, looking for our potential vulnerabilities and then, as a matter of fact, looking at the vulnerabilities of the other guys. We are trying to calculate whether they will simply beg off on challenging too many of our client’s rights because it would open up a Texas death match (where both sides lose). Patent infringement is sometimes called the sport of kings. It’s more expensive than polo. The more weapons (patents) you can stockpile, the better you can insulate yourself or possibly keep harm under control. 

Back when AOL was so well known that Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan starred in a movie playing off of their YOU’VE GOT MAIL trademark, the future of all of these so-called business method patents was bright, even though the development of these patents was pure speculation. A court decision in the early 90s paved the way for the business method patent, giving exclusive rights on methods not just in the technology field, but, quite famously or notoriously, for things like techniques for salting French fries in a fast food restaurant or creating a peanut butter and jelly sandwich (I wish I was being funny here). In the couple of decades which have passed, courts have put some limits on business method patents but have allowed a lot of them to remain powerful weapons which motivate companies like AOL and Microsoft to buy and sell. So, it would be easy to say AOL is abandoning the technology field, but given whom its competitors would seem to be, that’s a hard claim to make. Selling a patent portfolio of that size and scope to a company like Microsoft might mean that AOL gets lots of mail, from shareholders. True, you could buy a lot of minutes of dial-up time for a billion dollars. But how far will it go on this money? It’s easy to criticize, and if AOL really had no business model to exploit these patents on its own while Microsoft plainly does, then they might as well cash out. But if they end up just another site, AOL truly risks being cannibalized by the Big Boys. It kind of makes them the little “shop around the corner.”
 0 comments, 0 called-out + Comment now + Comment now Print Report Corrections Reprints&amp;Permissions 
More on Forbes Right Now
 
Features

 CEOs Afraid Of Going Social Are Doing Shareholders A Massive Disservice Your LinkedIn Intervention: 5 Changes You Must Make 7 Tips On Building Your Business With Better Metrics 
 
Post Your Comment
 Cancel reply 
Post Your Reply
 Please log in or sign up to comment. Enter Your Comment Submit Comment 
Forbes writers have the ability to call out member comments they find particularly interesting. Called-out comments are highlighted across the Forbes network. You&apos;ll be notified if your comment is called out.
 
Most Read on Forbes
 
 News People Places Companies 
 + show more Jess Collen Contributor Follow Following Unfollow + show more 
What is your company’s calling card? Intellectual property (IP) rights bring distinctive and often unique traits to what you do. I’ve been an intellectual property (IP) lawyer for more than 25 years. I advise my clients on how to use, defend and protect their IP assets, and have litigated their rights in the federal district courts, courts of appeal and the U.S. Supreme Court. I represent U.S. and foreign companies. I help clients decide on brand names, work on product marketing and protection strategies and advertising approval. I do a lot of work going after counterfeiters, especially for luxury goods companies. I also counsel on patent law and protection, and work extensively in copyright law, including with publishers, artists, and media companies. I’ve been lecturing and advising clients about IP rights on the Internet since the early 1990’s. I’ve had the privilege of taking leadership roles in professional organizations dedicated to advancing IP rights worldwide.
 
The author is a Forbes contributor. The opinions expressed are those of the writer.
 
Jess Collen’s Popular Posts

 Mondelez? Puh-LEEZE! 19,129 views .XXX Domains-A Big Bust? 5,882 views iPad Question-Are Apples Overpriced in China? 2,662 views HILLSHIRE BRANDS, And The Top 6 Reasons Not To Change Your Corporate Name 2,105 views JC Penney: Done In By &quot;Reverse False Advertising?&quot; 2,045 views 
 
More from Jess Collen
 
 Jess’RSS Feed Jess’Profile Jess’Website 
 
Who Just Made a Billion Dollars?
 Our Real-Time Billionaires scoreboard tracks the biggest holdings for 50 of the world’s wealthiest people. See who&apos;s up&amp;who&apos;s down right now» 
Inside Forbes
 
 The World&apos;s Most Powerful Celebrities - Forbes 
 Justin Bieber, Jennifer Lopez and The Rock star in our latest Celebrity 100. 
 
 Justin Bieber, Venture Capitalist: The Forbes Cover Story 
 
 Homes Of The World&apos;s Most Powerful Celebrities 
 

 
 The Rock is Kicking Ass and Saving Franchises 
 
 Forbes Real-Time Billionaires 
 
 
Channels

 Business Investing Tech Entrepreneurs Op/Ed Leadership Lifestyle Lists 
 
Company Info

 About Forbes Advertising Information Self-Serve Advertising Reprints&amp;Permissions Terms and Conditions Privacy Statement Contact Us Sitemap Help 
 
Affiliate Sites

 Forbes Russia Forbes Poland Forbes Romania Forbes Middle East Forbes China Forbes India RealClear Politics RealClear Markets RealClear World RealClear Sports 
 
Data Partners

 Distributed by AT&amp;T; Tested by Spirent Market Data by Morningstar Xignite Thomson Reuters AdChoices 
 
Publications
 
 Free Trial Issue Subscriber Services Buy Back Issues 
 2012 Forbes.com LLC All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
