<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006992" url="http://greenanswers.com/q/217126/food-agriculture/restaurants-markets/pink-slime-used-supermarket-hamburger-canada" time="2012-07-12-23:58" support="1" score="0.005721162345494073" bingtitle="Is &quot;pink slime&quot; used in supermarket hamburger in Canada ..." webtitle="Ispink slimeused in supermarket hamburger in Canada? | GreenAnswers">
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Previous in Restaurants &amp; Markets: How can restaurants reduce the amount of waste ... How much power is needed to power a fast food restaurant? What is the best fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In Join 
 
 Home Ask a Question Answer 
 Unanswered Questions Popular Questions Recently Asked Questions 
 Browse Topics See all... or choose one: 
 Animals&amp;Wildlife Business&amp;Economics Climate Change Education&amp;Activism Energy&amp;Fuels Food&amp;Agriculture Forests, Trees&amp;Plants Health&amp;Wellness Homes&amp;Buildings Ideas&amp;Philosophies Media&amp;Entertainment 

 Nature&amp;Ecosystems Other Policy&amp;Government Pollution&amp;Toxins Products&amp;Shopping Recreation&amp;Activities Recycling&amp;Waste Science&amp;Technology Sustainability&amp;Development Transportation Water, Oceans&amp;Ice 
 Explore 
 Articles Members Widgets FAQ About 
 Articles My Profile 
 
 earthsteader 

Karma: 123 (Level 2)
 Watch Question? Report Abuse 
Is &quot;pink slime&quot; used in supermarket hamburger in Canada?
 

This &quot;beef product&quot; is currently in question regarding Taco Bell. But it appears to be widespread and extremely unhealthful. I&apos;d like to avoid it. Is it used in grocery store ground beef and can it be used in Canada?

 http://www.grist.org/article/2010-07-30-ask-umbra-on-pink-slime-in-hambu... 

 
asked 1 year ago in Restaurants&amp;Markets 
 
 larissa 

Karma: 96 (Level 2)
 
Like it?
 
 Karma Points: 7 
 Report Abuse 
Pink slime is the fatty slaughterhouse trimmings added to most U.S. ground meat. It’s “the cheapest, least desirable beef on offer — fatty sweepings from the slaughterhouse floor, which are notoriously rife with pathogens like E. coli 0157 and antibiotic-resistant salmonella&quot; used an an additive in over 70% of U.S ground beef. Beef Products, Inc., or BPI, has developed a system that grinds the scraps of meat products into a paste that is then added to most ground beef. BPI is looking to expand its market share and has released a statement saying that:

The ultimate goal is to have our products incorporated in all ground beef and other further processed meats produced in the United States. Our products can also be found in Canada, Mexico, and Japan with expansion plans for Central America, Europe, and Pacific Rim countries.

Although it is the goal of BPI to infiltrate the Canadian market, the actual precedence of pink slime in Canada remains vague. Keep posted on Jo&apos;s blog: http://henderson-jo.blogspot.com/2011/04/pink-slime-voting.html. Today she emailed Health Canada to ask them what the policy is in this country with regard to pink slime.

 
 
 Citations: http://www.alternet.org/environment/144904/yummy!_ammonia-treated_pink_slime_now... 

 ...posted 1 year and 13 weeks ago 
 Comment on this Answer No comments yet. 
 
 PatriciaPham 

Karma: 680 (Level 3)
 
Like it?
 
 Karma Points: 3 
 Report Abuse 
Pink slime seems to be prevalent in the United States, and mainly in the fast food industry. There are inferences that pink slime can be found in Canada but it is very vague.

There is actually a blog on the whole subject of whether or not pink slime is in Canada. The answers seem unclear.

Here is the blog:

 http://rockinontheblog.blogspot.com/2010/01/whats-in-canadian-ground-beef.html 
 
 Citations: http://eatdrinkbetter.com/2010/08/12/pink-slime-in-fast-food-burgers/ 

 ...posted 1 year and 24 weeks ago 
 Comment on this Answer No comments yet. 
 
 shebola100 

Karma: 319 (Level 3)
 
Like it?
 
 Karma Points: 1 
 Report Abuse 
 According to Heather Travis, the director of public relations for Canada Beef, “pink slime” and ammonium hydroxide are not used in ground beef in Canada. They do not use ammonia in ground beef to kill e.coli 0157:H7 and it has not been approved for use in packing plants by Health Canada,” Travis wrote in an email. Although ammonium salts are approved for use in some foods by Heath Canada, and ammonium hydroxide is endorsed for many foods by the World Heath Organization , Travis said “pink slime” is not used in Canada. 
 
 Citations: http://www.vancouversun.com/business/Pink+slime+used+Canadian+beef+says+industry... 

 ...posted 13 weeks and 4 days ago 
 Comment on this Answer No comments yet. 
 Previous in Restaurants&amp;Markets: How can restaurants reduce the amount of waste they create? Next in Restaurants&amp;Markets: Are fast food restaurants bad for the environment? 
 Are there any restaurants that pair organic food with organic wine? What meal at taco bell is best for the environment? Are there any markets that specialize in local food? Is subway bad for the environment? Are there any seafood restaurants that base their menu’s on what is caught tha... 
 
 What’s the Big Deal about U.S. Tribal Water Rights? Eating Seasonally and Locally: Why It Matters The Enviropig - Should Its Funding Have Been Cut? The Keeper of the Male Code, Beaten But Not Destroyed Should the Government Force Green Policies? Ask the FDA: What’s Sneaking into your Shopping Cart? Rural Vs. Urban: From Where Does The Biologist Come? China&apos;s Water Scarcity Crisis Charles Darwin: 203 Years Young! Roses are Red, Violets are Blue, Valentines Can Be Green, And It’s Simple... California Governor Jerry Brown Looks to Reduce Holding Time of Animals in... What is your favorite type of eagle? 
 57,413 26 Join GreenAnswers now and we&apos;ll plant a tree on your behalf. After that, we&apos;ll plant another tree for every 5 questions you answer. 
 Most Viewed Most Watched Most Discussed 
 
 HOW MUCH SUBSIDY ON TYRE RECYCLE PLANT what are the current problems faced by yak how can hair salons be more careful about the enviroment? Please recommend a good resort for corporate outing and venue for training events near Pune in India. where else beside the river does an elephant migrate 
 
 what are five main ways in which natural environment of the pacific islands have been degraded or abuse What effect do recreational facilities have on the environment Whats the most recent animal entered on the endangered species list? How can the birds eggs fit inside the bird? Is it better to leave your grass clippings on your lawn or pick them up with the bag attachment? 
 What&apos;s this? 
 Type your question here...what are the growth requirements of plasmodium parasites what are the current problems faced by yak Why are the blue fun tuna populations at such a higher risk than the other tuna populations? Why is nuclear nonproliferation so difficult? how many stages of gang green are there? 
 GreenAnswers Newsletter Daily Monthly 
Environmental Articles
 
 Greenpeace Urges KFC to Stop Using Illegal Rainforest-Produced Paper Packaging Tech Giants Commit to Renewable Energy in Response to Greenpeace&apos;s Clean Our Cloud Campaign Disney Tightens Their Belt and Cuts Junk Food Advertising Roll Call: Welcoming Four New Species Arctic In Danger Fair Trade: The Damage of Global Trading What’s in This Season? Fruits Edition What’s in This Season? Veggies Edition Fruits and Strategies: Making the Most of the Farmers Market Obesity Epidemic: Whose Fault is it Anyways? 
 More Articles... 
Top 10 Members This Week
 
 
 12tree Karma (last 7 days): 72 
 
 heliosman Karma (last 7 days): 62 
 
 kiraisthewalrus Karma (last 7 days): 35 
 
 johan Karma (last 7 days): 31 
 
 sondarby Karma (last 7 days): 21 
 
 lizbryant88 Karma (last 7 days): 21 
 
 mrblevins Karma (last 7 days): 20 
 
 lovetheearth Karma (last 7 days): 20 
 
 bryguy Karma (last 7 days): 19 
 
 vivian2012 Karma (last 7 days): 19 
 
 More Members... 
Follow Green Answers .com
 
 RSS Twitter Facebook 
 
 Get the LiveOAK Network widget! Not seeing a widget? ( More info ) 
 
Copyright©2012 GreenAnswers.com LLC. All rights reserved.

 About FAQ Contact Terms&amp;Privacy Blog Widgets RSS Feed 
 
Please remember the information provided is from the community and is not intended to provide or substitute for informed professional advice. Please see the Terms of Use for the full disclaimer.
	</body>
</document>
