<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006967" url="http://www.dombom.com/dcforum/DCForumID33/366_2.html" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="51" score="0.08122692771660499" bingtitle="- Yahoo Answers RSS Scraper Test" webtitle="- Yahoo Answers RSS Scraper Test">
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000315" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001383" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000752" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000147" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000021" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000319" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000634" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001194" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000754" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000646" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000502" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>I mean, is it like healthier than eating at a fast food restaurant? Open Question: Tales Of The World Mabo Curry? How do u get the mabo curry quest? im so annoyed by this ...</description>
	<body>
		Follow Kurt Melvin on Twitter 
 
 

 Subject: &quot;Yahoo Answers RSS Scraper Test&quot;  Page 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Previous Topic | Next Topic 

 
 Printer-friendly copy      Conferences The New MadBomber Marketing and SEO Forum Topic #366 Reading page 2 of 5 pages 
 

 
 
 Kurt 
 Member since Dec-5-02 
 8892 posts , 5 feedbacks , 8 points Oct-11-10, 05:08 PM (PST)   76. &quot;Open Question: a group of students went to their favorite restaurant after the footba&quot; 
 

 Open Question: a group of students went to their favorite restaurant after the football game one friday night? 
they all ordered from the menu and forgot to the the server to give them separate checks. the bill totaled $27 including the tip. they decided to split the bill evenly and they figured out how much each of them owed. but then 3 people said they had no money. the rest of the people each had to chip in 45 cents extra to cover the tab. how many people were in the group?
 Open Question: free food for your mistakes? 
we spend a lot of money their for the family our order has been wrong 5 times yes 5 times so we had to say something. it messes
 Open Question: HELP... I need to find canada&apos;s cheesecake factory? 
I heard there is a cheese cake factory in Canada at Langstaff and Jane is it true i would love to go there tonight.
 Open Question: does anyone know what brand the sugar free french vanilla syrup is at mcdonalds? want to buy some.? 

 Open Question: Does Burger king pancakes taste like mcdonalds pancakes? 
I love mcdonalds pancakes. I hate pancakes except for mcdonalds hotcakes. Burger king has new breakfast items including the pancakes. I was wondering if burger king ripped off the pancakes and made it taste the same. Or does it taste different? If it does, which is better?
 Open Question: How much is a tall blended lemonade at starbucks? 
thanks
 Open Question: How old do you have to be to WORK at BC pizza? 
I am 14 and live in Lake City MI does anyone know how old you have to be to work at BC Pizza? Or Mcdonalds or Bk or something? I know you have to have a Work Permit? Please help ASAP
 Open Question: KFC, Burger King, Pizza Hut, or McDonald&apos;s? 
Which is your favorite and why?
 Open Question: Am I the only one who doesn&apos;t understand the point in having pizza of different sizes? 
I mean, don&apos;t they all have the same amount of slices....?
and, usually, a person will always eat the same amount of slices no matter if it&apos;s small/medium/large?
sorry if i&apos;m totally wrong about this 
 Open Question: I have 2 park places. Does anyone need one? 
I have 2 McDonalds #770 2010 Park Places. Does anyone need one, Would be happy to help someone wn the million!
 Open Question: Is there a way for me to get cheap auto insurance? 
I am 16 years old and from st.cloud minnesota. I don&apos;t have a car yet but I want to get one from around $3000-$4000. I have to go with State Farm because my parents have it. I am a safe driver and I get good grades. Is there a way to get cheap auto insurance through state farm through any special deals? Thanks
 Open Question: Does anyone remember the flavors TCBY had for the Arthur promotion? 

 Open Question: Anyone know of some REAL good food in or around anaheim California? 
Im taking my first vacation in years and am dying to try some great food in or around anaheim. I don&apos;t like chain restaurants so much...im looking for something special. I consider myself some what of a food snob =p hehhee Any suggestions would be awesome thanks!
 Open Question: Pappypizza.com Pizza delivery hot or ready to bake.? 
Do they deliver ready to bake pizza?
 Open Question: Pizza Auburn, WA. Any good local companies? 
Where is a good local Pizza Company around here that delivers, just moved to town and I do not like the Pizza Chains...too greasy and low quality cheese.
 Open Question: Pappy&apos;s Pizza in Auburn, WA? 
Where is Pappy&apos;s Pizza in Auburn, WA? They are so good, they used to be in Lakeland Towncenter but moved.
 Resolved Question: Mcdonalds interview.. yay.. help? 
Yeah I have a crappy interview at Mcdonalds tomorrow. Though I have no documents to say I&apos;m not a dirty immigrant because my mum lost it all. All I have is a bank card and college ID card, other details are arriving soon. Shall I even bother if I don&apos;t have these details? cheers guys
I also live in the UK and I&apos;m 17
 Open Question: I need a place to host a 30th birthday party in the Sacramento area? Nice dinner, not too formal? 

 Open Question: how long do you stay when working as a hostess in a restaurant? 
when you work in a restaurant pertically a hostess, do you stay your work hours (for example say if you were workin 12-5pm) do you stay for those 5 hrs or do you leave when business is slow?
 Open Question: Where is your favorite place to smoke Hookah in Maryland (MD)? 
Hookah lounges?
 Open Question: What shop in Blackpool have Henleys? 
Well me and my brother are planning to go shopping in Blackpool and i am wondering which stores should i be aiming at to buy certain Henleys brands? Thanks!
 Open Question: Does anyone remember that pizza commercial (I think Pizza Hut)? 
It was advertising &quot;old school&quot; Italian pizza and it had pictures of an old man and an old woman in picture frames talking about it? All I remember is &quot;mama mia!&quot; This is bothering me so much!
 Open Question: where can I find a lagal prostitute in Houston, TX? 
I don&apos;t wanna be charged with those street&apos;s girls so where is the best place to go find legal prostitutes, BS free?
 Open Question: How do I win McDonalds Monopoly game? 
So I know you collect pieces and stuff, could someone give me some more info on how winning is accomplished?
Also, can someone give me some info on the distribution of the rare pieces throughout the country?
Also, please provide some ways in which the collection of these pieces can be accomplished.
Where do the pieces come from? How are they distributed?
thanks
 Open Question: has anyone ever really won a house or thousands on McD&apos;s monopoly game? 
I always wonder if any of those md&apos;s prizes are ever won since you never hear about it..
 Open Question: where cana 15 yr old work in louisville ky? 

 Open Question: can anybody tell me what effect the recession had on the food and beverage industry in northern ireland? 
i also need the source. it has to be in northern ireland, not UK
 Open Question: ladki patane ka tarika..? 
can some one tell me the process to propose a girl i am making point from 5 days before she also i think possitive on me but i don&apos;t have any (+ve) idea to propose her..
 Open Question: male strip clubs in Montgomery or Auburn Al? 
I need to find a few male strip clubs in Montgomery or Auburn Alabama
My friends birthday is coming up soon
 Open Question: Do you want anyone to open a Hardee&apos;s, an Arby&apos;s, a Perkins or Ryan&apos;s in Brockton? 
Also, I want to put in a Sonic, a Bojangles, Back Yard Burgers, a Golden Corral, a Waffle House and a Huddle House in Brockton.
 Open Question: What are your fav dishes in restaurant? 
Hello, I would like to add some things to my menu in my restaurant, so i need you to tell me what are your favorite dishes and meals? The restaurant basically offers grill and pizza food, but you can add something completely new, just try to stick with basic European ingredients and short preparation time (less than 30min)
 Open Question: issss thisssss uglyyyy toooo youuuuu? 
i was thinking about dying my hair light blue and getting blood red streaks im rele chubby tho and my face is flabby i gotta lose weight but i still want to get a tattoo tho i wanna get it of an apple itll be right in my left eyelid what do u think shud i choose a diff styl if so tell me pls
 Open Question: Where&apos;s the best ceviche in Seattle? 

 Open Question: if someone had an OJE at Mcdonalds that he or she get the job? 
that means you get the job
 Open Question: Islam or Catholicism??? 
WHICH ONE IS CORRECT AND WHICH ONE IS BS?!?!
 Open Question: how many pizza rolls is too many? 

 Open Question: Does Dunkin Donuts pay more for third shift (overnight)? 
I know places like Walmart pays differential (higher wage) for overnight shifts, anyone have any idea if Dunkin&apos; does?
 Open Question: egl;vsnlbsnal. where do guys hang out in san francisco? 
i need to know where some guys hang out in sf, I WANNA FIND EM.
 Open Question: Can I ask for a McDonalds Monopoly Board in the drive-thru? 
I&apos;m just wondering.. I don&apos;t wanna feel i&apos;m asking for too much Lol
plus, i cant remember the last time i even went inside mcdonalds, if it wasnt at the food court, or rest station or something.
 Open Question: I went to whataburger (fast food) to go pick up my 1st check @12pm, she said come back after lunch.....when? 
whens &quot;after lunch&quot;?
 Open Question: Where can I get good Ramen in/around Arcadia? 
I know that just about any Asian restaurant in town serves Ramen, I&apos;m wanting to know if anyone has any specific recommendations based on a past positive experience.
 Open Question: Software MNC companies in DELHI ND NCR??? 
hey guys plz send me a full list of Software MNC companies in DELHI ND NCR........
plzzzzzzzz
 Open Question: Is there anywhere in America I can get a pizza with grasshoppers as a topping? 
I&apos;d like to find a place that makes pizza with grasshoppers as one of the toppings. I found a place that does locusts but it&apos;s just not the same. Thanks!
 Open Question: Why do restaurants rush you so much more in America as opposed to Europe? 
In New York, I saw a sign at Burger King that said you cannot eat there for more than 20 minutes. capitalism at its finest...
in Belgium, you have to call the waiters, whaling your arms at them to get the check. otherwise, you will sit there for hours. they&apos;re in no rush.
I&apos;m not talking about fancy restaurants. even cafe&apos;s and fastfood places.
 Open Question: What is the best burger joint in the bay? 
I&apos;ve been tasting burgers from places like barney&apos;s and I want to know what people think is the best. so I can taste it! Plus me and my friends go out about every week so where looking for some new places to spice up our dining experience. Lol. Help me plz!
 Open Question: Is this a good resume for McDonalds? 
First Last
My Address
City
123-456-7890 (Home) 123-456-7890 (Cell)
myemail
High SchoolCurrently Attending
Some High School
Address
Volunteer Work and Job History
Place
Location
Jul. 12, 2010 – Aug. 20, 2010
Summer Employee
•Room Repair
•Room Painting
Place
Location
Volunteer
•Inventory Sorting and Distribution
Skills and Qualifications
•Responsible individual that works at a consistent pace
•Experienced and knowledgeable with food service
•Courteous and friendly
•Has an excellent learning ability, and is good at math
I also might want to mention that I am 16.
 Open Question: What is the busiest/best Hooters resturaunt to work at in San Antonio? 

 Open Question: Where is a good spot for family friendly brunch in Toronto? 
We usually do Sundays at the Hot House (at Front and Church) but we&apos;re looking for something new.
Requirements:
- Must be able to accommodate up to 25 people including 4 kids under 2.
- Preferably accessible by transit and DVP (we have 8 who come in from the burbs)
- Buffet is nice - but not a must.
- Under $20 a person.
Suggestions?
 Resolved Question: Has anyone been tricked by their friends @ Hooters? 
For fun we all went out to Hooters. Little did I know my friends told the waitresses it was my birthday, WHICH IT WASN&apos;T!!! So halfway through my burger one of the girls pulls me into the middle of the packed resteraunt. They had me wear one of their uniforms over my clothes&amp;anaounced to the entire establishment it was my birthday. Then they had me to the hokey pokey with them. I didn&apos;t want to be mean so I went along anyways. So embaressing!
Meanwhile my friends were laughing their assess off
 Open Question: Is Cheeseburger Paradise Bar and Grill an expensive place to eat? 

 

   Alert | IP Printer-friendly page | Edit | Reply | Reply With Quote 
 
 

 
 
 Kurt 
 Member since Dec-5-02 
 8892 posts , 5 feedbacks , 8 points Oct-11-10, 05:08 PM (PST)   77. &quot;Open Question: I have to do a research project on a movie pertaining to American Hist&quot; 
 

 Open Question: I have to do a research project on a movie pertaining to American History...any ideas of movies? 
i have to research the validity of the movie and compare it to what actually happened in history. Although to me this sounds like something on the easy side, i cant seem to think of movies about American history. i would like to stray from war movies though because that would be a lot of research
thank you!
 Open Question: Have you ever got a perfect game playing Family Feud ? 
oh so close.. i need one 
 Open Question: What is the name of this song???????????? 
I heard this on 106.1 fm and it is the 5th best song (my opinion)
Here is some of the things i heard:
&apos;&apos;She said to let down all your friends and here to say, i never loved you anyways, i never did and i never will.&apos;&apos;
&apos;&apos;----should we kiss and, i took the bait and she didnt know what i was thinking,&apos;&apos;----should we kiss and, i took the bait and she didnt know what i was missing!&apos;&apos;
I hope you guys would know what this song is!! please tell me!!!
 Open Question: will there be an ironman 3? 
just after finially watching the long awaited ironman 2 i was dissaponted was not the first ironman movie better?. Any way after the credits rolled i fast foward it to the end of the credits and there was a clip at the end that goes for about 1 min any way some dude rocks up in a flashy car in a flashy suit at a dig site and says over a reciver &quot;we have located it&quot; and the camera zooms in on a hammer looking object and yhe sound of lightning ends that clip WTF.
is thor the guy with the lightning hammer going to appear in ironman 3?
 Open Question: John Mayer,&amp;Jack;Johnson, (:? 
Ohkay, I like John Mayer,&amp;Jack Johnson,&amp;i was wondering if anybody else knows any other songs, or artist that sing kinda like them, (: Please&amp;Thanks.
 Open Question: What alien superheroes in comics aren&apos;t superpowered? 
Here&apos;s a question for all you comic book nerds and geeks to wrap your brains around. There&apos;s no rule that says superheroes have to have physical superpowers- they can be attributable to their weapons, tools, equipment and conveyances. Many alien superheroes have superpowers, but which ones aren&apos;t?
The Hawkman family weren&apos;t superpowered- their powers came from their armor. The alien superheroes Flamebird and Nightwing didn&apos;t have physical superpowers.
Please list as many as you can. Thank you.
 Open Question: Im in to alternative music....band help? 
Out of alll the bands out there my two favorites are NeverShoutNever and All time Low!
I was listening to my iPod yesterday and I have 180 songs or so but like it was all the same bands..
Here are some more I like;
Simple Plan, Fall out Boy, Blink 182, We The Kings, Forever the Sickest Kids and Hit The Lights to name but a few(:
Can you please help me some with finding alternative bands like these ones^^^^
It would really help me
Thanks!
Also Coldplay is in there!
I also have another thing to ask, is Olw City alternative music?
 Open Question: Netflix movies keep stopping, pausing and skipping. Why? 

 Open Question: What is the thing Kanye West was playing at the VMA&apos;s? 
At the VMA&apos;s Kanye West was playing this little electronic device during the song RUnaway. What is it. Is it some sort of autotune machine. What are these little devices called.
 http://www.mtv.com/videos/misc/571850/runaway-live.jhtml 
 Open Question: What would you do if you saw hannah montana running in her bare feet away from a wolf? 
WOULD THE FACT THAT SHE IS BAREFOOT HAVE ANY IMPACT ON WHAT YOU WOULD DO
 Open Question: Let me have your opinions (Pictures included)? 
 http://postimage.org/image/rnr47xxg /
Let me have your opinions on this jacket for a guy? In all honesty.
 Open Question: Is there a music video out for this song? 
11th hour by Lauren﻿ Evans
I tried looking everywhere for a music video and all I found was just downloads for MP3 and a video
with just the song.
Help? 
 Open Question: From High School Debut
	</body>
</document>
