<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006372" url="http://www.familyguyx.net/season_6/" time="2012-07-12-23:14" support="3" score="0.0030192136807609235" bingtitle="Family Guy X | Season 6 Family Guy Episodes" webtitle="Family Guy X | Season 6 Family Guy Episodes">
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>Desperate to put an end to Stewie&apos;s reign of ... hand when a fire breaks out at a local fast food restaurant. ... has found it, but is currently using his credit card to ...</description>
	<body>
		Family Guy 

 Register Faq Bookmark Us Tell a Friend Contact Us 

 Home Episodes Information Clips Facebook Applications 

 Family Guy Episodes: Season 1 Season 2 Season 3 Season 4 Season 5 Season 6 S7 S8 S9 S10 
 Member Login: Remember Me? 


 Lost password? 

 Register Now! 
 
 
 Play Angry Birds Online 

 
 South Park Episodes 

 
 American Dad Episodes 
Family Guy Season 6 Episodes
 
 1 Blue Harvest 09/23/2007 1,377,224 Views 
 
With the Griffins stuck at home during a blackout, Peter begins to tell a story, which leads to a Star Wars flashback. Acting out scenes from Star Wars Episode IV: A New Hope, Peter plays Han Solo, Lois is Princess Leia, Stewie becomes Darth Vader, Brian plays Chewbacca, and Chris is Luke Skywalker.
 
 2 Movin&apos; Out (Brian&apos;s Song) 09/30/2007 611,284 Views 
 
Peter convinces Brian to move in with Jillian. Stewie moves in with them as well to help pay the rent, but he tries to interfere with Brian and Jillian&apos;s relationship by throwing Brian a drinking party. Meanwhile, Meg and Chris get jobs at the local convenience store. While Chris and the manager, Carl, talk about their favorite movies, Meg is stuck with all the hard work.
 
 3 Believe It Or Not, Joe&apos;s Walking On Air 10/07/2007 737,863 Views 
 
When Bonnie tells Joe that she is tired of being married to a handicapped person, Joe gets a leg transplant. Excited about his new ability to walk, Joe engages in extreme sport, and soon ditches his current friends, for more active ones. Peter and the guys are upset at how Joe is acting and decide to teach him a lesson.
 
 4 Stewie Kills Lois (1) 11/05/2007 991,763 Views 
 
Lois and Peter sail off on a cruise. Jealous that he was left behind, Stewie&apos;s matricidal tendencies are rekindled. When Brian challenges him to actually do it, Stewie carries out his diabolical plan.
 
 5 Lois Kills Stewie (2) 11/11/2007 1,033,816 Views 
 
Returning from her presumed death, Lois reveals her attempted killer to be Stewie. Stewie then takes his family hostage, slowly gaining more power until the world itself is at its knees. Desperate to put an end to Stewie&apos;s reign of terror, Lois realizes what she must do...
 
 6 Padre de Familia 11/18/2007 1,063,896 Views 
 
Peter starts an anti-immigration group, but immediately changes his views after discovering he was born in Mexico. Unable to prove his American citizenship, he is labeled as an illegal immigrant and forced to work as a laborer.
 
 7 Peter&apos;s Daughter 11/25/2007 1,792,589 Views 
 
Meg finds herself interested in a cute med student who treats her at the hospital and soon hits it off with him. However, an overprotective Peter is determined to drive the student away. Meanwhile, Brian and Stewie buy and renovate a dilapidated house.
 
 8 McStroke 01/13/2008 849,183 Views 
 
Peter decides to grow a mustache, but then he&apos;s mistaken for a fireman (because they all have mustaches), so he lends a hand when a fire breaks out at a local fast food restaurant. The owner gives him unlimited burgers as a &quot;thank you&quot; but he eats so many that he eventually has a stroke.
 
 9 Back to the Woods 02/17/2008 507,523 Views 
 
After attending a concert featuring Barry Manilow, Peter realizes that he has accidentally dropped his wallet there. However, he soon discovers that someone has found it, but is currently using his credit card to buy expensive things. After recieving a bank letter, Peter and Brian track down the culprit to a Chinese restaurant and discover him to be none other than James Woods, whom Peter had previously locked away in a Government Warehouse.
 
 10 Play it Again, Brian 03/02/2008 438,231 Views 
 
Lois is growing increasingly frustrated with Peter, who has been much more focused on spending time with his friends than with her. Brian, who had just won a vacation to Martha&apos;s Vineyard to receive a writing award, decides to take the two with him to help them sort things out between themselves.
 
 11 The Former Life of Brian 09/03/2008 310,452 Views 
 
Brian meets up with an old girlfriend, discovering that he is the illegitimate father of her unruly son. The child is dropped off at the Griffin&apos;s house so Brian can raise him; there the boy quickly gets out of hand, and Brian&apos;s self-centered approach to parenting doesn&apos;t settle too well with Peter and Lois...
 
 12 Long John Peter 09/03/2008 271,771 Views 
 
Peter buys a pet parrot and begins to believe he is a pirate. Not surprisingly, it all goes to his head as he literally becomes the scourge of the neighborhood until he accidentally kills his beloved bird...
 
Family Guy Episodes

 Season 1 Season 2 Season 3 Season 4 Season 5 Season 6 Season 7 Season 8 Season 9 
 
Random Family Guy Episodes
 
 Brian Writes a Bestseller 

Season 9 Episode 6
 Airdate: 11/21/2010 Total Views: 138,346 Rating: 8.5 
 Holy Crap 

Season 2 Episode 2
 Airdate: 09/30/1999 Total Views: 230,290 Rating: 8.5 
 DaBoom 

Season 2 Episode 3
 Airdate: 12/26/1999 Total Views: 278,266 Rating: 8.5 
 Death Has a Shadow 

Season 1 Episode 1
 Airdate: 01/31/1999 Total Views: 676,621 Rating: 8.5 
 Lois Kills Stewie (2) 

Season 6 Episode 5
 Airdate: 11/11/2007 Total Views: 1,033,816 Rating: 8.5 
 Refresh Random FG Episodes 
 
Popular Family Guy Episodes
 
 Peter&apos;s Daughter 

Season 6 Episode 7
 Airdate: 11/25/2007 Total Views: 1,792,589 Rating: 8.5 
 Blue Harvest 

Season 6 Episode 1
 Airdate: 09/23/2007 Total Views: 1,377,224 Rating: 8.5 
 Padre de Familia 

Season 6 Episode 6
 Airdate: 11/18/2007 Total Views: 1,063,896 Rating: 8.5 
 Lois Kills Stewie (2) 

Season 6 Episode 5
 Airdate: 11/11/2007 Total Views: 1,033,816 Rating: 8.5 
 Stewie Kills Lois (1) 

Season 6 Episode 4
 Airdate: 11/05/2007 Total Views: 991,763 Rating: 8.5 
 More Popular FG Episodes 
 
Copyright©2008 - FamilyGuyX.net

 Contact Us Disclaimer Privacy Policy 


 Mobile Games: smurfs village cheats Temple Run Cheats Dragonvale FarmVille 2 Facebook Games 


Family Guy is a registered trademark of Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation.. All related videos, clips, images etc. are copyrighted and owned by their respective owners.
	</body>
</document>
