<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006262" url="http://repairpal.com/high-idle-415" time="2012-07-12-22:56" support="1" score="0.0014711240719581288" bingtitle="high idle : RepairPal - Auto Repair and Maintenance Estimates ..." webtitle="high idle - 2005 Ford Focus">
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>I have a 05 focus sometimes when I put it in park it ... I had the car for 3 days after and when I was on line at a fast food restaurant, it began to o...</description>
	<body>
		Find a Shop Estimator MyCar Advice Checklist ( ) Checklist Add Note» Checklist 
 
 Cancel | Save 
Find the best Ford repair shops

RepairPal&apos;s independent, master mechanics track down the best of the best in auto repair. Learn more» 
 - Select Car Make - Acura Audi BMW Buick Cadillac Chevrolet Chrysler Dodge Ford Geo GMC Honda Hummer Hyundai Infiniti Isuzu Jaguar Jeep Kia Land Rover Lexus Lincoln Mazda Mercedes-Benz Mercury Mini Mitsubishi Nissan Oldsmobile Plymouth Pontiac Porsche Saab Saturn Scion Subaru Suzuki Toyota Volkswagen Volvo near Find a Top Shop 
Get the latest advice about your car
 Ford 2005 Focus Get Started Share 
 Google+ Facebook Twitter Email 
 Advice » Q&amp;A »2005 Ford Focus 
 Q&amp;A Problem Reports 
 Most Reported Newest RepairPal Verified 
 Recalls Encyclopedia 
 Brakes Drivetrain Electrical&amp;Lights Engine Exhaust&amp;Emissions Heating&amp;AC Scheduled Maintenance Suspension&amp;Steering 
 Auto Care Advice 
 Auto Basics Hints&amp;Tips How To&apos;s Lifestyle References Troubleshooting 
 Owners&apos; Reviews Blog 
 Car News For Fun General Interest Industry News Mechanic&apos;s Corner RepairPal News Technology Tips&amp;Tricks 
 
 View questions for: All Ford 
 Focus 
 2005 Ford Focus 
Q&amp;A
 Ask Your Question 
2005 Ford Focus
  
Question: high idle
 
Question
 lefthacker , 2.0L 4 Cylinder, Minneapolis, MN, April 16, 2011, 08:51   Rookie 

I have a 05 focus sometimes when I put it in park it revs up

 1 Answer Answer It Flag This Follow this Question Unfollow this Question 
 
Answer #1
 DaveJHM April 17, 2011, 00:43   Master 

I would look for a vacuum leak, an air intake leak, a sticking idle control valve or throttle body...

...or it could be a calibration issue with the processor that needs to be reprogrammed at the dealer. Hard to say without a proper diagnostic test.

 Reply Flag This Like | 1 person likes this 1 
 Related Items: 
 High idle and rough idle with check engine coming on. Car suffers from high idle and rough idle with check engine light coming on. Can a bad tps cause this problem. No vacuum...
Q&amp;A&gt;Ford&gt;2002 Ford Focus
 accelerator pedal too high rpm on my focus went too high,i serviced acc.cable,throttle,
checked vacuum leak,replaced intake manifold gaskets and idle air control valve.Now the rpm is OK, but accelerator pedal is too high.I k...
Q&amp;A&gt;Ford&gt;2003 Ford Focus
 My system emission light keeps coming on. I had it checked and it&apos;s idling high So, I am not sure what this means. They said it would cost a lot of $$$ to take everything apart to see what the problem is. It sometimes comes on for a couple of days, then goes away. I drive a...
Q&amp;A&gt;Ford&gt;2007 Ford Focus
 my car overheats when idling and moving in slow traffic A/C is not on when this happens. Mechanic could not duplicate condition and had the car for 3 days. I had the car for 3 days after and when I was on line at a fast food restaurant, it began to o...
Q&amp;A&gt;Ford&gt;2004 Ford Focus
 Engine After the car has been idle the engine has slow pickup and sounds like it&apos;s revving high...like it&apos;s struggling to get to the next gear.

I recently had the fuel filter changed, but that did not ...
Q&amp;A&gt;Ford&gt;2004 Ford Focus
 
 Answer Ranks 
This week&apos;s top 10

 1 globalhelper 6 rajewski.wayne 2 helpfull4u 7 milesauto 3 ziptie12 8 Chevy Power 4 i fixem 2 9 eric1125 5 Happy2012day 10 Dealer Diagnostics 
 
 Recent Ford Focus Questions 2007 Focus the gear shift isn&apos;t working what repair do I need? gear shift is not changing into gears I have oil on a spark plug, what does this mean? 2003 Ford Focus transmission problem Does P0455 self clear or does it require manual reset? See more» 
 Follow Us 
 Home Find a Shop Estimator MyCar Advice Welcome Shops&amp;Dealerships 

 About RepairPal Mobile Blog FAQ Feedback 
 
 Repair Shops : San Francisco | New York | San Diego | Chicago | Los Angeles | Denver | Dallas | Houston | Seattle | Las Vegas | San Jose | Miami | Sacramento 
 Makes : Ford | Toyota | Honda | Chevrolet | Dodge | BMW | Acura | Nissan | Volkswagen | Chrysler | Lexus | Mercury | Cadillac | Hyundai | Buick | Volvo | Audi 
 Models : Honda Accord | Toyota Camry | Honda Civic | Acura TL | Toyota Corolla | Ford Taurus | Volkswagen Jetta | BMW 325i | Ford Explorer | Ford Escort 
 Auto Care Advice : Auto Basics | Common Problems | Hints&amp;Tips | How To&apos;s | Lifestyle | Owners&apos; Stories | Q&amp;A | Recalls | References | Troubleshooting 
 Encyclopedia : Brakes | Drivetrain | Electrical&amp;Lights | Engine | Exhaust&amp;Emissions | Heating&amp;AC | Scheduled Maintenance | Suspension&amp;Steering 
 Use of this site is subject to express Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
By continuing past this page, you agree to abide by these terms. Copyright©2012 RepairPal, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
