<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006775" url="http://www.shopping.com/counting-scale-6lb/products" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="2" score="0.0018835633146194182" bingtitle="&quot;counting scale 6lb&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="counting scale 6lb- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>Select a Department ... operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant ... AVthing in its place is currently running a</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Pallet scale ,  Parts counting scale ,  Scale ,  Weigh tronix ,  more» Paper counting scale ,  Counting scale cas ,  Troemner weight ,  Toledo scale ,  Money counting machine ,  Counting scale weight ,  Levis 560 ,  Counting scale 60 ,  Couting scale ,  A d scale    less» Shopping 
 counting scale 6lb 
 Showing results for &quot;
counting scale 6lb
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ Sponsored Results MEASURETEK 12R982 Counting... $479.00 Grainger Detecto CS-6 6lb Top Loading Counting... $429.00    $353.02 
 6lb Counting Scale 6lb Counting Scale 
 New ( In stock ) 
CBD Bench Counting Scale Designed for versatility Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the CBD unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic weighing,... More 

CBD Bench Counting Scale Designed for versatility Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the CBD unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic weighing, dual counting with separate platform hook up ready, check counting, parts counting, weigh and count accumulation plus 100PLUs.The easy-to-use CBD is the right choice for industry when flexibility matters. Repetitive weighing tasks are fast and simple with a large stainless steel platform, and backlit display, The CBD includes features like RS232 interface, date&amp;time, a built in rechargeable battery pack and AC adapter, to make it ideal for production, warehousing or even in the field. Features Large backlit LCD Full numeric keypadColor coded keysRechargeable batteryRS-232 interface with multi-language, date and time output Stainless steel panAdjustable feet and level bubble2 weighing units ( Kg, lb,)Memory accumulation Dual channel connector 16.00 L. 14.00 W. 7.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /6lb-counting-scale/-loj9MBIlr_diawCysrQ1g==/info $545.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial 
 New ( In stock ) 
Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of... More 

Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of capacities listed below. Sturdy construction, stability, convenient viewing angle, temperature compensation for dependable accuracy in environments with fluctuating temperatures and easy readability make these the petite top loaders of choice. Whether the operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant, formulating paint mixtures by weight, verifying parcel weights in a shipping department, portioning in service areas, or counting by weight, there is a Detecto Top Loader right for the task. 12.00 L. 9.00 W. 9.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /top-loader-scale-5-lb-x/vd5xO_9x839C2_qRXrRn3Q==/info $54.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 MEASURETEK 12R982 Counting Scale,3kg/6lb 12R982 MEASURETEK 12R982 Counting Scale,3kg/6lb 12R982 
 ( In stock ) 
 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 3kg/6 Lb., Readability 0.1g/0.0002 Lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In.,... More 

 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 3kg/6 Lb., Readability 0.1g/0.0002 Lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In., Weighing Surface Depth 8-5/8 In., Max. Tare 3kg/6lb, Application Modes Weighing, Counting, Checkweighing, Accumulation, Apw, Connection Ports Rs232, Material Stainless Steel, Abs, Power Unit Ac Adapter, Rechargeable Battery, Standards Ul, Ce, Includes Ac Adapter, Ni-mh Battery Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /measuretek-12r982/gtgvhHXi7n7ODzwz0SYQ6g==/info Grainger $479.00 +$11.28 shipping Visit Store 
 Detecto Pt 5r (pt5r) Petite Top Loading Dial Scale 
 Detecto Pt 5r (pt5r) Petite Top Loading Dial Scale from $59.11 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details 
 Detecto 6 lb Digital Counting Scale Detecto 6 lb Digital Counting Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
Digital counting scale; 6 lb x .0005 lb/3 kg x .2 g capacity; Portable unit with 11.38&quot; x 8.25&quot; stainless steel platform; Built-in rechargeable battery pack monitors battery life and... More 

Digital counting scale; 6 lb x .0005 lb/3 kg x .2 g capacity; Portable unit with 11.38&quot; x 8.25&quot; stainless steel platform; Built-in rechargeable battery pack monitors battery life and recharges battery while in operation; Liquid crystal display is .75&quot; high with backlight; Shows weight, average piece weight and count; Color-coded keypad; 1 year warranty Less 
 Tundra Specialties Store not rated See Store Info /detecto-6-lb-digital/pk2oswpLhlmmzQUd3OPa_A==/info Tundra Specialties $328.06 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 MEASURETEK 12R982 Counting Scale,3kg/6lb MEASURETEK 12R982 Counting Scale,3kg/6lb 
 Free Ground Shipping on orders in July! ( In stock ) 
 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 3kg/6 lb., Readability 0.1g/0.0002 lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In.,... More 

 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 3kg/6 lb., Readability 0.1g/0.0002 lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In., Weighing Surface Depth 8-5/8 In., Max. Tare 3kg/6lb, Application Modes Weighing, Counting, Checkweighing, Accumulation, APW, Connection Ports RS232, Material Stainless Steel, ABS, Power Unit AC Adapter, Rechargeable Battery, Standards UL, CE, Includes AC Adapter, Ni-MH Battery Less 
 Zoro Tools Store not rated See Store Info /measuretek-12r982/yFam2k4juKm4GHHk07FfMw==/info Zoro Tools $285.00 Free Shipping Visit Store 
 MEASURETEK 12R983 Counting Scale,6kg/15lb 12R983 MEASURETEK 12R983 Counting Scale,6kg/15lb 12R983 
 ( In stock ) 
 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 6kg/15 Lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 Lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In.,... More 

 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 6kg/15 Lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 Lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In., Weighing Surface Depth 8-5/8 In., Max. Tare 6kg/15lb, Application Modes Weighing, Counting, Checkweighing, Accumulation, Apw, Connection Ports Rs232, Material Stainless Steel, Abs, Power Unit Ac Adapter, Rechargeable Battery, Standards Ul, Ce, Includes Ac Adapter, Ni-mh Battery Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /measuretek-12r983/lZgKAnhrPpofriY3o4QaPg==/info Grainger $479.00 +$11.28 shipping Visit Store -18% 
 Detecto CS-6 6lb Top Loading Counting Scale Detecto CS-6 6lb Top Loading Counting Scale 
 Counting Scale-Top loading counter model-Liquid crystal digital display with backlight-Count accumulator-6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g-Color-coded keypad-11.38 x 8.25 stainless steel platform-Rechargeable battery pack or 115 or 230 VAC 50/60 Hz ( In stock ) 
 Counting Scale-Top loading counter model-Liquid crystal digital display with backlight-Count accumulator-6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g-Color-coded keypad-11.38 x 8.25 stainless steel platform-... More 

 Counting Scale-Top loading counter model-Liquid crystal digital display with backlight-Count accumulator-6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g-Color-coded keypad-11.38 x 8.25 stainless steel platform- Rechargeable battery pack or 115 or 230 VAC 50/60 Hz Less 
 Instawares, LLC 371 store reviews See Store Info /detecto-cs6-6lb-top/bH2mMHChemB5oIOcJA9ysg==/info $429.00 $353.02 18% Off +$24.71 shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/48/72/42464f354b7647776962532d547a6a74337a67-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=9&amp;d;=285.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 MEASURETEK 12R983 Counting Scale,6kg/15lb MEASURETEK 12R983 Counting Scale,6kg/15lb 
 Free Ground Shipping on orders in July! ( In stock ) 
 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 6kg/15 lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In.,... More 

 Counting Scale, Dry Use, Capacity 6kg/15 lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 lb., Overall Length 11-5/8 In., Overall Width 13-1/2 In., Overall Height 4-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-1/2 In., Weighing Surface Depth 8-5/8 In., Max. Tare 6kg/15lb, Application Modes Weighing, Counting, Checkweighing, Accumulation, APW, Connection Ports RS232, Material Stainless Steel, ABS, Power Unit AC Adapter, Rechargeable Battery, Standards UL, CE, Includes AC Adapter, Ni-MH Battery Less 
 Zoro Tools Store not rated See Store Info /measuretek-12r983/WHrBFO5KvGwibS-Tzjt3zg==/info Zoro Tools $285.00 Free Shipping Visit Store -20% http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/59/54/78654d3537324751635742536739744b646341-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=10&amp;d;=343.2&amp;rt;=mr 
 Detecto CS-6 - Top Loading Counting Scale w/ Digital Display, 6 x .0005-lb Detecto CS-6 - Top Loading Counting Scale w/ Digital Display, 6 x .0005-lb 
 Scale, Counting, Top loading counter model, liquid crystal digital display with backlight, count accumulator, 6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g, color-coded keypad, 11.38&quot;x 12.63&quot;stainless steel platform, rechargeable battery pack or 115 or 230 VAC 50/60 Hz ( Detecto - CS-6 ) ( In stock ) 
Scale, Counting, Top loading counter model, liquid crystal digital display with backlight, count accumulator, 6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g, color-coded keypad, 11.38&quot; x 12.63&quot; stainless steel... More 

Scale, Counting, Top loading counter model, liquid crystal digital display with backlight, count accumulator, 6 lb/3 kg x .0005 lb/.2 g, color-coded keypad, 11.38&quot; x 12.63&quot; stainless steel platform, rechargeable battery pack or 115 or 230 VAC 50/60 Hz ( Detecto - CS-6 ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /detecto-cs6-top/aYTxeM572GQcWBSg9tKdcA==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $429.00 $343.20 20% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/4b/03/af/109857610-100x100-0-0_detecto+detecto+2240+100+digital+counting+scale+10.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=11&amp;d;=875.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Detecto 2240-100 Digital Counting Scale 100-lb Capacity 
 Detecto 2240-100 Digital Counting Scale 100-lb Capacity Red for Detecto from $875.00 2 stores See Details http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/product/no_image_100x100.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=12&amp;d;=829.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Tc6rsp Trooper Count Scale 15 Lb/6 Kg 
 Ohaus Tc6rsp Trooper Count Scale 15 Lb/6 Kg for Ohaus $829.60 Free Shipping 1 store See Details -20% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/58/33/70/416b39317349444f50536a504c6f7a514a5a41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=13&amp;d;=239.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. Table Top Counting Scale, Legal for Trade Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. Table Top Counting Scale, Legal for Trade 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Portable, accurate, and easy to use, the Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. table top counting scale is the practical solution to your weighing needs in warehouse, hardware store, or small business!... More 

Portable, accurate, and easy to use, the Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. table top counting scale is the practical solution to your weighing needs in warehouse, hardware store, or small business! This table top counting scale can be easily calibrated so you can quickly and consistently package the same amount of a product one after the other. And thanks to its rechargeable 200-hour battery, you can be sure that this unit will stay powered for days at a time, even without a nearby outlet. Made of stainless steel for easy cleaning and long-lasting durability, this rechargeable portion scale features a large 9&quot; x 6&quot; platform and programmable tare function designed to give you total control over all of your measurement needs up to 5 lbs. The backlit, alphanumeric LCD screen clearly shows the weight of portioned items, even in dark areas. To promote accurate and consistent record keeping, this scale can easily hook up to a PC or printer with its RC-232 data port. The Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. table top counting scale is NTEP Approved and comes with a 110V power supply. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details. Readout Measurements: 5 kg. x 0.0005 kg. 10 lb. x 0.001 lb. 160 oz. x 0.001 lb. Dimensions: Width: 15 1/8&quot; Depth: 12 3/8&quot; Height: 5 5/8&quot; Platform Dimensions: 9&quot; x 6&quot; Tor Rey software is not compatible with Apple / Mac computers. QC-5/10 From TOR REY Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /tor-rey-qc510-10-lb/X3pAk91sIDOPSjPLozQJZA==/info The WEBstaurant Store $299.00 $239.00 20% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/48/4b/45/6e4951465952486141613371344c514b693277-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=14&amp;d;=109.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 My Weigh i1200 -1200g x 0.1 Scale My Weigh i1200 -1200g x 0.1 Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
The i500, i1200, and i2600 are professional compact scales with a backlight and extra large LCD screen. The backlight makes it easy to read from a distance. Each scale now comes with a... More 

The i500, i1200, and i2600 are professional compact scales with a backlight and extra large LCD screen. The backlight makes it easy to read from a distance. Each scale now comes with a large Stainless Steel tray, parts counting features and 6AA batteries or an AC Adaptor. Scale professionals know that &quot;multiplied&quot; sensors simply won&apos;t cut it when accuracy and durability count. The i500 uses a true 5000 division load cell, the i1200 uses a true 12000 division load cell and the i2600 uses a whopping 26000 division load cell. These commercial grade sensors make this scale incredibly accurate and durable. The i series also has an integrated thermistor to compensate for temperature changes and auto zero tracking to ensure stability. Accuracy i500 i1200 i2600 0.1g 500g 1200g 2600g 0.005oz 17.635oz 18oz 91.71oz 0.005ozt 17.075 ozt 39ozt 83.6ozt 0.05dwt 322dwt 772dwt 1672dwt 0.5ct 2500ct 6000ct 13000ct 0.0005lb 1.1lb 2.65lb 5.75lb 1gn 7716gn 18518gn 40124gn Now Improved for 2005 with more features! Reads in Grams, Ounces, Pounds, Troy Ounces, Pennyweight, Carats, and Grains Tare and Beep function Certified Accurate +/- 0.1 gram True division load cells Large backlit LCD display Large Stainless Steel Platform Adjustable Auto Off and Backlight features Advanced Parts Counting feature Less 
 National Jewelers Supplie Store not rated See Store Info /my-weigh-i1200-1200g-x/HKEnIQFYRHaAa3q4LQKi2w==/info $109.95 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4b/43/57/3861444f30414f6d4f2d464a425f4357585867-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=15&amp;d;=100.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 M-Series Digital Scale- Restaurant And Industrial M-Series Digital Scale- Restaurant And Industrial 
 New ( In stock ) 
The NSF-Certified M-Series scales can be used in a variety of restaurant and industrial applications, from portion control to accurate quality control. The spill proof designed scale will... More 

The NSF-Certified M-Series scales can be used in a variety of restaurant and industrial applications, from portion control to accurate quality control. The spill proof designed scale will prove to be highly reliable in intense work environments. 13 lb / 6 kg (0.1 oz / 1 gr) Features: Measures in grams, pounds, ounces and pounds + ouncesStainless steel removable weighing platform for easy clean- upHold/Display will stay on after you step of the scale, and show measurement for short period of time and Parts Counting featureAdditional display on the back of the unitLCD display with on/off switch for blue backlight Four D batteries included (AC adaptor optional) Dimensions: 10.25&quot; x 11.75&quot; x 4.25&quot; 13.25 L. 11.50 W. 5.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /mseries-digital/KCW8aDO0AOmO-FJB_CWXXg==/info $100.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/47/6d/53/3278385548764d4e3151374a486a7a73723967-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=16&amp;d;=457.1&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EC3-US Digital Counting Scale,Cap 6 Lb OHAUS EC3-US Digital Counting Scale,Cap 6 Lb 
 Free Ground Shipping on orders in July! ( In stock ) 
Digital Counting Scale, Capacity 3000 Grams, Readability 0.1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing... More 

Digital Counting Scale, Capacity 3000 Grams, Readability 0.1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 8 7/8 In, Max Tare 3000 Grams, Plastic Material, Battery, AC Power Unit, UL, CE, NSF Standards, Includes AC Power Pack, Rechargeable Battery Less 
 Zoro Tools Store not rated See Store Info /ohaus-ec3us-digital/GmS2x8UHvMN1Q7JHjzsr9g==/info Zoro Tools $457.10 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/78/56/306d487470516a324b5f6e776a636a5a366b77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=17&amp;d;=284.75&amp;rt;=mr 
 CITIZEN 12R987 Weighing Scale, 6000g/6kg/13lb 12R987 CITIZEN 12R987 Weighing Scale, 6000g/6kg/13lb 12R987 
 ( In stock ) 
Weighing Scale, Compact, Capacity 6kg/13 Lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 Lb., Overall Length 13-1/2 In., Overall Width 12-5/8 In., Overall Height 5 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-5/8 In.,... More 

Weighing Scale, Compact, Capacity 6kg/13 Lb., Readability 0.2g/0.0005 Lb., Overall Length 13-1/2 In., Overall Width 12-5/8 In., Overall Height 5 In., Weighing Surface Width 11-5/8 In., Weighing Surface Depth 8-7/8 In., Max. Tare 6000g/6kg/13 Lb, Application Modes Weighing, Parts Counting, Checkweighing, Percent Weighing, Accumulation, Pre-set Tare And Unit Conversion, Material Stainless Steel, Abs, Power Unit Ac Adapter, Rechargeable Battery, Standards Ce,emc Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /citizen-12r987-weighing/_xV0mHtpQj2K_nwjcjZ6kw==/info Grainger $284.75 +$11.32 shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/55/76/74/6d657a7462566e37507a51566d4d566e524941-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=18&amp;d;=649.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 12lb Capacity Counting Scale 12lb Capacity Counting Scale 
 Usually ships in 5-7 business days ( In stock ) 
Stop wasting time counting paper by hand, invest in a paper counting scale. Hand-counting paper is one of the most time consuming and least profitable tasks in a print shop. These counting... More 

Stop wasting time counting paper by hand, invest in a paper counting scale. Hand-counting paper is one of the most time consuming and least profitable tasks in a print shop. These counting scales can turn a time consuming job into a speedy one, and do it far more accurately. The Counting Scales have been designed for cost-conscious users and will count paper from business card size up to 11&quot; x 17&quot;. Questions? We are here for you. Call us at (866)537-2244. Specifications&amp;Features: ModelHC-6Ki Capacity12 lbs. (6kg) Resolution0.002 lb. (1g) Quantity/Box1 Weight / Shipping Weight10 lbs. / 12 lbs. Product Code00MISC List Price$681.45 You Save5% Our Price$649 Less 
 Binding101 Store not rated See Store Info /12lb-capacity-counting/UvtmeztbVn7PzQVmMVnRIA==/info $649.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/b2/e5/f1/75955029-100x100-0-0_Hagen+Detecto+PT+25+Petite+Top+Loading+Dial+Kitche.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=19&amp;d;=58.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Hagen Detecto PT-25 Petite Top Loading Dial Kitchen - Food Scale, 25 lb. x 1/8 lb., Fixed Dial 
 Hagen Detecto PT-25 Petite Top Loading Dial Kitchen - Food Scale, 25 lb. x 1/8 lb., Fixed Dial from $58.95 Free Shipping 3 stores See Details -20% http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/75/69/49/5f625a5238356a574b33756532766447783877-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=20&amp;d;=239.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. Table Top Counting Scale, Legal for Trade Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. Table Top Counting Scale, Legal for Trade 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Portable, accurate, and easy to use, the Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. table top counting scale is the practical solution to your weighing needs in warehouse, hardware store, or small business!... More 

Portable, accurate, and easy to use, the Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. table top counting scale is the practical solution to your weighing needs in warehouse, hardware store, or small business! This table top counting scale can be easily calibrated so you can quickly and consistently package the same amount of a product one after the other. And thanks to its rechargeable 200-hour battery, you can be sure that this unit will stay powered for days at a time, even without a nearby outlet. Made of stainless steel for easy cleaning and long-lasting durability, this rechargeable portion scale features a large 9&quot; x 6&quot; platform and programmable tare function designed to give you total control over all of your measurement needs up to 10 lbs. The backlit, alphanumeric LCD screen clearly shows the weight of portioned items, even in dark areas. To promote accurate and consistent record keeping, this scale can easily hook up to a PC or printer with its RC-232 data port. The Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. table top counting scale is NTEP Approved and comes with a 110V power supply. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details. Readout Measurements: 10 kg. x 0.001 kg. 20 lb. x 0.002 lb. 320 oz. x 0.002 lb. Dimensions: Width: 15 1/8&quot; Depth: 12 3/8&quot; Height: 5 5/8&quot; Platform Dimensions: 9&quot; x 6&quot; Tor Rey software is not compatible with Apple / Mac computers. QC-10/20 From TOR REY Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /tor-rey-qc1020-20-lb/uiI_bZR85jWK3ue2vdGx8w==/info The WEBstaurant Store $299.00 $239.00 20% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/53/6d/4f/526b62756d71307a50673450767a584e754b77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=21&amp;d;=710.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pennsylvania Heavy Duty Counting Scale - 20lb Capacity Pennsylvania Heavy Duty Counting Scale - 20lb Capacity 
 New ( In stock ) 
Made in the U.S.A. Fast, accurate and dependable. Designed for speed and exceptional accuracy, this scale is the heart of any inventory control requirement. No other counting scale provides... More 

Made in the U.S.A. Fast, accurate and dependable. Designed for speed and exceptional accuracy, this scale is the heart of any inventory control requirement. No other counting scale provides more impressive performance and value with the same simplicity and rugged durability. Features include fast one button counting, Bright LED display, heavy duty cast construction, two different units of measure, 4 pre-set sample sizes, RS232 interface. 4 Year Limited Warranty. 20 lbs. / 10 kg. capacity. 14&quot;W x 15-1/2&quot;D x 5-1/4&quot;H overall. 22.00 L. 20.00 W. 6.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /pennsylvania-heavy-duty/SmORkbumq0zPg4PvzXNuKw==/info $710.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/64/74/6e/336370655244706b6151426271376746773567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=22&amp;d;=873.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Ranger Count RC6RS With RS232 Port Ohaus Ranger Count RC6RS With RS232 Port 
 Shipped Next Bus. Day ( In stock ) 
The Ohaus Ranger Count Counting Scales - 6RS Series. 6 models to choose from each with 13lb x 0.0005lb capacity, stainless steel platform&amp;great features. Models: RC6RS, RC6RS/1, RC6RS/2,... More 

The Ohaus Ranger Count Counting Scales - 6RS Series. 6 models to choose from each with 13lb x 0.0005lb capacity, stainless steel platform&amp;great features. Models: RC6RS, RC6RS/1, RC6RS/2, RC6RS/3, RC6RS/4, RC6RS/5 Less 
 OldWillKnottSca les 574 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-ranger-count-rc6rs/dtn3cpeRDpkaQBbq7gFw5g==/info $873.60 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/28/d4/90/126210604-100x100-0-0_ohaus+ohaus+ranger+count+plus+rp6rm+rs232+port.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=23&amp;d;=2076.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Ranger Count Plus RP6RM + RS232 Port 
 Ohaus Ranger Count Plus RP6RM + RS232 Port from $2,076.00 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/product/no_image_100x100.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=24&amp;d;=829.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Tc3rsp Trooper Count Scale 6 Lab/3 Kg 
 Ohaus Tc3rsp Trooper Count Scale 6 Lab/3 Kg for Ohaus $829.60 Free Shipping 1 store See Details http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4d/72/6f/447a58564675394b6f5662556b703271613841-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=25&amp;d;=120.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Prime Scales 13.2lbs / 0.0005lb Counting Scale with 10... Prime Scales 13.2lbs / 0.0005lb Counting Scale with 10 Pre-sets Memory | Check Weighing 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The PS-C30K06 is an excellent counting scale for professional industrial use. You&apos;re certain to ensure accuracy with this scale, no matter how fast-paced working conditions are. Its easy... More 

The PS-C30K06 is an excellent counting scale for professional industrial use. You&apos;re certain to ensure accuracy with this scale, no matter how fast-paced working conditions are. Its easy to use features include the following: Capacity: 13.2 lbs or 6 kgs Accuracy: 0.0005 lb or 0.2 gram Auto Zero Tracking Low Battery Indicator Large LCD with EL Back Light Three displays that virtually eliminate the margin of error - total weight, unit weight, and piece count. Large Heavy Gauge Stainless Steel Square Pan (12&quot; x 9&quot;) Stability Indication Auto Calibration Auto Back Light (Selectable) Unit Switching KG or LB with one button 1.3 Million Internal Resolution 30,000 Display Resolution 24 Bit AD Processor Highest Quality Sensor Die Cast Aluminum Sub-Support, Bottom Sensor Support&amp;Steel Thread Footing Built in, rechargeable battery - internal AC/DC adapter included. Memory function capable of 10 settings. A programmable alarm prevents errors, and can be preset to notify the operator when a certain weight or quantity is reached (check weighing). Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /prime-scales-132lbs/MroDzXVFu9KoVbUkp2qa8A==/info $120.00 +$11.99 shipping Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6d/33/4c/39764d4b4c51303368716f5a6c3765726d5367-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=26&amp;d;=457.1&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EC6-US Digital Counting Scale,Cap 15 Lb OHAUS EC6-US Digital Counting Scale,Cap 15 Lb 
 Free Ground Shipping on orders in July! ( In stock ) 
Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (Kg./Lb.) 6/15, Readability 0.2 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing... More 

Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (Kg./Lb.) 6/15, Readability 0.2 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 8 7/8 In, Max Tare 6000 Grams, Plastic Material, Battery, AC Power Unit, UL, CE, NSF Standards, Includes AC Power Pack, Rechargeable Battery Less 
 Zoro Tools Store not rated See Store Info /ohaus-ec6us-digital/m3L9vMKLQ03hqoZl7ermSg==/info Zoro Tools $457.10 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/48/4c/47554e695a6a7932434c7868356a567a396967-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=27&amp;d;=710.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pennsylvania Heavy Duty Counting Scale - 50lb Capacity Pennsylvania Heavy Duty Counting Scale - 50lb Capacity 
 New ( In stock ) 
Made in the U.S.A. Fast, accurate and dependable. Designed for speed and exceptional accuracy, this scale is the heart of any inventory control requirement. No other counting scale provides... More 

Made in the U.S.A. Fast, accurate and dependable. Designed for speed and exceptional accuracy, this scale is the heart of any inventory control requirement. No other counting scale provides more impressive performance and value with the same simplicity and rugged durability. Features include fast one button counting, Bright LED display, heavy duty cast construction, two different units of measure, 4 pre-set sample sizes, RS232 interface. 4 Year Limited Warranty. 50 lbs. / 22 kg. capacity. 14&quot;W x 15-1/2&quot;D x 5-1/4&quot;H overall. 22.00 L. 20.00 W. 6.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /pennsylvania-heavy-duty/PHLGUNiZjy2CLxh5jVz9ig==/info $710.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/2a/aa/28/92943691-100x100-0-0_Ohaus+Ohaus+VN31P5000X+Economical+Floor+Scale.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=28&amp;d;=1307.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus VN31P5000X Economical Floor Scale 
 Ohaus VN31P5000X Economical Floor Scale from $1,307.60 4 stores See Details http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/52/4e/7a/5869714c545366474b583770747a6e74735541-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=29&amp;d;=628.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EC3-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 6 Lb 1UXJ3 OHAUS EC3-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 6 Lb 1UXJ3 
 ( In stock ) 
Digital Counting Scale, Capacity 3000 Grams, Readability 0.1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing... More 

Digital Counting Scale, Capacity 3000 Grams, Readability 0.1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 8 7/8 In, Max Tare 3000 Grams, Plastic Material, Battery, Ac Power Unit, Ul, Ce, Nsf Standards, Includes Ac Power Pack, Rechargeable Battery Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-ec3us-digital/RNzXiqLTSfGKX7ptzntsUA==/info Grainger $628.00 +$11.81 shipping Visit Store -38% http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/86/bf/81/88396755-100x100-0-0_Zebra+Zebra+Direct+Receipt+2024+Thermal+Barcode+La.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=30&amp;d;=211.46&amp;rt;=mr 
 Zebra Direct Receipt 2024 Thermal Barcode Labels P N 800398 004 
 Zebra Direct Receipt 2024 Thermal Barcode Labels P N 800398 004 from $211.46 38% Off Free Shipping 8 stores See Details http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/68/67/5338394d716a776d696f724763676639707267-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=31&amp;d;=592.5&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EC30-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 60 Lb 1UXJ6 OHAUS EC30-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 60 Lb 1UXJ6 
 ( In stock ) 
Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (kg./lb.) 30/60, Readability 1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing... More 

Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (kg./lb.) 30/60, Readability 1 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 8 7/8 In, Max Tare 30,000 Grams, Plastic Material, Battery, Ac Power Unit, Ul, Ce, Nsf Standards, Includes Ac Power Pack, Rechargeable Battery Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-ec30us-digital/ghgS89MqjwmiorGcgf9prg==/info Grainger $592.50 +$11.81 shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/7a/68/6e/346f316c545a453679526449506f46434d4141-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=32&amp;d;=468.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 130lb Counting Scale 130lb Counting Scale 
 New ( In stock ) 
130lb Counting Scale Designed for versatility. Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the GBC unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic weighing, ... More 

130lb Counting Scale Designed for versatility. Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the GBC unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic weighing, Preset counting to a value, The easy-to-use GBC is the right choice for industry when flexibility matters. Repetitive weighing tasks are fast and simple with a large stainless steel platform, backlit display, The GBC includes features like RS232 interface, date&amp;time, a built in rechargeable battery pack and AC adapter, to make it ideal for production, warehousing. Features Large backlit LCD Full numeric keypadColor coded keysRechargeable batteryRS-232 interface with multi-language, date and time output Stainless steel panAdjustable feet and level bubble, Indicator support Pillar with full rotation and tilt. 2 weighing units ( Kg, lb,)Auto sleep, Memory accumulation. Rechargeable battery has up to 90 hours operation. 30.00 L. 15.00 W. 7.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /130lb-counting-scale/zhn4o1lTZE6yRdIPoFCMAA==/info $468.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6c/4d/45/71553536436c574f45457947563143766a6e51-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=33&amp;d;=649.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 30lb Capacity Counting Scale 30lb Capacity Counting Scale 
 Usually ships in 5-7 business days ( In stock ) 
Stop wasting time counting paper by hand, invest in a paper counting scale. Hand-counting paper is one of the most time consuming and least profitable tasks in a print shop. These counting... More 

Stop wasting time counting paper by hand, invest in a paper counting scale. Hand-counting paper is one of the most time consuming and least profitable tasks in a print shop. These counting scales can turn a time consuming job into a speedy one, and do it far more accurately. The Counting Scales have been designed for cost-conscious users and will count paper from business card size up to 11&quot; x 17&quot;. Questions? We are here for you. Call us at (866)537-2244. Specifications&amp;Features: ModelHC-15Ki Capacity30 lbs. (12kg) Resolution0.005 lb. (2g) Quantity/Box1 Weight / Shipping Weight10 lbs. / 12 lbs. Product Code00MISC List Price$681.45 You Save5% Our Price$649 Less 
 Binding101 Store not rated See Store Info /30lb-capacity-counting/lMEqU56ClWOEEyGV1CvjnQ==/info $649.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/79/55/42/52323235466c4d6b395a75464f666a58593677-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=34&amp;d;=507.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EB6-US Digital Pkg/portioning Scale,cap 13 Lb 2XKC2 OHAUS EB6-US Digital Pkg/portioning Scale,cap 13 Lb 2XKC2 
 ( In stock ) 
Digital Packaging/portion ing Scale, Compact, Capacity 6000 Grams, Capacity 6/13 Kg/lb, Readability 0.2 Gram, Readability 0.0002/0.0005 Kg/lb, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16... More 

Digital Packaging/portion ing Scale, Compact, Capacity 6000 Grams, Capacity 6/13 Kg/lb, Readability 0.2 Gram, Readability 0.0002/0.0005 Kg/lb, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 9 In, Max Tare 6/13 Kg/lb, Max Tare 6000 Grams, Weighing, Counting, Checkweighing, Percent Weighing, Steel/plastic Material, Ac/dc Power Unit, Includes Ac Adapter, In Use Coverul, Fcc, Ce, Emc Standards Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-eb6us-digital/yUBR225FlMk9ZuFOfjXY6w==/info Grainger $507.00 +$11.60 shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6e/6d/47/717031704131713565345938494e425f384b41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=35&amp;d;=691.94&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS TC3RS-2E0 Digital Counting Scale,Cap 6 Lb OHAUS TC3RS-2E0 Digital Counting Scale,Cap 6 Lb 
 Free Ground Shipping on orders in July! ( In stock ) Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (Kg./Lb.) 3/6, Readability 0.5 Gram, Repeatability 0.5 Gram, Linearity +/-0.5 Gram, Pan Size 13.5 x 9 In, Economy Zoro Tools Store not rated See Store Info /ohaus-tc3rs2e0-digital/nmGqp1pA1q5e4Y8INB_8KA==/info Zoro Tools $691.94 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/4e/6b/6e426e366b4e4d6349717a4e316d4345687567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=36&amp;d;=428.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 16lb Check Weighing Scale 16lb Check Weighing Scale 
 New ( In stock ) 
16lb Check Weighing Scale Designed for versatility. Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the GBC unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic... More 

16lb Check Weighing Scale Designed for versatility. Reliable performance, durable construction, and versatility make the GBC unmatched for value in industrial weighing. With basic weighing, Parts counting Check counting, Check weighing, Percentage weighing and Dynamic weighing. The easy-to-use GBK is the right choice for industry when flexibility matters. Repetitive weighing counting tasks are fast and simple with a large stainless steel platform, backlit display, The GBK includes features like RS232 interface, date&amp;time, a built in rechargeable battery pack and AC adapter, to make it ideal for production, warehousing. Features Large backlit LCD Full numeric keypadColor coded keysRechargeable batteryRS-232 interface with multi-language, date and time output. 1:400,000 Internal counting resolution. Stainless steel panAdjustable feet and level bubble, Indicator support Pillar with full rotation and tilt.5 weighing units ( kg, lb,g,oz, lb :oz). Auto sleep, Memory accumulation. Rechargeable battery has up to 90 hours operation. 30.00 L. 15.00 W. 7.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /16lb-check-weighing-scale/aNknBn6kNMcIqzN1mCEhug==/info $428.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4b/6d/78/62446b7a76496c6936503450776c6b39507567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=37&amp;d;=1108.8&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Ranger Count RC6RS/2 With Two RS232 Ports Ohaus Ranger Count RC6RS/2 With Two RS232 Ports 
 Shipped Next Bus. Day ( In stock ) 
The Ohaus Ranger Count Counting Scales - 6RS Series. 6 models to choose from each with 13lb x 0.0005lb capacity, stainless steel platform&amp;great features. Models: RC6RS, RC6RS/1, RC6RS/2,... More 

The Ohaus Ranger Count Counting Scales - 6RS Series. 6 models to choose from each with 13lb x 0.0005lb capacity, stainless steel platform&amp;great features. Models: RC6RS, RC6RS/1, RC6RS/2, RC6RS/3, RC6RS/4, RC6RS/5 Less 
 OldWillKnottSca les 574 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-ranger-count/KmxbDkzvIli6P4Pwlk9Pug==/info $1,108.80 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/d9/33/ac/127987723-100x100-0-0_ohaus+ohaus+ranger+counting+scales+rc6rs.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=38&amp;d;=1211.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus Ranger Counting Scales 
 Ohaus Ranger Counting Scales $1,211.00 1 store See Details http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4d/72/45/4f646534317670355470486c444c3554444267-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=39&amp;d;=628.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 OHAUS EC6-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 15 Lb 1UXJ4 OHAUS EC6-US Digital Counting Scale,cap 15 Lb 1UXJ4 
 ( In stock ) 
Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (kg./lb.) 6/15, Readability 0.2 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing... More 

Digital Counting Scale, Capacity (kg./lb.) 6/15, Readability 0.2 Gram, Overall Length 13 In, Overall Width 12 13/16 In, Overall Height 4 1/2 In, Weighing Surface Width 11 5/8 In, Weighing Surface Depth 8 7/8 In, Max Tare 6000 Grams, Plastic Material, Battery, Ac Power Unit, Ul, Ce, Nsf Standards, Includes Ac Power Pack, Rechargeable Battery Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /ohaus-ec6us-digital/MrEOde41vp5TpHlDL5TDBg==/info Grainger $628.00 +$11.81 shipping Visit Store http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/product/no_image_100x100.jpg?p=qf4kh4AxBj&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2005%3A46%3A21%20PM&amp;r;=40&amp;d;=829.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ohaus TC6RSP Trooper Count Scale 15 LB/6 KG Capacity 
 Ohaus TC6RSP Trooper Count Scale 15 LB/6 KG Capacity for Ohaus $829.60 Free Shipping 1 store See Details 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Counting Scale China 
 weighing scale,truck scale,crane scale Low price,High quality.Inquiry now! 
 www.nbeastbright.com/ 
 Medische weegschalen 
 Promotieprijzen: Seca, Tanita, Healthweigh, KOOP NU 
 www.farlamedical.com/ 
 Medical scale 
 Ready to Deliver to E.U. Countries Special Offers and Discount Inside 
 www.cfs-shop.com/Scales 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 Top 10 Luggage Scales 
 by Staff_Contributor Travelling can be a wonderful experience. Yet, an... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -30% Escali 13 lbs. C-Series $174.95 $249.95 Wayfair -20% Tor Rey QC-5/10 10 lb. Table $239.00 $299.00 The WEBstaurant Store -20% Tor Rey QC-10/20 20 lb. Table $239.00 $299.00 The WEBstaurant Store -38% Brecknell 60 lb. Capacity $211.46 $339.00 Discount Office Items 
Guides from our Merchants
 
 Cabling Solutions for Your Office or Building 
 The cable infrastructure in your office or building... 0 
 Current Sale items for AVthing in its place 
 AVthing in its place is currently running a 0 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068
	</body>
</document>
