<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006518" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20091227121512AAo1Du7" time="2012-07-12-23:27" support="1" score="0.0011880181555955706" bingtitle="How does Burger King put condiments on there burgers? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="How does Burger King put condiments on there burgers? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>I would like to know if Burger King, or any other fast food restaurant, uses a 3 in 1 condiment gun ... Is it proper to throw a full drink into the trash at Burger ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Nate Dawg Member since: October 28, 2009 Total points: 495 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How does Burger King put condiments on there burgers?
 I would like to know if Burger King, or any other fast food restaurant, uses a 3 in 1 condiment gun, like the ones on the Bud Light commercials to speed up the process of making the burger? 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by MmHmmYup Member since: November 02, 2009 Total points: 20,870 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 BK doesn&apos;t use a 3 in one. Mayo is spread with a spatula type knife and mustard and ketchup is in the red and yellow squeeze bottles. 
Source(s):
 Used to work at BK. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 4 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by ? Member since: December 27, 2009 Total points: 99 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 burger king is a fat place to go there the double double is the worst thing to eat in america try carls jr 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Rorydee Member since: September 07, 2009 Total points: 30,009 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I think they just use the red and yellow bottle you get at the dollar store. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Is it proper to throw a full drink into the trash at Burger King? How much does the Burger King in your area cost? Does anyone remember the Burger King dipping sause for their… How much money does Burger King make/save by not putting… Who is the girl at the beginning of the Burger King burger… 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
