<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006728" url="http://www.livingshanghai.com/shanghai-listings-directory/Restaurant-and-Dining-Listings-in-Shanghai/Fast-Food-Restaurant-in-Shanghai.html" time="2012-07-12-23:43" support="2" score="0.00956677773345341" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant in Shanghai - Expat Guide to Shanghai Life ..." webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant in Shanghai">
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant in Shanghai ... Healthy HelpingSpecifically tailored to the &quot;order ... Try porridge or noodle dishes as a quick pick me up ...</description>
	<body>
		LivingShanghai.Com 

Expats Best Guide in Shanghai
 
 

 
 
 Home City Guide 
 Shanghai Introduction Map&amp;Transportation City Service Useful Link&amp;Website 
 Listings Features News&amp;Opinions Photo&amp;Pictures 
 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - Before 1949 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1950-1978 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1979-1999 Shanghai Photo&amp;Pictures 2000-2010 
 Forum 
 
 Skip to content 
 
Fast Food
 

Fast Food Restaurant in Shanghai

 Listings Results 1 - 8 of 48 
 «   Start     Prev     1     2     3     4     5     6     Next     End   » 
 Add your listing here 
 Carl&apos;s Jr. 
 B1/F, Raffles City, 268 Xizang Zhonglu, near Fuzhou Lu, Huangpu District, Shanghai 
Sick of McDonalds and Burger King, but don&apos;t want to fork out 100 RMB on a gourmet burger? Then try Carl&apos;s Jr. Free salsa, tasty burgers with lots of choices for toppings, cheese fries&amp;hellip; A tad more expensive than McD&apos;s, but still cheap, and well worth it.
 Chinese Name 卡乐星 Chinese Address 黄浦区西藏中路268号来福士广场B1楼 近福州路 Telephone +86-21-6340 3663 Tags Fast Food 
 Café de Coral 
 Shanghai www.cafedecoralfastfood.com/eng/main/index.jsp 
This Chinese-style fast-food chain store is praised for its reasonably priced, delicious food. Baked pork chops with rice, washed down with milk tea, is a working-man&apos;s meal that will satisfy any discriminating palate.Shanghai Times Branch Add: B1, Shanghai Times Plaza, 99 Huaihai Zhonglu, Luwan District, Shanghai&amp;nbsp; Tel: 021-63918390Zhengda Branch Add: 4, Building 5, Zhengda Plaza, 168 Lujiazui Xilu, Pudong New District (Xinqu), ShanghaiTel: 021-50471070Tianshan BranchAdd: 541 Tianshan Xilu ... 
 Read More... 
 Chinese Name 大家乐 Chinese Address ,CCC
Wishding,90,Wishding Telephone +86-21-3378 1556 Tags Fast Food 
 Sarnies 
 123 Nanyang Lu, Shanghai 
An affordable sandwich place that offers filling portions and delivery--what more can couch slouches ask for? Sarnies offers a ranch of sandwiches, salads and fresh fruit smoothies, all for under RMB25. We recommend the Hilton Clash, a sandwich made with chicken breast, Canadian bacon, lettuce, tomato and a fried egg to top it all. . New Eats | A Healthy HelpingSpecifically tailored to the&quot;order in&quot;crowd, Sarnies offers a great range of healthy sandwiches, salads, freshly squeezed juices and ... 
 Read More... 
 Chinese Address 南阳路123号：近西康路 Telephone +86 21-62175223 Tags Sandwiches ,  Delis 
 Urban Soup Kitchen 
 No. 17 North Nanquan Rd., Shanghai www.urbansoupkitchen.com 
This casual eatery is an NYC-style soup, salad and sandwich place that features a menu of colorful international food. It&apos;s affordable and a quick option if you&apos;re looking to take your meal on the go.
 Chinese Address 南拳北麓17号：近浦东大道 Telephone +86 21-3331 1861 Tags Sandwiches ,  Delis 
 Zest Express 
 139 Wujiang Lu, Shanghai www.zestexpress.cn 
This organic eatery focuses on salad, and all their produce is brought in fresh from a nearby organic farm. They also offer a decent selection of soups and sandwiches to help you fill out your meal. Don&apos;t forget to pick up a frequent flyer card when you go; buy eight salads and get the ninth free. . Obsessed with ZestThis salad bar is a new offshoot of Guy Weiner’s Shanghai Organics’ farm, and offers made-to-order salads as well as soups, sandwiches, and other homemade baked goods. It’s also a ... 
 Read More... 
 Chinese Address 吴江路139号：近石门一路 Telephone +86 21-62183199 Tags Sandwiches ,  Delis 
 KFC 
 Shanghai www.kfc.com.cn 
Meilong Town Branch&amp;nbsp; Add: 1038 Nanjing Xilu, Jing&apos;an District, Shanghai Tel: 021-62181081Zhengda BranchAdd: 8F, Zhengda Plaza, 168 Lujiazui Xilu, ShanghaiTel: 021-50988126Airport BranchAdd: 2550 Hongqiao Lu, Shanghai Tel: 021-51153456Huaihai BranchAdd: 627-641 Huaihai Zhonglu, ShanghaiTel: 021-53510163Waitan Branch Add: 105 Zhongshan Dongerlu, ShanghaiTel: 021-63296506Hongkou BranchAdd: 2178 Sichuan Beilu, ShanghaiTel: 021-55600137Xuhui Branch Add: 52 Hongqiao Lu, Xuhui District, ShanghaiT ... 
 Read More... 
 Chinese Name 肯德基 Chinese Address ,CCC
Burger King,90,Burger King Telephone 1 800 544 5774 ext.8360 ext.326 Tags Fast Food 
 Xinya Dabao 
 Shanghai 
Xinya Dabao offers a variety of breakfasts, lunches and dinners. Try porridge or noodle dishes as a quick pick me up.Sichuan Branch Add: 2185 Sichuan Beilu, Hongkou District, Shanghai Tel: 021-56969428Opening hrs: 06:00-24:00Dafang BranchAdd: 33 Fujian Nanlu, Huangpu District, ShanghaiTel: 021-63266660Huaihai Branch Add: 282 Huaihai Zhonglu, Luwan Dsitrict, ShanghaiTel: 021-53510940Loushan Branch Add: 500 Loushanguan Lu, Changning District, Shanghai Tel: 021-62330550Changli Branch Add: 1096 Don ... 
 Read More... 
 Chinese Name 新亚大包 Chinese Address ,CCC
Da Niang Dumpling,90,Da Niang Dumpling Telephone +86-21-6524 1471 Tags Fast Food 
 Century Deli 
 Howard Johnson Plaza Hotel, 595 Jiujiang Lu, Shanghai 
Located in the ground floor of the Howard Johnson Plaza Hotel, this reliable deli offers a fresh batch of pastries, fresh coffee, superb sandwiches and sensuous desserts. Try the tuna with egg or pineapple with chicken sandwiches and top it off with a delightful almond, fruit, or lemon cream tart.
 Chinese Name 美食屋 Chinese Address 九江路595号：近湖北路 Telephone +86 21-33134888 ext. 6306 Tags Sandwiches ,  Delis Results 1 - 8 of 48 
 «   Start     Prev     1     2     3     4     5     6     Next     End   » 
 
 User Login 
 Login Close 
 Username 
 

 Password 
 

 Remember Me 

 
 
 Forgot your password? Forgot your username? Create an account 
 
 Main Menu 
 
 Home City Guide 
 Shanghai Introduction Map&amp;Transportation City Service Useful Link&amp;Website 
 Listings Features News&amp;Opinions Photo&amp;Pictures 
 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - Before 1949 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1950-1978 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1979-1999 Shanghai Photo&amp;Pictures 2000-2010 
 Forum 
 
 Listings Category 
 
 Search Listings 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
 Directory Menu 
 
 All Categories Add Listing Add Category Recently Added Recently Updated Most Favoured Featured Listings Most Popular Most Rated Top Rated Most Reviewed 
 
 Top Listings 
 
 Show more... 
 
Did you know that your Internet Explorer 6 (IE6) is out of date?

This template is compatible with IE6, however your experience will be enhanced with a newer browser.

To get the best possible experience using our website we recommend that you upgrade to a newer version or other web browser. A list of the most popular web browsers can be found below

           
   Do not show this message again     
 
City Guide
 Shanghai Introduction Map&amp;Transportation City Service Useful Link&amp;Website 
 
 


News&amp;Opinions
 Shanghai News&amp;Articles User Opinions or Blogs 
 
 
Features
 Dining, Gourmet&amp;Teahouses Nightlife, Bar&amp;Clubs Shopping Sightseeing Leisure, Culture&amp;Arts Education&amp;Training Body&amp;Soul Accommodation Business Others 
 
 
Listings Category
 Arts&amp;Culture&amp;Cinemas Bars&amp;Clubs Beauty, Spa&amp;Massage Education&amp;Training Restaurant&amp;Dining Shopping Health Sports&amp;Fitness Travel&amp;Sightseeing Business Services Other Services 
 
 
Photo&amp;Pictures of Shanghai
 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - Before 1949 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1950-1978 Shanghai Old Photo&amp;Pictures - 1979-1999 Shanghai Photo&amp;Pictures 2000-2010 
 
 
Forum
 Forum 
 Copyright 2010 Www.LivingShanghai.Com 
 
 Terms Of Use Contact Us Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
