<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006334" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2044016/Obama-Fried-Chicken-Is-President-giving-Colonel-Sanders-run-money.html" time="2012-07-12-23:02" support="4" score="0.004308532535167965" bingtitle="Obama Fried Chicken: Is the President giving Colonel Sanders a run ..." webtitle="Obama Fried Chicken: Is the President giving Colonel Sanders a run for his money?  | Mail Online">
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>When you order, everything is thrown into one bucket and ... model Alicia Douvall is first Cowell kiss and tell ... You won&apos;t fit a baby seat in that! Jack Osbourne buys a ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News U.S. Sport     TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 News Home Arts Headlines Pictures Most read News Board 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 9PM  13°C 12AM 14°C 5-Day Forecast 
It&apos;s Obama Fried Chicken! OFC pops up in China... but can the President also match the secret recipe of Colonel Sanders?

 
By Mike O&apos;brien 
Created 5:48 AM on 1st October 2011
 
 Comments ( 93 ) Share 
 
 
 

 Is Obama abandoning his bid for a 
second term in the White House and is giving Colonel Sanders a run for 
his money by opening a chain of fried chicken joints? 

 Now that&apos;s change you can&apos;t really believe in. 

 But in Beijing, China, a restaurant 
is actually calling itself OFC with a logo that looks alarmingly like 
the President dressed in the colonel&apos;s clothes. 

 Scroll down for video 
 
 
The presidential eatery: The Obama Fried Chicken restaurant in Beijing
 
Broad smiles: President Obama and the original master of Southern Fried Chicken Colonel Sanders

 
 The catchphrase underneath, apparently says &apos;We’re so cool, aren’t we?&apos; 

 The Obama Fried Chicken could be a response to the U.S. filing a complaint with the World Trade Organization about Chinese tariffs on American chicken exports.   
More...

 Cook up a storm with maillife.co.uk 
 

 According to the New York Times, the tariffs affect an industry that employs about 300,000 people and range from 50 to 100 per cent, which means some Chinese importers paid as much as twice the price for American chicken.
 
 
Obama obsession? A lookalike of the president was used in an actual for KFC in Hong Kong
 
 Maybe the Chinese have something of an Obama-chicken obsession. 

 Earlier this year in Hong Kong, an Obama lookalike was employed to advertize KFC. 

 The restaurant&apos;s sign was first spotted by TheShanghaiist.com and picked up by msnbc.com.  

 There are, of course, New York versions that caused quite a stir. 

 There is one in Harlem and one in Brooklyn. 

 Some people have complained the name plays into old racial stereotypes. 
 
Controversial: The Obama Fried Chicken joint in the Brownsville section of Brooklyn has been accused of racial stereotyping
 
Selling point: Obama&apos;s name also made it way on to the awning of this fast food joint in Harlem, New York
 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 Next 
 
 Police hunt dealer who sold Tetra Pak wife Eva Rausing the... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... Two hotel workers found NOT GUILTY of murdering a honeymoon... What a difference a trim makes! Neighbours breath a sigh of... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... The human right to claim benefits: Jobless could sue for... McDonald&apos;s force Olympics bosses to ban all other... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 93 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
I would rather eat my own warm, fresh vomit than touch anything with that guy&apos;s name on it.

- Robert Power, Las Vegas, Nevada, USA, 04/10/2011 02:21
 Click to rate     Rating   13 
 Report abuse 
 
At least he will have somewhere to go where he is welcome after the 2012 elections.

- Zapata, Canada, 03/10/2011 22:16
 Click to rate     Rating   16 
 Report abuse 
 
When you order, everything is thrown into one bucket and you must buy it before you know what&apos;s in it and it just too bad for you if you don&apos;t like all left wings!

- Dave , Hamilton OH, 03/10/2011 20:27
 Click to rate     Rating   54 
 Report abuse 
 
Do you suppose they have an ongoing special on&quot;Left Wings&quot;?

- Winston Smith, Blountsville, AL, 03/10/2011 19:58
 Click to rate     Rating   30 
 Report abuse 
 
I spoke with a friend of mine who is from China and the catchphrase apparently doesn&apos;t say:&apos;Were so cool, arent we?&apos;He said it says&quot;Go blow the cow pu*sy.&quot;Which is apparently a common phrase for someone who is talking about a bunch of B.S or is lying. He also thinks this is graffiti and not an actual sign.

- Chuck Sanchez, Baton Rouge, LA, 03/10/2011 18:45
 Click to rate     Rating   12 
 Report abuse 
 
And comes with a side of what Moochelle Obama calls&quot;How Do You Like Dem Apples?&quot;(Agree to higher taxes and you may elect to have either fried potatoes or 6 minutes without the Obama&apos;s all up in your face.)

- Peter, Raleigh, NC, 03/10/2011 17:37
 Click to rate     Rating   39 
 Report abuse 
 
Dark meat without a backbone. What a concept!

- Peter, Raleigh, NC, 03/10/2011 17:14
 Click to rate     Rating   75 
 Report abuse 
 
Obama is a pop star, not a political leader. Obama Fried Chicken explains his appeal. It&apos;s star-based, not reality-based. The guy never held a real job, spent 150 days in the Senate of the US, now thinks he can lead the world. What a joke!!

- Pouncekitty, New York, USA, 03/10/2011 17:10
 Click to rate     Rating   55 
 Report abuse 
 
The only problem with Obama Chicken is that there is no chicken, just battered hot air.

- GWIII, Western NY, 03/10/2011 16:24
 Click to rate     Rating   103 
 Report abuse 
 
You coulnd&apos;t get away with that here in the States, so funny! They already had some frozen Obama Fried Chicken in Germany a couple of years ago. Next: Obama Watermelons.

- Nico, Colorado Springs, 03/10/2011 15:34
 Click to rate     Rating   50 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using M&amp;S;virtual technology &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Playful by night: Kelly Brook nearly pops out of her dress as she dances at the dinner table Thom&apos;s eyes almost popped out too at restaurant in Italy Kim and Kanye as you&apos;ve never seen them before! Couple pile on the pounds in frumpy portrait... with the help of a little trickery Divorce leaves Tom feeling flushed: Cruise visits loos THREE times in 20 minutes on Oblivion set Filming in Iceland &apos;Still shocked and saddened&apos;: Tom Cruise plans to see Suri &apos;very soon&apos; as he struggles to get to grip with being dumped by Katie Holmes Former Scientology chief claims church &apos;brainwashed Tom Cruise&apos;s children and turned them against Nicole Kidman&apos; Marty Rathbun left in 2004 Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Doppelgangers! Joey Essex appears to be taking after Tom Cruise&apos;s style Uncannily similar jacket and shades to Top Gun star Lifting the summer spirit: Miranda Kerr sizzles as she debuts latest Victoria&apos;s Secret Cotton Lingerie range in sensual video No nudity, no sex, just cuddles: How one woman is making a living from snuggling - but for 38 an hour, would you pay to hug a stranger? Why This Morning&apos;s penis enlargement feature brought a tear to my eyes (for all the right reasons) PETER LLOYD found him brave Whittle-d down: Ricky becomes a one woman man again as he holds hands with new girlfriend while baring his chest (of course!) Year since Carley Stenson split That&apos;s no demure maxi! Miranda Kerr sexes up her floor-length dress with a plunging neckline and hip-high slit Two maxi dresses in a row The devil wears gym gear: Emily Blunt looks ready for the Olympics as she works up a sweat during gruelling work out session Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! Katy Perry in a spin as insurers try to ban her from wearing trademark rotating bra Experts are concerned about the resulting strain on her neck Paralympian rower bares all for ESPN&apos;s Body Issue and reveals &apos;for me, eating is one of the hardest things&apos; Inspiring Oksana Masters Mother in heart-breaking plea for return of son, three, &apos;missing&apos; in Corfu with Greek father amid tug-of-love custody battle Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Friends again: Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox enjoy reunite on night out after rift rumours They hadn&apos;t been seen together for months The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics It&apos;s Posh-er and hips! Made In Chelsea&apos;s Hugo Taylor and Natalie Joel sport matching outfits... but hers is cut a little lower Robert Blake launches into bizarre tirade at Piers Morgan in first interview since being sensationally acquitted of wife&apos;s murder Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; All by myself: Pregnant Camila Alves does some solo sightseeing in Berlin while her husband Matthew McConaughey promotes his new film She&apos;s learned her lesson! Lydia Bright teams up with Zoe Hardman to encourage the public to stay safe in the sun Been burnt before Getting down and dirty! British women&apos;s football team enjoy muddy bonding session as they prepare to open the Olympic Games Soldiering on: Bikini girl Rihanna lights up a suspicious roll-up cigarette as she unwinds in Barbados after family drama Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Curse of the Vera Wang wedding gown? How eight celebrities who married wearing her designs have ended up divorced After her own divorce Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Fleetwood Mac reuniting for tour next year, reveals Stevie Nicks Play their first shows since 2009, Stevie confirmed Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites What were you inking! The embarrassing matching tattoos that brand couples for life They take saying &apos;I love you&apos;, to a whole new level It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Raffaella Fico shows off her growing bump as she steps out after penning open letter to Mario Balotelli Maintains footballer IS the father Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? A forlorn looking Rihanna goes back to her plaited roots... after returning home for grandmother&apos;s funeral Grieving loss of beloved grandmother Dolly You&apos;re not fooling anyone! Tulisa spends five hours having her hair dyed blonde... then tries to hide it with a wig Next time put the wig on properly Tulisa! Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Caused quite a racket &apos;One doctor suggested I abort her&apos;: Against all odds one of the world&apos;s smallest surviving babies finally goes home Kenna Claire Moore is a little miracle That&apos;s one pricey push-up! The bra dripping in diamonds and gold selling for $1million Contains 750 grams of gold They&apos;re his mini mes! Liam Gallagher&apos;s sons Lennon and Gene are a chip off the old block Perfected that mean and moody scowl Fifty Shades of Grey author&apos;s saucy tale was inspired by her Latin roots, says her mother Alexandra Mitchell has praised her daughter&apos;s erotic trilogy Making the most of her bikini body: Actress Louisa Lytton shows off her slim frame on holiday Before rehearsing for latest theatre show Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it film with most complaints Some viewers described the scene as &apos;pornographic&apos; What would Marilyn say! Karolina Kurkova flashes a bit too much as she takes centre stage in a sexy photoshoot She took it a lot further! Angelina Jolie dresses her brood in angelic white... as Maleficent sticks to the dark side in head to toe black A woman of many talents &apos;Maybe it&apos;s time to go&apos;: Jennifer Lopez hints at American Idol departure as show seeks younger judges to rival Britney and Demi &apos;Duct tape over the camera and a $1,000 a night Presidential Suite&apos;: Inside Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s last weekend together Efforts to hide tension &apos;Look how broken up we look&apos;: Professor Green denies split from Millie Mackintosh Said he made up lesbian rumours 
 
CREDIT CARDS: OUR TOP PICKS

   Best balance transfer credit card rates   Best credit cards for cashback and rewards   Best credit cards for overseas use   Best credit cards for spending
	</body>
</document>
