<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006206" url="http://www.pos-warehouse.com/citizen3535.cfm" time="2012-07-12-22:53" support="2" score="0.0021815012099501126" bingtitle="Citizen iDP-3535 Receipt Printer - USA and Canada - POS Printer" webtitle="Citizen iDP-3535 Receipt Printer - USA and Canada - POS Printer">
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="41"/>
	<description>Our Canadian customers do not pay any expensive ... printer for point of sale applications, fast food, restaurant, and ... Click Checkout Counter to view Shopping Cart or to ...</description>
	<body>
		Canada Store 
 Expert Help 
 
 1-888-840-4945 
 Local calls dial: 905-812-2554 
 
 Home               Site Map                     Source it here and save ! Our Canadian customers do not pay any expensive brokerage fees or costly import duties.                     Request A Written Quote               Search 

 
 



 You may also 
 be
interested in: 

 Complete POS
 
SuperValue Package Deals

 

 Category links: 

 more receipt printers 

 more Citizen products 

 learn more about
interface cables
for this printer 


 

    Downloads: 

    Product Brochure w/ Specs 

 Citizen printer drivers 


 

 

 
 iDP-3535 
 

 Supplies for
this printer: 

 Multi-Ply Paper 
 

 Ribbons 
 

 
The Citizen IDP3535 is a high speed economy printer for point of sale applications, fast food, restaurant, and convenience store use.
 Fast Printing: 3 IPS Cash Drawer Kick-out&amp;Auto Winder (simultaneous) Two Color Printing (Black&amp;Red) User-Friendly Compact Design Great POS printer 
 

 
 Print Method Serial dot impact Printing Direction Bi-directional Font 7 x 7 dots (including half dots) Number of Columns/Dots 23 columns, 230 dots/line
28 columns, 280 dots/line
40 columns, 360 
dots/line Character Size 23 columns: 1.8 x 2.4 mm
28 columns: 1.5 x 2.4 mm
40 columns: 1.36 x 
2.4 mm Print Speed 23 columns: 4.0 lines/second
28 columns: 3.5 lines/second
40 columns: 
3.0 lines/second Line Pitch 4.23 mm (1/6 inch) Paper Width Friction: 3&quot; (76 mm)
Pin Feed: 3&quot; (76 mm) - 3.5&quot; (89 mm) Maximum Paper Diameter Friction: 80 mm Ink Ribbon Cassette Ribbon IR-61RB/B/P Interface RS-232C or Parallel Data Buffer 1 line Power Supply 100/120/230V AC Power Consumption Approx. 30 W Dimensions (W x D x H) 6.3&quot; x 7.2&quot; x 6.8&quot; Weight Approx. 6.2 lbs. Reliability Printer: MCBF 4.0 million lines
Head: 80 million characters Operating Temperature 32F to 104F Storage Temperature -4F to 140F 
 


 
 Buy It! 
 Canadian customers will be billed in Canadian funds. U.S. and 
 International customers will be billed in U.S. funds.
Shopping cart and on-site calculations shown in U.S. funds only.
Click Add to 
 add to Shopping Cart. Click Checkout Counter to view Shopping Cart or to complete your purchase. 
 
 Manufacturer

 Manufacturer Item No. Description

 List
Price
 Our Discount Price
 Our Price US Dollar
 Purchase

 Shopping Cart
 Accessories&amp;Related Items 
 Accessories, Options, Add-Ons and Additional Component Parts Related To The Primary Product On This Page.
Some Component Parts May Be Required For Operation Of The Primary Product. Manufacturer

 Manufacturer Item No. Description

 List
Price
 Our Discount Price
 Our Price US Dollar
 Purchase

 Shopping Cart
 CITIZEN SYSTEMS IR-61B IR-61B Ribbon (Black) for the 3530, 3535, 3540, 3541, 3550 and 3551, IR-61B $10.15 $7.05 $6.91 Checkout Counter CITIZEN SYSTEMS IR-61RB IR-61RB Ribbon (Red/Black) for the 3530, 3535, 3540, 3541, 3550 and 3551, IR-61RB $10.17 $7.06 $6.93 Checkout Counter CABLES TO GO CTG-02798 PARALLEL PRINTER CABLE (6&apos; Parallel PC to Printer, DB25 Male/Centronics 36 Male, 25 Cond.), CTG-02798 $24.40 $6.10 $5.98 Checkout Counter CABLES TO GO CTG-03019 SERIAL PRINTER CABLE, PCM-1970 Null Modem Cable (6FT, DB9F/25M), CTG-03019 $24.48 $6.12 $6.00 Checkout Counter 
 
 
 
 
 
Customer Service Guarantee
 
 By now you will have no doubt recognized that the prices at Point Of Sale Warehouse are the 
lowest prices that youll find anywhere for an extensive range of products including barcode scanners , barcode printers , receipt printers and cash drawers from the worlds 
finest barcode product manufacturers. You may also have taken note of our many compelling 
and exclusive value-adds - including extended manufacturers warranties and free web support 
for all products purchased here. Like thousands before you, you may already be a customer, 
or perhaps you are currently in the process of making your first purchase here. If so, on 
behalf of our entire team, let me say, &quot;Thank you for your business, and let me assure you 
that we will make every reasonable effort to secure and to maintain a long and mutually 
satisfactory relationship.&quot; 
If you have remaining questions, or for immediate assistance (between 9 A.M. and 5 P.M. EST) please call us toll free at 1-888-840-4945 . If you require a written quote , please click the button below. Yours truly,
 Point Of Sale Warehouse
 
 
 


 
 
 Now Accepting Payment By Interac e-Transfer
Simple, Convenient and Secure 

 Home | Terms&amp;Conditions | Customer 
Service | Industry Info | Search | About 
Us 

 The 
Monthly Point Of Sale Warehouse Mail - Product News&amp;Specials Delivered Every 
Month
To Your E-mail Address: 
 

 Copyright 2012

For more information about Point Of Sale Warehouse, contact pointofsale@live.ca 
Send any comments 
about the web site to pointofsale@live.ca 
Phone 905-812-2554  Toll Free 1-888-840-4945  Fax 905-919-1615
	</body>
</document>
