<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006168" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100508220305AAQR0z2" time="2012-07-12-22:51" support="1" score="0.006962609813551503" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Is it a good idea to open American fast food ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Is it a good idea to open American fast food restaurants in Disney parks overseas selling the same kind of foo?">
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; Transportation; Computers &amp; Internet; Consumer Electronics ... Is it a good idea to open American fast food restaurants in Disney parks overseas selling the ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Trisha T Member since: December 03, 2008 Total points: 135 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Is it a good idea to open American fast food restaurants in Disney parks overseas selling the same kind of foo?
 selling the same kind of food, sorry 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Nick Member since: September 02, 2008 Total points: 640 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 I had Applebees in the US, Germany, Kuwait, Qatar, and Ireland. I ordered the same thing and it tasted the same in all places. They all seemed to be fairly busy and made reasonable profits. 
Source(s):
 Life. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 86% 6 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Is it a good idea to… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by smenante... Member since: March 08, 2008 Total points: 1,049 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 As a rule, most of the biggest fast-food chains already have restaurant overseas, regardless of Disney.

The food does vary a bit, however, to account for the taste of the different cultures. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by JoeTheCh... Member since: March 06, 2010 Total points: 4,940 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 shup foo 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Patches the Dog 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
