<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006924" url="http://www.phentermine.com/forum/my-experience-phentermine/98729-initial-weight-gain-cutting-out-soda.html" time="2012-07-12-23:54" support="2" score="0.005366381761313188" bingtitle="Initial weight gain by cutting out soda? - Phentermine.com | the ..." webtitle="Initial weight gain by cutting out soda?">
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Occasionally I would order a diet coke at a fast food restaurant and they would ... you count your calories online they tell ... I don&apos;t actually eat a lot of condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Forum 
 Today&apos;s Posts FAQ Calendar Community 
 Groups 
 Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 View Forum Leaders 
 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? Chat Photos Buy Phentermine 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum Losing Weight with Phentermine My Experience with Phentermine Initial weight gain by cutting out soda? 
 Results 1 to 6 of 6 
Thread: Initial weight gain by cutting out soda? 
 
 
 LinkBack 

 LinkBack URL About LinkBacks   Bookmark&amp;Share Digg this Thread! Add Thread to del.icio.us Bookmark in Technorati Tweet this thread 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 May 15th, 2010,  07:08 PM #1 Ajay42 Gold Phenster 
 Join Date Feb 2009 Location Austin, Tx Posts 508 Lost Weight 25 lbs Current Weight 253 Goal Weight 175 Ajay42&apos;s Photos 
 
 Initial weight gain by cutting out soda?
 I quit drinking diet coke last Sunday. I pretty much gave up any non-diet soda&apos;s a long time ago because I&apos;m diabetic. Occasionally I would order a diet coke at a fast food restaurant and they would screw it up and I&apos;d have the&quot;full leaded&quot;but not very often.

Anyways (geez I just got started and already I&apos;m off on a tangent!)..

I generally don&apos;t ever have enough water, plus I figure the sodium content of a diet drink isn&apos;t really that good of a thing for me.... so I quit drinking even the diet soda. I&apos;ve replaced that with drinking water, and some tea, but mostly water.

I&apos;m probably still not getting the full ounce for every pound thing. I weigh 270 so that&apos;s a lot of water! But I&apos;m probably getting about 160-180 now between water and iced tea a day.

But I was kind of shocked to find myself gaining weight this week. I went from 268 last Saturday when I weighed at the gym, all the way up to 276 at one point this week. Now, I&apos;m back down to 270 as of today... but I worked out hard this week (even though it got a little hard because it was depressing to gain weight).

Has anyone else had an initial gain when adding more water and quitting soda? 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 
 
 

 My Weight Chart:
 
Yes, I could have reset my counter so that it didn&apos;t show last years loss and then gain... but I need to remind myself,every day, how easy it is to put it back on. Reply With Quote    
 Advertising 

 
Phentermine.com has no influence on adverts that are displayed on this Forum
   May 15th, 2010,  07:58 PM #2 Ally11 Gold Phenster 
 Join Date Mar 2010 Location Rhode Island Posts 619 Lost Weight -49 lbs Current Weight 224 Goal Weight 160 Ally11&apos;s Photos 
 
 
 Hi .. thats seems alot of weight gain for adding water it could of been maybe your sodium intake was high do you count your calories online they tell you how much sodium you should have a day or did you weight yourself after you worked out ? If you did i learned after you workout dont weight yourself and my trainer had told me that to it will add weight .. 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 Sw:273 3-4-10
Cw:224 11-26-10
Gw:160 to start ultimate goal 150



 
 

 

 


DETERMINATION = SUCCESS =) Reply With Quote May 16th, 2010,  11:28 AM #3 Ajay42 Gold Phenster 
 Join Date Feb 2009 Location Austin, Tx Posts 508 Lost Weight 25 lbs Current Weight 253 Goal Weight 175 Ajay42&apos;s Photos 
 
 
 I don&apos;t really have much added sodium in my diet. I have actually gotten rid of a lot of it with kicking the soda habit.

I do add some salt to the lean cuisine meal I have for lunch, because it&apos;s *really* bland otherwise. And if I have eggs, I usually add a little salt.

But compared to the endless amounts of french fries I used to eat, and chips... it&apos;s pretty insignificant.

I seem to have stabilized now. It ****s that I&apos;ve gone a week and am still slightly up.... but right now I&apos;m more focused on improving my running performance than I am on weight loss.

I figure if I continue to do the things that thin people do, the weight will take care of itself. 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 
 
 

 My Weight Chart:
 
Yes, I could have reset my counter so that it didn&apos;t show last years loss and then gain... but I need to remind myself,every day, how easy it is to put it back on. Reply With Quote May 16th, 2010,  03:55 PM #4 SchruteBeetFarms Silver Phenster 
 Join Date Apr 2010 Location Northeast Florida Posts 237 Lost Weight 72 lbs (45 by myself, 27 on Phen) Current Weight 148 Goal Weight Being fit and healthy(maintenance is a whole new animal!!) SchruteBeetFarms&apos;s Photos 
 
 
 Here&apos;s a few things to check:

Are you counting your calories religiously? Do you know EXACTLY how many you are consuming each day? You would be surprised in the calorie difference even if you just counted out 12 almonds vs. a handful...like 200!! Make sure you count every sauce, condiment, EVERYTHING that goes down the hatch.

Are you drinking straight iced tea with no sweetener? Is it a mix or is it fresh brewed with no sugar? There are hidden calories, even in some Crystal Light.

Are you weighing before you work out, after you work out, or after a meal? Best time to weigh is straight out of bed. Go potty and then weigh naked. Don&apos;t do anything before you do this. That is a true weight. If you are weighing yourself later in the day, with different clothes on each time, after eating, ESPECIALLY after exercise you could be getting a skewed number. The best way is to do it in the same clothes(or none), barefoot, at the same time of day.

My body does weird stuff. I will be at a standstill for days, then one morning I&apos;ve dropped 2 lbs! I think its so bizarre but as long as it is going down, I&apos;m not complaining. 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 Top row is me at 220 lbs in Summer 2009! Bottom row is me at 150 in May 2010! 9.5 months(only 2 of those on Phen) and 70 lbs GONE!!! From a size 18 to 8!! Reply With Quote May 16th, 2010,  08:49 PM #5 Ajay42 Gold Phenster 
 Join Date Feb 2009 Location Austin, Tx Posts 508 Lost Weight 25 lbs Current Weight 253 Goal Weight 175 Ajay42&apos;s Photos 
 
 
 Originally Posted by SchruteBeetFarms Here&apos;s a few things to check:

Are you counting your calories religiously? Do you know EXACTLY how many you are consuming each day? You would be surprised in the calorie difference even if you just counted out 12 almonds vs. a handful...like 200!! Make sure you count every sauce, condiment, EVERYTHING that goes down the hatch.

Are you drinking straight iced tea with no sweetener? Is it a mix or is it fresh brewed with no sugar? There are hidden calories, even in some Crystal Light.

Are you weighing before you work out, after you work out, or after a meal? Best time to weigh is straight out of bed. Go potty and then weigh naked. Don&apos;t do anything before you do this. That is a true weight. If you are weighing yourself later in the day, with different clothes on each time, after eating, ESPECIALLY after exercise you could be getting a skewed number. The best way is to do it in the same clothes(or none), barefoot, at the same time of day.

My body does weird stuff. I will be at a standstill for days, then one morning I&apos;ve dropped 2 lbs! I think its so bizarre but as long as it is going down, I&apos;m not complaining. I do weigh first thing out of bed in the morning.

I don&apos;t actually eat a lot of condiments normally. I have mostly had salads for lunch this week. I am on low carb and dressings are a little iffy there. Low-fat usually means spiked carbs, so I stay away from low fat dressings. I have regular ranch dressing. No croutons or anything like that on it.

When i drink tea, I use sweet n low in it. That&apos;s honestly not a diet thing really. It&apos;s the only sweetner I&apos;ve had that actually dissolves into iced tea. Sugar is even only good if it&apos;s brewed in. And it&apos;s off limits anyways.

It&apos;s mostly a moot point now anyways. I&apos;m back on track... just got derailed for a bit. 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 
 
 

 My Weight Chart:
 
Yes, I could have reset my counter so that it didn&apos;t show last years loss and then gain... but I need to remind myself,every day, how easy it is to put it back on. Reply With Quote May 16th, 2010,  10:31 PM #6 SchruteBeetFarms Silver Phenster 
 Join Date Apr 2010 Location Northeast Florida Posts 237 Lost Weight 72 lbs (45 by myself, 27 on Phen) Current Weight 148 Goal Weight Being fit and healthy(maintenance is a whole new animal!!) SchruteBeetFarms&apos;s Photos 
 
 
 There is a ranch dressing made with yogurt that is about half of the calories of normal ranch. I, too, hate low fat dressings. They look like snot and don&apos;t taste much better. We have a grocery store here in Florida called Publix that carries the yogurt dressing. They carry a lot of the healthier choices out there in their store. The dressing is in the refridgerated section in the produce, usually by the bags of lettuce. I think it is even better than the regular ranch dressing and my hubby, the all time picky taster, agrees. The brand I buy is made by Boathouse? I think. Marie&apos;s made one but I can&apos;t find it now. The Boathouse one says&quot;Yogurt&quot;on the front in big letters.

If you have a grocery store like this, or even a Whole Foods or Trader Joe&apos;s, I&apos;m sure you could find it there. It&apos;s about 70 calories for 2 tablespoons and its a lot less fat than the regular ranch too.

Glad to hear you&apos;re back to it. Bad weeks are out there. We just have to push through to the next week when all is good. My week this week wasn&apos;t great, but tomorrow is Monday and everything is fresh again 
 Share 
 Share this post on Digg Del.icio.us Technorati Twitter 
 
 Top row is me at 220 lbs in Summer 2009! Bottom row is me at 150 in May 2010! 9.5 months(only 2 of those on Phen) and 70 lbs GONE!!! From a size 18 to 8!! Reply With Quote 
 « Does Phentermine give you kidneystones? | Gained 5 lbs Grrrrrr!! » 
Similar Threads
 
 
 before TOM weight gain or is my weight gain due to first b12 shot 
 By akamal in forum My Experience with Phentermine Replies: 1 Last Post: May 6th, 2009, 10:34 AM 
 weight loss/ weight gain 
 By tjennys4 in forum New Members Replies: 2 Last Post: August 25th, 2008, 12:33 PM 
 How much weight do you gain with TOM? 
 By Sweet_Girl in forum My Experience with Phentermine Replies: 18 Last Post: May 22nd, 2008, 08:55 PM 
 Initial pounds lost -- water weight? 
 By PedalsFast in forum My Experience with Phentermine (Year 2002) Replies: 2 Last Post: April 1st, 2002, 04:07 PM 
 initial success 
 By kaykay in forum My Experience with Phentermine (Year 2002) Replies: 1 Last Post: January 5th, 2002, 12:00 PM 
 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Share on facebook tweet this! Digg it! del.icio.us StumbleUpon Bookmark on Google 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts   
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On [VIDEO] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On 
 
 Forum Rules 
 -- Classic -- Mobile 
 Contact Us Phentermine.com Archive Privacy Statement Top 
 All times are GMT -4. The time now is 05:54 PM . Phentermine.com - Copyright 1999-2010. All Rights Reserved. 
 Search Engine Friendly URLs by vBSEO 3.6.0 PL2
	</body>
</document>
