<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006620" url="http://eatingthruquakertown.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-23:34" support="23" score="0.030755149336669153" bingtitle="Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z" webtitle="Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z">
			<query id="000710" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001056" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000899" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001308" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000616" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000273" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000398" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001024" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000993" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001433" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001465" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001181" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>We had enough time to race cars and motorcycles and ... the cafe, we realized that you have to park on the ... This restaurant is not your typical fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z
 
 BROUGHT TO YOU DAILY BY RYAN LANDIS AND DEREK OVERBY! 
 
Our Rate and Price Scales!
 RATING 
 
 We rate based on a 1 to 5 scale. 1 being the WORST and 5 being the BEST. 
 
 PRICING 
 
 We price each restaurant using $ to $$$. 
 
$ (1-8 dollars spent, per person)
$$ (8-15 dollars spent, per person)
$$$ (15 + dollars spent, per person)
 
 Monday, August 8, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #18 - Dairy Queen (July 28, 2011) 
 &quot;Where It All Began&quot; 

Back in October of 2010, Ryan and I were dining on some fine ice cream and conversation in Dairy Queen with our significant others when we came upon the great idea of what it would be like to eat in every restaurant in Quakertown.  Fast forward to 9 months later, where we are starting to begin the &quot;D&quot; section of the restaurants in Quakertown. We do have several restaurants left that start with &quot;C&quot; but most of those are in Q Mart which are only open on weekends, or the others have really weird hours and close early. Therefore, Ryan and I will have to make extra time for those, so we began looking into restaurants that start with &quot;D&quot; and came upon Dairy Queen.

Dairy Queen is obviously known for their ice cream and blizzards, but does anyone really eat an actual dinner there? Well, we did, and we actually enjoyed it! Ryan and I both decided to order the 6 piece chicken tender basket which comes with your choice of sauce. We both chose the homestyle white chicken gravy, which was the cashier&apos;s recommendation. The basket came with fries and a drink, and at DQ, all the drinks come with free refills! (BONUS) As we got our food (which was cooked and put together at a high rate of speed), we noticed that every table in DQ was dirty, and some even had trash. It made for an unpleasant atmosphere when you are trying to eat a french fry but your hand is stuck to the table because of BBQ sauce left over from the previous customer.

The chicken tenders were nice and crispy and were fresh out of the oven. They had a tender taste and only one out of my six was a little bit too chewy for me. The gravy was an awesome addition and made for a delicious meal. If you don&apos;t like the gravy though, you can get BBQ sauce, honey mustard, ranch, etc. as a replacement. We topped off the meal with a free refill and we struggled not to buy ice cream to finish it off with dessert, as we are on a budget :) 

It was a good meal overall, but the cleanliness factor is important to us and that should be a top priority for any business.

FINAL RATING: 3/5
PRICE: $

206 South West End Blvd
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-536-7490

Until Next Time,
Derek&amp;Ryan Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 8:33 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Saturday, July 9, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #17 - China Wok (July 7, 2011) 
 &quot;Was Voted Top 100 Chinese Healthy Menus in the US in 2010&quot; 

And so it was, 17 restaurants later, Ryan and I were headed through the doors of China Wok. This chinese restaurant is different from most little &quot;hole-in-the-wall&quot; chinese restaurants. China Wok actually has plenty of booths so that you can sit in the restaurant and enjoy your meal as opposed to being limited to take out. We decided to do just that, and shortly after, the waiter/cook/cashier came out and gave us a menu and ordered our drinks. Ryan, as usual, ordered a water with a diet coke. I am cheap, so I just order a water every time. The waiter then brought out Ryans coke in a can, like one you would get in a vending machine. If anything, pour the can of soda in a glass to make it look more presentable! 

Once again, Ryan and I ordered our favorite Chinese dish, General Tso&apos;s Chicken, with a side of rice and an egg roll. Our egg rolls arrived almost immediately after and served as a nice appetizer. We weren&apos;t too impressed with the eggrolls, but that&apos;s okay because the main entree made up for it. We didn&apos;t have to wait to long to receive our food. The general Tso&apos;s chicken was cooked to perfection! Each piece was nice and crisp on the outside and a little chewy on the inside making a perfect texture. It is a little spicy which added a nice &quot;bite&quot; to it but if you don&apos;t like spicy foods, be sure to tell them that upon ordering. The rice was done very well and had pits of meat and peas mixed in as well. My two pieces of broccoli were not as warm as I would have liked but after all, I am not a huge fan of brocolli to begin with. The sauce on the general Tso&apos;s chicken was delicious as well! The menu had so many choices that you could come back again and again and order something new every time! 

The best part: I now have leftovers for another lunch! Hooray!

Now for some areas of improvement: Since our &quot;waiter&quot; was a cook, cashier and everything in between, I never got a refill on my water and was left to suck on ice cubes as my tongue was burning from all the spices. At the end of the meal, we sat there for a good 10 minutes until another lady that was working there came out and asked us if I wanted a box for my leftovers. Finally, our &quot;waiter&quot; came out later and we had to ask him for our check in which he replied that we need to come out in the lobby to pay. It was confusing and we wasted time just waiting. There should be a sign or something! 

I recommend the food at China Wok because the General Tso&apos;s chicken is some of the best General Tso&apos;s that I have ever had! However, the service and environment could use some work!

**China Wok is open 7 days a week and they do accept credit cards, but not checks!**

FINAL RATING: 3/5
PRICE: $

333 West Broad Street
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-538-8288

Until next time,
Derek&amp;Ryan Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 6:16 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Thursday, July 7, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #16 - Caitlyn&amp;Cody&apos;s Diner (June 23, 2011) 
 &quot;The Diner With An Identity Crisis&quot;  

        For this adventure of Eating Thru Quakertown, Derek and I headed out to a new dining joint located right off the Quakertown exit on 476 named Caitlyn&amp;Cody&apos;s Diner. Located conveniently off of the turnpike, C&amp;C&apos;s does not really have any serious competition to the weary traveler.  It is either stop at C&amp;C or wander into the heart of Quakertown a good 5 to 10 minutes away.
       We were extremely excited to try out a new restaurant, so upon entering the building, our morale was way up.
        That was up until it was time to be seated. The building is pretty big and it is made up of about 75% seating (including bar seating) and 25% of the space is an arcade. ( I know, I know, you&apos;re asking &quot;Why does the diner have an arcade?&quot;  We figured it out a little later and so will you). We were seated practically in the entrance of the restaurant, but we were still ready to chow down. Looking over the menu, we discovered that the menu really was limited in options. When our waitress came, we asked what she recommended. Her first response was &quot;anything but steak&quot; as she proceeded to inform us that the steaks were not done well and she would recommend that we not get them. She then finally recommended the Nachos and the French Dip. So that is exactly what we ordered.
       After having been in the restaurant for about 30 minutes, we figured out why the arcade was there. They put it there so that you would have something to do while waiting the overwhelming long time that it takes for your food to arrive. So make sure that you bring some extra cash for tokens. As far as arcades go, they had some pretty good options from racing to skee ball and the games were reasonably priced. We had enough time to race cars and motorcycles and when we came back our food had finally arrived.
       We had the Nachos for appetizers, but be ready though if you want more than just chips and cheese because you will need to shell out double the price. The nachos were good and they were loaded up pretty well, as you would expect for the price. While we were sitting there, we commented on how much seating there was available in the dining area, but to our surprise, 5 minutes later, they sat someone down at the table literally elbows length away. They had plenty of table choices but they decided to sit this man down so close he could have been sitting at our table. Things were not going so well up until this point.
       However, when our french dip came we were very optimistic. The sandwich and fries looked great. The looks were not deceiving. The sandwich was very full of flavor, even if it was a little soggy (they pour the au jus on the sandwich before bringing it out). The fries were crisped to perfection. Finally we were done eating and the bill was brought out to us. Start severing an arm or a leg because as far as diners go, this one will cost you. We waited in line, paid our bill and grabbed one more game of skee ball. Walking out the door, we had pretty much decided we would not be coming back unless the restaurant were to drastically improve.

FINAL RATING: 2.5/5
PRICE: $$

1907 John Fries Hwy
Route 663
Quakertown, PA 18322
215-536-8888

Until next time-
Ryan and Derek

Next Restaurant- China Wok Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 2:59 PM 4 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Friday, June 17, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #15 - Broadway Cafe (June 16, 2011) 
 &quot;Chicago, Rent, Stomp, Wicked, Phantom of the Opera, Broadway Cafe&quot; 

Broadway Cafe sits right in the heart of Quakertown, and right across the street from the train station. A rather small restaurant, this cafe seats maybe 20 people at the most. As Ryan and I approached the cafe, we realized that you have to park on the street and there are parking meters as well. It is 25 cents for 2 hours, so it&apos;s not very expensive, but certainly can be a nuisance if you don&apos;t have any loose change on your floormats. As Ryan and I opened the door to Broadway Cafe, we were hit with a smell that took us back to the days of our birthday parties held at Earl Bowl Lanes. Yes, the cafe had a very pungent smell: that of a bowling alley. It was not a pleasant smell needless to say. The front of the cafe has 2 large windows and it seemed kind of bland and empty. We would have liked to see some more decorations in the window fronts that made us feel like we were entering into a Broadway setting! We seated ourselves and looked over the menu before the waiter approached us. There was only one waiter working and 2 cooks in the back. 

I ordered the Broadway Burger because according to the menu, it was their &quot;House Specialty.&quot; I added lettuce, tomato and onion on the burger for no charge, and I also added american cheese as well for an extra 30 cents. I also ordered a small order of chili cheese fries, made with Mr. J&apos;s chili (Mr. J is the owner and cook). Ryan ordered a cheesesteak with sauce and onions, as well as a large order of cheese fries. We waited a good 10-15 minutes for our food, as there were about 10 other people there at the time. When we received our fries, the first thing that Ryan and I noticed was that the cheese on the fries consisted of 2 slices of American cheese melted onto the top. Once you at the 10 fries on the top, it was as if you ordered a regular side order of fries. I wasn&apos;t a big fan of the chili that was on my chili cheese fries, but the fries itself were excellent!

I also noticed that I never received cheese on my burger. When the waiter came over, I just informed him that there was no cheese on my burger and that I just wanted to make sure I wasn&apos;t charged the extra 30 cents. He apologized and informed me he would take it off my bill. A few minutes later, Mr. J himself came over and asked us how we were enjoying our meal and apologized again for not putting the cheese on my burger. I thanked him and said it wasn&apos;t a big deal, but in order to right a wrong, he offered Ryan and I free ice cream on them. We certainly took them up on the offer and the ice cream was delicious! We were very impressed that the owner personally apologized and did whatever he had to in order to please his customers. That was very professional and we respected that!

Overall, the gesture by the owner was very polite and we were very appreciative. We feel as though the front entrance should be worked on in order to look more appealing. The inside of Broadway Cafe has many different pictures and it has a Broadway theme, but the outside could use work. We also felt as though there should be music played softly in the background. It was quiet in the restaurant and you could hear your voice echo through the high ceilings. There was even a jukebox there, but it didn&apos;t appear to be running! The menu was very limited, but all the items on the menu were $6.25 or less! This could make for a nice, cheap date! 

**Broadway Cafe ONLY ACCEPTS CASH!**

FINAL RATING: 3/5
PRICE: $

241 West Broad Street
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-536-6442

Until next time,
Derek&amp;Ryan

NEXT RESTAURANT --&gt;Caitlyn and Cody&apos;s Diner Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 7:57 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Friday, May 27, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #14 - Chilkoots (May 26, 2011) 
 &quot;The Best Elk Burger in Quakertown&quot; 

Chilkoots: Home of Alaskan cuisine! Elk burgers, iditarod dogs. You can&apos;t beat the price and you can&apos;t beat the quality and experience! (Unless you hop on a plane, travel 4,500 miles and grab an elk burger). Chilkoots sits in a strip mall right next to Bon Ton on the 309. With it&apos;s bright colorful sign and lit up &quot;open&quot; signs, you can&apos;t miss it! The restaurant atmosphere was pretty relaxed and the inside had a &quot;fast food&quot; feel to it. You can either take out or dine in, and Ryan and I chose to dine in, obviously. (It is one of our rules, after all!) 

We were given a menu, which was just typed up on a paper and folded into a brochure. Chilkoots has a lot of food to offer! They have cheesesteaks, burgers, ribs (which I have heard to be delicious), soups, appetizers such as wings, fries, onion rings, etc.  Ryan and I wanted to try something that you don&apos;t find every day in Quakertown. Ryan ordered the Elk burger which comes with horseradish sauce. However, he substituted the horseradish sauce with BBQ sauce and cheese. The BBQ sauce is homemade! I ordered the Alaskan Iditarod hot dog with cheese. This was a larger verson of what I know of as a hot dog, but it did taste a bit different from your typical Hatfield Ballpark Franks. We also ordered cheese fries, as those are a fan favorite at Chilkoots, according to our waitress.

Our waitress was very polite and eager to serve us. She always had a smile on her face, and even though we arrived 50 minutes before closing time, both the cook (and owner), and waitress were very happy to chat and serve us to make sure that we had a great first experience. The cook served our county years ago and found himself living in Alaska for 9 years as a result. After that, he then found his way back to Bucks County after growing up in this area as a kid. However, he brought with him, the delicacies and culture of Alaska and decided to start Chilkoots. The owner, Stacy, said that he likes to hear feedback from his customers and in turn, it helps him to figure out what works and what doesn&apos;t. Stacy, the food was delicious and filling and Ryan and I are pretty sure that we won&apos;t need to eat for another week now! The flavors were amazing and Ryan could not stop talking about your homemade BBQ sauce. Thank you for a great experience and for being so welcoming and friendly! It certainly made for an enjoyable experience. We will certainly come back and visit again! To our waitress, thank you for your kind service! That really stood out and it&apos;s the customer service that brings back customers! (And the awesome cheese fries).

ROOM FOR IMPROVEMENT? Chilkoots is a great experience to try some Alaskan cuisine that you don&apos;t see everyday! They could certainly improve their menus. Make them colorful and stand out to the customer, and maybe laminate them, so they don&apos;t get dirty or damaged? The same goes for the posters hanging along the counter. Some of the posters were bent a little, so maybe laminate those, just to touch them up and keep them fresh. The food and services was great and we really appreciated it!

**Chilkoots accepts cash and credit cards (As long as the purchase is $10 or greater)

FINAL RATING: 4/5
PRICE: $

29 Quakers Way
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-536-3427

Until next time,
Derek &amp;Ryan Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 8:03 AM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, May 16, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #13 - Chick-fil-A (May 12, 2011) 
 &quot;Eat Mor Chikin&quot; 

Ah, the infamous Chick-fil-A. This restaurant is not your typical fast food restaurant. Chick-fil-A specializes in chicken sandwiches and I am sure you have all tried them at some point in your life. Now before we get started on this post, please remember that Ryan and I rate each restaurant with previous visits out of sight and out of mind. We rate each food junction as if it was our first time stepping foot in the building. 

As we pulled up to the Chick-fil-A nestled between a Wawa and Red Robin on 309, we noticed that the parking was already very limited. There happened to be a fundraiser night on this fine Thursday evening for Trumbauersville Elementary School. 10% of your food purchase went towards benefiting this elementary school. As a result, there were many families and children and seating was becoming hard to find. It was very busy as we arrived, so we had to stand in line for several minutes before we could order. I ordered a Chargrilled chicken sandwich deluxe meal (which comes with bacon and cheese) and a root beer and Ryan ordered a regular chicken sandwich meal (no pickles, of course) and an 8 piece chicken nugget along with a sweet tea. We were very excited about our waffle fries and the many sauces available to us. I chose the honey mustard sauce to accompany my fries and the buffalo sauce to add extra &quot;zing&quot; to my sandwich. Ryan chose the BBQ sauce for his sandwich and fries. We received our food and searched high and low for a seat. It was rather noisy and busy inside for us, so we took advantage of the pleasant weather and ate at the tables that they had located outside. 

We immediately noticed that the waffle fries were cooked nicely. They were a little crunchy (and not mushy like some other fast food joints) and they were actually hot! It was nice to know that our fries were actually cooked on the spot and not leftover from the previous day. Our sandwiches were hot as well and definitely did not disappoint. The sauces that were added to the sandwiches created an extra bite to it and made for a delicious meal. One of the best parts about Chick-fil-A is that we get free refills after the meal too! However, don&apos;t make the same mistake that I did and throw away your cup by accident. (oops.)

The service was pretty good considering how busy it was. Each cashier had a friendly smile on his or her face and they were genuinely pleasant with each customer that they came across. The only complaint that we have is that it was a little busy and overcrowded. However, Chick-fil-A was benefiting this elementary school and raising awareness in the community. They put on a lot of fundraisers at various Chick-fil-A&apos;s to help support their community. It is definitely for a great cause!

It is a relatively cheap night out and Chick-fil-A also accepts cash and cards!

Visit their website at   http://www.chick-fil-a.com/  for a menu, locations, and learn more about what &quot;First 100&quot; means to them!

FINAL RATING: 4/5
PRICE: $

602 N West End Blvd
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-538-8848

Signing Out,
Derek and Ryan Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 9:27 AM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Friday, April 22, 2011 
 
 Restaurant #12 - Bochi&apos;s Homemade Food (April 21, 2011) 
 &quot;Great Flavor From Argentina to the World&quot; 

Ryan and I took advantage of the beautiful weather last evening and ate at Bochi&apos;s Homemade Food. Bochi&apos;s is located in the heart of Quakertown and if you are familiar with Quakertown, (which you all should be by now) Bochi&apos;s is attached to the old Rita&apos;s Water Ice. Bochi&apos;s is a little shop with no seating indoors. The seating consists of two picnic tables located right outside in front of the shop. This allows you to enjoy the nice weather and take in the smells of home cooked empanadas. As we were deciding what to order, we noticed that all the signs (menus) that were posted on the front of the empanada stand could use some color to them as they were simply printed off of Microsoft Word 97. Unsure of what empanadas actually were, the lady at the stand showed us that they are about the size of pierogies. I ordered 3 empanadas and a small soda (which is actually just a normal size soda can), and Ryan ordered the special and bought 6 empanadas and got TWO free. He had to order his soda separate. There are about 12 different flavors to choose for your empanadas and the best part is that they let the customer choose flavors and mix them up. Naturally, we had to order every flavor available, with the exception of tuna and veggie. The flavors we ordered were:

-Beef
-Chicken
-Ham&amp;Cheese
-Spicy Chicken
-Spicy Beef
-Cheese&amp;Onions
-BBQ Pork (Our Favorite!) 
-Pepperoni and Cheese
-Sweet Corn  (Least Favorite) 

We were immediate lovers of Bochi&apos;s empanadas. The outside crust of the empanada reminds me of a chalupa that you would get at Taco Bell (For you Taco Bell lovers out there). We struck up conversation with the cashier (and owner) of Bochi&apos;s. Her and her husband (the cook) run Bochi&apos;s from 11 AM - 8 PM, Monday to Monday. They are originally from Buenos Aires, Argentina. They moved to the United States 6 months ago and opened Bochi&apos;s 3 months ago. It turns out that these empanadas are a specialty in Argentina! In fact, most of the food at Bochi&apos;s is a specialty in Argentina. It is not Mexican food! 

After our love for empanadas was discovered, we decided not to stop there. We ordered two flans (dessert), and one special Bochi&apos;s tarta. We received the flans first and they came right out of the fridge, very cold. I, personally, have never had a flan and didn&apos;t know what to expect. Ryan has had a few flans in his time and of all the ones he has tasted, they have been heated and warm. This one looked like it was baked at one point ( I sure hope so since a main ingredient is eggs), but the flan was cold and mushy and a little chunky. It reminded me of rice pudding, which I am not a fan of. 

At this point, we were waiting for our special Bochi&apos;s tarta to be heated up. The tarta was huge and looked like a small cake. We were excited and ready to dig in. The tarta consisted of: Cooked ham, cheese, bacon, tomato, sweet peas, and eggs. This sounded very delicious to us and finally the time was ready to experience what a tarta tasted like. As we bit into the tarta, unfortunately, we experienced what a luke warm, mostly cold tarta tasted like. I think it would have tasted a lot better if it were heated up 5 minutes longer!

Overall, the empanadas were excellent! However, the flans and tartas need a little bit of work. I expect all of you to visit Bochi&apos;s and order yourself some empanadas! The prices are very reasonable and the employees are very kind!

 **Bochi&apos;s only accepts cash, so make sure you have cash handy!** 

Also, Bochi&apos;s offers Takeout, Delivery, and Catering. Be sure to check out their website at http://www.bochisfood.com/ for a complete menu!

Our original rating was leaning towards a 4/5, but due to the disappointing flans and tartas, we dropped it to a 3/5.

FINAL RATING: 3/5
PRICE: $

500 West Broad Street
Quakertown, PA 18951
215-538-2075

Signing Out,
Derek&amp;Ryan Posted by Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z at 12:17 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2011 (19) 
 ►  February (8) 
 Who we are and What we do Restaurant #1 - Applebees (October 28, 2010) Restaurant #2 - Andrew&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Deli (Novemb... Restaurant #3 - Arby&apos;s (December 9, 2010) Restaurant #4 - Beckers (February 17, 2011) Restaurant #5 - Best Food In Town (December 23, 20... Restaurant #6 - Boston Market (January 6, 2011) Restaurant #7 - Burger King (February 3, 2011) 
 

 ►  March (3) 
 Restaurant # 8 - The Brick Tavern Inn (March 8, 20... Restaurant #9 - Big Richard&apos;s Steak Shop (March 20... Restaurant #10 - Captain Bob&apos;s Fresh Seafood (Marc... 
 

 ►  April (2) 
 Restaurant #11 - Bubbas Potbelly Stove (April 9, 2... Restaurant #12 - Bochi&apos;s Homemade Food (April 21, ... 
 

 ►  May (2) 
 Restaurant #13 - Chick-fil-A (May 12, 2011) Restaurant #14 - Chilkoots (May 26, 2011) 
 

 ►  June (1) 
 Restaurant #15 - Broadway Cafe (June 16, 2011) 
 

 ►  July (2) 
 Restaurant #16 - Caitlyn&amp;Cody&apos;s Diner (June 23, ... Restaurant #17 - China Wok (July 7, 2011) 
 

 ▼  August (1) 
 Restaurant #18 - Dairy Queen (July 28, 2011) 
 
 
 
Followers
 
About Me
 Eating Thru Quakertown -- A to Z View my complete profile 
 
 Awesome Inc. template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
