<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006876" url="http://www.roanoke.com/news/nrv/wb/247710" time="2012-07-12-23:51" support="4" score="0.004012481901274664" bingtitle="Change comes to Radford&apos;s east end - Roanoke.com" webtitle="Change comes to Radford&apos;s east end - Roanoke.com">
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>River City Grill server Audrey Lewis carries a tray ... Bells and Hunter also own West End Dawgs, a fast-food restaurant in ... &quot;We want to be the place where the locals eat.&quot; River ...</description>
	<body>
		.....Advertisement..... 
 www.roanoke.com 
 
Welcome: 
 Update Account 
(Not ? Click here )
 LOGIN TO YOUR ACCOUNT: 
 
 Forgot Password? | Not a User? Sign up 
 
CHECK THIS OUT!
 
BREAKING NEWS
 EVENTS CALENDAR 
Upcoming Events
 
 roanoke.com | New River Valley | News | Sports | Entertainment | Video | Business | Opinion | Blogs | Pets | Celebrations | Obituaries 
 Classified 

 

Saturday, May 22, 2010

 E-mail story RSS feeds 

Change comes to Radford&apos;s east end

Old buildings are becoming new again along Radford&apos;s East Main Street.


 
Matt Gentry | The Roanoke Times

River City Grill server Audrey Lewis carries a tray of food from the kitchen as co-owner Loren Hunter holds the door for her. Hunter, along with Chris and Heather Bell, opened River City Grill on April 22 in the former car dealership building at 103 Third Ave.
 


A pedestrian is reflected in the storefront glass of the former Radford Fitness Center on East Main Street. Renovations have started on the building, which has stood empty for nearly 10 years.
 


Yang Lin, owner of Nagoya Sushi, bought the Coffee Mill business in mid-April. Possibilities for the downstairs commercial space—the Coffee Mill from 2002 until February—could include moving Nagoya Sushi there, reopening the Coffee Mill or opening another restaurant, said Mimi Zheng, Lin&apos;s daughter.
 
 | Amy Matzke-Fawcett

 amy.matzke-fawcett@roanoke.com , 381-1674

RADFORD -- Things are happening in the city&apos;s downtown business district.

The building at 1144 E. Main St. that houses the Royal She-Sha Lounge and the former Coffee Mill space has been sold. Renovations have started on the former Radford Fitness Center, which has stood empty for nearly 10 years. A new restaurant has opened in a renovated building that once housed a car dealership.

Yang Lin, owner of Nagoya Sushi, bought the building and the Coffee Mill business in mid-April for $550,000, according to city property transfer records. The building also has three upstairs apartments.

Both the building and the business had been for sale since June.

&quot;We don&apos;t really have plans for the building yet,&quot; said Mimi Zheng, Lin&apos;s daughter. &quot;We&apos;re still working on the place.&quot;

Possibilities for the downstairs commercial space -- the Coffee Mill from 2002 until February -- could include moving Nagoya Sushi there, reopening the Coffee Mill or opening another restaurant, Zheng said.

That part of the city is going through a revitalization period, said Chris Bell, one of the owners of River City Grill on Third Avenue, because of the number of new businesses and building renovations. Bell, along with wife, Heather Bell, and business partner Loren Hunter, opened River City Grill on April 22 in the former car dealership building at 103 Third Ave.

When they heard a restaurant space would be available downtown, they knew it would be the perfect location for a restaurant, Bell said. The Bells and Hunter also own West End Dawgs, a fast-food restaurant in the city&apos;s west end, but wanted to open a full-service, sit-down restaurant.

River City Grill offers breakfast, lunch and dinner, along with a bar and catering services.

&quot;We wanted to bring something to downtown that it didn&apos;t have,&quot; Hunter said. &quot;We want to be the place where the locals eat.&quot;

River City Grill is a member of the &apos;Round the Mountain Artisan Trail, which promotes local art. The restaurant plans to hang local art on its walls to sell on consignment and hosts the Radford Fiddle and Banjo Jam each Monday night.

The building also has four office suites -- three of which are occupied by Main Street Radford, Enigma Photography and lawyer Adam DeVries -- and eight apartments, most of which are occupied.

Renovated buildings attract small-business owners to the city, said Becky Haupt, executive director of Main Street Radford, because it shows investors the community is interested in its downtown.

&quot;We want to be able to attract small, independent business owners,&quot; Haupt said. &quot;With these projects, we can show interested parties that we have a great community.&quot;

The former Radford Fitness Center at 1061 E. Main St. is another example of reinvestment.

Renovations there began earlier this year, including cleaning, structural reinforcement and roof and deck repair, said Joe Fortier, president of Taylor Hollow Construction. Fortier&apos;s company owns the building and is renovating it with a combination of federal Community Development Block Grants, private loans and donations, and other federal grants.

The 14,000-square-foot building has been empty for nearly 10 years.

&quot;It&apos;s a long, challenging process,&quot; Fortier said. &quot;We&apos;ve first got to strip it down to build it back up.&quot;

Tentative design plans for the building include eight upstairs apartments and one to three commercial spaces downstairs, he said.

Barring any unknown structural problems, he estimated the project will be finished in eight to 12 months.

&quot;It&apos;s going to be something for the citizens of Radford to be proud of,&quot; he said.

Other Taylor Hollow restorations in east Radford include the M. Jackson Hardware Building that now houses Sharkey&apos;s Rib&amp;Wing Joint; the building home to the Royal She-Sha Lounge and the former Coffee Mill; and the Hudson Building on Third Street.

Having most of the office suites and apartments rented shows there is community interest in the downtown and revitalized buildings.

&quot;I think that shows that if you invest in these old buildings, it shows what they can be and you can get them full,&quot; Fortier said.

The west end of Radford could also see a revitalization effort in the coming months.

Virginia Casting Industries announced plans last week to invest $9.1 million in the former Intermet foundry for a ductile iron components manufacturing operation and the city is spending $5.59 million to renovate the former Old Colony Box Factory on Robertson Street as a public safety building. When finished in the spring, the building will house the police department and city manager&apos;s office.
 
 jobs.roanoke.com | homes.roanoke.com | cars.roanoke.com .....Advertisements.....
 
 Local advertising by PaperG Keywords: City&amp;State and/or Zip: Category: Select Category: All Categories Agriculture Arts&amp;Entertainment Autos&amp;Vehicles Business Services Community Construction&amp;Materials Finance Food&amp;Dining Government Health&amp;Medical Industry&amp;Manufacturing Personal Services Real Estate Shopping Sports&amp;Recreation Travel&amp;Transportation Unknown Within: Distance: 5 miles 10 miles 15 miles 25 miles 50 miles findabiz.roanoke.com 
 The best of the New River Valley 
 
Site Index
 
News

 - Archives - Business - Columnists - Corrections - Virginia news - Local news - National news - New River Valley - Politics - Weather 
 
Sports

 - Auto racing - Baseball - College sports - Golf - High school sports - Outdoors - UVa basketball - UVa football - VT basketball - VT football 
 
Entertainment

 - Arts - Book reviews - Comics - Events calendar - Extra/InsideOut - Food - Lottery - Movie listings - Music - Puzzles - TV listings 
 
Local

 - Botetourt View - Celebrations - Laker Weekly - Newspaper in Education - Obituaries - Opinion/Editorials - smithmountainlake.com - SML visitor guide - So Salem - SWoCo - The Burgs - The Ticker - The Edge 
 
Online features

 - Blogs - Find a Biz - Datasphere - Movie listings - Multimedia - Photography - RSS feeds - RT the RT: Social media - Video 
 
Do business with us

 - Get the paper - Advertise with us - Awards and recognition - Buy a photo - Contact us - Intern at The Roanoke Times - Manage your paper - Manage your profile - Place a classified ad - Register online - Send a news tip - Tour The Roanoke Times - Work at The Roanoke Times - Become a Carrier 
 
Classified

 - Find a Biz - Celebrations - Coupons - Find an apartment - Find a car - Find a home - Find a job - Market Place - Notices - Pro talk: Ask an expert - Pets 
 
 Get the paper Create/manage your profile Professional standards Privacy policy, terms and conditions Contact us How this site works best Mobile site | Standard site
	</body>
</document>
