<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006777" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/y-j-carry-out-baltimore-316081" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="1" score="0.002235701803565634" bingtitle="Y &amp; J Carry Out - Reviews &amp; Menu - Cherry Hill - Baltimore 21225" webtitle="Y&amp;J Carry Out - Reviews&amp;Menu - Cherry Hill - Baltimore 21225">
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>Read reviews from Y &amp; J Carry Out in Cherry Hill Baltimore from trusted ... Make Online Reservations; Order Delivery &amp; Takeout; Popular Cities; Popular Chains</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions 
 Baltimore Restaurants » Cherry Hill » Y&amp;J Carry Out Share | 
Y&amp;J Carry Out
 
 0.0 star rating           
  
 (410) 355-1280 

 600 Cherry Hill Rd ( ) 

 Baltimore , MD 21225-1229 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 Read Reviews View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Tags: nothing yet. 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Y&amp;J Carry Out? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Y&amp;J Carry Out
 Write a review 
 0 reviews First reviewed by 
 You? Write a review! 
 
Best Dishes at Y&amp;J Carry Out
 
Thinking about visiting Y&amp;J Carry Out? Check out the full Y&amp;J Carry Out menu to decide if the menu items&amp;prices meet your expectations. When available, we&apos;ll provide pictures, dish ratings, and descriptions of each item. Y&amp;J Carry Out prices and menu items may fluctuate by location or over time, so use the following menu information as a reasonable guideline as to what is currently being served at the restaurant.
 
 Sort: Top Rated Most Popular 

No menu items or dish reviews have been added for this restaurant.
Be the first food lover to add a dish.
 
Menuism intends to provide as accurate information as possible. Y&amp;J Carry Out prices and menu items are known to fluctuate. The information above has been provided by Menuism users or 3rd party data sources. If you represent Y&amp;J Carry Out you are invited to feed us with more accurate information by contacting us.
 
 H&amp;E;Equipment Svc Inc Rent-A-Center FMB Laundry Allied Waste Services of Baltimore Positive Image Tattoos 
 18 reviews 5.0 stars Acme Ladder&amp;Equipment Co Downtown Dog Resort And Spa Overhead Door Co. of Baltimore 
 1 review 4.0 stars Walgreens Pete the Handyman, Inc. 
 Y&amp;J Carry Out is located near the cities of Fells Point, Canton, Morrell Park, Highlandtown, and Carroll. People found this by searching for: Y And J Cherryhill Carry Out, Y&amp;J;Carry Out, Y&amp;J Carryout, 600 Cherry Hill Road, Baltimore Mta, Y&amp;J Restaurant In Baltimore, Cherry Hill In Baltimore, and Y&amp;J;Carryout. 
Featured in Baltimore
 
 3.6 star rating           
 Tio Pepe Restaurant 
 5.0 star rating           
 Papa Leone&apos;s Spaghetti House 
 2.75 star rating           
 Ciao Bella 
 4.5 star rating           
 Houlihan&apos;s 
 4.0 star rating           
 Squire&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Catering 
 5.0 star rating           
 Red Lobster 
 5.0 star rating           
 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
 4.0 star rating           
 Sterling Seafood 
 4.5 star rating           
 Luna Del Sea 
 4.0 star rating           
 Chiu&apos;s Sushi 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 China Wok Chinese in Cherry Hill Mi&apos;s Chinese Food Cherryhill Carry Out 
Link to Y&amp;J Carry Out
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
