<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006485" url="http://www.sbsun.com/breakingnews/ci_19832437" time="2012-07-12-23:24" support="1" score="0.000500672631350938" bingtitle="Probe continues into fatal officer-involved shooting of Chino ..." webtitle="Probe continues into fatal officer-involved shooting of Chino Hills man in Monterey Park - San Bernardino County Sun">
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="41"/>
	<description>MONTEREY PARK - The investigation continues into ... an officer with a large pipe bender outside a fast-food restaurant ... Every patrol car is equipped with a video camera ...</description>
	<body>
		Live Traffic 10E 10W 15N 15S 215N 215S 210E 210W 

 
 
   This Site   Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 
 Subscriber Services Home Delivery e-Edition 
 Alerts RSS 
 Home News Colton Loma Linda Redlands San Bernardino Crime Elections Education Corrections Cold Cases S.B. County Watch Sex Offender Watch I.E.: Medicare Testing Ground Sports Buy Event Tickets Golf - Tee Times and Courses Preps Reign Hockey Inland Empire 66ers Local Colleges USC UCLA Lakers Clippers Dodgers Angels Kings Soccer Motorsports Horse Racing Live Odds Business MPG Go Green Real Estate News Technology Opinions Editorial Voice of the People Point of View Columnists Blogs LA.COM Film Music TV Buy Tickets Shopping and Beauty Recreation Neighborhood Arts Living Dining Find A Restaurant Lottery Horoscopes Health&amp;Fitness Travel Trevor&apos;s Travels Redlands Magazine Riverside Magazine Foothills Magazine Info Subscribe For Home Delivery Contact Us RSS Podcast Subscriber Services Place An Ad NIE Careers Classified Place an Ad Homes Jobs Shopping This Week&apos;s Ads Auto Search autos Buy/Sell a car Research/Finance a car Find a dealer Obits Directories Local Business 
 

 
 
 
 
CONTACT US


 CORRECTIONS: Did you find an error?
 LETTERS: Have an opinion? We want to hear it.
 TIPS: Is there a story we should be covering?
 
 
 Most Viewed Most E-Mailed 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 Area leaders share perspective on bankruptcy Robber breaks into officer&apos;s house in San Bernardino San Bernardino City Attorney: Evidence of budget falsification given... San Bernardino ponders impact of bankruptcy Colton police shoot and kill man trying to run them over, police said San Bernardino leaders couldn&apos;t see fiscal woes San Bernardino police chief: Current police staffing not at... San Bernardino authorizes bankruptcy filing Two shot, killed in San Bernardino in city&apos;s 22nd homicide Retreat trip turns deadly for Rancho Cucamonga man 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 San Bernardino City Attorney: Evidence of budget falsification given... City officials confident Ontario Convention Center firm can police... Robber breaks into officer&apos;s house in San Bernardino Ontario Convention Center finances under investigation Rancho Cucamonga proceeding with eminent domain for road 
 
 
More News
 
 Judge: Colonies lawyers to get limited Postmus evidence MediaNews Group pioneer Richard Scudder dead at 99   
 
 

 

 
 
 Tweet 
 
 Print    Email    Font Resize 
Probe continues into fatal officer-involved shooting of Chino Hills man in Monterey Park
 Brian Day, Staff Writer dailybulletin.com Posted: 01/26/2012 10:05:05 PM PST
	</body>
</document>
