<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006878" url="http://vanchen.hubpages.com/hub/The-Best-Single-Serve-Coffee-Makers" time="2012-07-12-23:51" support="2" score="0.0011769298638007713" bingtitle="The Best Single Serve Coffee Makers - vanchen on HubPages" webtitle="The Best Single Serve Coffee Makers">
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>... store, the local bakery, a fast food restaurant. It&apos;s cheap to buy but, over time, that bill adds ... All you do it put the capsule in ... Removable drip tray. Auto-off. Very ...</description>
	<body>
		HubPages 
 explore 
 topics hubs answers forums 
 sign in join now 
 flag 
 Explore  » Home (69,374) » Kitchen (3,989) » Kitchen Electronics (1,384) » Coffee Machines (421) 
 by vanchen 
243 Followers 
The Best Single Serve Coffee Makers
 
Coffee has become a part of our culture. The majority of us rely on it in the morning; we use to wake ourselves up, an aid in the beginning of what we hope will be a good day. You can get coffee anywhere - at the grocery store, the local bakery, a fast food restaurant. It&apos;s cheap to buy but, over time, that bill adds up; soon it becomes an unessary chore to scrounge money for your daily fix.

So what to do?

Make your own coffee with the help of a coffee maker. You&apos;ll save money, as well as time out your day. The qualtiy and taste might not be as &apos;unique&apos; as you&apos;re used to, but it will still get the job done.

________________________________________________________________
 See all 5 photos Single Serve Coffee Maker. 
What is Single Serve Coffee Maker?
 
It&apos;s just what it sounds like - a coffee machine which will brew your coffee and deliver you a single cup of it instantly. It takes what a super automatic espresso machine did and makes it better, delivering you a good cup of coffee with a single push of a button.

 The positives of a single serve coffee maker: 

 It does away with the grinding of coffee beans by having the coffee beans already in special pods. All you do it put the capsule in the coffee machine and you&apos;re good to go. Much smaller than big espresso machines; very portable. Much more efficient than other coffee makers. Capsules of coffee can stay fresh for up to 6 months. 




 The negatives of a single serve coffee maker: 

 Price is similar to other coffee machines that offer more features. Specific capsules only work for specific machines. You cannot mix and match. Some say the taste isn&apos;t as &apos;pure&apos;. 

________________________________________________________________

Here is a list of the best Single Serve Coffee Makers:

________________________________________________________________



 See all 5 photos Coffee makers have come a long way since. 
Keurig B60 Special Edition
 
 Price : $125

This one of the most popular single serve coffee makers and rightly so. Featuring a A chrome handle and LCD faceplate the Keurig B60 has an easy interface to use. Over thirty different coffee capsules are availible for this coffee maker, giving you a good variety to choose from.

 Features :

 Over 30 coffees to choose from. Cheap for a single serve coffee maker. LCD faceplate. Options for different sizes of mugs. 
________________________________________________________________


 See all 5 photos Why Starbucks when you can make your own? 
Senseo
 
 Price : $65

Similar to the Keurig as a single serve coffee maker, as well as about half the price. Isn&apos;t as flashy as other machines, but gets the job done just the same, using capsules instead of a grinder. Hot chocolate capsules also exist for the kids.

 Features :

 Cheaper. A variety of coffee capsules, including a hot chocolate one. Smaller and very portable 
________________________________________________________________ See all 5 photos A single serve coffee maker will make you a cup in an instant. 
Nespresso C110 CitiZ Single Serve Coffee Maker
 
 Price : $300

This single serve coffee maker is a bit more advanced than the other ones, and has a little more features. It&apos;s slimmer than most coffee makers allowing to fit almost anywhere; it has a style that fits almost anywhere, with chrome accents and powder coated levers. It&apos;s resoviour - where it holds the water - is large enough to hold 4 or 5 cups at once.

 Features :

 Automatic power-save mode. Easy capsule injection. Removable 34-ounce water container. Looks good anywhere. 
________________________________________________________________ See all 5 photos Coffee brewing made easy. 
Breville Single Serve Coffee Maker
 
 Price : $100

One of the easier and smaller single serve coffee makers on the market, the Breville is a compact coffee maker that works almost anywhere. It comes in three different colors, and allows you brew 6,8 or 10 ounces at a time. In 2 minutes you can get a full strength, full cup of coffee.

 Features :

 Comes in red, black, platinum. Brews in under two minutes. Removable drip tray. Auto-off. Very Cheap. 
________________________________________________________________ 
This Hub was last updated on June 30, 2011
 
You can help the HubPages community highlight top quality content by ranking this article up or down.
 Useful   • Funny   • Awesome   • Beautiful   • Interesting   Discover More Hubs Single Cup Coffee Maker: Brew Your Fresh Cup of Joe Each and Every Time Buy the Most Popular K-Cups for Your Keurig Coffee Machine Keurig Coffe Maker - The Keurig Coffee Maker Range You Can Choose Keurig coffee makers vs Bosch Tassimo, which is the better choice? Keurig Coffee Maker On Sale Buying Coffee K Cups for Keurig Coffee Makers 
 Loading... Comments 1 comment 
 Go to last comment 
 Coffee Lady 26  18 months ago
 
I see you do not list the Delonghi Coffee Maker range why not??
 

 
 Sign in or sign up and post using a HubPages account.
 8192 characters left. Post Comment 
No HTML is allowed in comments, but URLs will be hyperlinked. Comments are not for promoting your Hubs or other sites.
 working 

 
 
Hottest Hubs

 P90x X Stretch Routine 
I&apos;m sure by now you&apos;ve already heard of P90x. I mean if you&apos;ve found this article, then you must have already peformed some of the other works, like ab ripper x, or the rigourous yoga routine, and you&apos;re feeling a little sore. Am I right? Because... - 18 months ago 
 P90x Core Synergistics Workout Exercises 
Working out is an interesting thing because there are many different ways to do it. One can go to the gym, lift weights, do cardio, and then leave; this might cause certain muscles to become visibly stronger, or give him/her more endurance when... - 18 months ago 
 Working on a Cruise Ship - 3 Best Paying Jobs on Cruises 
Why work on a cruise ship? That&apos;s probably the first question the comes to mind when you hear about cruise ship jobs. Right? Well I think the most obvious answer to that question is also one of the best: you&apos;ll be working on a cruise ship.... - 17 months ago 
 
 Like This Hub? 
Over 50 Million people discover HubPages every month.
 HubPages 
 about us blog advertise faq link to this page copyright 

Copyright©2012 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. All rights reserved.

Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners.

HubPages ® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc.

 terms of use privacy policy (0.41 sec) HubPages Living 
 working
	</body>
</document>
