<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006429" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Hammond/El-Taco-Real" time="2012-07-12-23:21" support="1" score="0.0006202725091115998" bingtitle="El Taco Real - Fast Food Restaurant Hammond, IN" webtitle="El Taco Real - Fast Food Restaurant  Hammond, IN">
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>El Taco Real is a Fast Food restaurant located at 935 E Hoffman St in Hammond, IN . ... Love the smooth red salsa they bring out. Order a jalapeno with cheese to go ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
El Taco Real
 
Average User Rating
 
9
 
Amazing

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(219) 932-8333

 
 IN &gt; Hammond &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim El Taco Real listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by El Taco Real to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About El Taco Real
 El Taco Real is a Fast Food restaurant located at 935 E Hoffman St in Hammond, IN . El Taco Real has been described as an Amazing Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 9 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Mexican, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for El Taco Real
 
 
 
All Reviews for El Taco Real

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
9
 
Decor
 
9
 
Service
 
9
 
There are many imposters on both sides of the river. This is obviously one of them. I would suggest going to the originals like Camp Washington Chili, Blue Ash chili or Price Hill Chili. The food at these joints is still the original and the best around. Do your self a favor and skip the imposters. It&apos;s like saying, I will start a pizza joint just like LaRosa&apos;s. Good luck with that one. Trust me, stick with the originals. Go and see what I am talking about.
 
Overall Rating
 
9
 
&quot;Amazing&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about El Taco Real:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
El Taco Real Tips
 Everything is great. Love the smooth red salsa they bring out. Order a jalapeno with cheese to go with!
 
John W. Special fajitas are to die for!
 
Joshua K. Get the pork Nachitos... They are amazing
 
Ashley C. Queso fundito is to die foe!
 
Sherry V. 
El Taco Real News
 From Marrakech to Melbourne, the World&apos;s Best Cities for Street Food Dating back to the food hawkers of ancient Rome (with some centuries-old outdoor markets, like the Djemaa el Fna in Marrakech ... food trucks are begetting real restaurants. The Kogi Truck in Los Angeles, which spawned Chego, and New York&apos;s Mexicue ... Dine alfresco at restaurants with cozy fire pits, high-tech heated floors and — yes — blankets “Where else can you have a freaking fire pit in New York City without getting arrested ... and exchange it for a can of Budweiser. The real crowd-pleaser is out back, by the fire, where El Diablo Taco Truck conveniently sits, serving beef, chicken ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing El Real Tex-Mex Cafe El Real is located in the restored Tower Theater in the heart of Houston’s Montrose neighborhood. Address/Phone 1201 Westheimer (at Yoakum) 713.524-1201 El Camino Real - Kansas City, KS (913) 342-4333 · 903 N 7th St · &quot;Again, Tacos Al Pastor translates to &quot;Shepherd&apos;s Tacos.&quot; ... &quot;Probably the best corn tortillas in KC.&quot; El Rey Del Taco Truck - Astoria - Astoria, NY Categories: Restaurants Food Stands Restaurants Mexican Food Stands, Mexican. 3301 30th Ave Astoria, NY 11103 Neighborhood: Astoria (347) 754-2966 Long Island New York Classified Ads, Real Estate Rentals, Jobs ... Long Island Pennysaver and Town Crier Internet Advertising Source for Classified Ads, including Real Estate Rentals, Jobs, Garage Sales, Home Services and More! New York Restaurants and Recipes - NYC Dining and Chefs - New York ... A weekly guide to the New York restaurant scene -- from restaurant openings to reviews to recipes. Search more than 3500 restaurants by cuisine, price, neighborhood ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 88° 
Fri
 
 70° - 91° 
Sat
 
 73° - 93° 
Sun
 
 73° - 95° 
 
Address
 
El Taco Real

935 E Hoffman St

Hammond, IN 
 

 
Telephone
 (219) 932-8333 
El Taco Real
 
 Rating :  9 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
El Taco Real Photos
 
 Fast Food Mexican American 
 
 Local Places
 
 White Castle 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Tea Garden Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arby&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Em Incorporated 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Piccadilly Cafeteria 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Churchs Chicken 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hi Ho Barbecueno 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food El Taco Real 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pizza Inn 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hammond Regional Arts Center 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Courtyard by Marriott Hammond 
Cuisine: Airports Gallery 111 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Amsouth Bank ATM 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Hammond Art Museums Galleries 
See all Hammond Airports 
See all Hammond ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 El Taco Real Coupons 

 El Taco Real Hammond 

 El Taco Real Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Hammond Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
