<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006521" url="http://www.reporternews.com/news/2009/oct/31/battle-is-on-for-your-food-dollar/" time="2012-07-12-23:27" support="10" score="0.026312628963549294" bingtitle="Abilene restaurants are fighting for your business » Abilene ..." webtitle="Abilene restaurants are fighting for your businessAbilene Reporter-News">
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>... guess the cook took his break and then made my order. ... then you can pretty much call yourself a fast food restaurant. ... think in Abilene it&apos;s so common that people expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Login | Manage Account | Mobile | Contact | Archives | Subscribe | E-Edition | Reader Rewards 
 User Name: 
 Password: Forgotten your password?  | Create an account Register or log in using your account on these websites. site web 
Web Search powered by Yahoo! SEARCH
 Abilene Reporter-News 
 News 
 Today Local 
 Big Country 
 State Nation/World Weather Obituaries 
 Local/Area Funerals Today Death Notices Obit News 
 Politics 
 Elections 2012 
 Education Columnists 
 Doug Williamson Trish Choate Nellie Doneva Ronald Erdrich Thomas Metthe Brennan Peel Ethan Fowler 
 Publish Me 
 Opinion Life Photos Events 
 AP News GoFridayNight 
 Sports 
 Local High School High School Football 
 Abilene Christian High Abilene Cooper Abilene High Wylie High Six Man Big Country Beat Extra Points Lonestar Coverage Online Sideline 
 College College Football Professional 
 Abilene Ruff Riders Dallas Cowboys 
 Recreation Columnists 
 Marc David Harvey Johnston Rick Myers Bill Hart Greg Jaklewicz Evan Ren Joey Richards Sam Waller Daniel Youngblood 
 GoFridayNight.com --&gt;
 Business 
 Local AbileneBiz eMagazine Biz Notes Agriculture Markets&amp;Stocks National / International Real Estate Columnists Business Directory 
 Opinion 
 Blogs Editorials Letters to the Editor Editorial Cartoon Polls Columnists 
 Doug Williamson 
 
 Entertainment 
 Arts / Theater Books Dining 
 Bars&amp;Clubs Food&amp;Drink Specials Restaurants Open Now Submit Restaurant 
 Events 
 Event Calendar Submit Event Abilene Venues 
 Games Movies Music 
 Abilene Bands Abilene Venues mp3s Abilene Radio 
 Television 
 Lifestyles 
 Announcements 
 100th Birthday Anniversaries Announcements Engagements Quinceaneras Weddings 
 Family Fashion&amp;Style Faith&amp;Values Crave 
 Crave Recipes 
 Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden People Family Columnists 
 Jan Woodward Glenn Dromgoole Aaron Wilder Larry Zelisko Doug Mendenhall Kate Eason Laura Gutschke Trish Dressen Katrina Wright Sharon Randall Norbert Herzog and David Niesel 
 
 Media 
 Today&apos;s Photos Photo Archive Photo Galleries Photo Galleries by Topic Videos Audio/Podcasts YourSpace 
 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classified 
 
 
 

 Kingwood man, niece die in alleged drug overdoses     Texas police captain charged with indecency with girl 
 
 

 Shark steals woman&apos;s catch     Comic-Con stage preview     TV&apos;s memorable moments 
 
More Texas News:

 14-year-old gets 20-year term for killing teacher     Expert: Voter IDs in Texas won&apos;t affect turnout 
 
More Texas News:

 San Antonio drive-thru worker gets prison for porn     Highland Park police seek what prompted stabbings 
 
National News:

 Lawyer: W.Va. man denies enslaving, torturing wife     GOP House votes to kill health law ... again 
 
Sports News:

 Steve Nash surprised to find himself with Lakers     Saints, Brees apart on guaranteed money 
 
Entertainment News:

 Shaquille, funny videos to star in truTV series     And the Oscar goes to ... Batman? Could happen 
 
Science News:

 It&apos;s not lunacy: Not-a-planet Pluto boasts 5 moons     It&apos;s rats vs. penguins on contested Chilean island 
 
 
Abilene restaurants are fighting for your business

 By Jaime Adame Abilene Reporter-News Posted October 31, 2009 at 9:44 p.m. 

 Discuss Print A A A 
 

 
Photo by Thomas Metthe, Thomas Metthe/Reporter-News

Owner Brian Green boxes up a pizza for a to-go order Thursday at Cypress Street Station in downtown Abilene. Green says pizza has been on the menu for a while but recently gained popularity as one of the lower priced items on the menu.
 
Thomas Metthe/Reporter-News
Cypress Street Station patrons Jim Hofer (right) and William Jappe (left) sample the restaurant’s three new microbrews in the bar on Thursday. Cypress Street recently started brewing its own beer and has three types on the menu: a pilsner, wheat and bock.
 
Thomas Metthe/Reporter-News
Cypress Street Station bartender Kevin Pribble pours a glass of the restaurant’s new wheat beer microbrew Thursday.
 
Thomas Metthe/Reporter-News
Chef Greg Gee cooks vegetables in the kitchen Thursday at Cypress Street Station in downtown Abilene.
 
Small plates serve their purpose, according to Sharon Riley.

“It gets people in the doors. That’s the key,” said Riley, owner of two restaurants, Lytle Land and Cattle Co. and Sharon’s Bar-B-Que.

Overall, her restaurant revenues are down about 10 percent this year compared with 2008, she said.

“Last year was just a fantastic year,” Riley said. “This year has not been fantastic.”

At Lytle Land and Cattle Co., a steakhouse at 1150 E.S. 11th St. where the menu includes several $20-plus entrees, Riley has started offering small plate specials and other lower-priced fare.

“If you can keep people coming in and give them some options, less expensive things ... when things get better, they’ll order better,” Riley said.

For years, sales at full-service restaurants in Abilene have lagged behind limited-service restaurants like fast-food outlets. This gap has now narrowed, according to the latest sales data from the state comptroller’s office. Sales at limited-service restaurants totaled $22.4 million during the first quarter of 2009, only about $200,000 more than sales at full-service restaurants. In 2007 and 2008, that gap was an average of about $3.4 million.

“We compete with everybody,” Riley said.

“I mean, we compete with McDonald’s ... I’ve got a $5 sandwich at lunch” at Lytle Land and Cattle Co., Riley said.

Stalled sales

The latest sales data available is from the first three months of this year, before headlines blared about historically high unemployment rates in Abilene.

Gross sales increased by $2.8 million compared with the same three-month period last year, but there were also nine more full-service restaurants, raising the total to 88. The number of fast-food outlets has been stable for the past two years, with 114 quick-service restaurants during the first-quarter of 2009.

Rick Daffron, with his wife, Carolyn, are the owners of Rick&amp;Carolyn’s Burgers and Fries, which has three locations in Abilene, including one at 4458 Buffalo Gap Road.

Daffron said there is a reason why restaurant sales are strong in Abilene.

“You’ve got a low-income market around here, and that means you’ve got husbands and wives both working,” said Daffron. “They don’t feel like going home and cooking.”

So far, while restaurants may be seeing decreased sales — Daffron said his sales are down about 5 percent — few have actually closed. Grinders, a sandwich shop on South 1st Street, has been vacant for months after a reopening last year. Burgers by George, located at Sayles Boulevard and South First Street, has shut down, at least temporarily.

As restaurants leave, others arrive. Another chain restaurant, Pizza Inn, appears to be on the horizon, according to a city building permit issued this month for construction on North Judge Ely Boulevard.

Daffron said that prices in Abilene at many restaurants make eating out possible for many Abilene families.

“You can go to other restaurants that are reasonable. You can afford to eat out three, four, five times a week,” said Daffron, who bristles when his restaurants are described as fast food.

Perhaps blurring the line further between sit-down eatery and limited-service, his restaurants now offer pricier fare, like a rib-eye steak sandwich for $7.99.

“We haven’t had a price increase since September a year ago,” said Daffron. But he sees the new, more expensive menu items introduced this year as away to perhaps boost revenues during a time of slumping sales.

Menu changes

Several local sit-down restaurants are targeting consumers looking to spend less.

“We had to meet the need, and the need was less dining dollars out there,” said Brian Green, owner of Cypress Street Station. The downtown restaurant now offers more sandwiches for patrons at dinner, he said, as well as less expensive fare like fish and chips.

“In order to appeal to those folks, you have to appeal to a little tighter budget,” Green said.

The national chains seem to be following much the same strategy.

At Chili’s, the heavily promoted special is the “3 courses, 2 people, $20” deal.

Spano’s Italian Restaurant at 301 S. 11th St. has offered a similar four-course deal for two since August, said manager Denise Howe. Business began to dip at Spano’s in midsummer, she said.

“I just think people were afraid to spend money,” she said.

To boost customer traffic, Howe and others aren’t just turning to lower prices and value deals.

Howe said Spano’s last month began offering a 10 percent discount to college students and even has a “college night” every Tuesday.

At Joe Allen’s Pit Bar-B-Que, sales have been down about 6.5 percent so far this year, said manager Josh Allen. The restaurant recently decided to open for breakfast seven days a week.

“Thus far, it’s gone well. The business has picked up on a week-to-week basis,” he said.

Green’s Cypress Street Station just announced it will brew its own beer. While Green said he thinks beer sales will be a significant source of revenue, he also said he hopes that the new brews will boost food sales, as well.

“We had a decade or more of continued growth, and to see a dip in the economy is a natural thing obviously. And people have to adjust,” Green said.
 
 ©2009 Abilene Reporter-News. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
 Discuss Print 
 


 
 
 Also in Business 

 More 
 
 People all over Texas flock to Chick-fil-A opening in Abilene Want your MTV? Blame DirecTV, Viacom for losing it Water runs through this family 
 
Comments » 94 
 
 Comments 1 - 50 51 - 94 of 94 Newer Comments 
 
 October 31, 2009 10:35 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jojojo writes:
 
Lets all remember that the local restaurants need our help in any form we can give them, and their profits stay in Abilene. Lets all do our part to support them. HANG IN THERE GUYS.
 
 November 1, 2009 12:16 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Crash02 writes:
 
The last time I went to Rick&amp;Carolyn&apos;s on Pioneer I was the 2nd in line at the drive thru with no one inside or behind me. It took almost 25 minutes to get one burger and fries. I nicely asked why it took so long and the lady that brought me my food said&quot;the cook has 15 minutes from the time the order comes in to make the order.&quot;I guess the cook took his break and then made my order. It doesn&apos;t suprise me that Daffron&quot;bristles when his restaurants are described as fast food.&quot;It definitely wasn&apos;t fast and was not worth the wait. I haven&apos;t been back since.
 
 November 1, 2009 4:09 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 les47#311842 writes:
 
in response to Crash02 :

The last time I went to Rick&amp;Carolyn&apos;s on Pioneer I was the 2nd in line at the drive thru with no one inside or behind me. It took almost 25 minutes to get one burger and fries. I nicely asked why it took so long and the lady that brought me my food said&quot;the cook has 15 minutes from the time the order comes in to make the order.&quot;I guess the cook took his break and then made my order. It doesn&apos;t suprise me that Daffron&quot;bristles when his restaurants are described as fast food.&quot;It definitely wasn&apos;t fast and was not worth the wait. I haven&apos;t been back since.
 
Well Crash02 you probably experienced them actually cooking the burger rather than having one that was already cooked and just throwing it on the bun and then nuking it like some places do.
 
 November 1, 2009 6:32 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 cdsquaredz#207054 writes:
 
you know what....R&amp;C can take as long as they want to cook my grilled chicken on whole wheat...have you had one of those? They are the best!
 
 November 1, 2009 7:23 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 rnfhodges#303187 writes:
 
What a refresher to have a soda or tea with crushed ice for less than a buck anytime at Rick&amp;Carolyn&apos;s! You won&apos;t pay less than $1.50-$2.50 at most restaurants - what a profit they make on drinks, no wonder you see alot of patrons drinking water when they go to eat!
 
 November 1, 2009 7:31 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 ropers40 writes:
 
Daffron said it all when he said you have a low income market around here.
Abilene as it always has been and always will be.
I hated it when my girls gradurated from college and moved off but I also understand why they did.
I am with jojojo on this one lets help keep them open.
 
 November 1, 2009 8:37 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 RandyPool writes:
 
I think what is hilarious at first and sad upon deeper thought is that this thread will probably flame over who has the better $5.00 lunch. Names will be called, restaurants will be defamed as others are exalted as the best place to eat out 3 times a week is determined by the deep thinkers of this forum.

While those same thinkers, on another thread today, will SCREAM no more taxes for an absolutely needed advancement in education for children that has an annual cost of less than one night out for dinner.

I think Michael Ridgeway said it best in his letter from Iraq last week when he wrote.

“The real issue is the priority of what the prevailing culture is in the community in how individuals and businesses spend their monies/income. In the basis of a consumer economy and the “what’s in it for me” philosophy, people tend to be more concerned with themselves and their own immediate creature comforts and luxuries and will spend vast sums of money indiscriminately on themselves. Realistically, this is pure economic blindness and foolishness — little more than rearranging the chairs on the deck of the doomed Titanic”.
 
 November 1, 2009 9:20 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 saltydog writes:
 
in response to RandyPool :

I think what is hilarious at first and sad upon deeper thought is that this thread will probably flame over who has the better $5.00 lunch. Names will be called, restaurants will be defamed as others are exalted as the best place to eat out 3 times a week is determined by the deep thinkers of this forum.

While those same thinkers, on another thread today, will SCREAM no more taxes for an absolutely needed advancement in education for children that has an annual cost of less than one night out for dinner.

I think Michael Ridgeway said it best in his letter from Iraq last week when he wrote.

“The real issue is the priority of what the prevailing culture is in the community in how individuals and businesses spend their monies/income. In the basis of a consumer economy and the “what’s in it for me” philosophy, people tend to be more concerned with themselves and their own immediate creature comforts and luxuries and will spend vast sums of money indiscriminately on themselves. Realistically, this is pure economic blindness and foolishness — little more than rearranging the chairs on the deck of the doomed Titanic”.
 
Wrong Randy. I think it&apos;s more of a distrust of those in charge at AISD. Lots of wasted money in the past and not getting the whole story.
Nice try. Vote NO!!
 
 November 1, 2009 9:38 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 DB writes:
 
Abilene needs some everyday family resturants ie: diner type w/home cooking. IHOP&amp;Denny&apos;s isn&apos;t making it anymore. Same old crap.
 
 November 1, 2009 9:55 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 RandyPool writes:
 
Salty,

If we trust that the AISD is right and they are actually wrong, it cost us 8 bucks a year

If we trust the opponents are right, and they are actually wrong, it cost us 600 kids a year the chance at professional training.

I think that was the point Michael was making about voting our own self interest!
 
 November 1, 2009 10:02 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 BigBoots writes:
 
Looks like the so-called&quot;Movers and Shakers&quot;, Abilene&apos;s&quot;Civic Leaders&quot;,&quot;Business Leaders&quot;, etc, etc, etc, are starting to see the end of their arrogance and backscratching control.. This is obivious when one of them uses an article on Restaurants to tell us how sutpid we are not to support the Bond issue.. (I know, that&apos;s a long sentence)
 
 November 1, 2009 10:22 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 NDependentThinker writes:
 
I agree with Crash. It sure does take a long time at Rick&amp;Carolyns. I only stop by there if I&apos;m REALLY craving one of their burgers.
Well...since I&apos;m on here, may I suggest the Seafood Tavern&apos;s lunch menu? Very good stuff. I honestly think they have the best burgers in town.
 
 November 1, 2009 10:59 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 closingtime12 writes:
 
I&apos;m not even sure what to post except to continue to support local restaurants ! Do a little research on some of the places you might think are expensive. Many of them have specials, happy hours, huge appetizers you could split, and unlimited soup and salad specials.
 
 November 1, 2009 12:51 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 bigmoe writes:
 
I no longer live in Abilene. But when I do visit I call my daughter on the cell phone and tell her to go to Catfish Corner. I want my fish when I get to Abilene. I just love thier fish. I tell everyone I know to go there if their passing through. That&apos;s what I call good eats, and affordable.
 
 November 1, 2009 2:05 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Mellonello writes:
 
I agree with Sharon Allen, Restuarants would do much better if they offered smaller plates of food.
1. We have an obesity problem in Abilene and everywhere else in the U.S.
2. Smaller portions of well cooked food is better for you.
3. Serving veggies with entree is better for your than French fries and Fried foods.
4. Restaurants had this idea till recently, Pile on the food, and charge much more.
5. I honestly believe businesses would see more money, if they would cater to smaller portions, and smaller prices.
6. At 20.00 a person, and you take your wife and children, your going to walk out with over a 100.00 for that meal.
 
 November 1, 2009 3:13 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 rwnjc writes:
 
in response to RandyPool :

I think what is hilarious at first and sad upon deeper thought is that this thread will probably flame over who has the better $5.00 lunch. Names will be called, restaurants will be defamed as others are exalted as the best place to eat out 3 times a week is determined by the deep thinkers of this forum.

While those same thinkers, on another thread today, will SCREAM no more taxes for an absolutely needed advancement in education for children that has an annual cost of less than one night out for dinner.

I think Michael Ridgeway said it best in his letter from Iraq last week when he wrote.

“The real issue is the priority of what the prevailing culture is in the community in how individuals and businesses spend their monies/income. In the basis of a consumer economy and the “what’s in it for me” philosophy, people tend to be more concerned with themselves and their own immediate creature comforts and luxuries and will spend vast sums of money indiscriminately on themselves. Realistically, this is pure economic blindness and foolishness — little more than rearranging the chairs on the deck of the doomed Titanic”.
 
I am so sorry, Randy Pool, that you can&apos;t stand that others want to exercise their choice as to what to do with their hard earned money rather than you and others trying to pass this ridiculous bond package and make the decision for us. Your post is typical of the liberal mindset which suggests that reaching into everyone&apos;s pockets for your pet project of the week is the way to go. If I or anyone else want to spend their legally earned money any way they see fit it is NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.

Perhaps when this ridiculous career tech idea is voted down for the second year in a row, you and the&quot;300&quot;will finally get that NO MEANS NO.
 
 November 1, 2009 4:51 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jljs2#299237 writes:
 
I stopped eating at IHOP&apos;s when they stopped taking checks. I visit and always eat at IHOP in the morning, but not any more. So think about if you dont&apos; take checks you will not get my bussiness.
 
 November 1, 2009 5:09 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 1stplace writes:
 
jljs2#299237 writes:
I stopped eating at IHOP&apos;s when they stopped taking checks. I visit and always eat at IHOP in the morning, but not any more. So think about if you dont&apos; take checks you will not get my bussiness.
...
I hope that wasn&apos;t the only reason. I like to smell the food while sitting in a restaurant, not the restroom.
 
 November 1, 2009 7:09 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Mellonello writes:
 
Ever eat at the Dixie Pig for breakfast or lunch?? they have great breakfast and lunch for 6.oo with desert.
I do buy cornbread at Harold&apos;s, its the best cornbread in town, either plain or jalenpeno, but Im not fond of the meat to much chili poweder in the sauce.
 
 November 1, 2009 7:18 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Mellonello writes:
 
in response to RandyPool :

I think what is hilarious at first and sad upon deeper thought is that this thread will probably flame over who has the better $5.00 lunch. Names will be called, restaurants will be defamed as others are exalted as the best place to eat out 3 times a week is determined by the deep thinkers of this forum.

While those same thinkers, on another thread today, will SCREAM no more taxes for an absolutely needed advancement in education for children that has an annual cost of less than one night out for dinner.

I think Michael Ridgeway said it best in his letter from Iraq last week when he wrote.

“The real issue is the priority of what the prevailing culture is in the community in how individuals and businesses spend their monies/income. In the basis of a consumer economy and the “what’s in it for me” philosophy, people tend to be more concerned with themselves and their own immediate creature comforts and luxuries and will spend vast sums of money indiscriminately on themselves. Realistically, this is pure economic blindness and foolishness — little more than rearranging the chairs on the deck of the doomed Titanic”.
 
Mr Pool,
I don&apos;t think you get it!!! Resturants aren&apos;t losing business because of bad food or portion size, they are losing business because they all raised their prices where people in Abilene, at least most working blue collar people can&apos;t afford to go out and eat any longer.
Maybe you can afford it, maybe the mayor, and city council and most certainly the school administrators can, let&apos;s see,, Mr Polnick makes umm $200,000 a year. YUP I could afford to go out and eat and not worry about the cost If I made that kind of money to.
But most people in Abilene DON&apos;T!! Nor can most people other than yourself afford extra taxes.
People are still losing their jobs in Abilene and the ones who have lost jobs, are still looking. So I kinda feel your remarks are arrogant and self serving.
Trust me, most people aren&apos;t worried about themselves being comfortable, they are just worried about how to put FOOD on their table.
 
 November 1, 2009 7:50 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Bosenbach writes:
 
The locally famous steakhouse in this article needs to concentrate on pest control, not smaller plates. Our family quit eating there not because of price or taste, but for dead bugs on the window sills and mouse droppings in the tea glass. The server argued that the tea was fine.
 
 November 1, 2009 8:35 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 wild_bill#233490 writes:
 
Trust Randy to take a thread about &apos;food&apos; and turn it into the Career School Bond issue. If I could have voted (I don&apos;t live in Abilene), I would have voted AGAINST IT. AISD needs to learn that&quot;no&quot;means&quot;NO&quot;.

I love Sharon&apos;s, Harold&apos;s and Town Crier. I also love Rick and Carolyns for burgers and chicken-fried steak. Don&apos;t mind waiting for good food either. Also Joe&apos;s Pizza and Little Italy are WAY better than Spanos or Olive Garden for either sit-down or take out Italian. Gotta love Red Lobster as well. Tried Seafood Tavern after it first changed and was NOT impressed with either food or service. Haven&apos;t been back.

Everything in Abilene is &apos;higher&apos; except the job rate and pay scales for folks that actually work for a living. Speaking of...Randy what&apos;s the payscale for your workers? Care to comment?
 
 November 1, 2009 9:20 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 HORSER writes:
 
in response to Crash02 :

The last time I went to Rick&amp;Carolyn&apos;s on Pioneer I was the 2nd in line at the drive thru with no one inside or behind me. It took almost 25 minutes to get one burger and fries. I nicely asked why it took so long and the lady that brought me my food said&quot;the cook has 15 minutes from the time the order comes in to make the order.&quot;I guess the cook took his break and then made my order. It doesn&apos;t suprise me that Daffron&quot;bristles when his restaurants are described as fast food.&quot;It definitely wasn&apos;t fast and was not worth the wait. I haven&apos;t been back since.
 
25 MINUTE&quot;DRIVE THRU&quot;WAIT AT AMBLER LOCATION, FOR ME AS WELL !
 
 November 1, 2009 9:28 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Yahsone writes:
 
The problem for my wife and I is not the price of the food at local restaurants. Most are competitive in their fields. It is finding one that meets our kosher dietary needs. I know of just a few in town that don&apos;t cook their pork, shellfish, catfish, etc. on the same stove/grill and/or in the same pans as the foods that we could eat otherwise. We had found three that we feel we could eat at until recently.

Some restaurants in town have looked at us like we are idiots when we ask them if their foods contain any of the products we can&apos;t eat. I can tell them I eat vegetarian and they are fine. But tell them we eat kosher and some look at us like we have the cooties.

Now we have to check what type of cheese restaurants use. We just found out that some cheese manufacturers use lard as a releasse agent for their cheese molds. And trying to find out which ones do is like pulling eye teeth. And going to the grocery stores is a real challenge as manufacturers hide unclean products in everything.

We make our own breads because most bread makers use enzymes and additives that come from such sources as horse hair, horse urine, and human hair. And now we have to look at the source of gelatin in some foods like yogurt. Even with the kosher symbol on them, they are unclean because the gelatin sometimes can come from pork. As long as it is changed and out of the pig&apos;s body for a certain amount of time, some kosher organizations consider it kosher. OY VEY!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
 
 November 1, 2009 9:39 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Yahsone writes:
 
Mellonello, the reason restaurants have raised the price of their meals is becasue it cossts more to prepare that food now. I am sure you noticed that groceries cost more nowdays. The same is true for restaurants.

The costs for local business permits has gone up, electricity has gone up, gas for the stoves has gone up, and a whole host of other things involved in producing that meal you buy at a local restaurant has gone up.

For example, it used to cost the bakery I worked at about $14 for flour. That same bag now costs me about $20. It got as high as $40 for a while.

So next time you complain about the cost of a nice meal at a local restaurant, think about how much the owner is having to pay for the ingredients, etc. to produce that meal for you.
 
 November 2, 2009 6:24 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 What_it_is writes:
 
I don&apos;t know about Land and Cattle Co., I haven&apos;t been there, but the only places I will go out to eat now, are at the Asian food restaurants and Golden Corral buffet, or a fast food restaurant, only places I know where the service is good. I have received such offensive service at other places it is disgusting, and waitstaff and owners at the other places I have been to and am not going back to need to keep their hands to themselves and keep the conversation at a minimum and learn not to serve hot plates to children. I have never in my life been harassed like I have been in Abilene, by overly nosy and touch feely waitstaff and an owner, who actually had the audacity to come out and put her hands on me, to introduce herself, disgusted me, ruined my appetite and I find those actions to actually be assault. I got over charged and of course there is nothing I could do about it.There ought to rules against such horrible service and ill mannered actions.
 
 November 2, 2009 7:02 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jersey (Inactive) writes:
 
I&apos;m sorry but if you have a drive-thru, then you can pretty much call yourself a fast food restaurant. The few times I have eat at R&amp;C, the food was horrible. I have yet to figure out the fascination with Lytle Land and Cattle. Been there twice, worst food I have ever eaten in my life.
 
 November 2, 2009 7:08 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 ru4reall writes:
 
In this economy I spend my hard earned dollar with the restaurants that appreciate me, have great service, and try to give back to the community. Sharon&apos;s,Spano&apos;s,and Famous Daves all awesome.... The great thing is we have so many choices!
 
 November 2, 2009 7:49 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 nmdad writes:
 
Alfredo&apos;s kicks butt for the money! I made the mistake of ordering nachos supreme and a burrito one time and had to take half of each home. They have HUGE portions and a very reasonable price for real Mexican food. I like looking at the white folks going through the taco bell drive through while the Mexicans eat real Mexican food for the same price. It&apos;s always our first stop when we visit friends in Abilene.
 
 November 2, 2009 8:06 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 stephieee writes:
 
nmdad! Agreed! Alfredo&apos;s is AMAZING. I personally love Texas Roadhouse for a sit-down restaurant. The food has always been great, as well as the service! And such a fun atmosphere. Not bad prices either. I do have to say, I tried the whole 3 course, 2 people meal at chili&apos;s and WOW tons of food. Good deal for your money. Harolds BBQ is the best bbq no doubt. Lytle Land&amp;Cattle is extremely over priced! I have tried seafood tavern and they amazingly cheap lunch specials!! You should check them out. Jalapeno cheddar stuffed chicken breast! :) They&apos;re lunch specials are like 4.99-7.99 and that includes free iced tea with the meal. That&apos;s about the same as a fast food place but with much better food and great service. Had to brag on them...
 
 November 2, 2009 8:08 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 saltydog writes:
 
in response to Bosenbach :

The locally famous steakhouse in this article needs to concentrate on pest control, not smaller plates. Our family quit eating there not because of price or taste, but for dead bugs on the window sills and mouse droppings in the tea glass. The server argued that the tea was fine.
 
Agreed. My last visit, I had to contend with lots of flying bugs. When I asked my server she laughed and said&quot;they are always here.&quot;After that night I won&apos;t ever be.
 
 November 2, 2009 8:57 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 catchme writes:
 
&quot;touch feely waitstaff and an owner, who actually had the audacity to come out and put her hands on me, to introduce herself, disgusted me, ruined my appetite and I find those actions to actually be assault.&quot;

Was this at a strip joint? hahaha...
 
 November 2, 2009 9:14 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jersey (Inactive) writes:
 
whatitis must be a fun date! Your appetite was actually ruined by someone touching you and introducing herself?? Wow, you are wound up tight, aren&apos;t you!! This is the south, buddy, that is what people do.

You make it sound like they are only to SERVE you and not talk to you or look at you. You sound like a snob.
 
 November 2, 2009 9:29 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 elizabeth writes:
 
Due to busy schedules it seems we eat out more than home. My OPINION: R&amp;C is not a location that is even an option to eat, a dr pepper at the drive thru is okay but as for the food&amp;service not a chance. Spanos used to be one of my favorite places to eat but lately when we go in they are&quot;out of&quot;my selection&amp;the service is slow. I enjoy Lytle Land - and as far as you feel you are being overcharged... the prices are on the menu, if you don&apos;t want to pay that price order something else. It&apos;s not like the prices are secret. China Garden on S 14th is one of my favorites, great food and prices&amp;the waitstaff is just wonderful. Looks like a hole in the wall place but it can&apos;t be beat. Chilli&apos;s is 50/50, some days great food&amp;service, other you wonder if they even care you are there. Johnny Carino&apos;s - service&amp;quality of food has gone so far downhill in the past year I am surprised that anyone eats there. Dos Primos...LOVE it, food great, service great, cold beer in a mug with salt&amp;lime can&apos;t be beat! Famous Daves - give me the potato salad and just back away!
There&apos;s my opinion. :)
 
 November 2, 2009 9:37 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jersey (Inactive) writes:
 
elizabeth, have not had a chance to eat at Dos Primos but heard their beer is the best in town! Will have to give it a try. I really like Los Arcos on Ambler - their chicken enchiladas are to die for.
 
 November 2, 2009 10:12 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 elizabeth writes:
 
jersey I enjoy Los Arcos but always forget it is there even though I live on the North side.
Oh and on Burgers by George I hope it stays closed down! That place was the most disgusting place I had ever been in. Even the cockroaches didn&apos;t want to live or eat there. We went in there ONE time and the cockroaches were picketing at the front door... now honey that&apos;s bad!
 
 November 2, 2009 10:13 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 GravityParade writes:
 
I refuse to go to the Rick and Carolyn&apos;s because of the bad service experiences I&apos;ve had with their store on Buffalo Gap Road. I&apos;ve also experienced long wait times at the drive through window, and it ticks me off when they make me pull my car around the building to receive my order after I&apos;ve already paid. The last time this happened I waited 20 minutes for 2 burgers. When they ran my order out to me I was missing 1 burger, 1 fry and the fries were cold.

To the Person who said that the long wait time is because they&apos;re cooking the burger: first, it doesn&apos;t take more than 10 minutes to cook a burger. Second, even if they&apos;re making burgers per order, they should be staging the meat on the grill, so realistically it takes less than 5 minutes to make a hamburger. If I wait 10+ minutes for my order, you better make sure my fries are piping hot out of the fryer. Too many times I wait an excessive amount of time for my food, to receive cold fries. Getting cold fries is always unacceptable, but waiting 10+ minutes for cold fries is an insult.

A lot of restaurants act like they&apos;re doing you a favor by taking your business. On a regular basis I&apos;m confronted by the kind of apathetic service that would drive a place out of business in the DFW metroplex -- but I think in Abilene it&apos;s so common that people expect bad service so they tolerate it.

A Perfect example is Taco Bueno. Taco Bueno has been advertising a special cheeseburger taco on the menu. Using presumably hundreds of thousands of dollars in advertising to promote the special and to bring business to their stores. When I arrived at the Taco Bueno drive thru, I placed my order for cheeseburger tacos. When I get to the window 15 minutes later, they employee tells me it will be 20 minutes to wait for the cheeseburger tacos. Are you kidding me? You spend all that money in promotion to bring a customer to the store and you blew it at the point of sale? I kindly told the $7/hr to forget the order and to have a nice day.

This is not unlike many other experiences I&apos;ve had at Abilene restaurants. Very seldom do some restaurants get your order right. Routinely they ask you to pull your car up and in the case of Dairy Queen they stage every single car to spoof their speed of service metric. I hope I never hear any of these people curse their job because if you can&apos;t get a simple drive through order right, then you&apos;re career path doesn&apos;t have a bright future -- and that goes for the managers of these restaurants too. I could run a Taco Bell or Dairy Queen in my Sleep and double the revenue of these restaurants. They have the most apathetic, lazy approach to customer service. It&apos;s an oddity that these business can thrive in Abilene.

This is not to say that Abilene does not have some great restaurants and great food service workers/managers because they certainly do exist. There are even some brilliant examples in the fast food arena which stand out among their peers.
 
 November 2, 2009 10:29 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 closingtime12 writes:
 
I agree that you can&apos;t knock someone like Lytle for their prices. They are printed on the menu. Order the lunch special or split a large steak with a friend.

I am also a firm believer that you cannot go somewhere once or twice and judge them unless you order the special items that make them so good. The reason I rave about Lytle is the Large Ribeye. Yes it is expensive, but it is no more expensive then a lg steak at 4 or 5 of our other&quot;nice&quot;places. The reason I rave about Catfish Corner are the Onion Rings and the Hamburger Steak, Little Italy has dishes with Pink Sauce, and Mexican Food places have great fajitas, chimis, margaritas, and desserts and other items. Don&apos;t go judge them only on enchiladas !
 
 November 2, 2009 10:31 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 GravityParade writes:
 
in response to RandyPool :

I think what is hilarious at first and sad upon deeper thought is that this thread will probably flame over who has the better $5.00 lunch. Names will be called, restaurants will be defamed as others are exalted as the best place to eat out 3 times a week is determined by the deep thinkers of this forum.

While those same thinkers, on another thread today, will SCREAM no more taxes for an absolutely needed advancement in education for children that has an annual cost of less than one night out for dinner.

I think Michael Ridgeway said it best in his letter from Iraq last week when he wrote.

“The real issue is the priority of what the prevailing culture is in the community in how individuals and businesses spend their monies/income. In the basis of a consumer economy and the “what’s in it for me” philosophy, people tend to be more concerned with themselves and their own immediate creature comforts and luxuries and will spend vast sums of money indiscriminately on themselves. Realistically, this is pure economic blindness and foolishness — little more than rearranging the chairs on the deck of the doomed Titanic”.
 
Hi Randy, I&apos;m surprised that you can read this and spin the exact opposite analysis of what I think is evident in the phenomenon stated in this article. People aren&apos;t spending as much money as they were a few years ago, because collectively we&apos;re earning less money, Many of us are 2 income households and some of us have 1 income earner unemployed (not myself but I know many that are), so we&apos;re looking for ways to reduce expenses instead of increase expenses. Which is why a 20 million dollar bond, with no concrete details, is unappealing to people.
 
 November 2, 2009 10:44 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jennieevelyn writes:
 
GravityParade...your post hit the nail on the head. You just saved me a longer post, I could not agree more!

Already, Jack in The Box has hit the downhill...do the majority of employees look like they are tweakers? And not that looks are what count, but, their actions and mannerisms, as well as their general inability to function are oh, so obvious. After a very unsatisfying expedition to a local eatery yesterday, I truly believe that we are closer to Franklin County, Missouri than we realize.

And if that isn&apos;t bad enough, the attitude is atrocious. Sharon&apos;s BBQ has the worst customer service in the county! She needs to rethink her choice of management...or Elaine needs a new attitude.
 
 November 2, 2009 10:51 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 catchme writes:
 
elizabeth- you got that right about China Garden&apos;s on S 14th. LOVE that place! The food is always great and the staff is extremly friendly!
 
 November 2, 2009 12:57 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 elhuntress writes:
 
With N1H1 on the rise, we decided to stop eating out so much. I think that also has something to do with the drop in bussiness. I know that people who work in the restaurants are pressured into not taking time off when they are sick. Some places even threaten them with loosing their jobs. And along those lines...people stop taking your children to the grocery store, THEY TOUCH EVERYTHING.
 
 November 2, 2009 1:14 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 elizabeth writes:
 
Okay I have to ask... what is in Franklin County, Missouri
 
 November 2, 2009 1:22 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Bossy writes:
 
in response to les47#311842 :

Well Crash02 you probably experienced them actually cooking the burger rather than having one that was already cooked and just throwing it on the bun and then nuking it like some places do.
 
R&amp;C was my first job and I can actually say that they cook their meat on the grill vs Burger King or McDonalds. And the Grill Chicken Salad is Awesome.
 
 November 2, 2009 1:23 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 Mellonello writes:
 
Ya wanna a good burger, steak or fish, go to the store, and purchase what you need, go home, grill it on your grill,, fix a few veggies, and have a great MEAL at home with your children!
It&apos;s much cleaner, safer, and I guarnatee the food will be better.

If you do go to a resturant, take you antiseptic wipes,, I always do, and use them to wipe the table off myself, and the menu, and the silverware.
 
 November 2, 2009 1:25 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jennieevelyn writes:
 
Sorry elizabeth...it&apos;s one of the worst meth-affected counties in the U.S. And if you have ever driven thru...b/c I can assure you, you dont want to stop...it is bad. Meth mouth is easy to spot, as are the ticks and mannerisms, and I am seeing it in so many of our local businesses...especially in positions that don&apos;t pay well...like fast food.
 
 November 2, 2009 1:25 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 DB writes:
 
in response to bigmoe :

I no longer live in Abilene. But when I do visit I call my daughter on the cell phone and tell her to go to Catfish Corner. I want my fish when I get to Abilene. I just love thier fish. I tell everyone I know to go there if their passing through. That&apos;s what I call good eats, and affordable.
 
Their food sucks.
 
 November 2, 2009 1:50 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 elizabeth writes:
 
jennie all I can say is eeewww!
 
 November 2, 2009 2:27 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 jennieevelyn writes:
 
Franklin Co, Mo is one of the worst counties in the U.S. for meth. I used the comparison because I am seeing more and more of the&quot;meth-mouth&quot;and tweakers working in restaurants in our area...you can spot them a mile off by their ticks and mannerisms. Some of them may be&quot;recovering&quot;, but the majority are obviously active users.

I soooooo wish we had an adequate Farmer&apos;s Market for our area or access to more fresh produce!
 
 November 2, 2009 5:26 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 nmdad writes:
 
in response to DB :

Their food sucks.
 
I disagree..I go to Catfish corner and Alfredos each visit to Abilene. The only catfish in Albuquerque comes from Cracker Barrel and is not near as good as catfish corner.
 
 Comments 1 - 50 51 - 94 of 94 Newer Comments 
 
Share your thoughts

Comments are the sole responsibility of the person posting them. You agree not to post comments that are off topic, defamatory, obscene, abusive, threatening or an invasion of privacy. Violators may be banned. Click here for our full user agreement .
 
 Username * Don&apos;t have an account? Sign up for a new account 

 Password * Can&apos;t remember? Reset your password 

 Comment 
 
 
 
Comments can be shared on 
 
 
 Facebook
 and 
 Yahoo!.
Add both options by connecting your profiles .
 
Most Popular
 
 Viewed Commented Emailed 
 
 Abilene City Council approves purchase of armored vehicle Published 7/12/2012 at 8:53 a.m. 24 comments Salaries might be sweetened in Abilene ISD Updated 7/11/2012 at 6:11 a.m. 25 comments Chick-fil-A fans camping out in hopes of scoring free chicken (with video) Updated 7/11/2012 at 7:41 a.m. 13 comments Letter: Officers do not wish ill will Published 7/10/2012 at 11:00 p.m. 12 comments Abilene losing Border Patrol station, both its agents Published 7/10/2012 at 10:00 p.m. 19 comments 
 
Photo Galleries
 2012 women Olympic athletes Political Cartoons - 07/13/12 Political Cartoons - 07/12/12 
 Strict ID laws may block valid votes Published 7/8/2012 at 11:08 p.m. 76 comments Texas ranked worst in U.S. on health care Published 7/5/2012 at 9:28 p.m. 102 comments DCOA meets today to discuss funding for Pactiv Published 7/9/2012 at 6:00 p.m. 27 comments Abilene City Council approves purchase of armored vehicle Published 7/12/2012 at 8:53 a.m. 24 comments Salaries might be sweetened in Abilene ISD Published 7/10/2012 at 10:00 p.m. 25 comments 
 
 Malware may knock thousands off Internet on Monday Published 7/5/2012 at 5:00 a.m. 13 comments Roofers getting calls to fix last year&apos;s repairs Published 7/2/2012 at 8:00 p.m. 0 comments Fireworks accident claims life of Tarleton student Published 7/5/2012 at 7:20 p.m. 0 comments &apos;God particle&apos; discovered, now the fun begins Published 7/8/2012 at 3:00 a.m. 5 comments Smith Pipe faces $129,800 in OSHA penalties for workplace hazards Published 7/3/2012 at 6:44 p.m. 29 comments 
 
Weather
 
 Currently 36-Hour Your Photos 
 Currently 94 ° Partly Cloudy Wind: Variable 6mph Today 95 ° 69 ° Fri 04:00 AM Partly Cloudy Temp: 73° Fri 04:00 PM Hot Temp: 94° Sat 04:00 AM Partly Cloudy Temp: 72° 
Feels Like: 73°

Humidity: 73%

Precip: 9%
 
Feels Like: 93°

Humidity: 29%

Precip: 10%
 
Feels Like: 72°

Humidity: 69%

Precip: 8%
 Transit of planet Venus 6/5/12
8:34 p.m.
 Lunar Eclipse June 4th 5:35am 6/4/12
9:31 p.m.
 Approaching Storm 5/29/12
10:39 p.m.
 Approaching Storm 5/29/12
10:39 p.m.
 Solar Eclipse Phenomenon 5/20/12
8:35 p.m.
 Solar Eclipse 2012 from North Abilene 5/20/12
8:51 p.m.
 More Weather» 
Calendar
 
 Thursday Jul 12 Friday Jul 13 Saturday Jul 14 More BROWSE Icon 
 
 
 Women&apos;s luncheon - 07/12 Abilene Country Club 

11:30 a.m.
 
 ArtWalk - 07/12 Downtown Abilene 

5 p.m.
 
 Dining for Women - 07/12 First Christian Church 

6 p.m.
 
 Concert - 07/12 Kent&apos;s Harley Davidson 

6:30 p.m.
 
 Dance - 07/12 Old Glory Community Center 

7 p.m.
 
 More Events» 
 
 Bake sale - 07/13 De Leon, Shoppin Baskit 

9 a.m.
 
 Put on your dancing shoes - 07/13 Oplin Community Center 

7:30 p.m.
 
 More Events» 
 
 Run and ride - 07/14 Gorman City Park 

8 a.m.
 
 Car wash - 07/14 De Leon First National Bank 

9 a.m.
 
 Block party - 07/14 Minda Street Church of Christ 

noon
 
 Dance - 07/14 Desdemona Activity Center 

7 p.m.
 
 Square dance - 07/14 Wagon Wheel 

7 p.m.
 
 More Events» 
Loading...
 More Events» 
Business Directory
 
 Search Browse 
 Business: e.g. salon Location: e.g. Abilene, TX 
 Powered by Local.com 
 Auto Dealers Auto Repair Books Carpet Cleaning Child Care Coffee Shops Dentists Doctors Florists Furniture Golf Courses Gyms Hair Salons Hotels Insurance Jewelry Lawn Services Locksmiths Movers Pizza Plumbing Realtors Remodeling Restaurants Storage Veterinarians 
 Powered by Local.com Full Directory» 
Features
 

 
 
 Poll

Why would students put off retaking the STARR exams?
 
 Sky&apos;s eye view

AISD&apos;s planetarium gives students peek of what&apos;s way out there
 
 Prairie Dogs pounded

Cats 6-8 starter Nation comes up big in six-hit shutout
 
 Colts complete sweep of Prairie Dogs

Dogs let one slip away to Colts in 12 innings
 
 Always at play

Visiting NCCIL artist inspired by toys 
 
 Rolling in dough

Abilene bakeries, doughnut shops busy
 
 GoFridayNight.com

Abilene, Big Country and Texas High School Football at its best.
	</body>
</document>
