<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006691" url="http://www.instructables.com/id/9-Surprising-Uses-For-Mustard-that-dont-involve-/" time="2012-07-12-23:40" support="3" score="0.0036538016961949163" bingtitle="9 Surprising Uses For Mustard (that don&apos;t involve a sandwich)" webtitle="9 Surprising Uses For Mustard (that don&apos;t involve a sandwich)">
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>Yes, just when you thought your favorite condiment couldn&apos;t get any better, I present ... I used to work in a fast-food restaurant and was always burning myself on the heat ...</description>
	<body>
		Share What You Make sign up or login or 
 
 Go 
 Create Explore Contests More 
 
3 Simple Ways to
Share What You Make

With Instructables you can share what you make with the world—and tap into an ever-growing community of creative experts.
 
Other ways to share:  

 Ask a Question What is a Question? 
Questions are a super-easy way to get answers from the Instructables community. Learn how to build, do, or make anything! You just ask a question and the community will provide answers. You choose the best answer! Forum Topic Submit a Forum Topic! 
The forums are the place to ask questions, share a cool project from another site, find collaborators for your latest project, or discuss anything of interest to the Instructables community. Guides What is a guide? 
Guides are a collection of Instructables, such as &apos;5 Minute Recipes&apos; or &apos;Father&apos;s Day Gifts&apos;.
 Start creating your own now! Group Start a new group Upload Images Do you have a lot of images to upload? 
If you prefer to upload your images before you submit, then this is for you.
 Remember to tag them so they will be easier for you to find when you are viewing your library.
 You can also upload images when you are creating your posts. Bug Report Did you find a bug or have a suggestion for us? 
We appreciate all the help our users give us in tracking down bugs and making the site better for everyone. 
 Photos Photos 
Share one or more photos of a project, recipe, or whatever you&apos;ve made, quickly and easily.
 
 Get Started 

 Learn more&amp;Get Tips 
 Step by Step Step-By-Step 
Share your step-by-step photos with text instructions of what you made so others can do it too!
 
 Get Started 

 Learn more&amp;Get Tips 
 Video Video 
Share your how-to video. You&apos;ll need your embed code from a video site such as YouTube.
 
 Get Started 

 Learn more&amp;Get Tips 
 
 
 Life Hacks 
 Education Finances Kids Life Skills Parenting Travel Decorating Craft See More» See Less« 

 Art Beauty Christmas Cleaning Duct Tape Fashion Furnishing Gardening Green Halloween Health Holidays Jewelry Kitchen Lamps Organizing Paper Pets Printing Relationships Reuse Sewing Yarn 
 Print PDF Favorite Email     
9 Surprising Uses For Mustard (that don&apos;t involve a sandwich)
 i Image Information
	</body>
</document>
