<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006591" url="http://www.fark.com/comments/7027349/On-Monday-10-new-items-will-mark-Burger-Kings-biggest-menu-expansion-since-chain-opened-its-doors-in-1954-Where-is-your-god-now" time="2012-07-12-23:31" support="4" score="0.004557307655785934" bingtitle="FARK.com: (7027349) On Monday, 10 new items will mark Burger King ..." webtitle="FARK.com:  (7027349) On Monday, 10 new items will mark Burger Kings biggest menu expansion since the chain opened its doors in 1954. Where is your god now?">
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>The place near my school has the new items. The ... soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars ... hint people: I am never going to go to a fast food restaurant to order ...</description>
	<body>
		It&apos;s Not News It&apos;s Fark.com Real news. Real funny Log In  |  Sign Up» Login Password Forgot password? X 
 Fark TotalFark my Fark About/FArQ Contests Store Contact Us Mobile 
 Search: Password Login Turn on javascript (or enable it for Fark) for a better user experience. If you can read this, either the style sheet didn&apos;t load or you have an older browser that doesn&apos;t support 
style sheets. Try clearing your browser cache and refreshing the page. 
 Main Sports Business Geek Entertainment Politics Video 
 

 On Monday, 10 new items will mark Burger King&apos;s biggest menu expansion since the chain opened its doors in 1954. Where is your god now?    ( courant.com ) 186
 More: PSA , Burger King , American cheese , iced coffees , five guys , Golden Arches , franchisee , smoothies   
 •       •       • 

 7094 clicks; posted to Business» on 02 Apr 2012 at 5:40 AM    |  Favorite    |   share:     more»    |     shirt it! 
 

 
 
 Share this link: 

 URL: http://fk.cm/go/7027349 Bookmark: URL: http://fk.cm/7027349 Bookmark: Article Comments close 
 186 Comments    ( +0» ) 
 Paginated (50/page) Single page Single page, reversed Normal view Change images to links Show raw HTML   Show posts from ignored users   
 View Voting Results: Smartest and Funniest 
 First | « | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | » | Last | Show all   
 
 CavalierEternal 2012-04-01 09:40:09 PM 
 They got rid of the spicy chicken sandwich. F*ck &apos;em. 
   
 
 Ambivalence 2012-04-01 09:44:24 PM 
 I hadn&apos;t been to burger king in YEARS, I recently decided to get a burger and some onion rings. Holy hell those onion rings were horrible! They had no taste whatsoever. how do you screw up onion rings? how many times were those suckers cooked and frozen and thawed and recooked and canned and shiate? 
   
 
 RCraig 2012-04-01 09:46:29 PM 
 I just wish they could get the farkin&apos; order correct half the time. 
   
 
 ecmoRandomNumbers 2012-04-01 09:59:19 PM 
 All Tom McDonald had to do was look at Burger King&apos;s competitors to see why sales at the chain were falling. A Burger King franchisee since 1989, McDonald said the chain&apos;s menu hadn&apos;t changed much over the years. 

The irony. 
   
 
 DamnYankees 2012-04-01 10:04:37 PM 
 CavalierEternal : They got rid of the spicy chicken sandwich. F*ck &apos;em. 

What? Did they really? THATS THEIR BEST GODDAMM THING. 
   
 
 chiett 2012-04-01 10:06:33 PM 
 FTA: &quot;McDonald&apos;s quickly adapted. The world&apos;s biggest burger chain reinvented itself as a hip, healthier place to eat...&quot; 

WTF ?? 
   
 
 CavalierEternal 2012-04-01 10:07:26 PM 
 DamnYankees : CavalierEternal: They got rid of the spicy chicken sandwich. F*ck &apos;em.

What? Did they really? THATS THEIR BEST GODDAMM THING. 

Sh*t you not, I pulled up to the BK drive-thru window two days ago.

&quot;Hi, can I get three spicy chickens with bacon?&quot;

&quot;Sir, we don&apos;t carry the spicy chicken anymore.&quot;

&quot;...&quot;

 
   
 
 GAT_00 2012-04-01 10:09:32 PM 
 Will any of them not suck? I haven&apos;t been to a BK in years because everything sucked.

 On Monday, it plans to launch a lineup of smoothies, frappe coffees, chicken strips and snack wraps. 

So probably still sucking. Here&apos;s a hint people: I am never going to go to a fast food restaurant to order coffee. I&apos;m going to DD or Einstein Brothers, or if nothing else Starbucks. 
   
 
 MBK 2012-04-01 10:19:23 PM 
 Ambivalence : I hadn&apos;t been to burger king in YEARS, I recently decided to get a burger and some onion rings. Holy hell those onion rings were horrible! They had no taste whatsoever. how do you screw up onion rings? how many times were those suckers cooked and frozen and thawed and recooked and canned and shiate? 

Their onion rings are...chopped up onions, battered and put in a ring shape.

As opposed to real onion rings, which are whole onions, battered.

They really do suck :( 
   
 
 violentsalvation 2012-04-01 10:25:10 PM 
 I went to one in New Mexico the other day and had something I think was called a Texas Double Whopper. It was actually really good. jalapenos, cheese, bacon, probably 1000 calories. I sound fat. 
   
 
 GAT_00 2012-04-01 10:27:26 PM 
 violentsalvation : I sound fat. 

It&apos;s the Internet. We already assume you are. 
   
 
 Hobodeluxe 2012-04-01 10:41:37 PM 
 MBK : Ambivalence: I hadn&apos;t been to burger king in YEARS, I recently decided to get a burger and some onion rings. Holy hell those onion rings were horrible! They had no taste whatsoever. how do you screw up onion rings? how many times were those suckers cooked and frozen and thawed and recooked and canned and shiate?

Their onion rings are...chopped up onions, battered and put in a ring shape.

As opposed to real onion rings, which are whole onions, battered.

They really do suck :( 

 

this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert. 
   
 
 violentsalvation 2012-04-01 11:06:33 PM 
 GAT_00 : violentsalvation: I sound fat.

It&apos;s the Internet. We already assume you are. 

I prefer hefty or pudgy. 
   
 
 RobertBruce 2012-04-01 11:07:44 PM 
 Just keep making a good Whopper, don&apos;t halve the amount of cheese on anything ELSE now, and stfu. 
   
 
 SilentStrider 2012-04-01 11:09:32 PM 
 GAT_00 : So probably still sucking. Here&apos;s a hint people: I am never going to go to a fast food restaurant to order coffee. I&apos;m going to DD or Einstein Brothers, or if nothing else Starbucks. 

I dunno, McD&apos;s coffee, the actual hot black coffee (not the frappes cappuccinos or whatever) is not bad. Not the greatest coffee ever, but since I&apos;m using it for the caffeine fix, its palatable. 
   
 
 Bagelox-99 2012-04-01 11:19:35 PM 
 BK is going down. It&apos;s obvious when you enter one of their outlets. Sad to say, but rejiggering the menu at this point may be the least of their worries. 
   
 
 eraser8 2012-04-01 11:21:25 PM 
 Hobodeluxe : this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert. 

I think you mean baklava for dessert.

A balaclava is kinda like a ski mask:

 
   
 
 foo monkey 2012-04-01 11:32:02 PM 
 chiett : FTA: &quot;McDonald&apos;s quickly adapted. The world&apos;s biggest burger chain reinvented itself as a hip, healthier place to eat...&quot;

WTF ?? 

McD has healthy options, like the salads, but people buy Big Macs. Aside from the salads, most of the&quot;healthy&quot; options are jacked up with sugar or salt.

The Southwestern grilled chicken salad isn&apos;t bad, but once you pick out all the iceberg lettuce cores, it&apos;s like five bites. Less fat and fewer calories than a happy meal. 
   
 
 RminusQ 2012-04-01 11:44:00 PM 
 The place near my school has the new items. The Chicken Selects (and that&apos;s really what they are, a direct ripoff of Chicken Selects) were meh. I&apos;ve yet to try the smoothies, but I&apos;ll probably be disappointed when I do. 
   
 
 Harv72b 2012-04-01 11:47:04 PM 
 RCraig : I just wish they could get the farkin&apos; order correct half the time. 

Burger King has only screwed up my order twice, and both times I wound up with more expensive items than what I paid for. So that&apos;s not really an issue for me. 
   
 
 Sim Tree 2012-04-02 12:01:01 AM 
 eraser8 : Hobodeluxe: this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert.

I think you mean baklava for dessert.

A balaclava is kinda like a ski mask: 

Mmmmm, balaclava. 
   
 
 ShawnDoc 2012-04-02 01:41:55 AM 
 FTFA The result: On Monday, it plans to launch a lineup of smoothies, frappe coffees, chicken strips and snack wraps. 

So its doing exactly what McDonald&apos;s did 3 or 4 years ago. 
   
 
 Paris1127 2012-04-02 01:45:52 AM 
 Hobodeluxe : this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert. 

 

YOU WILL EAT THAT DESSERT OR ELSE!!!1!! 
   
 
 SpikeStrip 2012-04-02 01:58:59 AM 
 i hate burger king. i love burger king. i&apos;m ambivalent towards burger king. 
   
 
 SoothinglyDeranged 2012-04-02 02:21:04 AM 
 Paris1127 : Hobodeluxe: this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert.

[us.123rf.com image 640x958]

YOU WILL EAT THAT DESSERT OR ELSE!!!1!! 

Bwuahahaha

/That is all. 
   
 
 propasaurus 2012-04-02 02:54:32 AM 
 Meanwhile, places like Five Guys are thriving by just serving really good burgers instead of frappes and smoothies. Hell, In n Out has a basic menu of burgers, fries, shakes and soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars down the street.
Make a really effin&apos; good Whopper and ditch the frappes, salads and other novelty items. 
   
 
 RancidSorbet 2012-04-02 03:04:40 AM 
 Sorry, Burgerville wins every freaking time. 
   
 
 Teknowaffle 2012-04-02 04:37:08 AM 
 propasaurus : Meanwhile, places like Five Guys are thriving by just serving really good burgers instead of frappes and smoothies. Hell, In n Out has a basic menu of burgers, fries, shakes and soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars down the street.
Make a really effin&apos; good Whopper and ditch the frappes, salads and other novelty items. 

Pretty much this.

Somewhere along the line, some marketing idiot said &quot;you know what people love? Choice. Why do one thing well, when we can do dozens terribly so people don&apos;t have to go anywhere else?&quot;. It is the Wal-Martization of fast food.

Hell, go to your local candy aisle. Think back to the early 90s and the Reese&apos;s line. There were cups, and then pieces. That was it. And both were delicious. Around 1996 came the Nutrageous, which completed the peanut butter candy family. Bite-sized hard candies, 2 bite cups, and then a bar. A happy family.

Then, as 2000 started to approach, it started to get insane with Reese&apos;s products. White chocolate, dark chocolate, fast break, sticks, whipps. None of them filled a void in the product line. I have never seen anyone actually buy one of these other products.

But we like the illusion of choice I guess and that is what matters in our pitiful lives. 
   
 
 SnarfVader 2012-04-02 04:52:06 AM 
 RancidSorbet : Sorry, Burgerville wins every freaking time. 

Yeah, but you have to take out a loan to eat there. 
   
 
 Confabulat 2012-04-02 06:09:55 AM 
 Teknowaffle : propasaurus: Meanwhile, places like Five Guys are thriving by just serving really good burgers instead of frappes and smoothies. Hell, In n Out has a basic menu of burgers, fries, shakes and soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars down the street.
Make a really effin&apos; good Whopper and ditch the frappes, salads and other novelty items.

Pretty much this.

Somewhere along the line, some marketing idiot said &quot;you know what people love? Choice. Why do one thing well, when we can do dozens terribly so people don&apos;t have to go anywhere else?&quot;. It is the Wal-Martization of fast food.

Hell, go to your local candy aisle. Think back to the early 90s and the Reese&apos;s line. There were cups, and then pieces. That was it. And both were delicious. Around 1996 came the Nutrageous, which completed the peanut butter candy family. Bite-sized hard candies, 2 bite cups, and then a bar. A happy family.

Then, as 2000 started to approach, it started to get insane with Reese&apos;s products. White chocolate, dark chocolate, fast break, sticks, whipps. None of them filled a void in the product line. I have never seen anyone actually buy one of these other products.

But we like the illusion of choice I guess and that is what matters in our pitiful lives. 

Yep. If I drive into an Arby&apos;s it&apos;s because I have an odd craving for a roast beef sandwich. I don&apos;t want to spend 5 minutes perusing the menu to figure out the new offers, and if the guy in front of me at the drive-thru tries, I&apos;ll honk my horn because what kind of idiot figures out what to order when they pull up the menu at Arby&apos;s.

Same thing with Burger King. Deal with what you have. Make a better Whopper and fix your fries. McDonald&apos;s beats you for some pretty simple reasons. I walk into McDonald&apos;s knowing what I might want, and knowing what I&apos;ll get.They&apos;ve gotten really good at that. 
   
 
 tweek46420 2012-04-02 06:26:36 AM 
 it used to be

1. burger king for the burgers (when the actually were still flame-broiled)
2. mcdonalds for the fries
3. wendys for the shake


now i just go to Chipolte 
   
 
 Summer Glau&apos;s Love Slave 2012-04-02 06:32:43 AM 
 RobertBruce : Just keep making a good Whopper, don&apos;t halve the amount of cheese on anything ELSE now, and stfu. 

Word. 
   
 
 AverageAmericanGuy 2012-04-02 06:40:26 AM 
 tweek46420 : it used to be

1. burger king for the burgers (when the actually were still flame-broiled)
2. mcdonalds for the fries
3. wendys for the shake 

The question on everyone&apos;s mind:

 Link (new window) 
   
 
 Gobobo 2012-04-02 06:49:17 AM 
 McD&apos;s used to suck and BK was the best massive chain, but now BK is rapidly going downhill and KFC is already just an excuse to eat saturated fat with a little chicken attached.

Making your own burger is the only way to go now. 
   
 
 Babwa Wawa 2012-04-02 07:37:30 AM 
 CavalierEternal : They got rid of the spicy chicken sandwich. F*ck &apos;em. 
   
 
 swaxhog 2012-04-02 07:40:40 AM 
 chiett : FTA: &quot;McDonald&apos;s quickly adapted. The world&apos;s biggest burger chain reinvented itself as a hip, healthier place to eat...&quot;

WTF ?? 

Around here a lot of the McD&apos;s are turning into coffee houses. They have big McCafe signs, the drive through menu is 75% taken up with coffee offerings. They even say &quot;Welcome to McCafe, how can I ....&quot; I don&apos;t know if anyone is buying into it yet, but they seem to be trying really hard to reinvent themselves. 
   
 
 OhioUGrad 2012-04-02 07:48:01 AM 
 DamnYankees : CavalierEternal: They got rid of the spicy chicken sandwich. F*ck &apos;em.

What? Did they really? THATS THEIR BEST GODDAMM THING. 

Agreed, guess I&apos;ll no longer go there....

/As a hangover &quot;cure&quot; once put a spicy chicken patty on a double cheeseburger....was amazing! 
   
 
 Babwa Wawa 2012-04-02 07:49:41 AM 
 swaxhog : chiett: FTA: &quot;McDonald&apos;s quickly adapted. The world&apos;s biggest burger chain reinvented itself as a hip, healthier place to eat...&quot;

WTF ??

Around here a lot of the McD&apos;s are turning into coffee houses. They have big McCafe signs, the drive through menu is 75% taken up with coffee offerings. They even say &quot;Welcome to McCafe, how can I ....&quot; I don&apos;t know if anyone is buying into it yet, but they seem to be trying really hard to reinvent themselves. 

 GAT_00 : Here&apos;s a hint people: I am never going to go to a fast food restaurant to order coffee. I&apos;m going to DD or Einstein Brothers, or if nothing else Starbucks. 

Coffee is such a high margin item that it doesn&apos;t even matter whether a majority of people order it. It&apos;s better than soda, because it allows you to differentiate your offering from your competitors.

Y&apos;all remember how krispy kreme had a huge surge? The couldn&apos;t take advantage of it because they didn&apos;t have a coffee strategy. A normal person buys more coffee than doughnuts - to the tune that you&apos;ll get 14 times the profit out of a coffee customer than a doughnut customer.

The food is there just to draw you in. 
   
 
 missiv 2012-04-02 08:32:28 AM 
 eraser8 : Hobodeluxe: this is the place for onion rings and a steak in a sack, and beer. and maybe some balaclava for dessert.

I think you mean baklava for dessert.

A balaclava is kinda like a ski mask:

[www.deadcaterpillar.com image 300x300] 

 
Baccalàis salted cod fish.

 
Bobby Bacala works for Junior and likes to play with trains.

Are we straight? 
   
 
 ryant123 2012-04-02 08:35:11 AM 
 MIAMI - When Burger King set about to fix its ailing empire, the fast food giant started by scrutinizing everything on the menu - even the mayonnaise . 

So...they decided to address the obvious major component of their repugnant food? 
   
 
 GoodyearPimp 2012-04-02 08:35:55 AM 
 Babwa Wawa : A normal person buys more coffee than doughnuts - to the tune that you&apos;ll get 14 times the profit out of a coffee customer than a doughnut customer. 

Uh, that&apos;s because coffee costs almost nothing to make. 
   
 
 IrateShadow 2012-04-02 08:40:00 AM 
 Last time I went to a Burger King, I paid over $10 for a combo meal. For that kind of money, I&apos;d rather go to five guys or to something that&apos;s nor a franchise. 
   
 
 Babwa Wawa 2012-04-02 08:55:42 AM 
 GoodyearPimp : Babwa Wawa: A normal person buys more coffee than doughnuts - to the tune that you&apos;ll get 14 times the profit out of a coffee customer than a doughnut customer.

Uh, that&apos;s because coffee costs almost nothing to make. 

Yeah. And that&apos;s why the pimp the hell out of it. The profit from 10 cups of coffee offsets the cost of a man-hour at one of these stores. It takes far more doughnuts to do the same.

This is why a coffee strategy is important for any fast food vendor that wants to maintain a wide presence (like McD&apos;s, but not necessarily like Arby&apos;s). 
   
 
 Mugato 2012-04-02 09:10:04 AM 
 Not interested

 
   
 
 dletter 2012-04-02 09:10:29 AM 
 Burgers now come with one slice of cheese instead of two, so it melts more evenly. 

Oh yeah, I&apos;m sure THAT was the reason to cut down on the cheese, while keeping the prices the same or raising them. 
   
 
 TNel 2012-04-02 09:18:37 AM 
 propasaurus : Meanwhile, places like Five Guys are thriving by just serving really good burgers instead of frappes and smoothies. Hell, In n Out has a basic menu of burgers, fries, shakes and soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars down the street.
Make a really effin&apos; good Whopper and ditch the frappes, salads and other novelty items. 

Five guys has good burgers? That&apos;s news to me, the only ones I&apos;ve gotten from there are greasy patties and fries that are par fried. 
   
 
 oldfarthenry 2012-04-02 09:27:33 AM 
 
It&apos;ll *puff-puff-wheeze* fail! 
   
 
 Spawn_of_Cthulhu 2012-04-02 09:31:17 AM 
 Burger King changed their fries a few months back to giant, undercooked, mushy, tasteless objects that aren&apos;t even close to food. If that&apos;s an example of their decision making process (&quot;People like our small, crispy fries so let&apos;s make them big and soggy instead!&quot;) I have no interest in trying anything new there.
I haven&apos;t eaten fast food since November so any of it would probably taste horrible to me now anyway.
/still fat, but down almost 100 lbs 
   
 
 Silly Jesus 2012-04-02 09:38:00 AM 
 Confabulat : Teknowaffle: propasaurus: Meanwhile, places like Five Guys are thriving by just serving really good burgers instead of frappes and smoothies. Hell, In n Out has a basic menu of burgers, fries, shakes and soft drinks, and there&apos;s always a line of cars down the street.
Make a really effin&apos; good Whopper and ditch the frappes, salads and other novelty items.

Pretty much this.

Somewhere along the line, some marketing idiot said &quot;you know what people love? Choice. Why do one thing well, when we can do dozens terribly so people don&apos;t have to go anywhere else?&quot;. It is the Wal-Martization of fast food.

Hell, go to your local candy aisle. Think back to the early 90s and the Reese&apos;s line. There were cups, and then pieces. That was it. And both were delicious. Around 1996 came the Nutrageous, which completed the peanut butter candy family. Bite-sized hard candies, 2 bite cups, and then a bar. A happy family.

Then, as 2000 started to approach, it started to get insane with Reese&apos;s products. White chocolate, dark chocolate, fast break, sticks, whipps. None of them filled a void in the product line. I have never seen anyone actually buy one of these other products.

But we like the illusion of choice I guess and that is what matters in our pitiful lives.

Yep. If I drive into an Arby&apos;s it&apos;s because I have an odd craving for a roast beef sandwich. I don&apos;t want to spend 5 minutes perusing the menu to figure out the new offers, and if the guy in front of me at the drive-thru tries, I&apos;ll honk my horn because what kind of idiot figures out what to order when they pull up the menu at Arby&apos;s.

Same thing with Burger King. Deal with what you have. Make a better Whopper and fix your fries. McDonald&apos;s beats you for some pretty simple reasons. I walk into McDonald&apos;s knowing what I might want, and knowing what I&apos;ll get.They&apos;ve gotten really good at that. 

The only roast beef I enjoy is attached to a young lady. 
   
 
 Fizpez 2012-04-02 09:57:44 AM 
 Wife sent me to BK on Saturday because she loves the Onion rings with zesty sauce.... they were SO awful she mentioned that we might never eat there again.

I tasted one - flavor was 100% semi burned breading (although they didnt look burned). There was zero actual onion flavor.... I still like their double cheese burger but that&apos;s probably about it.... 
   
 Displayed 50 of 186 comments 
 First | « | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | » | Last | Show all 
 View Voting Results: Smartest and Funniest 
 Redisplay/refresh comments 
 
 This thread is closed to new comments. 

 Submit a Link»    Like Fark! +1 Fark! Follow @fark on Twitter Business via RSS 
 
 Top Links Top Comments Top Submitters Press/Publicity 
 Headlines of the Week 
 All Latest Fark Forum Link Voting Sports Forum Fark Blogs Geek Forum Fark Book Entertainment Forum Fark Travel Guide Politics Forum Fark Parties Fark Party Forum Fark Chat Photoshop Forum PS/Photo Browser Farktography Forum Fark Quiz 
 From the Fark Shop : 
 
F-cking Llamas 
iPlunge Phone Stand 
3 Ring Binder Mighty Wallet 
Indiana Bones and the Dead Who Consume 
 More from the Fark Shop »  
 Stories from our partner sites: 

 
 Jackie Chan Hates the Rush Hour Movies! 
 Even Indy&apos;s BluRay Set Is Ashamed of... 
 How Apple Works 
 11 Terrifying Ventriloquist Dummies 
 More news at Scribol» 

 
 Va. man wins second lottery in 3 months 
 Tom Brady stares down CVS customers 
 Woman receives ticket for cursing 
 Man sues over middle finger arrest 
 More news at UPI» 

 
 Steven Tyler -- I&apos;m QUITTING&apos;America... 
 Brendan Fraser -- Sued for Allegedly... 
 TMZ Live: Joe Paterno ... NAILED by I... 
 Penn State Apologizes for Sandusky Sc... 
 More news at TMZ» 

 
 Hitman: Absolution&quot;The Streets of Ho... 
 Official Disney Epic Mickey 2: The Po... 
 Official Show Floor Photos From Comic... 
 Guild Wars 2 Beta Key Giveaway -- Pla... 
 More news at G4TV» 

 
Also on Fark

 Main Christian and Muslim scholars unite to save you from the evils of hotel porn. See? We can all get along    ( religion.blogs.cnn.com ) »  (27 comments) Sports Can Bubba Ray handle the 3 Faces of Joseph Park? Will Rob Van Dam beat Samoa Joe and get higher... in the Bound For Glory standings? Is that horrible Dixie/AJ Styles/CM Punk&apos;s sister angle finally over? It&apos;s TNA Impact, 7 PM on Spike    ( impactwrestling.com ) »  (34 comments) Business McDonald&apos;s huge Olympic $ponsor$hip demands that all competing retailers surrender their french fries    ( news.com.au ) »  (89 comments) Geek A history of HTML5, from conception to adoption    ( visual.ly ) »  (5 comments) Entertainment Jennifer Lopez wants to leave American Idol, behind    ( eonline.com ) »  (14 comments) Politics Conservative reporter says that by fighting to preserve women&apos;s reproductive rights and access to birth control, Democrats have insulted women by&quot;reducing them to sexual beings&quot;    ( rawstory.com ) »  (72 comments) Video Jesus Christ blamed for huge gas explosion in Ohio (language is NSFW)    ( liveleak.com ) »  (18 comments) 

 Fark :: Main | Sports | Business | Geek | Entertainment | Politics | Video Total Fark :: TotalFark | TF Discussion | All | Commented | Top Voted | Greenlit FArQ :: About Us | Quick Answers | FarkIt | Posting Rules | Farkisms Contests :: Photoshop | Farktography | VideoEdit | Caption Buy Fark :: Headline Shirts | Fark Book | Fark Store 

 Submit a Link» 

Copyright©1999 - 2012 Fark, Inc | Last updated: Jul 12 2012 17:31:51
 Contact Us   |   Report a bug/error msg   |   Terms of service/legal/privacy policy 
 Runtime: 0.221 sec (220 ms)
	</body>
</document>
