<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006091" url="http://www.thatsfit.com/2009/11/18/food-addict-binges-eats-junk-from-trash-joins-aerobics-class-loses-275-pounds/" time="2012-07-12-22:46" support="4" score="0.0048470731151453875" bingtitle="After Eating Food from the Trash, Man Loses 275 Pounds - That&apos;s Fit" webtitle="After Eating Food from the Trash, Man Loses 275 Pounds - That&apos;s Fit">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="51"/>
	<description>After Eating Food from the Trash, Man Loses 275 Pounds Posted on Nov 18th 2009 5 ... and milkshakes for lunch; and a family-of-four-size meal from a fast-food restaurant for ...</description>
	<body>
		Click here to visit the new home of that&apos;s fit! 
Hot on HuffPost Healthy Living:

 Cherie Lost 85 Pounds: &apos;I&apos;m Still Me, But Healthier&apos; Gina Ryder: We Tried It: Jackie Warner&apos;s Workout 
   
 AOL.com MAIL 
 En Español That&apos;s Fit 
 Main Diet 
 Diet Diet Reviews Recipe Rehab with Tanya Zuckerbrot Too Good To Be Food with Keri Glassman Jonny&apos;s Take Best Life with Bob Greene SELF Meal Plans 
 Fitness 
 Fitness Workouts DVD Reviews Fit or Fiction Fit After 40 Fit Family Fit Travel Men&apos;s Fitness Running Walking We Tried it Yoga 
 Celebrity 
 Celebrities Interviews Biggest Loser 
 Success&amp;Motivation 
 Success&amp;Motivation Success Stories Tipping the Scales Better Body Better Living 
 America Takes It Off Experts 
 Denise Austin Jonny Bowden Keri Glassman Mandy Ingber Liz Neporent Harley Pasternak Tanya Zuckerbrot 
 Videos 

 Send Feedback 
 
 After Eating Food from the Trash, Man Loses 275 Pounds 
 Posted on Nov 18th 2009 5:00PM by Deborah Dunham Filed Under: Diet&amp;Weight Loss Email This 
Visit msnbc.com for Breaking News , World News , and News about the Economy 
 


When Gregg McBride stepped on the scale one day, he thought it was broken. He later discovered the &quot;error&quot; message it displayed did not mean it was broken after all -- it just didn&apos;t go over 450 pounds, which was how much Gregg weighed at the time.

The 36-year-old&apos;s struggle with weight began in early childhood when his parents told him he couldn&apos;t eat junk food . But instead of setting a healthy example, this strict diet only hurt Gregg, so much so that he would steal money from his father&apos;s wallet to buy junk food and secretly scarf it down. &quot;They thought they were helping,&quot; Gregg told the Today Show . &quot;But in hindsight, I can see that they created a forbidden fruit. I ate junk food like it was going out of style.&quot;

Gregg&apos;s food addiction continued to get worse over the next 30 years. He was consuming nearly 9,000 calories a day on a menu that included soda for breakfast; several cartons of Chinese food and milkshakes for lunch; and a family-of-four-size meal from a fast-food restaurant for dinner, with a whole bag of cookies for dessert.

Despite Gregg&apos;s many attempts to lose the weight, nothing stuck .&quot;I tried every diet out there: the wacky ones, the public ones, the dangerous ones ,&quot; he said. &quot;But I just kept getting bigger and bigger.&quot;

Gregg even tried a liquid fast where he didn&apos;t consume solid food for weeks. But when he spotted a half-eaten bag of potato chips in his trash, he stared at it for an hour before finally reaching in and devouring it.

While he was known as the &quot;funny fat guy&quot; to his friends, there was nothing funny about the way Gregg felt about himself. &quot;It took every ounce of courage to walk into a room and not feel judged,&quot; he said. After college while job hunting, he said interviewers wouldn&apos;t even look him in the eye. &quot;I felt like I had a disease that no one wanted.&quot;

Finally one day a co-worker told Gregg, &quot;Just stop eating so much!&quot; Gregg admits he was mad at first, but somehow those words resonated with him and became his mantra .

Gregg began exercising his body and exercising better control over food. His daily intake went from mounds of junk food to small portions of healthy food totaling just 1,700 calories. He even signed up for an aerobics class with a group of women who became some of his biggest fans. &quot;I had a support system of strangers,&quot; Gregg said. &quot;It was amazing.&quot;

Today, Gregg has lost a total of 275 pounds and is known as a &quot;show-stopper&quot; on the Joy Fit Club . He&apos;s still funnier than ever, making light of the fact that America saw his &quot; man boobs &quot; in a &quot;before&quot; photo and ecstatic that he can now buy jeans where &quot;real people&quot; shop. He is also working on a book about his weight loss journey. The title? &quot;Just Stop Eating So Much!&quot;

 Click on the gallery below to see more amazing transformations. 

 http://xml.channel.aol.com/xmlpublisher/fetch.v2.xml?option=expand_relative_urls&amp;dataUrlNodes=uiConfig,feedConfig,localizationConfig,entry&amp;id=660726&amp;pid=660725&amp;uts=1258572858 http://www.aolcdn.com/ke/media_gallery/v1/ke_media_gallery_wrapper.swf Weight Loss Success By Mary Kearl 

 Mother-Daughter Diet Duo: Sherrie and Courtney Harris, Before 

 Sherrie&apos;s Starting Weight: 285 Lbs
 Courtney&apos;s Starting Weight: 217 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: For both, most meals consisted of fast food, fried foods and carb-heavy sides like mac and cheese and mashed potatoes. Neither paid attention to portion sizes. &quot;Exercise was changing the channels on the remote, or going up the stairs to watch TV in our rooms as we ate M&amp;M&apos;s or Cheez-Its,&quot; Sherrie adds. Provided by Sherrie Harris 
 Double the Weight Loss Success 


 By Mary Kearl 

 Mother-Daughter Diet Duo: Sherrie and Courtney Harris, Before 

 Sherrie&apos;s Starting Weight: 285 Lbs
 Courtney&apos;s Starting Weight: 217 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: For both, most meals consisted of fast food, fried foods and carb-heavy sides like mac and cheese and mashed potatoes. Neither paid attention to portion sizes. &quot;Exercise was changing the channels on the remote, or going up the stairs to watch TV in our rooms as we ate M&amp;M&apos;s or Cheez-Its,&quot; Sherrie adds.

Provided by Sherrie Harris

 Mother-Daughter Diet Duo: Sherrie and Courtney Harris, After 

 Sherrie&apos;s Current Weight: 138 Lbs
 Courtney&apos;s Current Weight: 151 Lbs
 Why Weight Watchers? &quot;My attitude towards diet and fitness has done a full 180! I am well aware now of what &apos;portion control&apos; means! It&apos;s all about portion control in actuality. With Weight Watchers, I can have whatever I want, however, [the question is] whether or not I want to spend the points for whatever the item is. I treat my points allotment as a checkbook. Would I buy something at full price or wait until it goes on sale? I try always to get the most bang for my points,&quot; says Sherrie.
 Why Losing Together Helped: &quot;Because if I got discouraged and felt I couldn&apos;t do it, I could go to Mama, and we would get through it together,&quot; Courtney says.
Sherrie adds, &quot;Courtney is a culinary student and does 95 percent of the cooking in our house. She was doing the cooking when I started Weight Watchers and would call me at work and ask what I wanted for dinner. We would discuss the healthy way to prepare it, and it was done ... So it has encompassed my entire family.&quot;

Provided by Sherrie Harris

 Successful Spouses: Cathy and Pat Sullivan, Before 

 Cathy&apos;s Starting Weight: 217 Lbs
 Patrick&apos;s Starting Weight: 257 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: No breakfast; no real meal for lunch -- just junk food like chips, crackers and fast food; and dinner consisted of fatty foods, few vegetables and fruits, and dishes served with sauce or gravy.

Provided by Cathy Sullivan

 Successful Spouses: Cathy and Pat Sullivan, After 

 Cathy&apos;s Current Weight: 164 Lbs
 Patrick&apos;s Current Weight: 185 Lbs
 Why Weight Watchers? &quot;Just being in a room with other people in the same situation [helped]. Plus, it was encouraging to listen to other people&apos;s stories and ideas, and to share our own insights,&quot; Cathy explained.
 Why Losing Together Helped: &quot;Because I wasn&apos;t trying to cook for me and then something else for my family,&quot; says Cathy. &quot;Because we both wanted to feel better and look better, and we were both on the same page all the way around. We were able to support each other in every aspect.&quot;
 Tip for Those Going Solo: &quot;If you can commit yourself to doing it, then great. But if you want extra incentive, extra motivation and a better chance of taking the weight off and keeping it off -- then try it with someone. You are not alone -- you have a support system, even if it is just one other person. In the end, you are more motivated because you want to prove to this other person that yes, you can do it!&quot;

Provided by Cathy Sullivan

 Twin Sisters Fabiana and Simona Dixon, Before 

 Fabiana&apos;s Starting Weight: 197 Lbs
 Simona&apos;s Starting Weight: 197.4 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: &quot;We would wake up and go to McDonald&apos;s for an Egg McMufffin with two hash browns and a glass of orange juice. Then we would each have a bagel with extra cream cheese to hold us over until lunch, when we would go to Chipotle and have the steak burrito with everything (not to mention a side of chips and guacamole each). Around 3 or 4 p.m. we would have a couple of candy bars and a bag of chips each (Munchos or Doritos with a king-size Twix and/or Kit Kat bar). For dinner we would eat two baskets of chips with salsa, soup and a bean and rice burrito, a chicken enchilada and rice and beans. We would then hit up Baskin-Robbins for a double-scoop hot fudge sundae. We had as many calories in a day as we now have in a week! This was our starting point and our rock bottom,&quot; the sisters explained in an e-mail.

Courtesy of Fabiana and Simona Dixon

 Fabiana and Simona Dixon, After 

 Fabiana&apos;s Current Weight: 149.6 Lbs
 Simona&apos;s Current Weight: 147.2 Lbs
 Why Weight Watchers? &quot;Weight Watchers taught us how to stop dieting -- which in our opinion means a temporary solution -- and start living, which is a change in lifestyle. They helped us get to the core of our issues and find out why we find comfort in food. Only after these issues are addressed can a permanent change truly be made,&quot; the sisters explained.
 Why Losing Together Worked: &quot;Having a partner to lose weight with ... keeps you accountable, provides support and keeps you motivated. You don&apos;t want to let them, or yourself, down ...&quot;
 Accountability: &quot;Going to the gym with someone gives you less opportunity for excuses. Plus, you know if you don&apos;t go, that person will be calling and calling you to get you to come.&quot;
 No Cheating Allowed: &quot;On bad days or days when one of us feels discouraged, one will deter the other from hitting the Taco Bell drive-thru and instead suggest a walk or making Mexican food at home, with fat-free beans and fat-free sour cream. You would be amazed at how good you feel that you didn&apos;t &apos;cheat&apos; that day!&quot;
 Staying Motivated: &quot;You see the other one&apos;s losses on the scale and if they can do it, you can too!&quot;
 Keeps You on Your Toes: &quot;Working out together brings out a little of our competitive sides, and we then push one another to run that extra two minutes, sprint that much harder, lift that extra five pounds or play that extra game of basketball.&quot;

Courtesy of Fabiana and Simona Dixon

 Amy Hess (Partnered With Her Weight Watchers Team), Before 

 Starting Weight: 212 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: &quot;[I ate] lots of fast food and restaurant take-out. I never felt like I was done with a meal unless I was very full. And every meal consisted of an appetizer, main course and dessert.&quot;

Provided by Lynette Giles McMillin

 Amy Hess (Partnered With Her Weight Watchers Team), After 

 Current Weight: 155 Lbs
 Why Weight Watchers? &quot;If a day goes by that I don&apos;t get a workout in that was planned, I feel slighted, cheated out of that time. Trying new foods, many of which are suggested at meetings and in our group, has shown me so many new options and made me realize that I like more variety than I imagined.&quot;
 Why Losing Together Helps: &quot;Working out with a partner makes the time go by faster. I have someone there cheering me on -- [it also builds up] my competitive side, which also makes the workouts more exciting. It&apos;s easier to fight the good fight when you have reinforcements.&quot;

Provided by Lynette Giles McMillin

 Lynette McMillin (Partnered With Her Weight Watchers Team), Before 

 Starting Weight: 158 Lbs
 Typical Pre-Diet Day: &quot;First, I would drink Coca-Cola all throughout the day. I would go for days not remembering my last glass of water. If I ate breakfast, it was Chick-fil-A biscuits with hash browns or a sugary cereal. Lunch was usually large portions of leftovers from the night before, or nibbles of chicken nuggets off of the kids&apos; plates with cookies, chips and candies throughout the day. Dinner [consisted of] meat-heavy dishes and lots of potatoes or pasta. It would be pizza and fast foods if it was a busy night ... and after the kids were finally in bed, let the snacking begin!&quot;

Provided by Lynette Giles McMillin

 Lynette McMillin (Partnered With Her Weight Watchers Team), After 

 Current Weight: 122 Lbs
 Why Weight Watchers? &quot;I needed to see people who were transparent in their struggle so I didn&apos;t feel like such a loser in this area of my life. I also needed to see people who were succeeding, so that I knew it would be possible to reach my goals. At the Weight Watchers meetings there were beginners, people who were still losing, people who were backsliding and people who had already reached goal -- I needed every one of their stories!&quot;
 Why Losing Together Helped: &quot;I am a very busy mom of four who is not used to spending time and energy on herself. If I had tried to do this alone, I would have quit very early in my program. When I started asking these girls to hold me accountable, they helped turn this discipline and new lifestyle into fun. They encouraged me when I had a bad week, gave me new recipes, exercised with me when I didn&apos;t think I could work out, slapped me around when I started to backslide and make dumb choices and cheered my successes in a way that made me feel that this time and effort I was finally spending on myself was worth it.&quot;

Provided by Lynette Giles McMillin

 

 21 Comment Tags: dieting , gregg mcbride , GreggMcbride , joy fit club , JoyFitClub , just stop eating so much , JustStopEatingSoMuch , weight loss , WeightLoss Email This 
Around the Web
 
 Women&apos;s History Month: Inspiring Women in Their 20s (College Candy)
 
 Get Wow Arms With This Yoga Sequence (FitSugar)
 
 10 Relatively Easy Things to Give Up (Blisstree)
 
 3 Secrets to Craving a Healthy Diet (Fit Bottomed Girls)
 
Related Videos
 
   Losing Weight - Eating Less   Losing Weight - Eating Out   Losing Weight - Eat More and Lose Weight   How to Lose Weight by Eating Organic 
     
Reader Comments (Page 1 of 1)

 
 Bleixen 11-22-2009 @ 8:26PM 
 
What did you do to loss weight? I am 33 years old and I have two kids, I agree when you say that after your second baby you couldnt get back to your normal weight because it is happening to me right now. Can you give a hand to find a way to loss all that weight i get extra on me??? thank you

 reply 
 
 bill 11-21-2009 @ 2:38PM 
 
I was fat from age 5 to 17. I&apos;m age 50 now. I just started exercising more at age 17. I&apos;m a lifelong non-smoker but ex second-hand smoker when I was a kid.

Laws of physics apply to the human body. When you take in excess energy and do not use it, the energy will be put in some other form, which means more body fat, which will be stored until used (burned). Some of us prefer to spend part of each day devoted to burning that stored energy through exercise. Others are sedentary and cannot burn it off faster than they consume more energy (more food consumed).

 reply 
 
 Callie 11-21-2009 @ 3:08PM 
 
That&apos;s not even the same guy in the before and after pictures. Eyebrows don&apos;t change with weight loss, nor does a persons smile.

 reply 
 
 Beth 11-21-2009 @ 3:58PM 
 
I agree it isnt the same person. Different nose, different smile


 
 Yelena 11-22-2009 @ 3:10PM 
 
It&apos;s called plucking your eyebrows, and people can have different smiles at different times. It&apos;s really stupid to think that they would put pictures of different people. Why would they do that?


 
 Amy 11-21-2009 @ 6:25PM 
 
You people are crazy - it is the same guy. You don&apos;t realize how much someone changes when they lost that much weight. His smile is different because it is REAL and he is happy with himself now. I can only dream to reach that level of satisfaction someday. Good for you! Keep up the great new habits and keep that weight off - you are a true inspiration!


 
 LillieFaerie 11-23-2009 @ 4:48AM 
 
Callie: Faces do change, and do the rest of the body parts. I used to work with Weight Watchers and saw several persons who minimized their body size change so much that it was difficult to recognize the individual as the same person. Muscle vs. fat change facial features drastically and perhaps a smile is more full due to the fact that he&apos;s estatic with his accomplishments. His hair and eyebrows will change either due to coloration or just because he&apos;s out and doing things in the sun all the time. My kids went from toeheads to dark brown from a move from sun country to the north.

It is true, the easiest way to loose weight is to eat less and be exercise more. What a wonderful accomplishment and here is hoping that he maintains his accomplishment through conscious enjoyment of what he eats and what he does.

 reply 
 
 J Katz 11-21-2009 @ 3:44PM 
 
Not eating so much does work. I started putting javanu protein creamer in my coffee in between meals and helped my gorging at meal time. Also lots of water.

 reply 
 
 don 11-21-2009 @ 4:42PM 
 
yeah he did the right thing strict diet and exercise i bet he didnt take any magic pills or and programs online guaranteeing results, but the keyword is diet is you dont have a good diet dont expect to lose weight

dont believe any ads online that say&apos;&apos;get ripped in 4 weeks&apos;&apos; or &apos;&apos;lose 1lb a day by following these secrets&apos;&apos; those ads are bulls**t and wont work

 reply 
 
 Gregg 11-21-2009 @ 5:15PM 
 
I was 476 lbs and now I am 397 lbs. It&apos;s slow and tedious to lose weight but the advice is correct. I f you eat less, you can lose the weight. I do have to say, I thought the two pics weren&apos;t of the same person. And did he have surgery to remove all the left over sagging skin?

 reply 
 
 maggie252 11-21-2009 @ 5:16PM 
 
Congratulations to him for his weight loss. That is truly fantastic that he was able to change his eating and start to exercise and lose the weight and to keep it off. I wish him continued good luck wiwth his new healthy lifestyle.

 reply 
 
 davon africa 11-21-2009 @ 5:28PM 
 
We could see the women so excited. Did you notice when he came out how they were all glancing at him below his waist. These women are really bad. Now he will have trouble trying to get away from the women and gays. Good Luck.

 reply 
 
 Carolyn 11-21-2009 @ 5:53PM 
 
&quot;Just stop eating so much!&quot; Eureka! Why didn&apos;t I think of that! Now that the &quot;secret&quot; has been told, no one will ever had a weight problem again! Seriously, what a lame freakin&apos; article.

 reply 
 
 ida 11-21-2009 @ 6:03PM 
 
MORE POWER TO YOU ! LONG LONG LIFE FILLED WITH JOY AND SUCESS ! BLESSINGS

 reply 
 
 Chris Robinson 11-21-2009 @ 6:07PM 
 
what should all the people that are overweight and exercising and not losing weight do??? You mean he never tried to eat less and exercise. give me a break


 
 LuckeeK7 11-21-2009 @ 6:41PM 
 
That&apos;s sad that that guy couldn&apos;t find a way ( or wasn&apos;t instructed) to just portion control his favorite foods and add healthy food in.

And that nutritionist drives me nuts. It is nutritionist like her that had me yo yo dieting for years. The kind that expects everyone who wants to get slim to be scared to death of McDonalds for the rest of their lives!

There is a middle ground you know!

 reply 
 
 Sally Hiatt 11-22-2009 @ 11:53AM 
 
What is the weight loss secret this guy had? Obviously He is still keeping it a secret. Thats all well and good for somebody thats a big eater, cutting back and eating better, but it doesnt work for a lot of people. For some of us, you can cut down, cut back, cut out and cut calories, and still stay fat. Still waiting for the real secret. Tired of dieting and starving and avoiding and being hungry. Tired of explaining why the weight wont come off, mainly because I dont know why it wont come off. Dont eat fast food, dont drink soda, stay home and avoid restaurants. Dont buy cookies and ice cream and all the things people use like chips and dips and candy and goodies. Been to every Dr. and kept logs on every bite and they cant figure it out. I feel bad for every overweight person out there taking so much flack for something they may not be able to help. I expect to hear a lot of flack over this, but you have to live it to know what your talking about


 reply 
 
 suchagooddog 11-21-2009 @ 7:55PM 
 
i knew mr. mcbride about 15 years ago. while you may be inspired to read of his weight loss, you&apos;ll also find it interesting to hear that he&apos;s one of the most self-involved, egotistical, make that TYPICAL &apos;hollywood&apos; types that put the fear of god into middle america. hey gregg, if you&apos;re reading this -- ran into drew several years ago, so glad to hear he finally wised up and saw you for who/what you really are and is living a happy life with you no where in it

 reply 
 
 kyle76066 11-21-2009 @ 8:01PM 
 
GOOD FOR HIM!!!
Too bad there are so many &apos;haters&apos; and scammers that attempt to take his thunder. Read some of these posts.......really sad people. Sad, sad, sad.

 reply 
   ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
   Newsletter   RSS Feed   Twitter   Facebook 
 
Share Your Success Story
 Jupiter Images 
Have you lost weight and kept it off? We want to know how you did it and what keeps you inspired!
 Share Your Success Story   
 
 
 Workout Generator 
Customize your fitness routine and get the result you want.
 Dining Out Guide 
Make healthy choices wherever you are eating.
 How Many Calories? 
Find nutritional info for your favorite recipes.
   
 
 HealthyLiving: What it&apos;s like to go completely off the grid http://t.co/VK7lmzxH #unplugandrecharge Thu, 12 Jul 2012 20:03:01 +0000 from twitterfeed HealthyLiving: 11 signs you need to change the way you communicate http://t.co/Em2KGLPk Thu, 12 Jul 2012 19:14:00 +0000 from twitterfeed HealthyLiving: 11 fruits and vegetables we should be eating -- and why http://t.co/J5IQ1iak Thu, 12 Jul 2012 18:29:01 +0000 from twitterfeed HealthyLiving: INFOGRAPHIC: How long ago did you buy your bedding? http://t.co/N3zaDaZj Thu, 12 Jul 2012 17:44:00 +0000 from twitterfeed HealthyLiving: Are you one of those people who thinks they have every disease? How to cope with hypochondria http://t.co/iohU7JXI Thu, 12 Jul 2012 17:03:01 +0000 from twitterfeed follow us on twitter 
Sites We Love
 
 
 FEED 
 The Popularity Contest: Why Losers Might Finish First 10 Signs a Fitness Gadget is a Gimmick 
 More from DailySpark.com 
 
 FEED 
 The Biggest Loser Workout 3 Exercises for Athletic Fitness 
 More from LIVESTRONG.COM 
 
 FEED 
 10 Tips to Cope With Psoriasis Sleep Better with Fibromyalgia 
 More from Everyday Health 
 
 FEED 
 Five on 5 with Grace Potter! Five on 5: 4th of July Tips from Chef Katie Lee 
 More from Self 
 
 FEED 
 How to Splurge and Still Lose Weight Fat-Blasting, Full-Body Tabata Workout 
 More from Fitsugar Also on AOL That&apos;s Fit Send Feedback 
Quick Links

 21 Pounds in 21 Days Diet Belly-Bloating Foods Low Calorie Foods Lose Belly Fat Flat Ab Moves
 Lose Water Weight 
 
More That&apos;s Fit

 Celebrity Diets Diet Reviews Fitness DVDs Workouts Recipe Makeovers Yoga Poses 
 
More Healthy Living

 Health News Everyday Health Healthy Beauty Healthy Recipes Healthy Families Challenge Mind&amp;Body 
 
More AOL Lifestyle

 DIY Life Heidi Klum on AOL Home Decor KitchenDaily My Daily Pet Health 
 
More from AOL

 Salud Games Huffington Post Movies Television Travel 
 HuffPost Healthy Living. 
 About Us Site Map Privacy Policy Terms of Service Trademarks AOL Downloads Advertise With Us About Our Ads 
 ©2012 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
