<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006833" url="http://www.daytondailynews.com/blogs/content/shared-gen/blogs/dayton/taste/entries/2009/06/04/sonic_drivein_open_less_than_a.html" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="5" score="0.013189966128232906" bingtitle="DaytonDailyNews: Dayton, Ohio, news and information" webtitle="DaytonDailyNews: Dayton, Ohio, news and information">
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Pay Newspaper Bill; Newspaper Vacation Stop; Start Newspaper ... It is the only fast food restaurant in Dayton that serves ... Last time I had to give my order three times and ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe now Customer Service 
 
 Register Now 

 Sign In E-mail preferences 
 Flash player is required to view weather conditions. Download 
 DaytonDailyNews.com 
 
 Home 
 Site map 
 Local News 
 Community Crime News Ohio News Nation&amp;World News Summary Obituaries Weather Traffic&amp;Maps Past Articles Politics Local Data Ohio Lottery Press Releases Special Reports 
 Sports 
 High Schools Cincinnati Reds UD Flyers WSU Raiders Miami RedHawks OSU Buckeyes Dayton Dragons Dayton Bombers Cincinnati Bengals Cleveland Browns Local Auto Racing Pro Auto Racing Scores&amp;Stats 
 Business 
 Stock Quotes Business Leads Local Directory Business Events Build Your Own Ad B2B Magazine 
 Entertainment 
 Movies Things To Do Restaurants Music Bars&amp;Clubs Theater&amp;Arts TV Comics&amp;Games Kings Island Recreation Amusement Parks 
 Life 
 Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Think Education 937Moms Health Technology NIE 
 Opinion 
 Blogs Mike Peters Message Boards 
 Photos&amp;Video 
 Photos Videos Photo&amp;Page Reprints 
 Help 
 Pay Newspaper Bill Newspaper Vacation Stop Start Newspaper Delivery FAQ Our Policies Contact Us Photo&amp;Page Reprints Past Articles Legal Notices 
 Jobs Cars Homes Classifieds&amp;Deals Local Directory 
 site web 
 Classifieds Autos Real Estate Jobs Shopping 
 
 Photos More... 
 Child endangerment case 2012 ESPYs show 2012 ESPYs red carpet Latest featured videos from DaytonDailyNews.com 
Blogs
 
Blogs

 : 
 Miami, Sinclair pair up for information health technology degree Jul. 12 : 
 Is The Beast king? Coaster to be pitted against others on show Sunday Jul. 12 : 
 Middletown&apos;s Marshall, Trotwood&apos;s Burrows named Champion Gridiron Kings Jul. 12 
 
 &gt; See all blogs 
 E-mail this page Sonic Drive-In open less than a year closes | Taste: Dayton food and restaurants 
 Taste: Dayton food and restaurants 
   
About Taste: Dayton food and restaurants


Mark Fisher writes about restaurants, food and wine for the Dayton Daily News. If you have a news tip about a local restaurant, email Mark or call (937) 225-2258.


 



March 2011

 Sun Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31     

RSS Syndication

 XML Taste: Dayton food and restaurants 
 XML More &apos;DDN&apos; feeds 
 
Follow me

 Find Dayton-area restaurants My wine blog, Uncorked Lounge Lizards blog Leadbelly Boys blog ActiveDayton.com Miami Valley Restaurant Association Dayton Independents Ohio Restaurant Association Dayton Dining social network site 
 
Categories

 cooking classes&amp;cookbooks Food and health food and kids Food fights Food trends&amp;eating habits Grocery industry news Just for Fun Kitchen tips Local food news Local restaurant news New food items Reader feedback/surveys Recipes Restaurant closings Restaurant industry news Restaurant openings Restaurant promotions/giveaways Restaurant reviews Restaurant service Restaurant specials Something different 
 
More recent entries

 Dayton one of two U.S. test markets for new Tim Hortons lunch items New Italian restaurant at The Greene sets opening date Savona will pair four-course dinner with Sierra Nevada beers Benham&apos;s to host wine dinner Dayton restaurant owner pleads not guilty to 4 felony counts New cafe now open in Oakwood Perkins serves up free pancakes today, for a cause Boulevard Haus owner Eva Christian indicted on four felony counts Restaurant Week diners will choose from three price tiers this summer after popularity drops Two local restaurant chains make FastCasual.com&apos;s top 100 &apos;Movers&amp;Shakers&apos; list More entries... 

Archives

 March 28, 2011 March 22, 2011 March 21, 2011 March 18, 2011 March 16, 2011 March 15, 2011 March 13, 2011 More archives... 
 
 Home &gt; Blogs &gt; Taste: Dayton food and restaurants &gt; Archives &gt; 2009 &gt; June &gt; 04 &gt;Entry 

 Sonic Drive-In open less than a year closes 

By Mark Fisher | Thursday, June 4, 2009, 03:10 PM

PIQUA—A Sonic Drive-In that had been open just under a year has closed abruptly.

The restaurant at 1292 E. Ash St. apparently closed over the weekend or early this week, said Lisa Whittaker, director of the Piqua Area Chamber of Commerce, who learned of the closing on Tuesday.

“There was definitely no warning, and yes, I’m very surprised,”Whitaker said. City and chamber officials held a ribbon-cutting at the restaurant in late June 2008.

A man who answered the phone at the Piqua Sonic said he was cleaning up the restaurant and could not comment on the closing. Representatives of Houchens Industries , the Bowling Green, Kentucky company that is the franchise owner for other Sonic Drive-In restaurants in the Dayton area, did not immediately return phone and email requests for comment.

In April, a Houchens employee who oversees some Dayton-area Sonics told the Dayton Daily News that the company was more than halfway toward its goal of opening 29 restaurants in the Greater Dayton area. A Sonic opened a few days ago in Sidney, and another new Sonic at 7888 Brandt Pike in Huber Heights is scheduled to open soon.
 
 Permalink | Comments (47) | Post your comment | Categories: Restaurant closings 
 Tweet 
Comments
 
By 
 
 
 
 sonicker

June 10, 2009 3:32 PM | Link to this 

I love me some Sonic! The onion rings are SWEET BATTERED, that’s the meant-to-be flavor of them. It’s not the cooks fault. It’s the ingredients! Either you like them or you don’t. Oh well
 
By 
 
 
 
 sonicker

June 10, 2009 3:30 PM | Link to this 

Well, the onion rings are“sweet battered”so that explains the sweet thing. If you don’t like them, don’t order them! I’ve been eating Sonic for years
 
By 
 
 
 
 Sorry Beej

June 8, 2009 11:06 AM | Link to this 

You lost me when you said Sonic had great food. When you said that, your lecture lost all credibility.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Nancy

June 6, 2009 3:53 PM | Link to this 

Piqua location’s food was not good. After years of Sonic commercials and no restaurants in this area, my first visit was a big letdown. How can you ruin a fried tater tot?! Sidney store seems good so far. Too much growth in a bad economy maybe?
 
By 
 
 
 
 Chad

June 5, 2009 10:35 PM | Link to this 

Maybe if Obama and the Dems would stop taxing the“greedy corporations”so such they could stay open!!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 me

June 5, 2009 9:20 PM | Link to this 

not all sonics suck.you have a wait at most fast food restaurants,but the friendliness of the employees can ease the pain.it stinks these sonics had to close, but those who are criticizing them really should give it a rest. all fast food is a choice,don’t eat there but don’t criticize the jobs that pay for these kids to learn responsibility.patience is a virtue.
choice,don’t eat there but don’t cri
 
By 
 
 
 
 BEEJ

June 5, 2009 9:10 PM | Link to this 

Wow,easy to criticize Sonic, they have great food,the rings are an aquired taste but far from nasty.WC is what it is, kinda snack food if you me.Work fast food for a week, all of you critics that wait so long for service….you’ll learn that you too are not perfect and mistakes get made notl always.The closing ask me
 
By 
 
 
 
 priorsonicfan

June 5, 2009 8:43 PM | Link to this 

To David M, I don’t care if the staff is 50 or 15 the training and expectations should be the same. They should be at least competent enough to take a tater tot and drink order without messing up 3 times and still serving it incorrectly. If you want a successful business it begins with customer service and a quality product. The Sonic on Colonel Glenn has neither.
 
By 
 
 
 
 ArmChairEconomist

June 5, 2009 3:13 PM | Link to this 

Another fine example of keeping employees in the dark, then throwing them under the bus at the last possible second with no notice. There is no loyalty anymore, no on
 
By 
 
 
 
 Hawk

June 5, 2009 8:17 AM | Link to this 

No surprise, they came into this area too aggresively with too many openings in such a short time, just like Quizno’s. I tried the Piqua Sonic a couple months ago, I got tired of waiting in a non-moving drive-through so I left. I didn’t move for like 10 minutes. Still better than foodd-poisoning haven Jack in the Box.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Neonmoon

June 4, 2009 10:15 PM | Link to this 

Try a mocha java chiller. Yum, yum.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Doc

June 4, 2009 10:01 PM | Link to this 

I’m with ya, WC dude!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 White Castle

June 4, 2009 9:45 PM | Link to this 

For all of you who complain about WC’s burgers…Rest assured they’re 100% beef…Not every one’s cup of tea! I eat them 3/4 times a week for the last 40 years. And no my health is just fine as is my waistline. It’s all in moderation! Sonic??? Good drink deals but that’s about it!
 
By 
 
 
 
 sh

June 4, 2009 9:12 PM | Link to this 

my daughter got a banana split at sonic a while back…and they forgot the banana!!! how does that happen???
 
By 
 
 
 
 Doc

June 4, 2009 8:48 PM | Link to this 

To the White Castle haters-
Yes, much like your mother’s and you wife’s cooking, WC burgers are an acquired taste. But once your taste buds awaken and grow up, you’ll never want mom’s cooking again!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 David M.

June 4, 2009 7:16 PM | Link to this 

I for one think that Sonic is a great place to go. So what if they have bad Onion Rings. There are 50 other things on the menu to choose from. If you are just going to a restaurant for onion rings go to Red Robin. Plus, for the people that complain about the service, what do you expect? Sonic is not a fancy, sit down restaurant. You either eat at the tables outside, in your car or you take it home. You have teenagers and young adults taking the orders and making the orders. They are going to make mistakes. This is not a career for most of them. They want to get paid, plain and simple. If you dont like your order getting messed up then I would suggest not going to a fast food establishment. 

Also, for the people that Sonic is doomed to close because they get no business look no further than the McDonalds across the street from the Sonic in Kettering. That place is dead 5 days out of the week. 

I think the main reason that I like Sonic so much is the variety. It is the only fast food restaurant in Dayton that serves breakfast all day. And when it is hot out nothing is better than one of their Cranberry Limeades.
 
By 
 
 
 
 stuck

June 4, 2009 7:09 PM | Link to this 

Sonic is awful. I had gone to the one on Col. Glenn a couple of times and the drive thru line was ridiculous. They came out and told us we’d get faster service if we pulled into the carport…insane! The food was meh…For argument sake, I tried another one.. same crappy food (overpriced, at that) same slow service. The only saving grace is that they’ve got some neat drinks.
 
By 
 
 
 
 annoymous

June 4, 2009 6:16 PM | Link to this 

i worked for sonic in greenville and Englewood. the piqua store closing is a surprise to me cause the lat timei spoke with my freinds at those stores, there was no talk of closing any stores. so now i wonder if they willbe closing my local Sonic. I like the food at Sonic. I hope they reown the Piqua store.
 
By 
 
 
 
 sallie mae

June 4, 2009 6:12 PM | Link to this 

I WANT JACK IN THE BOX!!!!!!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 David

June 4, 2009 6:07 PM | Link to this 

I went to Sonic once and have never been back.The food was way overated The parking lot is always empty when I drive by. I think Sonic will eventually go the way of Rally’s. I can’t believe there will be two in .Huber within miles of each other. I expect one will close.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Pete

June 4, 2009 5:59 PM | Link to this 

I have tried several of the local Sonic restaurants and found the food good and the service good for a fast food restaurant. we should be concerned with all the local business and stop piling on. When McDnalds is the only choice left, I will choose not to eat out.
 
By 
 
 
 
 John

June 4, 2009 5:59 PM | Link to this 

You can’t really open several restaurants in one year. I think that kind of growth in this industry is way too fast.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Joe

June 4, 2009 5:46 PM | Link to this 

I have been told the Sonic in Urbana has closed as well. Open less then a year. oh well……
 
By 
 
 
 
 Bill

June 4, 2009 5:45 PM | Link to this 

I eat at the one in Clayton about twice a week and yet to have a complaint. Use to do white castle years ago in Cincinnati and was glad to see them in Dayton till I had one. lunch meat is thicker than their burger
 
By 
 
 
 
 T-Bonious Funk

June 4, 2009 5:42 PM | Link to this 

I also am sorry for the loss of jobs, but like a lot of folks, I am not surprised to hear that a Sonic has closed already. THE FOOD SUCKS!!! All the hype we heard from those who loved it, and the funny commercials lead up to a big old let-down. Nastiest. Onion Rings. Ever.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Ted

June 4, 2009 5:39 PM | Link to this 

To Doc…White Castle???? Mmmm crappy grey mystery meat. I prefer real hamburger on my hamberger.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Ted

June 4, 2009 5:28 PM | Link to this 

Sonic sucks…others don’t
 
By 
 
 
 
 BigJack

June 4, 2009 5:27 PM | Link to this 

I love me some Sonic!!! Glad to read that it wasn’t the Col. Glenn, Kettering or HH locations, cuz those are the ones I go to. As fast food goes you can’t beat it. I go to Sonic fairly often and have yet to experience the problems others have mentions. I hate onions of any kind, so I can’t speak to the ring issue, but their shakes, slushies, burgers, etc are da bomb!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 Notshocked

June 4, 2009 5:09 PM | Link to this 

Can’t say I’m surprised. I’d go there in the afternoon for the“Happy Hour”and wait forever being the only customer. Then my freeze would be all surripie. It sucked compaired to Troy and the others
 
By 
 
 
 
 William

June 4, 2009 4:50 PM | Link to this 

You know, there are a few of us out here who like Sonic….
 
By 
 
 
 
 Scooby does not

June 4, 2009 4:50 PM | Link to this 

So…who’s going to forward all these negative comments to the Sonic franchise people in BG, Kentucky? They probably have no idea…
 
By 
 
 
 
 michael

June 4, 2009 4:45 PM | Link to this 

I was not impressed after all of the good things I had heard about sonic! I thought the onion rings haa been dipped in sugar, i could not eat them and the food was not“tops”
 
By 
 
 
 
 The Dust

June 4, 2009 4:37 PM | Link to this 

Close them all and save your money. More unemployment coming to a neighbor near you.
 
By 
 
 
 
 oreo25

June 4, 2009 4:37 PM | Link to this 

White Castle? Yuck!! Tastes how wet cat food smells…I’d take sonic over that slop any day!
 
By 
 
 
 
 mtgolflady

June 4, 2009 4:31 PM | Link to this 

We used to love Sonic for a chili cheese dog and pink lemonade when we were in college at EKU in the early 80’s. I was excited to finally have them in Dayton. Boy was I in for a shock. Same experience of getting an incorrect order and the food was horrible. A smear of chili and a light sprinkle of cheese on the dog, and the same mess on the tator tots even though I didnt order the tots that way. Charged me almost $2.00 extra for the tot mess and havent been back since. Bring back the old Sonic chili cheese dog!
 
By 
 
 
 
 Scott

June 4, 2009 4:15 PM | Link to this 

Doesn’t surprise me. I think the food tastes like it came from a carnival. Don’t care for it at all in Kettering either.
 
By 
 
 
 
 susan

June 4, 2009 4:14 PM | Link to this 

Big surprise, there was never anyone there!
 
By 
 
 
 
 Unsure

June 4, 2009 4:14 PM | Link to this 

When I tried the onion rings I thought the same thing,‘what do they fry these in?’Kind of tastes like they add sugar to the batter. YUCK!!!!!
 
By 
 
 
 
 Scooby does not

June 4, 2009 4:11 PM | Link to this 

No surprise that the one in Piqua closed. Went there one time back in March. Sorry for those who lost jobs…but, wow.
 
By 
 
 
 
 LB

June 4, 2009 4:06 PM | Link to this 

I’m in agreement with priorsonicfan…Had my very first Sonic burger in the winter at the Col. Glenn location. I had to give my order 4 times and it still wasn’t correct when I got it. Then I was turned off at the taste of the fries and onion rings. What do they use for cooking oil? Whatever it is makes the fries/onion rings taste like donuts. If I want donuts, I’ll stop at the bakery. Never again for me.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Doc

June 4, 2009 4:01 PM | Link to this 

Huh. Your dog buried it,‘eh?
Mine wolfs‘em down almost as fast as me.
But I feel you.
I’d rather eat ka-ka than eat a sonic burger. :)
 
By 
 
 
 
 Michael

June 4, 2009 3:58 PM | Link to this 

They have one opening in Huber, thanks for the tip
 
By 
 
 
 
 cb

June 4, 2009 3:56 PM | Link to this 

good riddence. sonic is overpriced and not very good. i won’t ever go to one again.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Nursecilla

June 4, 2009 3:53 PM | Link to this 

There are way too many Sonics and they DO NOT have good food. We have tried 4 different ones and have never had anything that was even close to being good. I am sure more will close because when I pass by them, they are never busy.
Just becuase they are cheap to build, doesn’t mean they should build them everywhere. Give me Taco Bell anyday.

good.
 
By 
 
 
 
 priorsonicfan

June 4, 2009 3:51 PM | Link to this 

I fell in love with Sonic when I went out west years ago, so I was thrilled when they made their way to the Dayton area. That quickly ended when I visited the Sonic on Colonel Glenn. I’ve gone three times and each time was a disaster. Last time I had to give my order three times and it still came out incorrectly. It was cold which only enhanced the horrible flavor of whatever they are frying the tots in. It took forever and the staff that I dealt with seemed incompetent. If they don’t get their act together, I could see them closing as well. I certainly won’t be going back again and wouldn’t recommend it to anyone.
 
By 
 
 
 
 LW

June 4, 2009 3:46 PM | Link to this 

The one on Wilmington looks pretty busy when I go by there. I stopped in once and they had to have people directing traffic. Happy hour and your drinks are half price. White Castle.. I gave my dog one of those once. He buried it.
 
By 
 
 
 
 Doc

June 4, 2009 3:40 PM | Link to this 

Good. Maybe they’ll close the one on Wilmington Dr. in Kettering and BRING BACK White Castle…(I know; wishful thinking)
 
Post a comment
 
 Name: 
 

 E-mail * : 
 

Remember me? Yes No 

 Comments: 
 

 

 
 
*HTML not allowed in comments. Your e-mail address is required .
     Home | News | Sports | Business | Entertainment | Opinion | Life | Recreation | Photos&amp;Video | Cars | Jobs | Homes 
 Advertising Media Kit | Online Ad Studio | Advertiser Tools | Customer Service | Contact Us | Our Partners | RSS | Site Map 
 
Copyright©2011
Cox Media Group Ohio, Dayton, Ohio, USA. All rights reserved.

By using this site, you accept the terms of our Visitors Agreement and Privacy Policy . You may wish to note our other business policies .
	</body>
</document>
