<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006592" url="http://helpnewbies.com/receipt-printer/" time="2012-07-12-23:32" support="11" score="0.030362559571524346" bingtitle="Receipt Printer | Help For Newbies" webtitle="Receipt Printer | Help For Newbies">
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="10"/>
	<description>Receipt Printer - epson readyprint tmt direct thermal ... 8.07″ Depth 5.91″ 8.07″ 9-pin Paper end ... is high speed device for bank card, POS, fast food, restaurant and ...</description>
	<body>
		Help For Newbies 

Affiliate And Internet Marketing For Newbies
 
 
 Home Affiliate Marketing Computer Components Direct Mail Marketing Direct Response Advertising Direct Response Internet Marketing Direct Response Marketing Agency Direct Response Marketing Jobs Direct Response Online Marketing EMarketing Emotional Direct Response Marketing Internet Advertising Business Internet Marketing Resources Internet Marketing Secret Internet Marketing Small Business Internet Marketing System Internet Marketing Tips Keyboards, Mice&amp;Input Monitors&amp;Projectors Networking&amp;Communications Online Advertising Online Marketing Articles Online Marketing Course Online Marketing Jobs online marketing strategy Online Marketing Tips PC Desktops PC Laptops&amp;Netbooks Printer Supplies&amp;Accessories Printers 
 Copy Scan Printer Ribbon Print Factory Portable Photo Large Format Kit Video Canon Bjc Print Server Brother Dcp Ink System Usb Network Receipt Printer Code Reader Network Card Dell Printer Printer Copy Dvd Printer Service Manual Pin Printer Toner Cable Printhead Print Printer Cable Cable Black Wincor Nixdorf Fax Scanner Page Count Primera Bravo Main Logic Printer Printhead Color Laser Pages Printed Toner Cartridge 
 Scanners Search Marketing Social Media Marketing Agency Social Media Marketing Company Social Media Marketing Jobs Social Media Marketing Services Social Media Optimization Social Network Marketing Social Networking Software Technology Books&amp;Resources The Internet Marketing Company Viral Marketing Web Domains&amp;Services 
 
 
Receipt Printer
 
 

Point of Sale (POS) systems have now become the choice of business management for most retailers in managing their time in activities business day. The system point of sale is a computer replacing the traditional cash register can perform a variety of innovative features such the recording and tracking customer orders, transaction processing, management, loyalty programs, and credit card transactions flow, and management of store inventory.

The features found at the point of sale equipment are designed to improve and strengthen business operations. A major advantage of a POS is that it makes the shopping experience for consumers.
 
The following describes how the systems point of sale improves the shopping experience:

1. One characteristic that most consumers dislike shopping is waiting too long to checkout. Point of sale allows the equipment payment services faster thus reducing the amount time a client should expect to pay for their items.

2. Systems Point of Sale enables firms to offer programs reward loyalty. Research has shown that consumers appreciate these programs and are encouraged to return to work where they are a member of the loyalty program. Point of sale equipment allows effective management of these programs. The more often consumers go into a store, the more likely they are to buy other products or services. An example of this type of program is the&quot;points&quot;card program.

3. POS systems allow a company to manage their inventories and welcoming their customers buying preferences. The POS system allows you to view sales reports in real time in order to follow products that sell. You can stock your business with the most popular products.

4. Shoppers often become very frustrated when they see an error on their purchase receipt. Systems Point of Sale can make it more efficient and accurate transactions thus reducing the cases of customers&apos;complaints to incorrect transactions. It also reduces store, you go online.

5. Systems POS allow you to follow that Customers buying so you Can Learn more about your customers, their buying habits and personal preferences. This will allow you to better respond their shopping needs.

6. Because POS systems reduce the amount of staff time businesses must spend the execution of operations business, they can spend more time helping customers. Customers will be pleased with the personal attention.

7. The most technologies peak that is used with a POS system allows the treatment of a variety of credit cards, debit cards, gift cards, and the ability to process coupons. Customers prefer shopping in a store where there are more choices on how they pay for their items.

Keeping customers satisfied is essential to develop and maintain a successful business. And management, improved and enhanced business will result in a company more profitable. When you choose a selling point, we should examine how the system will improve Customers SHOPPING EXPERIENCE. Point Of Sale is a proven method to alleviate the shopping experience for consumers.

Not only are payment gateway services allowing consumers to experience a better shopping experience, but some of the offered merchant services also allow businesses to better manage their information. As retailers accept credit card , hassle of using cash is eliminated.

 Receipt Printer 
 

 
 
 
 
Epson Readyprint TM-T20 Direct Thermal Receipt Printer USB
 

$184.00
 

Epson’s cost-effective ReadyPrintTM T20 thermal printer is the latest addition to Epson’s line of energy-efficient POS printers. Based on Epson’s advanced printing technology, ReadyPrint was designed specifically to meet the needs of low volume retailers with basic POS printing functionality, high reliability and ease-of-use features. Epson ReadyPrint T20 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Rece… 

 
 
 
 

 


 

… 

 
 
 
 

 


 

… 

 
 
 
 
High-speed 58mm POS Receipt Thermal Printer USB Black
 

$49.50
 

Feature£º Communication interface optional parallel port or serial port Character can enlarge print, adjust character the line spacing printed Support of different densities bitmap and download of graphics printing Support for raster bitmap print In the driver printing (mode), it implement and call the hard word bank to high-speed printing technical parameters:Cashbox Control DC 12V/1A Prin… 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-T88V Thermal Receipt Printer (USB/Serial/PS180 Power Supply)
 

$282.00
 

The TM-T88V POS thermal printer is the latest addition to Epson’s industry-leading TM-T88 POS printer series. The TM-T88V delivers more speed and more reliability than ever before. It offers 50% faster printing of text and graphics than the TM-T88IV, 35% more reliability, new ease-of-use features and dual interfaces. In addition, the TM-T88V was the first POS thermal printer to be ENERGY STAR qual… 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-P60 Thermal Transfer Printer–Receipt Print
 

$469.99
 

The Mobilink TM-P60 Receipt Printer, built with Epson’s quality and reliability, is designed to meet the needs of both retail and hospitality industries for high-speed, on-the-go thermal receipt printing…. 

 
 
 
 
Six Hundred Receipts, Worth their Weight in Gold,
 

$15.47
 

This is a pre-1923 historical reproduction that was curated for quality. Quality assurance was conducted on each of these books in an attempt to remove books with imperfections introduced by the digitization process. Though we have made best efforts–the books may have occasional errors that do not impede the reading experience. We believe this work is culturally important and have elected to bri… 

 
 
 
 
Out of the kitchen into the house,: Receipts of Elizabeth Kinkead Battaile
 


 

… 
 
 
 
 
 
Samsung SRP-275C Receipt Printer
 

$181.99
 

Samsung SRP-275C Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Wasp WRP 8055 Receipt Printer
 

$329.49
 

Wasp WRP 8055 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
HP POS Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$640.49
 

HP POS Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer
 

$288.99
 

Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP113U Receipt Printer
 

$203.99
 

Star Micronics TSP113U Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CT-S2000 Receipt Printer
 

$261.12
 

Citizen CT-S2000 POS Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-350plusII Receipt Printer
 

$213.99
 

Bixolon SRP-350plusII Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-500CG Receipt Printer
 

$215.99
 

Bixolon SRP-500CG Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CD-S503 Receipt Printer
 

$235.99
 

Citizen CD-S503 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CD-S503 Receipt Printer
 

$259.99
 

Citizen CD-S503 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-350plusII Receipt Printer
 

$214.49
 

Bixolon SRP-350plusII Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP800Rx TSP847UIIRX Receipt Printer
 

$545.49
 

Star Micronics TSP800Rx TSP847UIIRX Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP800 TSP847IIU Receipt Printer
 

$399.99
 

Star Micronics TSP800 TSP847IIU Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP100 TSP143LAN Receipt Printer
 

$276.93
 

Star Micronics TSP100 TSP143LAN Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP650 TSP654 POS Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$188.49
 

Star Micronics TSP650 TSP654 POS Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics SP700 SP742 Receipt Printer
 

$228.99
 

Star Micronics SP700 SP742 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TUP500 TUP592-24 Receipt Printer
 

$429.99
 

Star Micronics TUP500 TUP592-24 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Seiko APU-9347-C02 Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$499.99
 

Seiko APU-9347-C02 Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics SP500 SP542 Receipt Printer
 

$214.49
 

Star Micronics SP500 SP542 Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP650 TSP654 POS Network Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$306.49
 

Star Micronics TSP650 TSP654 POS Network Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP650 TSP651 POS Network Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$219.99
 

Star Micronics TSP650 TSP651 POS Network Thermal Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-275A Dot Matrix Printer–Monochrome–Receipt Print
 

$156.94
 

Samsung Bixolon SRP-275AG Receipt Printer 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP651 Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Monoch
 

$172.49
 

Star Micronics TSP651 Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Monochrome 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon STP-103II Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Rec
 

$112.81
 

Bixolon STP-103II Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Receipt Print 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-F310 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Rece
 

$207.99
 

Bixolon SRP-F310 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Receipt Print 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP143ECO Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Mon
 

$209.99
 

Star Micronics TSP143ECO Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Monochrome 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP143IIU Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Mon
 

$225.99
 

Star Micronics TSP143IIU Direct Thermal Printer–Receipt Print–Monochrome 

 
 
 
 
Seiko DPU-S445 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Mobile–Receipt
 

$567.99
 

Seiko DPU-S445 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Mobile–Receipt Print 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-F310 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Rece
 

$212.49
 

Bixolon SRP-F310 Direct Thermal Printer–Monochrome–Desktop–Receipt Print 
 
 
 
 
 
Serial Usb Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$288.99
 

SERIAL USB THERMAL RECEIPT PRINTER 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SRP-500CG Receipt Printer
 

$398.77
 

BIXOLON SRP500C INKJET PRNT2CLR RECEIPT PRINTER SERIAL GREY A 

 
 
 
 
Seiko KPU-S347 Receipt Printer
 

$471.99
 

203 dpi 24 V DC 3.15″x Roll Paper 5.20″5.51″7.87 in/s 80 9.25″9.25″Height x 5.20″Width x 5.51″Depth EMI Standard: VCCI class ACEFCC class A Featuring Variable Paper Width Capacity Plus Paper Presenter and Programmable Retractor For kiosk printing applications where versatility and capacity are primary criteria, the KPU-S347 Receipt Printer subassembly is the ideal choice. The KPU-S347 Receipt Printer offers an adjustable paper width feature (2 1/4 inches to 31/4 inches), KPU-S347 Receipt Printer accommodate a large (9-inch) paper roll to reduce the time spent reloading paper and maximize efficiency. Plus, horizontal paper position. Cutter KPU-S347 Receipt Printer KPU-S347S-11V-E Receipt Print Seiko Seiko Instruments USA, Inc Thermal Transfer Printer Yes www.seikoinstruments.com 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon Samsung Receipt Printer Color Serial SRP270AG
 

$153.87
 

Bixolon Samsung Receipt Printer Color Serial SRP270AG 

 
 
 
 
Star Micronics TSP100 TSP143IIU Receipt Printer 39464210
 

$229.63
 

Star Micronics TSP100 TSP143IIU Receipt Printer 39464210 

 
 
 
 
Smart Buy Serial Usb Receipt Printer
 

$288.99
 

SMART BUY SERIAL USB RECEIPT PRINTER 

 
 
 
 
HP Hybrid POS Receipt Printer
 

$641.99
 

1 lpm 203 dpi MICR Direct Thermal Printer FK184AT HP Hewlett-Packard Hybrid POS Receipt Printer Monochrome Receipt Print Yes www.hp.com 

 
 
 
 
Samsung SRP-270C Receipt Printer
 

$221.99
 

0 lpm 110 V AC 220 V AC 40 5.87″5.87″Height x 5.91″Width x 8.07″Depth 5.91″8.07″9-pin Paper end sensor Reliability Auto-cutter: 1500000 cuts The SRP-270C combines high reliability, design quality and low price that the competition can’t match. Compatible with most leading systems, the SRP-270C has a full set of Windows drivers for plug and play installation. Specially SRP-270C is very suitable for the store manager to save running cost considerably and to purchase the receipt printer at low price. The SRP-270C is ideal for both POS receipt printing and remote printing for food and drink preparation orders in hospitality applications. Bixolon Bixolon America, Inc Cutter ESC/POS Gray Receipt Print SRP-270C Receipt Printer SRP-270CEG Thermal Transfer Printer www.bixolon.com 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-U295 Receipt Printer
 

$285.99
 

0 lpm 42 7-pin Paper dimensions Slip: 80 to 182 x 69 to 257mm The Epson TM-U295 is the world’s smallest slip printer, perfect for POS terminals. With four print sizes, four print directions and a“page mode”that lets you print practically anywhere on the document, it offers all the options you need. The TM-U295 is also equipped with a host of user-friendly features, such as an easy-to-operate touch panel and an automatic paper eject function. C31C163272 Custom Size Dot Matrix Printer Epson Epson Corporation Monochrome PC Receipt Print TM TM-U295 Receipt Printer White Yes www.epson.com 

 
 
 
 
Samsung SRP-275C Receipt Printer
 

$222.99
 

0 lpm 110 V AC 160 x 144 dpi 2.28″2.76″220 V AC 3″40 6.18″6.18″Height x 6.30″Width x 9.41″Depth 6.30″8 KB 9-pin 9.41″Auto Cutter Custom Size: 3″The SRP-275C dot matrix receipt printer is optimized for high-speed so customer receipts and kitchen orders print faster than ever. For maximum efficiency, the SRP-275C printer offers drop-in paper loading and two-color, black and red printing to highlight special offers and print logos, and an adjustable paper width feature that allows you to use paper rolls for more flexibility and greater cost savings. Black Custom Size Dot Matrix Printer Epson ESC/POS Fast Ethernet Monochrome Not Applicable PC Plain Paper Receipt Paper Receipt Print Roll Paper SRP-275C SRP-275C Receipt Printer SRP-275CEPG Samsung Yes www.samsungusa.com 

 
 
 
 
Poslab TP-260 USB/Parallel/Serial Thermal Receipt Printer (Black) Add A Receipt Printer To Your Checkout!
 

$162.47
 

Poslab TP-260 USB/Parallel/Serial Thermal Receipt Printer (Black) Add A Receipt Printer To Your Checkout! 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CBM-291 Receipt Printer
 

$254.99
 

0.71″1.97 in/s 1.97″2.05″2.28″2.56 mil 203 dpi 24 V DC 3.90″34 4 KB 4.17″4.29″4.29″Height x 4.17″Width x 3.90″Depth CBM-291 is a Line Thermal printer which can be equipped in a rack and is widely used for various data communication, POS terminal and various measurement devices. This printer can be used for various applications since abundant functions are incorporated. Mounting backet Automatic CBM-291 Receipt Printer CBM-291-34FDC Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Cutter Direct Thermal Printer EAN-13 EAN-8 ITF Ivory JAN Monochrome PC Receipt Print Thermal Paper UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Samsung SRP-350 Receipt Printer
 

$179.99
 

110 V AC 180 x 180 dpi 220 V AC 3.13″x Roll Paper 3.30″4 KB 42 5.71″5.91 in/s 5.91 in/s1 lpm 5.91″5.91″Height x 5.71″Width x 7.56″Depth 7.56″8 MB Paper End Sensor Paper Near End Sensor Automatic Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Cutter EAN/JAN-13 EAN/JAN-8 ITF Monochrome PC Receipt Print SRP-350 Receipt Printer SRP-350P Samsung Thermal Paper Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E White Yes www.samsungusa.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CT-S2000 Receipt Printer
 

$467.54
 

With its unique high-speed DMA (Direct Memory Access) the CT-S2000 Receipt Printer is a two-color, thermal printer capable of real-world speeds up to 220 mm/second and offers variety of advanced printer features including: Spill-Shield design to prevent damage from moisture or foreign objects to the internal mechanism, large capacity (102mm) drop-in paper loading, Quick-Clear technology for one-touch clearing of cutter jams, a two-million cut rated auto paper cutter. Manufacturer: Citizen Micro HumanTech Manufacturer Part Number: CT-S2000PAU-BK Manufacturer Website Address: www.citizen-america.com Brand Name: Citizen Product Model: CT-S2000 Product Name: CT-S2000 Receipt Printer Product Type: Thermal Transfer Printer Technical Information: Recommended Use: Receipt Print Technical Information: Print Color: Color Interfaces/Ports: Parallel Port: Yes Interfaces/Ports: USB: Yes Media Types&amp;Handling: Media Type: Thermal Paper Media Types&amp;Handling: Media Size: Custom Size Platform Supported: PC 

 
 
 
 
Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer
 

$523.85
 

SPPR200 MOBILE RECEIPT W/BATT/ PRNTCHARGER/STRAP BT/SER/USB BLACK 

 
 
 
 
Citizen iDP3551F Receipt Printer
 

$216.99
 

0 lpm 110 V AC 220 V AC 40 6 KB 6.30″7.64″7.64″Height x 6.30″Width x 8.35″Depth 8.35″9-pin Auto Cutter Paper auto loading 76mm± 0.5 mm (W) x 83 mm The iDP-3551F printer is high speed device for bank card, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use. It is fast and cost effective and has the latest in drop-in paper loading technology, all in a compact and versatile design. Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Custom Size Dot Matrix Printer Epson ESC/POS Fanfold Paper IDP3551F-40PF 120V-CW Monochrome Plain Paper Receipt Print White Yes iDP3551F iDP3551F Receipt Printer www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CT-S310 Receipt Printer
 

$189.99
 

110 V AC 2.83″203 x 203 dpi 220 V AC 256 KB 3 Year Limited 3.27″4.76″4.76″Height x 5.71″Width x 7.68″Depth 5.71″5.90 in/s 7.68″UL C-UL FCC class A TUV GS CE marking Black CT-S310 Receipt Printer CT-S310A-PAU-BK Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 EAN-13 EAN-8 ITF Monochrome Receipt Print The Citizen CT-S310 POS printer the smallest footprint in its class and a dual-interface standard. All this, plus it can be positioned horizontally, vertically, or even wall mounted for extra versatility. Best of all, it comes with the features you have come to know and trust from one of the most respected names in POS printers. Thermal Paper Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
HP POS Thermal Receipt Printer
 

$643.99
 

1 lpm 11.40″203 dpi 6.50″6.60″6.60″Height x 6.50″Width x 11.40″Depth The HP Hybrid Thermal Printer is a multifunctional printer with MICR (Magnetic Ink Character Recognition) for retail environments. Its compact size makes the HP Hybrid Printer one of the smallest on the market today. Automatic Cutter Direct Thermal Printer FK184AA HP Hewlett-Packard Magnetic Stripe Reader Monochrome Not Applicable PC POS Thermal Receipt Printer Receipt Print Thermal Paper Yes www.hp.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen PD24 Portable Receipt Printer
 

$517.99
 

1 Year 1.60″1.60″Height x 5.70″Width x 4.40″Depth 2 in/s 2″203 dpi 4.09″4.40″40 5.70″64 KB Media Sensor: Reflective Media Width: 4.4″PD24 Portable Receipt Printer Lithium Ion Battery Citizen’s PD24 Portable Receipt Printer is the latest design for users requiring the ultimate in portable printing technology. The PD24 Portable Receipt Printer at 2 inches per second allowing for a typical 8 inch long receipt to be printed in just over 4 seconds. This coupled with the PD24 Portable Receipt Printer small size and weight (1.18 lbs.) make it the perfect printer for hospitality, route accounting, healthcare, law enforcement, field service, and retails applications. Black Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Custom Size Custom Size–4.40″Cut Sheet Paper Direct Thermal Printer EAN-13 EAN-8 ESC/P ESC/POS ITF Interleaved 2 of 5 Lithium Ion (Li-Ion) Mobile Monochrome Multi-copy Paper NW-7 PC PD PD-24 PD24 Portable Receipt Printer Receipt Receipt Print Ticket UCC UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen PD24B Portable Receipt Printer
 

$607.99
 

1 Year 1.60″1.60″Height x 5.70″Width x 4.40″Depth 2 in/s 2″203 dpi 4.09″4.40″4.40″x Roll Paper 40 5.70″64 KB Media Sensor: Reflective Media Width: 4.4″PD24B Portable Receipt Printer Lithium Ion Battery Citizen’s PD24B Portable Receipt Printer is the latest design for users requiring the ultimate in portable printing technology. The PD24B Portable Receipt Printer at 2 inches per second allowing for a typical 8 inch long receipt to be printed in just over 4 seconds. This coupled with the PD24B Portable Receipt Printer small size and weight (1.18 lbs.) make it the perfect printer for hospitality, route accounting, healthcare, law enforcement, field service, and retails applications. Black Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Cut Sheet Paper Direct Thermal Printer EAN-13 EAN-8 ESC/P ESC/POS ITF Interleaved 2 of 5 Lithium Ion (Li-Ion) Mobile Monochrome Multi-copy Paper NW-7 PC PD PD-24B PD24B Portable Receipt Printer Receipt Receipt Print Ticket UCC UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-T90 Receipt Printer
 

$378.99
 

1 lpm 180 x 180 dpi 2 Year Limited 2.80″24 V DC 4 KB 4″5.51″5.83″5.83″Height x 5.51″Width x 7.91″Depth 56 7.91″EMC Standards: VCCI Class A FCC Class A CE Marking Canada EMI AS/NZS 3548 Safety Standards: UL CSA TUV (EN60950) Built with the same high quality and reliability of Epson’s best selling TM-T88 series, the TM-T90 brings you the added advantages of ultra fast speed, cost-effective graphics printing and large paper roll capacity. The TM-T90 delivers outstanding reliability that is critical in high-volume environments. Paper width: 58mm 2.28″, 2.36″&amp;amp; 3.14″Automatic C31C390161 Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Cutter EAN-13 EAN-8 Epson Epson Corporation Gray ITF Monochrome Not Applicable PC PDF-417 Receipt Receipt Print TM-T90 Receipt Printer Tear-off Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.epson.com 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-T88IV Receipt Printer
 

$356.99
 

0.02″x 3.30″2 Year 24 V DC 3.27″4 KB 5.71″5.83″5.83″Height x 5.71″Width x 7.68″Depth 56 7.68″7.90 in/s 99.06 mm/s Print Speed: 7.9″/second for graphics and text and 3.9″/second in 2-color print mode Two-color printing of receipts including logos and all other graphics Ease-of-use features including drop-in paper loading Improved cover design for increased spill resistance Same fast print speed for both text and graphics PS-180 AC adapter TM-T88IV Receipt Printer PS-180 Power Supply EMI Standards: FCC ICES-003 Class A Safety Standards: UL1950 CSA C22.2 No.950 The TM-T88IV POS thermal printer is the latest addition to Epson’s innovative, industry-leading TM-T88 POS printer series. Designed specifically for high-volume retail and hospitality environments, the TM-T88IV delivers more speed and more reliability than ever before. It offers 25% faster printing of text and graphics than the TM-T88III. Automatic C31C636A8991 Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Color Cutter Direct Thermal Printer EAN-13 EAN-8 Epson Epson Corporation Fast Ethernet ITF PDF-417 QR Code Receipt Print TM-T88IV Receipt Printer Thermal Paper UPC-A UPC-E White Yes www.epson.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CMP10 Mobile Receipt Printer
 

$162.99
 

1.96 in/s 1.97″120 V AC 2.28″2.28″x Roll Paper 2.48″2.48″Height x 4.57″Width x 4.09″Depth 203 dpi 4.09″4.57″42 64 KB CMP10 Mobile Receipt Printer Li-ion Battery Softcase SC10-01 Diameter of paper roll in stock (Paper cover): 50mm Reliability: Thermal head: 100,000 pulses or 50km EMC&amp;amp; Safety Standards: UL C-UL TUVGSCEFCC Class BVCCI Class B Citizen CMP10 Mobile Receipt Printer, a small, lightweight mobile receipt printer provides wireless capability through an infrared (IrDA). Increasing customers sense of security since the credit card does not leave their sight. Weighing less than 12 ounces, the CMP10 Mobile Receipt Printer can be easily carried. Black CMP-10-U5-SC CMP10 Mobile Receipt Printer Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 EAN-13 EAN-8 ESC/POS Lithium Ion (Li-Ion) Mobile PC Receipt Print Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CMP-10BT Mobile Receipt Printer
 

$314.99
 

1.96 in/s 1.97″120 V AC 2 Year Limited 2.28″2.28″x Roll Paper 2.48″2.48″Height x 4.57″Width x 4.09″Depth 203 dpi 4.09″4.57″42 64 KB CMP-10BT Mobile Receipt Printer Li-ion Battery Softcase SC10-01 Diameter of paper roll in stock (Paper cover): 50mm Reliability: Thermal head: 100,000 pulses or 50km EMC&amp;amp; Safety Standards: UL C-UL TUVGSCEFCC Class BVCCI Class B Citizen CMP-10BT Mobile Receipt Printer, a small, lightweight mobile receipt printer provides wireless capability through Bluetooth wireless capability. Increasing customers sense of security since the credit card does not leave their sight. Weighing less than 12 ounces, the CMP-10BT Mobile Receipt Printer can be easily carried. Black CMP-10BT Mobile Receipt Printer CMP-10BT-U5SC Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 EAN-13 EAN-8 ESC/POS Lithium Ion (Li-Ion) Mobile PC Receipt Print Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com 

 
 
 
 
Epson TM-U375 POS Receipt Printer
 

$458.99
 

0 lpm 1 Year Limited 12.90″24 V DC 4 KB 40 5.70″5.70″Height x 7.30″Width x 12.90″Depth 7.30″9-pin Cool White The TM-U375 is a compact printer that offers 40 column receipt / journal printing, up to 15 lines check/charge validation printing and unlimited lines of slip printing. C31C159022 Dot Matrix Printer Epson Epson Corporation Epson ESC/POS Label Monochrome PC Plain Paper Receipt Print TM-U375 TM-U375 POS Receipt Printer Yes www.epson.com 

 
 
 
 
Samsung SRP-275A POS Receipt Printer
 

$150.99
 

0 lpm 160 x 144 dpi 40 6.18″6.18″Height x 6.30″Width x 9.41″Depth 6.30″8 KB 9-pin 9.41″Tear Bar Version Paper Width: 57.5 ± 0.5mm 69.5 ± 0.5mm 76 ± 0.5mm Samsung SRP-275A POS Receipt Printer providing advanced features, lower initial cost, and legendary dependability. The fast, easy to use printer is designed to produce receipts, coupons, logos and barcodes for retail, quick service and hospitality applications. Using industry standard emulations, Samsung printer is easily integrate and certified with many popular POS applications. Dot Matrix Printer Epson ESC/POS Monochrome PC Plain Paper Receipt Print SRP-275A POS Receipt Printer SRP-275AUG Samsung Yes www.samsungusa.com 

 
 
 
 
Mobile 2&amp;quot; Receipt Printer
 

$545.99
 

Seiko Mobile 2″Bluetooth Direct Thermal Receipt Printer The DPU-S245 is a highly reliable, cost-effective 2″Bluetooth wireless mobile thermal printer. USB&amp;Serial interface included. IrDA (Ver. 1.2). Compact, rugged, very lightweight, and easy-to-use, the DPU-S445 is ideal for wide range of mobile printing applications. Print speeds up to 90 mm/second. Label, receipt, and cut sheet printing support. Includes Power adaptor, Power cable, Battery pack, Protective carrying case. 

 
 
 
 
Samsung Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer
 

$284.99
 

1 1.57″1.72″1.72″Height x 3.13″Width x 5″Depth 110 V AC 2.15″203 dpi 220 V AC 3.13″3.14 in/s 5″Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer Battery Battery Charger Belt Strap Installation CDRoll Paper The BIXOLON Mobile Printer SPP-R200 is a small, lightweight mobile receipt printer that brings user convenience and functionality to any mobile receipt printing applications such as Mobile, POS Retail, Hospitality,Parking,Citations Deliveries On board Transportation, Field Repairs, Installation Warehouse Logistics, Utility billing Meter Reading. Bixolon Bixolon America, Inc Bixolon SPP-R200 Receipt Printer Black Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Data Matrix Direct Thermal Printer EAN-13 EAN-18 EAN-8 ITF Lithium Ion (Li-Ion) Magnetic Stripe Reader Maxi Code Mobile Monochrome PC PDF-417 QR Code Receipt Print SPP-R200BG Thermal Paper UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.bixolon.com 

 
 
 
 
Citizen CBM-1000 II Receipt Printer
 

$306.99
 

110 V AC 2.28″x 3.27″–Roll Paper 2.83″203 dpi 220 V AC 3 Year Limited 3.15″x 3.27″3.30″5.71″5.91 in/s 6″6″Height x 5.71″Width x 7.48″Depth 64 7.48″Printing width: 72mm NV bit map data area: 256K bytes Reliability: Thermal head: 100,000,000 pulses or 100km EMC&amp;amp; Safety Standards: UL C-UL FCC Class A TUV-GS CE The Citizen CBM-1000 II Receipt Printer fits perfectly in a wide variety of POS applications. It combines high-speed, two-color printing with a compact footprint. The CBM-1000 II Receipt Printer also features a longer-life paper cutter, barcode printing and flash memory for storing and printing logos. And with a spill-resistant top and a quick-and-easy paper drop-in mechanism, the CBM-1000 II Receipt Printer is the ideal choice for POS printing. Black CBM-1000 II Receipt Printer CBM-1000II-UF120S-BK Citizen Citizen Micro HumanTech Codabar Code 128 Code 39 Code 93 Color EAN ESC/POS Ethernet ITF JAN Label PC Receipt Print Thermal Paper Thermal Transfer Printer UPC-A UPC-E Yes www.citizen-america.com
	</body>
</document>
