<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006872" url="http://www.bestsampleresume.com/sample-customer-service-resume/fast-food-cashier-resume.html" time="2012-07-12-23:51" support="5" score="0.022918722276352742" bingtitle="Fast Food Cashier Resume Sample Fast Food Cashier Resume, Resume ..." webtitle="Fast Food Cashier Resume Sample">
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="168"/>
	<description>Receive the orders and the respective cash from the ... Red Burger Fast Food Restaurant, Riverside, CA (2005-Present) Cashier. Welcoming the customers with proper ...</description>
	<body>
		Resumes Resume Templates Resume Cover Letter Resume Objectives Interview Tips Career Search Salary Articles 

 Resume Search: 
Fast Food Cashier Resume
 Resume » Customer Service Resume »Fast Food Cashier Resume 
Fast food restaurant is one of the most eminent food businesses across the states and is providing a great deal of employment to youngsters (mostly to teenagers!).
Working at a fast food restaurant doesn&apos;t always mean preparing burgers and sandwiches. The other important job is that of a cashier which includes duties such as,
 To welcome the customers Receive the orders and the respective cash from the customers Handing over appropriate food parcels Other assistance as demanded 

The fast food cashier also has to coordinate with other staff, such as the culinary workers to check the status of the food orders etc.
Now go through the sample resume given below.



 

 Sample Fast Food Cashier Resume Justin Nelson 
456, X Street, Y Avenue,
Riverside, CA-92506
(123) 456-7890
justin@email.com

 Objective : To work as a cashier at a well reputed and well-liked fast food restaurant and offer my best services to gain excellent career move ahead
 Summary of Qualifications: 
 Large and diverse cashier work experience at renowned fast food restaurants Immense familiarity with the general duties of a fast food cashier Vast exposure to the commonly arising troubles at cash counters and ability to find innovative remedies for situations Uncommon ability of identifying invalid and fake currency, effortlessly Extra ordinary fluency in communication and enormous customer convincing abilities Excellent hand at computer tools and web 


 Professional Work Experience:
Red Burger Fast Food Restaurant, Riverside, CA (2005-Present)
 Cashier 
 Welcoming the customers with proper verbiage and probing for their food orders politely Transferring the food orders to the subordinates for getting it prepared Monitoring consistently the food quality and service quality of orders being served Tallying the orders served and collected cash at the end of the day Taking care of all the bank transactions for the restaurant&apos;s bank account Generating and forwarding the periodic cash reports to the higher officials 

 ABC Fast Food Restaurant, Riverside, CA (2005-Present)
 Assistant Cashier 
 Recording the orders received by the cashier and forwarding them to culinary workers Monitoring the status of placed orders and encouraging the workers for faster preparation of orders Assuring the quality of food and arrangement of dishes are as per the standards marked by the higher authorities Maintaining detailed records of served orders and collected cash Assisting the cashier in generation of the daily cash reports 

 Academic education: 
 Secondary school graduate from Riverside Public School, Riverside, CA (2003) 

 Personal Details: 
 Date of Birth: XX / XX / 1987 Marital status: Single Expected employment status: Full time Ready to Relocate: Y / N 

 References: Will be available on request

 Related Links : 
 Head Cashier Resume Example Customer Service Cashier Resume Example 

 Accounting Resume 
 Acting Resume 
 Administration Resume 
 Administrative Assistant Resume 
 Advertising Resume 
 Agriculture Resume 
 Analyst Resume 
 Art Resume 
 Attorney Resume 
 Architect Resume 
 Banking Resume 
 Clerical Resume 
 Communication Resume 
 Computer Resume 
 Construction Resume 
 Consultant Resume 
 Customer Service Resume 
 Data Entry Resume 
 Dental Assistant Resume 
 Designer Resume 
 Driver Resume 
 Engineering Resume 
 Executive Resume 
 Financial Resume 
 Fire Resume 
 Government Resume 
 Graphic Designer Resume 
 Healthcare Resume 
 Help Desk Resume 
 Hotel Manager Resume 
 Human Resources Resume 
 Insurance Resume 
 Lawyer Resume 
 Legal Resume 
 Librarian Resume 
 Logistics Resume 
 Management Resume 
 Manager Resume 
 Manufacturing Resume 
 Marketing Resume 
 Medical Resume 
 Military Resume 
 Model Resume 
 Nursing Resume 
 Pharmaceutical Sales Resume 
 Pharmacist Resume 
 Physical Therapist Resume 
 Police Resume 
 Programmer Resume 
 Public Relations Resume 
 Recruiter Resume 
 Sales Resume 
 Security Resume 
 Social Worker Resume 
 Software Resume 
 Student Resume 
 Teacher Resume 
 Technical Resume 
 Technician Resume 
 Technology Resume 
 Video Game Designer Resume 
 Web Designer Resume 
 Web Developer Resume 
 Resume Search: 
 

 
 By Jim Karter
	</body>
</document>
