<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006822" url="http://companydatabase.org/c/vending-machines-manufacturers/related-equipment/portion-pac-inc.html" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="4" score="0.006926821601809201" bingtitle="Company: Portion Pac, Inc. - Ok, so who makes those little white ..." webtitle="Company: Portion Pac, Inc. - Ok, so who makes those little white cups that hold the honey you drizzle on your morning bagel? Or the foil-topped grape jelly containers the waitress brings you at the local breakfast joint? Portion Pac, that&apos;s who.">
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000160" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>... markets shelf-stable portion-control food products for the catering, fast-food, restaurant ... Heinz to Close Dallas Condiment Plant in June - Food Industry News. 7 May 2008 ...</description>
	<body>
		companydatabase.org       Search company profiles and industry reports to find what you&apos;re looking for. 

   Search Sponsored Links 
 
 
 Home &gt;   Vending Machines Manufacturers &gt;   Related Equipment &gt;   Portion Pac, Inc. 

 

Portion Pac Inc
 - 
 
 Company Homepage : Portion Pac, Inc. 
 Location : Mason, OH, United States

 Ok, so who makes those little white cups that hold the honey you drizzle on your morning bagel? Or the foil-topped grape jelly containers the waitress brings you at the local breakfast joint? Portion Pac, that&apos;s who. A subsidiary of Heinz Foodservice, Portion Pac manufactures and markets shelf-stable portion-control food products for the catering, fast-food, restaurant, and vending-machine industries. Its national name-brand products (including Welch&apos;s, Log Cabin, Musselman&apos;s, Mrs. Butterworths, ReaLemon) include cream cheese, jams, jellies, ketchup, mustard, salad dressings, steak sauce, salsa, syrup, and more. 


 Sponsored Links 
 
 
Portion Pac Inc
 - Related Companies
 

 Heinz Foodservice 
 Mother&apos;s Mountain 
 Carol Hall&apos;s Hot Pepper Jelly Company 
 Griffin Food Company 
 Heinz North America Consumer Products 
 Prairie Ridge Cheese 
 Garlic World 
 Oasis Foods Co 
 Kozlowski Farms, Inc. 
 H. J. Heinz Company of Canada Ltd. 

 Sponsored Links 
 
 

Portion Pac Inc
 - Map
 
 
 View Larger Map 

 

Portion Pac Inc
 - Web
 

Portion Pac


 Portion Pac :: Overview 

... leader in the production of portion control products with an unparalleled ... We make delicious portion-control condiments, jam and jellies, dressings, ...

 Portion Pac Inc - Dallas, TX : Citysearch.com 

Get details on Portion Pac Inc - Dallas, TX, at Citysearch - over 1 million user reviews&amp;editorials about local businesses.

 Portion Pac, Inc. - What does PPI stand for? Acronyms and abbreviations ... 

What does PPI stand for? Definition of Portion Pac, Inc. in the list of acronyms and abbreviations provided by the Free Online Dictionary and Thesaurus.

 Portion Pac, Inc. Company Profile - Yahoo! Finance 

Capsule info for Portion Pac, Inc. ... Industry Center &gt; Food - Major Diversified &gt; Portion Pac, Inc. Company Profile. Summary ... Portion Pac, that&apos;s who. ...

 

Pennsylvania Supreme Court Recognizes


 Ohio Department of Development | Newsroom 

Ohio is recognized globally as an innovative leader in developing a ... J. Heinz Company L.P. dba Portion Pac, Inc., (Warren County), will receive a $50, ...

 Duane Morris LLP - Pennsylvania Supreme Court Recognizes an &quot;Ordinary ... 

... H.J. Heinz Company, L.P., H.J. Heinz Finance Company, and Portion Pac, Inc. ... Philadelphia office, represented H.J. Heinz Company and Mitsui&amp;Co. (USA), Inc. ...

 United States, Litigation and Arbitration, Pennsylvania Supreme Court ... 

5 Mar 2009 - United States - Litigation and Arbitration - Pennsylvania Supreme Court Recognizes An Ordinary Course Of ... Company, and Portion Pac, Inc. ...

 JD Supra: Legal Articles - Pennsylvania Supreme Court Recognizes an ... 

Duane Morris Wins Appeal for H. J. Heinz and Mitsui On February 23, 2009, ... H.J. Heinz Company, L.P., H.J. Heinz Finance Company, and Portion Pac, Inc. ...

 

H.J. Heinz


 Choice Food buys Portion Pac plant - Nashville Business Journal: 

... has added the local operations of Portion Pac Inc., a subsidiary of H.J. Heinz ... Portion Pac in Nashville, which has been renamed Choice Food of America Inc. ...

 In This Issue 

Portion Pac Inc. Achieves Partner Level in. the Tennessee Pollution Prevention ... is happy to announce that Portion Pac Inc., a division of H.J. ...

 Choice Food Group - Milestones 

... plant that previously housed manufacturing operations for Portion Pac, Inc. ... H.J. Heinz Corp. announced that they we closing Portion Pac, Inc. ...

 Heinz to Close Dallas Condiment Plant in June - Food Industry News 

7 May 2008 - As part of a consolidation effort, H.J. Heinz Co. plans to close its Portion Pac Inc. plant in Dallas, Texas, late next month.

 

Mason


 FindOwnerSearch - Brand Owner PORTION PAC, INC. 

Owner. Home. PORTION PAC, INC. Owner: PORTION PAC, INC. Owner Address: 7325 SNIDER ROAD MASON OHIO 450409601. Owner Web Site: http://www.portionpac.com / Owner Phone: ...

 Portion Pac Incorporated, Mason, OH : Reviews and maps - Yahoo! Local 

Portion Pac Incorporated, Mason, OH : Reviews and maps - Yahoo! Local, 513.398.0400. Get Ratings, Reviews, Photos and more on Yahoo! Local.

 76 Cincinnati Food Beverages Executives - Buy/Trade Contacts 

Executive directory, sales leads and contact lists including phone ... 94% B.. R... Marketing Executive. Portion Pac, Inc. Mason, OH. 12/15/08. 93% S.... N. ...

 FDA Enforcement Report 

... Company, Inc., Kilgore, Texas. ... MANUFACTURER Portion Pac, Inc., Mason, Ohio. ... REASON Usage instructions are printed upside down on a portion of the lots. ...

 

Heinz


 Atlanta Business Chronicle: Portion Pac Inc related content 

American City Business Journals Inc. is the nation&apos;s largest publisher of metropolitan business ... Heinz North America said it will close its Portion Pac Inc. ...

 Choice Food buys Portion Pac plant - Nashville Business Journal: 

... has added the local operations of Portion Pac Inc., a subsidiary of H.J. Heinz ... Portion Pac in Nashville, which has been renamed Choice Food of America Inc. ...

 Foodservice.com FoodShow - Food&amp;Beverage : Taco Sauce 

Portion Pac Inc. Taco Sauce. Portion Pac Inc. Taco Sauce. Portion Pac Inc. Taco Sauce. Portion Pac Inc. Taco Sauce. Heinz USA. Taco Sauce Single Serve. Heinz USA ...

 Choice Food Group - Milestones 

... plant that previously housed manufacturing operations for Portion Pac, Inc. ... H.J. Heinz Corp. announced that they we closing Portion Pac, Inc. ...
 
 Sponsored Links 
 
 

 Sponsored Links 


Portion Pac Inc
 - Reference
 

Wikimedia Foundation


 Pacific ocean perch - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

Fishing generally selectively removes the older and faster-growing portion of the population. ... of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc., a U.S. registered 501(c) ...

 Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... based on the Metropolitan highway, and forms the Kanagawa portion of the highway. ... trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc., a U.S. registered 501(c)(3) ...

 Baby Pac-Man - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... pinball portion of the game, making Baby Pac-Man notoriously difficult despite its infant hero. ... the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc., a U.S. registered 501 ...

 Macrocycle - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

http://www.iupac.org/publicati ons/pac/1990/pdf/6206x1027 .pdf. ... trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc., a U.S. registered 501(c)(3) ...

Portion


 MIM-104 Patriot - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

The most recent upgrade, called PAC-3, is a nearly total system redesign, ... target, and home in on the warhead portion of an inbound ballistic missile. ...

 Team Pacman - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... and on their website, but his portion of Team Pacman&apos;s match against Team 3D ... Eric · The Latin American Xchange (Homicide and Hernandez) · Beer Money, Inc. ...

 Pacoima, Los Angeles, California - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

The DC-7B, with a portion of its left wing sheared off and while ... Brandon Browner, NFL/CFL player (Oregon State Alumni, 2004 Pac-10 Freshman Of The Year) ...

 List of companies in Greater Cincinnati - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

Portion Pac, the leading producer of portion control products in the country (in ... Humana Inc. to expand in Cincinnati USA - Cincinnati USA Regional Chamber ...

PAC


 List of companies in Greater Cincinnati - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

Portion Pac, the leading producer of portion control products in the country (in ... Humana Inc. to expand in Cincinnati USA - Cincinnati USA Regional Chamber ...

 Prison reform - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... coming to realize that a significant portion of prisoners had come to commit ... Penal Affairs Consortium (PAC) is an alliance of 40 organisations working ...

 Radio repeater - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... the higher or lower portion of the 440-450 segment of the band (the standard ... Motorola, for example, marketed a vehicular repeater system called PAC*RT. ...

 Tracy, California - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... School 1978-1981 / Arizona State Sun Devils 1981-1985 4 Time Pac 10 Champion. ... Assessment, Circle B Ranch, Tracy, California, Earth Metrics Inc, San Mateo, Ca. ...

Jerry


 Tazz - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... out of the ring, a large portion of the ECW locker room joined him ... (Brian Knobbs and Jerry Sags) · The Legion Of Doom (Animal and Hawk) · Money Inc. ...

 Yoshihiro Tajiri - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

He would also feud against the entire stable of Evolution for a good portion of 2004. ... and Jerry Sags) · The Legion Of Doom (Animal and Hawk) · Money Inc. ...

 Dynamite Kid - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

http://www.wrestling-titles .com/canada/ab/calg-pac-h .html. ... (Brian Knobbs and Jerry Sags) · The Legion Of Doom (Animal and Hawk) · Money Inc. ...

 Mike Lockwood - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia 

... Shootin&apos; the Shi Crap&quot;, and a portion of the profits from the sale ... (Brian Knobbs and Jerry Sags) · The Legion Of Doom (Animal and Hawk) · Money Inc. ...
 Sponsored Links 

Portion Pac Inc
 - Images
 


Portion Pac
 

 



 
 Privacy Policy - About - Contact - Advertising 
(C) 2009 companydatabase.org, All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
