<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006112" url="http://www.squidoo.com/waukeshafishfry" time="2012-07-12-22:47" support="2" score="0.0006482421196275253" bingtitle="Waukesha Fish Fry - Squidoo : Welcome to Squidoo" webtitle="Waukesha Fish Fry">
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="143"/>
	<description>... quite a few high tables that can seat ... untouched), applesauce, and condiments were ... You place and get your order at the counter like a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Log In Explore Topics Join Us 
 Go 
 Squidoo 
 Close Home » Food&amp;Cooking » Restaurants » Diners 
Waukesha Fish Fry
 
 9 Comments 
 What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… What Do You Think ab… Review Requests 
 
 
 8 Like 

 Like 8 Pin It 
 
 Ranked #2,377 in Food&amp;Cooking ,
 #46,728 overall
 
Friday Night Fish Fry
 The Friday night fish fry is nearly unique to Wisconsin, or at least to the Midwest. Outside of this region, it is virtually unheard of. It has become a mainstay of Friday night dining out due to the heavy concentration of Catholic population which, years ago, did not eat red meat on Fridays. Instead, they ordered fish at local restaurants. Even though that tradition is not followed as strictly as it used to be, the fish fry facet continues today.

Perch and cod make up the bulk of the fish varieties that are served, but many other types are offered as well. An all-you-can-eat fish fry is also a common find.

Following is a list of restaurants in Waukesha, Wisconsin, that are known to offer a Friday night fish fry, along with my review of the same. This is not a comprehensive list, but you should find something you&apos;ll like. Restaurant owners and staff were not aware beforehand that their food and services were being reviewed.


 Image: Carlos Porto / FreeDigitalPhotos.net 
 
Table of Contents

 Albanese&apos;s Roadhouse Alexis Andrea&apos;s Red Rooster Casa del Rio Christina&apos;s Family Restaurant Chubby&apos;s Tap Dady-Oh&apos;s Dave&apos;s Restaurant Eric&apos;s Porter-Haus Fox Run Lanes Gasthaus Golden Gate Gyro&apos;s West J. Lotti&apos;s Jack&apos;s Cafe Jimmy&apos;s Grotto John&apos;s Drive-In Key Westconsin La Estacion Mexican Restaurant Margarita&apos;s Mexican Grill Master Z&apos;s Cue Club Matteo&apos;s Italian Ristorante Michael&apos;s Italian-American Restaurant Pat&apos;s Rib Place RJ&apos;s Pub and Grill (Formerly Tallinger&apos;s) Rochester Deli Sunset Family Restaurant The Spot on Sunset Review Requests 
 
Restaurant Web Sites

Also addresses and phone numbers
 Albanese&apos;s Roadhouse 2301 W Bluemound Rd., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-785-1930 Andrea&apos;s Red Rooster N14 W22032 Watertown Rd., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-574-1230 Casa del Rio 408 E. Main St., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-542-4080 Eric&apos;s Porter-Haus 229 Wisconsin Ave., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-542-1300 Gasthaus 2720 N Grandview Blvd., Waukesha, WI 53188
262-544-4460 Golden Gate 1427 E. Racine Ave., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-547-2171 Gyro&apos;s West 1538 E Moreland Blvd., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-544-0211 J. Lotti&apos;s 225 South St., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-522-3009 Jack&apos;s Cafe N4 W22496 Bluemound Rd., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-521-2444 Jimmy&apos;s Grotto 314 E. Main St., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-542-1500 or 262-547-8906 LaEstacion 319 Williams St., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-521-1986 Master Z&apos;s 2454 N. Grandview Blvd., Waukesha, WI 53188
262-522-3615 Matteo&apos;s Italian Ristorante 1608 E. Sunset Dr., Waukesha, WI 53189
262-544-6022 Michael&apos;s 1400 S. Grand Ave., Waukesha, WI 53186
262-549-0406 Pat&apos;s Rib Place 151 E. Sunset Drive, Waukesha, WI 53189
262-544-4099 Rochester Deli 143 W Broadway, Waukesha, WI 53186
262-522-9611 The Spot on Sunset 316 W. Sunset Dr., Waukesha, WI 53189
262-542-5560 
Albanese&apos;s Roadhouse
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 4:30 P.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: Since there would have been a 20-25 minute wait, according to our hostess, we elected to eat in the full-service bar, which is the room you enter through the main entrance. There is ample seating for the size of the parking lot. The bar are holds quite a few high tables that can seat various numbers of guests. We sat at a small table against the wall that could serve three diners.

Lighting: Overall room lighting was low which seemed fitting since it was a bar. There was a lit candle on each table.

Ambiance: The feeling in the room was what you&apos;d expect in a sports bar when there was no&quot;big game&quot;going on. It was friendly and, for the size of the crowd (perhaps 50?), not overwhelming - even though the room was full.

Appearance: Initially, the table was not set. I&apos;m not sure if that&apos;s because it had been recently vacated or if they just don&apos;t expect each table to be used for a full meal. The bar had at least 10 TVs - 6 of which I could see without turning around. Only 2 of the 6 were showing the same channel. All were showing sports, as expected.

Temperature: There was a cool, constant breeze under the table which made us keep our jackets on. I don&apos;t think I want to call this a fault, though, because the temperature could easily have become uncomfortable without it, due to the room full of talkative people.

Noise level: The crowd was loud but not overbearing. I could imagine it being a lot louder on gameday.

Cleanliness: Tables, chairs, floors, walls - all appeared clean. We did not leave the bar area or approach the bar itself or use the restrooms.

Distractions: There was nothing to detract from the meal, unless you count the lady&apos;s light-up pumpkin necklace.

HOST
Friendliness: Our hostess was courteous, if brief.

Helpfulness: Offering a table immediately in the bar was greatly appreciated.

Speed: The hostess wasn&apos;t at her podium when we entered, but she appeared a few seconds later.

Appearance: She was neatly dressed and kempt.

SERVER
Friendliness: Our server was polite and did not hover over us more than necessary. She was probably quite busy, since the building appeared to be near capacity.

Helpfulness: She knew what beers were on tap immediately. (I didn&apos;t let her finish the list.) She also knew we could substitute vegetables as a side, even though it wasn&apos;t listed on the menu.

Speed: Service was normal, perhaps even faster than normal considering the high room population.

Appearance: Like the hostess, she was neat and not unkempt.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Whitefish, cod, perch, walleye, blue gill.

Taste: I enjoyed the 6 individual perch, but it was a little bland. The breading was very light, and only a few herbs or spices were added. I used the lemon slice and tartar sauce they provided.

Temperature: The bread was fresh but not warm. The bowlful of spaghetti was warm. The fish was hot, but not too hot.

Appearance: Everything was neat and pleasing to the eye.

Cost: Perch dinner = $14.50. There is a cheaper Friday night fish fry special, but it was for cod. I will always take perch over cod.

Value: This was a good meal for the price. I left feeling full but not stuffed.

Other Comments: The meal started with a salad (chosen instead of soup) and bread. My salad was traditional and included a good, fresh tomato. I could actually spread the butter found in the packet without tearing the slice of bread.

Options for the main meal (besides the soup or salad) included spaghetti, mostaccioli, or baked potato, according to the menu. The server mentioned fries instead of the potato. Being an Italian restaurant, I had to try the spaghetti, which was thin with a slightly sweet tomato sauce.

Dining Date: 11/12/10 
What Do You Think about Albanese&apos;s Roadhouse?
 submit 
 Reply Karen Apr 14, 2012 @ 8:31 pm | delete Best baked fish in Waukesha Reply RecipePublishing Jul 31, 2011 @ 10:53 am | delete I love to cook and eat! My kitchen is always open. Reply glsonn Jul 31, 2011 @ 12:10 pm | delete And I love to eat without cooking...thus this list! :) 
 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Alexis

500 E Broadway ... Ph. 262-446-4600 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 6:00 A.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: Many tables and booths in a fairly large room.

Lighting: The room as a whole was rather dimly lit. There was a light hanging over our booth.

Ambiance: There was an unexpected feel of elegance.

Appearance: I think the interior has been updated fairly recently. Or at least it is well-kept.

Temperature: I didn&apos;t notice a problem, so it must have been just right.

Noise level: There was faint music (classic rock?) playing over the sound system.

Cleanliness: Good.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: I&apos;m not sure whom I should count as our host. There were at least 4 people who visited our booth. The one who seated us was really our server. She wasn&apos;t rude, but she wasn&apos;t pleasant all the time either. I think she was just tired.

Helpfulness: Nothing special needed from her as host.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Uniform.

SERVER
Friendliness: See above under Host.

Helpfulness: She pointed me to the salad bar when I chose salad over soup, but then brought me soup later. She admitted her mistake and returned the soup when she saw I already had a salad. Other than that, she was there when needed and was helpful if brief.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Cod and perch.

Varieties of Fish: Cod and perch.

Taste: The breading on the perch was very light making use of a fork a necessity. The taste was thus rather bland since there wasn&apos;t anything special in the breading.

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: All looked good. The french fries were in a bowl on the side. If I had not selected the salad (bar), there would have been no traditional cole slaw. There was no rye bread, but there were rolls that reminded me of the taste of doughnuts.

Cost: Perch dinner = $8.99 (same as cod)

Value: The complimentary Miller Lite (wine was also a choice) was a nice, unexpected addition. I&apos;m not sure, but it seemed to be an option with all meals.

Other Comments: I was surprised that there weren&apos;t more customers. The place was nearly empty when we arrived. A couple of families came later. I think the location might be a strike against them. It&apos;s in a part of Waukesha that&apos;s a little hard to get to.

An interesting feature was found under the plastic at the checkout counter. They have paper money from dozens of countries around the world.

I think it was a manager or owner who visited our booth (rather randomly) to see if everything was okay. Maybe he does that for all customers. If so, very good.

Dining Date: 5/20/11 
What Do You Think about Alexis?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Andrea&apos;s Red Rooster
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 9:30 P.M.

Seating: As far as I could see, there are two dining areas plus a bar. One of the dining areas is adjacent to the entrance; that is, there&apos;s no foyer in between.

Lighting: Overall room lighting was adequate.

Ambiance: There&apos;s nothing fancy about the Red Rooster. If it hadn&apos;t been for the high ceilings, I might have thought I was in someone&apos;s redecorated basement.

Appearance: The rooms had a very open feel. We didn&apos;t sit in the bar, but it almost felt like we were in it anyway. The chairs were the same style we have at home. I expect something nicer when I dine out. The walls were plastered with self-promotional advertising - informational, but a little tacky.

Temperature: With no foyer, the room was cool, even though there was a double door with airlock in between.

Noise level: The music from the jukebox in the bar was loud. The lack of carpeting anywhere added to the effect.

Cleanliness: I&apos;m sure everything was clean, but there was an overall feeling of potential uncleanliness. It&apos;s a little hard to explain.

Distractions: Despite some of the items mentioned above, I wouldn&apos;t really say anything was a distraction. Two TVs were visible, but the volume was turned down on both.

HOST
Friendliness: She was friendly, but did not greet us at the door. Again, the lack of foyer was a factor here. Instead, she called to us from across the room telling us to sit wherever we liked.

Helpfulness: Little help was offered immediately. See above.

Speed: The hostess did notice us as soon as we entered the room.

Appearance: Nothing special. No uniform that I recall.

SERVER
Friendliness: Our server was polite and had a sense of humor.

Helpfulness: Our server was fine, but seeing other servers just hanging around the kitchen(?) area doing nothing was a little concerning. Even if they didn&apos;t have any customers to help, was there nothing else they could be doing?

Speed: She asked us way too soon how our food looked. I think even she might have realized it was too soon, since she didn&apos;t ask how it tasted. We barely had time to taste anything.

Appearance: Same as the hostess.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, perch, walleye, blue gill.

Taste: I got 2 large and 3 medium sized pieces of perch. They tasted good. There were no obvious spices added to the breading.

Temperature: The fish was fine, but the fries were almost cool by the time they got to our table.

Appearance: The food was nicely arranged on the plate.

Cost: Perch dinner = $12.49.

Value: Average. There were too many fries to finish, which wasn&apos;t the worst thing since they were cool from the start. There was only a half slice of marbled rye bread - a little stingy. The butter was soft and spreadable though. The fork was light and apparently inexpensive, but the knife was higher quality.

Other Comments: There were three of us; one ordered steak which may have taken a little longer to prepare. However, the meal did seem to take long to arrive (note the cool fries above), and there was at least one other table of diners who ordered after us but were served before us.

Dining Date: 2/4/11 
What Do You Think about Andrea&apos;s Red Rooster?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Casa del Rio
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 11:00 P.M. on Fridays

Seating: Lots of tables and booths. There is also a large room in back for larger parties, if desired.

Lighting: Good; bright. I like to see what I&apos;m eating.

Ambiance: A friendly atmosphere.

Appearance: Everything has a Mexican flavor as expected.

Temperature: It was a warm day, so the air conditioner was appreciated.

Noise level: Bright rooms make voice travel easily. There was a TV, but the volume was not turned up. Music was playing over other speakers part of the way through the meal.

Cleanliness: Fine.

Distractions: Not truly a distraction, but we could feel the air conditioner through the bench seats of the booth.

HOST
Friendliness: Our host was very kind, referring to my wife as senorita.

Helpfulness: Good.

Speed: He greeted us almost at the door.

Appearance: Smartly dressed.

SERVER
Friendliness: Our mature, female server was very polite referring to my wife as honey once - probably out of habit.

Helpfulness: Good. Nothing extra special to mention.

Speed: Service was normal.

Appearance: Very neat.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Cod.

Taste: This was probably the best cod dinner to date. There was something very pleasant in the breading.

Temperature: The bread was fresh but not warm. The fish was warm, not hot.

Appearance: Everything was neat and pleasing to the eye. The lids on the ketchup, cole slaw, and tartar sauce containers was a nice touch.

Cost: Cod dinner = $8.95 for the regular meal. $10.95 for all-you-can-eat.

Value: Decent value for a cod dinner.

Other Comments: Chips and salsa are provided for free as an appetizer. My beer was served in the bottle.

The 2 half-slices of rye bread were pre-buttered. Nice. No need to worry about the butter being too hard.

The lemons were cut so that it made them hard to squeeze over the 3 medium-large pieces of cod.

Dining Date: 6/3/11 
What Do You Think about Casa del Rio?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Christina&apos;s Family Restaurant

350 Delafield St. ... Ph. 262-542-6739 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 5:30 A.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: There are about 40 tables; most are in one of two rooms. There is also a counter you can sit at in the smaller room.

Lighting: Ample and pleasant.

Ambiance: It&apos;s seems strange to say this, but it simply felt like a restaurant - a place where you&apos;d want to go to eat. The only thing that felt a little out of line was the video slot machines - which people were actually playing.

Appearance: Christina&apos;s looks like it was recently remodeled. Everything looks new and fresh, from the carpeting to the tables to the partially dropped ceiling.

Temperature: Pleasant - no jacket or extra fan needed.

Noise level: If you don&apos;t count the loud person at the next table, noise was not a problem.

Cleanliness: Very well kept.

Distractions: The video slots could be a problem if you were seated near them. We were not.

HOST
Friendliness: Very good. He acknowledged us even though he was busy...bonus points!

Helpfulness: Good.

Speed: As noted, he was busy with someone paying their tab, but he got to us as soon as possible. There really should have been another host (or hostess as the sign said) to assist him. Maybe someone called in sick.

Appearance: So-so. No uniform, but neat.

SERVER
Friendliness: She was very nice.

Helpfulness: She forgot to ask how a steak should be cooked. When asking about side dishes that came with the dinners, she always asked what kind of soup we wanted without mentioning salad. That&apos;s unusual. Normally the server asks if you want soup or salad. She also didn&apos;t list the types of potatoes available.

Speed: Our main meals came before we finished our salads. There were large salads, but even so, that&apos;s really speedy service.

Appearance: She wore a fairly common uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: More types were available here than anywhere else I&apos;ve eaten to date. Unfortunately, perch was not among the 9 fish varieties offered. Cod, salmon, white fish, tilapia, smelt, catfish, mahi mahi, and two others I can&apos;t remember.

Taste: I tried the smelt. I&apos;ve never had smelt before. It tasted fishy as expected and had a pasty (as opposed to flaky) consistency. I assume this is all normal for smelt. There were 20-25 pieces of fish. Smelt are really small.

Temperature: Hot as expected.

Appearance: Everything was neat and pleasing to the eye.

Cost: Smelt dinner = $8.25. Included was a free beer (or wine) and dessert.

Value: This was a very good meal for the price. Too bad there was no perch. I would eat here again but not for the fish.

Other Comments: There was bread wrapped in cellophane (which I didn&apos;t get to try) and saltine crackers. I&apos;m told the butter was soft. The salads had a lot of peppers which was unusual. I don&apos;t usually care for peppers, but these were not hot, so they were okay.

The silverware was unexpectedly heavy duty...more bonus points.

Dining Date: 9/2/11 
What Do You Think about Christina&apos;s Family Restaurant?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Chubby&apos;s Tap

1220 The Strand ... Ph. 262-548-9284 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES

IMPORTANT: Chubby&apos;s accepts only cash, NO CREDIT CARDS, so make sure you have some bills in your pocket before ordering.

Friday Hours: 3:00 P.M. - 2:30 A.M.

Seating: Chubby&apos;s is mainly a bar, so besides the bar itself, there are only 3 adjacent high tables with seating for about 6.

Lighting: The lights were dim, but that was not unexpected for the circumstances.

Ambiance: It&apos;s a bar noted for Mexican food.

Appearance: Chubby&apos;s has a little bit of a cluttered feel. There&apos;s not much room to move around, but there&apos;s no need to do so either.

Temperature: Toasty warm.

Noise level: There was very loud music from the classic rock cable TV channel. Good music, but too loud for the relatively small room.

Cleanliness: Spic and span.

Distractions: Nothing other than the loud music.

HOST
Since Chubby&apos;s is not really a restaurant, there is no host or server as such. There&apos;s just the bartender.

Friendliness: She was friendly, but a little surprised that I asked if they served fish.

Helpfulness: She gave us menus from behind the bar and complimentary chips and salsa.

FOOD
Availability: Fried fish was mentioned on the menu, but there was no mention of what kind of fish it was.

Varieties of Fish: I think the fish was cod. It was 4 squares or paddies. It may have been frozen as opposed to fresh - I&apos;m not sure.

Taste: The fish tasted good, if a bit salty.

Temperature: Hot. Good and hot.

Appearance: The food was nicely arranged on the plate - 4 fish squares over a bed of fries. Tartar sauce came in 2 sealed tubs, like butter often does. There was no rye bread, but I didn&apos;t expect any.

Cost: Fried fish = $7.25. Tap beer = $2.50.

Value: Excellent value if you don&apos;t mind the bar atmosphere and loud music.

Other Comments: The silverware and plates were quite inexpensive. There were 5 TVs (one was turned off) which I thought was quite a few for the size of the room.

One of the other patrons, who had obviously been there before, was surprised that fish was on the menu. As mentioned earlier, Chubby&apos;s is known for Mexican cuisine.

Dining Date: 2/11/11 
What Do You Think about Chubby&apos;s Tap?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Dady-Oh&apos;s

250 W. Broadway ... Ph. 262-547-7077 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 5:00 P.M. - 9:00 P.M.

Seating: In the front of the restaurant, there are 6 booths with wooden benches. Behind the bar in the middle there are a number of tables. We chose the booth in the farthest corner next to the window where we could see the street outside.

Lighting: There is very little lighting. The small chandelier overhead was not turned on. There was a small lamp on the table.

Ambiance&amp;Appearance: The room, if you could call it that, has an unusual combination of features. There are coat trees attached to most of the booths. There are (Christmas) decorations on the window ledge. There is a bookshelf on the far wall containing magazines (current, I assume) and some books. Presumably the reading materials are there for more than decoration. The wall hangings have a strange mixture of themes. You can sorta see the storage area behind the bar including some neon signs up high. The radio plays over the speakers. I&apos;m not sure which local station it was.

Temperature: Cool. There was a light draft that I don&apos;t think was there because of our proximity to the large front window.

Noise level: All things considered, I wouldn&apos;t consider it a noisy place.

Cleanliness: Everything looked clean, but then it should have been because we got there shortly after it opened for the evening.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: Dady-Oh&apos;s is family-owned. One of the hostesses recognized my wife and had a brief chat with her.

Helpfulness: Fine.

Speed: Fine.

Appearance: A neat black uniform.

SERVER
Friendliness: Good.

Helpfulness: Even though the menu says,&quot;Sorry, no substitutions,&quot;she promised to check if veggies could take the place of a potato.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Same black uniform as the hostess.

FOOD
Availability: All there.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, blue gill, walleye, white fish. The menu didn&apos;t specify which fish was included in the Friday night fish fry, so I figured it would be cod, and it was. I didn&apos;t ask, but apparently no perch is available.

Taste: For cod, it was okay.

Temperature: Only warm. It should have been hot, but I think it was sitting around for a while before it was served.

Appearance: The 3 medium-large cod and pile of fries were a bit jumbled. It looked appetizing enough though.

Cost: Cod dinner - $9.45

Value: Okay, considering it was only cod.

Other Comments: It seemed to take a long time for the food to arrive. It was about 25 minutes. We even commented on that shortly before it arrived.

The fries were good; they were lightly salted.

I would have expected cheaper silverware and was pleasantly surprised to find heavyweight utensils.

The butter was soft and easy to spread on the marble rye bread.

The menus were basically cheaply laminated place mats. They showed signs of wear and could use a replacement/upgrade.

This would not be my first choice for a Friday night fish fry.

Dining Date: 12/17/10 
What Do You Think about Dady-Oh&apos;s?
 submit 
 Reply joe Apr 24, 2012 @ 10:25 am | delete Your lack of experience as a critic shows that you cant tell haddock from cod... Reply glsonn Apr 24, 2012 @ 6:16 pm | delete I don&apos;t see what leads you to believe this. There is no reference to haddock in this review. 
 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Dave&apos;s Restaurant

316 W. Broadway ... Ph. 262-547-0312 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 5:00 A.M. - 8:00 P.M. (Apparently a good place to have breakfast)

Seating: There are several tables and a few booths up front. There are more booths towards the back of the room along the bar that has low stools. Think, diner.

Lighting: Bright. Plenty of hanging lights to lighten the room.

Ambiance: Dave&apos;s is a diner, not a bar.

Appearance: The restaurant is well-kept-up, but it&apos;s obvious the building has been there quite a while.

Temperature: Just right. Thank you!

Noise level: Being diner-style, you can hear kitchen noises easily and the workers chatting. There is soft music overhead. There were 2 TVs, but the volume was not turned up on either this night.

Cleanliness: Nice and clean.

Distractions: None, unless you count the workers&apos; chatting.

SERVER
Again, being a diner, rather than a full-blown restaurant, there is no hostess.

Friendliness: Very nice.

Helpfulness: Fine.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Nicely dressed and kempt.

FOOD
Availability: All good.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, red fish, perch, catfish.

Taste: The perch reminded me of the stuff I grew up with. Classic taste - not too much or too little added flavor-wise.

Temperature: Hot off the grill.

Appearance: The main portion of the meal was nicely laid out on an oval plate. Fries came a little later on their own small circular plate.

Cost: Perch dinner - $8.50

Value: Excellent! A (fish) dinner - 3 large pieces of perch - comes with choice of potato, soup or salad, and free dessert - ice cream or pudding. Sodas (and tea) come with one free refill (which I didn&apos;t need).

Other Comments: I started with a generous salad of fresh, crisp, cool lettuce, tomatoes, strong onions, and cucumbers (which always go to my wife). Before we were able to finish our salads - and granted, we were the only customers at the time - our main course arrived. So we finished our salads along with our fish dinners. The tangy cole slaw hit the spot too. The only thing missing from a typical fish dinner was some rye bread, but I didn&apos;t miss it at the time.

Dining Date: 2/18/11 
What Do You Think about Dave&apos;s Restaurant?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Eric&apos;s Porter-Haus
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 5:00 P.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: Eric&apos;s is a converted private residence with 2 stories. I knew that but didn&apos;t realize that the upper floor is also used for seating. Apparently at the time we arrived - even though it was before 5:00 P.M. - the main floor was full. Our hostess asked if we would mind dining upstairs. We were the first ones seated up there, but others soon followed.

Lighting: Each table has a candle and a bright light overhead recessed into the ceiling. The wattage is just right.

Ambiance: The floors are carpeted, so the feeling is very homey, as you&apos;d expect. There was a large clock on the wall next to our table. It was working but doesn&apos;t show the correct time. The background music was standards by Durante, Martin, Crosby, and others with the occasional Christmas tune thrown in due to the season.

Appearance: Everything is appropriate to an older home. There&apos;s nothing gaudy or out of place.

Temperature: While not cold, the room did feel a little cool at first. No drafts though. Our hostess thought it was cool too and adjusted the thermostat accordingly. With more people and more heat, the temperature soon was just right.

Noise level: The music from the speaker on the wall was not too loud. The only other noise came from the guests.

Cleanliness: All appeared spotless. Sorry about the French fry I dropped and couldn&apos;t find later.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: Very good.

Helpfulness: As mentioned above, she found a seat quickly and raised the thermostat as needed.

Speed: Very fast. I thought it might take longer because she had to seat someone in line before us.

Appearance: Neat as a pin.

SERVER
Friendliness: Good.

Helpfulness: She lit the candle on our table. When we ordered, she asked if I wanted chowder even though it wasn&apos;t a standard part of my meal. I don&apos;t know if there would have been an extra charge.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Neatly dressed in a basic black uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we wanted was available, sorta. I had asked for an MGD. The server came back later to say there was only MGD Lite, which was fine with me.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, perch, walleye. Most can be fried or baked.

Taste: The fish were lightly battered, so there wasn&apos;t much taste except for the fish themselves, which is as it should be in this case. The tartar sauce seemed weak for some reason. Dipping the fish in ketchup was more satisfying.

Temperature: Hot to start.

Appearance: Everything looked rather jumbled on the plate - 10 medium-sized fish, some under the fries, and the small cup of tartar sauce on the edge.

Cost: Perch dinner = $17.99. There is a cheaper Friday night fish fry special, but it was for cod. I will always take perch over cod.

Value: We used a Groupon coupon or this would have been quite expensive.

Other Comments: The silverware is heavy, quality metal - not your cheap diner material. The salt and pepper shakers didn&apos;t match - close, but no cigar.

The bread we were served before the main course was rye with a heavy dose of large-crystal salt on top. It did a number on the roof of my mouth, much like Cap&apos;n Crunch. The butter was cold packets. Since the bread was barely warm, the butter didn&apos;t spread well at all.

There was only one beer on tap - not a brand I recognized, but I&apos;m no expert on beers.

We are discovering that most restaurants will let you substitute one item for another. In this case it was the standard pasta (that came with shrimp) that could be replaced by steamed broccoli.

The fries with my perch were nothing fancy and seemed to get tough rather quickly - even before they got cold.

There was a bus boy attending the upstairs tables. I felt a little sorry for him as he often had too little to do, since the server was quite efficient.

Dining Date: 12/10/10 
What Do You Think about Eric&apos;s Porter-Haus?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Fox Run Lanes

2440 W. Sunset Dr. ... Ph. 262-544-2010 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 2:30 A.M.

Seating: Besides the bar, there are plenty of tables on what doubles as a dance floor and more on a raised area adjacent to it.

Lighting: The lights were dim but ample.

Ambiance: Pool tables abound as well as video game machines. And the bowling lanes are just a room away.

Appearance: Open, clean, if a bit old.

Temperature: Nice and warm.

Noise level: Quiet, except for the occasional video game bells and whistles. If anyone was bowling, we couldn&apos;t hear it.

Cleanliness: Well kept.

Distractions: A few people were playing pool on the other side of the room. Their language was a tad bothersome.

HOST
Since Fox Run Lanes is not really a restaurant, there is no host or server as such. There&apos;s just the bartender and a young man who probably also helps with the pin setters on the bowling lanes.

Friendliness: She was friendly, but may have been a little surprised that we were just there for a meal.

Helpfulness: She gave us a menu from behind the bar and provided the drinks as soon as we ordered them as any good bartender should.

FOOD
Availability: Cod in a basket.

Varieties of Fish: Cod filets.

Taste: The fish tasted good for cod.

Temperature: Hot off the grill or out of the oven.

Appearance: Nothing fancy. Three pieces of fish and some fries in a basket, plus ketchup and tartar sauce.

Cost: Fried fish = $5.50.

Value: Excellent value if you don&apos;t mind the bowling alley/pool hall/bar/dance hall atmosphere.

Other Comments: If you&apos;re hungry while bowling or playing pool, Fox Run Lanes can satisfy your hunger. It&apos;s not a place I&apos;d suggest just for the meal.

Dining Date: 2/25/11 
What Do You Think about Fox Run Lanes?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Try Your Own Fish Fry
 When you want to go out but can&apos;t, or you can&apos;t decide where to go, try frying up your own fish using the recipe of your choice. 
Gasthaus
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 4:30 P.M. - 9:30 P.M.

Seating: There is ample seating at tables (mostly for 4). Perhaps they should have more tables for 2. We were seated at a table for 4 which results in a waste of space.

Lighting: The room would have been quite dim if it weren&apos;t for the large stained glass windows facing north and the fact that the sun had not set.

Ambiance: As you would expect from the name, Gasthaus, the atmosphere was German styled.

Appearance: Lots of stained glass and wood. Felt expensive, though I&apos;m not sure it really is.

Temperature: Just right. Not too hot or too cold.

Noise level: There was faint music in the distance. The bulk of the noise was from the patrons.

Cleanliness: Everything was clean as expected.

Distractions: We were seated near the lobby, so there was a fair amount of traffic as people were shown to their tables.

HOST
This was a little unusual. I think we had the manager as our host because there wasn&apos;t anyone else around to show us to a table at the time. He didn&apos;t have any menus in hand, so we asked for some from the server(?) who cleared away the 2 place settings that we wouldn&apos;t be using. She was not our real server though and never did bring the menus. Our real server brought just one later because she knew I just wanted the fish fry. Then the manager(?) came back and gave us a second menu anyway. Confusing.

Friendliness: All were friendly enough.

Helpfulness: Almost too helpful. See above.

Speed: Almost too fast. See above.

Appearance: The manager was in a suit; everyone else was in German-style uniform.

SERVER
Friendliness: Friendly, but with a touch of arrogance???

Helpfulness: She forgot my drink until I reminded her. She was able to rattle off the list of (mostly German) beers on tap. Unfortunately, unless you know those (uncommon) beers, it would take a while for the server to explain them all.

Speed: Adequate.

Appearance: In uniform.

FOOD
Availability: All was available, but you can&apos;t make substitutions when having the fish - even when having the baked fish.

Varieties of Fish: Fried or baked cod. No perch.

Taste: Good, for cod. The breading had nearly no taste of its own. I added salt and used the tartar sauce, as usual.

Temperature: Just right.

Appearance: All was laid out well. Cole slaw, potato salad (untouched), applesauce, and condiments were served before the main course. All were provided in their own china bowls. There was salty (cool) rye bread in a basket along with butter that was soft enough to spread with a little effort.

Cost: Cod dinner (all you can eat) = $14.95

Value: If you don&apos;t have coupons, this isn&apos;t the best value - especially if you prefer perch.

Other Comments: The potato pancakes had a steak flavor. I have no idea if this is normal for the Gasthaus.

Their house amber beer is quite good.

Dining Date: 4/29/11 
What Do You Think about the Gasthaus?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Golden Gate
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 P.M. - 11:00 P.M.

Seating: Half of the building (in a strip mall of sorts) is a bar with large screen TV. The other half, where we ate, is all tables - perhaps 20 or so.

Lighting: The lighting was dim, but there are large storefront windows with shades that add significant brightness. All in all, it was good.

Ambiance: It felt more like an American restaurant (despite the decor, see below) than a Chinese restaurant. Perhaps it was the clientele (see below).

Appearance: The room and the help is decorate in oriental garb from head to toe. There&apos;s lots of red. Quite nice overall.

Temperature: I didn&apos;t even think to think about the room temperature, so it must have been just right.

Noise level: The virtually-all-over-65 crowd was very noisy. If there was any music playing, I couldn&apos;t hear it. It was so loud that I had trouble hearing the server.

Cleanliness: Very good.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: Fine.

Helpfulness: Fine.

Speed: Good. She greeted us immediately from her little booth.

Appearance: All the help were dressed in red shirts and black slacks. The shirts were oriental styled as mentioned earlier.

SERVER
Friendliness: Very good.

Helpfulness: Very good. I&apos;m fairly sure she thought I had a hearing problem but didn&apos;t lean into it.

Speed: Good except for bringing the check. We had to wait too long. That said, she was busy the whole time with other tables.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Perch, cod, broiled red salmon, lemon fish, sweet and sour fish

Taste: Good ol&apos; perch!

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: Everything was arranged well.

Cost: Perch dinner = $13.95

Value: Average. Slightly pricey, but at least it was perch.

Other Comments: The meal started with egg drop soup which was much better than it sounds. Warm rye bread with butter that was actually spreadable followed.

The fries had a crispy, bumpy breading that made them stick together. They tasted fine.

Silverware was of decent quality. There were 3 spoons - a circular soup spoon, a normal teaspoon, and a very large tablespoon (or even larger?). I&apos;m not sure what the large spoon was for. Perhaps dessert?

Dining Date: 7/15/11 
What Do You Think about Golden Gate?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Gyro&apos;s West
 FACILITIES
Hours: Fridays till 11 P.M.

Seating: Ample seating in booths and tables.

Lighting: Good ceiling lighting and over individual tables. Quite bright overall.

Appearance: The building has the feeling of a diner from the inside. Parking is sufficient but feels cramped due to other establishments being very close by. (Access is a little unusual as you cannot get there directly from Moreland Blvd., especially when coming from the west.)

Temperature: Pleasant, especially considering the frigid temps outside on the night we went.

Noise level: Both a local radio and local TV station could be heard competing with each other. The TV screen is at the far end of the room and so is only visible to about half of the diners. Combined with conversations from the guests and the uncarpeted floor, it made for a rather loud room. On top of all that, there is noise from the kitchen that leaks into the dining area.

Cleanliness: Everything appeared to be spic and span.

Distractions: See the noise level above - especially the TV, radio, and occasional buzz from the kitchen machinery.

HOST
Technically, there was no host or hostess. We just had to seat ourselves. One worker did immediately come to our table to take drink orders and to tell us our waitress would be there soon.

SERVER
Friendliness: She was brief and to the point.

Helpfulness: The meal as presented in the menu did not match what she said it would be. She offered no explanation for this difference.

Speed: Our server arrived almost too fast. We could have been allowed more time to look at the menu before her first visit. Since we thought we knew what we wanted, it turned out okay though...sort of. (See below)

Appearance: She was dressed suitably for the occasion and location.

FOOD
Availability: Cod or catfish.

Variety: No perch. Sadness.

Taste: I ordered baked cod because I misread the menu and didn&apos;t see that fried was available. The very large single&quot;loaf&quot;of fish was bland unless tartar sauce was applied. There appeared to be some seasoning added, but it didn&apos;t add any significant taste.

Appearance: Chicken dumpling soup and two packets of saltines was served first. One large codfish, a little lettuce and a couple of veggies were on the main cheap, lightweight plate that arrived later. Also, there was a large, thin piece of salty bread on a separate plate. Condiments were also included. The butter was soft and spreadable.

Cost: $10.95

Value: Average value, considering there was no perch.

Other comments: The soup had one bit of inedible gristle. The fish dinner, according to the spiral-bound menu, was supposed to include fries and cole slaw. Instead, a baked potato was offered. The silverware, like the plates, was also inexpensive.

I like Gyro&apos;s West for the Greek gyros. I wouldn&apos;t go back for the fish.

Dining date: 1/21/11 
What Do You Think about Gyro&apos;s West?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
J. Lotti&apos;s
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: Booths and tables are in one large room along with the bar.

Lighting: Overall dim. We were right by the window, and the sun was shining, so we didn&apos;t notice the dimness so much.

Ambiance: One word came to mind: Trendy.

Appearance: Neat. Kinda sporty. There were 4 flat screen TVs hung around the one large room. There were icicle lights hanging from the ceiling that didn&apos;t add much to the decor.

Temperature: Just right. The front door was propped open.

Noise level: The music playing over the speakers - that near techo stuff that makes you want to jerk your head to the side in time with the beat - wasn&apos;t too, too loud, but I could have stood with some variety.

Cleanliness: Everything looked clean except for the dead moth on the window ledge.

Distractions: The music was a little much.

HOST
Friendliness: Nice.

Helpfulness: As expected. Instead of asking if we cared where we sat, she could have asked if we had a preference. Semantics.

Speed: Good. She was posted right at the door.

Appearance: No uniform. The see-through top (with more garments underneath) seemed a little out of place.

SERVER
Friendliness: Our server was polite but could have smiled a little more - not that she was unpleasant.

Helpfulness: She seemed a little surprised that I asked if the advertised fish and chicken dinner was the only fish fry available. I was surprised that haddock was their only option.

Speed: Fine.

Appearance: Neat, uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Apparently only haddock (baked and fried) is available.

Taste: I think this is the first time I&apos;ve eaten haddock. I prefer the fried over the baked. But I still prefer perch overall.

Temperature: Everything that was supposed to be warm was warm. Nothing was extremely hot.

Appearance: Everything was fine.

Cost: $14.00 for all-you-can-eat haddock and chicken

Value: An average value. Probably better if you prefer haddock (and chicken), which I don&apos;t.

Other Comments: Marble rye bread, cole slaw (in a small bowl about 2/3 full), fries and hush puppies were all served as appetizers, though they were really part of my dinner. Thus there was no plate on which to butter the bread, to lay the used knife, or to squirt the ketchup. It was a little awkward, though well-intended.

The butter was soft and spreadable. I wonder if it really should have been that soft.

There was no room on the 2-person table for the ketchup bottle, so the server set it on the wide window ledge.

The silverware was cheap. The knife was spotty but clean.

The fries were the good, real potato kind, salted just right. The chicken lacked all the spices you&apos;d get at KFC, so it tasted a little bland.

Dining Date: 6/17/11 
What Do You Think about J. Lotti&apos;s?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Jack&apos;s Cafe
 Jack&apos;s is open on Friday nights only from May through October. It is only during that time that they serve fried fish. 
What Do You Think about Jack&apos;s Cafe?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Jimmy&apos;s Grotto
 FACILITIES

IMPORTANT NOTE: Jimmy&apos;s is cash only. No credit. There is an ATM in the entryway.

Friday Hours: 9:00 A.M. - 1:00 A.M

Seating: Several low (normal height) tables, several high 2-person tables (one of which we used), and several booths.

Lighting: Fairly bright.

Ambiance: Almost diner-like or like a fast food place.

Appearance: Homey. There&apos;s wallpaper with small fleur-de-lis everywhere.

Temperature: Just right. The A/C was on. It was a very hot day, so it wasn&apos;t too cold.

Noise level: Not many people dine in. There was classic rock playing in the background.

Cleanliness: Generally clean, but it&apos;s mostly up to the patrons to keep it that way. Ceiling vents are a little rusted or dirty, but that&apos;s not really a problem. Didn&apos;t check the restrooms, but parents had no qualms about sending their children into them unattended.

Distractions: There was nothing to detract from the meal.

HOST
There isn&apos;t really a host as such, since this is run more like a fast food restaurant with the addition of ordering ahead and delivery.

SERVER
This is no server. You place and get your order at the counter like a fast food restaurant.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Cod

Taste: The fish was rather bland even with tartar sauce. You usually can&apos;t pick up a piece of cod like you can with perch, but this time I could.

Temperature: The fish was hot as expected. The fries were only warm.

Appearance: The fish dinner was served in a styrofoam take-out/delivery box. There was tin foil covering the bottom of the box. Our small drinks were also served in coffee-sized styrofoam cups. It&apos;s very obvious that Jimmy&apos;s concentrates on take out and delivery as opposed to dine in.

Cost: Perch dinner = $7.50

Value: Slightly below average value, considering all the styrofoam and lack of perch.

Other Comments: Jimmy&apos;s top items are pizza and their signature Ponza Rotta. Thus we were informed, even before ordering, that it would be a 30-35 minute wait for either of those items. Our fish dinner and cheeseburger took almost that long anyway.

Four half-slices of (rye?) bread were served in cling wrap. Between each pair were 2 pads of butter that were so hard they could not be spread. I think the idea was that, if this were being delivered to someone&apos;s home, the fish and fries would have softened the butter. I ended up taking half of this home. It took 25 seconds in the microwave to make the butter spreadable.

Plastic knives and forks are on the counter. Again, serve yourself. Ketchup is behind the counter in the small refrigerator. Ask for it.

Dining Date: 7/1/11 
What Do You Think about Jimmy&apos;s Grotto?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
John&apos;s Drive-In

1317 Arcadian Ave. ... Ph. 262-542-2842 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 7:00 P.M.

NOTE: Cash only. Leave your credit cards at home.

John&apos;s Drive-In is just that - a drive-in. The only seating available is picnic tables. Since it was too hot and buggy to eat outside, we placed our order and took it home to eat.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available. They have quite a variety on the menu for rather low prices.

Taste: Pretty good for a cod filet sandwich.

Temperature: The filet was still warm after a 10-minute ride home.

Cost: Cod filet sandwich = $3.00+

Value: Good, if you&apos;re going for the root beer more than the fish.

Other Comments: John&apos;s is really known for its root beer. It&apos;s very sweet and probably goes well with all of their offerings, fish or otherwise. I might go back for the root beer rather than for the fish.

Dining Date: 7/8/11 
What Do You Think about John&apos;s Drive-In?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Key Westconsin

331 Riverfront Plaza ... 262-446-2346 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 9:00 P.M.

Seating: Mostly low (normal) tables and a few high tables. You can also eat outdoors at tables on the front sidewalk. We didn&apos;t because it was too hot, but some patrons were using them.

Lighting: Bright. The light blue ceiling, open room, and large front windows help a lot.

Ambiance: You&apos;re supposed to feel like&quot;you&apos;re on vacation&quot;in Key West. The staff pulls it off fairly well without being overbearing.

Appearance: It&apos;s obviously an older building (just look at the panels in the ceiling) that has been remodeled - probably more than once. According to Google, as of this writing, it used to be Sakura Japan Sushi and Grill. It currently has a pleasant appearance.

Temperature: The A/C must have been set just right for the steamy day we were having.

Noise level: My wife noticed first that there is virtually no fabric in the room. So with the wood floors and high ceiling, it is very bright acoustically. All sounds seem amplified. So while no one was making any especially loud noises, it still seemed very noisy inside. And that was without any music playing.

Cleanliness: Good.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: Good.

Helpfulness: Good.

Speed: Very good.

Appearance: All staff members wear either a polo shirt with the Key Westconsin logo or a flowery island shirt for effect. All the shirts were different, so I assume they provided their own.

SERVER
Friendliness: Good, borderline too friendly.

Helpfulness: Good. She made suggestions and tried to keep the Key West theme going. All our final choices were perfect according to her.

Speed: Very good.

Appearance: See above.

FOOD
Availability: Everything was available. My Island Wheat took a few extra minutes to arrive because the bartender had to start a new keg.

Varieties of Fish: Haddock. I didn&apos;t notice any other choices.

Taste: Good for haddock.

Temperature: Hot.

Appearance: Well done. Cole slaw is usually served in a side bowl or cup, but here it was placed on the plate. Not much difference really, but it can get warmed by being next to the fish.

Cost: Haddock dinner - $8.95. Four pieces of fish lightly breaded. Note that other dinner items are more pricey in general.

Value: Decent, for haddock. Good if you prefer haddock. Very good if you prefer haddock and so does everyone else in your party and that&apos;s all you order.

Other Comments: The Island Wheat beer is from Door County. It was very tasty; not as wheaty as Sam Adams. The marble rye was a little dried out, especially around the edges. The butter was spreadable though. The cole slaw tasted good but was also a little dry.

Very thick cloth napkins and high quality silverware.

The tables were covered with a white cloth (not sure if it was fabric or vinyl). On top of that were several sheets of (butcher?) paper. The obvious idea is that (hopefully) just the top sheet is removed when a customer is done, so no actual cleaning of the table is needed.

Dining Date: 7/22/11 
What Do You Think about Key Westconsin?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
La Estacion Mexican Restaurant
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 10:00 A.M. - Midnight

Seating: La Estacion (The Station) has a main dining room of a dozen or more tables, a bar room, and an upstairs room and&quot;hallway&quot;(for lack of a better term) for about 10 more tables. We were seated at a table in the small upper room. There were 4 chairs at the table, but it was really only big enough for 2. The Party Train - one of the train cars adjacent to the restaurant can be reserved for special occasions (as far as I know).

Lighting: The lights were fairly dim but ample.

Ambiance: There is a flavor of the Southwest, at least, what I imagine the Southwest to be like. I&apos;ve never been to a restaurant in the Southwest to be able to truly compare it. The staff appeared to be all Hispanic and able to speak both English and Spanish. I believe this is intentional in order to make the Hispanic community in Waukesha feel especially welcome. I wasn&apos;t listening closely, even though it was loud enough, but the music seemed to have a Mexican flavor to it as well.

Appearance: The building seems old, but I don&apos;t know how long it&apos;s been there. There were a couple of cracks in the walls. Even though it was bigger than we first thought it would be, it still felt a little crowded. Adjacent to our small upper room was a place for dirty dishes (I think) in a tiny alcove. It seemed like they didn&apos;t have anywhere else to put what was in there, but that the area should have been used for something a little more customer-friendly and pleasant.

Temperature: On the cool side, but comfy. Didn&apos;t need to keep my jacket on.

Noise level: Loud. The building wasn&apos;t made to absorb any sound. The music from the bar room downstairs easily travels throughout the building. Conversations had to be loud too, which just adds to the volume.

Cleanliness: Clean as expected. I did notice a few cobwebs in a vent in the ceiling.

Distractions: The noise level and the staff&apos;s use of the alcove was just a little bothersome. Still tolerable overall though.

HOST
Friendliness: Good.

Helpfulness: I&apos;m not sure if the main room downstairs was filled, but we weren&apos;t offered a choice of where to sit. We were immediately taken upstairs. This is not a complaint, just a statement of fact.

Speed: No problems here.

Appearance: Neat uniform.

SERVER
Friendliness: Extremely polite and friendly.

Helpfulness: Good.

Speed: Decent. We were in a bit of a hurry and wished he would have come back sooner at the end of our meal, but his timing wasn&apos;t really out of line.

Appearance: Next uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Cod.

Varieties of Fish: Cod filets. I didn&apos;t notice any other fish on the menu.

Taste: The best cod I&apos;ve had to date. The breading was thick and seasoned. Often you can&apos;t pick up a piece of cod like you usually can do with perch. This cod looked like perch filets and could be handled with the fingers as I prefer.

Temperature: Hot as expected.

Appearance: Three pieces of medium-sized fish and some fries on a hot plate. Ketchup, tartar sauce (with too many pickle bits), cole slaw (very good), and applesauce were served in metal cups on a side plate.

Cost: Fried fish = $9.75 for all you can eat (I only had the 3 original filets) on Friday only.

Value: Good value if you don&apos;t mind the noise in the building. Other menu items were more expensive.

Other Comments: Chips and 2 kinds of salsa were served immediately and were free.

There was a separate menu just for drinks. I think my dinner menu was missing a page or two. The menus were bilingual.

Very nice silverware. Solid.

We had desert - good cheesecake - because we had one of those coupons where you have to spend $35 to get $25 off and needed to run up the bill a little to meet that minimum.

Parking is free in 2 lots and on the street, but you might have a tough time finding a spot. La Estacion is popular, and there are other establishments across the street that need space too.

Dining Date: 4/1/11 (This is not an April Fool&apos;s review.) 
What Do You Think about La Estacion Mexican Restaurant?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
What to Drink with Your Fish Fry
 Need something tasty to drink with your fried fish? Try one or more of these. 
Margarita&apos;s Mexican Grill

421 S. Grand Ave. ... Ph. 262-521-1446 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 10:00 A.M. - 3:00 A.M.

Seating: Several tables and a bar.

Lighting: Ample.

Ambiance: Unusual. There&apos;s the bar and the tables as mentioned, but there are also advertising streamers hanging from the ceiling. Without those it would feel more like a plain restaurant, but with them it feels more like a bar.

Appearance: Neat, sort of homey. I think the restaurant may have been an add-on to a house.

Temperature: Very hot. If there was air conditioning available, I don&apos;t think it was working. I was sweating by the end of the meal.

Noise level: Quiet. Initially we were the only customers.

Cleanliness: Fine for the age of the building.

Distractions: None.

HOST
None. One of the staff called from her seat in front of the large TV over the bar saying we could sit wherever we wanted.

SERVER
Friendliness: Okay.

Helpfulness: She was unpolished, to put it nicely.

Speed: Fine.

Appearance: Nicely dressed. I think she was a young member of the owning family.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Cod.

Taste: Below average. I think the fish might have come out of a box purchased at a local grocery store. There was nothing special or appealing about it. It was slightly overcooked. Often a lemon slice for squeezing over the fish is provided. This time there were 2 lime halves. I tried to use one to flavor the fish, but it didn&apos;t help.

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: Fine.

Cost: Unknown. The cod meal was not on the menu. It was advertised on a poster on the wall, and I didn&apos;t get the price. Our bill was not itemized.

Value: Poor.

Other Comments: I think the only reason they offer a fish fry is because they run a restaurant located in Wisconsin and are open on Friday nights, not because they have anything significant to offer here. I cannot recommend Margarita&apos;s Mexican Grill for the fish fry. They may be fine for Mexican fare.

Dining Date: 8/19/11 
What Do You Think about Margarita&apos;s Mexican Grill?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Master Z&apos;s Cue Club
 IMPORTANT UPDATE!

The original review below is no longer very accurate. What follows here is an updated review explaining the significant changes - mostly improvements - that have occurred in the interim.

FACILITIES
Seating: There are now over 30 tables in the dining area. At least, they are numbered, we were seated at #30, and I saw higher numbers at other tables. The menu mentions 15-20 tables, but I think their popularity forced them to recently add even more. Our table seemed rather crammed into its space. My chair didn&apos;t fit well into its space due to the angle of the raised floor (stage) to which it was adjacent.

I don&apos;t see this as a bad thing really. It simply shows how popular Master Z&apos;s has become. If there were room for expansion, they might consider expanding.

HOST
Due to increased business, we had to wait about 20 minutes this Friday (5/4/12) evening. We were even given one of those flashy gizmos that lets you know when a table is ready so you can wait wherever you and still be alerted at the proper time.

I think we could have played pool for free while we waited, but we declined.

SERVER
At the appropriate time, our server returned to ask if she should put in another order for me for more fish, since all fish dinners were all-you-can-eat. I declined, knowing that I already had a bigger meal than I would be able to finish.

FOOD
Of course, I had the perch again. This time I got 5 delicious filets, instead of 4. The 2 half-slices of marbled rye were not buttered, but the wrapped pads of butter were room temperature - squishy, even - so buttering the bread was extremely easy. Kudos to whomever decided not to keep the butter in the fridge.

Cost: $12.95. Tap beer: $2.50

OTHER
Comments: The fish, as noted above, was very tasty again. The waffle fries were only warm, but they didn&apos;t toughen as before. The lemon slice didn&apos;t have snipped ends, so squeezing was easy this time. The cole slaw and tartar sauce were in their own small bowls. There was more tartar sauce than needed, which is better than not enough. The cole slaw was more tart than I normally prefer.

The silverware was wrapped in a napkin and sealed with a paper band. Normal stuff, but an improvement over last time. The bundle included a knife and fork (no need for a spoon) which were heavy-duty, though slightly spotted (a minor point).

Date: 5/4/12 (shortly after 5:00 P.M.)

=== END OF UPDATE ===

=== ORIGINAL REVIEW BELOW ===

FACILITIES
Hours: Open at 11:00 A.M. daily

Seating: We sat at a table for 4 on a raised stage area next to the DJ booth and almost directly under the disco ball. The table had a significant wobble, but that was the floor&apos;s fault, not the table&apos;s.

Lighting: Our table was brightly lit, but other areas were more in the shadows.

Ambiance: Master Z&apos;s is essentially a pool hall - a nice one - and so has that feel.

Appearance: There is a large area housing the pool tables opposite the bar and dining area. There aren&apos;t many tables, but that&apos;s not the main reason the establishment exists. It&apos;s the pool, darts, music, TVs (all 6 set to the same channel) and sometimes dancing.

Temperature: Very comfy.

Noise Level: The classic rock from the overhead speakers was a little loud, but maybe that&apos;s just because I&apos;m getting to be a classic too.

Cleanliness: Everything seemed spic and span.

Distractions: The single menu was situated in a holder in the center of the table. We had to move it off to the side to see each other decently. If there had been 4 of us, I&apos;m not sure what we would have done about it. If there had been lots of people playing the games, that could have been quite distracting, but there weren&apos;t any such detractors for the majority of our time there. (We arrived at about 5:00.)

HOST
None - Seat yourself.

SERVER
Friendliness: Our server was very friendly.

Helpfulness: There were no table settings, so our server brought one set of silverware and some napkins shortly after taking our order. She checked in on us from time to time and asked if I wanted more fish when I had one piece left. I declined because I knew I wouldn&apos;t be able to eat any more.

Speed: She was quick about her duties.

Appearance: Her outfit was nothing fancy. I don&apos;t think it would qualify as a uniform, but again, I wouldn&apos;t expect one at this restaurant.

FOOD
Availability: Master Z&apos;s offers perch which, as usual, I chose. I was given 4 jumbo-sized fish to start.

Variety: Blue gill, perch, and cod.

Taste: The fish itself was good, being perch. The slightly crunchy breading was a little heavy on the salt and spices. By the time I got to the fourth one, I had had enough of the taste (besides being full).

Temperature: The fish were warm, not so hot that I had to wait for them to cool.

Appearance: The meal was well laid out on a large square plate. The cole slaw, which was neither sweet nor sour, was in its own frilly little bowl.

Cost: $12.00 for the fish fry. $1.50 for the beer. It may have been happy hour, so don&apos;t expect that price all the time...I just don&apos;t know.

Value: This is a very good value, if you don&apos;t mind eating in a pool hall. I didn&apos;t mind.

OTHER
Comments: The seasoned waffle fries were good, but they got tough as they cooled. I&apos;m not sure if that was a factor of the food itself or how it was prepared. The marble rye bread came pre-buttered - a nice touch. The traditional lemon slice was cut off at each end making it hard to squeeze over the perch. It was nice to see the old style, upright, glass ketchup bottle instead of the newer upside down plastic squeeze bottle.

Date: 11/19/10 (5:00 P.M.) 
What Do You Think about Master Z&apos;s Cue Club?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Matteo&apos;s Italian Ristorante
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 4:00 P.M. - Midnight

Seating: There are 2 main rooms on either side of a fireplace, plus a small bar. Each room has tables, and the&quot;back&quot;room also has booths. The booths do not have padding on the wooden benches.

Lighting: The lighting was dim. The hostess moved a candle to our booth when we got there. I&apos;m not sure if they don&apos;t have enough for each table or what.

Ambiance: The room feels very homey. The building looks as if it might have been a residential place at one time.

Appearance: Everything was neat and in order. There was a TV in each of two corners of the room. The volume was turned down on both.

Temperature: The air was cool; I&apos;m glad I was wearing a sweatshirt.

Noise level: There was a radio playing on the overhead speakers. As the room filled with people, the noise level didn&apos;t increase much.

Cleanliness: All good.

Distractions: None to speak of.

HOST
Friendliness: Courteous.

Helpfulness: Nothing special was needed.

Speed: It took a minute or so to get us marked on the chart for some reason.

Appearance: Fine.

SERVER
Friendliness: Friendly.

Helpfulness: She was a bit coy about what kind of soda they served. It wasn&apos;t strictly Pepsi or Coke products as usual. We think we overheard later that they use Black...something-or-other.

Speed: It felt a little slow considering we both ordered fish on a Friday.

Appearance: Fine.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, lake perch, walleye pike. See the full menu at Foodspot: http://www.foodspot.com/Clients/WI/Waukesha/MatteosItalianRistorante/default.aspx?accid=13754

Taste: There were 9 medium-sized filets. I think that&apos;s the most fish I&apos;ve been served to date. The breading reminded me of crispy KFC. It got too hard and crunchy as it cooled.

Temperature: Warm, but it cooled fast.

Appearance: The server had to come to the table 3 times to bring us everything. First I got the plate of fish. Then she brought a basket of fries. Finally she served a small basket of marbled rye bread.

Cost: Perch dinner = $12.95. There is a cheaper Friday night fish fry special, but it was for cod. I will always take perch over cod.

Value: This was a good meal for the price. There were a few too many fries, but that&apos;s not uncommon.

Other Comments: The rye bread (no longer warm) had salt baked on top, but not the larger sea salt as we had at Eric&apos;s. The fries were good but thin and tended to break when picked up as long as they were warm. I thought it was a little unusual that my wife&apos;s diet soda was served from a can. The cole slaw was good and tart and was served in a plastic cup. (Are you listening Sunset Family Restaurant?)

We nearly got free drinks from the bar when our server almost left them at our table by mistake.

Dining Date: 3/11/11 
What Do You Think about Matteo&apos;s?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Michael&apos;s Italian-American Restaurant
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 3:30-midnight

Seating: The building isn&apos;t very big, so it fills up fast. There are tables and booths of various sizes. We arrived shortly after 5:00 and could only sit at the table right by the entryway, if we didn&apos;t want to wait. The hostess even gave us the option of waiting even though that table was open, leading me to think they try not to make people sit there if at all possible. We took the table anyway.

Lighting: The room was dimly lit. There was a candle on the table, more for atmosphere than light.

Ambiance: Michael&apos;s feels more upscale than many restaurants. There is no dress code, but they could easily implement one.

Appearance: Lots of brick - inside.

Temperature: Good. Lukewarm.

Noise level: Crowd noise was dampened by the environment. The overhead music, which was a mix of standards and world in various languages, was at a good volume to be heard but was not overpowering.

Cleanliness: Good.

Distractions: Since we took the table near the entryway, there was a lot of traffic and activity by the hostesses. It was actually more interesting than distracting though, and we did ask for that table, so I&apos;m not complaining.

HOST
Friendliness: Nice.

Helpfulness: As mentioned above, she offered the first table or the option to wait for another.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Black and white uniform with red bow tie.

SERVER
Friendliness: Nice young man.

Helpfulness: He knew his stuff. Not sure if he was new to the job, but his conversation seemed a little over-rehearsed and stilted at first.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Uniform.

FOOD
Availability: No veggies. Not sure about the garlic bread. See below.

Varieties of Fish: Cod (fried or baked), lake perch, salmon.

Taste: The breading was very light and had no detectable spices, so it was very bland without the addition of tartar sauce.

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: Pleasant. 5 large filets partially covering some fries. Everything else was on the side.

Cost: Lake perch - $14.95

Value: Okay with a coupon for a free dinner when you buy a dinner and two drinks.

Other Comments: The table was covered first with a linen tablecloth which was covered with a vinyl cloth - a good idea for an Italian place with lots of sauces.

The menu said the dinner came with soup or salad. The waiter said the salad would cost a dollar extra - unusual. The menu also said garlic bread or hot bread came with the meal. The waiter didn&apos;t offer the options and just brought hot bread.

The bread wasn&apos;t a good match with the butter. The bread was small and hot; the butter was large and cold. No spreading was possible.

The cole slaw (very finely shredded), ketchup, and tartar sauce each came in their own containers on the side. Silver, metal containers were used for the ketchup and tartar sauce - no paper here.

The silverware was rolled up in the cloth napkin; my knife was upside down compared to the two forks. My wife&apos;s was fine. The silverware wasn&apos;t cheap, but it wasn&apos;t the most expensive I&apos;ve used either.

Dining Date: 3/25/11 
What Do You Think about Michael&apos;s?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Pat&apos;s Rib Place
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 11:00 A.M. - 9:00 P.M.

Seating: There are only 3 four-seat and 2 two-seat booths. There are several high chairs along the bar/counter.

Lighting: Rather dim.

Ambiance: A lot of carry-out happens here. It felt crowded, not very welcoming. The old time blues playing loudly over the speakers didn&apos;t help any. There were three smallish TVs hanging from the walls. No sound was coming from them, and they were too far away to read the captions.

Appearance: Crowded. Decor gave a home-made, unprofessional flavor.

Temperature: Fine.

Noise level: The blues (CDs?) were way too loud for the small room. This was the only style of music that was played the entire time we were there.

Cleanliness: Fine.

Distractions: The music was a distraction as noted earlier.

HOST
There is no host.

SERVER
Friendliness: Fine.

Helpfulness: Fine.

Speed: This doesn&apos;t really apply since you go to the bar/counter to place your order.

Appearance: Fine.

FOOD
Availability: NO PERCH ON A FRIDAY NIGHT! In Wisconsin, this is unpardonable, especially when it&apos;s still advertised on a chalkboard behind the bar at chest level. Is it too hard to erase and replace with a note that perch is temporarily unavailable? And why wasn&apos;t there better planning of supplies earlier? This is a big negative. I almost walked out without ordering at all.

Varieties of Fish: Cod, catfish.

Taste: The cole slaw and fries were good, but the cod was nothing special and a little overdone. There were 4 large pieces; I only ate 3.5 of them. This is the only place to date where I didn&apos;t finish the fish.

Temperature: Hot as expected for the cod and fries. The single slice of plain white bread was not warm, but I wouldn&apos;t expect it to be when you (probably) just pull it out of the store-bought loaf wrapper. (I kinda doubt it was fresh baked.)

Appearance: Rather a jumble on a dish that was too small to hold everything any other way.

Cost: Co dinner = ~$10? I never saw an itemized bill, so this is a guess. The prices shown on the chalkboard were for PERCH WHICH THEY DIDN&apos;T HAVE.

Value: I can&apos;t tell what kind of value this would be for a perch dinner since THEY DIDN&apos;T HAVE PERCH AVAILABLE ON A FRIDAY NIGHT!

Other Comments: The ribs we also ordered were also overcooked and dry. It appears (on their Web site) that Oprah and Kathy Griffin rave about this place. I don&apos;t think so. I cannot recommend Pat&apos;s Rib Place for fish or ribs.

Dining Date: 9/9/11 
What Do You Think about Pat&apos;s Rib Place?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
RJ&apos;s Pub and Grill (Formerly Tallinger&apos;s)

S31 W24661 Sunset Dr. ...Ph. 262-544-6161 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: n/a

Seating: Besides the seats at the bar, there are both high and low tables. They were not preset with placemats, silverware, etc. as usual. The room feels a little cramped because they reserve some space for live music. There was none playing while we were there.

Lighting: Lighting was good, aided by many storefront windows.

Ambiance: This is really a sports bar. There is a game room, video game machines, Packers neon sign, etc.

Appearance: Feels cluttered and on the old side.

Temperature: Just right.

Noise level: The large screen TV at the far end of the bar has speakers in the dining area. It was turned up too loud for a Friday evening when there was no Packers game on.

Cleanliness: Didn&apos;t notice anything amiss.

Distractions: There are plenty of potential distractions but none of them distracted this day.

HOST
None. We seated ourselves.

SERVER
Friendliness: Very nice.

Helpfulness: Average (which is good).

Speed: Average (again good).

Appearance: Dressed nicely.

FOOD
Availability: There were no peppers in the kitchen for the chicken meal that my wife ordered.

Varieties of Fish: Cod.

Taste: The 4 large filets were tasty for cod. I could pick them up with my fingers and dip them in the large cup of tartar sauce.

Temperature: Good and hot.

Appearance: Everything was neat and pleasing to the eye.

Cost: Perch dinner = $15 for 2 cod dinners.

Value: Decent, as long as there are at least 2 of you who will eat cod.

Other Comments: As mentioned above, the restaurant was formerly called Tallinger&apos;s (and may be still run by a Tallinger) which would explain why there is still a Talinger Burger on the menu.

The silverware is very cheap and showed dishwasher water spots.

The butter was spreadable. The dark marble rye was okay. A serving of very yellow cole slaw was brought early with soup and salad that the others were eating. The ketchup bottle appeared to have been refilled and was now too full. It too quite a bit of pumping to get it started.

Dining Date: 8/5/11 
What Do You Think about RJ&apos;s Pub and Grill?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Rochester Deli
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 10:00 A.M. - 8:00 P.M.

Seating: There are tables inside but also on the sidewalk out front. The weather was nice so we made this our first outdoor meal using one of the metal tables (with umbrella) and chairs provided. We weren&apos;t the only customers to do so.

Lighting: Inside, the lighting seemed a little dim, but outside, of course, it was as bright as day.

Ambiance: I can&apos;t tell you about the feeling inside, but outside it was a breath of fresh air.

Appearance: Again, not much to say about the inside. the sidewalk area was neat. There was a place provided for garbage and used dinnerware.

Temperature: I think the temperature inside would have been fine. Outside was wonderful.

Noise level: No crowd noise and no traffic noise to speak of. The restaurant is located on a quiet street.

Cleanliness: Everything was as clean as could be expected for being outdoors.

Distractions: Nothing unpleasant.

HOST
There is no host to speak of. One of the staff did provide us with menus and tried to explain how the Deli worked. I think we didn&apos;t quite understand where you could order from.

SERVER
Friendliness: Fine.

Helpfulness: Good. There apparently is some rule about taking alcohol from inside the building to the outside; it has to be done by the staff. I couldn&apos;t carry it out by myself. If you know anything about this, please enlighten us.

Speed: Normal.

Appearance: Fine.

FOOD
Availability: Everything we ordered was available.

Varieties of Fish: I think there was only cod.

Taste: Very good for cod - probably one of the two best cod dinners to date. The breading had a wonderful seasoning. I think it was called&quot;Italian&quot;or some such.

Temperature: Good, as expected.

Appearance: Since we ate outside, the meal was served in what amounted to a pie tin. I assume this was to help keep it warm.

Cost: Breaded cod dinner = $8.55. Baked cod dinner = $9.55.

Value: Very good for a cod dinner. (Remember, I prefer perch.)

Other Comments: The meal came with potato pancakes. For the uninitiated, these are essentially has browns in paddy form. There was also applesauce. I think it&apos;s a German tradition to dip something in the applesauce - possibly the potato pancakes. Again, if you know more about this, please let me know.

If I recall correctly, the silverware was high quality stuff. I didn&apos;t expect this from a deli.

Dining Date: 8/12/11 
What Do You Think about Rochester Deli?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Sunset Family Restaurant

535 W. Sunset Dr. ... Ph. 262-524-9555 (No Web site)
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: n/a

Seating: There are lots of booths and tables available. The booth we used felt a little small with our large winter coats.

Lighting: The room was brightly lit.

Ambiance: The place felt like a very large diner.

Appearance: Everything looked modern and in good shape.

Temperature: Very good, pleasant.

Noise level: The crowd noise and kitchen noise (even though we were as far from the kitchen as possible) seemed rather loud. I&apos;m not sure why this was so. Maybe people were just talking louder than usual.

Cleanliness: Good.

Distractions: The restaurant is right next to the railroad tracks. A train did speed by while we waited for our meal, but the noise was negligible.

HOST
Friendliness: Nice.

Helpfulness: Nothing special needed from her.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Normal for a diner.

SERVER
Friendliness: Okay. She could and should have smiled more.

Helpfulness: She seemed unsure of what all the specials were. She also wasn&apos;t sure if the shrimp creole was breaded.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Fine; standard stuff.

FOOD
Availability: Some desserts were apparently not available by this time of day (supper).

Varieties of Fish: Cod, perch (ocean or lake), haddock, salmon.

Taste: I don&apos;t recall ever having ocean perch before, at least not knowingly. The taste was fine, though I would try the more expensive lake perch on a return visit.

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: The food was laid out well, but I wouldn&apos;t have put the single lemon slice on top of the cup of cole slaw.

Cost: Ocean perch dinner = $8.65

Value: Great if you go for one of the special dinners. You get a tap beer or glass of wine, soup or salad, vegetable, and dessert included in the price. There was more than any of us could finish. We took all the desserts home.

Other Comments: My menu was missing the paper clipped insert showing the specials. The spiral bound menu with laminated covers was somewhat outdated, I think, because it still asked that customers not smoke cigars or pipes. As far as I know, this is forbidden everywhere in Wisconsin restaurants now.

We received 3 huge dinner rolls which were not warm (though not stale by any means), but the packets of butter were hard (though not impossible to spread).

The tomatoes on my salad were a little tough skinned, but it is March.

Silverware was very inexpensive.

There was no salt at all on the fries. I added my own, but normally some sort of spice is added beforehand. There was no salt on the corn either. It was good tasting corn though.

The meager amount of cole slaw really should not have been served in a paper cup.

I still miss rye bread when it&apos;s not offered.

The main course seemed to take longer than normal, and I couldn&apos;t see any reason for it. The place was not overcrowded.

Dining Date: 3/4/11 
What Do You Think about Sunset Family Restaurant?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
The Spot on Sunset
 FACILITIES
Friday Hours: 6:00 A.M. - 10:00 P.M.

Seating: Many tables and booths in a fairly small room.

Lighting: The room was well lit with lots of large windows bringing in more light than the electric lights.

Ambiance: The Spot has a homey feel.

Appearance: This building was obviously a fast food chain (possibly a Burger King) in a former life. The drive through boards are still up (but empty) at the back of the building.

Temperature: Cool. I think the air conditioner was on for a while, but it was only 66 degrees outside.

Noise level: The loudest sound was a relatively low level of crowd talk. There was overhead music, but it seemed distant and wasn&apos;t noticeable after a while. There was a TV in the bar/waiting area, but I couldn&apos;t hear if the volume was turned up or not.

Cleanliness: Good.

Distractions: None.

HOST
Friendliness: Nice.

Helpfulness: Nothing special needed from her.

Speed: Good.

Appearance: Uniform.

SERVER
Friendliness: Very pleasant.

Helpfulness: Very good. She attended the table when needed and avoided it when she could see she wasn&apos;t needed. She was too young to pour my beer.

Speed: Very good.

Appearance: Uniform.

FOOD
Availability: Cod, salmon, and tilapia - all available, as far as I know.

Varieties of Fish: Cod (breaded or beer battered), salmon, tilapia.

Taste: I chose the (all you can eat) beer battered cod. It tasted fine; I couldn&apos;t have told you that the coating was beer batter, if I hadn&apos;t been told so myself.

Temperature: Hot, as expected.

Appearance: All looked good. The cole slaw was on the plate itself instead of in a side dish.

Cost: Ocean perch dinner = $9.99

Value: The (10 oz.?) free beer (Miller Lite) along with the introductory soup (cheesy chicken enchilada) makes this one of the better values for a cod meal.

Other Comments: The soup choices were the enchilada or the traditional clam chowder. The enchilada tasted like a taco; it was very good.

The french fries are the downfall of this meal. They reminded me of the kind that one of the fast food chains switched to a few years ago that we really disliked.

The ketchup was in a Heinz upside down bottle. A lot of water came of before I finally got to the red stuff itself.

A dark, round dinner roll tasted sweet, even without any condiments, and almost made up for the bad french fries.

The three cod filets were so tender that I couldn&apos;t spear them with my fork. Normally you&apos;d think that&apos;s a good thing, but it made it very difficult to dip the fish into the bowl of tartar sauce.

Dining Date: 5/6/11 
What Do You Think about The Spot on Sunset?
 submit 

 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
Review Requests

Which restaurant should I review next?

Suggest which restaurant&apos;s fish fry I should review next.
 submit 
 Reply Erik Smith Jan 27, 2012 @ 8:54 pm | delete Spring City has a good fish fry for a family style place, check it out! Reply glsonn Jan 27, 2012 @ 9:25 pm | delete Thanks for the suggestion. We actually did have fish there, but I never got around to writing up the review. Reply agent009 Nov 27, 2011 @ 11:59 am | delete Actually, there are fish fries in other parts of the country for the same reason such as the Buffalo, NY region. Reply glsonn Nov 27, 2011 @ 1:30 pm | delete Thanks! That&apos;s good to know for road trips. 
 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
 8 Like 
 
 by glsonn 
 
 I&apos;m a husband, father, and grandfather who loves to play fun board games with friends and family and who wants to teach them to as many people as poss... more » 

 8 featured lenses Winner of 9 trophies ! Top lens» Waukesha Fish Fry 
 Feeling creative? Create a Lens! 
Explore related pages

 Panera Bread - A Restaurant Review Panera Bread - A Restaurant Review Quiz: French Terms On A Restaurant Menu Quiz: French Terms On A Restaurant Menu philippines fast fun food philippines fast fun food The Golden Corral (Akron, Ohio) The Golden Corral (Akron, Ohio) Judy&apos;s on Cherry: Hearth-fired Euro Cafe Judy&apos;s on Cherry: Hearth-fired Euro Cafe Johnny Carinos Italian Kitchen Johnny Carinos Italian Kitchen 
Related Tags

 Fish Fry diners best restaurants dining out restaurant restaurants waukesha wisconsin glsonn 
 
 TOS Originality Pact About Us SquidooHQ Charity Report Abuse Feedback&amp;Bugs 
 Copyright©2012,
 Squidoo, LLC and respective copyright owners This page and all the pages on Squidoo generate income for lensmasters and charities based on affiliate relationships with our partners, including Amazon, Google, eBay and others. Have fun. 
Want our Newsletter?
 Sign up! Notify me by email when new comments are added. 
 Enter Your Name to post as a vistor
 or Login 
 E-mail Address:   Post Comment Cancel
	</body>
</document>
