<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006978" url="http://www.gamewinners.com/playstation2/GrandTheftAutoViceCity-e.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="6" score="0.006025027567911332" bingtitle="Grand Theft Auto: Vice City glitches: Sony PlayStation2" webtitle="Grand Theft Auto: Vice City glitches: Sony PlayStation2">
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>Change size of garbage bags: Get a sniper rifle and ... bat, then get any car that has a passenger seat ... Enter a fast food restaurant with a wanted level.</description>
	<body>
		HOME | CHEATS | NEWS | REVIEWS | FORUMS 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 CHANNELS · ARCADE 
· DS 
· DVD 
· GAME BOY ADV 
· GAMECUBE 
· PC 
· PLAYSTATION2 
· PLAYSTATION3 
· PSP 
· WII 
· XBOX 
· XBOX 360 
· MORE... 
 
 


 
 THIS PAGE · EMAIL THIS 
· PRINTER VIEW 
· SUBMIT CODE 
 


 
 THIS SYSTEM · OTHER GAMES 
· REVIEWS 
· MESSAGES 
· NEW RELEASES 
· COMING SOON 
· TOP SELLERS 
 


 
 GAMING · NEWS 
· BOOKS/GUIDES 
· SALES 
· SEARCH 
 

 
Grand Theft Auto: Vice City cheats:
Glitches

 Note: Button presses are described in PlayStation2 version
format. Use the equivalent key on the PC keyboard or button on
the Xbox controller when playing that version. 
 Fly under Vice City: 
In the PlayStation2 version, get a helicopter (Hunter recommended),
and go to the front of the WK Chariot Hotel in the Downtown area.
This is the same hotel that was across from Candi Suxxx&apos;s and
Shrub&apos;s love nest. It is marked&quot;Vice Point Langer&quot;on the front. Take your helicopter and fly it under the front
awning. Basically, fly it directly up to the front door. Then,
hold X and fly straight up. You will fly through a fake
(non-solid) roof, and be inside the hotel. You can see the spiral
stairwell that you have to run up to take the photos in the Martha&apos;s
Mugshot mission from the outside. From there, fly downward and
you are now under the game map and can go anywhere. Note: Do not
fly too low or too high or you may appear above ground or end
up dying in the water.
 Nikadiemus . 
In the PlayStation2 version, go to your Mansion. If you have a
Sea Sparrow get into it. If not, try the helicopter on the roof.
From where the Sea Sparrow is located, turn around and go into
the pool area in the mansion. When in the pool area, fly up through
the roof. When you are completely above the ceiling of the pool
area, fly north towards the black box/room. When you are over
the brown underworld, press Square and go under the game
world. You can then fly anywhere under the water.
 Jon
Beck. 
Get a helicopter (Sea Sparrow recommended) and fly to Hyman Memorial
Stadium. Go to the entrance to the stadium in the helicopter.
Notice the balconies above the entrance. Go to the lowest balcony
and fly towards the middle. Rise up and you will go through the
ceiling. Then, turn sideways in the helicopter to drop yourself
inside the stadium. Lower yourself so that you would be below
ground level. Go to the left or the right out from under the stadium
and look up. You are now underwater. Go straight and you will
find yourself under the city. Feel free to explore everything
underwater in your helicopter and under the city. Note: Explore
the Ammu-Nation close to the stadium to see a picture.
 Bond2k48 . 
Enable the&quot;Dodo car&quot;and&quot;Car floats on water&quot;codes. Get a Rhino tank (using a code if desired). Use the Right
Analog-stick to aim the canon on the tank behind you. Drive
the tank and shoot at the same time. When you see the tank start
to float, pull the Left Analog-stick backwards while shooting.
Shooting the cannon gives the tank enough force to stay in the
air for a long time. Fly the tank to the striped building to the
right of the Vercetti Estate mansion (on the side of the airport).
Then, fly through the top of the building (where the roof should
be). You will hit the floor and fall through into the Vice City
underworld. You can now fly your tank under the entire island.
If you want to resurface, fly up through the water in the ocean.
You will not get hurt because of the&quot;Car floats on water&quot;code.
 TopNoTcHpLaYa123 . 
Go to the bridge that leads to the eastern island from Prawn Island
in a helicopter. The smaller the helicopter, the better. Fly under
that bridge, then face the eastern island and go up slightly.
You will realize that you can go through it. Then, go forward
towards the eastern island and squeeze through the small space.
You will now be under the city. To exit this glitch, either get
out of your helicopter or just fly very low.
 Dark Fish . 
 Fall from water to sky: 
Enable the&quot;Dodo flying&quot;and&quot;Float on water&quot;codes. Go into the water and drive around. Gain speed and fly
into the air. Try to flip your vehicle upside down in the water.
If done correctly, the car will sink and a clicking sound will
start. You and the vehicle will drop out of the sky and land somewhere
random in Vice City. Note: You may need to try this a few times
with different cars. If it does not work immediately, you will
die.
 Muff1nm4n . 
Enable the&quot;Float on water&quot;and&quot;Perfect handling&quot;codes. Find a Comet (recommended) or a Sabre Turbo. Drive the
car out to a deep spot, to the point where you are floating over
an underwater-rock formation. Back up slightly, drive forward,
and press L3 until you are vertical. This may require a
few attempts, and you may need to enable the&quot;Full health&quot;code. Your car will sink with you in it, but you will not get
hurt. You will continue falling until you respawn to a random
location. If you use the rock method, you can drive around on
the rock; however if you attempt to go into the sand your car
will begin to sink. You can also leave your car and walk on the
rock. If you or your car leave the rock, you will sink and respawn
at random, completely unharmed.
 Donutboy08 . 
 Walk underwater: 
Enable the&quot;Hilary costume&quot;and&quot;Sabre Turbo&quot;codes. Enable the&quot;Change wheel size&quot;code two or more
times. Note: This may also work with a Sabre Turbo from Sunshine
Autos. Get in the car, and you will not die when you drive into
the water. Once the car gets to the blue part on the bottom, it
falls through and appears back on the street. Also, if the car
stops while underwater (does not fall through), you can get out
and walk around.
 Adam Bellows . 
Get in the Sea Sparow behind the film studio on Prawn Island.
Do a back flip into the water and get out of the plane. Get back
in and try flipping it over to its other side. If done correctly,
you will be underwater without losing any health. You can get
out and walk around. Note: There is a sunken boat located under
the bridge by the film studio, near the far side of the bridge.
 Eric B . 
 Travel underwater: 
In the PlayStation2 version, get a Sabre Turbo, and enable the&quot;Floating car&quot;and&quot;Dodo car (flying)&quot;codes.
Get into the ocean and gain some speed. Fly straight up, then
immediately straight down so the nose of your car hits the water
in a vertical position. You must hold X the entire time
until you are underwater. You can hold Square underwater
to tread water. You will travel straight down underwater for approximately
thirteen seconds. You will then emerge with one wanted level or
more and your vehicle damaged, on a nearby location on land.
 LagunaSeca . 
Get a Comet and enable the&quot;Floating car&quot;code. Go in
the water and flip the Comet near one of the big rocks. You can
drive on them, then slowly drive off and it will go down. Hold
down the gas, and after a short time you will be placed on land,
with a lot of dirt in the air.
 UTPlayer2 . 
Enable the&quot;Change wheel size&apos;&apos; code three times. Get a Banshee
or Stinger. Those two cars get heavier and more powerful. Drive
to a water source and go in. You can then get out of your car
and take no health or armor damage. However, to exit the water
source you must be in your car or halfway back to dry land or
you will start drowning. It is now safe to go back in the water.
 Zach Berti . 
 Invisible water: 
Get a Tropic (boat). One can be found near the back of Links View
Apartments. Drive to open ocean and look through in first person
view at the ocean. Look through the glass to see that there is
no water and you can see straight to the bottom. This is useful
when trying to see the shark and various wrecks such as the submarine
and the cargo freighters.
 mattdapyro . 
 Drive through windows: 
Get a car and drive to the blue building beside the road that
leads to Starfish Island. Drive up the steps to any floor. Drive
up to a window. If you hit, you are in the wrong location. You
can drive through the window onto the ledge and pull off some
insane jumps. If you cannot find the window you can pass through,
go outside and find where the building is damaged, then return
and go out there.
 Harry Andrews . 
 Drive motorcycle underground:
 Get a motorcycle and go south of Little Havana. Immediately
before you get to first big blue and white boat, look to your
right .You will see a long, short white building with a green
roof. On one side of it is a rail .Run directly into the front
of it with a little speed. You and your bike should appear to
fall under Vice City. After a few seconds you should appear back
in the middle of the road. You can repeat this as many times as
desired.
 Hayley Belliveau . 
 Get to other islands early:
 Enable the&quot;Dodo car (flying)&quot;and&quot;Cars
float on water&quot;codes. Go to Cortez&apos;s pier in a car and glide
over the barrier. The car should float on the water. Once you
have done this, drive on the water to the other island. You can
then fly onto the island. Buy a safe house there and use helicopters
to get to and from the islands.
 Ian
Garden. 
 Wedge vehicles into ground:
 Enable the&quot;Change Wheel Size&quot;code three
to five times and the&quot;Better Handling&quot;code. Get a
Sabre Turbo, Banshee, Comet or Stinger. Find a straight piece
of road, such as the one from Viceport to Downtown. Gain some
speed. When you are up to speed, look on the opposite side of
the road (left when heading north or right when heading south.
Look for a car such as a Landstalker, Perennial, or other&quot;light&quot;vehicle. Hit it head on. If done correctly, the front end should
be in the ground and the vehicle will be stuck. Also, if you hit
it at the correct speed and angle, you will jump into the air
and the vehicle you hit will be stuck in the ground on fire. This
may require some practice. Note: Do not hit cars with big wheels
such as the Infernus or Cheetah, because it will not work and
may flip you upside down with no way of flipping back over.
 peraltap . 
 Restore destroyed car:
 If you get a car that you want to save and it explodes
in front of your garage, push the body of the car into the garage
and walk away. Then, stand in front of the garage door. It will
open and your car will be like new.
 Frank . 
 Look through walls:
 Take a rocket launcher and run into a wall. Turn around,
hold R1 and turn towards the building. You should see through
it.
 SKildau . 
 Walk inside a bridge:
 Go to the film studio on Prawn Island and take the
Skimmer (seaplane). Go beneath the bridge to the right and stop
under the lowest part of it. Get out of the plane and you will
be inside the bridge. Sometimes you can even walk around, but
will fall through the ground and end up back on the streets.
 pieter moonen . 
 Kill people through window:
 Enter a building that has windows. You can kill people
outside throw the windows by using a flamethrower.
 Janinus . 
 Knockout instead of kill:
 If you shoot one of the people around your mansion
and other important properties in the head, it will only knock
them out for a moment.
 Lincoln Humphry . 
 Invisible hostage:
 Get a hostage in your car. If you get out, run around
to the passenger&apos;s side and throw him or her out. He will just
sit there. When you get in the car, you will hear screams as though
you have a hostage. As you pull away the screams will fade. The
person will not move from where they are unless you lose the car.
 Wazabam . 
 See through any solid object:
 Get a rocket launcher and walk up to any building.
When Tommy touches wall, press the Analog-stick just enough
so that he turns around. Hold R1 and turn back towards
the wall to see through it.
 Seymour Butts 
 Change size of the moon:
 Use the sniper rifle at night, zoom in on the moon,
then shoot it. It will get bigger or smaller.
 Bittman . 
 Change size of garbage bags:
 Get a sniper rifle and zoom in on a group of two garbage
bags. Start shooting at them to make one very big and the other
very small.
 the ryester . 
 Lose extra health from prostitute:
 If you use a prostitute to get your health above 100
and go to a save point, your health will drop back to 100 when
you exit the save point.
 guywhelan . 
 Lose extra health with a prostitute:
 After you complete the Pizza Boy mission and get 150
health, if you pick up a prostitute, your health will drop to
125 immediately. Thus, after the Pizza Boy missions, there is
no longer a point of getting a prostitute for health gain.
 The Gamer . 
 Prostitute follows you:
 Get a fast, expensive sports car (Cheetah, Infernus,
etc.) at night. Pick up a prostitute from anywhere. Make sure
that she approaches the driver&apos;s side of the car. When she gets
to about the middle of the front or the back of the car, get out.
Wherever she is at, she should run directly to you. She should
follow you everywhere you go on foot and in the car. She will
not get in the car, but she will run behind. Also, she will stay
along with you the entire day, and will not disappear as usual
when the sun rises. You can get as many prostitutes to follow
you as desired.
 Oz1291 . 
 Never ending session with prostitute:
 Steal any two door car. Pick up a prostitute and drive
to any grassy area with a wall nearby. Drive up to the wall and
park your car with your passenger&apos;s side against it. The prostitute
will&quot;do her thing&quot;as usual, but after your car rocks
the final time, the prostitute will not get out of the car, and
will squeal and scream endlessly. You can let this go on forever,
as your money will stop counting down after the final rock. The
best place for this is near the Pole Position Club. All variety
of prostitutes frequent the area, and there is a little grassy
alley behind some bushes immediately across the street from Ocean
Heights Apartment.
 JoeDaddy. 
 Stand on car in mid-air:
 When you go over a ramp or jump, open your car door
in mid-air. You will get out and will be standing on the car while
it is floating in mid-air.
 RulinDAWomen699 . 
This can also be done by driving off a bridge and bailing out
in mid-air.
 Lnierenb . 
 Sink through a car:
 Get a Packer, and drive a motorcycle on top of it.
Exit the motorcycle and you will sink through the packer as if
it was not there. You will then pop up next to it.
 the ryester . 
 Vehicles disappearing from garage:
 Vehicles stored in the garages at the Hyman Condo complex
can disappear from them if you take the helicopter on the roof
and return later.
 Kevin Halacy . 
 Store more than two cars or motorcycles
in garage:
 When you have two cars or motorcycles in your garage
at your safe house, you usually will not be able to store any
vehicles inside. To get around this, get off the car or motorcycle
in front of the full garage. The garage will open. Get on your
motorcycle or into your car quickly and drive it into the garage
before the door closes.
 Brian
Roth. 
Buy a house with a garage, then get a car. Put the car in the
garage doorway, and make sure there is more room for the other
cars. Get out of the car, with it still in the doorway. The garage
door will remain open. You can now fit a few motorcycles or another
car in the garage. Then, move the car that is in the doorway out
of the way.
 NeoPetzIzCool. 
 Get more than two motorcycles into a single
garage:
 Get a motorcycle and drive it to a garage with two
other motorcycles. Drive your motorcycle to the garage and get
off to open the garage door. Then, get back on and drive it in
before the garage door has a chance to shut. When you save the
game, the third motorcycle will remain in the garage.
 Kittiesaresoft2 . 
 Save in a vehicle:
 In the PlayStation2 version, go to any save icon and
park a vehicle so when you get out, it will save. Cancel the save
then press Triangle to get in. The game will save while
you are in the vehicle.
 Raptor . 
Warning: This may freeze your game or cause it not to load.
 Tommy . 
 Re-appearing cars:
 If you have any vehicles in a garage, you can blow
it up into scrap metal. If the metal is in the garage, make the
garage door close. Once you have it open again, the car that was
destroyed will appear again, while the scrap metal of the car
that was destroyed is still there.
 NOS. 
 Slower cars with faster speed:
 Get a slow car (Washington, Glendale, etc.) and shoot
the tires out on it. Then, shoot the windshield out and get in
the car. Hold the hand brake and the gas at the same time for
about five to ten seconds then release the hand brake. At first
you will slide all over the street and sparks will be flying everywhere.
Hold the car going through turns and try to keep it straight to
get faster speed than before.
 Chase Gupton . 
 Cheaper Pay N&apos; Spray:
 In the PlayStation2 version, pull into the Pay N&apos; Spray
garage. Hold the brakes when pressing Triangle and get
out of the garage. Repeat this for however many cars you can fit
into the Pay N&apos; Spray. You will be charged for only one paint
job although more than one vehicle was painted.
 Samie J . 
Drive a flaming ambulance into a Pay N&apos; Spray, get out, and destroy
it. While it is in there and before it disappears, drive another
car of any type into the Pay N&apos; Spray. You will get a free pain
job, but the car will disappear.
 Jester . 
 Car drives itself:
 Drive fast towards a Pay N&apos; Spray and bail out, making
the car roll in by itself. Get another car and park it where the
door closes. Get in the car that you rolled into the garage. The
door will try to close on the car in the doorway, but cannot.
Instead, it will shoot out the car that was in the way at a tremendous
speed out of the garage while the car you are in gets sprayed.
 ED . 
Get a baseball bat, then get any car that has a passenger seat
(Caddy recommended). If you have a car with a door, use the bat
to break it off, or lose the door any way desired. When the doors
are off, drive along the road and get someone to steal your car
through the passenger side. Just as they get into the car, drive
away. You should stay in the car and the thief will drive around
Vice City with you inside. Note: You will be in the driver&apos;s seat
but will be invisible. Press Triangle to get out when desired
and the car will stop slowly.
 James Meeking . 
 Never fall off motorcycle:
 In the PlayStation2 version, take a PCG 600 to a clothes
shop. The easiest one is&quot;Collar And Cuffs&quot;with the&quot;Mr. Vercetti&quot;outfit. Get off the motorcycle, and get
the outfit. Once it is gone, place the motorcycle parallel to
the edge of the small steps, so that the clothes still respawn.
Once you do this, get on the motorcycle at the exact moment when
you buy the clothes. You will be stuck the motorcycle as though
the game merged you into it. This now allows you to drive around
safely without worry of falling off. Also, it lets you use an
assault riffle as a drive-by weapon. However, once you fire the
gun, the bike will return to normal, allowing you to fall off
again and disabling the gun. However, as long as you hold Circle ,
you will still shoot assault rifle. This glitch can also be done
with other motorcycles.
In the PlayStation2 version, in order to do this glitch, you need
to be in a point in the game where your cell phone is ringing.
Also, you will need any motorcycle. Go to Rafael&apos;s and get off
your bike. If your cell phone is ringing, hold L1 . While
holding L1 , walk over and get the clothes icon, then get
back on the bike. You must hold L1 the entire time. Drive
off and release L1 . The screen should turn black, and you
will then should be standing up, as if you were not on the bike.
You can pull wheelies all the way back and not fall off. You can
also do a lot insane stunt bonuses that you otherwise would be
incapable of doing. While on the motorcycle, switch to grenades
or molotov cocktails to throw them off. Note: The cocktails will
heavily damage your bike. This trick also works in cars, and you
can see Tommy&apos;s legs appearing from the bottom.
 BenDroSkateORama . 
 Haunted motorcycle:
 Have someone as a passenger on your motorcycle. Drive
up north to Hyman Memorial Stadium. As you are facing the stadium
from the adjacent street, turn left on the first street that loops
around and drive through the grass. Go through the two palm trees
all the way to the last telephone pole. Turn to the right and
you will see the ocean. As you look to the ground, you can see
a ledge of land underneath the layer of water. Ride the bike over
to the ledge, trying not to fall into the ocean. You will notice
that your life will begin to drain. Be careful not to go in too
deep. As soon as you hear your passenger moan, get out. You will
notice a pile of blood underneath. If you are lucky, you might
get a trail of blood every time you accelerate. If you get off,
the passenger will still be on the bike. After a while he/she
will disappear. You will notice that if you accelerate and try
to jump off the bike, it will just brake. Also, notice the person
shows up with some camera angles. If you walk to the back of your
bike, a trail of bloody footprints will be left behind as you
go forward. Note: This was done with an Angel and a bodyguard
(Tommy&apos;s henchman in a blue shirt) that you can get completing
the game 100%.
 Taco . 
Find a motorcycle with two people and knock them both off. Get
on the bike, allow the previous passenger to board, and ditch
the previous driver. Drive the bike with passenger to the beach.
Back up right to the coastline. With the back of the bike facing
the water, slowly back the bike into the water. At some depth,
the water causes damage to you, and your passenger will die. You
can then drive out clean, but you may notice some strange resistance
and/or bumping. This is because the passenger&apos;s body is trapped
inside the bike. In some cases, the passenger disappears and reappears
from behind you. The bike will continuously have bloody wheels.
You can now drive the bike wherever desired, leaving a trail of
bloody tracks. If you get off the bike and remount it, the passenger
will still be inside. If you bail, in some cases the passenger
will not fall off the back (which means the bike never lands on
its side). However, in some cases he does, which causes his bloody
corpse to smack the ground, along with any money or items he may
have been carrying. While riding the haunted bike you cannot do
the jump-bail off the back. Also, you can combine this code with
the&quot;Never fall off motorcycle&quot;glitch, if you perform
this one first.
 Jaquio . 
 Woman stuck in motorcycle:
 Enable the&quot;Tommy Groupies&quot;code and get
any motorcycle (Sanchez recommended). Get a lot of women to follow
you. Run over a few, but do not kill them. When they try to get
back up, one should get stuck in a wheel. Note: You can do wheelies
and stoppies and she still will not fall off. The only way she
will fall off the wheel is if you crash.
 Swift M. . 
 Motorcycle as sniper platform:
 Drive a motorcycle along the road that Sunshine Autos
is on. Drive sideways up the hill across from Sunshine Autos,
and while the motorcycle is sideways in the air, get off. Your
motorcycle will usually freeze in midair, and if you are lucky,
you will be on top of it and can use it as a sniper platform.
If a policeman comes under you, shoot the motorcycle to make it
fall on him and he will occasionally be decapitated.
 thuggd_out03 . 
 Morph into car:
 The effect of this glitch is similar to the&quot;Never
fall off motorcycle&quot;glitch, except with a hoodless car.
Find a hoodless car and park it near the clothes. Get it near
your door. When you get out, you will automatically change clothes.
Get back and wait for a response, then go on the driver&apos;s side
(make sure you closed the door) by the back of the car and press Triangle . Tommy will jump into the car and change clothes
at the same time. You will be morphed into the car. The only cars
that this will work on are the Comet, Stallion (hoodless), and
Stinger. Your feet will appear under the car. Also, it is easier
to park the car so that the clothes are actually touching you
when you in the car. Then, get out, auto change, and when it reappears,
go back in. When you press Forward + Up or some
buttons, you will teleport and return to where you were. If you
morphed into the car and get out, aim with the rocket launcher.
You will zoom in and out and move around.
 ViCeCiTyPlAyEr5 . 
Take the helicopter from the Hyman Condo and fly to the clothes
icon. Fly it so you have three quarters of icon in by joystick.
Get out and make sure you leave the door open. As soon as you
start entering, press X . You should leave the door open
and start flying up. If done correctly, you should see Tommy&apos;s
legs sticking out of the helicopter.
 Kevin Warner . 
 Vehicle stuck in a telephone pole:
 Enable the&quot;Change wheel size&quot;code three
times and get a Saber Turbo. Gain speed and drive into a wooden
telephone pole. You should get stuck and get a new car.
 Crayola110 . 
Get a Rhino, turn the barrel 180 degrees, and shoot while driving
to go faster. Drive into one of the brown telephone poles that
cannot be knocked down. You will occasionally get stuck with the
pole through the middle of the tank. Your health will drain until
you die, unless you can get out.
 thuggd_out03 . 
 Extreme exhaust special effect:
 Go to Little Havana and get a Cuban Hermes. Take that
car and drive it so it is on the wrong side of the highway in
Little Havana, facing the Downtown area. Accelerate at full throttle
so that you fly into downtown on two or four wheels (depending
on how fast you are going). Go straight so that you are facing
Ammunation. There is a huge set of staircases on your right. Drive
on to the stairs carefully, but not releasing X the entire
time. Release X when you are three quarters of the way
up. Then, once in the air, press then tap X (air revving).
You should see flames coming out of the exhaust pipes until you
land on the surface ahead. Note: You may want to practice with
a car that has less slippery handling before attempting this jump.
 Niapretsam . 
 Free money in taxi without a passenger:
 When you start the taxi mission, try to pick up a person
next a police officer and get one star. Stop next the police officer
and make sure he approaches your car from the passenger side (where
the person you picked up should be sitting). As soon the cop opens
the door, speed away. The cop will pull out your passenger, but
the game will think that he is still in the taxi. Upon arrival
at the location which the passenger specified, you will be awarded
money, as if he was still in the car.
 The Gamer . 
 Partially destructible taxi:
 Fail a mission by getting wasted to resume at a hospital.
A taxi will be waiting outside to pick you up. Do not go in it.
Instead, jack a car, then ram the cab on the right side. Notice
that this side is indestructible. However, the left side can be
destroyed.
 DDarkKnight90M . 
 Sit in taxi with no driver:
 Get wasted during a mission. You will end up at a hospital.
Near the hospital, you should find a taxi with a pink arrow pointing
down at it. Get a flamethrower (use the&quot;Weapons tier 1&quot;code if needed). Get beside the taxi and flame it. Immediately
when you flame the taxi, get in it. The driver should get out
screaming, and you will be stuck in the back seat (or passenger
seat) with no driver in front. At this point, all you can do is
turn the taxi missions on and off and get an extra passenger in
the passenger seat.
 Joel Samuels . 
 Angry SUVs:
 Ride a PCJ600 and get behind three SUVs and a Stinger
stuck at a red light. Shoot the Stinger to make it drive into
the back SUV, then shoot it again until it is on fire. Drive quickly
to a place where you can view the havoc from a distance. When
the Stinger explodes, the SUVs will not explode as they should.
However, they will turn and circle you, trying to kill you. Some
might disappear, but they never all leave.
 Jonathan Asbell . 
 Coach bumper shed:
 Buy the Hyman Condo then steal a Coach. Bring the Coach
to Hyman Condos and put it in a garage at an angle. Leave the
garage and repeatedly reopen and shut the door. The back bumper
of the Coach will keep falling off.
 paulr2005 . 
 Infernus engine smoke:
 When you are in the Infernus and get the engine to
start smoking, the car will smoke from the front. However, its
engine is in the back and the trunk is up front.
 The Game . 
 Flippy Maverick:
 Enable the&quot;Cars Float On Water&quot;code. Steal
the News Maverick. Take off and go over a body of wide, deep water.
Land on the water, then press the Left Analog-stick Back and hold it. In a moment you should be underwater. Note: It is
always useful to enable the&quot;Health&quot;code. When you
turn back over, you should be flipping wildly. This also works
in any other direction, however backwards is always best.
 Keith Simmons . 
 Wheeled Maverick:
 Fly a regular Maverick into the Pay N Spray and go
at Sunshine Autos. It will get four wheels.
 some freakin awesome kid that you probably know . 
 Zebra taxi damage immunity:
 For some reason, the entire Zebra taxi can appear damaged
except for the passenger side. The two doors on the passenger
side cannot get scratched or removed, other than when the entire
vehicle explodes.
 The Gamer . 
 Wrecked flying helicopter:
 In the PlayStation2 version, ,get three or more stars
on your wanted meter and have a rocket launcher ready. When the
police helicopter appears, hit it with a rocket. Immediately enable
the&quot;Lower wanted level&quot;code, but do not press Down to complete the cheat until after you here the helicopter explode.
Once you hear it explode, press Down to complete the code.
Look up in the sky to see the destroyed helicopter flying away.
 Meccablue85 . 
 Wildly spinning helicopter:
 Get the V.C.N. chopper at the V.C.N. building at the
Downtown area. Enable the&quot;Cars float on water&quot;code.
Go to any deep part of the ocean then fly as high as possible.
Make sure you do not have any objects surrounding you for about
100 feet, then press nothing except the Left Analog-stick all the way Back or Forward . You should plummet
into the water upside-down, then quickly pop back up spinning
and twirling in the air uncontrollably. If you want to stop, the
next time you pop up on the surface, hold X . Note: This
may require several attempts.
 Niapretsam . 
 Boat with wheels:
 Get a boat and drive it very fast on the coast and
to land on the ground. Push it with a car to make it move. It
will move easier when pushed from the back. To turn it, run into
its sides. Enable the&quot;Health&quot;code to prevent it from
exploding, as pushing will damage it severely. Push it into a
Pay &apos;N&apos; Spray and it will have wheels after the doors open again.
 Fishchicken . 
 Drive boat upside down:
 When your are walking near the Malibu Club, on the
other side of the river is a boat. Enable the&quot;Better driving
skills&quot;code and get the boat. Try to flip the boat by hitting
the dock. You will flip and be able to drive upside down. The
steering controls will be reversed. To get out, go near the dock
and press Triangle . You will appear on the top of the boat.
Jump on the dock or any other place of land.
 Gokartracerbmw . 
 Floating signs:
 When you destroy the Dodo plane, the sign that it tows
around will keep floating. There are only two ways you can blow
it up; either with the Sea Sparrow or Hunter helicopter. Get behind
the Dodo (but not too close to avoid getting damaged), then start
firing at it. As soon as it explodes, you will see the banner
start floating around.
 simar69 . 
 Floating people:
 Go to the Starfish Island mansion and go to the jetty.
Enable in&quot;Weapons (tier 2)&quot;code. Slash someone with
your katana. If they are afraid to fight, they will more then
likely jump in to the water and kill themselves. Take out the
grenades than lob one so that it goes under the dead person and
detonates. When you have done this, the person will be floating
in the air. Note: This may require a few attempts. You cannot
take too long to do this, or the person will disappear.
 bid jonny jonhson . 
During the mission where you have to fly the mini-planes with
bombs on the bottom in the Cuban boats, get to where the boats
are located. You will a Cuban sitting on the steps. Roll backwards
down the hill to push him. Push him away from the steps and he
will remaining sitting in mid-air.
 Reddevil080 . 
Play the Haitian Gang mission where you have to fly the remote
control airplanes to the Cubans and sink their boats. Before you
do this, go to the Cuban sitting on the steps near the boats.
Accelerate the plane forward so you push him away from the steps.
He should be still sitting, but not on anything. You do this with
others in town (for example, a pedestrian sitting on a bench).
 Tony right . 
 Shoot people in the air:
 Get a fire truck and run over two people. Make sure
there are no cops around. When the ambulance arrives and the paramedics
start to do CPR, press the Circle and aim the water at
them. You should push them away. Wait a few seconds and they should
pop high into the air and fall back down alive.
 Kevin Warner . 
 Floating car:
 Go to the parking garage next to the mall and find
an Infernus. They are usually very abundant in the garage. Drive
up to the very top level. There is a ramp placed on the northwest
corner of the roof that you can ramp off of. Immediately before
you hit the ramp after gaining an exceptional amount of speed,
veer to the left. Your vehicle should flip sideways while flying
through the air (the driver&apos;s side facing up). Immediately when
this happens, bail out of the vehicle. By doing so, the car will
stop in mid air and you will be standing on top of it. You do
not have to perform it with the Infernus, but, due to that car&apos;s
speed and shape, it is the most effective. If you bail out of
the car and did not do it correctly, you will likely to take a
considerable amount of damage due to the fall.
 Narthumpulous . 
 Disappearing cashier:
 Go to the North Point Mall. Then, go over to one of
the restaurants in the mall. This trick requires a gun that can
automatically aim. Aim your gun at the cashier, which will make
him raise his hands. Stop aiming at him, then aim at him again.
This will force him to take a step back. Repeat this until the
cashier backs up so far that he will fall through the floor and
disappear.
 Buck5307 . 
 Headless driver:
 Find a Ruger or a Sniper. Look for any car, get in
front of it, and make it stop. Make sure only one person is inside
the car. Shoot the person in the head and run quickly to the driver&apos;s
side door. Use the rear view ( L1 + R1 ) and move
the car slightly. Watch as the headless driver walks to you.
 The Gamer . 
Go up to a stopped car (mostly at a red light), Take out a machine
gun, aim, and shoot the driver&apos;s head off. Quickly enter the car
through the passenger&apos;s side. When you are in the driver side,
drive off. The&quot;headless&quot;driver will still be standing,
but then fall on the ground.
 Lil&apos; K101 . 
 Free stripper at Pole Position:
 To get a free dance, go into the room where you have
to press X to exit. Hold X the entire time and you
will not pay the stripper.
 andy storkson . 
Note: You cannot change camera angles with this in effect.
 Niapretsam . 
 Phil Cassidy&apos;s missing arm:
 During the first intermission sequence in the Boomshine
Saigon mission, Phil gets one of his arms blown off by the bomb
he placed on the boomshine barrels. Continue the mission and get
Phil to the doctor. Watch as he gets out of the car. The arm that
he blew off is now switched with his other arm.
 Jamie Weir . 
 Regenerating people:
 To see people appear out of the middle of nowhere,
aim the sniper rifle in the distance at a sidewalk or a road.
People will just appear and walk around.
 the ryester . 
 Shoot manual aim weapons with the auto
aim system:
 It is highly recommended that you earn the fire-proof
ability, as you will be catching yourself on fire in order to
do this glitch. Get Molotov Cocktails from Downtown. Equip the
Molotov Cocktail on a busy street then step away from pedestrians
and catch yourself on fire. While on fire, switch to an M4, M60,
or Ruger and try using the targeting system. You will notice that
instead of manual aiming with the white crosshairs, Tommy will
use the auto-aiming system, as with the regular guns such as the
pistol, sub-machine guns, etc. Do this to make your aiming a lot
easier. You can switch the auto-aiming crosshair to different
targets by holding L2 or R2 . Also, you really never
get to see the M4, M60, or Ruger in action but will have a new
angle. You can shoot heavy guns and get a good look at them. When
you release the button to target the effect wears off and you
must catch yourself on fire again. One recommended place to witness
these weapons at the new angle is at the El Corrupto Banco in
Little Havana. Step behind the counter, catch yourself on fire,
equip the desired weapon, then wait for pedestrians or cops to
spawn.
 Yung Yung . 
 Unlimited ammunition:
 If you keep getting the same amount of weapons repeatedly
and get the amount of ammunition over a certain number, the game
will not be able to display that high amount causes it to give
you unlimited ammunition. Here are the limits for the guns/explosives.
 Warren . Slot 4: Explosives
 Grenades: 1,000
Teargas: 1,000
Molotov:1,000
Bomb/Detonator:1,000 Slot 5: Handguns
 Colt 45:10,000
Colt Python: 10,000 Slot 6: Shotguns
 Chromed Shotgun: 10,000
Spaz Shotgun: 10,000
Stubby Shotgun: 10,000 Slot 7: Uzis
 TEC-9: 10,000
Ingram Mac 10: 10,000
Uzi 9mm: 10,000
MP5: 10,000 Slot 8: Assault Rifles
 Ruger: 10,000
Colt M4: 10,000 Slot 9: Heavy Metal
 Rocket Launcher: 10,000
Flame-Thrower: 10,000
M60: 10,000
Minigun: 10,000 Slot 10: Snipers
 Sniper Rifle: 10,000
PSG-1: 10,000 
 Unlimited Colt .45 ammunition:
 If you have a Colt .45 in your weapon slot and complete
The Shootist mission with a score of 70 or more, it will have
unlimited ammunition.
 Sinocord . 
 Unlimited submachine gun ammunition:
 If you had a submachine gun like the Uzi or Ingram
with lots of ammunition (for example, 5000) and you are now low,
you can get it all back by stealing a PCJ-600. Waste the rest
of the ammunition while still on the bike. When it is all gone,
drive through the electronic gate at the golf course. It will
reappear behind it, with the highest amount of ammunition you
had before using it all.
 cf1989 . 
 Floating road blocks:
 Go into an alley that has orange road blocks. Start
shooting them and moving them around. Walk a few blocks away and
when you return they should be floating in the air.
 the ryester . 
 Taxi driver pickup:
 In the PlayStation2 version, steal any taxi cab and
immediately press R3 to start a taxi mission. The person
you are supposed to pick up is often the taxi cab driver you just
pulled out.
 Drake . 
 Dive a blown up car:
 Go to the driver side of a car and pull the person
out. While you are pulling him out, start the&quot;Destroy all
cars&quot;code until you get to the last L2 . When you
start to shut the door, press L1 to finish the code. If
done correctly, you can drive what appears to be a wrecked car.
 Martinrollin . 
 No stars for police collision:
 Normally, if you hit a cop car while driving your wanted
level will increase. However, if you are driving and hit the cop
head-on, there are no repercussions (no wanted level increase,
no cops chasing you around, etc.) This may be helpful in missions
that are time-sensitive if you can make sure to hit the cops head-on.
 S c o t t . 
 No stars for shooting police cars:
 Find a cop car and stop it, either by standing in front
of it or putting a car in its way. Shoot out the cop car&apos;s tires
or any car tires around you. The police will not take any action.
 Jerm . 
 No stars for killing:
 Practice flying any helicopter and when you are comfortable
controlling it, take it to a spot with a lot of people, such as
any part of the beach on the eastern island. Rest the helicopter
on the ground without getting out and tilt it left or right so
that the blades are spinning closer to the ground and chop up
the pedestrians. Kill as many pedestrians or cops as desired.
On the beach near the lighthouse is a rampage where you must run
over 20 or 30 gang members. You can use a helicopter and chop
them up and the game will still count them as kills.
 Gregg Davidson . 
 Mid-air skid marks:
 Get a motorcycle (PCJ 600 recommended) and find a Packer
driving down the road. Stay directly behind its ramp, just keeping
up with it. Suddenly, hit the gas but do not launch off the top
of the Packer -- just roll back down the ramp in reverse to see
your skid mark floating in the air.
 the ryester . 
Get a Packer and park a car on top of it. Drive the Packer in
reverse so that the car falls off the top of it. The car will
leave a big skid mark hanging in the middle of the air.
 the ryester . 
 Water skid marks:
 Enable the&quot;Car floats on water&quot;code, then
take the bus out on the water. Drive at top speed, hit the brakes,
and look at the water behind the bus.
 Dellas. 
 Climb a tree:
 Go to where a beach or a body of water is located.
There should be some palm trees nearby. Find one that is bent
(or curved) and try to climb it. Note: Do not run up the tree
or you will fall in -- walk slowly. When you get close to the
top, slow down. If you continue walking, you will fall.
 Oz1291 . 
 Aim with cell phone:
 In the PlayStation2 version, when the phone is ringing,
equip yourself with any kind of auto-aiming weapon (such as a
pistol). Press R1 to aim it at a random pedestrian. While
still holding R1 , press L1 to answer the phone.
Tommy will continue to aim in the same spot, though now he is
using the cell phone instead of the gun. You may release R1 and he will continue to aim at the same spot, even if the pedestrian
moves. Note: Depending on how you move, he may switch between
holding the phone to his ear, and pointing it at the blank spot
that the pedestrian used to occupy.
 Drache Yen . 
 Shoot yourself:
 In the PlayStation2 version, get a semi-automatic weapon
(Uzi recommended) on an Angel or a Freeway. Look left and press Square to reverse and Circle to shoot. You will
appear to be shooting yourself.
 Cool1 . 
In the PlayStation2 version, this trick requires a Colt .45 (a
regular handgun). Stand still, then fire. When he raises his arm
to fire, rotate the Left Analog-stick . If done correctly,
he should shoot himself. No damage is taken though. This may take
a few attempts.
 Thomas Howard . 
Get a PCJ and go to an open area so that you can turn around.
Get any submachine gun you can do a drive-by with. Get on the
PCJ and go in reverse. Turn to the right and look left. Your gun
should be under Tommy&apos;s stomach. Press Circle to shoot.
Tommy willl shoot himself. Note: This will deduct health.
 david hastings . 
 Kick or punch through glass:
 Enter a fast food restaurant with a wanted level. The
cops might try to shoot you through the window. Jump up on a table
and stand in front of the glass window. You can kick and punch
them through the glass if they are standing close enough.
 Andy . 
 Die without&quot;Wasted&quot;message:
 In the PlayStation2 version, drive the remote controlled
AI plane right next to the car and press Circle . The plane
will blow up and the car will light on fire. When it goes back
to its normal mode, it will not give you a chance to quickly get
out and away from the car. It will start you back in front of
the hospital. A white screen to show you have been blown up and
you have died will appear, but it will not show the word&quot;Wasted&quot;on your screen at any time.
 will Capps . 
 Get arrested without a wanted level:
 Get a wanted level near a cop. Get at least a level
one wanted level and wait for the cop to come up to the driver&apos;s
side door. Quickly enable the first part of the&quot;Lower wanted
level&quot;code. Do not move at all. When the cop is by the door
press Down to finish the code. If done correctly, the cop
should still pull you out and arrest you, even with your wanted
level canceled. Note: Try this during Mr. Whoopee runs because
your wanted level raises with every three to four deliveries.
 junkdoodle101 . 
 Weapon stuck on detonator:
 After you get a 100% completion, the game awards you
with unlimited ammunition, among other things. This causes a glitch
if you get the bombs from Phil&apos;s Place or the car bomb from 8
Ball&apos;s. The weapon selector gets stuck on the detonator. Do not
use these weapons after you get a 100% rating.
 Scott Glandon . 
 Talk to weapon:
 If you do not have any weapons and someone calls, pick
it up. Then, enter a weapon code. After it is active, Tommy will
have a sword, pistol, or some other weapon and will be talking
to it instead of the phone.
 warlord2080 . 
 Fall off the world:
 Get on a bike and ride it fast towards a clothes store.
Jump off, and it will stop just inside the doorway. Run inside
and jump on the bike, then onto the door. Jump in any direction
and you will fall or float depending on which direction you go.
You will then land back outside the store.
 dale annous . 
 Double Tommy image:
 In the PlayStation2 version, get any driveable vehicle
such as a car or bike. Then, go to Kaufman Cabs before that business
has been bought. Take the car and drive it to the green arrow.
Place it at an angle so that when you get in, the&quot;Do you
want to purchase property? Press L1&quot;message will appear.
When you are halfway in the car, press L1 .When the intermission
sequence appears, you will see Tommy in the car. Note: This works
if you are using a bike, because you can see the image of him
better. It is possible to get a helicopter, Rhino, or Hunter in
the intermission sequence. Also, enable the&quot;Invisible cars&quot;code to get a better view of him when in the vehicle.
 Meccablue85 . 
 Downtown: Invisible ground above Hyman
Memorial Stadium:
 Drive a Rhino and get about five stars on your wanted
meter so that the FBI is chasing you. Enable the&quot;Dodo (flying)
car&quot;code and turn the turret of the Rhino so that it is
pointing backwards. Keep firing it to gain a lot of speed and
begin to fly. Keep firing it and fly around to the stadium. You
will need a good amount of altitude when flying over the stadium.
If you have a five star wanted level, you should see some FBI
Ranchers that seem to be driving on nothing. That is the invisible
ground. You will have to drop down onto it from the top, then
enable the&quot;Lower wanted level&quot;code to get rid of the
FBI. By the sounds that the invisible ground makes and its width,
it appears to be the terrain used for the HotRing without all
of the textures.
 nmtguy . 
 Downtown: Fall through world:
 While on a motorcycle do jumps at the dirt bike course.
If you go behind the course and keep riding, you will eventually
come out under a bridge. Speed up rapidly. Turn to the right or
you will smash into a wall and fly into the ocean and die. Because
of the extreme acceleration, you will not be able to turn in time.
You will smash to the side of the wall after the two girders which
hold up the bridge. Sparks will fly and the world as you see it
will be inverted. Your bike suddenly disappears and you will fall
down into blue hell. Tommy will flop around as if falling into
the ocean and the screen will shake rapidly. You suddenly find
yourself on the road next to the bridge with your bike a close
distance away. This can also happen behind the arena. There is
a large parking lot behind the arena. There are many curves because
it goes around the entire building. Accelerate on your bike and
repeat the stunt. Only try to turn where there is a sharp curve.
The same thing should happen as with the bridge.
 TheMoldyBurrito . 
Drive to the right of the Hyman Memorial Stadium and into the
parking lot. You must have a small car and enable the&quot;Car
floats on water&quot;code. As you drive, count the arrows. When
you get the eighth arrow, turn right. If you are at the correct
location, you will have turned north. Drive to the wall. The wall
is transparent and your car will fall through it. Then, turn around
and drive directly into it. Keep driving and you will hit a spot
where you will begin falling through the water. You will fall
through and appear back in front of the stadium.
 Seymour Butts . 
Take a Reefer boat to the wall where you can fall through the
world at Hyman Stadium and drive through it. The boat will get
stuck. Press Triangle , go to the end of the boat, and jump
off. You will pop through the concrete and lose five health points.
 Seymour Butts . 
Go up to the north side of Hyman Memorial Stadium in a small boat.
Pass the helipad and drive the boat along the half-walls by the
stadium. Slowly bump into the walls. You will eventually hit a
wall that you can sink through. Drive farther and you will fall
through the world and appear in front of the stadium.
 Seymour Butts 
 Downtown: Walk through wall:
 Starting at the Hyman condo, turn in the direction
of the stadium. Instead of going straight, turn left. Keep going
and you should pass Schuman Health Care Center. Shortly down the
road (still going straight), there will be a black driveway going
up slightly. Just before that is a small tan road. Turn on this
and move a very small distance. To your left, you will see a black
platform with a door on it. Go onto the platform. You can go through
the corner of this platform. The building that you just entered
is the health care center that you passed earlier.
 Cryptkiller5 . 
 Downtown: Drive through wall:
 In the parking lot at Hyman Memorial Stadium is a wall
that you can go through. It is one of the half walls that are
supposed to stop you from going into the wall. If you follow the
arrows, its one of the last roads.
 Andrew Pieterick . 
Enable the&quot;Cars drive on water&quot;code. Take a car or
boat to the helicopter pad at Hyman Memorial Stadium. Take a car,
if needed, into the water. Drive behind the helipads (opposite
of the road) and face north. Go forwards until you reach the location
where the shore wall becomes a right angle. Aim for one of the
two walls that make up that angle. Then, drive straight into it.
It does not matter if your vehicle is higher than the wall. You
will be pass through the wall and go in the underworld. Note:
you will fall and not be able to control where you are going.
You will then respawn on the road.
 Kyle Kowalsky . 
 Downtown: Enter the hospital:
 Get a motorcycle and go to Downtown. Go the building
with the long staircase that has a rampage at the top. Go back
down the stairs and go to the police station to get a good run
at the stairs. Hit the stairs as fast as possible. If done fast
enough, you will fly over to the next building. Once there, turn
around and go to the right where there is a ledge and some vents.
Turn around and go to the other end of the building. Then, return
to the ledge as fast as possible and hit the vent. You will fly
to another building. Keep driving and you will fall off to a circular
edge. Drive straight off the edge onto the balcony of the hospital.
if done correctly, you will be inside the building. To leave the
hospital, drive through the wall to the outside again.
 stevee . 
 Downtown: Spawn at Hyman Memorial Stadium
instead of the hospital:
 Enable the&quot;Weapons tier 2&quot;code and enter
the stadium. Fail the Bloodring race intentionally and leave.
Walk down street to the intersection where you can turn around
and see the stadium, look ahead to see your condo, or look to
the right to see the hospital. Equip the rocket launcher, go up
to traffic, and blow up a car directly next to you. It will kill
you, and instead of appearing at the hospital with no weapons,
you should respawn at the stadium with all your weapons.
 Seymour Butts 
 Downtown: Ghost car in Hotring arena:
 When you are in the Hotring arena, get out of your
car with a sniper rifle or another weapon that uses the manual
targeting system. Try to shoot of the head of another Hotring
race driver. He should fall out. If you leave the car sitting
by itself for awhile, it will start to drive around by itself,
and even try to blow itself up. After the driver is dead and has
fallen out, get in the car. For about five seconds you can drive
normally in his car. After that, you will have almost no control
over the car (gas, brakes, etc.), except for changing views. If
you wait long enough, the car will eventually catch fire by itself,
or after it rams other cars or the walls. The flames also cannot
be put out by use of the&quot;Restore health&quot;code. Note:
Do not close the car door after the driver has fallen out or it
will lock and not be able to re-opened.
 Jason Conley . 
 Downtown: 0:00 winning time at Dirt Ring:
 Get a Sanchez. Wait for the Dirt Ring at Hyman Memorial
Stadium. When the time comes, park your Sanchez next to the door.
Go inside. When the screen starts to fade, get on your bike and
accelerate. Wait for the start and do not get on the other bike
(it starts the timer). Get the checkpoints with your&quot;outside&quot;Sanchez. When you have collected the checkpoints, go on the other
bike. You should have won $50,000$ with a time of 0:00.
 andy carbajal . 
 Downtown: Fire in Love Fist building:
 Go to the Love Fist building (as featured in the Publicity
Tour mission). Use the&quot;Look through the wall&quot;glitch.
You should see floating fire in the building where the stage should
be.
 SKildau . 
 Escobar International Airport: Get weapons
inside:
 Go through the metal detector at the airport and your
weapons will be removed. Keep running at the glass where your
weapons are located and you can actually get some of them back
while inside the airport.
 The Gamer . 
 Escobar International Airport: Teleport
to underpass:
 In the PlayStation2 version, ride a fast motorcycle
(PCJ 600 recommended) to Escobar International Airport. Find a
parked jet in one of the hangars (near the airstrip). Gain speed,
then ride through the wing of the jet. You will crash, but you
will appear on the underpass outside the airport with your feet
sunk in the road. To escape, press Square . You will appear
on the underpass, but the motorcycle will still be on the jet.
 Irwin Oroceo . 
 Escobar International Airport: Grand
Theft Auto 3 fire department logo:
 Go to the part of the airport across from Fort
Baxter. Go to the two garages with the signs that read&quot;Don&apos;t
even think of parking here&quot;. Look up and you will see the
same logo as found in Grand Theft Auto 3 , which reads&quot;LCFD&quot;instead of&quot;VCFD&quot;.
 pieter moonen . 
 Leaf Links: Jack Caddy through gate:
 In the PlayStation2 version, when you go to Leaf Links
Golf Course&apos;s front gates, wait until a Caddy comes up to the
gate. They try to go through the gate all thetime. When they turn
their golf carts around so you are looking at one side of the
Caddy, walk up to the gate and press Triangle . You will
step through the gate and jack the Caddy.
 Drew Lanich . 
 Leaf Links: Become a pedestrian:
 In the PlayStation2 version, go to the Leaf Links Golf
Club. When you see a Caddy, steal it. Stay near the person that
you stole it from. Usually, they will try to steal it back from
you. Make sure they are closer to the passenger side of the Caddy
when you do this. As they are walking towards you to try to steal
it back, get ready to hit the gas. As they are getting back in
the Caddy, floor it. Instead of kicking you out of the Caddy,
they will take your place and your body will disappear. The camera
will stay on the Caddy, but you will be gone and the pedestrian
takes your place. Stop accelerating and the camera will follow
the pedestrian around. The only thing you can do at this point
is change the radio stations and look around with L2 and R2 . This very difficult to do and requires some practice.
 Mashuk Billah . 
 Leaf Links: Enter through fence:
 Go to Leaf Links. Go to the right side gate. On the
right hand side of the gate is a bridge leading to the pizza place.
If you go to the right of the gate where the brown pillar is located,
you should see a fence and a ledge. Jump on the ledge and you
should fall through. You are now in Leaf Link. If you need to
get out, go along the south wall. Keep going to you see the bridge
that connects to the other half of the course and jump out.
 Kevin Warner . 
 Little Havana: Helicopter with wheels:
 After acquiring Sunshine Autos, get a Sparrow. Fly
it to Sunshine Autos and set it down just outside the Pay &apos;N&apos;
Spray in back, If you are confident in your flying abilities,
attempt to fly it into the spray area. If not, turn it around
so that the cockpit is facing the four garages and push it inside.
Once it is in there, get inside. After it is sprayed, fly it out
of the garage and you will have a helicopter with wheels.
 David McGibney . 
Note: After getting a helicopter with wheels, enable the&quot;Cars
float on water&quot;code. You can now land on the water with
your helicopter.
 Some gamer . 
 Little Havana: Shoot through glass wall:
 Get a gun that will visibly go through the glass wall
when you fire, such as the mini-gun or flamethrower. In other
words, you have to see a part of it going through the glass. Fire
the gun through the glass wall as Sunshine Autos. You will not
see any fire or blood, but nonetheless, you can still kill anything
through the glass wall. This works best on the first floor of
Sunshine Autos. Use this trick to fend of the cops at a five or
star wanted level.
 The Gamer . 
 Little Havana: List mistake:
 On the fourth and final list for Sunshine Autos, the
list says to get a&quot;Baggage&quot;instead of the vehicle&apos;s
true name, the&quot;Baggage Handler&quot;.
 Kris Valdez . 
 Little Havana: Untouchable clothes:
 Go to the Little Havana Streetwear store. The front
door will be open. Enter it, then turn to your left. You will
see the clothes icon with the word&quot;Havana&quot;.
 NOS. 
It is possible to get this outfit. To do so, ghost ride a motorcycle
into the door, then jump over it so you are on the counter in
the store. Place your back towards the clothing icon and use a
rifle that can aim to blow up the motorcycle. The resulting explosion
will push you backwards towards the clothes. You should see Tommy
float under the screen as if he is falling, then he will appear
outside in the Havana outfit.
 eparkelypsenow . 
Another way to get these clothes is to ghost ride a PCJ-600 inside.
However, this must be done at a slight angle so that the bike
will fall on its side. Go into the doorway and jump onto the bike&apos;s
side. Suddenly, Tommy will go through part of the ceiling. Look
around and notice that a few feet ahead is the clothing icon.
If you jump at the precise distance, you will land on the clothes
icon, sink through it, and start falling under the city. Sometime
during the fall, the screen will black out and you will suddenly
appear in front of the shop wearing the Cuban outfit.
 Seymour Butts . 
 Little Havana: Go through billboard:
 Go to the big billboard at Cherry Poppers. Try to land
a helicopter on it. You will go half way through the billboard.
 Kyle Weber . 
 Little Havana: Car stuck in wall:
 Take a long vehicle (Coach bus recommended) to Sunshine
Autos after completing the Shakedown mission, but before buying
the business. Park the vehicle so that the house icon is next
to the door, but so the vehicle is blocking the driveway down
to the garages. Get in, and when you are halfway inside, press L1 . After the intermission sequence, you will still be
in the vehicle, which is now stuck in the wall, and you cannot
get it out.
 Seymour Butts . 
 Ocean Beach: Matrix-type move:
 Go into the lighthouse on the beach. Climb to the very
top staircase. Then, attempt to jump down to the last stairs through
the middle. Tommy will jump, do a small Trinity-style move from
The Matrix, then go back to the stairs.
 BOVEDATRIBES . 
 Ocean Beach: Unbreakable hotel window:
 Go to your hotel room at the Ocean View hotel. Shoot
out of the window with a gun that shoots bullets. They will pass
straight through without making a hole. If you use a rocket launcher,
it will hit the window explode in the room without damaging the
window. This is useful when assassinating someone on the street.
 stumbows . 
 Ocean Beach: Upside down view:
 Find a motorcycle or scooter, go to Apartment 3C. Drive
through the door and the world will be upside down. Be careful
not to get stuck.
 NELSON SMITH . 
 Ocean Beach: Stupid police:
 Get as many wanted level stars as possible. Then, drive
as quickly as you can towards the port where Cortez&apos;s boat is
found. There will be a long white warehouse near the port. Drive
to the back where the port is, so that the that warehouse is to
your right. Look to your right leading under the building near
the Cheetah parked outside. There will be a parking lot. Drive
inside. Once inside, go to the farthest wall from the entrance.
Once there you will hear the cop cars crash into the wall, flip
over, and explode just outside, as if they were trying to drive
through the wall. This will continue until you get rid of the
stars.
 Ecksfox . 
 Prawn Island: Get inside fence:
 When at the film studio, look north at the fountain.
You will see three houses that surround the fountain. Go to the
entrance of the house that is to the left of the fountain. There
is a fence that surrounds this house (and the other two). Stop
in between the opening of the fence. If you take a right or a
left, you can walk directly into the fence by walking straight
through where the fence ends (creating the opening to walk into
that house&apos;s yard). The fence to the right only goes about 15
feet before you have to stop. However if you take a left at that
entrance between the fences you can walk almost all the way around
the entire house. This is useful because sometimes cops cannot
shoot you when you are inside of the wall, and you can toss grenades
and run down the fence, blowing up any police or cars directly
outside where you dropped the grenade.
 Evan Brogan . 
 Starfish Island: Appear to be shrunk:
 Go to Starfish Island and find any mansion that has
trees in its backyard. Stand next to the&quot;tree&quot;and
you will appear as if you have shrunk very small. The&quot;trees&quot;behind the Starfish Island houses are actually big patches of
grass.
 Brian Wallenstein . 
 Starfish Island: Grind on the Vercetti
mansion railing:
 Complete the mission where you kill Diaz to take control
of the mansion. Get a PCJ 600. Go to the stairs at the outer entrance
and go into the grass facing the stairs. Then, face the front
door, gain a lot of speed, then jump off the bike. If done correctly,
the bike should go into the mansion. After that walk, into the
Mansion and get on the bike. Drive up to the top of the stairs
where the office is located. Get to the rail and make the front
of your bike face it. Pop a wheelie and drive, then release X and Down after your bike is sliding down the rail the way
you were facing.
 varnesfam1 . 
 Starfish Island: Leaving the wrong way
in the Vercetti mansion:
 Use the Sea Sparrow or any helicopter except for the
Hunter. Go inside the&quot;indoor&quot;swimming pool at the
back of the Vercetti estate and fly up the non-solid roof. After
you pass the wall below/in front, you will see a brown background
below you. When you are above this background, go down a few meters.
You should see a black box in front/above you. Fly next to the
black box and try to go around it until you are above it. Then,
descend into the box and land on the solid floor. You will recognize
this room as part of the main entrance room. Get out of the helicopter
and walk toward the door. Normally you would walk out of the building.
However, this time you will end up back in the building. Note:
You will have to enable the&quot;Full health&quot;code frequently
to fix your helicopter as it hits invisible walls a lot.
 Matt . 
 Starfish Island: Walk in mansion while
it is invisible:
 Take a Caddy and drive to the back of the mansion.
Drive it into the pool and go through the door on the right. Once
inside you should be in the mansion while it is invisible
 SKildau . 
 Starfish Island: Garage door:
 At Vercetti Estate, as you go up the left side stairs
in the front and go towards the front door, you will hear the
garage door open and it will come up from beneath you.
 Kris Valdez . 
When you acquire Diaz&apos;s mansion, you gain a garage with it. You
can stand on top of this garage when you walk up the stairs in
the middle of the porch that is facing the road on Starfish Island.
Then, walk left (east) until you are parallel with the garage
behind Lance&apos;s Infernus. When you get close enough to the railing
directly above the garage, it will open and you will pop up. You
will be standing on the garage when you normally should be standing
on the concrete of the mansion walkway. Note: This may only work
if there is a large vehicle such as a Boxville or an Enforcer
in the garage, or if you have spawned any cars or entered any
cheats to affect the game. Saving will make this glitch permanent,
but no harm will be done to the game information.
 Hardflip12338 . 
 Starfish Island: Big faced bills:
 In the Vercetti Estate, go into the office at the top
of the main stairs where you save the game. Select a sniper rifle.
Then, directly right in front of the safe and crouch down. Zoom
in and look at the bills. The one closest to Tommy (and some others)
have the new style big heads paper currency. If this game takes
place in the 1980s, they should be the old small head style bills.
 DJ Hellfire . 
 Starfish Island: Slide down mansion railing:
 In the PlayStation2 version, use the following trick
to make Tommy slide down the railing in his mansion. Once you
enter the mansion, go about halfway up the stairs then jump towards
the rail. While in the air, repeatedly tap Triangle and
Tommy should slide up or down the rail.
 Greg . 
 Starfish Island: Fall through world:
 Go to the Vercetti Estate with a taxi vehicle, after
completing 100 fares and unlocking the&quot;Boost&quot;. Drive
into the pool area, and just before you hit the back wall, press L3 . The car will jump through the ceiling and begin falling.
 Seymour Butts . 
 Vice Point: Pedestrians sitting on air:
 Go into the North Point Mall and look around on the
benches. Sometimes the pedestrians will sit down on them, however
they sit strangely and are actually sitting on air.
 MysticalSoulDX . 
 Vice Point: Dark mall:
 Go to North Point Mall near the top of the first area
in a Caddy. Drive the Caddy in the mall. There will be a wall,
but you can go through the middle door. Drive through the middle
door and you will be in the mall, but cannot see anything because
the game will not load that area.
 Fr4zer . 
 Vice Point: Fall through world:
 Steal a car and drive to the northern point of the
North Point Mall. Between some buildings, you will find a large
bush near some smaller ones with a palm tree in front of it. Behind
the bush is a ramp. Walk along the bottom edge of the ramp and
you will find a hole in the ground that Tommy literally falls
into. In doing so, he drops below the game world for a bit, then
lands hard on his feet again on the sidewalk in front of the bush.
 Elak Swindell . 
Go to the Vinyl Countdown store in the mall. When you enter the
store, go left of the farthest display isle with records on it.
Jump on top. Make sure you are on the very top. Your head should
appear through the ceiling. Jump up and down until the game glitches
and you are above the store. There should be a ledge. Go on it
and to your right until a black wall appears. Jump off into the
blackness and you should land outside in a glitch version of the
game world, with people walking above you, below you, and with
you. This is only useful when finding the hidden packages and
secret cars. Dying is the only way to turn everything visible
again. There is a&quot;truck&quot;with tread-like wheels somewhere,
which is a glitched version of the actual Perennial.
 Mike . 
Go to the Vice Point Pay &apos;N Spray. Then, go to the next house
that has a group of torches, but stay on the sidewalk. Go right
and there will be a tree. Run between the tree and the wall. You
will fall under the road and you will appear back on the road
again.
 tonyhawk_35 . 
Go to the Corner Store (straight up the road from the El Swanko
Casa) with a cab that has boost unlocked (completing 100 fares).
Go into the store just fast enough for the cab to jump. If you
go too fast it will crash into the doorway. Press L3 and
the cab will bounce through the ceiling and fall through the store.
It will land somewhere around there.
 Seymour Butts . 
 Vice Point: Vehicles in club:
 Get a Freeway motorcycle and drive it into the Malibu
Club for an interesting glitch.
 Sean Robertson . 
Drive to the Malibu Club, then spawn a Caddy. Drive through the
doors. The Malibu Club will be invisible, and there will be water
inside.
 XxRideThePigxX . 
 Vice Point: Non-reflecting mirror In Malibu
Club:
 Upstairs in the Malibu Club is a mirror on one of the
walls with a model that resembles Colonel Cortez&apos;s ship. Walk
over to it. Looking into the mirror in first person view, you
can see that it reflects the things in the office like a painting
on the wall, the chairs, a few lights, the model ship, and the
doorway. However, it does not reflect you.
 Jamie Weir . 
 Vice Point: Invisible city:
 Enter the Malibu Club and go up to the bar. Jump over
the counter and approach the two drink cabinets on the right.
Jump on the small one, take a few steps back, and jump onto the
larger one. Tommy&apos;s head will go through the ceiling. Run, jump,
just basically move around. This may take many attempts, but Tommy
will eventually end up through the ceiling and on the roof. Look
at the room with the ship. Note that the&quot;mirror&quot;in
that room upstairs is actually a window into this glitched Malibu
Club. Turn around and walk through the blue dome. Look down to
see the whole Malibu Club. Exit the dome and walk a short distance
towards the beach. Notice that you can see the road below you.
If you run towards that road and jump far enough, you will fall
through the world. If you done correctly, you will be outside
in a glitched Vice City. If done wrong, you will appear back in
the Malibu Club. In the glitched Vice City, everything is normal
except no objects load. The walls and buildings can still be entered,
but you cannot see them. You can start missions, fly the helicopters,
drive vehicles, and even go to the Ammunation store and see the
weapons floating in the air. The trick is to know where the walls
should be located. Watch the on-screen map to make sure you stay
on the road. To exit this glitch, walk into a place that loads
separately (through the front door of the Malibu Club, your mansion,
etc.).
 Seymour Butts . 
Another way to do this is to drive a Caddy through the front doors
of the Malibu Club. Get out and slowly walk back towards the doors.
The Caddy will still be inside when the game loads the Malibu
Club&apos;s interior. Get back in the Caddy and drive through the front
doors again. It will be invisible.
 Seymour Butts . 
Drive a motorcycle at the entrance of the Pole Position Club and
jump off, letting it ride inside. Then, go inside and get on it.
When you ride out of the club on the bike, the game will not load,
leaving Vice City invisible.
 Wazabam . 
You must own the Pole Position Club for this glitch. Get on a
motorcycle (the crotch rocket or Angel recommended), then go to
the front door of the Pole Position. Drive a little south to get
yourself some distance from the front door. Drive as fast as possible,
lined up with the door. Get off the motorcycle just before the
door and ram it through the hallway. If done correctly, you will
see the motorcycle in the club. Then, drive the motorcycle out
the door. All the buildings are there, but most of them are invisible.
At most places you can ram a car into the building, but not come
out like you can in the Pole Position. This glitch can be useful
for finding the hidden packages.
 Yakuza
Red in neck. 
 Vice Point: Invisible ground:
 Have a helicopter and take it to the beach at Vice
Point. Go along the beach until you see three buildings very close
together, and the middle building is green with red, yellow, and
gray on the top. Fly up to the gray and land on it. This may require
some practice. When you land on the gray, get out and walk towards
the other building. You can walk for about 10 feet, then fall.
 kyle . 
 Vice Point: Go through wall:
 Go to the police station, walk down the hall, take
a right, walk up the stairs, and go to the first office on the
right past the filing cabinet into the room. When inside, jump
onto the desk and try to get behind the desk. If done correctly,
when back there you will be stuck. Grenade yourself so that you
will fall, then spin around when you notice you cannot get up.
You are now stuck standing sideways on the wall spinning. Try
looking in first person view.
 Rokin SMP . 
 Vice Point: Motorcycle in mall:
 You can take any kind of motorcycle into the North
Point Mall. You can then drive around in the mall freely. However,
it is easier to drive up the&quot;down&quot;escalator to go
up and ramp down when you want to go down.
 Derrick S. Keyser . 
 Vice Port: Go through wall:
 After you buy the Boat Yard, take the boat out on the
outer side of the dock. Go full speed just as you pass the outer
dock and jump. You will go through the wall and be under the stairs.
Note: You must reload or reset your game to continue.
 Jon Mead . 
 Washington Beach: Police station with little
interior:
 Go to the Washington Beach police station (the one
you can enter, which is a short drive south from the Malibu Club).
Run inside. You will notice that it reads VCPD as you go in. While
tapping X , run through the doors back outside, then rapidly
run back into the station. Repeat this many times, and occasionally
you will run into the police station without the game pausing
to load the interior because you are rapidly moving between these
two areas. The invisible walls are still there -- do not worry
about falling into the water.
 Seymour Butts . 
 Bank Heist mission: Backwards head:
 Walk into the manager&apos;s office. Stand in front of the
filing cabinets by the manager. Face the manager and slowly walk
towards him. At some point, it will look like Tommy&apos;s head is
backwards and see his face. Turn around to see the back of his
head and the front of his body.
 Jeff Clem . 
 Demolition Man mission: Fly in building:
 When you complete the mission, there will be big holes
in the building. Get a helicopter (Maverick or Sparrow recommended),
and go to the side that faces Starfish Island. Maneuver by the
edges, and you will able to enter the building. You cannot fly
up the building; you must stay in one place. To get out, fly backwards.
 peraltap . 
 Fastest Boat mission: Squallo spellings:
 Get the Squallo from the boatyard or from completing
the Fastest Boat mission for Diaz. Once you get in the boat, the
game will say that the boat is called the Squallo. Get out and
look at the hull in first-person view, and it is actually marked&quot;Squallo II&quot;.
 KowsilMcCalm . 
 Love Juice mission: No motorcycles:
 During the first of the Love Fist mission (Love Juice)
when you pick up Mercedes to take her back to the band, do not
use a motorcycle of any kind. She will not be able to get on the
back if it during the intermission sequence, although anyone can
during other missions.
 Damian . 
 Martha&apos;s Mug Shot mission: Limo drives
itself:
 When Candy is walking to the Stretch, quickly take
out a flamethrower and torch the car. The driver will get out.
Then, get in the Stretch. Candy will also get in, then the car
will leave and drive by itself with both of you inside.
 wrsinger . 
Before Candy gets to the limo, run up to it and shoot the driver
in the head so that he will open the door, decapitated. Jump in
the limo and when Candy gets in, the car will drive itself to
the destination. You will not have to worry about losing the car.
 Thomas Slagle . 
 Martha&apos;s Mug Shot mission: Fail mission
without running out of film:
 After intermission sequence has finished with you talking
to the director and you regain control of the game, enable the&quot;Weapons tier 2&quot;code and throw the grenade. When you
throw it, a message stating that you failed the mission due to
running out of film will appear, when you actually never took
any photos at all.
 Meccablue85 . 
 No Escape mission: Invisible Cam Jones:
 Spawn a Caddy and get Cam in it. Cam will disappear,
and when you get out he will re-appear.
 Kyle . 
 Publicity Tour mission: Fire room:
 After the bomb has been defused, drive to the venue
as usual. Accelerate to full speed then eject yourself from the
vehicle. The Love Fist Limo will pass through the pink objective
marker and a message stating that you killed Love Fist will appear.
You will then appear inside the venue, surrounded by four pillars
of fire. While in this room, you cannot be wasted due to an odd
camera angle, but you also cannot move. Cheats can still be enabled.
Note: This room is actually the Love Fist&quot;temple of rock.&quot;
 ShadowLocke . 
Go back towards the building with the pink marker where the band
needs to be. Stop a long distance away from it. Then, floor the
gas so that the limousine is at top speed. Bail out of the car
before you hit the marker. The car will roll through the marker.
The screen will black out. The message&quot;Mission Failed. You
killed Love Fist!&quot;will appear, and you will be inside the
building you stopped in front of. However, it will be empty except
for some fire -- the game will glitch and not load the interior.
You will have to reset the game, as the only button that now works
is Select .
 Seymour Butts . 
 Publicity Tour mission: Stuck in concert
hall:
 After the bomb is disarmed, bail out of the car on
the pink circle. A message should appear stating that you killed
Love Fist, but you will be inside the concert hall. Note: You
cannot move, change weapons, or die. To escape, you must reset
the game.
 Forrest Rand . 
 All Hands On Deck mission: Ship still on
map:
 After the mission, Cortez takes his boat out of Vice
City. However, his ship still appears on the map when you go to
the Marina (where you took missions from him).
 The Game . 
 Back Alley Brawl mission: Kill chef with
Faggio:
 In this mission, there is a short intermission sequence
with dialog. If you drive up to him in a car, Tommy will get out
of the car to fight. If you drive straight at the chef with a
Faggio, an intermission sequence will show Tommy driving over
the chef, killing him.
 Ross Stickler . 
 Bank Heist mission: Floating driver:
 When your driver leaves to drive around the block,
get a helicopter and fly up to the building next to the bank.
The driver will be floating above the building in the taxi he
left in.
 Tim C. . 
 The Chase mission: Easy completion:
 After you go to Diaz to start the mission, check the
window, get upstairs, and start chasing the thief. If you can
sprint and weave in and out of tight spots well, you will pass
him on the roof and jump off the edge of the building first. Get
in the BF Injection and wait. The thief will jump down, get in,
and drive you there. You will be invisible at the end of the mission,
but when you exit from the car it will be completed successfully.
 ryan smith . 
 Death Row mission: Enter Malibu Club:
 Instead of walking into the pink circle, run at top
speed to go into the Malibu Club. To get out, just walk through
the black block.
 OzMan127 . 
 The Job mission: Phil Cassidy dialogue:
 Start killing every hostage as soon as Phil Cassidy
holds them up. After about four to five hostages are dead, every
hostage will start to attack you, Cassidy, and Cam Jones. Beware
-- Cassidy and Jones will make little effort to defend themselves.
If either one of them dies, the mission will end in failure. After
all the hostages are dead, Cassidy will follow you upstairs to
the safe. When Tommy Vercetti heads back down to get the manager,
he still asks Cassidy if things are okay -- even though Cassidy
is now on the second floor. When you are on your way back with
the manager, Cassidy stills says,&quot;I said nobody move&quot;,
yet he is still on the second floor. When you go back down to
help Phil, go to the pink marker, then go back to the corridor
that leads to the back of the bank. After that, get ready to fight
the S.W.A.T. team.
 The Job mission: Hold up manager in other
ways:
 When getting up to the part where you have to go back
in the elevator and bring the manager to the safe, you do not
need a gun. If you have your fist or brass knuckles selected,
Tommy will stick out his hand as if it was in fact a weapon to
bring the manager with him. You can also do it again when you
get back to the safe. You can also use one of those many tools
(chainsaw, truncheon, katana, etc.) to aim at him. It is especially
interesting to see Tommy hold the truncheon as if he is holding
an M5 or Ruger.
 Will Moore . 
 Keep Your Friends Close mission: Wrong
subtitle text:
 When Tommy tells Rosenberg to get 20 million of counterfeit
money, the subtitles state 3.
 teena21 . 
 Keep Your Friends Close mission: Slow details:
 When the message&quot;Defend your safe!&quot;appears,
go to any other island. The radar will turn blank, and the details
will take many seconds to load. The helicopters that are not at
your mansion will not spawn, although the seaplane at the film
studio will.
 austin cox . 
 Martha&apos;s Mug Shot mission: Easy transport:
 Get to Candy&apos;s Stretch before her and shoot the driver
in the head. Get in the driver&apos;s seat and wait for Candy to enter.
You will automatically be driven to the destination as though
you were the passenger. Once you stop to drop Candy off, it will
drive you to the Malibu Club. From there, go to the building on
the other side of the one that Candy entered.
 Jordan Oliver and James Pain . 
 Publicity Tour mission: Wrong dialogue:
 When you have to drive around waiting for Love Fist
to defuse the bomb, they will (very eventually) defuse it. However,
if you stop just when they say they will pull out the wire, one
of them will say after defusing it&quot;Hey! we&apos;re okay&quot;,
the car will explode after the defusion.
 Cheslly1969Proy . 
 Rub Out mission: Get stuck in Diaz&apos;s mansion:
 When you get in the mansion, if Lance dies your mission
will fail. Then, all the doors that were closed before the mission
will close again. If you go out of the hallway and Lance dies
down at the bottom of the stairs going to the roof, there will
be an open space with nothing in it, and you will see the stairs
on the inside by the front doors. You will then be stuck in the
mansion.
 Adam LeMoine . 
 Treacherous Swine mission: Fall through
ground:
 Start the mission and before entering the pink circle
where Gonzalez is located, get a car and drive straight into it
fairly fast and straight. Your car might stand straight up. Then,
it will go on to Gonzalez. You and your car should be there. Get
in the car and drive it down the stairs toward him. He will end
up outside and you will follow. Your car should be about half
way in the door. Kill him, enable the&quot;Lower wanted level&quot;code, then return to your car. Enter it, then exit it. You should
fall down and be able to see the ground above, and end up by the
street where your car is located. You will lose some health, but
not a lot. Eventually your car will blow up and you will not be
able to get it out.
 Jdbcooldog . 
 Ice Cream Factory saves:
 The game may glitch at times when it is saved at the
Ice Cream Factory. When that save is reloaded, the game will turn
black and freeze. PlayStation2 version cheat codes, hints, FAQs 
 PC version cheat codes, hints, FAQs 

 Copyright ©2002-2011
Al Amaloo. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
