<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006139" url="http://www.cctexas.com/?fuseaction=main.view&amp;page=1990" time="2012-07-12-22:49" support="4" score="0.0031503359338065397" bingtitle="City of Corpus" webtitle="City of Corpus">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="21"/>
	<description>Use returnable, reusable or refillable drink ... onto their garbage until they find a trash bin or get to ... Those who buy their lunch at a fast-food restaurant and discard ...</description>
	<body>
		News Releases City’s on Facebook Twitter with CC Community Calendar The Coastal Wave Events Calendar July 4th Holiday Schedule July 4th Big Bang Celebration Memorial Day Holiday Schedule     
 
 MAKE IT SPARKLE 
 
 
 
 
 The City&apos;s anti-litter campaign includes a series of public service announcements. Check them out by clicking on the icons to the left.  
 
Litter has been a problem in Corpus Christi for quite some time.   Great strides have been made recently in addressing the situation, thanks to strengthened City ordinances , additional code enforcement officers, the new Environmental Court , and efforts such as the Neighborhood Initiative Program (NIP).   But there is still much more to be done.   
 Since the City simply doesn’t have the resources to address the situation alone, we’ve launched a new anti-litter campaign in hopes of generating greater awareness of the litter problem.   The goal of the “Make It Sparkle” campaign is to wipe out litter in our All-America City .   The City is asking residents and businesses to take pride in Corpus Christi and do their part to keep our city clean.   Through a combination of education and enforcement, and with the support of the community, we’re determined to “Make It Sparkle!” 
 The City spends tens of thousands of tax dollars each year picking up litter.   We’re asking people to take responsibility and help clean up Corpus Christi . Littering in our neighborhoods and streets eventually costs hundreds of thousands of dollars when the entire environment is accounted for as a result of pollution. 
 
 It’s easy to prevent litter in our City:  
 Always put your trash in a proper container. If one is not available, hold on to your garbage until you find one. Use a litterbag in your vehicle.   The City has designed a “Make It Sparkle” car litterbag, which is available in the Public Information Office at City Hall.  Pick up at least 5 pieces of trash a day in a public place and put it in a trash container. Reduce and reuse as much as you can and recycle.  Keep storm drain inlets free of trash, oil and grass clippings (which could flow out to our bays and estuaries). Put your garbage out for collection as close to pickup time as possible and secure items in your recycling bin. Keep your property clean and mowed. Participate in household hazardous waste collection days. Use returnable, reusable or refillable drink containers. Support and take part in community cleanups, recycling programs, legislation and other efforts to reduce litter. Set a good example - Don&apos;t Litter!   Take pride in keeping your community clean tell others about the negative effects of littering 

 Who Is Responsible For Litter? 

 Everyone! A littered community indicates a lack of respect and responsibility for our home. Many people are conscientious about litter, and make the small effort of holding onto their garbage until they find a trash bin or get to their home or car. They also teach children about not littering. These efforts are important and appreciated.
 
But a wide variety of people actually create litter. Those who buy their lunch at a fast-food restaurant and discard the wrappers and cups as they walk; people who empty their car ashtrays and garbage bins in parking lots, are also guilty. There are some parents who change diapers in their parked car, then dispose of the dirty diaper in the parking lot.   Some people take their household garbage to park trash bins, causing the bins to overflow. Litter is also caused when residents put out their garbage in poorly-secured bags or cans. Sometimes, when animals get into garbage at the curb, no one bothers to clean it up. Dumpsters in the back of businesses may not be emptied often enough, or perhaps employees don&apos;t bother to make sure garbage tosses into the dumpster are accurate. Many smokers toss their butts on the ground - not to mention cigarette packaging. Cigarette butts are litter too, and can take years to decompose.
 
We have plenty of trash cans throughout the City of Corpus Christi , yet a lot of littering happens within sight of a trash can. Often it&apos;s by people simply being lazy or thoughtless - not taking pride in and responsibility for our City.   And our constant wind only adds to the problem, often spreading litter out of our immediate reach. 

   

 What’s the City doing to reduce litter? 

   

 More than a half-dozen City departments already make litter control and prevention one of their top priorities.   Below, you’ll find helpful links to their programs which are aimed at improving the quality of life in Corpus Christi . 

  

 * * * * *  

 Environmental Programs 

 The Office of Environmental Programs handles environmental matters that could impact our community, such as pollution issues and hazardous materials incidents. The office also helps educate the public about a variety of environmental concerns. Our environmental outreach programs include household hazardous waste, storm water system protection, environmental conservation through activities like tree plantings, and energy conservation through activities like home weatherization and the Clean Cities program that promotes the use of Alternative Fuel Vehicles. In addition, the office ensures the City follows all state and federal environmental, health and safety requirements. 

   

 Neighborhood Services 

 The Neighborhood Initiative Program is dedicated to cleaning up some of the neediest areas of the City.   The NIP addresses concerns of citizens who live in these targeted areas by providing enhanced city services in the area during a three-week period. Services include such things as trash and brush collection, street repairs, mowing of vacant lots, enhanced police patrols, new street signs, enhanced street lighting, traffic light replacement, stray animal pick-up, storm water inlet cleaning and boarding up of vacant houses. 

   

 Parks&amp;Recreation 

 The Parks and Recreation Department cleans city parks, and assists with special events as needed.   The Beach Operations Division picks up litter daily in the 8-miles of city-maintained beaches. 

   

 Storm Water 

 As part of its mission, the Storm Water Department aims at improving the environment by improving the quality of storm water runoff.   The Storm Water Department cleans trash out of approximately 18,320 storm drain inlets that flow to the bays, cleans 115 miles of major drainage ditches, cleans 668 miles of minor roadside drainage ditches, mows more than 2000 acres of roadside ditches and the right-of-way area of major ditches, and ensures all Storm Water discharge is within standards set by the Federal Clean Water Act. 

   

 The Storm Water Department maintains an active Education and Outreach Program, focusing on public outreach, education programs in schools, marketing programs, and inlet stenciling programs.    

   

 Streets and Solid Waste Services 

   

 Wastewater 

   

 Water 

 The Water Department maintains an active water conservation program, focusing on public outreach, education programs in schools, marketing programs, Xeriscape workshops and free water saving kits. 

  

 * * * * * 

  

 Successful litter control must be a continuous, ongoing effort, which involves the entire community - from youth to seniors, business, community groups and the media.   In addition to the programs offered by the City departments listed above, other volunteer opportunities are available through the Beautify Corpus Christi Association. 

  

 
 
 
 

 
Home | Residents | Business | Visitors | City News | Government 
 Search | Privacy/Accessibility Policies | Contact Us 
 ©2009 City of Corpus Christi, Texas. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
