<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006536" url="http://ecowomen.net/tag/plastic-straws/" time="2012-07-12-23:28" support="44" score="0.08705222499172702" bingtitle="plastic straws | Eco Women: Protectors of the Planet!" webtitle="plastic straws | Eco Women:  Protectors of the Planet!">
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000009" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001132" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000308" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>... the distance they have to travel–the nearest fast food restaurant ... less, even though they’re eating in and the tray ... She skips straws and cup lids, opting to fill cups ...</description>
	<body>
		Eco Women: Protectors of the Planet! 

Saving the planet one day at a time.
 Search 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Home About the Eco Women Easy Eco Actions Eco Shop! 
 
Tag Archives: plastic straws 
 
 Suck it! 
 Posted on February 24, 2010 by melissawest 1 
 Enviro Girl and her family don’t eat out much, but when they do, they go to a locally owned family restaurant.  When the craving for a burger and fries hits, they go to a locally owned chain of burger joints, and only patronize Culver’s or  McDonald’s when in dire straits while on the road to visit relatives in another state.  Part of their virtue in this matter has to do with the distance they have to travel–the nearest fast food restaurant (unless you count a Subway in a local convenience store) is 10 minutes away by car.  By the time the Momvan gets loaded and driven, Enviro Girl can slap together sandwiches or pasta.

When they do go out to eat on that rare occasion,  Enviro Girl is astonished by the amount of waste generated by take-out food.  Individually wrapped portions, condiment packets, stacks of paper napkins and straws get loaded onto their tray–in paper BAGS no less, even though they’re eating in and the tray seems sufficient to move their food from counter to table.  The health factor of eating fast food is bad enough, but the pile of garbage left behind after a meal is indisputably problematic.  And then there’s the matter of the plastic toys double-wrapped in plastic that get tossed into her kids’meals.

Enviro Girl has learned that you can request“No toy”with a happy meal–you just say,“No toy.”You also save .50-.75 per meal because that toy costs extra, even though the menu doesn’t tell you that.  She skips straws and cup lids, opting to fill cups and drink straight from them like she does at home.   These are small choices, but they do add up–imagine if every parent buying a kids’meal at a fast food restaurant said,“No toy.”There’d be nothing to sell at rummage sales!

Seriously, eating fast food generates a LOT of waste.  Sitting down in a restaurant generates a paper napkin and maybe a straw, depending on your drinking preference.  Enviro Girl usually needs the napkins, but opts out of the straw and you can too–here’s how:

 

You can buy your own straw–or a family four-pack–from GlassDharma , never needing to use another plastic disposable straw again! GlassDharma’s handmade in the U.S.A. glass drinking straws come in a range of sizes, from chubby and stout for the toddler set to tall and slightly bended for the iced-tea-by-the-pool set.  By using a glass drinking straw, you eliminate waste in landfills (think of how those straws and cup lids add up–if McDonald’s, Starbucks, Burger King, Subway, Wendy’s and Culver’s serve up millions of beverages each week, you can bet those orders resulted in a lot of straws ditched into the garbage.

The other advantage of glass drinking straws includes avoiding the toxins that leach out of plastic.  If reducing plastic is important to you, opting out of  a plastic straw is an easy place to target.  Like the plastic shopping bag, plastic straws could become the exception, not the rule, if consumers gave this issue a little thought. GlassDharma’s straws are durable, dishwasher&amp;microwave safe, and come with a pretty hefty guarantee.

Enviro Girl encourages you to check out GlassDharma’s site–the family four-pack of drinking straws with a scrubbing brush costs $23, and the way Enviro Girl’s kids like to drink out of straws, that’s money well spent in her opinion.   But if buying your own reusable glass straw doesn’t appeal, Enviro Girl encourages you to just“Say No”to the straw.  And while you’re at it, take a pass on the plastic lid, too!
 Posted in 3 Rs , food | Tagged fast food and garabage , fast food waste , GlassDharma , plastic and fast food , plastic straws , say no to drinking straws and happy meal toys | 1 Reply 
Search the Eco Archives
 Search Eco Women: Protectors of the Planet 
 
 Promote Your Page Too 
Top Posts

 Water, the stuff of life Eco safe in the summer sun Eco Back To School Week: Notebooks, paper, pencils, and more Berry fresh Peanut Butter Bibliomania CD&apos;s are going the way of vinyl Eco Back-to-School: Pencils, paper, and more! Hot, buttery popcorn Alternatives to Plastic Wrap 
 
Categories
 Select Category 3 Rs books clothes contests eco baby eco holidays eco kids eco pets electronics fast facts food gardening green around the world health house stuff in the office issues living green on a budget magazines personal care quick link school transportation travel Uncategorized websites&amp;blogs 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 
 Get your daily Eco Women! 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 221 other followers

 

 
 
RSS

 RSS - Posts RSS - Comments 
 
 Eco Women: Protectors of the Planet is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License . Theme: Twenty Eleven | Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“Eco Women: Protectors of the Planet!” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 221 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
