<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006603" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/50593416/bsc-beverage-1" time="2012-07-12-23:32" support="2" score="0.0020518771869934413" bingtitle="bsc_beverage[1]" webtitle="bsc_beverage[1]">
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000009" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>There are various types of fast-food restaurant: ... The seat should be 46 cm from the floor and 23 cm ... Never put cutlery into glasses, put them in ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   FO OD A N D B EVERAGE SER V I CE - I B.Sc. (Catering Science and Hotel Management) First Year, Part III, Paper 2 School of Distance Education This watermark does not appear in the registered version - http://www.clicktoconvert.com   Bharathiar University, Coimbatore - 6410 46 Copyright 2008, Bharathiar University All Rights Reserved Compiled and Printed by FRONTLINE INSTITUTE OF HOTEL MANAGEMENT STUDIES 14, Vallalar Salai, Pondicherry - 605011 for This watermark does not appear in the registered version - http://www.clicktoconvert.com   SCHOOL OF DISTANCE EDUCATION Bharathiar University Coimbatore - 641046 CONTENTS Page Nos. UNIT - I Lesson 1 Introduction to Hotel Industry 3 - 12 Lesson 2 Restaurant 13 - 28 Lesson 3 Waiter 29 - 36 UNIT - II Lesson 4 Restaurant Operating Equipments 39 - 62 Lesson 5 Ancillary Departments 63 - 68 Lesson 6 Preparation for Servi ce 69 - 76 UNIT - III Lesson 7 The Menu 79 - 94 Lesson 8 Forms and Techniques of Service 95 - 110 UNIT - IV Lesson 9 B r eakfast 113 - 124 Lesson 1 0 Beverages 125 - 142 UNIT - IV Lesson 11 Order Taking Procedures in a Restaurant 145 - 158 Lesson 1 2 Savoury 159 - 166 Lesson 13 Ice Cream 167 - 178 This watermark does not appear in the registered version - http://www.clicktoconvert.com of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
bsc_beverage[1]
 Download or Print 143 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 03/12/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
