<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006594" url="http://www.liveleak.com/view?i=6d8_1327377667" time="2012-07-12-23:32" support="5" score="0.022882950764979725" bingtitle="Suspect with Crowbar Shot Outside Carls Jr - Monterey Park,CA" webtitle="LiveLeak.com - Suspect with Crowbar Shot Outside Carls Jr - Monterey Park,CA">
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="39"/>
	<description>MONTEREY PARK, Calif. (KABC) -- A suspect armed ... Police arrived as the suspect was exiting the fast-food restaurant. ... Punches Himself Repeatedly In Back Of Squad Car ...</description>
	<body>
		Create Account  |  Log in  |    
 
 Home Recent Items Channels Forums 
 
 News&amp;Politics  | Yoursay  | Must See  | Iraq  | Afghanistan  | Entertainment  | Chat  | Staff Blog  | More Blogs  | Top Leakers 
 Suspect with Crowbar Shot Outside Carls Jr - Monterey Park,CA 
Shots fired at :40
MONTEREY PARK, Calif. (KABC) -- A suspect armed with a crowbar was shot outside of a Carl&apos;s Jr. restaurant in Monterey Park on Monday morning.

Authorities say the incident began with the suspect breaking windows at Carl&apos;s Jr. in the 1200 block of Avenida Cesar Chavez just before 9:30 a.m. The suspect then walked inside, while workers and customers ran outside.

Police arrived as the suspect was exiting the fast-food restaurant. After repeatedly telling the suspect to drop the weapon, the suspect was Tasered.

Police said the Taser was ineffective, and the suspect swung the three-foot metal bar at officers twice. At least one officer opened fire on the suspect.

The suspect was taken to a local hospital, where he was pronounced dead.

No one else was injured in the incident. The officer-involved shooting is under investigation.

(Copyright ©2012 KABC-TV/DT. All Rights Reserved.)


Story on Local News http://abclocal.go.com/kabc/story?section=news/local/los_angeles&amp;id=8515794 


Source: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bY5ioBvrYIg&amp;sns=fb 
 Loading the player ... Get Embed Code 
 
 Item Info Links 
 Added: Jan-23-2012   Occurred On: Jan-23-2012
 By: TheWino 
 In: Other News 
 Tags: Police , Suspect , Crime , Cops , Shooting , Killed 
 Location: Monterey Park , California , United States ( load item map ) 
 Marked as: approved, featured
 Views: 83224 | Comments: 1441 | Votes: 21 | Favorites: 52 | Shared: 1520 | Updates: 0 | Times used in channels: 3 | Reports: 0 (Reposts: 0) 
 Direct link: 
 

 Direct link without comments: 
 
 You need to be registered in order to add comments! 
 View comments (1441) 
 Tweet 
 Advertisement below 
 
 Items 
 Related User 
 
 
 Police Chief Details Church Shooting. 
 
 Driver hits police car while cops are inside Kebab shop 
 
 Funeral of missing police suspect found entombed inside bank&apos;s chimney 27 years after he disappeared 
 
 SACRAMENTO, CA - POLICE DEPT TOP COPS FOIL PHARMACY ROBBERY - SHOOT SUSPECT - 11-31-07 
 
 Video Shows Suspect Slamming Into Police Car 
 
 Corrections Officer K.O.&apos;s Suspect 
 
 Russia: Suspect Punches Himself Repeatedly In Back Of Squad Car Then Leaves 
 
 Police Dog Saves Cops Life. 
 
 After Break-in, South African Police Botch Crime Scene 
 
 INSERTING A NPA UP YOUR OWN NOSE?! 
 
 Police kill bandit after shooting officer 
 
 Police Investigating Gas Station Shooting 
 
 Assassination in Guatemala on Politician w/ a Swift Response by Police - Suspect Captured 
 
 
 Advertisers 
 Advertise on Liveleak 
 Liveleak Forums 
 ProChan - Anonymous Interaction 
 Videos of Guns and Explosives! 
 China Wholesale 
 Create your own video channels 

 
 F.A.Q. |   Site Support |   Contact Us |   Privacy Policy |   Terms&amp;Conditions |   Copyright |   Advertise 
 BACK TO TOP
	</body>
</document>
