<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006653" url="http://hotpads.com/apartments/1121-Granada-Avenue-Nashville-TN-37206--1zeutzxsyzsky" time="2012-07-12-23:38" support="1" score="0.0004355806550219275" bingtitle="Adorable 1 Bedroom Near 5 Points - Apartments for Rent in ..." webtitle="Adorable 1 Bedroom Near 5 Points - Apartments for Rent in Nashville, TN - HotPads">
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Adorable 1 Bedroom Near 5 Points ... Number of rooms: ... annual interest rate: (%) down payment:</description>
	<body>
		HotPads.com 

 My Search 
 My Favorites 
 Create Listings 

 Resources 
 Mobile Apps HotPads Answers Property Management Finder Renters Guide Buyers Guide Insurance Center 
 
 sign in | create an account You must sign in or create an account to save your search. your searches: save a new search save edit save this search   go 
 for rent for sale foreclosures buy vs. rent my favorites 
 list map check-in: check-out: bedrooms studio 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 to studio 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 any nightly rate at most price per month price to keywords favorites contacted notes hidden viewed update advanced» rental sublet find a roommate corporate housing for sale new home foreclosure auction land vacation rentals adults children hotel rooms 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 adults children The map-based search on HotPads.com can only be viewed
 by a browser with JavaScript enabled. Please enable JavaScript, or upgrade to a modern
 browser (such as Firefox .
 
 In the meantime, check out the resources on the front page to learn more about what HotPads.com can do for you!  loading results... 
 information street view similar listings stats buy vs rent 
 
Adorable 1 Bedroom Near 5 Points
 1121 Granada Avenue, Nashville , TN 37206 Pricing 
 Beds Baths Price 1 bed 1.0 $650 
 last updated: 1 month, 4 days ago Property Information 1121 Granada Avenue Nashville , TN 37206 Apartments for Rent Check Availability Preview Message 
Nashville, TN - Apartment
 Description 
Great 1 apartment located in a cottage style quadplex in East Nashville. Close to all the great local restaurants, bars, coffee shops, art and entertainment that East nashville has to offer.Hardwood floors, new appliances, great paint colors. $670/month includes water$600 depositPlease call 615.418.4916
 Schools Students who live in this medium building at 1121 Granada Avenue attend the following Davidson County (Unified School District)
 
 public schools * : 
 School Level School Primary School Rosebank Elementary School Middle School Bailey Middle School High School Stratford Comprehensive High School 
 *School attendance boundaries are constantly changing and may contain errors. Always verify them with school administration before making any commitments relating to this property.   More Details Property Web Site 
 Inquire for more information 
   Listed By Easter and Patton, LLC 
   Surrounding Area Stats 
 Type Name This Listing Zip Code 37206 the same City Nashville-Davidson County 7% less County Davidson County 34% less Congressional District TN 5 34% less State TN 6% less Area Code 615 32% less Primary School Rosebank Elementary School the same Middle School Bailey Middle School the same High School Stratford Comprehensive High School 2% less Unified School District Davidson County 34% less 
   More detailed statistics...   Resources Renters Guide 
 Renters Insurance 

 HotPads Insurance Center 
 Moving and Storage Center 
   Contact this Property 
   Show Phone Number ... 
 
 your first and last name your email your phone # your move date your message your questions go here! Send Inquiry     cc: me 
 commercial solicitations prohibited  Sending, please wait... Thanks for inquiring! We&apos;ll fill the box out for you from now on, but feel free to make changes.

 See all the properties you&apos;ve inquired on here. Avoid Scams:
DO NOT WIRE MONEY
Never pay a &quot;membership fee&quot;
 more tips on avoiding scams... 
 
 We suggest contacting these similar properties: 
 
 Mission Priest Lake 1, 2, 3 bedrooms, $678+ 3555 Bell Road, Nashville, TN 37214 Apartments for Rent 7.3 miles away from this building 
 
 1316 Tulip Grove Road 1, 22 bedrooms, $585+ 1316 Tulip Grove Road, Hermitage, TN 37076 Apartments for Rent 8.4 miles away from this building 
 
 308 Plus Park Boulevard Studio, 1, 2 bedrooms, $489+ 308 Plus Park Boulevard, Nashville, TN 37217 Apartments for Rent 4.1 miles away from this building 
 (show more) Sorry, there was an error sending your inquiry. It has been too long since you have loaded this page for us to process your inquiry. Please reload this page to try again.

If you continue to have problems, please contact us at info@hotpads.com. Sorry, there was an error sending your inquiry. Please make sure you&apos;ve filled out the form completely and try again. If you continue to have problems, please email us at info@hotpads.com

 Send another... 
 add to favorites email a friend share on facebook add
notes report listing 
 
Tell a friend:


 friend&apos;s email: your email: message: cc: me      Send     Cancel 
 Did you know? You can tell more than one friend by adding &quot;;&quot; between email addresses! 

 Sending, please wait...


 
 


 Close Sorry, there was an error. Please make sure that you have entered a valid&quot;To&quot;and&quot;From&quot;e-mail address, then try again. 
 Close 
Add note to this listing:
 (edit) Save     Cancel 

 Sending, please wait...


 Advertise here. View a larger map and street view Loading... 
 
 Mission Priest Lake 1, 2, 3 bedrooms, $678+ 3555 Bell Road, Nashville, TN 37214 Apartments for Rent 7.3 miles away from this building 
 
 1316 Tulip Grove Road 1, 22 bedrooms, $585+ 1316 Tulip Grove Road, Hermitage, TN 37076 Apartments for Rent 8.4 miles away from this building 
 
 308 Plus Park Boulevard Studio, 1, 2 bedrooms, $489+ 308 Plus Park Boulevard, Nashville, TN 37217 Apartments for Rent 4.1 miles away from this building 
 
 300 Bakertown Road 1, 2 bedrooms, $495+ 300 Bakertown Road, Antioch, TN 37013 Apartments for Rent 8.3 miles away from this building 
 
 1 bed, 1.0 bath, 730 sqft, $619 1 bedroom, $619 110 Archwood Place, Madison, TN 37115 Apartments for Rent 6.2 miles away from this building 
 
 600 Weakley Lane Studio, 1 bedroom, $579+ 600 Weakley Lane, Smyrna, TN 37167 Apartments for Rent 18.3 miles away from this building 
 
 2005 Borowood Drive 1, 2, 3 bedrooms, $599+ 2005 Borowood Drive, Nashville, TN 37217 Apartments for Rent 8.5 miles away from this building 
 
 1 bed, 1.0 bath, 700 sqft, $589 1 bedroom, $589 203 Sealey Dirve, Madison, TN 37115 Apartments for Rent 6 miles away from this building 
 
 100 Willow Creek Drive 1, 2, 3 bedrooms, $685+ 100 Willow Creek Drive, Mount Juliet, TN 37122 Apartments for Rent 13.2 miles away from this building 
 
 5319 Nolensville Road 1, 2 bedrooms, $499+ 5319 Nolensville Road, Nashville, TN 37211 Apartments for Rent 9.5 miles away from this building 
 
 371 Wallace Road 1, 2 bedrooms, $644+ 371 Wallace Road, Nashville, TN 37211 Apartments for Rent 7.7 miles away from this building 
 
 4601 Packard Drive 1, 2, 3 bedrooms, $539+ 4601 Packard Drive, Nashville, TN 37211 Apartments for Rent 9.1 miles away from this building 
 
 108 Thompson Lane 1, 2 bedrooms, $599+ 108 Thompson Lane, Nashville, TN 37211 Apartments for Rent 5.4 miles away from this building 
 
 1 bed, 1.0 bath, 640 sqft, $545 1 bedroom, $545 644 Glastonbury, Nashville, TN 37217 Apartments for Rent 4.3 miles away from this building 
 
 Center Court at Nashboro Village - Great Locati... 1 bedroom, $579 115 Nashboro Boulevard, Nashville, TN 37217 Apartments for Rent 8.8 miles away from this building 
 
 Come Beat the Heat here at Windsor Park!! Immed... 1 bedroom, $674 100 Windsor Park Lane, Hendersonville, TN 37075 Apartments for Rent 12.3 miles away from this building 
 
 Special Of The Year!!! All The Extras With No E... 1 bedroom, $634 100 Mountain High Drive, Cane Ridge, TN 37013 Apartments for Rent 11.3 miles away from this building 
 
 The Park At Five Points At East Nashville 1 bedroom, $585 1120 Litton, Nashville, TN 37216 Apartments for Rent 1.1 miles away from this building 
 
 
comparison of 1 bedroom apartments for rent in nearby areas:

 Zip Code City County 37206 Nashville-Davidson County Davidson this listing $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... median price $650 the same $699 7% less $990 34.3% less average price $745 12.8% less $816 20.3% less $1,064 38.9% less Metro Area Congressional District State Nashville-Davidson--Murfreesboro, TN TN 5 TN this listing $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... median price $950 31.6% less $990 34.3% less $695 6.5% less average price $1,087 40.2% less $1,068 39.1% less $1,634 60.2% less Area Code Primary School Middle School 615 Rosebank Elementary School Bailey Middle School this listing $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... median price $950 31.6% less $650 the same $650 the same average price $1,087 40.2% less $650 the same $745 12.8% less High School Unified School District Stratford Comprehensive High School Davidson County this listing $650 this listing is... $650 this listing is... median price $665 2.3% less $990 34.3% less average price $686 5.3% less $1,064 38.9% less 
 Statistics are calculated from HotPads listing asking prices, not final sale, rent or lease prices. Loading... 
    
 
 loading... 
 list map current search name   (edit)   (delete) created Email updates: Hourly Daily Weekly Never Update your saved search with the current settings:  save updated! location: go dates: Check-in: Check-out: update bedrooms: studio 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 to studio 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 any bathrooms: 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 5.5 6 6.5 7 7.5 to 0 0.5 1 1.5 2 2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 5.5 6 6.5 7 7.5 any nightly rate price per month price : to update size (in sqft): to update minimum lot size (in acres): to update price per square foot: to update price per bedroom: to update rental sale vacation types: rental sublet find a roommate corporate housing resale new home foreclosure auction land vacation rentals reservation information: Adults: Children: hotel rooms Number of rooms: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 adults 
 children 
 buy vs. rent calculation: 
 mortgage term: (years) annual interest rate: (%) down payment: ($) 
 property type: single family home divided house condo townhouse medium building large community allows pets: cats dogs done keywords: history: new listings listings I&apos;ve viewed my favorite listings listings with my notes listings I&apos;ve contacted hidden listings quality: listings without prices listings with 0+ 1+ 2+ 3+ 4+ 5+ photos listings created within today 1 day 2 days 3 days 4 days 5 days 6 days 1 week 2 weeks 3 weeks 4 weeks 1 month 2 months 3 months listings updated within today 1 day 2 days 3 days 4 days 5 days 6 days 1 week 2 weeks 3 weeks 4 weeks 1 month 2 months 3 months 
 Find A Place: Rentals - For Sale - Buy vs. Rent - Foreclosure - Land Resources: Tools - Create a Listing - Featured Listings - Renters Guide - Buyers Guide - Answers HotPads Info: About - Press - Blog - Advertise - Feeds - Jobs - Terms - Privacy - Sitemap - Report Fraud 
HotPads.com is a map-based real estate search engine, listing homes for sale, apartments, condos, and rental houses.
 
©2012 hotpads.com
	</body>
</document>
