<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006759" url="http://thedisneydrivenlife.com/2011/05/04/counter-service-savings-you-can-count-on/?amp" time="2012-07-12-23:45" support="1" score="0.0021925171537254097" bingtitle="COUNTER SERVICE SAVINGS YOU CAN COUNT ON | the Disney Driven Life" webtitle="COUNTER SERVICE SAVINGS YOU CAN COUNT ON | the Disney Driven Life">
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Another way to reduce the cost of your counter service meal is to order a la carte. ... I can’t think of a fast food restaurant that offers that much food for that ...</description>
	<body>
		the Disney Driven Life Community for Neurotic Disney People 
 Home Be Counted! 
 Register For A NDP Number NDP Roster 
 Blog 
 Blog Categories Blog Archives Recent Comments Recent Posts About Our Contributors 
 Community 
 Confessional DDL Principles 
 About 
 Mission Statement Owners Staff Top Contributors Share The DDL 
 Social Media 
 DDL Live collect the mouse Twitter Facebook YouTube 
 

 Contact Media 
 DDL Live inner mouse iTunes Featured 
 Blogs Podcasts 
 
 Merchandise 
 DDL Merchandise inner mouse Merchandise collect the mouse Merchandise Get My Magic 
 Events 
 Meet-Ups Academy Awards 
 DDL Academy Awards 2010 
 
 Affiliates 
 Supporters Share The DDL 
 Living The Life 
 Be Counted! Give The Gift Zero to Hero Plan Tweetwatch The Sacred Seven 
 
 BOOK CLUB: ODDS, BOBS, HAMMER AND TONGS MY EXPERIENCE AT THE IMGINATION PARK DISNEY STORE (Atlanta, GA) Blog Lifestyle articles 
COUNTER SERVICE SAVINGS YOU CAN COUNT ON
 by Mark J. (NDD#102) | Published: Wednesday, May 4, 2011 
Photo Credit: Dennis Brown, NDU 5
 
Vacationing at Disney World on a budget doesn’t mean you can’t enjoy the convenience and experience of dining in the parks.  While it is no doubt cheaper to eat food from outside the resort, there are a number of ways to save money on the food you purchase inside the parks.

The counter service food, while still more expensive than comparable fast food you’ll find at home, is way less expensive, both in terms of money and time, than eating at the table service restaurants.  We eat almost all of our meals in the counter service restaurants.  We come away with our bellies full without our wallets being empty and are back on the rides quickly.

 

There are several tips we use to reduce our food budget even further when eating counter service.  First of all, portion sizes at Disney World are large.  I’m typically a big eater, especially when I’ve been walking for miles around a theme park, and the chicken wrap at Pecos Bill’s is so large that I have trouble finishing it.  This makes it easy to share a single entrée if you’re not very hungry.  You can also share drinks.  We’ll sometimes order a large soft drink and three cups of ice for the four of us.  This not only saves a little money, but reduces the amount of empty calories we take in.  Or you can order ice water (not the bottled water) for free.  I can’t stand the taste of the water from the fountains in the parks, but the water in the restaurants isn’t bad.  I’ll drink a cup of ice water with my meal, then use another to refill the water bottle I carry with me.

Another way to reduce the cost of your counter service meal is to order a la carte.  The prices displayed on the menu screens are for combo meals, which include the entrée and a side; for example, a cheeseburger and fries.  Disney doesn’t advertise it, but you can order the entrée by itself and skip the side.  Again, this saves not only money, but calories.  If I’m in the mood for fries, though, sometimes one of us will order the combo meal and another just the entrée and we’ll share the fries.

Finally, counter service restaurants offer what I feel is a true value, even compared to real world prices—the kids’ meal.  These include the entrée (usually a burger, pizza, or chicken nuggets), two sides (fries, grapes, carrots, cookie), and a small drink for $4.99.  I can’t think of a fast food restaurant that offers that much food for that price in its kids’ meal.  And kids’ meals are filling for an adult, too.  My wife and I often order them for ourselves.  Not only are they cheaper, but the portion sizes are a little more reasonable.  I’m noticing a trend—most everything that saves you money on food also saves you some calories.  A double win!

Eating at Disney World doesn’t have to break the bank.  By being a smarter shopper, you can get quick, filling meals at the counter service restaurants and still have enough money for souvenirs.  Disney World offers some unique table service restaurants, however.  For many people, the table service dining is one of the highlights of a trip to Disney World, right up there with the attractions.  Next time, I’ll discuss some ways to save money at these restaurants as well.

 Contributed by: Mark Jeffries (NDD#102) Mark is the DDL Finance Blogger. 
 
Related posts:

 TABLE SERVICE SAVINGS EATING OFF-SITE WITHOUT LEAVING THE PARKS OUT OF THE WORLD SAVINGS Disney Room Service Please! DISNEY CRUISE LINE ROOM SERVICE 
 Tweet Contributed by Mark J Contributed by: Mark Jeffries (NDD#102) Mark is the DDL Finance Blogger. For other articles by Mark J click here 
Related posts:

 TABLE SERVICE SAVINGS EATING OFF-SITE WITHOUT LEAVING THE PARKS OUT OF THE WORLD SAVINGS Disney Room Service Please! DISNEY CRUISE LINE ROOM SERVICE 
 Posted in Dining Tips , Finance , Fitness , Lifestyle | Tagged Budgeting , counter service restaurants , Organization and Plannning , Saving money Bookmark the permalink .
Bookmark the Permalink | Post a Comment | Leave a Trackback BOOK CLUB: ODDS, BOBS, HAMMER AND TONGS MY EXPERIENCE AT THE IMGINATION PARK DISNEY STORE (Atlanta, GA) 
 Delightfully Disney 
Great tips! We often times share a soft drink as well, and not just at WDW!
 Mark J 
We’re with you. We usually share a soda everywhere we go. The more I learn about high fructose corn syrup, the more I try to cut it out of my diet. Plus, portion sizes are so large any more! A“small”drink is more than enough for 2 or 3 people.
 http://www.facebook.com/people/James-Leavor/60600957 James Leavor 
great tips. i love the counter service as well. at the all stars / pop resorts–i love getting the kids meal for breakfast. great food for a lot cheaper 
 
 
 Home Be Counted! Blog Community About Social Media 

 Contact Media Merchandise Events Affiliates Living The Life 
 © 2008- 2012 DDL | All Rights Reserved. No reproduction without written permission.
Please use the contact links above to send questions, comments, or corrections.
Use of this site is bound by The Disney Driven Life Disclaimer and The Disney Driven Life Rights and Usage . Recent Comments BLOG TOPICS: Recent Posts Disney Company Events History News Rumors Statistics Disney Driven Life DDL Announcements DDL Audio DDL Blogger of the Month DDL Meets DDL Photos DDL Tech DDL Video Disney Reviews D23 Disney Channel Disney Institute Games Imagineering Media Movies Recreation Resorts Restaurants Travel Reports inner mouse Podcast Vidcast Lifestyle Beauty and Fashion Career Business Celebrities Charity Community NDP Community NDP Community Report NDP of the Month NDPs in Action Culture African American Culture Asian Culture European Culture Fine Arts Music Psychology Seasons&amp;Holidays Education Environment Ethics Advice JL Speaks Finance Food Dining Tips Recipes Gifts Health Fitness Hobbies Collections Hats Pins Vinylmation Crafts Scrapbooks Gaming Literature Book of the Month Poetry Haiku Photography Hidden Mickeys Home Photos Park Photos Riddles Shopping Sports Interior Design Leisure Organization and Plannning Philosophy Relationships Marriage Honeymoons Weddings Parents Children Kids&apos; Viewpoint Pets Teens True Confessions of a Neurotic Disney Mom Solo Life Dating Special Needs Statistics Technology Vacation Cruises Disney Vacation Club Hidden Treasures Planning Travel Tips Uncategorized Top Contributors Blog Archives
	</body>
</document>
