<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006607" url="http://www.cabq.gov/envhealth/inspections/" time="2012-07-12-23:32" support="7" score="0.0197807479765814" bingtitle="Environmental Health | Restaurant Inspection &amp; Business Search" webtitle="Environmental Health | Restaurant InspectionBusiness Search">
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001101" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000236" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>Household Hazardous Waste. Contact. Lori Stoller, Consumer Health ... After a full assessment of an eating establishment, Food safety specialists fill out a ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content | Skip to navigation 
 Search Site 
 Albuquerque - Official City Website 

 Home Living Visiting Business A-Z Transparency 
 
 Environmental Health Home 
 Environmental Health News 

Disease Prevention

 H1N1 Influenza 
 Flu Shot Clinics 
 Mosquito Control 
 Bed Bugs 
 Bug of the Month 
 Influenza 
 Hepatitis 
 Staying Healthy 


Consumer Services

 Bake Sale Permits 
 Mold 
 Restaurant Inspections 
 Design/Construction of Food Establishments 
 Special Event Vendor Permits 
 Noise Monitoring 
 Vehicle Pollution 
 Tattoos / Body Art 
 Pool Safety 
 Report Food / Pool Complaint 


Environmental Protection

 Air Quality 
 Groundwater Monitoring 
 Landfill Monitoring 
 Household Pharmaceutical Disposal 


Healthy Living

 Safe School Lunches 
 Proper Hand Washing 
 Food Safety 
 Household Hazardous Waste 


Contact

Lori Stoller, Consumer Health Protection, Manager
 Phone: (505) 768-2718
 Email: lstoller@cabq.gov 
 Mailing Address: 
1 Civic Plaza NW
Albuquerque, NM 87102
 Physical Address: 
3rd floor City Hall Rm 3023
 
 Restaurant Inspections, Training Opportunities&amp;Business
 Search 

This service reflects current data. 
 
 Search Restaurant
 Inspections, Business Registrations&amp;Liquor Licenses 

 Free Basic Food Safety Training 
 
The Basic Food Safety training (BFST) is for individuals that are responsible for the operational
maintenance, food preparation, storage, distribution or sales of food at restaurants, mobile units, hotels,
cafeterias, hospitals, nursing homes and retail stores within the City of Albuquerque.
 
 2012 Food Training information and schedule 

( English / Spanish )
 
 Commonly Asked Questions 

 How do I register my business? What is a restaurant inspection? What is the difference between a Red and a Green Sticker? How often are restaurants inspected? How do I report a Food Born Illness? 

 What is a restaurant inspection? 

Routine inspections
 at food establishments are a&quot;snapshot&quot;of
 food safety operations on the particular day they are done.
 Critical and non-critical violations are recorded on an inspection
 form. Critical violations are factors that have been identified
 as items that could potentially cause a food borne illness.
 Most critical violations are typically corrected on the spot.
 However, some critical violations require additional time
 for compliance. If an establishment has one critical violation
 in a particular visit, they are placed ON NOTICE. They are
 given a specific time frame to correct the violation. If
 they correct it, they are taken off Notice. If they have
 not corrected the critical violation, they are downgraded.
 If they have four (4) or more critical violations in one
 visit, we issue a DOWNGRADE or pursue more severe enforcement
 action, depending on the situation. 

 What is the difference between a Red and a Green Sticker? 

All food service establishments must display the current grade
 sticker in a visible location. You will typically see the grade
 on the front door at eye level or lower. Some food service establishments
 with drive-thrus display the grade on their outside menu board
 as well.

If you see a green approved sticker, it means that a food service
 establishment received a passing grade at their last inspection
 from the food safety specialists. It means they have demonstrated
 skills and knowledge that create a safe and sanitary food service
 environment.

If you see a red unsatisfactory sticker, it means that the food
 service establishment failed a routine inspection and has been
 downgraded. Several factors contribute to a downgrade. The food
 service establishment either had four or more critical violations
 in one Health Department visit or a repeat of a critical violation
 from a previous inspection.

Food service establishments can still operate with a red sticker;
 however, downgraded food service establishments have ten (10) days
 to contact us for a reinspection before we suspend their operating
 permit. Most food service establishments correct the critical violations
 and contact us within 24 hours. If a food service establishment
 is downgraded more than 3 times in a three-year period, their permit
 is immediately suspended. 

 How often are Restaurants Inspected? 

It depends
 on the risk factors at a particular food service establishment.
 Food safety specialists are constantly on the look-out for those
 clues that help to categorize food related businesses into a High,
 Medium, or Low risk category. After a full assessment of an eating
 establishment, Food safety specialists fill out a form that helps
 to clarify the risk factors and determine how often their establishment
 is inspected. However, don&apos;t be alarmed when we refer to&quot;risk&quot;.
 A high-risk food service establishment simply means it falls into
 a category that would require at least three (3) inspections per
 year. Hospitals, nursing homes, schools and day care centers are
 just a few examples of food operations that could be identified
 as High Risk.

Fast food operations are typically in a medium risk category and
 are inspected at least twice per year. Bars, convenience stores,
 snack bars and some low complexity food service establishments
 are in a low risk category and are inspected once per year.
 
Translate this page:

 Español Français Deutsch 
 
 News Calendar About Contact Us Disclaimer&amp;Legal Statements Website Feedback? 
 Copyright©1994-2012 City of Albuquerque. All rights reserved. Official website for the City of Albuquerque www.cabq.gov
	</body>
</document>
