<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006810" url="http://zurich.amazes.us/" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="3" score="0.0035920498914159575" bingtitle="Zurich Amazes.Us" webtitle="Zurich Amazes.Us">
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>... the full and vast selection of foods and condiments ... near the main station also has a small fast-food restaurant. ... Sunday Trash, Schiffbaustrasse 3, +41 44 272 44 02.</description>
	<body>
		Home Random Page Advertise 
 
 
 
Zurich
in Articles 

 
Wikipedia says:

 Population 365,098 (Dec 2009) [ 1 ] - Density 3,974 /km 2 (10,292 /sq mi) Area   91.88 km 2 (35.48 sq mi) Elevation 408 m (1,339 ft)  - Highest 871 m - Uetliberg  - Lowest 392 m - Limmat Postal code 8000–8099 SFOS number 0261 Mayor (list) Corine Mauch (as of 2009) SPS/PSS Twin towns Kunming 
 San Francisco Website www.stadt-zuerich.ch 
 SFSO statistics 
 Zurich View map of Zurich 

 Zurich ( German : Zürich ) is the largest city in Switzerland and the capital of the canton of Zurich . It is located in central Switzerland [ 2 ] at the northwestern tip of Lake Zurich . While the municipality itself has approximately 380,500 inhabitants, the Zurich metropolitan area is an urbanised area of international importance constituted by a population of nearly 2 million inhabitants. [ 3 ] Zurich is a mixed hub for railways, roads, and air traffic. Both Zurich Airport and railway station are the largest and busiest in the country.

Permanently settled for around 7,000 years, the history of Zurich goes back to its founding by the Romans, who, in 15 BC, called it Turicum . During the Middle Ages Zurich gained the independent and privileged status of imperial immediacy and, in 1519, was the place of origin and centre of the Protestant Reformation in German-speaking Switzerland, led by Ulrich Zwingli . [ 4 ] 

Zurich is a leading global city and among the world&apos;s largest financial centres. [ 5 ] The city is home to a large number of financial institutions and banking giants. Also, most of the research and development centres are concentrated in Zurich and the low rate of tax attracts overseas companies to set up their headquarters there. According to several surveys from 2006 to 2008, Zurich was named the city with the best quality of life in the world as well as the wealthiest city in Europe. [ 6 ] [ 7 ] [ 8 ] 

An impressive number of museums and art galleries can be found in the city, among which the Swiss National Museum and the Kunsthaus . [ 9 ] Zurich also hosts one of the most important theatres in the German-speaking world. [ 10 ] 


Latest Tweets about Zurich:

 Bulletproofdork : “@edmx: @CarlosIQ a mí me gustaría una playera de Zurich :D #ytunieve XD // +1 Yay! Traenos una! Solo a nosotros xD 9 minutes ago via Twitter for iPhone · Reply · View Tweet servicejobsCH : #Job #Service Manager - Performance Improvement - Financial Services: ZH-Zürich, Take Charge of your Career. Now... http://bit.ly/hJtGPz ( expand ) 10 minutes ago via twitterfeed · Reply · View Tweet servicejobsCH : #Job #Service Senior - Performance Improvement - Financial Services: ZH-Zürich, Take Charge of your Career. Now.... http://bit.ly/gsyT1h ( expand ) 10 minutes ago via twitterfeed · Reply · View Tweet Jobs_WebSello : #Job #Schweiz #ch Junior Risk Manager: kessler vogler gmbh - Zürich - Für unseren Kunden, einer der führenden As... http://bit.ly/btpLrf ( expand ) 10 minutes ago via twitterfeed · Reply · View Tweet eeddbbmm : The Zurich , Switzerland airport is basically an exhibition of the Helvetica typeface. 10 minutes ago via TweetDeck · Reply · View Tweet edmx : @CarlosIQ a mí me gustaría una playera de Zurich :D #ytunieve XD 11 minutes ago via TweetDeck · Reply · View Tweet · Show Conversation Hide Conversation Job_Medicinal : Medicinal NNIT A/S - Senior pharma CRM consultant for life sciences consulting: http://bit.ly/hfKc7Y ( expand ) 12 minutes ago via twitterfeed · Reply · View Tweet 
 http://www.zuerich.com/ says:
Zürich - Your city - Official Website of Zürich Tourism - zuerich.com - Zürich Tourism



 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home
 +41 (0) 44 215 40 00 
 City Map
 
 Webcam
 
 
 
 
 
 -13°
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 Choose Language
 
 Deutsch
 English
 Français 
 Italiano
 Español
 
 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Visitors
 
 Meeting&amp;Convention
 
 Media
 
 Travel Trade
 
 Premium Service
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Accommodation 
 
 
 
 
 Hotels /
 
 
 Packages /
 
 
 Apartments /
 
 
 B&amp;B;/
 
 
 Hostels /
 
 
 Campsites 
 
 
 
 
 
 Gastronomy 
 
 
 
 
 Restaurants /
 
 
 Cafes and Bars /
 
 
 Nightlife 
 
 
 
 
 
 Tours 
 
 
 
 
 Guided City Walks /
 
 
 City Tours /
 
 
 Excursions /
 
 
 Team Events 
 
 
 
 
 
 Experience 
 
 
 
 
 Attractions /
 
 
 Shopping /
 
 
 Culture /
 
 
 Events /
 
 
 Nature /
 
 
 Around Zürich 
 
 
 
 
 
 Information 
 
 
 
 
 Contact /
 
 
 Arrival /
 
 
 Transport /
 
 
 Facts /
 
 
 ZürichCARD /
 
 
 Brochures      Zürich. Christmas magic.
 ... be captivated by Zürich&apos;s Christmas atmosphere
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 The legendary New Year&apos;s Eve fireworks display
 ... Celebrate New Year’s Eve with spectacular fireworks at Switzerland’s largest New Year’s Eve party
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Time-honored treats in this gourmet’s paradise
 ... at one of Zürich’s guild house restaurants
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Unlimited shopping pleasure
 ... shopping in Zürich provides inspiration for both lovers of exclusive brands and followers of fashion
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Cultural highlights
 ... at the Kunsthaus Zürich, for example, with art ranging from the 15th century to the present
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Green Oases In and Around Zürich
 ... such as the Masoala Hall at Zoo Zurich
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Hotel search
 
 
 
 
 
 Arrival
 
 
 
 Nights
 
 
 1
 2
 3
 4
 5
 6 
 
 
 Persons
 
 
 1
 2
 3
 4
 
 
 
 
 Rooms
 
 
 1
 2
 3
 4
 5
 6 
 
 
 
 
 all
 single
 double
 multi-bed room
 apartment
 three bed room
 four bed room
 five bed room
 suite
 junior suite
 
 
 
 
 Price (max.)
 
 
 
 CHF
 EUR
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Stars (min.)
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 max. Distance
 
 
 
 1
 3
 5
 10&gt;10
 km
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 from
 
 City center / Main railway station Zürich
 
 
 
 Airport Zürich
 
 
 
 
 Search by name›More options›Hide search options Sorell Hotel Seefeld***+
 from CHF 160 per double room
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Sorell Hotel Seidenhof***+
 from CHF 240 per double room
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Hotel Krone Winterthur
 from CHF 150 per double room
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Sorell Hotel Rütli***
 from CHF 180 per double room
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Hotel Zürichberg Zürich
 from CHF 250 per double room
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 





 


 
 


 



 


A walk through the old Town
Wed / Sat / Sun, CHF 20 / EUR 14 





 
 

 




Social Media&amp;Apps 












 


 
 






 




Our Key Partners 






 


 
 

 




Zürich Spirit Gold Promotor 




 
 &gt; more promoters of Zürich Spirit Gold 


 
 

 





 

Check out what other travellers say about Zürich. 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 





 
 Zürich – The Unique Mix As a lifestyle capital on the water, Zürich offers the unique mix of discovery, pleasure, nature and culture. The finest culinary highlights, unlimited shopping pleasure, over 50 museums and more than 100 galleries, Switzerland’s liveliest nightlife, numerous events and countless green oases in the center of the city tempt guests to linger and enjoy.
 



 




 
 
 
 
 New Year&apos;s Magic
 New Year&apos;s Eve in Zürich
 Switzerland’s largest New Year’s Eve party with spectacular fire-works&amp;more tips for celebrating New Year’s Eve. more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Accommodation
 Online Hotel Reservations
 Book now free of charge: there’s a choice of over 250 hotels – from backpacker to luxury. more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Packages
 PICASSO&amp;HOTEL
 From October 15, 2010 until January 30, 2011, the Kunsthaus Zürich will revive the first museum…more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Restaurants
 Zunfthaus zur Waag
 The menu at the Zunfthaus zur Waag reflects the culinary creativity of its kitchen. You will be…more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Attractions
 Zürich Highlights
 There are so many sights to see in Zürich. Discover the highlights here. more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 ZürichCARD
 Your City-Card
 The ZürichCARD provides a whole range of benefits. more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 



 









 
 
 
 
 Zürich ideas for...
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Young people
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 50+
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Groups
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Gays&amp;Lesbians
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Luxury lovers
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Smart spenders
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Families
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 People with disabilities
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Green Tourists Hotel Reservations for Groups
 
 We will find&amp;book the appropriate hotel in Zurich for your group. more
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 A walk through the Old Town for Groups / with a Private Guide
 
 Everyone – even locals – will find that a guided walk through the Old Town is a worthwhile trip…more
 
 
 
 
 
 year-round 
 Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun 
 
 
 
 
 
 Free quote
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 City Tour in Your Own Bus with Private Tour Guide
 
 Enjoy a city tour in your own bus with a private tour guide from Zürich Tourism.

Discover…more
 
 
 
 
 
 year-round 
 Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun 
 
 
 
 
 
 Free quote Print
 Read this page
 Send to a friend
 
 
 
 
 Copyright©Zürich Tourism
 





 
 
 


 
 
 
 
 
 About this website
 
 
 Order, Book&amp;Download
 
 
 Choose Language:
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Sitemap
 
 Imprint
 
 GTC
 
 Privacy Policy
 
 
 
 
 
 Contact:
 +41 (0) 44 215 40 00 
 information@zuerich.com
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Hotels
 
 
 Restaurants
 
 
 Tours
 
 
 ZürichCARD
 
 
 Car Rental
 
 
 Vouchers
 
 
 Tickets
 
 
 Souvenirs
 
 
 Brochures
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Deutsch
 English
 Français 
 Italiano
 Español
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 







 Order newsletter
 http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich says:
Zurich - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia


































 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Zurich
 
 
 
 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Jump to: navigation,
 search
 
 
 
 For other uses of &quot;Zurich&quot;, see Zurich (disambiguation).


Zurich




Top: Night view of Zurich from Uetliberg, Middle left: National Museum, Middle right: Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Bottom: View over Zurich and the lake.





Country
Switzerland



Canton
Zurich


District
Zurich


47°22′N 8°33′E﻿ / ﻿47.367°N 8.55°E﻿ / 47.367; 8.55Coordinates: 47°22′N 8°33′E﻿ / ﻿47.367°N 8.55°E﻿ / 47.367; 8.55





Population
365,098 (Dec 2009)[1]


- Density
3,974 /km2 (10,292 /sq mi)


Area 91.88 km2 (35.48 sq mi)


Elevation
408 m (1,339 ft) - Highest
871 m - Uetliberg - Lowest
392 m - Limmat


Postal code
8000–8099


SFOS number
0261


Mayor (list)
Corine Mauch (as of 2009) SPS/PSS


Twin towns
 Kunming
 San Francisco


Website
www.stadt-zuerich.ch 
SFSO statistics







Zurich







View map of Zurich


Zurich (German: Zürich) is the largest city in Switzerland and the capital of the canton of Zurich. It is located in central Switzerland [2] at the northwestern tip of Lake Zurich. While the municipality itself has approximately 380,500 inhabitants, the Zurich metropolitan area is an urbanised area of international importance constituted by a population of nearly 2 million inhabitants.[3] Zurich is a mixed hub for railways, roads, and air traffic. Both Zurich Airport and railway station are the largest and busiest in the country.
Permanently settled for around 7,000 years, the history of Zurich goes back to its founding by the Romans, who, in 15 BC, called it Turicum. During the Middle Ages Zurich gained the independent and privileged status of imperial immediacy and, in 1519, was the place of origin and centre of the Protestant Reformation in German-speaking Switzerland, led by Ulrich Zwingli.[4]
Zurich is a leading global city and among the world&apos;s largest financial centres.[5] The city is home to a large number of financial institutions and banking giants. Also, most of the research and development centres are concentrated in Zurich and the low rate of tax attracts overseas companies to set up their headquarters there. According to several surveys from 2006 to 2008, Zurich was named the city with the best quality of life in the world as well as the wealthiest city in Europe.[6][7][8]
An impressive number of museums and art galleries can be found in the city, among which the Swiss National Museum and the Kunsthaus.[9] Zurich also hosts one of the most important theatres in the German-speaking world.[10]




Contents


1 Name
2 History

2.1 Early history
2.2 Old Swiss Confederacy
2.3 Modern history
2.4 Coat of arms


3 Government
4 Geography

4.1 Topography
4.2 Climate
4.3 Climate protection
4.4 Urban area


5 City districts
6 Transport
7 Demographics

7.1 Languages
7.2 Religion
7.3 Social


8 Main sights

8.1 Churches
8.2 Museums
8.3 Parks and nature
8.4 Architecture


9 Economy

9.1 Contributory factors to economic strength
9.2 The Swiss stock exchange


10 Education and research
11 Media

11.1 Television and radio
11.2 Print media


12 Culture

12.1 Opera, ballet and theaters
12.2 Food
12.3 Nightlife and clubbing


13 Sports

13.1 Events


14 Notable people
15 See also
16 References

16.1 Notes


17 External links





[edit] Name
The Swiss standard German pronunciation of the name is [ˈtsyːrɪç] ( listen). In Zurich German without the final consonant, Züri [ˈtsyɾi], although the adjective remains Zürcher [ˈtsyrxər]. The city is called Zurich [zyʁik] in French, Zurigo [dzuˈriːɡo] in Italian, and Turitg [tuˈritɕ] in Romansh.
In English, the name is usually written Zurich, without the umlaut. It is pronounced /ˈzjʊərɪk/ (ZEWR-ik) or /ˈzʊərɪk/; more recently sometimes also with /ts/ as in German.[11]
The earliest known form of the city&apos;s name is Turicum, attested on a tombstone of the late 2nd century AD in the form STA(tio) TURICEN(sis) (&quot;Turicum tax post&quot;). Neither the name&apos;s linguistic origin (most likely Rhaetic or Celtic) nor its meaning can be determined with certainty. A possibility is derivation from *Turīcon, from the Gaulish personal name Tūros.[12] The stress on the long vowel of the Gaulish name, [tuˈriːkon], was lost in German [ˈtsyːʁɪç] but is preserved in Italian Zurigo [dzuˈriːɡo].
A first development towards its later, Germanic form is attested as early as the 6th century with the form Ziurichi. From the 10th century onward, the name has more or less clearly been established as Zürich (Zurih (857), Zurich (924)).[13]
Zurich is sometimes referred to as &quot;Downtown Switzerland&quot; for publicity reasons.[14]
[edit] History
Main article: History of Zurich
[edit] Early history




Zurich in Roman times


Settlements of the Neolithic and Bronze Age were found around Lake Zurich. Traces of pre-Roman Celtic, La Tène settlements were discovered near the Lindenhof hill. In Roman times, Turicum was a tax-collecting point at the border of Gallia Belgica (from AD 90 Germania superior) and Raetia for goods trafficked on the Limmat river. After Emperor Constantine’s reforms in AD 318, the border between Gaul and Italy (two of the four praetorian prefectures of the Roman Empire) was located east of Turicum, crossing the Linth River between Lake Walen and Lake Zurich, where a castle and garrison looked over Turicum’s safety. The earliest written record of the town dates from the 2nd century, with a tombstone referring to it, discovered at the Lindenhof.
In the 5th century, the Germanic Alamanni tribe settled in the Swiss plateau. The Roman castle remained standing until the 7th century. A Carolingian castle, built on the site of the Roman castle by the grandson of Charlemagne, Louis the German, is mentioned in 835 (in castro Turicino iuxta fluvium Lindemaci). Louis also founded the Fraumünster abbey in 853 for his daughter Hildegard. He endowed the Benedictine convent with the lands of Zurich, Uri, and the Albis forest, and granted the convent immunity, placing it under his direct authority. In 1045, King Henry III granted the convent the right to hold markets, collect tolls, and mint coins, and thus effectively made the abbess the ruler of the city.[15]
Zurich became reichsunmittelbar in 1218 with the extinction of the main line of the Zähringer family and attained a status comparable to statehood. During the 1230s, a city wall was built, enclosing 38 hectares, when the earliest stone houses at the Rennweg were built as well. The Carolingian castle was used as a quarry, as it had started to fall into ruin.[16]
Emperor Frederick II promoted the abbess of the Fraumünster to the rank of a duchess in 1234. The abbess assigned the mayor, and she frequently delegated the minting of coins to citizens of the city. However, the political power of the convent slowly waned in the 14th century, beginning with the establishment of the Zunftordnung (guild laws) in 1336 by Rudolf Brun, who also became the first independent mayor, i.e. not assigned by the abbess.
An important event in the early 14th Century was the completion of the Manesse Codex, a key source of medieval German poetry. The famous illuminated manuscript – described as &quot;the most beautifully illumined German manuscript in centuries;&quot;[17] – was commissioned by the Manesse family of Zurich, copied and illustrated in the city at some time between 1304 and 1340. Producing such a work was a highly expensive prestige project, requiring several years work by highly skilled scribes[18] and miniature painters, and it clearly testifies to the increasing wealth and pride of Zurich citizens in this period.
[edit] Old Swiss Confederacy




A scene of the Old Zurich War


On May 1, 1351, the citizens of Zurich had to swear allegiance before representatives of the cantons of Lucerne, Schwyz, Uri and Unterwalden, the other members of the Swiss Confederacy. Thus, Zurich became the fifth member of the Confederacy, which was at that time was a loose confederation of de facto independent states. Zurich was the presiding canton of the Diet from 1468 to 1519. This authority was the executive council and lawmaking body of the confederacy, from the Middle Ages until the establishment of the Swiss federal state in 1848. Zurich was temporarily expelled from the confederacy in 1440 due to a war with the other member states over the territory of Toggenburg (the Old Zurich War). Neither side had attained significant victory when peace was agreed upon in 1446, and Zurich was re-admitted to the confederation in 1450.[19]




The Murerplan of 1576.


Zwingli started the Swiss Reformation at the time when he was the main preacher in the 1520s, at the Grossmünster. He lived there from 1484 until his death in 1531. The Zurich Bible, based on that of Zwingli, was issued in 1531. The Reformation resulted in major changes in state matters and civil life in Zurich, spreading also to a number of other cantons. However, several cantons remained Catholic and became the basis of serious conflicts that eventually led to the outbreak of the Wars of Kappel.
During the 16th and 17th centuries, the Council of Zurich adopted an isolationist attitude, resulting in a second ring of imposing fortifications built in 1624. The Thirty Years&apos; War which raged across Europe motivated the city to build these walls. However, the fortifications required a lot of resources, which were taken from subject territories without reaching any agreement. The following revolts were crushed brutally. In 1648, Zurich proclaimed itself a republic, shedding its former status of a free imperial city.[20]




Fighting on the Paradeplatz during the Züriputsch


The Helvetic Revolution of 1798 saw the fall of the Ancien Régime. Zurich lost control of the land and its economic privileges, and the city and the canton separated their possessions between 1803–1805. In 1839, the city had to yield to the demands of its urban subjects, following the Züriputsch of 6 September. Most of the ramparts built in the 17th century were torn down, without ever having been besieged, to allay rural concerns over the city&apos;s hegemony. The Treaty of Zurich between Austria, France, and Sardinia was signed in 1859.[21]
[edit] Modern history




Bahnhofplatz in 1900


Zurich was the Federal capital for 1839–40, and consequently the victory of the Conservative party there in 1839 caused a great stir throughout Switzerland. But when in 1845 the Radicals regained power at Zurich, which was again the Federal capital for 1845–46, Zurich took the lead in opposing the Sonderbund cantons. Following the Sonderbunb war and the formation of the Swiss Federal State, Zurich voted in favour of the Federal constitutions of 1848 and of 1874. The enormous immigration from the country districts into the town from the &quot;thirties&quot; onwards created an industrial class which, though &quot;settled&quot; in the town, did not possess the privileges of burghership, and consequently had no share in the municipal government. First of all in 1860 the town schools, hitherto open to &quot;settlers&quot; only on paying high fees, were made accessible to all, next in 1875 ten years&apos; residence ipso facto conferred the right of burghership, while in 1893 the eleven outlying districts were incorporated with the town proper
Extensive developments took place during the 19th century. From 1847, the Spanisch-Brötli-Bahn, the first railway on Swiss territory, connected Zurich with Baden, putting the Zürich Hauptbahnhof at the origin of the Swiss rail network. The present building of the Hauptbahnhof (the main railway station) dates to 1871. Zurich’s Bahnhofstrasse (Station Street) was laid out in 1867, and the Zurich Stock Exchange was founded in 1877. Industrialisation led to migration into the cities and to rapid population growth, particularly in the suburbs of Zurich.
Zurich was accidentally bombed during World War II.
[edit] Coat of arms




The coat of arms on the Town Hall


The blue and white coat of arms of Zurich is attested from 1389, and was derived from banners with blue and white stripes in use since 1315 . The first certain testimony of banners with the same design is from 1434. The coat of arms is flanked by two lions. The red Schwenkel on top of the banner had varying interpretations: For the people of Zurich, it was a mark of honour, granted by Rudolph I. Zurich&apos;s neighbours mocked it as a sign of shame, commemorating the loss of the banner at Winterthur in 1292.
Today, the Canton of Zurich uses the same coat of arms as the city.
[edit] Government
See also: List of mayors of Zurich
The City Council (Stadtrat) constitutes the executive government of the City of Zurich and operates as a collegiate authority. It is composed of nine councilors, each presiding over a department. The president of the executive department acts as mayor. Current city president is Corine Mauch. Departmental tasks, coordination measures and implementation of laws decreed by the City Parliament are carried by the City Council. The election of the City Council by registered voters is held every four years. The executive body holds its meetings in the City Hall, on the bank of the Limmat. The building was built in 1883 in Renaissance style.
On the other hand, the City Parliament (Gemeinderat) holds the legislative power. It is made up of 125 members, with elections also held every four years. The City Parliament decrees regulations and by-laws that are executed by the City Council and the administration. The sessions of the City Parliament are public. Unlike the member of the City Council, the members of the City Parliament are not politicians by profession, but they are paid a fee based on their attendance. Any resident of Zurich allowed to vote can be elected as a member of the City Parliament. The legislative body holds its meetings in the Town Hall, opposite to the City Hall.[22]
As of 2010, the Zurich City Council is made up of four representatives of the SDP (Social Democratic Party, one of whom is the mayor), two members of the FDP (Free Democratic Party), two members of the Green Party and one member of the CVP (Christian Democratic Party).[23]
[edit] Geography




The Limmat river in Zurich


Zurich is situated at 408 m above sea level on the lower (northern) end of Lake Zurich (Zürichsee) about 30 km north of the Alps, nestled between the wooded hills on the west and east side. The Old Town stretches on both sides of the Limmat river, which flows from the lake, running northwards at first and then gradually turning into a curve to the west. The geographic (and historic) centre of the city is the Lindenhof, a small natural hill on the west bank of the Limmat, about 700 meters north of where the river issues from Lake Zurich. Today the incorporated city stretches somewhat beyond the natural hydrographic confines of the hills and includes some neighbourhoods to the northeast in the Glatt Valley (German: Glattal) and to the north in the Limmat Valley (German: Limmattal). However the boundaries of the older city are easy to recognize by the Schanzengraben canal. This artificial watercourses has been used for the construction of the third fortress in the 17th and 18th centuries.
[edit] Topography
The municipality of Zurich has an area of 91.88 square kilometers, of which 4.1 km² is composed by Lake Zurich. The area includes a section of the northern Swiss Plateau. The banks of the Limmat constitute the densest part of the city. The river is oriented in the southeast-northwest direction, with the flat valley floor having a width of two to three kilometers. The partially channeled and straightened Limmat does not flow in the central part of the valley, but always along its right (northeastern) side. The river Sihl meets with the Limmat at the end of Platzspitz, which borders the Swiss National Museum. The Limmat reaches the lowest point of the municipality in Oberengstringen at 392 m above sea level.




The Uetliberg from Lake Zurich






Zurich from Waidberg


On its west side the Limmat valley is flanked by the wooded heights of the Albis chain, which runs on the western border. The Uetliberg is, with 869 m above sea level, the highest elevation of the surrounding area. Its summit can be reached easily by the Uetlibergbahn. From the platform of the observation tower on the summit, an impressive panorama of the city, the lake and the Alps can be seen.
The northeast side of the Limmat valley includes a range of hills, which marks the watershed between the Limmat and the Glatt. From the northwest to the southeast, the height of the mostly wooded knolls increases: the Gubrist (615 m), the Hönggerberg (541 m), the Käferberg (571 m), the Zürichberg (676 m) and the Adlisberg (701 m). Between the Käferberg and the Zürichberg is located the saddle of the Milchbuck (about 470 m), an important passage from the Limmat valley to the Glatt valley.
The northernmost part of the municipality extends to the plain of the Glatt valley and to the saddle which makes the connection between the Glattal and Furttal. Also a part of the Katzensee (nature reserve) and the Büsisee, both of which are drained by the Katzenbach to Glatt, belong to the city.
[edit] Climate
Zurich has, depending on the definition used, an oceanic or humid continental climate (Köppen Cfb/Dfb), with four distinct seasons. Decisive for the climate of Zurich are both the winds from westerly directions, which often result in precipitations and, on the other hand, the Bise (east or north-east wind), which is usually associated with high-pressure situations, but cooler weather phases with temperatures lower than the average. The Foehn wind, which plays an important role in the northern alpine valleys, has a limited impact on Zurich.
The annual mean temperature at the measuring station of the Federal Office of Meteorology and Climatology in Zurich (556 m above sea level on the slope of the Zürichberg, 150 m above the level of the city center) is 8.5 °C (47.3 °F). The coldest month mean temperatures are measured in January with −0.5 °C (31.1 °F) and the warmest are measured in July with 17.6 °C (63.7 °F). On average there are 88 days in which the minimum temperature is below 0 C°C, and 26 days in which the maximum temperature is below 0 °C. There are on average 30 summer days (above 25 °C) throughout the year, while hot days (with a temperature reaching 30 °C) are only three. The average high temperature in July are 23.6 °C (74.5 °F) and low temperature are 11.6 °C (52.9 °F). Spring and autumn are generally cool to mild. These values are relatively low compared to other stations on the plateau but they can be explained by the altitude of the station. In the Limmat valley more summer days and hot days can be expected. Zurich has an average of 1482 hours of sunshine per year. The 1,136 millimetres (44.7 in) rainfall spread throughout the year. During the summer months and especially the three summer months, levels of rainfall are higher than those measured in winter. The meteorological station at Kloten gives an average precipitation of 1,031 millimetres (40.6 in).


Climate data for Zurich (Kloten, 1961–1990)


Month
Jan
Feb
Mar
Apr
May
Jun
Jul
Aug
Sep
Oct
Nov
Dec
Year


Average high °C (°F)
2.0
(35.6)
4.5
(40.1)
8.8
(47.8)
13.2
(55.8)
17.9
(64.2)
21.2
(70.2)
23.6
(74.5)
22.7
(72.9)
19.5
(67.1)
13.7
(56.7)
7.0
(44.6)
3.1
(37.6)
13.1
(55.6)


Average low °C (°F)
-4.1
(24.6)
-3.2
(26.2)
-0.7
(30.7)
2.5
(36.5)
6.4
(43.5)
9.7
(49.5)
11.6
(52.9)
11.2
(52.2)
8.5
(47.3)
4.9
(40.8)
0.2
(32.4)
-2.8
(27)
3.7
(38.7)


Precipitation mm (inches)
67
(2.64)
68
(2.68)
68
(2.68)
78
(3.07)
96
(3.78)
115
(4.53)
106
(4.17)
121
(4.76)
83
(3.27)
70
(2.76)
84
(3.31)
74
(2.91)
1,031
(40.59)


% Humidity
86.0
81.5
75.5
72.8
72.4
72.9
72.2
75.2
78.9
84.9
85.4
86.1
78.7


Avg. precipitation days
10.9
9.5
10.9
11.6
12.4
12.2
11.2
11.5
8.4
8.0
10.1
10.4
127.1


Sunshine hours
35
69
115
144
176
191
223
195
155
92
49
31
1,475


Source: MeteoSchweiz [24]


[edit] Climate protection
The city of Zurich is among[citation needed] the world-leaders in protecting the climate by following a manifold approach. Recently[when?], for example, the people of Zurich voted in a public referendum to write into law the quantifiable and fixed deadline of one tonne of CO2 per person per annum by 2050. This forces any decision of the executive to support this goal, even if the costs are higher in all dimensions. Some examples are the new disinfection section of the public city hospital in Triemli (Minergie-P quality – passive house)[clarification needed], the continued optimisation and creation of public transportation, enlargement of the bicycle-only network, research and projects for renewable energy and enclosure of speed-ways[clarification needed].
[edit] Urban area
The areas surrounding the Limmat are almost completely built over (residential, industrial areas, commercial zones). Also densely built, the sun-exposed and preferred residential locations on the hills overlooking Zurich, Waidberg and Zürichberg and the bottom section of the slope on the western side of the valley on the Uetliberg.
The green lungs of the city include the vast forest areas of Adlisberg, Zürichberg, Käferberg, Hönggerberg and Uetliberg. Major parks are also located along the lakeshore (Zurichhorn and Enge). Furthermore, the cultivated area through parks and gardens is loosened. Larger contiguous agricultural lands are located near Affoltern and Seebach. Of the total area of the municipality of Zurich (in 1996, without the lake), 45.4% are settlements, industry and commerce, 15.5% are transports, 26.5% are forests, 11%: is agriculture and 1.2% is water.





View over Zurich and Lake Zurich from the Uetliberg


[edit] City districts
Main article: Subdivisions of Zurich




Satellite photo of central Zurich






Zurich&apos;s twelve municipal districts.


The previous boundaries of the city of Zurich (before 1893) were more or less synonymous with the location of the old town. Two large expansions of the city limits occurred in 1893 and in 1934 when the city of Zurich merged with many surrounding municipalities, that had been growing increasingly together since the 19th century. Today, the city is divided into twelve districts (known as Kreis in German), numbered 1 to 12, each one of which may contain anywhere between 1 and 4 neighborhoods:

District 1, known as Altstadt, contains the old town, both to the east and west of the start of the Limmat river.
District 2 lies along the west side of Lake Zurich, and contains the neighbourhoods of Enge, Wollishofen and Leimbach.
District 3, known as Wiedikon is between the Sihl river and the Uetliberg, and contains the neighbourhoods of Alt-Wiedikon, Sihlfeld and Friesenberg.
District 4, known as Aussersihl lies between the Sihl and the train tracks leaving Zürich Hauptbahnhof.
District 5, known as Industriequartier, is between the Limmat and the train tracks leaving Zürich Hauptbahnhof, it contains the former industrial area of Zurich which has gone under a large-scale rezoning to create upscale modern housing, retail and commercial real estate.
District 6 is on the edge of the Zürichberg, a hill overlooking the eastern part of the city. District 6 contains the neighbourhoods of Oberstrass and Unterstrass. There neighbourhoods are home to Zurich&apos;s wealthiest and more prominent residents.
District 7 is on the edge of the Adlisberg hill as well as the Zürichberg, on the eastern side of the city. District 7 contains the neighbourhoods of Hottingen and Hirslanden.
District 8, known as Riesbach, lies on the eastern side of Lake Zurich.
District 9 is between the Limmat to the north and the Uetliberg to the south. It contains the neighbourhoods Altstetten and Albisrieden.
District 10 is to the east of the Limmat and to the south of the Hönggerberg and Käferberg hills. District 10 contains the neighbourhoods of Höngg and Wipkingen.
District 11 is in the area north of the Hönggerberg and Käferberg and between the Glatt valley and the Katzensee (Cat&apos;s Lake). It contains the neighbourhoods of Affoltern, Oerlikon and Seebach.
District 12, known as Schwamendingen, is located in the Glattal (Glatt valley) on the northern side of the Zürichberg.

Most of the district boundaries are fairly similar to the original boundaries of the previously existing municipalities before they were incorporated into the city of Zurich.
[edit] Transport
Main articles: Verkehrsbetriebe Zürich, Zurich trams, and Zurich S-Bahn
See also: Zurich model




A paddle steamer on Lake Zurich


Public transport is extremely popular in Zurich and its inhabitants use public transport in large numbers. About 70% of the visitors to the city use the tram or bus and about half of the journeys within the municipality take place on public transport.[25] Within Zurich and throughout the canton of Zurich, the ZVV network of public transport has traffic density ratings among the highest worldwide. When adding frequency, which in Zurich can be as often as 7 minutes, it does become the densest across all dimensions. Three means of mass-transit exist: the S-Bahn (local trains), trams, and buses (both diesel and electric, also called trolley buses). In addition, the public transport network includes boats on the lake and river, funicular railways and even the Luftseilbahn Adliswil-Felsenegg (LAF), a cable car between Adliswil and Felsenegg. Tickets purchased for a trip are valid on all means of public transportation (train, tram, bus, boat). The Zürichsee-Schifffahrtsgesellschaft (commonly abbreviated to ZSG) operates passenger vessels on the Limmat river and the Lake Zurich, connecting surrounding towns between Zurich and Rapperswil.




The busy Hauptbahnhof main hall


Zurich is a mixed hub for railways, roads, and air traffic. Zürich Hauptbahnhof is the largest and busiest station in Switzerland and is an important railway hub in Europe. It has several other railway stations, including Oerlikon, Stadelhofen, Hardbrücke, Tiefenbrunnen, Enge, Wiedikon and Altstetten. The railway network is mainly operated by the Federal Railways but Zurich is also served by the major InterCity trains from the neighbouring countries.
Zurich Airport is located less than 10 kilometres northeast of the city in Kloten. Zurich Airport has its own railway station, which is located underground. It is directly connected to Zurich and most of the major Swiss cities. There is also an airfield in Dübendorf.
The A1, A3 and A4 motorways pass close to Zurich. The A1 heads west towards Berne and Geneva and eastwards towards St. Gallen; the A4 leads northwards to Schaffhausen; and the A3 heads northwest towards Basel and southeast along Lake Zurich and Lake Walen towards Sargans.
[edit] Demographics




Augustinergasse in the old town


There are officially 358,540 people living in Zurich (as of 2007[update]),[26] making it Switzerland&apos;s largest city. Of registered inhabitants, 30.6% (115,379 people) do not hold Swiss citizenship.[27] Of these, German citizens make up the largest group with 22.0%, followed by Italians. The population of the city proper including suburbs totals 1.08 million people.[28] However, the entire metropolitan area (including the cities of Winterthur, Baden, Brugg, Schaffhausen, Frauenfeld, Uster/Wetzikon, Rapperswil-Jona and Zug) has a population of around 1.68 million people.[29]
[edit] Languages
The official language used by the government and in most publications is German, while the main language is Zurich German (Züritüütsch), which is a dialect of Alemannic. As of 2000, speakers with Alemannic or German as their mother-tongue make up 77.7% of the population. Italian follows behind at 4.7% of the population. Other native languages spoken by more than 1% of the population include South Slavic languages (2.2%)—this includes Serbian, Bosnian, Croatian, Macedonian, and Slovenian, Spanish (2.2%), French (2.1%), English (1.8%), Portuguese (1.6%), Albanian (1.5%).[30]
[edit] Religion
Since the reformation led by Huldrych Zwingli, Zurich has remained the centre and stronghold of protestantism in Switzerland. In the course of the 20th century, this has changed as Catholics became larger than the reformed church in the city, with 33.3% in the year 2000.[31] An increasing number of residents, about 16.8% of the population in 2000, declared themselves as being without religion.[citation needed]. However since 2000, those declaring no religion or having a religion other than either mainstream Protestantism or Catholicism has grown rapidly. As per the end of 2009, this group declaring no religion or a religion other than mainstream Christianity is the largest within both the Canton of Zurich and the City of Zurich.[32] For the city of Zurich, at the end of 2008, less than a third (112,000) were catholics, even fewer (97,000) were reformed and by far the largest group with 157,000 is those with none or another confession (like Muslims).[33]
[edit] Social
The level of unemployment in Zurich was 2.6%[34] in August 2007. About 4% of the city population, 15,500, live either directly or indirectly on welfare payment from the state (April 2005).[35]
[edit] Main sights
Further information: Zurich old town




The Bahnhofstrasse seen from Paradeplatz


Most of Zurich&apos;s sights are located within the area on either side of the Limmat river, between the Main railway station and Lake Zurich. The churches and houses of the old town are clustered here, as are the most expensive shops along the famous Bahnhofstrasse. The Lindenhof in the old town is the historical site of the Roman castle, and the later Carolingian Imperial Palace.
[edit] Churches

Grossmünster (great minster) (near Lake Zurich, in the old city), where Zwingli was pastor; first built around 820; declared by Charlemagne imperial church


Fraumünster (our lady&apos;s minster) first church built before 874; the Romanesque choir dates from 1250–70; Marc Chagall stained glass choir windows; (on the opposite side of the Limmat). During 2004 the Fraumünster was fully renovated. During this period the installed scaffolding went above the tip of the tower allowing a unique and exceptional 360° panoramic view of Zurich.


St. Peter (downstream from the Fraumünster, in the old city); with the largest church clock face in the world.

[edit] Museums

Zurich Museum of Art – The Museum of Art, also known as Kunsthaus Zürich, is one of the significant art museums of Europe. It holds one of the largest collections in Classic Modern Art in the world (Munch, Picasso, Braque, Giacometti, etc.). The museum also features a large library collection of photographs.[36]


Swiss National Museum – The National Museum (German: Landesmuseum) displays many objects that illustrate the cultural and historical background of Switzerland. It also contains many ancient artifacts, including stained glass, costumes, painted furniture and weapons. The museum is located in the Platzspitz park opposite to the Hauptbahnhof.[37]


Centre Le Corbusier – Located on the shore of the Lake Zurich nearby Zürichhorn, the Centre Le Corbusier (also named: Heidi Weber Museum), is an art museum dedicated to the work of the Swiss architect Le Corbusier, inside the last house he designed.


Rietberg Museum – The Rietberg Museum, situated in Gablerstrasse, is one of the great repositories of art and culture in Zurich. The museum also displays exhibits gathered from various corners of the world: bronze artifacts from Tibet, ceramics and jade, Indian sculpture, Chinese grave decorations, masks by African tribes etc.


Museum of Design – The Museum of Design is a museum for industrial design, visual communication, architecture and craft. It is part of the Department of Cultural Analysis of the Zurich University of the Arts.[38]


Haus Konstruktiv – The Haus Konstruktiv is a museum with Swiss-wide and international recognition. The museum is about constructive, concrete and conceptual art and design. It testimonies to Zurich’s industrial architecture in the immediate vicinity of the Main Station.[39]


Uhrenmuseum Beyer – The Uhrenmuseum is located in the heart of the city. Documenting the history of timekeeping and timekeepers, the museum is home to a large collection of mechanical timepieces as well as a collection of primitive time keeping devices such as water clocks, sundials and hourglasses


Guild houses – The Guild houses (German: Zunfthaus) are located along the Limmat river (downstream from the Grossmünster): Meisen (also a porcellan and fayence museum), Rüden, Haue, Saffran, Schneidern, Schmiden, Zimmerleuten, and some more.

[edit] Parks and nature

Zoological Garden – The zoological garden holds about 260 species of animals and houses about 2200 animals. One can come across separate enclosures of snow leopards, India lions, clouded leopards, Amur leopards, otters and pandas in the zoo.[40]


Botanical Garden – The Botanical Garden houses about 15,000 species of plants and trees and contains as many as three million plants. In the garden, many rare plant species from south western part of Africa, as well as from New Caledonia can be found. The University of Zurich holds the ownership of the Botanical Garden.


Chinese Garden – The Chinese Garden is a gift by Zurich&apos;s Chinese partner town Kunming, as remiscence for Zurich&apos;s technical and scientific assistance in the development of the Kunming city drinking water supply and drainage. The garden is an expression of one of the main themes of Chinese culture, the «Three Friends in Winter» – three plants that together brave the cold season – pine, bamboo and winter cherry.


Uetliberg – Located to the west of the city at an altitude of 813 meters above sea level, the Uetliberg is the highest hill and offers views over the city. The summit is easily accessible by train from Zurich main station.[41]

[edit] Architecture




The Sunrise Tower (2005) was the first approved high-rise building in twenty years


Compared to other cities, there are few tall buildings in Zurich. The municipal building regulations (Article 9)[42] limit the construction of high-rise buildings to areas in the west and north of the city. In the industrial district, in Altstetten and Oerlikon, buildings up to 80 meters in height are allowed (high-rise area I). In the adjacent high-rise areas II and III the height is limited to 40 meters. Around the year 2000, regulations became more flexible and high-rise buildings were again planned and built. The people&apos;s initiative &quot;40 meters is enough,&quot; which would have reduced both the maximum height and the high-rise buildings area, was clearly rejected on 29 November 2009.[43] At this time in Zurich about a dozen high-rises buildings were under construction or in planning, including the Prime Tower as the tallest skyscraper in Switzerland.





Panoramic view of Münsterhof square with some of the Guild houses


[edit] Economy
Zurich is a leading financial center and global city.[5] The Greater Zurich Area is Switzerland&apos;s economic centre and home to a vast number of international companies. By far the most important sector in the economy of Zurich is the service industry, which employs nearly four fifths of workers. Other important industries include light industry, machine and textile industries and tourism. Most Swiss banks have their headquarters in Zurich and there are numerous foreign banks in the Greater Zurich Area. Located in Zurich, the Swiss Stock Exchange was established in 1877 and is nowadays the fourth most prominent stock exchange in the world. In addition Zurich is the world&apos;s largest gold trading centre. Ten of the country&apos;s 50 largest companies have their head offices in Zurich, among them UBS,[44] Credit Suisse, Swiss Re and Zurich Financial Services.[45]
[edit] Contributory factors to economic strength
The high quality of life has been cited as a reason for economic growth in Zurich. The consulting firm Mercer has for many years ranked Zurich as a city with the highest quality of life in the world.[6][7] In particular, Zurich received high scores for work, housing, leisure, education and safety. Local planning authorities ensure clear separation between urban and recreational areas and there are many protected nature reserves.[46] Other cities in the country, Berne and Geneva, were also listed among the top ten. Zurich is also ranked the sixth most expensive city in the world. In 2008, Zurich was ranked ninth. The city ranked behind Hong Kong and ahead of Copenhagen. It is the third most expensive city in Europe and second most expensive city in Switzerland after Geneva.[47]
Zurich benefits from the high level of investment in education that is typical of Switzerland in general and provides skilled labour at all levels. The city is home to two major universities, thus enabling access to graduates and high technology research. Professional training incorporates a mix of practical work experience and academic study while, in general, emphasis is placed on obtaining a good level of general education and language ability. As a result the city is home to many multilingual people and employees generally demonstrate a high degree of motivation and a low level of absenteeism. Such characteristics are reflected in the high level of productivity the region enjoys and account for the opening of offices and research centres in the city by large corporations.[46]
[edit] The Swiss stock exchange




The Swiss stock Exchange on Selnaustrasse.


The Swiss stock exchange is called SIX Swiss Exchange, formerly known as SWX. The SIX Swiss Exchange is the head group of several different worldwide operative financial systems: virt-x, Eurex, Eurex US, EXFEED and STOXX. The exchange turnover generated at the SWX was in 2007 of 1,780,499.5 million CHF; the number of transactions arrived in the same period at 35,339,296 and the Swiss Performance Index (SPI) arrived at a total market capitalization of 1,359,976.2 million CHF.[48][49]
The SIX Swiss Exchange goes back more than 150 years. In 1996, fully electronic trading replaced the traditional floor trading system at the stock exchanges of Geneva (founded in 1850), Zurich (1873) and Basel (1876).
Since 2008, the SIX Swiss Exchange has been part of the SIX Group, as SWX Group, SIS Group and Telekurs Group merged.
[edit] Education and research




Main building of the University of Zurich


About 60,000 people study at the 20 universities, colleges and institutions of higher education in Zurich. Two of Switzerland&apos;s most distinguished universities are located in the city. The Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (ETH Zurich) which is controlled by the (federal) state and the University of Zurich that is under direction of the canton of Zurich. Both universities were listed in the top 50 world universities rated in 2007.[50]
ETH was founded in 1854 by the Swiss Confederation and opened its doors in 1855 as a polytechnic institute. ETH achieved its reputation particularly in the fields of chemistry, mathematics and physics and there are 21 Nobel Laureates who are associated with the institution. ETH is usually ranked the top university in continental Europe.[51] The institution consists of two campuses, the main building in the heart of the city and the new campus on the outskirts of the city.
The University of Zurich was founded in 1833, although its beginnings date back to 1525 when the Swiss reformer Ulrich Zwingli founded a college of theology. Nowadays with its 24,000 students and 1,900 graduations each year, the University of Zurich is the largest in Switzerland and offers the widest range of subjects and courses at any Swiss higher education institution.
The Pedagogical College, the Zurich University of Applied Sciences (ZHAW) and the Zurich University of the Arts (ZHdK) are another three top-class technical colleges which contribute to Zurich&apos;s reputation as a knowledge and research pole by providing applied research and development. Zurich is also one of the co-location centres of the Knowledge and Innovation Community (Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation) of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology.[52]
[edit] Media
Many large Swiss media conglomerates are headquartered in Zurich, such as tamedia, Ringier and the NZZ-Verlag. Zurich is one of the most important media locations in the German speaking part of the country. This status has been recently reinforced by the increase in availability of online publications published in Zurich.[citation needed]
[edit] Television and radio




Buildings of the Swiss television


The headquarters of Switzerland&apos;s national licence fee funded German language television network (&quot;SF&quot;) are located in the Leutschenbach neighborhood, to the north of the Oerlikon train station. Regional commercial television station &quot;TeleZüri&quot; (Zurich Television) has its headquarters near Escher-Wyss Platz. The production facilities for other commercial stations &quot;Star TV&quot;, &quot;u1&quot; TV and &quot;3+&quot; are located in Schlieren.
One section of the Swiss German language licence fee funded public radio station &quot;Schweizer Radio DRS&quot; is located in Zurich. There are commercial local radio stations broadcasting from Zurich, such as &quot;Radio 24&quot; on the Limmatstrasse, &quot;Energy Zürich&quot; in Seefeld on the Kreuzstrasse, Radio &quot;LoRa&quot; and &quot;Radio 1&quot;. There are other radio stations that operate only during certain parts of the year, such as &quot;CSD Radio&quot; (May/June), &quot;Radio Streetparade&quot; (July/August) and &quot;rundfunk.fm&quot; (August/September).
[edit] Print media
There are three large daily newspapers published in Zurich that are known across Switzerland. The Neue Zürcher Zeitung (NZZ), the Tages-Anzeiger and the Blick, the largest Swiss tabloid. All three of those newspapers publish Sunday editions. These are the &quot;NZZ am Sonntag&quot;, &quot;SonntagsZeitung&quot; and &quot;SonntagsBlick&quot;. Besides the three main daily newspapers, there are free daily commuter newspapers which are widely distributed: 20 Minuten (20 minutes), published weekdays in the mornings, News (weekday morning) and Blick am Abend,[53] weekdays but in the late afternoon, and Cash,[54] a finance-related weekday free newspaper published in the mornings, but only available at certain branded newspaper sales kiosks.
There are a number of magazines from major publishers that are based in Zurich. Some examples are: Bilanz, Die Weltwoche, and Annabelle.
[edit] Culture





This section needs additional citations for verification.
Please help improve this article by adding reliable references. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed. (March 2009)


See also: List of annual events in Zurich




Opening of the Zurich Film Festival (2008)


Zurich has a rich cultural tradition. In addition to high-quality museums and galleries, Zurich has high-calibre chamber and symphony orchestras and several important theatres.[55]
The Zurich Film Festival is one of the most important upcoming international film festivals. In just a few years, the Festival became firmly established upon the national and international festival landscape. Over the course of 11 days, it attracts both stars and new talents and celebrates popular international productions.[56]




Zurich during the Street Parade (2008)


One of the largest and most popular annual events in Zurich is the Street Parade, which is also one of the largest techno and dance music festival in the world. Proceeding along the side of Lake Zurich, it normally occurs on the second Saturday in August. The first edition was held In 1992 with about 1,000 participants. By 2001 the event had reached the size of 1 million participants.[57][58] The Zürifäscht, on the other hand, is a triennial public festival. It features music, fireworks set to music,[58] and other attractions throughout the old town. It is the largest public festival in Switzerland and is attended by up to 2 million visitors.[59]
The Kunst Zürich is an international contemporary art fair with an annual guest city; it combines most recent and youngest art with the works of well-established artists.[60] Another annual public art exhibit is the city campaign, sponsored by the City Vereinigung (the local equivalent of a chamber of commerce) with the cooperation of the city government. It consists of decorated sculptures distributed over the city centre, in public places. Past themes have included lions (1986), cows (1998), benches (2003), teddy bears (2005), and huge flower pots (2009). From this originated the concept of the CowParade that has been featured in other major world cities.
Zurich is also the home to several art movements. The Cabaret Voltaire where the Dada movement was founded in 1916. Constructive Art Movement took also one of the first steps in Zurich. Artists like Max Bill, Marcel Breuer, Camille Graeser or Richard Paul Lohse had their ateliers in Zurich, which became even more important after the takeover of power by the Nazi-Regime in Germany and World War II.
[edit] Opera, ballet and theaters




Opernhaus


The Zurich Opera House (German: Zürcher Opernhaus) is one of the principal opera houses in Europe. Built in 1834, it was the first permanent theatre in the heart of Zurich and was at the time, the seat of Richard Wagner&apos;s activities. Later in 1890, the theatre was re-built as an ornate building with a neo-classical architecture. The portico is made of white and grey stone ornamented with the busts of Wagner, Weber and Mozart. Later, busts of Schiller, Shakespeare and Goethe were also added. The auditorium is designed in the rococo style. Once a year, it hosts the Zürcher Opernball with the President of the Swiss Confederation and the economic and cultural élite of Switzerland.[61]
The Schauspielhaus Zürich is the main theatre complex of the City. It has two dépendances: Pfauen in the Central City District and Schiffbauhalle, an old industrial hall, in Zurich West. The Schauspielhaus was home to emigrants such as Bertolt Brecht or Thomas Mann, and saw premieres of works of Max Frisch, Friedrich Dürrenmatt, Botho Strauss or Elfriede Jelinek. The Schauspielhaus is one of the most prominent and important theatres in the German-speaking world.[62]
The Theater am Neumarkt is one of the oldest theatres of the city. Established by the old guilds in the Old City District, it is located in a baroque palace near Niederdorf Street. It has two stages staging mostly avantgarde works by European directors.
The Zürcher Theater Spektakel is an international theatre festival, ranking among the most important European festivals for contemporary performing arts.[63]
[edit] Food
The traditional cuisine of Zurich consists of traditional fare, reflecting the centuries of rule by patrician burghers as well as the lasting imprint of Huldrych Zwingli&apos;s puritanism. Traditional dishes include Zürcher Geschnetzeltes and Tirggel.
[edit] Nightlife and clubbing




Zurich at night.


Zurich offers a great deal of variety when it comes to night-time leisure. It is the host city of the world-famous Street Parade, which takes place in August every year.
The most famous districts for Nightlife are the Niederdorf in the old town with bars, restaurants, lounges, hotels, clubs, etc. and a lot of fashion shops for a young and stylish public and the Langstrasse in the districts 4 and 5 of the city. There are authentic amusements: Brazilian bars, punk clubs, HipHop stages, Caribic restaurants, arthouse-cinemas, Turkish kebabs and Italian espresso-bars, but also sex shops or the famous red light district of Zurich.
In the past ten years new parts of the city have risen into the spotlight. Notably, the area known as Zurich West in district 5, near the Escher-Wyss square and the S-Bahn Station of Zurich Hardbrücke.
[edit] Sports
The people of Zurich enjoy an active lifestyle and sport is an integral part of Swiss culture and society. The abundance of international sporting facilities make Zurich an attractive place for sport lovers and several international sport federations are located in the city.




FIFA headquarters


Association football is an essential aspect of sports in Zurich. The city is home to two major Swiss football teams listed in Switzerland&apos;s highest league; Grasshopper-Club Zürich founded in 1886 and FC Zürich which has existed since 1896. The Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) is headquartered in the city. In 2007 were inaugurated the new FIFA headquarters building, designed by architect Tilla Theus
Among the most popular sports in Switzerland is ice hockey. In Zurich it is represented by the ZSC Lions. The International Ice Hockey Federation (IIHF) officiating as head organisation for ice hockey leagues worldwide is based in Zurich as well.
Biking is a popular sport as well as a mean of transport in Zurich. Biking routes are generally marked with red and white signs and the yellow lanes are exclusively meant for the bikers. Also hiking trails are well marked with yellow signs, which give the hiker the probable time it will take him to reach his destination. There are specific maps available for hiking and walking trails throughout Switzerland. Some of the most accessible walks in the Zurich area are the Uetliberg and the Zürichberg.
As many as 30 clubs and 7 indoor Curling facilities can be found in the greater Zurich area. The Curling season starts in early September and continues until the end of April.[64]
[edit] Events




2007 Zürich Weltklasse


Weltklasse Zürich, sometimes referred to as the one day Olympics, is one of prestigious one day athletics meet held annually at the Letzigrund Stadium. The Weltklasse is reputed as one of the best and most classy athlete meet in the world after the Olympics. Since it started in August 12, 1928, the sporting event has witnessed new world records and national records. Till date as many as 24 world records were set in Weltklasse.[65][66][67]
Zurich Marathon is a popular sport event, inviting numerous athletes from every corner of the globe. Zurich Marathon is a long distance running event, covering approximately 43 kilometers at one stretch. The running course starts from Zurich and passes through Bahnhofstrasse, Bellevue, Mythenquai, Quaibrücke, Talstrasse and Utoquai, and along Lake Zurich to several other places. New Year&apos;s Eve run is another important running event. The race is held on January 1 each year and the start takes place at midnight exactly.
Zurich was one of six venues of the 1954 FIFA World Cup and one of eight venues of the UEFA Euro 2008. The Euro 2008 games were held in the Letzigrund Stadium. Work on the new Letzigrund was completed in exceptionally quick time and the stadium opened in August 2007 just one year after the demolition of the old arena.
Zurich also hosted the 1998 World Ice Hockey Championships. The city previously co-hosted the 1953 and 1939 editions.
[edit] Notable people
People who were born or died in Zurich:

Antonio Ligabue (1899–1965), Italian painter, born in Zurich
Grand Duchess Marie Alexandrovna of Russia (1853–1920), Duchess of Edinburgh, died in Zurich
Richard Avenarius (19 November 1843 – 18 August 1896) Philosopher
Diego Benaglio (1983–) footballer
Felix Bloch (1905–1983), physicist, born in Zurich
Heinrich Bullinger (July 18, 1504 – September 17, 1575), reformer and theologian.
Elias Canetti (1905–1994), novelist, died in Zurich
Wilhelm Filchner (1877–1957), explorer, died in Zurich
Max Frisch (1911–1991), novelist, born and died in Zurich
Christoph Froschauer (ca. 1490–1 April 1564) Printer of the Froschauer Bible
Conrad Gessner (1516–1565), naturalist, born and died in Zurich
Marcel Grossmann (1878–1936), mathematician, died in Zurich
Otto Hunziker (1873–1959), pioneer in the international dairy industry
James Joyce (1882–1941), Irish novelist, died in Zurich (buried at Fluntern cemetery in Zurich)
Carl Jung (1875–1961) Lived and died in Zurich
Gottfried Keller (1819–1890), poet, born and died in Zurich
Amanullah Khan (1929–1960), Deposed Afghan reformist King died in Zurich
Otto Klemperer (1885–1973), German conductor, died in Zurich (buried at Isreatlitischer Friedhof Oberer Friesenberg)
Hugo Koblet (1925–1964), cycling champion
Johann Kaspar Lavater (1741–1801), poet and physiognomist, born in Zurich
Hugo Loetscher (1929–2009), writer, born and died in Zurich
Dieter Meier (1945), conceptual artist and musician with electronica group Yello, born in Zurich
Conrad Ferdinand Meyer (1825–1898), poet, born in Zurich
Wolfgang Pauli (1900–1958), physicist, died in Zurich
Johann Heinrich Pestalozzi (1746–1827), educational reformer, born in Zurich
James Sadleir (c. 1815–1881), fugitive swindler, murdered in Zurich
Johann Jakob Scheuchzer (1672–1733), scholar, born in Zurich
Johanna Spyri (1827–1901), author of Heidi, died in Zurich
Tobias Stephan – NHL Player
Pancho Vladigerov (1899–1978), Bulgarian composer, born in Zurich
Huldrych Zwingli (1484–1531), reformer

Famous residents:

Gustav Bertha (2000–2009)
Boris Blank, musician with Yello
Mileva Maric, Serbian mathematician and the first wife of Albert Einstein
Albert Einstein (1896–1900, 1909–1911, 1912–1914)
James Joyce (1915–1919)
Udo Jürgens
Celtic Frost
Patricia Kaas
Vladimir Lenin (1917)
Thomas Mann (1933–1942)
Kurt Tucholsky (1932–1933)
Tina Turner
Tristan Tzara (1896–1963)
Richard Wagner (1849–1861)

[edit] See also




Switzerland portal




Eastern Switzerland
List of mayors of Zurich
Paddle steamer Stadt Zürich

[edit] References
[edit] Notes



^ Canton of Zurich Statistical Office (German) accessed 26 May 2010
^ &quot;Zurich entry at the Swiss Tourist Board&quot;. Myswitzerland.com. http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/destinations/resorts/holiday-destinations-in-switzerland/zurich.html. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ The Zurich Metropolitan Area: a motor for Europe, Stadt-zuerich.ch. Retrieved on 2010-03-10
^ History zuerich.com. Retrieved on 2010-03-10
^ a b World&apos;s 10 Most Powerful Cities prlog.org. Retrieved on 2010-03-10
^ a b &quot;2007 World-wide quality of living survey&quot;. Mercer. 2007-04-02. http://www.mercer.com/referencecontent.htm?idContent=1173105. Retrieved 2008-08-08. ^ a b &quot;Mercer&apos;s 2008 Quality of Living survey highlights&quot;. Mercer. 2008-06-10. http://www.mercer.com/qualityofliving?siteLanguage=100. Retrieved 2008-08-08. ^ Mercer – Quality of Living global city rankings 2009 – Mercer survey, 28 April 2009
^ Museums and galleries zurich-relocation.ch. Retrieved on 2010-03-10
^ Zurich Culture worldtravelguide.net. Retrieved on 2010-03-10
^ Jones, Daniel (1997). English Pronouncing Dictionary. Cambridge: Cambridge UP. p. 559. ISBN 0521-45903-6. ^ Andres Kristol, Zürich ZH (Zürich) in: Dictionnaire toponymique des communes suisses – Lexikon der schweizerischen Gemeindenamen – Dizionario toponomastico dei comuni svizzeri (DTS|LSG), Centre de dialectologie, University of Neuchâtel, Verlag Huber, Frauenfeld/Stuttgart/Wien 2005, ISBN 3-7193-1308-5 und Éditions Payot, Lausanne 2005, ISBN 2-601-03336-3, p. 992f.
^ Zürcher Ortsnamen – Entstehung und Bedeutung, H. Kläuli, V. Schobinger, Zürcher Kantonalbank (1989), p. 109.
^ [1]
^ Early History of Zurich europe-cities.com. Retrieved 2010-07-15.
^ Zurich as the part of the German Empire europe-cities.com. Retrieved 2010-07-15.
^ Ingeborg Glier, reviewing Koschorreck and Werner 1981 in Speculum 59.1 (January 1984), p 169.
^ Koschorreck and Werner 1981 discern no fewer than eleven scribes, some working simultaneously, in the production.
^ Old Swiss Confederacy europe-cities.com. Retrieved 2010-07-14.
^ Reformation to Napoleonic Era europe-cities.com. Retrieved 2010-07-15.
^ &quot;New International Encyclopedia – Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;. En.wikipedia.org. 2009-04-10. http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_International_Encyclopedia. Retrieved 2009-05-06. ^ &quot;Official site of the city parliament in German&quot;. Gemeinderat-zuerich.ch. http://www.gemeinderat-zuerich.ch/. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ Politics&amp;Law stadt-zuerich.ch. Retrieved 2010-07-14.
^ &quot;MeteoSchweiz – Tabellen&quot; (in German). MeteoSchweiz. http://www.meteosuisse.admin.ch/web/de/klima/klima_schweiz/tabellen.html. Retrieved 2009-05-28. ^ Public transportation zurich-relocation.com. Retrieved on 2010-06-26
^ Bundesamt fur Statistik (Federal Department of Statistics) (2008). &quot;Bilanz der ständigen Wohnbevölkerung (Total) nach Bezirken und Gemeinden&quot;. http://www.bfs.admin.ch/bfs/portal/de/index/themen/01/02/blank/key/raeumliche_verteilung/kantone__gemeinden.html. Retrieved November 5, 2008. ^ &quot;Bevölkerung Stadt Zürich&quot; (in German) (PDF). Statistical Office of the City of Zürich. 2008-03-06. http://www.stadt-zuerich.ch/internet/stat/home/publikationen/regelmaessige-publikationen/quartalsweise_erscheinende/2007_4Q_BEV.ParagraphContainerList.ParagraphContainer0.ParagraphList.0002.File.pdf/BEV_4Q_2007.pdf. Retrieved 2008-08-22. ^ Statistical Office of the City of Zürich
^ &quot;Statistical Office of the Canton of Zürich&quot;. Statistik.zh.ch. http://www.statistik.zh.ch/raum/agglomerationen.php?p=3. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ Population Numbers Flyer (German)
^ &quot;Gemeinde Zürich:&quot;. Data.statistik.zh.ch. https://data.statistik.zh.ch/infospc/geport/gemeinde.jsp?bfs=171. Retrieved 2009-05-06. ^ &quot;Wohnbevölkerung nach Konfession&quot;. http://www.statistik.zh.ch/themenportal/themen/daten_detail.php?id=673. Retrieved 2010-06-25. ^ http://www.zh.kath.ch/publikationen/arbeitspapiere/wohnbevoelkerung-der-gemeinden-nach-der-konfession-am-31-dezember-2008-amtsblatt/wohnbevoelkerung-der-gemeinden-nach-der-konfession/file
^ Stadt-zuerich.ch
^ Population chart
^ Kunsthaus Zürich – das Kunstmuseum in Zürich. Kunsthaus.ch (2008-06-30). Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ Swiss National Museums. Musee-suisse.com. Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ Museum-gestaltung.ch. Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ Haus Konstruktiv. Hauskonstruktiv.ch. Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ Zoo.ch[dead link]
^ Uetliberg – Zürich – Your city – Official Website of Zürich Tourism. Zuerich.com. Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ Bauordnung der Stadt Zürich
^ 40 Meter sind den Zürchern nicht genug. www.tagesanzeiger.ch. Retrieved 2009-12-05
^ &quot;UBS AG in Zurich, Bahnhofstrasse 45.&quot; (PDF) UBS. Retrieved on 2 July 2010.
^ Zurich bcg.thetime.co.uk. Retrieved on 2010-06-26
^ a b Zurich: Overview usatoday.com. Retrieved on 2010-06-26
^ Worldwide Cost of Living survey 2009. Mercer.com (2009-07-07). Retrieved on 2010-02-09.
^ SWX.com Market capitalization of listed securities, 2000–2007
^ SWX.com Key figures: annual turnover and trades, 1998–2007
^ &quot;Newsweek Ranking&quot; (PDF). http://ucla.nus.edu.sg/NewsweekTop100GlobalUniversities2006.pdf. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ ETH Zurich (Swiss Federal Institute of Technology) topuniversities.com. Retrieved on 2010-04-30
^ &quot;Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation&quot;. Knowledge and Innovation Community. http://eit.europa.eu/fileadmin/Content/Downloads/PDF/news_items/Summary_Climate-KIC.pdf. Retrieved 9 February 2010. ^ &quot;Blickamabend.ch&quot;. Blickamabend.ch. http://www.blickamabend.ch. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ Cash.ch
^ Zurich worldtravelguide.net. Retrieved 2010-07-14.
^ Zurich Film Festival festivalfocus.org. Retrieved 2010-07-14.
^ Street Parade travelguide.all-about-switzerland.info. Retrieved 2010-07-15.
^ a b &quot;Zurich festivals&quot;. Markstravelnotes.com. 2008-01-20. http://www.markstravelnotes.com/europe/switzerland/canton_zurich/zurich/faescht/. Retrieved 2010-07-03. ^ &quot;Zürifäscht 2010&quot;. Zuerifaescht.ch. http://www.zuerifaescht.ch/. Retrieved 2010-06-15. ^ Kunstzuerich.ch. &quot;Kunst Zürich 2007 | Kunstmesse Zürich&quot;. Kunstzuerich.ch. http://www.kunstzuerich.ch/. Retrieved 2009-05-06. ^ Zurich: Swiss urbanism at its best worldradio.ch. Retrieved 2010-07-29.
^ Zurich Culture worldtravelguide.net. Retrieved on 2010-06-27
^ &quot;Theaterspektakel&quot;. Theaterspektakel.ch. http://www.theaterspektakel.ch/(cyneig45iqfbdv2qwogr1w55)/Frames/index.aspx?Page=default&amp;Parm=. Retrieved 2009-05-06. ^ Sport zurich-relocation.ch. Retrieved on 2010-07-14
^ weltklassezuerich.ch. Retrieved on 2010-07-14
^ Zurich is number one with 16 Berlin Champions competing weltklassezuerich.ch. retrieved on 2010-07-14
^ IAAF considers expanded Golden League supersport.com. Retrieved on 2010-07-14



[edit] External links



Wikimedia Commons has media related to: Zürich





Wikisource has original text related to this article:
Zürich




Stadt Zürich (German) Official site
City of Zurich Official Site, English Version
Zürich Tourism Official site
Zürich Info Zürich Informations
Zürich Discussion Group
24 Hours in Zurich Travel Guide to Zurich
Zurich Festivals Guide to events and festivals in Zurich
Zurich travel guide from Wikitravel
Touring Zurich - slideshow by The New York Times








v • d • e

Cities in Switzerland by population





300,000+


Zurich








100,000+


Basel · Bern · Geneva · Lausanne · Winterthur







30,000+


Bienne · Chur · Fribourg · Köniz · La Chaux-de-Fonds · Lucerne · Lugano · Neuchâtel · St. Gallen · Schaffhausen · Thun · Vernier







15,000+


Aarau · Adliswil · Allschwil · Baar · Baden · Bellinzona · Burgdorf · Carouge · Dietikon · Emmen · Frauenfeld · Gossau · Grenchen · Herisau · Horgen · Kloten · Kreuzlingen · Kriens · Lancy · Littau · Locarno · Meyrin · Monthey · Montreux · Muttenz · Olten · Onex · Ostermundigen · Pratteln · Rapperswil-Jona · Regensdorf · Renens · Schwyz · Sierre · Sion · Solothurn · Spiez · Steffisburg · Thalwil · Vevey · Volketswil · Wädenswil · Wettingen · Wetzikon · Wil · Yverdon-les-Bains · Zollikon · Zug













v • d • e

Districts in the city of Zurich






Altstadt (1) · 2 · Wiedikon (3) · Aussersihl (4) · Industriequartier (5) · 6 · 7 · Riesbach (8) · 9 · 10 · 11 · Schwamendingen (12)














v • d • e

Capitals of Swiss cantons   Aarau, Aargau
Herisau/Trogen, AR
Appenzell, AI
Basel, Basel-Stadt




Liestal, Basel-Land
Bern, Bern
Fribourg, Fribourg
Geneva, Geneva




Glarus, Glarus
Chur, Graubünden
Delémont, Jura
Lucerne, Lucerne




Neuchâtel, Neuchâtel
Stans, Nidwalden
Sarnen, Obwalden
Schaffhausen, SH




Schwyz, Schwyz
Solothurn, Solothurn
St. Gallen, St. Gallen
Frauenfeld Thurgau




Bellinzona, Ticino
Altdorf, Uri
Sion, Valais
Lausanne, Vaud




Zug, Zug
Zurich, Zurich


















v • d • e

Lake Zurich (Zürichsee)






Switzerland   Canton of Zurich (Horgen · Meilen · Zürich) · Canton of St. Gallen (See-Gaster) · Canton of Schwyz (Höfe · March)





Settlements

Altendorf · Au · Bäch · Bollingen · Erlenbach · Feldbach · Feldmeilen · Freienbach · Herrliberg · Horgen · Hurden · Jona · Kehlhof · Kempraten · Kilchberg · Küsnacht · Lachen · Männedorf · Meilen · Nuolen · Oberrieden · Pfäffikon · Rapperswil · Richterswil · Rüschlikon · Schmerikon · Stäfa · Thalwil · Uerikon · Uetikon am See · Wädenswil · Zollikon · Zurich








Islands

Au peninsula · Lützelau · Ufenau






Rivers

Jona · Limmat · Linth






Valleys

Limmattal · Sihltal






Mountains

Adlisberg · Etzel · Pfannenstiel · Uetliberg · Zimmerberg · Zürichberg






Landmarks

Albis · Felsenegg · Seedamm






Transportation

S-Bahn Zürich · Südostbahn · Zürichsee-Schifffahrtsgesellschaft (ZSG)






 






Retrieved from &quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich&quot;
 
 
 Categories: Municipalities of the canton of Zurich | Municipalities of Switzerland | Zurich | Cantonal capitals of Switzerland | Cities in SwitzerlandHidden categories: All articles with dead external links | Articles with dead external links from July 2010 | All articles with unsourced statements | Articles with unsourced statements from March 2010 | All pages needing cleanup | Vague or ambiguous time from March 2010 | Wikipedia articles needing clarification from March 2010 | Articles containing potentially dated statements from 2007 | All articles containing potentially dated statements | Articles with unsourced statements from March 2009 | Articles with unsourced statements from November 2008 | Articles needing additional references from March 2009 | All articles needing additional references 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


 Personal tools
 
 Log in / create account
 



 
 


 Namespaces
 
 Article
 Discussion
 






 Variants
 
 
 
 



 
 
 


 Views
 
 Read
 Edit
 View history
 






 Actions
 
 
 
 






 Search
 
 
 
 
 
 
 



 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


 Navigation
 
 
 Main page
 Contents
 Featured content
 Current events
 Random article
 Donate to Wikipedia
 
 










 Interaction
 
 
 Help
 About Wikipedia
 Community portal
 Recent changes
 Contact Wikipedia
 
 






 Toolbox
 
 
 What links here
 Related changes
 Upload file
 Special pages
 Permanent link
 Cite this page 
 






 Print/export
 
 Create a bookDownload as PDFPrintable version 






 Languages
 
 
 Afrikaans
 Alemannisch
 አማርኛ
 العربية
 Aragonés
 ܐܪܡܝܐ
 Arpetan
 বাংলা
 Bân-lâm-gú
 Беларуская
 Беларуская (тарашкевіца)
 Boarisch
 Bosanski
 Brezhoneg
 Български
 Català
 Чӑвашла
 Česky
 Cymraeg
 Dansk
 Deitsch
 Deutsch
 Eesti
 Ελληνικά
 Español
 Esperanto
 Euskara
 فارسی
 Français
 Gaeilge
 Gàidhlig
 Galego
 한국어
 हिन्दी
 Hornjoserbsce
 Hrvatski
 Ido
 Bahasa Indonesia
 Иронау
 Íslenska
 Italiano
 עברית
 Basa Jawa
 ქართული
 Kiswahili
 Latina
 Latviešu
 Lëtzebuergesch
 Lietuvių
 Lumbaart
 Magyar
 മലയാളം
 मराठी
 مصرى
 Bahasa Melayu
 Nāhuatl
 Dorerin Naoero
 Plattdüütsch
 Nederlands
 日本語
 Nordfriisk
 ‪Norsk (bokmål)‬
 ‪Norsk (nynorsk)‬
 Occitan
 پنجابی
 Piemontèis
 Polski
 Português
 Română
 Rumantsch
 Runa Simi
 Русский
 Shqip
 Sicilianu
 Simple English
 Slovenčina
 Slovenščina
 Српски / Srpski
 Srpskohrvatski / Српскохрватски
 Suomi
 Svenska
 Tagalog
 தமிழ்
 ไทย
 Türkçe
 Українська
 ئۇيغۇرچە / Uyghurche‎
 Vèneto
 Tiếng Việt
 Volapük
 Winaray
 Wolof
 吴语
 ייִדיש
 Yorùbá
 粵語
 中文
 
 



 
 
 
 
 
 This page was last modified on 22 December 2010 at 00:04.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of Use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc., a non-profit organization.Contact us
 
 
 Privacy policy
 About Wikipedia
 Disclaimers
 http://www.zurichna.com/ says:
Zurich Business Insurance - Risk management solutions for commercial companies.
 
 
 

 

 




















 
 

 
 
 
 
 

 





 






















 
 
 



 
 
 Global websitesSitemapOther US sitesContact  Home
 
 Products
 
 Corporate Business
 
 Claims
 
 Online Services
 
 Careers
 
 Media
 
 About Zurich
 
 Login Zurich reports solid operating performance for the first nine months of 2010
Recent News Releases Making Headlines Zurich Online Network 

 

 
 
 
 
Whitepapers Webinars - Register Now Custom Content in the Media 

 
 
 
 
 
 
Insurance Solutions by Industry Manage your risk Industry Contacts 

 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

Helpful risk management tools and information delivered to your inbox.
 
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 Zurich Virtual Literature Rack
 Easy access to marketing materials
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Automotive
 Learn about the leading causes of loss impacting your automotive business 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Manufacturing
 Identify your manufacturing company&apos;s top ten risks with Zurich Virtual Risk Consultant
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Accident&amp;Health
 Help protect your employees by managing business travel risks.
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Real Estate
 Learn how to reduce your vacant building risks and become more aware of coverage pitfalls.
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Energy
 Better understand your company&apos;s top ten risks with Zurich Virtual Consultant. 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 
 View all our FREE HelpPoint Delivered subscription offers
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 Terms of usePrivacyAgent/Broker Compensation DisclosureCopyright © 2010 Zurich
 http://wikitravel.org/en/Zurich says:
Zurich travel guide - Wikitravel
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 Help Wikitravel grow by contributing to an article. Learn how.
 Zurich
 
 From Wikitravel
 Switzerland : Zurich (region) : Zurich
 
 Jump to: navigation, search 
 
 Contents
 
 

Understand

[+]
Get in 
By plane

By train

By car

By bus

By boat



[+]
Get around 
[+]
Public transportation 
By tram and bus

By rail

By boat



On foot

By bike

By car



See

[+]
Do 
Events

Shows and Theater



Learn

Work

[+]
Buy 
Swiss clocks and watches

[+]
Swiss chocolate 
Brands

Confectioneries



Swiss handcrafts

Swiss army knives

Markets

Other



[+]
Eat 
[+]
Budget 
Food courts



Mid-range

Splurge



[+]
Drink 
[+]
Bars 
Center

Kreis 2 (Wollishofen)

Kreis 4 (Langstrasse)

Kreis 5 (Zürich West)



Clubs

Gay and lesbian travellers



[+]
Sleep 
Budget

Mid-range

Splurge

Camping



Stay safe

Contact

Cope

Get out

 
 
 
 
 Zurich [1] (German: Zürich, Zürich German: Züri) is the largest city in Switzerland, with a population of some 364,500 in the city proper and close to 1 million in the agglomeration area. Zurich is on Lake Zurich, where the lake meets the Limmat River, in the north of Switzerland. 


[edit] Understand
Zurich is the largest city of the Swiss Confederation (Switzerland) by land area and population. It is the financial center of Switzerland and houses the stock exchange and the headquarters of a large number of national and international companies. National and international media agencies as well as most of the national TV channel companies are also located here. Because Zurich is the central node of the Swiss-wide train network and also runs the biggest and busiest international airport in the country, it generally is the first place where tourists arrive. Because of the city&apos;s close distance to tourist resorts in the Swiss Alps and its mountainous scenery, it is often referred to as the &quot;portal to the Alps&quot;.

 View across Zurich from Grossmünster
Contrary to what some believe, Zurich is not the capital of Switzerland-- that honor falls to Berne. Zurich has long been known for being clean and efficient. Due to this, it has been continuously ranked as the city with the highest living standard world-wide for many years. However, only for the last ten years has it truly become a fascinating and worthwhile travel destination. This is mostly thanks to the liberalization of the cultural, party and gastronomy sectors. An increasingly cosmopolitan population has helped, as well, though more button-down Geneva remains Switzerland&apos;s most culturally heterogeneous city.

The official language is German, used in all official publications Limmatquai street and river Limmatand announcements, and practically everyone can speak it, but the native language of the masses is Swiss German. The most common dialect is called Züritüütsch. English and French are also widely spoken and often used in official publications and announcements alongside German. Any of these languages will do easily. Note that it&apos;s often wise to speak German rather than attempting to speak Swiss German; some people may think you&apos;re trying to make fun of their language.
[edit] Get in
[edit] By plane
Zurich Airport [2] (IATA: ZRH) (German: Flughafen Zürich-Kloten) is Switzerland&apos;s largest and busiest airport run with Swiss efficiency. It is actually in the community of Kloten and it is a 12 minutes by train from central Zurich. The trains depart about every 10-15 minutes but early morning and late evening connections are a bit less frequent, so if you travel at these times check the schedule [3]. A single ticket to the Hauptbahnhof (Central Station) costs CHF 6.20. Several bus lines connect to the airport and provide access to the Winterthur region.
Most major airlines fly to Zurich but SWISS [4] is still the Swiss flagcarrier and covers the biggest part of the international traffic at the airport. Almost every large hotel in Zurich provides shuttle buses from the airport to your hotel. The stops for these buses are a short walk to the right from Terminal 1 arrivals.
Zurich Airport has high passenger costs due to several noise reduction and approach restrictions. Most no-frill airlines fly to Basel which is 1.5 hrs away by train. EasyJet resumed its flights to Zurich in 2007 after a three year absence and Air Berlin offers several flights to Germany and Southern Europe.

[edit] By train
Regular trains to and from other Swiss and European cities leave from and arrive at Hauptbahnhof, the main train station, conveniently located in the city center at the end of Bahnhofstrasse, with easy access to mass transit. The Zurich Hauptbahnhof (HB) is served by the local S-Bahn commuter trains, InterCity (IC and ICN) connections throughout Switzerland, Italy&apos;s Cisalpino [5], Germany&apos;s ICE, France&apos;s TGV [6], and various other direct night train services to/from as far as Amsterdam, Berlin, Rome, Lecce, Barcelona, Budapest and Beograd.
For train times and tickets, visit the SBB [7] or Deutsche Bahn [8] websites, although you may not be able to book many international journeys online through these websites. If you are already in Europe, your local train station office should usually be able to book these trains. A rail pass may make your trip cheaper. For more long-distance international journeys, visit Seat61 [9] for more information.
The train station and the connecting underground mall has shops, restaurants, and a grocery store which locals use when they need to do Sunday shopping, as it is not subject to the closing hours laws otherwise in force in the city. It also hosts a Christmas market around Christmas.

[edit] By car
Almost every highway in Switzerland leads straight into Zurich. This might be quite easy for tourists, but is also really painful if you have to cross Zurich on a daily basis.

[edit] By bus
The main bus station is next to the main train station, where the river Sihl flows into the river Limmat.
Many buses arrive there from other European cities, mainly southern destinations like the Western Balkans or Spain. There is a bi-weekly bus to Banja Luka, Bosnia and Herzegovina [10] 
(look for &quot;Cirih&quot;).

[edit] By boat
As Zurich is located at the end of lake Zurich, it can be reached by boat from other lake villages, e.g. Rapperswil at the upper end of the lake.

[edit] Get around
[edit] Public transportation
Zürich is famous for its highly efficient, clean and safe public transport system, owned and managed by the Zürcher Verkehrsverbund (ZVV) which covers the entire canton of Zürich as well as Rapperswil-Jona in the canton of St. Gallen and Pfäffikon SZ in the canton of Schwyz. The network includes trams, buses, S-Bahn (suburban trains), cable cars and boats. The size and complexity of the network may be daunting at first, but you will soon realize that there are dozens of ways to get from one place to another and following any of them will still be efficient.
The system is divided into numerous fare zones, with the city centre and innermost suburbs being in zone 10 and the outer suburbs located in other zones (Winterthur is in zone 20, for example), and the more zones you pass through, the more you&apos;ll have to pay for your journey. There are single tickets, day cards, monthly cards and annual cards. The monthly and annual cards are collectively referred to as ZVV NetzPass.
Tickets must be purchased from a ticket vending machine before boarding or from one of the ticket selling kiosks. The ticket vending machines are in German, English, French and Italian and offer almost all regular tickets available (not personal tickets though). You select the zones you wish to pass through upon buying the ticket, with a zone map on every machine as well as clear instructions coming to your aid, so feel free to choose! Once you&apos;ve got your ticket it gives you access to all modes of transport. 
If you&apos;re staying for a longer period, consider a monthly ZVV NetzPass, because even though there are no regular tickets valid for something between 1 day and a month, it takes only 10 zone 10 day cards for a zone 10 monthly card to be cheaper. When travelling in all zones, it takes only 8 day cards for the monthly card to be cheaper.
If you don&apos;t mind starting your travels after 9:00, the &quot;ZVV-9-UhrPass&quot; is the best option. It is available as both daily, monthly and annual cards and will save you a lot of money compared to regular similarities, especially given that the 9:00 rule does not apply on weekends.
There are also so-called Z-passes, which can be used not only in Zürich, but also in one of the neighbouring cantons (Aargau, Schaffhausen, Schwyz, Zug, St. Gallen or Thurgau); however, only one additional canton is possible, so if you&apos;re not going to one neighbouring canton more often than the others you are probably better off with just a normal all zones Zürich monthly card and buying single ticket from the last valid station to your final destination. The Z-pass system also has its zones, even in the neighbouring cantons. It is only available as monthly and annual cards and can not be bought from ticket vending machines.
For all details regarding fares, see [11] (in German) or [12] (in English)
The Swiss Pass is valid on all public transportation in Zurich, and if you are a tourist visiting most of Switzerland, this may be your best way to saving both money and time spent trying to figure out zones, routes, and fare options. Eurail passes are valid only on the S-Bahn and boats. Interrail passes are valid on the S-Bahn (although the ZVV website claims a &quot;reduction&quot; for other routes for Interrail holders). Nevertheless, you may find you don&apos;t need the trams and buses if you don&apos;t mind walking around a little.

[edit] By tram and bus
 Trams in Zurich
Several tram lines and buses (some electrified) cover the city at street level. Like all other public transport in Zurich, you purchase and validate tickets before boarding, or risk a fine if they decide to spot check. The most surprising thing about trams and buses in Switzerland is that they are extremely punctual and you can find a schedule at every stop accurate to within a couple of minutes.

[edit] By rail
The &apos;S-Bahn&apos; is Zürich&apos;s convenient and fast suburban rail system which covers nearly all suburbs of Zürich and beyond. Zürich&apos;s S-Bahn system provides convenient and fast service throughout the region. All lines except the rural ones pass through the Hauptbahnhof. The ZVV offers directions[13] for a series of excursions on the S-Bahn.
You must have a validated ticket before you board. If you do not have a ticket you will be liable for an on-the-spot fine of 80CHF.

[edit] By boat
There are two types of boat-based public transportation operated in Zürich: river buses and lake steamers. The river boats operate in the summer months only and the lake boats operate on a much reduced schedule during the winter.
The river buses operate between the Landesmuseum (near the Hauptbahnhof) along the Limmat River and out in the Zürichsee (Zürich Lake) to Tiefenbrunnen. There are several stops along the Limmat River. 
The Zürichsee Schifffahrtsgesellschaft (ZSG) [14] operates lake steamers which leave from Burkliplatz (at the end of Bahnhofstrasse). The ZSG&apos;s website provides information on destinations and ships. The ZSG offers a variety of tourist-oriented trips (including Jazz Brunch, and historic restored steam ships), and a popular trip is to Rapperswil at the south end of the Zürichsee. The town has a beautiful castle overlooking the lake surrounded by a medieval town.

[edit] On foot
The main train station, old town and the lake promenade and all nearby tourist attractions are easily walkable. You may find that you don&apos;t need transportation for most of your tourist needs once you get into the city.

[edit] By bike
You can &quot;rent&quot; bikes, skateboards etc. for free from 7AM-9:20PM daily May-Oct at several places in Zurich and year-round at the central train station. All you need is your passport and a CHF 20 deposit as guarantee. This offer is called &quot;Züri rollt (German only)&quot;[15]. You can get and return the bikes at several locations: the bikegate just next to the central station, next to the &quot;Globus City&quot; shopping center, next to the opera, or at the Swissotel in Oerlikon. If you can&apos;t find these places, don&apos;t hesitate to ask some locals, they should know at least the bikegate at the central station. The Zurich Transit Company, VBZ also provides information about these bikes in English [16]. Nevertheless, you shouldn&apos;t count on it because sometimes the &quot;rent&quot; spots run out of bikes.

[edit] By car
Driving in Zurich is possible but it is painful as the city center is not easy to navigate by car.

[edit][add listing] See
 Central Zurich and the St. Peter Church
 Grossmünster in Zurich
 Fraumunster windows by Chagal
Most of the interesting sights are in the old town around the river and lakefront.

 Grossmünster, Zwingliplatz, [17]. Old Romanesque church, symbol of reformed Zurich, where reformer Huldrych Zwingli was appointed the people&apos;s priest in 1519. Tower 4CHF. edit

 Fraumünster, Kämbelgasse 2, [18]. Old Gothic church (former convent) with window paintings made by Marc Chagall. edit

 Landesmuseum, Museumstrasse 2, ☎ +41 44 218 65 11, [19]. Tu-Su 10AM-5PM and most public holidays including M. The biggest Swiss history museum. You can also learn about the various traditions of the cantons comprising Switzerland. It&apos;s currently undergoing major refurbishment works until 2009 though many exhibitions are still open. edit

 Kunsthaus, ☎ +41 44 253 84 84, [20]. One of the major Swiss art museums. Its specialities are modern sculpturer Giacometti and the surrealist 18th Century painter Fuseli, both Swiss. Entry is free to the main collection Wednesdays. edit

 Schanzengraben. A small canal that used to be part of the city fortifications between Limmat and Sihl. From the main station, go to Gessnerallee, find the stairways down to the tiny creek, and walk all the way to the lake. edit

 Rietberg Museum, Gablerstrasse 15, ☎ +41 (0)44 206 31 31, [21]. One of Europe&apos;s best collections of Asian art (mainly Indian drawings). edit

 Langstrasse. Red light district of Zürich, with more drug dealers and police than usual, but interesting because even this most notorious spot in Switzerland is so clean and safe. The area is the most overtly multicultural spot of the town. In recent years, ateliers and stylish bars start to coexist side by side to the about 15 strip clubs. edit

 Zoo, Zürichbergstrasse 221, ☎ +41 44 254 25 05, [22]. With the new Masoala Rainforest Hall, the Zoo is really worth a visit! edit

 Lake Promenade. Especially during summer, the lake is a beautiful place to spend the evening or the weekend. Starting from Bellevue, the boardwalk goes for about three kilometers along the lake towards Tiefenbrunnen. About halfway from Bellevue there is a meadow where you will find thousands of people on a sunny day. edit

 Chinese Garden, ☎ +41 44 435 21 11, [23]. This small but beautiful Chinese garden was offered to the city of Zurich by the Chinese city of Kunming as symbol of gratitude after Zurich helped Kunming with technical knowledge. edit

 Le Corbusier House, (near Chinese Garden), [24]. A beautiful, modern villa planned by the famous Swiss architect. The visiting hours are very limited (i.e. one day / week only in the summer) and entry is expensive. Additionally, there is a legal battle between the city (owner) and the long time tenant. edit

 Lindenhof. The hill in the heart of the old town. A beautiful view of the city and one time location of a Roman fort. edit

 Niederdorf. The old town offers beautiful alleys, restaurants and shopping mainly aimed at younger consumers. In the evenings, people visit the Niederdorf&apos;s many bars. edit

 Bahnhofstrasse. One of the busiest and best known shopping streets in the world. Highly refined. Certainly a must-see for every tourist in Zurich! (see below). edit

 Museum Buehrle, Zollikerstrasse 172, ☎ +41 44 422 00 86, [25]. A rich private art collection worth visiting - although a little less rich after a recent brazen robbery in broad daylight. Call ahead, as it&apos;s currently not open during regular hours. edit

 Jacob Coffee Museum, Seefeldquai 17, ☎ +41 44 388 61 51, [26]. An original museum which describes the evolution of coffee and different aspects of the culture that has developed around it. edit

 Zurich West. This modern quarter used to be an industrial one, but modern urban developments made it into a center of vibrant night life. edit

 Buildings on Lake Zurich
[edit][add listing] Do
 Take the Polybahn, a 19th century funicular, up the steep hill for a fine view. Starts at tram station Central and goes up to the ETH. Zone 10 ZVV ticket is valid. Nice terrace up there. During the week, the student cafeteria below the terrace is also open to the public.
 Go skiing by train—Buy a snow&apos;n&apos;rail ticket (train&amp;skipass) at the Hauptbahnhof during winter months, train out in morning, back in evening. Flumserberg is the closest large ski-resort, popular with people from Zurich, with a good range of runs for beginners and experts. Retreat to the right side of the resort if the rest gets busy.
 Take a trip on the Zürichsee with one of the two old steam ships. There are a few different routes you can choose from, which will vary mainly in the distance. Or rent a small rowboat.
 Go up Uetliberg, a hill overlooking Zurich. You can hike up, or take a train from the main station. Enjoy the 360 degree view from a tall viewing tower (not for vertigo sufferers!). This is also the start of the planetenweg (planetary walk), an 8 mile walk along the ridge with models of the planets along the way. These are scaled down in true proportion to the solar system. To look at Zürich from the other hills, go to the Irchel (Tram station Milchbuck) or Käferberg (Bucheggplatz, walk up the hill and keep left of the forest).
 Go club-hopping—Zürich has proportionately the largest number of clubs per capita in Europe. Pick up a free copy of the 20 Minuten (20 Minutes) paper and start exploring. 
 Go for a bike ride! You can get free bikes, skates or other fun transport at several stops throughout town. Beware though that biking within the city is only for the experienced, as trams and buses frequent the roads and tram tracks are a serious hazard to inexperienced cyclists.
 The Grossmunster sometimes has organ concerts in the evenings. Check the front door for notices.
 Explore the full and vast selection of foods and condiments available at any Swiss supermarket, heavily influenced by cultures of all the countries around Switzerland. Migros is everywhere and cheap for Swiss standards; Coop is slightly more expensive but has a greater selection of high quality foods; Globus at Lowenplatz has a more upscale supermarket in the basement which is worth at least a browsing.
 Take a 45 min train ride to see the largest waterfall in Europe, the Rhine Falls. Take the train from the Zurich Airport or Zurich HB (central station) to either Winterthur then transfer trains to Schloss Laufen (from April-Oct) or Schaffhausen then take the city bus #1 or #6 to Neuhausen Zentrum.

[edit] Events
 Streetparade, [27]—Currently the biggest open air techno rave in Europe. It happens one day each year on the second Saturday of August, during which trucks which function as mobile soundsystems (&quot;Love mobiles&quot;) start driving along the lake side, starting from the east at Utoquai and ending at the west at Hafen Enge. Every year this event attracts nearly a million visitors who dance in the streets to the music which you can hear from anywhere in the city. After the Streetparade the party doesn&apos;t stop, there are open air parties along the route until midnight and club parties at various locations in town until late the next day, to keep the party going. Don&apos;t be surprised if the city&apos;s cleanliness isn&apos;t up to its usual standard the next day. 
 Swiss national day, August 1st—Celebrations are carried out in many cities in the evenings and fireworks are launched at night. Watch them over the lake, or if you&apos;re experienced with safely launching fireworks yourself, you can buy them in the days leading up to the national holiday and have fun. The display over the Rheinfall, one hour away by S-Bahn, is also extremely popular.
 Züri Fäscht, which occurs every 3 years (next in 2013), is a weekend festival celebrating Zurich.
 Sechseläuten, around mid-April, the guilds of Zürich celebrate their traditional spring festival with the burning of the snow man (Böögg). A procession of several hundreds of people with historical guild costumes and horses takes place in the center of the town.

[edit] Shows and Theater
 Rote Fabrik (Red Factory), [28]. An old silk factory converted to a center of youth culture and art in the 80&apos;s. The Red Factory became one of the most exciting parts of cultural life. An artists coop, a couple of kilometers south, form along the west bank of Lake Zurich. They have a variety of events, including music, film, and theater. edit

 Theater am Neumarkt, Neumarkt 5, [29]. Closed Summer. Closer to downtown. edit

 Schauspielhaus, Schauspielhaus Pfauen, Rämistrasse 34, 8001 Zürich (Tram stop Kunsthaus), ☎ +41 44 258 77 77, [30]. Zurich&apos;s Schauspielhaus is one of the most important theatres in the German speaking part of Europe. The Schauspielhaus has several locations, the most important one being the Pfauen. Students can get really cheap last minute tickets (10 minutes before the show) if they show their student ID. The best seats, if available, costs 20 CHF that way. edit

 Opernhaus, Falkenstrasse 1, CH-8008 Zurich (Tram stop Opernhaus, or take the S-train to Stadelhofen), ☎ +41 44 268 64 00, [31]. The Zurich Opera house shows frequently changing productions of world famous operas. As with the Schauspielhaus, students get a big last-minute discount. The best seats costs 45 CHF for students. edit

 Cinema Arthouse Le Paris (Arthouse Le Paris), Gottfriedkellerstrasse 1, CH-8001 Zurich (Tram stop Stadelhofen, or take the S-train to Stadelhofen), ☎ +41 44 250 55 00, [32]. Frequently changing Arthouse Movies, students get a discount. edit

[edit] Learn
 ETH Zürich (Eidgenössische Technische Hochschule) [33] is one of the most renowned technical universities in the world.
 University of Zurich, [34].

[edit] Work
Switzerland has a very strict labor market. You will need a work permission visa and promotion from an employer. 
For citizens of the old EU-15 countries the bilateral agreements makes it easier to gain a temporary work permit typically for 5 years that is renewable if you have worked. Often a 1 year permit is issued to EU applicants, as such candidates can repeatedly renew even these 1 year permits. Legally, EU applicants have the same status as Swiss applicants when applying for jobs (employer does not need to justify hiring them, and must hire them in preference to non-EU/non-Swiss applicants if skills are equivalent).
For all other citizenships you need a company behind you and you must have skills that are rare in the Swiss (or EU!) labor market. 
Working without permission can lead to a night in prison and deportation depending on you and the agreement with your home country.

[edit][add listing] Buy
 Bahnhofsstrasse
For shopping in Zürich there are three different areas in the center:

 Bahnhofstrasse, which runs from the Zürich Train Main station &quot;Hauptbahnhof&quot; right down to the lake. Bahnhofsstrasse is famous for being one of the most exclusive and expensive shopping streets in the world. Here you can get anything from diamond rings to chocolate to fur coats. Globus and Jelmoli are two fiercely competitive department stores, both of whom carry items from many high-end brands.
 Niederdorf, which is the Old Part of Zurich and expands from &quot;Bellevue&quot; by the Lake right to &quot;Central&quot; which is just over the River from the train station. The Niederdorf is more for young people. Aside from a lot of fast food places you will find a lot of trendy clothes stores here.
 Löwenstrasse, which runs west of Bahnhofstrasse from the main train station, has lower range shops and a large branch of Migros, a department store chain.

[edit] Swiss clocks and watches
You may be disappointed to know that most of the cheap watches and clocks in Switzerland are imported from China and Japan for their cheap quartz movements (including most of the wall clocks and alarm clocks sold at department stores, for example). Don&apos;t purchase a &quot;Migros Budget&quot; clock for 8CHF thinking it is a Swiss clock! Nevertheless, real Swiss-made clocks are still well-known for their quality and reliability, and intricate mechanics. The following are true Swiss-made watches:

 Swatch, possibly your best bet for a &quot;cheap&quot; Swiss watch (40-100CHF) and perhaps better suited for the younger generation. Available in their stores on Bahnhofstrasse and various other locations, or in department stores.
 M-Watch, based on both Mondaine and Migros and available in Migros Electronics stores such as the one on the 2nd floor of the Lowenplatz location. Also relatively inexpensive (40-100CHF). Do not confuse this with &quot;M-Budget&quot; which is an imported cheap watch.
 Mondaine is known for their use of the famous SBB railway clock face. You can buy a replica of the SBB clock as a watch or a wall clock in most major railway stations, among other locations. However, you should note that most of them do not replicate the hallmark smooth movement of the second hand for 58.5 seconds followed by the 1.5 second pause that is characteristic of real SBB railway clocks, but they do replicate the clock face. They are quartz, and the price may seem a little inflated to you (130-180CHF). The vast majority of SBB railway clocks are actually produced by Mobatime (Moser-Baer AG), not Mondaine, even though Mondaine&apos;s name appears on some of the larger clocks such as the Treffpunkt in Zurich HB. Mondaine&apos;s wall and desk clocks, however, are only of &quot;Swiss design&quot; and are manufactured in China and Taiwan.
 Mid-range brands (100-500CHF) can be found at clock and watch stores throughout the city. Just walk in and have a look if you&apos;re interested.
 Upper-end watches and clocks, such as Rolex, are also sold, but you should probably do more research into them than you can find here. If you just want to stare at some of the most expensive watches for sale, take a look at the Bucherer store window at Bahnhofstrasse and see what a 25,000CHF watch looks like.

[edit] Swiss chocolate
[edit] Brands
 Frey is the number one in the Swiss Chocolate market and is mainly sold in Migros and Denner supermarkets. It is offering a premium quality for a customer friendly price. Having a market share of more than 45% it is well established in the market.

Chocolat Frey is accessible by taking S-Bahn S3 to Aarau (42 min) and then the Aargau local bus number 1 to the stop &quot;Industrie&quot; (8 min). It offers factory tours for free. It is 100% Swiss and produces as one of the only Swiss manufacturers from bean to bar all by itself. It also is present in more than 50 export markets. In Export it is very often available under Private Label offers such as those from Marks&amp;Spencer, Loblaw, Tesco, Coles, Woolworths and many more.

 Lindt is available at the Coop and other supermarkets besides Migros for 2-2.50CHF, but Lindt chocolates are also sold at the factory store[35], which is accessible by taking the S-Bahn S8 to Kilchberg (12 min) and then bus 163 to the stop &quot;Lindt&amp;Sprüngli&quot; (2-3 min). Hours are limited (M-F 9AM-5PM). The factory store prices are somewhat lower than supermarket prices (on the order of 10-20%), but there are some sale items, including factory rejects (for underweight chocolates, improper packaging, or filling showing through) that are sold for roughly half-price.

The Lindt factory used to offer tours and free samples, but this is no longer the case.
The larger Coop supermarkets carry many brands, including Lindt, Camille Bloch, Goldkenn, and others, including all sorts of alcohol-filled chocolates.

[edit] Confectioneries
 Teuscher [36]—An upscale confiserie that specializes in truffles. There are three stores in Zürich: Bahnhofstrasse 46, Storchengasse 9 and Jelmoli Department Store.

 Sprüngli
 Sprüngli—A Zurich institution that offers a variety of sweet and savory goodies including a wide variety of chocolates, from hand-made truffles to special chocolate bars. There are locations throughout the city, including Bahnhofstrasse and inside Zurich HB. Some specialities include the Luxemburgerli, a sort of soft macaroon resembling a hamburger in looks but is actually completely pastry and cream, and comes in a variety of flavors; the Truffe du Jour, a chocolate truffle that is made daily from raw cream and is meant to be consumed immediately; and the extraordinary Grand Cru Sauvage truffle, made from wild cacao beans from Bolivia. Most items are rather pricey but worth it. The flagship store on the Paradeplatz is a very popular spot for breakfast, lunch and afternoon tea. Try their berry-filled muesli, it&apos;s like no other muesli you&apos;ve ever had. There are two handy stores at the Kloten airport for last-minute gifts to bring home.

 St. Jakobs Confiserie, Badenerstrasse 41, [37]. The background organisation, Behindertenwerk St. Jacob, aims at providing jobs for disabled people.

[edit] Swiss handcrafts
 Schweizer Heimatwerk, Uraniastr 1 (on the Limmat river), [38]. Also branches in the Hauptbahnhof (main station), airport, and Rennweg 14 in the Bellevue area. Quality Swiss handcrafts and other Swiss-made products presented in a gallery-like setting. You won&apos;t find many cuckoo clocks and the like here (cuckoo clocks are not really Swiss, they are from the Black Forest (Schwarzwald) in Germany!), the emphasis is on real traditional crafts and the work of modern craftspeople. You will find things like sleek modern hand-blown glassware and beautiful hand-carved wooden items from the Appenzell region. A worthwhile visit even if you just browse.

[edit] Swiss army knives
 Coop City in Bahnhofstrasse sells the Victorinox line at uninflated prices, although you won&apos;t get additional bells and whistles like customized faceplates or engraving. Many other department stores also carry them.
 Any cutlery shop will probably carry both Victorinox and Wenger lines of products. However, do make sure they are not inflating the price. For example, a SwissChamp (possibly the most popular model) should be retailed around 78CHF.

[edit] Markets
 Flohmarkt Bürkliplatz (Fleamarket), Bürkliplatz (in the Bellevue area near the Stadelhofen station). May-Oct Sa 6AM-3:30PM. Fairly relaxed yet large flea market with many interesting stalls.
 Flohmarkt Kanzlei (Fleamarket), Helvetiaplatz, [39]. Open Sa 8AM-4PM. A big fleamarket that hosts up to 400 stalls on busy days.

[edit] Other
 Pastorini Spielzeug, Weinplatz 3 (near the river). A high-end toy store.
 There is an English language bookstore at the intersection of Bahnhofstrasse and Rennweg.

[edit][add listing] Eat
The quintessential Zürich dish is Zürigschnätzlets, veal in a cream and wine sauce. Various kinds of grilled Wurst (sausages) are also popular. These are most often accompanied by boiled potatoes, Rösti, a Swiss potato pancake (grated potato, formed into a pancake then pan fried until crisp in butter or oil) or Chnöpfli, in German sometimes called Spätzle, (small noodle dumplings).


 Rösti
Veal is still very popular, though the use of turkey and other meats as a substitute is growing. 
While Fondue (melted cheese in a central pot, dip bread into it) and Raclette (cheese melted in small portions, served with potatoes and pickles) are not really local to Zürich (they come from the Western Switzerland) they are commonly available at restaurants aimed at tourists. 
The bread available in Zürich is generally delicious. There are many varieties, and your best bet is to go to a bakery or a supermarket in the morning or just after work hours, when most people are doing their shopping and bread is coming out fresh. 
Try grilled Bratwurst from street stands, served with a large crusty roll of sourdough bread and mustard, or sandwiches made with fresh baked Bretzeln (large, soft pretzels). A typically Swiss bread is the Zopf, a braided soft bread that is commonly served on Sundays (the other name for it is Sonntagszopf). 
For breakfast, try a bowl of Muesli, which was invented as a health food in Switzerland. The Sprüngli confectionery store tea rooms serve a deluxe version of this fiber-filled cereal with whole milk, crushed berries and cream. 
There are a huge variety of cheeses available at the supermarkets, specialty stores and markets, as well as all kinds of hams and dried sausages. Dairy products are generally delicious, especially the butter. Do not miss the supermarkets! You should take a thorough look through Migros or Coop and maybe even assemble your own lunch or dinner some time. Even the cheap, budget prepackaged desserts in the supermarket exceed the quality of what you may be used to. 
For those with a sweet tooth, there&apos;s a huge variety of chocolates to enjoy, from the cheapest chocolate bar to individually hand-made truffles. (See the Shopping section above). The chocolate bar displays at the supermarkets will overwhelm you! Also enjoy pastries and cakes from the various Konditorei scattered around town. In pastry shops, you can also find special pastry from Zurich: The most famous of them probably is Tirggel, a rather hard pastry made of flour and honey. Although traditionally made and eaten during the Winter holidays, many pastry shops (including larger supermarkets) sell them throughout the year. Often, they&apos;ve got sights of Zurich printed on the top, can be stored for months and thus make up a pretty good and cheap souvenir. Another famous type of pastry are Luxemburgerli exclusively sold by the confectionery chain of Sprüngli (part of the famous chocolatier Lindt&amp;Sprüngli). A typical cake is the Mandelfisch, an almond cake shaped like a fish. 
Like most European cities, Zürich abounds with cafés where you can enjoy a leisurely cup of coffee, glass of wine or other beverage, and watch the world go by. 
There are many international dining options available too. The current hot trend seems to be pan-Asian noodle/rice/sushi places. However, due to the far distance to the sea and the lack of original, well-trained Chinese/ Japanese cooks, the quality cannot live up to that of the original countries. Instead, the Italian cuisine holds the highest popularity among the foreign restaurants. They can be found throughout the city and are relatively cheap. Turkish fast food restaurants are also a delicious, cheap option.
Vegetarian food is easy to find throughout the city. Vegans may have a little trouble because cheese is used generously in most food, but should be fine living off supermarkets at the very least. Hiltl, the first vegetarian-only restaurant in Europe, is also worth a visit. You choose from the buffet, where your meal is priced by weight or from a variety of à la carte menus, which are a bit more pricey, but include vegetarian/vegan versions of popular Swiss meals like Züri-Gschnätzlets or Beef Stroganoff amongst Indian food and classic vegetarian plates. Another vegan friendly restaurant is &quot;Bona Dea&quot;, which is located directly at Zurich Mainstation.


[edit] Budget
 Baba&apos;s take-away part of the Restaurant Pumpstation [40] is located direct at the lake promenade (south of Banhof Stadelhofen). During the summer (April-October) serves fresh grilled sausages, ribs, and chicken for about 6 to 10 Francs. 
 Lee&apos;s take-away, Preyergasse 8 (in the Niederdorf). Stand-up place serving excellent large portions of Asian food. Special student dishes under 10CHF. 
 Pizzeria Molino, Limmatquai 16 (near Stauffacher), +41 044 261 01 17. Pizzas and pastas in a relaxed setting. 
 Ah-Hua, Ankerstrasse 110 (next to Helvetiaplatz) offers delicious Thai dishes to budget prices. Great pit-stop in a Langstrasse pub crawl. 
 Gambrinus, Langstrasse 103 (near Helvetiaplatz) is a typical Swiss restaurant with good food and cold beer. It is located in the Red Light District (Langstrasse) of Zurich and is not the ideal place to bring children or acquaintances. Gambrinus looks like a pub more than anything else,but the staff are friendly and speak English. Try the Zürigschnätzlets mit Rösti or the Fondue (one of the best in Town). Prices are from CHF 14 onwards.
 Rheinfelder Bierhalle, Niederdorfstrasse 76 (at the beginning of the Niederdorf, near Central), +41 44 251 57 09. In this huge and boisterous restaurant you get good-value food and rich portions (only try the Jumbo Jumbo Cordon-Bleu when really hungry). Cheap beer. 
 Millennium Restaurant, on Limmatplatz (Limmatstrasse at Langstrasse) (right across the X-tra bar). Offers great pizzas, large hamburgers, spicy kebabs and other Italian and Turkish dishes at reasonable prices. Staff is very friendly and service is great. Perfect for lunch or a late-night snack. 
 Vorderer Sternen Grill, 22 Theaterstrasse. Zurich&apos;s most famous sausage stand next to the UBS bank building at Bellevue. Red or white sausage for 6CHF, piece of bread and (hot!) mustard is included.

 Restaurant in Zurich
[edit] Food courts
 The Migros and Coop supermarkets (several branches all over the city) are good places to assemble an inexpensive and delicious picnic lunch consisting of freshly baked bread, cheese or ham and fresh fruit. Migros Gourmessa is the &apos;gourmet&apos; takeaway counter, available in larger Migros stores including the Migros City branch at Löwenstrasse. The Coop Bahnhofbrücke branch near the main station also has a small fast-food restaurant. Note: the Migros branch in the main station is open on Sundays when most other stores are closed, and also until 9PM on weekdays, whereas the Coop Bahnhofbrücke is open 7 AM to 10 PM every day except Sunday.
 Jelmoli, St. Annahof and Manor department store restaurant for a cheap buffet lunch, good salad and vegetable stands. All located at Bahnhofstrasse and open during the day

[edit] Mid-range
 Rosalys, Freieckgasse 7 (near Bellevue), +41 044 261 44 30. Typical Swiss food including Älplermacrone (pasta with apple purée). Excellent cocktail bar, too.
 Commercio, Mühlebachstrasse 2 (near Stadelhofen station, Mühlebachstrasse) +41 044 250 59 30. Excellent pasta and a busy atmosphere.
 Commi-Halle,Stampfenbachstrasse 8 (near Central), +41 044 250 59 60. Italian food served late.
 Swiss Chuchi, Roseng 10, (in the Niederdorf), +41 044 266 96 66 . A kitchy place serving up classic Swiss fare, mainly for tourists. Serves fondue year-round.
 Zeughauskeller, Bahnhofstrasse 28a (near Paradeplatz), +41 044 211 26 90. Offers hearty sausages, stews, rösti potato etc. in a Brauhaus-like setting. Touristy, but good and large portions. Housed in a historical building, built in 1487. Open 11:30AM-11PM.
 Bierhalle Kropf, In Gassen 16 (just down the street from the Zeughauskeller), +41 044 221 18 05. Offers beer hall fare such as sausages and pork shanks in a somewhat refined setting. The restaurant features a beautiful painted ceiling.
 Globus Bellevue—This relatively new branch of the Globus department store in the Bellevue near the Stadelhofen station is totally dedicated to food. There is a large eatery on the ground floor that serves various fusion-type foods (decent noodle bowl) and a passable sushi bar. The ground floor has a gourmet food market, and upstairs there are kitchen wares. 
 Sprüngli Paradeplatz, at Paradeplatz. The flagship store of the Sprüngli confectionery store chain has a beautiful turn-of-the-century style dining room upstairs that is extremely popular for breakfast, lunch and afternoon tea. Choose from the menu or from the gorgeous display case filled with beautiful cakes, tarts, open-face and regular sandwiches. Try the muesli! Great people watching too, since this is the place for an after-shopping snack for the rich ladies of Zurich.
 King&apos;s Kurry, Freyastr 3, (next to Bahnhof Wiedikon), +41 43 268 48 28. Offers a good value daily Indian lunch buffet. 
 Masala, Stauffacherstrasse 27, (near Stauffacher), +41 44 240 03 61. Tasty Indian cuisine.
 Hiltl, Sihlstrasse 102 (behind Jelmoli department store), +41 044 227 70 00, [41]. The oldest vegetarian restaurant in Europe (from 1890). Reopened in March 2007 after renovation work. 

 Tibits, Seefeldstrasse 2 (behind the Opera house), ☎ 044 260 32 22, [42]. The fast-food outlet of Hiltl, Europe&apos;s oldest vegetarian restaurant. Offers a nice self-service buffet of fresh veggies and fruit and a surprising variety. Try the freshly squeezed juices. Buffet: 3.60 for 100g. edit

 Outback Lodge, Stadelhoferstrasse 18 (at Bahnhof Stadelhofen), +41 44 252 15 75. Unrelated to the U.S. Outback Steakhouse chain. Enjoy Aussie tucker like ostrich, kangaroo, and crocodile, as well as more conventional fare. Popular with locals as well as expats. Has a hopping bar scene (see Drink section). There&apos;s also a branch in Winterthur. 
 Iroquois, Seefeldstrasse 120, +41 44 383 7077. Tex-mex food in the trendiest part of town, with the best margaritas in Zurich. 
 Tiffin&apos;s, Seefeldstrasse 61 (between Kreuzstrasse and Feldeggstrasse), +41 44 382 18 88. Great place for Asian food. Crowded, closed on Sundays. 
 Lily&apos;s, Langstrasse 197, (between the railway and Limmatplatz), +41 44 440 18 85. Great Thai and other Asian food. The curries are particularly good and come in huge portions. Come before 7PM or after 9PM if you don&apos;t want to wait.
 Nooba, Kreuzplatz 5, +41 43 243 60 06. Pan-Asian noodle bar, a short walk up the hill from Stadelhofen station. Stylish setting, attentive and multi-lingual service and a broad selection of freshly prepared noodle, rice and curry dishes.
 Nooch, Heinrichstrasse 267 (opposite the Cinemax movie multiplex), +41 43 366 85 35 [www.nooch.ch]. Yet another Pan-Asian noodle, rice and curry joint. Also has a sushi bar.
 Ristoranto Toscano, Schmidgasse 17, [43]. A very good Italian restaurant in the old part of the city (Niederdorf). You should try the Spaghetti al Bacio! Closed for lunch on Saturday and all day on Sunday.
 Restaurant Eisenhof, Gasometerstrasse 20. Has the warm feel of an old pub. The house specialty is horse steak, served on a hot stone with fries.
 Blinde Kuh, Mühlebachstrasse 148, [44]. Restaurant in complete darkness, served by blind people. An amazing experience.

[edit] Splurge
Mesa Restaurant, Weinbergstr. 75, 8006 Zürich, ☎ +41 (0) 43 321 75 75, [45]. 17 points from Guide Gault Millau and one star from Guide Michelin proves that traditional kitchen with catalan influences as one of the best restaurants in Zurich edit
 Kronenhalle, Rämistrasse 4 (at Bellevue), +41 44 262 99 00. The city&apos;s most famous restaurant where all the glitterati go to see and be seen. Good Swiss food and heavenly chocolate mousse are one reason to go, the opportunity to dine among original artwork by famous Swiss and European artists (who payed in paintings instead of money) the other. Dress nicely, and treat yourself to a drink at the classy bar before or after your meal. Mains 30-65CHF.

 Widder Hotel, Rennweg 7, +41 44 224 2526 High-class food in a cool setting. The hotel has a trendy bar, great piano music, cool red leather decor, and halogen lighting. Mains 20-50CHF.

Zunfthaus Zur Waag, Münsterhof 8, (near Bahnofstrasse), +41 44 216 99 66. Very authentic Swiss high end restaurant. To ensure your meal does not get cold, they split your order into 2 plates and bring you one at a time. Mains 25-50CHF.

 Le Dezaley, Römergasse 7 (Near the Grossmünster Cathedral in a street connecting Limmatquai and the Niederdorf), ☎ +41 44 251 61 29, [46]. Traditional French-Swiss food from the French-speaking Kanton Waadt (Vaud). One of the best fondue restaurants in Zurich. Mains 25-40CHF. edit

 Blaue Ente, Seefeldstrasse 223, (at the far end of tram 2 and 4 near Bahnhof Tiefenbrunnen), +41 44 388 68 40 [47]. Romantic cuisine in a beautiful building.
Coco Grill&amp;Bar, Bleicherweg 1A (next to Paradeplatz), ☎ +41 (0) 44 211 98 98, [48]. Mo-Fri 10 AM-2:30PM&amp;5PM -Midnight, Sa 5:30-Midnight. Grill restaurant that offers set menus for lunch and a menu surprise for dinner (either fish or meat). Also has a good wine selection and very nice in the summer due to a small garden edit

The restaurants at the top of the Uetliberg are great to combine a nice view of town (a hike in the summer) and some great food. It also has a cheaper self-service area.

[edit][add listing] Drink
Zurich has a lot of places to go out. There are a lot of clubs, restaurants, cafés, bars but also many museums and theaters. The most common drinks in Zurich include: Beer, Swiss white wine (e.g. Fendant), Swiss red wine (is delicious), and Spanish red wine (is generally good value here). At apéro time (after work), you will find many people drinking a Cüpli (glass of sparkling wine).

[edit] Bars
[edit] Center
 Bierhalle Wolf, Limmatquai 132 (At the northern end of the old-town, facing the river), ☎ +41 44 251 01 30 (info@bierhalle-wolf.ch), [49]. A lively beer hall often with live music. In addition to the beer selection, they serve great local food. edit
 Federal, Main Station (Tram 3,4,6,7,10,11,13,14, Bus 31, Main Station). A big Brasserie-like bar inside the Main Station with a choice of 100 Swiss-only beers. edit
 Nachtflug, Stüssihofstatt 4 (Niederdorf). Stylish, coffee and some snacks during the day, large choice of drinks at night.

 Outback Lodge Stadelhoferstrasse 18, (at Bahnhof Stadelhofen), +41 44 252 15 75. Australian in theme, drinks and food, but also well visited by the locals.

 Blue Note, Stockerstrasse 45. Jazz club, quite expensive but great atmosphere.

 James Joyce bar, Pelikanstrasse 8. Where the writer himself used to go. Now mostly frequented by bankers.

 Oliver Twist, Rindermarkt 6. An Irish/British style pub with a good atmosphere, and many English-speaking foreigners.

 Öpfelchammere (apple chamber), Rindermarkt 12. Not a real pub or café, they only serve wine or water. But if you succeed in climbing over the roof beams, you get a free glass of wine to drink hanging upside down and you can mark your name into the wood afterwards.

 Widder Bar, Widdergasse 6. By far the best stocked whiskey bar in town, with a separate whiskey menu containing 250 single malts. In the famous hotel of the same name.

 Corazón, Zähringerplatz 11, +41 44 261 09 59. A Spanish themed bar with a good selection of wines and excellent service.

 Bohemia, Kreuzplatz (just up from Stadelhofen), (bohemia@bohemia.ch), [50]. Trendy place popular for its coffee during the day and an even better nightlife. Usually a popular place for college students. edit

 Barfussbar, Stadthausquai (a 3 minutes walk from Bürkliplatz along the Limmat river), [51]. 20h-24h Wed, Thu, Sun, summer only. During the day this is a public bath for women only. But at night (after 8 o&apos;clock) men are also allowed. It is a beautiful place to spend a warm summer night with a great view of Zurich. edit

 Rimini, Schanzengraben (Go down Badweg from Talstrasse), [52]. 7:30PM-12AM, Sa 5PM-12AM, only in summer and only when it&apos;s not raining. Another open air bar. This one is at the men&apos;s public baths. Really cool atmosphere because of the nice colored lights and the straw mats and pillows. edit

 El Lokal, Gessnerallee 11 on the Sihl [53]. Bar, restaurant, and intimate gig venue attracting alternative crowd, &quot;soccer vs elvis vs che guevara&quot; themed.

[edit] Kreis 2 (Wollishofen)
 Shamrock Irish Pub, Studackerstrasse 1 (end station of the 7, Wollishofen), [54]. Open to Midnight everyday. Irish Pub with regular event&amp;good crowd (food served) edit

[edit] Kreis 4 (Langstrasse)
 Casablanca, Langstrasse 62, (near Helvetiaplatz), +41 44 241 60 00. Cool, modern setting.
 New Velvet, Ankerstrasse 116, (near Helvetiaplatz); nice little brazilian bar with cool music and cooler people. Closed on sunday.
 Xenix, Kanzleistrasse 56 by Helvetiaplatz [55]. Small art house cinema with a busy beer garden in summer. There&apos;s a mixture of students, bohemians, and bicycle messengers posing with their fixies.
 Total Bar, Tellstrasse 19, (a block east of the Langstrasse). Tiny bar serving a range of Zurich&apos;s microbrews. There&apos;s always good music.
 Acapulco, Neugasse 56, (near Langstrasse). Bar with comfortable seats and on week-ends quite crowded. Every Sunday is karaoke evening.
 Riffraff, Neugasse 57, (near Langstrasse), +41 44 444 22 00, [56]. Cinema bar attracting a largely alternative crowd.

[edit] Kreis 5 (Zürich West)
 4. Akt, Heinrichstrasse 262, (near Escher-Wyss Platzfor), +41 44 271 03 68. Teens and tweens love this place.
 Hard One, Hardstrasse 260, (near Escher-Wyss Platz), +41 44 444 10 00. A roof lounge on top the Cinemax complex. Older crowd, very expensive, but stylish. 
 Moods, (in the Schiffsbau near Escher-Wyss Platz), +41 44 276 80 00, [57]. Jazz club in the Schiffbau complex, concerts on Saturdays.

[edit] Clubs
Zurich has proportionally more clubs than any other city in Europe. You will find anything from very &quot;fancy&quot; clubs to places you can just chill. If you want, you can go to a club every night. There is always a Club that has a party going and Zurich&apos;s young make sure to splash all their income on going out.
A lot of clubs are located in the so called Zurich West (District 5). The internet site usgang.ch [58] is a good place to look up what&apos;s up.

 Rohstofflager (raw material storage), Toni-Areal, Förrlibuckstr 109, [59]. This club also has concerts. Sadly closed as of September 2010. edit
 X-Tra, Limmatstrasse 118, [60]. Probably the biggest Club near the Limmatplatz. Free admission on Mondays. edit
 Hive Club, Geroldstrasse 5, +41 76 321 32 16, [61]. Many rooms to wander through and listen to DJ&apos;s from Switzerland and abroad.
 K5-Club, Hardturmstrasse 171, +41 44 440 04 90‎.
 Indochine, Kaufleuten [62], St. Germain, and Mascotte are the more fancy clubs in Zurich.
 Zukunft [63], Abart [64], and Helsinki [65] are for a more alternative and artsy crowd.

[edit] Gay and lesbian travellers
 Rathauscafé, Limmatquai 61, +41 44 261 07 70. Coffee and a croissant in the morning, moving over to sparkling wine in the afternoon and early evening. Nice terrace in the summer. Mixed crowd, friendly service.
 Cranberry, Metzgergasse 3, (opposite Rathauscafé), +41 44 261 27 72. Very crowded on Fridays and Saturdays 8PM-midnight, before the boys head to the clubs.
 Barfüsser, Spitalgasse 4. Once Europe&apos;s oldest gay bar, it has now been converted into a fancy and large lounge and sushi place. Has a relaxed atmosphere and mixed crowd.
 T&amp;M Disco club, Marktgasse 14, and Aaaah house club, [66]. Open daily, but only crowded on Friday and Saturday. Share the same house and entry ticket at Marktgasse 14, you can switch atmosphere as much as you like. 23CHF cover charge on busy nights. 
 Sunday Trash, Schiffbaustrasse 3, +41 44 272 44 02. Gay and Lesbian party in Labor Bar, Schiffbaustrasse. Place to be on Sunday night, 9PM-3AM, 10CHF cover charge.

[edit][add listing] Sleep
Zurich is the financial center of Switzerland and most travellers come with an expense account. The hospitality sector focuses therefore mostly on the 4 and 5 star sector. Zurich is known for its superb hotels, but these won&apos;t come cheap. Best is to go on a company rate, because rack rates are sometimes ridiculous.

[edit] Budget
 Couchsurfing [67]. has a lot of members in Zurich. Public transportation is very fast and good, so also consider staying in surrounding areas instead of in the city centre. 

 City Backpacker/Hotel Biber, Niederdorfstrasse 5 (In the old-town, a few minutes walk from the main station), ☎ +41 44 251 90 15 (sleep@city-backpacker.ch, fax: +41 44 251 90 24), [68]. The most convenient hostel for backpackers. There are shared bathroom and cooking areas. Dormitory 34CHF, Private rooms available from 71CHF. edit

 Hotel Krone Limmatquai, Limmatquai 88 (In the heart of the old-town), ☎ +41 44 251 42 22 (krone@reconline.ch), [69]. checkin: 14:00; checkout: 11:00. A simple, small hostel. Some rooms have river view. from 34 p.p.. edit

 Hostel Krone Zurich, Limmatquai 88.1 (in the center of the city), ☎ +41 44 260 11 70 (booking@hostel-zurich.com), [70]. checkin: 14:00. A simple, small hostel in old town of Zurich, 4 minutes from the mainstation. tripple room from 120 in summer till 98 CHF in winter. edit

 Youth hostel, Mutschellenstrasse 114 (2 kilometer, 15 minute tram ride from the center), ☎ +41 43 399 78 00 (zuerich@youthhostel.ch), [71]. A little way out of the center, but the city is easily reached by public transport (take the S-Bahn to Wollishofen and walk over the hill). A clean and sleek facility, if a little quiet. From 42CHF for a dormitory bed with breakfast; 104CHF for a single room with shower. edit

 Martahaus, Zaehringerstrasse 36, +41 44 251 45 50 (Fax +41 44 251 45 40, email: info@martahaus.ch), [72]. A &quot;clean and friendly&quot; place which doubles as a hostel and a one-star hotel. They also have weekly and monthly rates for rooms, as well as a couple of studio apartments. 40-150 CHF (dormitory bed to double room with a shower). (current as of December 2008) - Closed for complete renovation. Reopening in autum 2010 (stand march 2010)

 Otter, Oberdorfstr, 7, +41 44 251 22 07 (Fax: +41 44 251 22 75), [73]. A good hotel for the price. The rooms have been decorated with the kind of care that one normally expects in a much more expensive hotel, each with its own theme. You can choose from the jungle room with its hammock, or the pink Carmen, or go for the top floor apartment. Each floor&apos;s three rooms share a bath, shower and toilet (WC), with the exception of the apartment which has its own shower. 115 CHF for a single room, 150 for a double, and 200 for 2-person apartment (240 for 4-person apartment). 

 Hotel Splendid, Rosengasse 5, [74]. This hotel is relatively cheap. The rooms are clean but spare. Private showers and bathrooms are not available, you share with your floor. What is really great is the location, right close to the Gemüsebrücke and the city center! 62CHF to CHF 85 for a single, from CHF 160 for a 4-person room, plus 2.50 City-Taxe per person. 

 Etap Hotel, Technoparkstrasse 2, +41 43 276 20 00, Fax : (+41) 44 276 20 01; website: [75] . This hotel is in a great place if you want to party. Located in Zurich West, next to some great bars and restaurants. The rooms are clean and comfortable. 90CHF (low season) to 155CHF (high season) for a single room, and from 100 CHF for double/triple occupancy. For Zurich, this is cheap. Located near a tram station, which takes 10 minutes to get to the main train station. 

 Hotel Schäfli, Badergasse 6, +41 44 251 41 44. Fax: +41 44 2513476. The location is the draw in this somewhat run-down hotel. Situated in the old-town near the station and just by the charming Niederdorfstrasse, where there are tons of bars and restaurants. The shower has a timer. Be sure to get all the coins for the shower you need by Saturday, as the reception desk closes on Sundays. 102 CHF for a double room.

 Hotel Neufeld, Friesenbergstr.15, +41 43 960 7373, Fax: +41 43 960 7374; website:[76] . The comfortable, modern 3*** owner-run hotel is located just a few minutes away from the city centre. All 40 new renovated rooms are comfortable and modern furnished. Perfect for businespeople and tourists. The rates start from CHF 110 for a single and CHF 155 for a double room, including tax breakfast and free wifi.

[edit] Mid-range
Hotel Adler, Rosengasse 10, +41 (0)44 266 96 96, Fax +41 (0)44 266 96 69, email: info@hotel-adler.ch. Clean rooms and breakfast is included in the price. They have a terrific restaurant attached and associated with the hotel that has delicious fondue. The hotel is in a great area for foot exploration. With many bars, restaurants, and cafes all within a few minutes. They have a single computer on the 2nd floor with free internet access. 110-230CHF single room; 180-310CHF double)

 Ambassador à l&apos;Opéra, Falkenstrasse 6, CH-8008, ☎ +41 044 258 98 98 (welcome@ambassadorhotel.ch, fax: +41 (0)44 258 98 00), [77]. Four star boutique hotel situated in the town center, opposite the Opera House and only ten minutes away from the main station Hauptbahnhof and 30 minutes from the Zurich airport. Newly renovated and exquisitely decorated. Single room from 220CHF, two-person room from 390CHF in the low season. edit

 Claridge Hotel Zurich, Steinwiesstrasse 8-10, ☎ +41 44 267 8787 (info@claridge.ch, fax: +41 (0)44 251 24 76), [78]. Four star hotel located within 5 minutes walking distance from Bahnhof Stadelhofen. The theater and the museum of art are just around the corner. Single room from 190CHF, double room from 230CHF. edit 

 Helmhaus, Schifflände 30, ☎ +41 44 266 95 95 (hotel@helmhaus.ch, fax: +41 (0)44 266 95 66), [79]. Three tram stops with tram number 4 from the main station. Located directly next to the Limmat in the old town of Zurich. Very traditional four star hotel with first-class service, style and modern comfort. Single room from 230CHF, double room from 300CHF. edit

 Rex, Weinbergstrasse 92, ☎ +41 44 360 25 25 (rex@zuerich-hotels.ch, fax: +41 (0)44 251 24 76), [80]. Three star hotel, 5 minutes by tram number 7 from the Hauptbahnhof. All rooms are non-smoking. Single room from 158CHF, twin room from 194CHF. edit

 Wellenberg, Niederdorfstrasse 10, ☎ +41 043 888 44 44 (reservation@hotel-wellenberg.ch, fax: +41 (0)43 888 44 45). The four star Art Deco Hotel Wellenberg with its idyllic inner court terrace is in the car-free old town of Zurich, 10 walking minutes from the Hauptbahnhof. The rooms are modern and elegant. One-person room from 290CHF, two-person room from 370CHF. edit 

Palais Kraft, Kraftstrasse 33, +41 44 388 84 85, Fax +41 44 388 84 86, email: welcome@palaiskraft.com, [81]. Three luxury rooms in Zurich&apos;s most prestigious residential building. Located 2 kilometers from the center, above the university district at Toblerplatz (Trams 5 and 6, direction Zoo), in the heart of Zurich&apos;s prime residential area. The rooms come with a large well-stocked fridge, kitchenette, 32&quot; or bigger flat screen TV, wireless internet access, and open to the terrace of the Palais Kraft. Beginning at 385 CHF per room/night, including continental breakfast, soft drinks, snacks, internet, local calls, and all taxes. 330CHF double-bed guest room with bath and kitchette.

 Designer Hotel Greulich, Herman-Greulich-Strasse 56, CH-8004 Zurich, ☎ +41 (0)43-243 42 43 (mail@greulich.ch, fax: +41 (0)43-243 42 00), [82]. Located in the heart of Zurich&apos;s vibrant Aussersihl district, the stunning Hotel Greulich is a haven of style and comfort with a renowned gourmet restaurant. Online booking. (47.37854477,8.52059215) edit

[edit] Splurge
Hotel Widder, [83], Rennweg 7, +41 44 224 25 26. Best hotel in town, known for excellent service and unique location in the old town, but just 1-2 min from Bahnhofstrasse. Prices from from 600CHF single room up to 1500CHF for 1 bedroom suite.
Hotel zum Storchen, [84], Am Weinplatz 2, +41 44 227 27 27. On the river Limmat with an exclusive restaurant.
 Baur au lac, [85], Talstrasse 1, +41 44 220 50 20. Perfect location at the lake, excellent restaurant, popular with actors, celebrities, and politicians.
 Savoy Baur en Ville, Paradeplatz, (fax: +41 (0)44 215 25 00), [86]. Rooms are clean and modern but small. edit
 Park Hyatt Zurich, Beethovenstrasse 21 (east on zurich after 200 miles on gimmelwald), ☎ +41 43 883 1234 (zurich.park@hyattintl.com), [87]. expensive but has a very nice room and spa there is a casino too 2000. edit
 Dolder Grand [88], Kurhausstrasse 65, +41 44 456 60 00 Recently renovated flagship hotel of Zurich with amazing view and excellent spa.
ALDEN Hotel Splügenschloss, [89], Splügenstr. 2, +41 44 289 9999. A small and intimate five-star boutique hotel in Zürich, located on a quiet side street, near the lake shore and Bahnhofstrasse. The hotel comprises of two restored landmark buildings and has a modern interior.

[edit] Camping
Zurich has numerous camping sites, in true Swiss style they are usually very clean, all the sites are the the southern end of the city, normally in river valleys (for obvious reasons). Most campsites close for the winter.

Camp site Waldhof [90]. Quiet and idyllic campsite. 
Camp site Zürich-Seebucht [91]. 
Camp site Züri-Leu.

[edit] Stay safe
Zürich, like most cities in Switzerland, is relatively safe. Nevertheless, be on guard for thieves and pickpockets. Carry your wallet or purse in a secure way, not in your hip pocket or a backpack outer pocket. 
In recent years, certain areas along the lakefront are frequented by young people who sometimes try to pick a fight when they are drunk. Do not let them provoke you, as they are likely to be there in numbers and will use any excuse to go at you.
Public Transportation is very safe. You can use it without any special precautions.
If you decide to bicycle in the city, understand that Zurich is a city of public transportation. Beware of tram tracks which can get your wheel stuck and send you flying into traffic, of the trams themselves which travel these tracks frequently (and may scare you into getting stuck into the track as just noted), and the buses, which make frequent stops in the rightmost lane. In short, bicycling downtown should be only done by those experienced with cycling with such traffic.

 Gay and lesbian travelers — Zurich is the favorite place to live for Switzerland&apos;s (German-speaking) gays and lesbians. The Canton of Zurich was the second canton, after Geneva, to allow registered partnerships for same-sex partners for example. The city of Zurich is probably the place of Switerland that offers the most open environment for gays and lesbians. Gays and lesbians need not take special precaution for their safety on the streets. A random homophobic behaviour is unfortunately always possible to happen though.

[edit] Contact
 The Wings lounge, Limmatquai, [92]. Wireless internet. Free. edit
 Urania Internet Cafe, (Close to Bahnhofstrasse and above a car park.), [93]. PCs, printers, and a selection of snacks. edit

[edit] Cope
Permanence Hauptbahnhof at the main train station provides urgent out-patient care for tourists without prior appointments. [94] There is also a dentist downstairs at the station. For serious emergencies rush to &quot;Kantonsspital&quot;, the university clinic which has a 24/7 emergency ward. Tram stop &quot;Universitätsspital&quot; (look out for the golden boy in front, then follow the red &quot;Notfall&quot; signs). They will not send away people with serious, urgent health problems. Ambulance phone number is 144.
If you&apos;re on a budget, don&apos;t stay out too late — the &quot;N&quot; night buses only run on weekends. When they run, they run only once per hour and you must purchase a Nachtzuschlag for 5 CHF from the machine and validate it before boarding. On work nights, there is no public transportation at all after about 12:30AM (although expensive taxis still exist in case you&apos;re stuck).
Stores are generally closed on Sundays including all supermarkets in the city, except those in the main train station and airport. 
On Sundays, there are supermarkets open at the following train stations: Zurich main station, Enge, and Stadelhofen.
Avoid reaching/visiting Zurich on 1 May. The city is on a Labor Day/May Day holiday. The trams don&apos;t run for half the day so getting around could be a problem. Also, there could be some minor violent outbreaks and damages to cars.
Zurich has two police departments, the Stadtpolizei Zurich which is responsible for the city area and the Kantonspolizei Zürich which is responsible for the whole region. With approximately 1800 and 3000 employees, these departments are the biggest in Switzerland. While police officers in Zurich will happily help you out if you are in trouble or need an information, they are also known for approaching &quot;suspicious&quot; persons in order to check their papers. This procedure is annoying, but legal as you will probably have a hard time proving you were not acting suspicious. Carry a photocopy of your passport and your onward ticket with you, stay calm and polite and you probably won&apos;t have much trouble.

[edit] Get out
Short excursions from Zurich:

 Rapperswil — Pretty town on the other end of the Zurichsee, accessible by S-Bahn S5 (36 min), S7 (39 min) or S15 (36 min), or boat (tip), famous for its rose gardens, beautiful old-town with castle and many lake-side restaurants and cafés.
 Winterthur — Since in winter there is little to do outdoors, people flock to this city, the city of museums. It can be reached by taking S-Bahn S7 (33 min), S8 (28 min), S12 (20 min, fastest route) or S16 (30 min), to Winterthur Hbf.
 The Rheinfall, a large-volume waterfall. Take the S-Bahn S7, S8, S12 or S16 to Winterthur or S16 to Andelfingen and change there for S33 to the station called Schloss Laufen am Rheinfall. This station, however, is only open during summer. If you&apos;re going to the Rheinfall during winter (which you probably won&apos;t), you should get off at Dachsen, the station before Schloss Laufen am Rheinfall on the S33, and take the 634 bus to the stop Schloss Laufen, Rheinfall.
 Schaffhausen — Pretty town located very near the Rheinfall, accessible by S-Bahn S16 or S22 or S33, though S22 and S33 are rural local lines, so if you&apos;re coming from Zürich Hbf and, let&apos;s suppose, have an all-zone ZVV travelcard, you should buy a ticket between Andelfingen and Schaffhausen and use the S16. Dachsen (Schloss Laufen am Rheinfall during summer) is actually the last stop in the ZVV area, but Andelfingen is the only stop S16 makes between Winterthur and Neuhausen am Rheinfall outside the ZVV area; therefore you can save even more if you buy the ticket from Dachsen (Schloss Laufen am Rheinfall during summer), and change to S33 at Winterthur or Andelfingen.
 Stein am Rhein — A pretty town, accessible by S-Bahn S29 Winterthur - Stein am Rhein, which is connected to other S-Bahn lines at Winterthur (S7, S8, S12, S16), Oberwinterthur (S8, S12), Wallrüti (S12), Reutlingen (S12) or Seuzach (S12). If you have an all-zone ZVV travelcard, you should buy a single ticket from Stammheim.
 Baden. A cosy town just outside Zurich. Accesible by S-Bahn S6 (37 min) or S12 (30 min). If you have an all-zone ZVV ticket you should by a single ticket from Otelfingen (for S6) or Dietikon (for S12)
 Lucerne (Luzern) — Pretty city, home of the transport museum, and further excursions possible. It can be reached by the IR train routes Zürich Airport - Oerlikon - Zürich Hbf - Thalwil - Zug - Lucerne (45 min) or Zürich Hbf - Thalwil - Baar - Zug - Rotkreuz - Lucerne (50 min).
 Arth-Goldau — Your gateway to the Rigi railway, also less than one hour away.

Other further away easy excursions from Zurich include:

 Sankt-Gallen — Famous for its convent and extremely ornate Stiftsbibliothek. Also the point of access for the Appenzeller Bahn system, which can take you to the pretty town of Appenzell where there is a cheese factory you can visit.
 Solothurn — A very pretty baroque town in the northern metropolitan area of Berne, accessible by frequent ICN trains.
 Einsiedeln.
 Basel — Near the triple point between France, Germany, and Switzerland. Approx. 65 minutes from Zürich Hbf with IR train route (Chur) - Zürich Hbf - Aarau - Basel, or 70 minutes with IR route Zürich Hbf - Brugg - Basel.

Access to most other parts of Switzerland is extremely easy, thanks to the efficient and frequent SBB train system. Other locations easily accessible from Zurich worth a complete visit in their own right include:

 Berne — The capital of Switzerland, nice looking city, 57 minutes away by IC train routes St. Gallen - Winterthur - Zürich Hbf - Berne - Genève Aéroport or Romanshorn - Winterthur - Zürich Hbf - Berne - Brig, or 79 minutes by IR train route Zürich Hbf - Baden - Brugg - Aarau - Olten - Berne.
 Chur and Landquart — Although not so much to see within these cities, they are your starting points for exploration of the nature-rich and mountainous canton of Graubünden and the Rhaetische Bahn system which runs over naturally scenic routes.
 Interlaken — Your gateway to the Berner Oberland, an incredibly scenic part of Switzerland with some of the highest peaks in the Alps. You can continue from there using the (also incredibly touristy) Berner Oberlandbahn to the Lauterbrunnen valley and beyond, or get off somewhere and hike away from the touristyness if you are fit for it.

The fastest route to Interlaken is taking an IC train to Bern and then another IC to Interlaken (this takes 117 min). However, if you have time to spare, try reaching Interlaken by taking an IR train to Luzern first and then taking another IR train from Luzern to Interlaken (Golden Pass or Zentralbahn, takes 171 min). It&apos;s a much more scenic route.

Jungfraujoch, you can definitely take a day trip from Zurich, although there is so much more that the Berner Oberland offers that you&apos;ll be missing if you don&apos;t spend more time there.

From Interlaken, take the Berner Oberland Bahn to Lauterbrunnen, then Wengernalpbahn to Kleine Scheidegg and finally the submountain railway Jungfraubahn (totally taking 137 min).

 Lausanne is 2 1/2 hours away by train and is a gateway to the Lavaux vineyard region.
 Geneva is three hours away.
 The Italian-speaking region of Ticino, including the fortified city of Bellinzona are up to three hours away.
 The canton of Valais includes the famed Matterhorn in Zermatt and other gorgeous scenery, but is a little harder to reach from Zurich as there are no direct trains to these areas. Nevertheless, if you know where you are going, [htpp://www.sbb.ch] can give you the schedules.
 The Schwarzwald (Black Forest) of Germany is also easily accessible from Zurich. ICE trains run every two hours during the day to Stuttgart, stopping at Rottweil where you can find decent connections to most places in the Black Forest. There is also the Bodensee (&quot;Lake Constance&quot;) which you can reach by good connections to Konstanz.

Zurich is also extremely well-connected to the rest of Europe by train, with direct trains to as far as Barcelona, Belgrade, Brussels, Amsterdam, Berlin, Budapest, Zagreb, Bari, and Rome, just to name a few.



This is a guide article. It has a variety of good, quality information including hotels, restaurants, attractions, arrival and departure info. Plunge forward and help us make it a star!


 


Retrieved from &quot;http://wikitravel.org/en/Zurich&quot;
 Category: Guide articles 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Views
 
 
 Article
 
 
 Discussion
 
 
 Edit
 
 
 History
 
 
 
 
 
 Personal tools
 
 
 
 My page
 
 
 My talk Preferences
 
 
 My watchlist
 
 
 My contributions
 
 
 Log in / create account
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Navigation
 
 
 
 Main Page
 
 
 Project Home
 
 
 Travellers&apos; Pub
 
 
 Recent changes
 
 
 Random page
 
 
 Help
 
 
 Uploads&amp;bug reports
 
 
 Wikitravel Extra
 
 
 
 
 
 feeds
 
 
 
 Travel news and trivia
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Search Toolbox
 
 
 What links here
 Related changes
 Don&apos;t upload file
 Special pages
 Printable version Permanent link 
 
 
 
 
 
 In other languages
 
 
 
 de: Zürich
 
 
 es: Zurich
 
 
 fi: Zürich
 
 
 fr: Zurich
 
 
 it: Zurigo
 
 
 ja: チューリッヒ
 
 
 nl: Zürich
 
 
 pl: Zurych
 
 
 pt: Zurique
 
 
 sv: Zürich
 
 
 
 
 
 
 other sites
 
 
 
 Wikitravel Shared
 
 
 Wikipedia
 
 
 Wikevent
 
 
 Open Directory
 
 
 World66
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
This page was last edited at 18:16, on 11 December 2010 by Petr Skřivánek. Based on work by Geert Bernaerts, Claus Hansen, Ryan Holliday and georg.zangger@gmail.com, Wikitravel user(s) Roundtheworld, Anonymous user(s) of Wikitravel and others.Text is available under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0, images are available under various licenses, see each image for details.Privacy policyAbout WikitravelTerms of use
;

 Last updated on 2012-07-12 14:18:38 by Amazes.Us. 889 views. Share | 

 This category Amazes.us: Ads , Articles , Astronomy , Book Reviews , Business , Cars , Cats , Cities , Financial , Government , Greeting Cards , Holidays , Literature , News , Social Networking , Stories , Tales , Websites , Wildlife 
 
 Copyright 2010 Amazes.us. All Rights Reserved. Privacy Policy 
 
 Rainbow Wildlife Rescue - Squirrels - Rescue - How YOU can Help to Save a Life - Rainbow Wildlife Rescue in the News - Wildlife Movies on Youtube - How to raise a Kitten - How to raise a Puppy - Funny Animal E-Cards - LOLcatZ Postcards - Wildlife Education
	</body>
</document>
