<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006537" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Washington/Bens-Chili-Bowl" time="2012-07-12-23:28" support="2" score="0.00201603304096513" bingtitle="Bens Chili Bowl - Fast Food Restaurant Washington, DC" webtitle="Bens Chili Bowl - Fast Food Restaurant  Washington, DC">
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="16"/>
	<description>Bens Chili Bowl is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1213 U St Nw ... Every inviting condiment you order on the pie is as fresh as you can get.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Bens Chili Bowl
 
Average User Rating
 
6
 
Good

 3 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(202) 667-0909

 http://www.benschilibowl.com/ 
 DC &gt; Washington &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Bens Chili Bowl listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Bens Chili Bowl to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Bens Chili Bowl
 Bens Chili Bowl is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1213 U St Nw in Washington, DC . Bens Chili Bowl has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 6 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Delicatessens, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Bens Chili Bowl
 Add a Review 
 
 
All Reviews for Bens Chili Bowl

 
 Tanika 
 


November 04, 2008
 
Food
 
9
 
Decor
 
6
 
Service
 
8
 
I&apos;ve had my share of food and love to try different things but this one here is one of my top ten. I love the half smoke with chili and cheese. It melts in your mouth. Everything I&apos;ve had here is delicious! A true DC landmark!

I Ate:


 
Overall Rating
 
8
 
&quot;Great&quot;
 
 
 


November 18, 2008
 
Food
 
1
 
Decor
 
1
 
Service
 
1
 
Everyone raves about Ben&apos;s Chili Bowl, but I just can&apos;t get excited about it. My boyfriend absolutely loves their half smoke, but I find it extremely unappealing. The restaurant itself is dirty and seems unsanitary to me. I&apos;m ok with the occasional greasy spoon, but this pushes it over the edge. Obviously there are a lot of other people who disagree with me, because the line is always out the door. And at their stand in Nationals Park, you&apos;d miss several innings standing in line.

I Ate:

 half smoke: messy ($4) 
 
Overall Rating
 
1
 
&quot;Terrible&quot;
 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
9
 
Decor
 
9
 
Service
 
9
 
If you are a lover of Pizza, as I am then put Boompa&apos;s at the top of ofyour list. Every inviting condiment you order on the pie is as fresh as you can get. The sauce is perfect and the pie is baked with topping consideration like good pie&apos;s back east. If you go there order the &apos;whole kitchen&apos; and get ready to enjoy!
 
Overall Rating
 
9
 
&quot;Amazing&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Bens Chili Bowl:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   3

 
Comments
 
 
Bens Chili Bowl News
 Chili for the holidays? Why the heck not! Maybe my family will decorate bowls of chili instead of cookies? Just thinking. Chili, the restaurant Lucky 777 Chili just opened in New York City (just in ... Chili, the breakfast staple Ben’s Chili Bowl in Washington, DC, is a chili extravaganza. 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Bens Chili Bowl - Home Long-time U Street eatery serving chili, sandwiches, and burgers. Includes History, menus, photo gallery, and catering information. Ben&apos;s Chili Bowl - U Street Corridor - Washington, DC Categories: Restaurants Hot Dogs Restaurants Burgers Hot Dogs, Burgers. 1213 U St NW (between N 12th St&amp;N 13th St) Washington, DC 20009 Neighborhood: U Street Corridor Ben&apos;s Chili Bowl - Washington, DC Categories: Restaurants Hot Dogs Restaurants Burgers Hot Dogs, Burgers. Nationals Park 1500 S Capitol St SE Washington, DC 20003 Sports Bar in New York, NY | Restaurant Bar&amp;Party Room - Local ... Blondies Sports Bar is a sports bar in New York, NY. We are also a restaurant bar and we have a party room. Call us today for more information. New York City Restaurants, Coupons, New York City Restaurant Reviews New York City Restaurants, MenuPalace.com is New York City&apos;s ultimate Restaurant dining guide. Find restaurants for any occasion quickly. View menus, photos ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 87° 
Fri
 
 75° - 88° 
Sat
 
 79° - 91° 
Sun
 
 79° - 93° 
 
Address
 
Bens Chili Bowl

1213 U St Nw

Washington, DC 
 

 
Telephone
 (202) 667-0909 
Bens Chili Bowl
 
 Rating :  6 out of 10 based on 3 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Bens Chili Bowl Photos
 
 Fast Food Delicatessens American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Star Pizza Restaurant&amp;Carryout 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Mirrors 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Teddys Roti Shop 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hunan Garden 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Great Wall Szechuan House Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food China Sea Carryout 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Golden China 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Georges Carryout 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardees 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lung Wah Carryout Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Creativedimesionsbylarana 
Cuisine: Art Craft Supplies Art of Venturing Hotline 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Adamson Editions 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Association of Art Museum 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Echo Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Washington Art Craft Supplies 
See all Washington Art Museums Galleries 
See all Washington Other Lodging 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Bens Chili Bowl Coupons 

 Bens Chili Bowl Washington 

 Bens Chili Bowl Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Washington Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
