<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006238" url="http://www.hcgweightlossdiets.com/hcg-food.html" time="2012-07-12-22:55" support="3" score="0.011376915327691365" bingtitle="HCG Food Allowed To Eat on HCG Diet Protocol" webtitle="HCG Food Allowed To Eat on HCG Diet Protocol">
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Note: No more than 2 cups (16 oz) total per day of dairy (including soy &quot;dairy.&quot;) HCG Diet Food Allowed to Eat: Eggs* * While on HCG phase 2 maintenance diet only!</description>
	<body>
		HCG Food


 Foods Allowed To Eat While On HCG Diet 


 List of HCG Food for Weight Loss Protocol 


The HCG food we are allowed to eat or not to eat while on Dr. Simeons HCG diet for weight loss protocol is everyone concern.

QLG is providing a list of HCG foods allowed and other products that can be used while on the hCG diet.

One of the most important things to do is preparing yourself with this list of foods so you can get everything at hand before deciding to continue on the hCG diet protocol.

You should prepare this list of approved foods. Go to the closest grocery store and get hot ready to buy all of them.

Once you have them, take your time to prepare the food allowed, classify it correctly, bag them properly and store it in your refrigerator.

The most important thing is, you must remove all visible fat on the meats! It means, zero, &quot;nada&quot; in fat. Here is the food list to start with HCG Phase 1 diet for 21 days .



 HCG Food Allowed to Eat: Meats 

 BEEF: 
Lean cuts only, such as eye of round, round tip, bottom round, top round, tenderloin, top loin, sirloin, flank, London broil, lean or extra lean ground beef; jerky only if home made without sugar.

 VEAL: 
Lean cuts only (chop, leg outlet, top round).

 POULTRY: 
Chicken breast, turkey breast, Cornish hen, duck (do not eat the skin of any of these!).

 FISH: 
Fresh or frozen albacore tuna, tilapia, haddock, white fish, halibut, cod, albacore tuna canned in spring water.

 OTHER MEAT: 
Buffalo (bison), elk, goat (fat trimmed).

 Note: Trim all, meats of as much excess fat as possible. 


 HCG Food Allowed to Eat: Cheese 

 CHESSE: Low fat only! and for the HCG phase 2 maintenance diet only!

Any reduced fat varieties (2%, low fat, part skim):
- American, cheddar, feta, mozarella, parmesan, provolone.
- Cottage cheese, ricotta chesse.
- String cheese.
- Cream cheese substitute (non dairy).
- Goat&apos;s milk and sheep&apos;s milk cheese.
- Laughing Cow Light.

 Note: Cheese is counted as a protein, not as dairy. 


 HCG Diet Food Allowed to Eat: Dairy - Milk and Milk Products* 

 * While on HCG phase 2 maintenance diet only! 

 Low Fat: 
- Milk
- Buttermilk
- Kefir
- Powdered skim milk
- Canned evaporated milk
- Goat&apos;s milk
- Half and half (limited)
- Yogurt, plain and no-added-sugar vanilla only!

 SOY DAIRY: On HCG phase 2 maintenance diet only!
Look for soy milk or soy yogurt with no added sugars.
 Note: There is some controversy about eating soy.
 Note: No more than 2 cups (16 oz) total per day of dairy (including soy &quot;dairy.&quot;)


 HCG Diet Food Allowed to Eat: Eggs* 

 * While on HCG phase 2 maintenance diet only! 

Whole eggs (preferably the high omega 3, less saturated fat kind from vegetarian fed hens): chicken eggs, duck eggs.

Eggs substitutes, such as Egg Beaters.


 How To Be More Efficient with HCG Diet Protocol 

When you place your order of whether HCG Phase 1 sublingual diet or HCG phase 2 maintenance diet you get an electronic book with full description on all the HCG foods approved to eat while on Dr. Simeons HCG diet for weight loss protocol.

For your conveniences we recommend you to proceed to order the HCG Complete to make the 21 days or 42 days diet journey more pleasant and problem free on HCG allowed foods!


 HCG Food - Back to Diet Phase 3 Recipes
	</body>
</document>
