<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006858" url="http://www.livingonadime.com/store/living-dime-ebook-extravaganza/" time="2012-07-12-23:50" support="3" score="0.010932877164610322" bingtitle="Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza - Frugal Living - Save Money ..." webtitle="Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza - Frugal Living - Save Money And Get Out Of Debt - Living on a Dime®">
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... includes lots of useful tips to help you reduce your grocery bill ... In the time it takes to wait in line and order at the fast food restaurant (or regular restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Living On A Dime ® 

Save money and get out of debt!
 
 
 Home Store Print Coupons About FAQ Contact Affiliates 
 
 Frugal Living 
 Managing Money 
 Ask Tawra and Jill Budgeting Getting Out Of Debt Kids And Money Saving Money Everyday 
 Kids Holidays 
 4th of July Christmas Easter Halloween Thanksgiving Valentine’s Day 
 Miscellaneous 
 Bath and Beauty DIY Entertainment Gardening Moving 
 
 Groceries 
 Cooking Tips Kids And Food Menu Planning 
 Quick and Easy Menus 
 Quick And Easy Print Coupons 
 Recipes 
 Beverages Breads 
 Quick Breads Yeast Breads 
 Breakfast Desserts 
 Cakes Candies Cookies Pies 
 Dips Drinks Gluten Free Homemade Cleaners Kids Recipes Leftovers Meats And Main Dishes Miscellaneous Recipes Mixes and Gifts In A Jar Pasta And Rice Quick and Easy Recipes Salads and Dressings Sauces Side Dishes Soups Vegetables 
 Housekeeping 
 Cleaning Decorating Laundry Organizing Staying Home 
 Chit Chat CFS/FM 
 
Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza
 
 

Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza!

 We are pleased to present the Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza, which includes 12 of Living On A Dime’s Money-Saving e-Books in one package! 

 

 The Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza includes the following thirteen e-books to save you money and make your life easier! This set includes e-books that show you how to save money in the kitchen, put together delicious and easy dinners, get and keep your home organized, save money on kids activities, move on a budget, save money on creative gifts and much more!

 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 

 Here is a list of the e-books that are included along with a brief description of each one: 

 

 
 Money Management e-book 

 Money Management is a 72 page e-book designed to help you say goodbye to debt! Packed with lots of stories and advice, this e-book is an essential tool for your Debt Elimination Kit.

 Money Management includes the story of how Michael and Tawra paid off $20,000 debt on $22,000 per year income.
 
 Do you find the idea of budgeting daunting? You’ll find information about how to make a budget and how to make budgeting simpler and easier . Learn how to reduce your financial stress. You don’t have to be a slave to debt! 
 
 
 
“We’ve learned so much from Tawra…As of last week, our regular bills are finally all paid up! We’re no longer behind on any of them and can start working on our debt instead of playing catch-up with the utility companies. This was due in very large part to Tawra and her mom’s wonderful advice, ideas and guidance.”

-Karen from Ontario, Canada
 
“I was the most wasteful profligate spendaholic, I earned a lot, and thought I was entitled to spend every penny on myself. Now I have a savings, a growing IRA and have come to my senses.”

-Kathy from California
 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 

 
 Grocery Savings e-book 

 Save over $10,000 in a year–Stop throwing your money down the garbage disposal! Grocery Savings includes lots of useful tips to help you reduce your grocery bill. Many people see dramatic savings after using the tips from this e-book.

In the Grocery Savings e-book, Tawra and Jill explain why using coupons is not the best way to save money, how to shop without making so many impulse buys, how to organize your pantry, make a shopping list, and reduce food waste at home.

 
 
“Your tip for separating chips, crackers and snacks into small snack bags is such a great and simple idea.
This has helped us save money on throwing away stale crackers and chips.”

-Pam from Tennessee
 

 

 
 Cleaning Cents e-book 

The Cleaning Cents e-book will inspire you to get your house in order and stop throwing your money away in the chaos and clutter.
 
 Clean in organize in five minutes! Save on household cleaners. Save money on clothes. 
 
 
 
“I am an at-home medical transcriptionist. After reading your article about not wearing pajamas all day, getting fully dressed for the day as if you were going to a job, even when your job entailed staying home, I told my co-workers about it on our monthly conference call, since it helped me greatly improve my line count (and my mind set).”

-Francine
 
“I am not one who has a lot of debt, however I never seemed to have any money. Some of the stuff you talk about just seems so simple, yet it just never dawned on me to look at it that way. I especially like your tips for in the kitchen. I have to admit that I am prone to looking at my dirty dishes in the sink and messy counters and just wanting to order a pizza for dinner. Lately, I have really put forth the effort in keeping it clean and now I actually want to cook.”

-Dimity from Washington
 

 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 

 
 Kids Cents e-book 

 Are you a financially overrun parent? Learn new insights on raising kids while keeping spending low.
 
 Learn easy breakfast and snack ideas. Save on school supplies and lunches. Throw inexpensive but memorable birthday parties. Get the kids to help with chores! 
 
 
 
“Thank you for your article about back to school&amp;buying school clothes. I had already purchased perfectly good clothes for my daughter this summer at garage sales, but like many others, was planning on buying“school clothes”. Why? I don’t know, because it’s just been one of those things people do without even considering why. When I read that article, it was like a lightning bolt –of course, if the clothes she’s been wearing are in good condition, why go&amp;buy more just because school is starting? You saved us a good deal of money, I’m sure. Thanks again!”

- Chantelle
 

 

 
 Debt Free Holidays e-book 

 Debt Free Holidays is a 52 page e-book to show you how to have fun during the holidays without spending a lot of money. The articles focus on Valentine’s Day, Easter, Halloween and Christmas.

Topics in Debt Free Holidays include:
 
 Christmas On a budget gift ideas to keep you from becoming a basket case the $6 gourmet Valentine dinner for two Easter Basket ideas and using Easter leftovers great costumes for less the $25 Halloween Party 
 

 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 

 
 Gifts In A Jar e-book 

 “Gifts In A Jar” shows you how to make all sorts of cool, yummy gifts that will save you money while endearing you to your friends for life! Gifts In A Jar features ideas to make delightful Gift Baskets like those in the expensive stores—everything from the Honeymoon Basket to the Get Well Basket.

 
 
“I learned to make my own gift baskets which is so much more economical than buying already made ones. It has saved me hundreds of dollars a year on gift giving.”

-Marilyn from Florida
 

 

 
 Menus From Dining On A Dime e-book 

 Too Tired To Cook? Eating out is one of the top causes of debt, but what do you do when you’re too tired to figure out what to make for dinner?

 Menus From Dining On A Dime includes over 70 menus to make your meal planning easier! 

 
 
 “I purchased 10 copies of“Dining On A Dime”and the Menus From Dining On A Dime to go with them. They are making great gifts. Everyone who I’ve given one to has been amazed at how great it is.”

The planner is wonderful and makes it so easy to work up menus from the cookbook for a week, a month or more in no time!!”

“Thanks for having such great tools for all types of cooks.”

-Judy from Louisiana
 

 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 

 
 Plan Ahead Leftovers e-book 

Don’t wait until your refrigerator is full of odds and ends to think about leftovers—Plan Ahead!!

 Plan Ahead Leftovers includes 15 pre-planned menus and 38 recipes to make your life easier! Cook once and eat three to five different meals!

 Plan Ahead Leftovers includes beef, chicken and ham recipes for the main dishes and includes 10 dessert recipes. Plan Ahead Leftovers also includes tips to making your own menu plans.
 

 

 
 Quick And Easy Menus On A Dime e-book 

Quick And Easy Menus On A Dime is designed to take the guess work out of menu planning so that you always have a meal plan in a moment’s notice. This menu guide is packed with quick and easy menus that can be prepared in 30 minutes or less! 

Using these easy dinner plans, you can be in and out of the kitchen faster and at a much lower cost than eating out! In the time it takes to wait in line and order at the fast food restaurant (or regular restaurant) you can have a delicious, healthy home cooked meal that will satisfy your hungry family and save you a bundle.

 Quick And Easy Menus On A Dime contains 65 meal plans and 149 recipes with menus for beef, pork, chicken, fish, meatless and holiday meals.
 

 

 Quantity:  
 

 Buy The Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books now! 

 
 Pretty for Pennies e-book 

 What do foot massage oil, chocolate lip balm and almond lotion have in common? Find these and other homemade recipes in Pretty for Pennies!

 Pretty for Pennies is a Bath and Beauty Guide that includes make-it-yourself directions for elegant, all-natural bath and beauty products.
 

 

 
 Moving On A Dime e-book 

 Moving On A Dime is Jill and Tawra’s moving guide that includes do-it-yourself directions for moving without the need for hair transplant products when you’re done.

This 26 page eBook contains everything you need to know from de-cluttering to packing to surviving the big moving day.
 

 

 
 Valentine’s Day On A Dime 

 Celebrate Valentine’s Day in a more meaningful way! The average American man spends $157 on his sweetheart at Valentine’s Day and the typical woman spends $85, but spending more doesn’t make it more special.

 Valentine’s Day On A Dime includes lots of tips and suggestions to spice up your Valentine’s Day and to spark your creativity so that you can develop your own special ways to say,“I love you!”
 

 

 

 This special“Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza”offer includes 12 of our popular Living On A Dime e-books (normally valued at $87) for only $49! 

 

 Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza! 
Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza!

 A set of 12 popular money-saving Living On A Dime e-books to help you save money! Read about it here .
 Price: $39.00 Quantity:  
 

 

 These e-books are pdf files, available for immediate download after purchase . What is an e-book? Click here to find out.

When your order completes, you will receive an e-mail confirmation with download instructions for your e-books. If you experience any difficulties with your order, please contact us here .
 
 

 Your Order is Secure With Paypal. A Paypal account is NOT required to order. 
 
 100% Satisfaction Guarantee!!!!! 

 If you are not satisfied for any reason, we will give you your money back up to 60 days after purchase. 

If you have a question about ordering our products, contact us here .

 
 
4 comments to Living On A Dime E-book Extravaganza

 Less is More this Christmas! Timely Help for the Busy Sandwich Generation | SandwichINK for the Sandwich Generation November 28, 2011 at 6:04 am 
[...] If you are like me and can&apos;t stand that kind of stress, try some of these Christmas ideas from Living on A Dime to help you have a relaxed and Merry [...]
 Quick And Easy Menus On A Dime Free Giveaway!«How to save money and get out of debt–frugal recipes–Living on a Dime® March 12, 2012 at 2:15 pm 
[...] Now through Monday, you can get 50% off of Quick And Easy Menus On a Dime Print Books or e-books and 50% off of the Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books. [...]
 Living On A Dime Extravaganza Free Giveaway!«How to save money and get out of debt–frugal recipes–Living on a Dime® March 14, 2012 at 9:17 am 
[...] Now through Monday, you can get 50% off of Quick And Easy Menus On a Dime Print Books or e-books and 50% off of the Living On A Dime Extravaganza e-books. [...]
 Congratulations Giveaway Winners!«How to save money and get out of debt–frugal recipes–Living on a Dime® March 19, 2012 at 12:47 pm 
[...] to the winners of Living On A Dime Extravaganza and the Save Money When You Are Sick [...]
 
 
Copyright©2012 Kellam Media And Publishing, Inc. - All Rights Reserved - Disclosure Policy - Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
