<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006942" url="http://www.mnn.com/food/healthy-eating/photos/top-10-organic-fast-food-restaurants/chipotle" time="2012-07-12-23:55" support="2" score="0.008215290581568908" bingtitle="Organic fast-food restaurants: Chipotle | MNN - Mother Nature Network" webtitle="Organic fast-food restaurants: Chipotle | MNN - Mother Nature Network">
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>Top 10 organic fast-food restaurants ... Hey idiot you don&apos;t have to eat at chipotle you aren&apos;t being forced at least ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome Blogs Photos Videos Social The Nest 
 
 Join OR Log in 
 Visit MNN    
 
 improve your world 
 
 
 Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 
 
 
 Earth Matters 
 Browse All» Animals Weather Energy Politics Space Translating Uncle Sam Wilderness&amp;Resources 
 Health 
 Browse All» Allergies Fitness&amp;Well-Being Healthy Spaces 
 Lifestyle 
 Browse All» Arts&amp;Culture Travel Natural Beauty&amp;Fashion Recycling Responsible Living 
 GREEN TECH 
 Browse All» Computers Gadgets&amp;Electronics Research&amp;Innovations Transportation 
 Eco-Biz&amp;Money 
 Browse All» Green Workplace Personal Finance Sustainable Business Practices 
 Food&amp;Drink 
 Browse All» Beverages Healthy Eating Recipes 
 Your Home 
 Browse All» At Home Organic Farming&amp;Gardening Remodeling&amp;Design 
 family 
 Browse All» Babies&amp;Pregnancy Family Activities Pets Protection&amp;Safety 
 
 
 MNN.COM › Food › Healthy Eating › Photos › 
 Top 10 organic fast-food restaurants 
 
Top 10 organic fast-food restaurants

 Photo 1 of 10   
 
 Prev Next Photo: Gregglesworth /Flickr 
 
 
 
Join the conversation
 View: Follow this conversation Add your comment 
 All (11) 
 

 Nathan 09/16/2010 09:21 AM 
I stop and grab lunch there when I&apos;m around one. I like that they at least put some effort into where they get their ingredients from. Do I go there trying to loose weight? No. I go there for a good burrito! I can at least know I am getting healthier ingredients than McDonald&apos;s!
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 robert 07/29/2010 21:25 PM 
Check out how much sodium is in their chicken burrito. About a weeks worth of RDA.
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 Bill 05/18/2010 10:25 AM 
Chicken, Onions, Peppers, two scoops of Pico de Gallo and Hot Sauce in a bowl. Lean mean and a ton of veggies with no calorie bomb
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 Allie 04/25/2010 03:28 AM 
Hey idiot you don&apos;t have to eat at chipotle you aren&apos;t being forced at least respect the fact that they are doing a lot better than other fast food places. No one said organic is fat free. Organic just means that the food doesn&apos;t come from drugged up animals. If your so against a cover up fast food then go to another country because that is America for you.
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 mc 04/26/2010 15:16 PM 
&gt;Hey idiot

Greetings to you too.

&gt;you don&apos;t have to eat at chipotle you aren&apos;t being forced

I have nothing against Chipotle. I know many people that love it. It&apos;s a free country. This is a compilation of 10 fast food establishments that are singled out as somehow being better than others by virtue of their organic or otherwise sustainable practices. However, in my mind, hurting someone with chemicals and artificial ingredients is no worse than assisting freedom-lover&apos;s.... More 
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 mc 03/29/2010 18:14 PM 
This is bordering on irresponsible. How about getting organically fat? Chipotle is notorious for their calorie bombs and this is simply providing moral cover for the type of overconsumption that is at the heart of many of this site&apos;s purported ambitions to change.

At least provide a warning. This sort of implicit endorsement is misleading and out of alignment with your stated aims.
.... More 
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 SLO_lane_Cycler 02/02/2011 19:57 PM 
MC - I have to agree with you on this one.
For those of you who don&apos;t agree, maybe look at it this way: truly healthy consumption is an all-or-nothing process, meaning every element from ingredients to portion size must be considered. Ignoring even one aspect can bring the meal as a whole into the category of unhealthy eating.
For example: Switching to cereal for breakfast instead of donuts has the opportunity to be a healthy choice--granted that you don&apos;t eat four entire bowls.... More 
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 Brenda 07/16/2010 12:20 PM 
Wow!
Portion control is not a new concept. Calorie counts are easy to find on the Internet or at a local library or bookstore. This post does not &quot;border on irresponsible.&quot; I believe it is touting organic restaurants, not low fat restaurants. Your comment comes off as quite ignorant.
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 mc 07/18/2010 18:01 PM 
I actually responded to &quot;Allie&quot; with what might be relevant to your comment. Despite my seeming &quot;ignorant&quot; to you, I&apos;m actually pretty vested in the subject matter - I&apos;m a nutritionist. Part of civil dialogue is first demonstrating comprehension of your peer&apos;s position. To that end I don&apos;t think I completely understand your point. Reposting:

This is a compilation of 10 fast food establishments that are singled out as somehow being better than others by virtue of their organic or otherwise.... More 
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 Anonymous Today 16:22 PM 
Did anyone say you had to eat the whole burrito in one sitting?
 
 | Reply report this post   
 

 Patrick 03/19/2010 18:22 PM 
What does, &quot;mostly antibiotic-free and vegetarian-fed&quot; mean?

Does mostly mean 50.1% or 99%?
 
 | Reply report this post   
 
Add your comment
 
Sign in with one of these accounts or just
add your comment below.

 Log in or
 create
 an account   
 
 
 
 Enter your comments 
 E-mail: Used only for emailed comments and will not be displayed with your post Follow this conversation Notify me with an email when other people comment on this article. The posting of advertisement, profanity or personal attacks is prohibited.
Click here to review our Terms of Use 
Chipotle
 Chipotle Mexican Grill was started in Denver in 1993 by Steve Ells and is known for its guacamole and burritos—its large (organic) burritos. The folks at Chipotle believe food should come packed with integrity. That means free range meats that are mostly antibiotic-free and vegetarian-fed. Not all their beans are organic yet, but the percentage is rising quickly. Related Topics 
 Green Dining MNN lists Organic Foods 
 ADVERTISEMENT ADVERTISEMENT From our sponsor 
Ocean Mysteries Resource Report: Re&amp;De from Georgia-Pacific
 Ocean Mysteries, Georgia Aquarium&amp;Georgia-Pacific present the Resource... more&gt; 
Behind the Beak
 Hear what a penguin had to say about starring in a TV commercial created for... more&gt; 
Charlie&apos;s PB&amp;J
 See what happens when Charlie wants a PB&amp;J, when there is no J. more&gt; 
Ocean Mysteries Resource Report:
 Now&amp;Then from Georgia-Pacific more&gt; 
Detective Charlie
 Who has been digging up mom&apos;s flowers? more&gt; Sustainability—A Long Term Approach 
 
 Tweet
	</body>
</document>
