<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006918" url="http://maps.thefullwiki.org/Burger_King_products" time="2012-07-12-23:54" support="7" score="0.013797204103252227" bingtitle="Map of Burger King products - The Full Wiki" webtitle="Map of Burger King products - The Full Wiki">
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000338" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>... expanded menu featuring the introduction of the company&apos;s &quot;Specialty Sandwich&quot; product line. The products were some of the first by a fast food restaurant ... small tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Wikis   Quiz   Map   Search 
 
 The Full Wiki 
 
Search:
 
 


More info on Burger King products
 
   Wikis 
 Encyclopedia Related links Related topics 
   Quiz 
 Quiz 
    Map 
 Maps 
 
 
 
Burger King products: Map
 
       
 Categories: Burger King foods 
 
 
Wikipedia article:
 
Map showing all locations mentioned on Wikipedia article:
 
 

 When the
international fast food
restaurant chain Burger
King (BK) first opened in Miami, Florida in 1954, its menu consisted predominantly of
hamburgers, french fries, soft drinks, milkshakes and
desserts. Beginning with the Whopper sandwich in 1957, BK has expanded the breadth of its menu from
hamburgers to non-beef items such as chicken, fish and vegetarian
offerings including salads and meatless sandwiches. Other additions
include a breakfast menu and such non-soft drink beverages such as Icees , juices and bottled waters. Additionally,
as the company expanded both inside and outside the United States,
it introduced localized versions of
its products that conform to regional tastes and cultural or
religious beliefs. To generate additional sales, BK will
occasionally introduce limited time offers (LTO) of special
versions of its products or bring out completely new products
intended for either long or short term sales. Not all of these
products and services have been successful; in 1993, Burger King
introduced limited table service and
special dinner platters, but this concept failed to generate
interest and was discontinued.

1978 saw the introduction of an expanded menu featuring the
introduction of the company&apos;s &quot;Specialty Sandwich&quot; product line.
The products were some of the first by a fast food restaurant chain
designed to capture the adult-oriented market, members of which
would be willing spend more on a higher quality product. It was at
this time that the company also added a breakfast menu. The new
product launch was part of a plan by the then-company president Donald N. Smith to expand Burger King&apos;s menu to reach
the broadest demographic market possible
in order to better compete with McDonald&apos;s and fend off then newcomer Wendy&apos;s growing market share. The plan was
successful and the company&apos;s sales increased by 15%.

Despite a second major menu expansion in 1985, during much of the
1980s and 1990s the company&apos;s market gains diminished due to
neglect of the brand at the hands of then-parent Pillsbury and its
successors Grand
Metropolitan / Diageo . Upon the sale of the
company to a group led by TPG Capital in
2004, the trend of targeting an expanded audience was renewed under
a plan by its then-CEO Brad Blum . During
Blum&apos;s tenure, the company added several products that featured
higher quality ingredients such as whole chicken breast,
non- process cheeses such as cheddar and pepper jack , and other menu fare that attempted
to appeal to the adult palate and demographic. As in the past, not
all of these products met corporate sales expectations, or in the
case of several of its larger offerings resulted in negative
publicity due to nutritional concerns.


History

Sandwiches and entrées
 When the company began, its menu consisted predominantly of
hamburgers, french fries, soft drinks, and desserts. In 1957, BK
added its signature item, the Whopper . This
hamburger was created by Burger King founders James McLamore and David Edgerton as a way to differentiate BK
from other burger outlets at the time. Now Burger King&apos;s flagship
product, the Whopper has expanded into a line of sandwiches all
made with the same ingredients. Additionally, the Whopper sandwich
has undergone several modifications in its recipe since being added
to the menu, with a change from a plain bun to a sesame seed roll
in the early 1970s and a temporary increase in weight to a third
pound, , in the mid 1980s being two of the most notable. Since its
inception, the Whopper has become synonymous with Burger King and
become the focus of much of its advertising. The company has even
named its new kiosk-style restaurants Whopper Bars .

In 1978, Donald N. Smith was hired from McDonald&apos;s to help
restructure the Burger King&apos;s corporate operations in order to
better compete against his former company as well as then up and
coming chain Wendy&apos;s. On of his first changes was to modify the
menu with the addition of the Burger King specialty sandwich line
in 1979, which significantly expanded the breadth of the BK menu
with many non-hamburger sandwiches including new chicken and fish
offerings. The new line was one of the first attempts by a major
fast food chain to target a specific demographic, in this case
adults aged between 18 and 34 years, members of which were
presumably willing spend more on a higher quality product. The new
products were successful and the company&apos;s sales increased by 15%.
While most of the line has since been discontinued, the company&apos;s Original Chicken Sandwich is still offered in all of its global markets and the ham and
cheese sandwich is a regional offering.

 BK Chicken Tenders officially
made their debut in a menu revision/expansion in 1985 to address
the absence of a chicken based finger product akin to McDonald&apos;s Chicken
McNuggets . Original portion sizes were six-, nine-, twelve and
a twenty-five piece party pack. At the time the product had to be
withdrawn over limited availability of chicken meat from producers,
the product was re-introduced about six months later. Originally
made with sliced fillets of chicken, the
product was reformulated into a formed, chopped-chicken product
several years later. A related product, Fish Tenders, was
introduced to complement Chicken Tenders during another menu
expansion in 1989. The product was an order of fish sticks sold in the same style container as
the Chicken Tenders with a Tartar sauce package for dipping.
Portion sizes corresponded to the Chicken Tenders. It was
discontinued in 1990. Beginning in 2006, BK started changing the
original chicken tenders shape to crowns.

1990 saw the introduction of the company&apos;s first broiled chicken
product, the BK Broiler. The sandwich was the first broiled chicken
the company sold; it included a dill-ranch mayonnaise served on an
oat bran roll. In 1988, BK reformulated the BK Broiler into a
larger, more male-oriented sandwich served on a Whopper bun, increasing its patty size while
changing the sauce to mayonnaise. In 2002, BK changed the name of
the sandwich to Chicken Whopper and added a smaller Chicken Whopper
Jr. sandwich. The company replaced the Chicken Whopper line with
another broiled sandwich line in 2003, the BK Baguette line . The main selling points
behind the Baguette line was that they were served on a fresh
cooked baguette roll, and came in several varieties all of which
were topped with a series of ingredients that were low in fat. They
were sold in the US at one time but are now only sold in the
European market. After the failure of the Baguette line in North
America, the sandwich was again reformulated to its current
iteration, the TenderGrill sandwich.

In order to appeal to as many demographic groups as possible and to
better compete with its fast food competitor Wendy&apos;s , Burger King added a value menu in 1998 with
items priced at 99¢ ( USD ). This menu featured
seven products: Whopper Jr., five-piece Chicken Tenders, a bacon
cheeseburger, medium sized french fries, medium soft drink, medium
onion rings and small milkshake . In 2002
and 2006, BK revamped its value menu by adding and removing several
products such as chili and its Rodeo Cheeseburger . Many of these
items, such as Chili, tacos , the Sourdough
burger (Similar to the Whopper Jr., with sourdough bread ) and Chicken Tender
sandwiches have since been discontinued, modified or relegated to a
regional menu option.

To better appeal to an adult palate, BK introduced several new
products to its menu in 2003, including new or revamped chicken
products, a new salad line and its BK Joe brand of coffee. The
first of these items was the TenderCrisp chicken sandwich, an entirely new sandwich which featured a fried
whole muscle chicken breast on a new corn-dusted roll. This new
sandwich was part of then-CEO Greg Brennamen&apos;s plans to bolster the
company&apos;s &quot;Have it your way&quot; advertising program designed to draw
younger people to its stores. Some items, including the Enormous Omelet Sandwich line and
the BK Stacker line, brought negative
attention due the large portion size, amounts of unhealthy fats and
trans-fats. At the time, many of the products featured higher
quality ingredients like whole chicken breast, Angus beef, Cheddar cheese and Pepperjack cheese. Again, not all these products,
such as the BK Baguette line , met
corporate sales expectations. Others products, such as Burger
King&apos;s line of &quot;indulgent&quot; burgers originally called the Angus Burger , have undergone
multiple reformulations. The Angus Steak burger was originally
based around a frozen patty; despite high expectations from the
company the sandwich fared poorly when introduced. After a
reformulating program, it was relaunched as the Angus Steakhouse
burger introduced in 2008. With the introduction of the new
broilers in 2009, Burger King replaced the Angus Steakhouse burger
with the A1 Steakhouse XT burger. A third
variation of the Angus burger is sold in the European
markets.


Ancillaries
 Burger King zesty onion ring dipping
sauce. BK revamped its french fries in North
America in 1997. The improved fries were treated with a coat of potato-based starch that gave the
fries a crisp coating that would maintain crispiness longer. The
company introduced them in a series of advertisements that claimed
the new fries tested better in consumer taste comparisons against
McDonald&apos;s fries. The fries were in research and development for
over two years and already had been available in several markets.
Additionally, other ads were released featured Mr. Potato Head in a series of demographic
targeted commercials. In Turkey and Europe, they also sell potato wedges , a type of French fry that is
thick cut and wedge shaped. In 1991, the company introduced Twister
fries, spiral cut fries with a spicy coating, as part of a
promotional push. Part of the products appeal was they were served
in a paper drink cup as opposed to the normal fry carton the
company was using at the time. The product was designed as a short
term promotion that would be periodically reintroduced.

In 2002 Burger King offered &quot;Shake &apos;em up Fries&quot;, an order of its
fries that included a spice packet that the customer added to a bag
with the French fries. The customer then was expected to shake them
until the fries were coated with the spices.

Beyond French fries, the company has introduced several other side
products over the course of it existence. Onion rings have been part of its menu for the
majority of its history. Originally made from whole, sliced onions,
they were reformulated into a formed product made from onion paste
in 2001 as part of another menu revamp. In the same 2001 menu
revamp, the company added an onion ring specific dipping sauce,
emphasizing it again during its 99¢ BK Value Menu introduction in
2002. As part of its BK Cravers value menu introduction in 2005,
the company briefly sold jalapeño
poppers accompanied by a side of ranch dressing as part of its national menu.
The same menu also added mozzarella
sticks with a side of marinara
sauce ; the mozzarella sticks have since been relegated as a
regional menu item in the US but are sold on the national menu in
Canada.


Breakfast
One of Smith&apos;s other significant contributions to the menu was the
addition of a breakfast product line, which until this time was not
a market Burger King had served. Besides the addition of the Croissan&apos;Wich in 1983, the breakfast
menu remained almost identical to the McDonald&apos;s offerings until
the 1985 menu revamp. This expansion introduced BK&apos;s A.M. Express
product line which included French
toast sticks and Mini-muffins . The new
breakfast line was designed to be portable because studies had
shown that an increasing percent of consumers were eating breakfast
on the go.

The late 1990s saw the co-branding several of it breakfast products
with former parent Pillsbury; a new fresh baked biscuit bread in
1996 and the addition of mini sized cinnamon rolls called
Cini-Minis in 1998. As part of the &quot;cache&quot; built into the products,
Burger King advertises that products are cooked fresh in the
restaurant each morning.


Regionalization
 

As the company expanded both inside and outside the United States,
it introduced localized versions of
its products that conform to regional tastes and cultural or
religious beliefs. International variations add ingredients such as teriyaki or beetroot and fried egg to the Whopper in Australia,
beer in Germany, Italy and Spain, and halal or kosher products in the middle East and
Israel.

 In
countries with predominantly Islamic populations, such as Saudi
Arabia , pork is not served due to Muslim dietary laws . Additionally, in Muslim countries meat is slaughtered in the halal
method and labeled as such. Similar adaptations also occur in
Israel where kosher dietary laws forbid the mixture of meat and
dairy products; because of this, cheeseburgers are not popular.
Many BK&apos;s in Israel are fully kosher.

In many international markets, BK will offer products or condiments
that fit the local taste. For example in Canada, BK offers poutine gravy and vinegar for its french fries and peri-peri sauce is available as a sandwich
topping in the United Kingdom. Hungry Jack&apos;s offers the &quot;Aussie
burger&quot; with fried egg, beetroot and other Australian flavors. In
Asian markets, dark meat chicken is preferred over the white meat
and poultry products sold in these markets often are advertised as
such. One of the more regionally differentiated lines of products
is the company&apos;s dessert offerings. Domestically BK offers several
desserts including Otis Spunkmeyer chocolate-chip cookies, apple pie slices, Hershey&apos;s Sundae pie slices
(a type of chocolate creme pie )
and a rotating pie type, usually a flavor of cheesecake as part of
its dessert menu. Internationally the company sells turnovers , tortas , Cini-Minis , muffins , brownies , vanilla
soft-serve ice cream in cones and sundaes. In most markets where BK
sells ice cream, it also sells a mix-in dessert under various
names. Additionally, some of these international dessert products
differ from the domestic products in terms of preparation, a
primary example is the pies sold in Asian countries that are fried, turnover -style instead of the
deep-dish tart -type associated with American
sweet-filled pies.


Preparation methods
Burger King cooks its foods in one of four ways: broiling , deep frying , baking or microwaving . As per its mottos and advertisements , BK cooks its burgers and
grilled chicken on an automated grill, while its other chicken
products, fish, sides and breakfast sausage are deep fried in
vegetable oil. BK prepares its eggs, biscuits, Cini-Minis and
cookies by baking in a convection
oven and microwaves its BK Veggie (US) burger patty.


The Broiler
Burger King has used a variety of food broilers over the course of
its history. The original broiling concept was created in 1952 when
Matthew Burns and Kieth Kramer acquired the rights to George Read&apos;s
Inst-Shake and Insta-Broiler machines. The Insta-Broiler cooked the
burgers in a wire basket between two broilers, allowing the burgers
to be cooked from both sides simultaneously. The machine was
capable of cooking over 400 patties per hour, and allowed the
company to grow rapidly. When Burger King franchisees James McLamore and David Edgarton , both of whom would later
purchase the company in 1953, opened their first location in Miami
they revamped the unit into a &quot;flame broiler&quot; – the forerunner of
the modern unit used by Burger King today. The company eventually
contracted with Nieco Automatic
Broilers of Windsor, California for the manufacture of its units, who manufactured
all subsequent units until the start of the 2000s. 

 When the
time came for the company to develop a new broiler, it turned to
its equipment manufacturer Nieco , and St. Louis,
Missouri -based Duke
Manufacturing . Burger King&apos;s goal was to maintain the
company&apos;s trademark flame broiling method while allowing more
product options on a flexible cooking platform. The solutions that
Nieco and Duke devised met that goal by using control features
during cooking. The cooking methods employed by the two
manufacturing company&apos;s vary in their methods; Nieco employed two
chains, one that maintained a single speed and cooking temperature
and another that had a flexible speed setting and variable
temperature control. Duke&apos;s solution utilizes an oven that cooks
according to preset parameters for time and temperature, one
heterogeneous product batch at a time. These two newly designed
broilers have continued an idea of a flexible, multipurpose broiler
the company had been working on as far back as 1999. The first batch-style
broiler was introduced in April 1999 and deployed as part of an
in-store test of the new device in central Wisconsin during the summer of 1999. 

Beyond the flexibility of the new broilers, the new equipment has
several features intended to decrease operational costs. A more
efficient design of the burners in the Nieco units produces a 30%
reduction in energy consumption. The Duke units produce a $4,000
-$5,000 ( USD ) annual savings on energy for the
compared to the original units which ran at as if they were at full
capacity all day. The units are so fuel efficient that in many US states the company and its franchises
qualify for energy-efficiency rebates.


Kitchen equipment
Before any products are sold, the company pre-cooks the ingredients
and holds them in a heated holding cabinet. To insure that product
consistency is maintained and reduced the amount of products
discarded as waste, Burger King utilizes a computerized monitoring
system created by Integrated
Control Corp , or ICC. The system, called Kitchen Minder,
monitors time and temperature in the cabinets and notifies staff
and managers when to prepare more food and discard older products.
Initially developed during a period from 1998 to 2000, the system
is designed to work with its holding cabinet system that was also
developed by Duke. The initial test designs were time consuming to
program because each bay in the holding units had to be programmed
manually, requiring several minutes for each product or several
hours to program up to six units with eight bays each. When BK
finally deployed the system in 2001, the updated units utilized a Palm Pilot to configure the units using a
custom program designed to easily configure the units via IR or serial port . A
kitchen flow software system that helps centralize information
about the system was deployed in 2007, combined with the new
equipment further helped streamline costs for the company and its
franchises. Along with the holding system, Burger King deployed
newer high-speed toasters decrease make times; the new toasters,
while faster, require more maintenance increasing over all labor
costs.


Sandwich preparation
During periods of high volume sales, BK will pre-prepare high
demand items such as hamburgers and cheeseburgers; during &quot;slower&quot;
periods all sandwiches are made to order. The Whopper sandwiches,
Angus burgers, TenderGrill and TenderCrisp chicken sandwiches and
BK Veggies are all made when ordered. Usage of microwaves in
sandwich preparation is limited to maintaining sandwich heat and
not used to cook the product, except for the BK Veggie. BK prepares
its salads in-store daily, as well as cookies and biscuits. Most of
its biscuits are pre-made and frozen while some US stores do
prepare them fresh.


Demographic targeting

Value
BK targets &quot;value-oriented&quot; customers with its BK Value Menu. In
the US, this menu contains products that are usually priced in the
$1.00 to $1.49 range. In non-US markets, the BK Value Menu
typically takes on a different name with prices set to reflect the
approximate value of one US dollar. The naming of the value menu
will vary for each market. Internationally the company is standardizing
its value menu under the King Deals banners that features items for
sale at 1.00€ in the E.U. and 1 dirham in Dubai . Regardless of which market, the value menu usually includes smaller
sandwiches and entrées, small sized side orders, small sized drinks
and desserts. In the US, the value menu now has a breakfast
offering, again in the same format as the lunch/dinner value
menu.


Children
As with all major fast food vendors, BK has a menu that
specifically targets children. The company formerly introduced its
child-oriented product line in North American during the summer of
1990 with an advertising program called the Burger King Kid&apos;s Club.
In the US the meal itself is called the Kids Club
Meal and it is primarily positioned against the popular Happy Meal from McDonald&apos;s. The meal
includes an entrée, a side order, beverage and a toy. The toy is
usually a product tie-in with a movie
or popular television show. The entrée and side offerings differs
from market to market, as will portion size.

In the North American Market, BK further divides its children&apos;s
menu in to three segments: toddler, kids and &quot; tween &quot;. The only difference between the first
two groups is the prize offering; the toddler will receive an age
appropriate toy. The toys were originally designed by Kentwood,
Michigan -based Sassy Inc., and were introduced in 2000 as a
supplement to the company&apos;s existing children&apos;s line. Burger
King changed toddler toy designer to Hudson, Ohio -based Little Tikes in
2003. 

The tween offering was introduced in 1999 and is called the Big Kids Meal . The Big Kids Meals consist of a
double hamburger, a double cheeseburger or a six-piece serving of
Chicken Tenders plus a small order of fries, and a 16-ounce drink
and a toy. Further additions to the line included a six-piece
serving of the company&apos;s Chicken fries product. The introduction of
the Big Kids Meal was not without controversy. McDonald&apos;s
challenged Burger King&apos;s use of the name in a federal suit that
claimed McDonald&apos;s had used the name first. According to the
filing, McDonald&apos;s stated the company had used the term in a
limited manner in Michigan in 1998 as part of a promotion in
Detroit. The suit was judged to be without merit and dismissed in a summary judgment .


Adult
 To appeal to the adult market, BK offers several sandwiches and
other products made with higher quality ingredients such as whole
breast chicken fillets , Angus beef , and other &quot;premium&quot; ingredients.
These sandwiches are usually served on a better quality roll, such
as baguettes or corn dusted potato rolls. Through 2009 and 2010 the
company intends to add other higher end product such as barbecued
ribs, grilled fish, an improved grilled chicken sandwich, kebabs
and an extra thick burger. It is believed that these new offerings
will disrupt the differentiations between the fast food and casual
dining markets with a combination of taste, competitive pricing,
speed of service and convenience. Further, the adult oriented
products of Burger King and it competitors have been criticized by
restaurant industry commentators as a temporary blip. The
&quot;indulgent&quot; products are seen as blurring the lines between the
fast food and casual dining market segments and, while they draw in
newer customers looking for value, the effect may only be
temporary. Once the economic instabilities of the late-2000s recession fade, customers
may return to such casual chains as Chili&apos;s and leaving the fast food chains back where they started in terms
of customer numbers and profits.

Within the adult market, BK targets specific sub-groups within the
adult market with products like the BK
Stacker and BK XXL lines at late teen to
young adult males or health conscious individuals with products
such as salads, grilled chicken and veggie burgers. Products such
as the BK Veggie , a meatless burger
initially introduced in 2002, target the female and more health
oriented demographic using a co-branded marketing program utilizing
a patty produced by the Kellogg
Company&apos;s Morningstar Farms division. Another sub-market in this group is on-the-go parents and
commuters; The company&apos;s BK Chicken
Fries , French-fry cut pieces of breaded chicken, is
specifically targeted to this segment. First introduced in 2005,
the product was successful enough that Burger King eventually
expanded the marketing of chicken fries to the children&apos;s
demographic with a kid&apos;s meal version of the product in 2007. The
meal was launched with a cross promotion with Nickelodeon&apos;s SpongeBob Squarepants using a series
of commercials that raised the ire of the American Family Association due
to perceived nudity concerns.


The &quot;Superfan&quot;
One particular market target of importance to the company is
identified as the Superfan . The super-fan is a demographic
group that includes individuals that are 18 to 49 years old, visit
a fast food restaurant five times a month and eat fast food 16
times a month. Burger King, and other vendors, hope to attract this
group because of the large sums of money that they represent, thus
increase sales and drive an increase in global sales. While
superfans account for less than 20% of Burger King&apos;s customer base,
they account for nearly 50% of the company&apos;s business. By focusing
on this demographic group, the company can increase sales because
of the ease in generating repeat visits by the demographic versus
coaxing new customers from other chains such as Panera Bread . The company has used advertising
featuring its mascot the Burger King in tandem with new product
rollouts such as its BK Wrapper product to help generate the
increased number of visits by the client segment.


Nutrition
One of the companys first forays into healthier products, salads,
was in 1983 with introduction of its salad
bar . The salad bar was met with light to moderate success at
the time, but the company&apos;s franchises complained of high operating
costs and poor return on investment. Part of the product, a pita
salad, was quickly dropped from the salad bar, as were plans to use
the bar unit to boost breakfast sales. In 1987 the company
augmented its salad bar with a test line of prepackaged salads
including chef and garden salads. The salad bar was eventually
eliminated in favor of packaged salads with the 1990 introduction
of another new salad line that was accompanied by a licensing
agreement with Paul Newman &apos;s Newman&apos;s Own, Inc. for its salad dressings to
accompany the products. Burger King again revamped its salad line
in 2004 with the introduction of its Fire Grilled Salad products.
Burger King sought to differentiate this line of salads by
packaging the warm meat toppings, a choice of grilled shrimp or
broiled chicken, separately from the cold salad which added the
appearance of an additional layer of freshness in the presentation
of the product. Currently in the United States the salads are
pre-made off site and sold with just two toppings and Ken&apos;s Foods Ken&apos;s Steakhouse brand salad
dressing. Internationally the salads vary in composition and style
from market to market. In all markets, salads are one of their
female and health conscious targeted menu items. In parts of
Europe, these are sold under the &quot;King Delight&quot; or &quot;LA Range&quot;
banner.

 The new Burger King healthier Kids&apos;
Club meal including Kraft macaroni and cheese, apples and chocolate
milk. response to recent trends in obesity in the US and other nations,
Burger King has begun to modify its menu and practices in regards
to its food preparation and product offerings. In addition to
offering lower fat menu item such as salads, the company has
recently modified its nutrition guides to include dietary
guidelines and other nutritional data. Unlike McDonald&apos;s in the US,
BK does not print nutritional data on its product packaging. One of
its reactions to the concerns over trans-fats was to initiate a program in January
2008 to phase out the added trans-fat in its products as well as
switch its cooking oils and shortenings which are used in the
manufacturing and cooking of their foods to pure vegetable oils
that are free of hydrogenated fats .
The program ended in early 2009 with the complete change over to
the new oils. Most, but not all, of the products contain no added
trans-fats; products such as the beef used in the hamburgers still
contain naturally occurring trans-fats.

To address concerns over the increase in childhood obesity in
Western nations and accusations of unhealthy offerings for children
by groups such as the Center for Science in
the Public Interest , the company created a nutritional program
called BK Positive Steps that is aimed at children and
their families. The program began with the introduction products
such as broiled Chicken Tenders, Kraft Macaroni and Cheese, and
apple &quot;fries&quot; which are french cut apples
served in a fry box that will be featured in a new low fat Kid&apos;s
Club Meal. According to a statement by Burger King the new Kid&apos;s
Club meals will contain no more than 560 calories per meal, less
than 30% of calories from fat, less than 10% of calories from
saturated fat, no added trans fats and no more than 10% of calories
from added sugars. Additional changes to its menu were announced in
May 2009, including reduced sodium levels in its Chicken Tenders
product by approximately 33%, switching its milk products in the
U.S. to non-fat and adding calcium fortified apple juice to its
beverage line up. The broiled Chicken Tenders product is only sold
in the UK/Ireland market; additionally the product line has been
expanded to include a boiled mini chicken sandwich for the
company&apos;s kids meals in this region.

The company has adapted it menu to accommodate different dietary
lifestyles. For those who do not eat meat, the company has added
several vegetarian options, including salads, the BK Veggie Burger sandwich, and its deep-fried Spicy
Bean Burger that is sold in Burger King&apos;s international
locations. The majority of these products do not qualify as vegan due to the presence of egg or dairy
products; an example of this is the BK Veggie Burger which is
approved by the British Vegetarian
Society ; Society guidelines do not require their approved
products to be vegan, and allows ovo-lacto-vegetarian ingredients.
The Veggie Burger is also widely sold in other countries, sometimes
under different names (e.g. as &quot;Country Burger&quot; in Germany). On the
other end of the spectrum, Burger King has added low-carb variants of several of its products that
are in accordance with high protein diets, such as the Atkins Nutritional Approach (Atkins Diet) or the South Beach
Diet . Low-carbohydrate preparation consists of eliminating
bread and certain condiments, such as ketchup, during preparation
and serving the product as a salad.

BK food is prepared with several known food allergens, including
wheat, milk, soy and eggs.


Products
The range of products sold usually depends on the time of day.
Lunch items such as hamburgers and fries are traditionally not
served during breakfast time, however some BK stores do sell food
under their &quot;Burgers for Breakfast&quot; program. Breakfast operational
hours vary but are usually from store open (and anywhere from 2:00
to 4:00 am in 24-hour stores) to 10:30 am on weekdays or
11:00 am on weekends. In some 24-hour restaurants, such as
airports and service plazas , many
items are already available for immediate take away. Breakfast
items are not served at any time except breakfast, but there are
some exceptions; the Cheesy Tots are
always available upon request at most US BK restaurants. Food
prices vary by region and country.


Packaging
Burger King&apos;s product packaging has undergone many changes over the
years. Unlike McDonald&apos;s, the company never used the clamshell style box made of Styrofoam , so when the environmental concerns over
Styrofoam came to a head in the late 1980s, the company was allowed
to tout its use of paperboard boxes for
its sandwiches. To cut back on the amount of paper that the company
used, the paperboard box was fully eliminated in 1991 and was
replaced with waxed paper. Smaller sandwiches, e.g. hamburgers,
were originally served in small paper bags through 1979 when BK
began wrapping its smaller sandwiches in waxed paper. Paperboard
boxes are still used for its &quot;finger food&quot; products like Chicken
Tenders and Fries, French toast sticks
and desserts.

For a short time after BK began moving to a fresh made model where
certain sandwiches are made only after being ordered instead of
being pre-made ahead of time, BK used an aluminum foil wrapping for its Whopper
sandwich that is similar to Wendy&apos;s North American sandwich
packaging.

Starting in 2005 with the BK Chicken Fries product, BK began
adapting some of its product packaging so that it could be placed
in an automotive cup holder . The BK
Chicken Fry box, while square in shape, will sit comfortably in the
cup holder and its top, when opened, forms a small tray that is
designed to hold dipping sauce. Burger King accredits the design of
this box with helping to make its Chicken Fries the most popular
adult-oriented chicken product in the US. It has since added a
trademarked and patented round french fry container which it calls
the FryPod , a play on the Apple iPod name, which is a paper cup made from 50% recycled
materials that is also designed to fit in an automotive cup
holder. The package design won honorable mention in an
packaging industry design competition. Additionally, BK&apos;s large and
King sized beverage containers are made from molded HDPE plastic with a funnel-like shaped bottom that
allows the over sized cups to fit in the smaller sized cup
holders.


Reformulations
Over time, the company will reformulate various products in an
attempt to boost sales of the product or to improve the taste,
appearance an/or physical consistency of the product. One such
example of this is the BK Big Fish , the
company&apos;s fish sandwich offering in North America. Burger King&apos;s
original fish sandwich, introduced in the 1970s, was called the
Whaler; it was a smaller fish sandwich made with tartar sauce and
lettuce served on the small sesame seed roll BK used for their hamburgers. When Burger King introduced its
broiled chicken sandwich in 1990, the BK
Broiler , it changed the fish sandwich&apos;s breading to a panko style, began serving it on an oatmeal dusted roll that
was used for the broiled chicken sandwich and renamed the product
from the Whaler to the Ocean Catch sandwich. When BK reformulated
the BK Broiler, the company also reformulated the Ocean Catch as
the BK Big Fish in its current configuration. The sandwich was
again briefly reformulated after the phase out of the Baguette
sandwiches and was reintroduced as the Big Fish in 2005.


Limited time offerings
To generate additional sales, BK will occasionally introduce
limited time offers (LTO) that are versions of its core products or
new products intended for either long or short term sales. Many of
these LTO products focus on its core menu products such as the
Whopper which has featured variations such as the the Texas Double
Whopper with added jalapeños , bacon
and pepperjack cheese; all new sandwiches like the Chick&apos;n Crisp sandwich (now a permanent item
in many regions) or test products such as the company&apos;s Great
American Burger, which was another attempt at a premium sandwich in
2003. It was made with a Whopper patty and several new ingredients,
including a bakery-style bun; peppered bacon; whole-leaf, as
opposed to shredded, lettuce; seasoned mustard; and special sauce.
The burger also had American cheese, mayonnaise, tomato and onions.
A similar burger was tested in Wisconsin in 1999. That Great
American burger featured a single burger patty and different
toppings. It was designed to be cooked on a forerunner of the
current batch broiler.

Other LTO product sought to expand existing product lines with new
base ingredients. The company&apos;s 1993 offering, a Meatloaf Specialty Sandwich , was introduced
as part of a push into limited table
service . Other LTO variants in its Specialty Sandwich line
included an Italian sausage sandwich served in one of three ways:
with onions and peppers, parmigiana style
with mozzarella cheese and marinara sauce or all four
ingredients; one of two steak sandwiches made from steak fillets or
later, restructured beef; A ham and cheese sandwich with
mayonnaise, lettuce and tomato; and a veal parmigiana sandwich.


Trends
The company is not above following trends within the fast food and
fast casual industry. The 1984 introduction of its salad bars was
one example of this. BK sells various forms of wraps in several of its markets. The company
introduced its first wrap product called a BK Wrapper in North
America as a breakfast option in April 2008, with a lunch/dinner
version later that year in September. These products were in
response to industry trends for products that are easier to consume
on the go. The lunch/dinner version of this product sold through
late-2009 when they were eliminated due to weakening sales.


Licensed products
In 2007, Burger King began licensing its logo and items to outside
companies for non-Burger King products. The licensed products
company Broad Street Licensing Group and its manufacturing partner
the Inventure Group introduced the first two products, flavored
potato crisps, in the fall of that year with two flavors, flame
broiled burger and french fries with ketchup. Inventure added a
third flavor, onion rings, in 2008. A second licensed product, the
company&apos;s child-oriented BK Fresh Apple Fries, was licensed for
sale in supermarkets in 2009 to the Cruch Pak company. The company
has stated while the products are important in providing brand
identity, they will not be concentrating their resources on them
and will be investing the licensing fees into the company&apos;s
marketing fund. Industry pundits have criticized the company for
this scheme, with Rob Frankel, author of the book The Revenge
of Brand X , stating &quot; that just because you can do
something does not mean you should... &quot;

The licensing deals have proven so successful, Broad Street has
expanded the product line to seventeen countries across the globe
while increasing it to more than a half dozen varieties all
designed to mimic the flavors of some of Burger Kings core menu
products. The success of the product line and licensing deals
garnered the companies an award as &quot;Brand Extension of the Year&quot; by License! Global magazine, and earned a nomination
for &quot;Best Corporate License of the Year&quot; by the Licensing Industry
Merchandisers Association (LIMA).

 ConAgra Foods has also entered into a
licensing agreement with Burger King in 2009 for a new line of
microwavable french fry products. The new products, King Krinkz,
seasoned crinkle-cut fries; King Kolossalz, an extra-large package
of fries; and King Wedgez, seasoned potato wedges were slated to be
released in September 2009. The packaging is designed to resemble
BK&apos;s FryPod fry container.


Failed products
Throughout its history, Burger King introduced several new products
that performed well in testing, but did not catch on with the
public. The failure of the BK Baguette
line of sandwiches was just one of the company&apos;s products that
did not meet corporate expectations, one of its earlier failures
was the Bull&apos;s-eye Barbecue Burger. The sandwich consisted of two
side-by-side hamburger patties, American cheese and bacon with Bull&apos;s-eye Barbecue brand barbecue sauce served on the same
roll as the Specialty Sandwiches. Later it was sold as a
traditional style double cheeseburger.

In 1993, during its time under the ownership of Britain-based Grand
Metropolitan, Burger King experimented with table service. After 4
p.m., customers would place their order at the counter, and their
order would be brought to them at their table. Customers were given
complimentary popcorn to eat while waiting for their meal. To
coincide with the offering, a series of Meals called the Dinner
baskets were introduced. The dinner baskets included the Whopper
Dinner Basket, Steak Sandwich Dinner Basket, Fried Chicken Dinner
Basket, and Shrimp Dinner Basket. In the New England region of the US, BK sold a Fried clam Basket. The dinner came with
two sides, including a choice of a side salad, cole slaw , french fries, or baked potato. Lasting
approximately a year, the sit-down restaurant concept was abandoned
in 1994 in favor of the original quick-service formula.

Another failed product under Grand Metropolitan successor Diageo
was the the BK Back Porch Grillers line of burgers that featured a
spiced and flavored patty served on a bakery style roll. There were
two varieties: The Regular served with mayonnaise, whole leaf
iceberg lettuce, tomato and grilled onions and the Bacon Cheddar
with bacon and smoked cheddar cheese. There
was one LTO variety, the Black Stack Griller made with Black Strap
Barbecue sauce (a strong molasses flavored
sauce), bacon, lettuce and tomato. The Griller patty was flavored
so that it had a taste similar to a hamburger that had been grilled
over a charcoal fired grill.

One of its international failures was the BK Crown Jewels line of sandwiches
originally sold in New Zealand. These larger, adult oriented
sandwiches were made with fried and grilled chicken or a Whopper
patty and a variety of toppings served on a Kaiser (bulkie) roll.
Toppings included a mango lime sauce, avocado , aioli , a Cajun spiced sauce and relish . Originally
successful, the sandwiches peaked the interest of Burger King&apos;s
corporate offices and were being looked for a potential global
rollout. However, interest in the product eventually faded and the
products were discontinued.

Introduced as direct assault on corporate rival McDonald&apos;s, the Big King was Burger King&apos;s response to the Big Mac and had a similar style and taste.
The sandwich was originally introduced in 1995 under the name
Double Supreme during its testing stage. The name was switched to
Big King when it was introduced nationally in 1997, and again to
the King Supreme when reintroduced in 2002. The sandwich was
eventually discontinued in the North American market but is still
sold in many of the company&apos;s international markets in several
forms.


 In the 1970s, the chain offered a hot ham and cheese sandwich
called the Yumbo. 



Burgers

 BK Burger Shots are Burger Kings
version of mini-burgers are smaller, &quot;bite size&quot; hamburgers similar
to the sliders products sold at White Castle and Krystal . European locations sell them
as the BK Six Pack, while in the UK and Ireland it is a variation
on the Angus burger called the Angus 6 Pack, which contains six
small burgers attached together. In the United States they are
based its Burger Bundles/Burger Buddies product from the
1980s. 



Breakfast

 German Burger Kings launched a breakfast menu around 2005. In
contrast to other key markets, the breakfast menu consists of
bagel-based breakfast sandwiches. The breakfast menu is not
available at every BK in Germany, normally most locations that
offer the breakfast menu are standalone restaurants or locations
located at key rest stops right by many German autobahns. In 2008 BK completely re-vamped the UK&amp;Ireland breakfast
menu, breakfast sandwiches are now called Breakfast Butty
sandwiches and are served on buttered corn-dusted rolls as the
primary bread. All sandwiches are served with ketchup or HP Sauce,
and the include either a round Cumberland Sausage ring, thick bacon
rashers or an egg omelet patty. Both
Argentinian and Chilean BKs serve a simple Toastada breakfast sandwich, ham
and cheese on toasted bread. In Honduras, BK has a breakfast typical to the region. It is
named BKatracho which includes beans, tortillas, sour cream,
scrambled eggs, cheese and ripe banana. In El Salvador, like Honduras, also has a typical food named
BKguanaco. It serves same as BKatracho except it has bread instead
of tortilla and no sour cream. The Breakfast Burrito \ Wrap is an offering made with a floury tortilla , shredded cheese, eggs and hash browns or sausage. BK also offers pancakes , French toast , French toast sticks, huevos rancheros and scrambled eggs in regional and international
menus. Biscuits and gravy is
available in parts of the southern US. 



Other products

 In Argentina and Chile, sells the Churrasquito sandwiches made
with steak fillets, mayonnaise, lettuce and tomatoes on a fresh
baguette roll. They are both one of their larger, adult oriented
sandwiches made with higher quality ingredients than their
&quot;standard&quot; menu items. 



Product suppliers

Purchasing guidelines for meat
Like many of its competitors, BK has been targeted by various
animal welfare groups, such as PETA , over the
treatment of the animals it uses in manufacture of its ingredients.
In a concession to these groups, BK adopted a series of policies
for its suppliers for several of its raw animal products, e.g.,
establishing a preference for eggs and pork-based products from
those suppliers that use cage-free production methods.

 2001 Guidelines 
 Conduct announced and unannounced inspections of its
slaughterhouses, including chicken slaughterhouses, and take action
against facilities that fail inspections Establish animal-handling verification guidelines for all the
slaughterhouses of its suppliers; Confine no more than five hens in each battery cage, require
that the birds be able to stand fully upright, and require the
presence of two water drinkers per cage; Stop purchasing from suppliers who force-molt hens; Develop auditing procedures for the handling of &quot;broiler&quot;
chickens; Institute humane handling procedures for chickens at
slaughterhouses; Begin purchasing pork from farms that do not confine sows to
stalls. 


 As part
of the guidelines agreement, the company filed a 2002 petition with
the Food and Drug
Administration requesting the United
States Department of Agriculture step up enforcement of the Humane Slaughter Act of 1958. The USDA agreed with the request, stating &quot; it is granting your
petition and is developing a proposed rule that addresses the issue
of humane handling. &quot; However the USDA failed to indicate when
it intended to publish the proposal in the Federal Register and
solicit public comment, which would be the first step before the
agency drafts a final rule.

 2008 Updated guidelines 
 Immediately begin purchasing 10% of its pork products from
suppliers that do not use gestation crates, metal enclosures that
confine sows and restrict the animal&apos;s movement, and double that
amount by the end of 2008; Immediately begin purchasing 2% of eggs laid by hens who are
not confined to small wire &quot; battery
cages &quot;, and more than double that amount by the end of
2008; Issue a statement to its egg suppliers stating that it will
give purchasing preference to those that do not use battery
cages; Issue a statement to its chicken product suppliers stating that
it will give purchasing preference to those that use or switch to controlled atmosphere
killing (CAK), which is considered to be a more humane method
of chicken and turkey slaughter. 



Food

 Tyson Foods (Chicken, beef) Heinz Foods (condiments,
potato products) Hershey&apos;s foods (desserts,
beverages) Ken&apos;s Foods (salad dressings) Edwards Baking (desserts) Otis Spunkmeyer (desserts, US&amp;Canada) Cadbury (desserts, UK) Pillsbury (breakfast products) 


 McCain Foods became a supplier of
potato products to the company in 1998, shortly after an agreement
with farmers in Maine to supply potatoes for use in the fast food
market.


Beverages

 Dean Foods (beverages) SABMiller (beer, Germany) 


Traditionally Burger King has sold soft drinks from the Coca-Cola Company in its home market.
During 1983, PepsiCo was able to garner the
$444 million ( ) beverage supplier contract from its rival, and,
despite extreme market debate over the future of the contract, had
it renewed for a second term in 1987. The company was able to win
the contract by strengthening its marketing and advertising program
ties between the Burger King and itself. However, the contract only
lasted three more years when, partially based upon Pepsi&apos;s growth
as a restaurant operator with its Tricon
Restaurants division, Burger King moved its beverage contract
back to Coca-Cola.

Since 1990, Burger King has continued using Coca-Cola as its
beverage supplier, renewing its contract in several times. Despite
extending the contracts several times, the Coca-Cola contract was
not with out its problems; The 1999 contract called for the
addition of Coca-Cola branded Icee products to
be made a permanent menu item in all American locations. After the
rollout, it was discovered that Coca-Cola employees had faked
product test information to bolster prospective sales numbers to
entice franchisees to enroll in a summertime advertising push. When
all was said and done, several Coke employees were terminated and
Coca-Cola changed in-store promotional materials to emphasize the
Icee name. The 2003 contract officially extended the relationship
between the two companies so that Coca-Cola was the exclusive
supplier of soft drinks for the company. Before this, individual
international franchises would field their own contracts with the
company of choice. The 2003 contract gave Coca-Cola new access to
the three thousand operating or planned restaurants on the
Asia-Pacific rim, Europe as well as all of South and Central
America.

In 1999, Burger King added a second soft drink supplier contract
with a deal with the Dr Pepper
Snapple Group to include Dr. Pepper to its beverage line up in North American restaurants.

Burger King&apos;s supply contracts for non-carbonated beverages are
separate from the one for its sodas. Despite utilizing Coca-Cola
for sodas, when the company first chose to introduce a bottled
water product it chose Nestlé&apos;s Poland Spring brand over Coke&apos;s Dasani . When the contract expired in 2003, BK chose
to move to Pepsi&apos;s Aquafina , the top
selling brand at the time. In 2008 Burger King renewed its
relationship with Nestlé by entering into an agreement to sell Pure
Life bottled water products manufactured by the food conglomerate.
However, BK moved away from Pepsi&apos;s Tropicana brand juices in 2001 when it went with
Coca-Cola&apos;s Minute Maid brands for its
North America market.

Produced by Sarah Lee&apos;s Douwe Egberts brand, BK Joe is Burger King&apos;s coffee line that the Burger King
advertises it as being made from Arabica
coffee . The line was first introduced in 2001 in North America
and parts of Europe later. The product made using Douwe&apos;s Cafitesse
system, a platform that eschews coffee brewed from ground beans in
favor of a beverage made from a coffee concentrate with hot water
added. The advantage of this system is that each cup of coffee is
made at the time of order with minimal waste and labor. The product
is not designed to compete with products from companies such as
Starbucks, but instead to appeal to those customers who seek a
consistent cup of coffee. In other parts of Europe, BK sells Nestlé &apos;s Nescafé brand coffee. In other international
markets BK sells coffee drinks such as Flat
white or Latte .


Distributors
For many years Burger King owned and operated its own distribution
system, known originally as Distron. Distron, founded shortly after
establishment of Burger King, primarily served the company owned
stores and approximately 50-60% of franchised stores. Franchise
groups were free to purchase supplies from one of seventeen
independent distribution systems, often operated by larger
franchise groups such as Carrols Restaurant Group . The
Distron setup remained relatively stable until the time of the
company&apos;s purchase from Pillsbury by Grand metropolitan. Grand Met
was not happy with the distribution group, originally thinking to
sell it before the purchase, reorganized the division. Distron was
reorganized into two separate groups for procurement (Burger King
Purchasing, BKPS) and distribution (Burger King Distribution
Services, BKDS) while laying off over a hundred staff members in
the process.

In 1992, Burger King and its franchises formed Restaurant Services
Inc. (RSI), an independent purchasing cooperative , which covered 100% of BK stores in
the United States. The creation of RSI was based on a proposal by
then-CEO Dave Gibbons create an organization that would be
autonomous from BK corporate operations, provide full financial
disclosure to participants on pricing issues and revenues while
enjoying the participation of the entire chain for the maximum
benefits of volume purchasing. The format of RSI was based on the
system employed by KFC for its distribution
system and operated in a similar manner. Two weeks after the
formation of the co-operative, Grand Met sold the physical assets
of BKDS to Canadian-based buyout firm Onex Corporation and folded BKP into
RSI.

Currently the company utilizes independent distributors such as
Maines Paper and Food Service and Sysco for
supplying North American stores with food and paper products.


References

Notes



See also

 Burger King
advertising McDonald&apos;s products In-N-Out Burger
products 


 

 Embed code: 
 



 

 
 
 Got something to say? Make a comment. Your name Your email address Message Please enter the solution to case below
 45-15= 


 
 


 
 
 
The text of the above Wikipedia article is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License . This content and its associated elements are made available under the same license where attribution must include 
 acknowledgement of The Full Wiki as the source on the page same page with a link back to this page with no nofollow tag.
 Blog About The Full Wiki Contact us Privacy Policy 
 Version 0609, c
	</body>
</document>
