<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006113" url="http://www.myrtlebeachscrestaurants.com/Giant-Crab-Restaurant-Row.html" time="2012-07-12-22:47" support="82" score="0.12389382692897462" bingtitle="Giant Crab Restaurant Row Seafood Restaurants" webtitle="Giant Crab Restaurant Row Seafood Restaurants">
			<query id="001211" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001463" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001179" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000708" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001022" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000960" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000991" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000208" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001306" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000177" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000396" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000614" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001431" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000240" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001117" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000426" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000520" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001274" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000551" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001336" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000582" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000333" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000771" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000114" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000457" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>... declined because I had the phone number on my receipt ... then toronto --i would rather go to a fast food restaurant. ... this, and when you order a big beer you can keep ...</description>
	<body>
		Giant Crab - Restaurant Row Restaurants&amp;Seafood Restaurant Reviews 
 
 Myrtle Beach Restaurants 
Home Page 20800 Reviews Restaurants by Area 
 Barefoot Landing Broadway at the Beach Calabash Carolina Forest Cherry Grove Colonial Mall Conway Garden City Georgetown Litchfield Beach Little River Longs Market Common Murrells Inlet Myrtle Beach North Myrtle Beach Ocean Isle Pawleys Island Restaurant Row Shallotte Sunset Beach Surfside Beach 
 Restaurants by Type 
 American Bakery Bar&amp;Grill Breakfast Chinese Delivery/Take Out European Fondue German Ice cream/Desserts International Irish Italian Japanese Jewish Mediterranean Mexican Other Pizza Seafood Steak House Thai Theme 
 Open during Holidays 
 Valentines Day Thanksgiving Day Christmas Eve Christmas Day New Years Eve New Years Day 
 Additional Navigation 
 Site Search Area Map Site Map Text Site Map 
 Gone, gone, gone... 
 Archives 
 Who Gets the Most Reviews? Frequently Asked Questions Coupons&amp;Discounts Restaurant News Help&amp;Feedback Advertising Options Editors Table Add a Restaurant About Us Contact Us 
Giant Crab

Seafood Restaurant in Restaurant Row
 Giant Crab features an extensive buffet that includes broiled, fried and baked seafoods, peel-and-eat shrimp, raw and steamed oysters, mussels and clams, prime rib, baked ham, roasted turkey, beef ribs, chicken, soups, salads, freshly baked bread, kid&apos;s selections like hamburgers, hot dots, corn dogs, chicken fingers and french fries, and a dessert bar that includes cakes, icecream, and fresh fruit in season.

There are currently 186 independent, user-submitted restaurant reviews for Giant Crab. 
 Giant Crab 
9597 North Kings Highway
Restaurant Row
843-449-1097
 Write a Review | Submit a Photo 
Reviews of Giant Crab
 
 
Posted:11-27-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Absolutely HORRIBLE!! Was very expensive and the food was bland and not only that they do not have the price of the buffet posted; even using a coupon it was $60 for 2 adults and a 3 year old...RIDICULOUS price for the quality of food. I wouldn&apos;t even pay $20. The only thing that was decent was the crab legs; and unfortunately I had already had a large plate of other items and didn&apos;t want to waste it or our money so I choked it down....EXTREMELY disappointed! The hibachi food was flavorful either. The bread was pretty good and the waitress was kind but that the only positive thing about this place... I am going to check this site before trying any other seafood restaurants...surely there is one out here that is affordable and tasty... btw Hamburger Joes has the BEST wings I have ever eaten!!
 Nashville, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:10-04-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: As usual the food was GREAT!! Loved everything. We love crablegs so paying $24 for all you can crab legs is a bargain. The Hibachi grill was excellent and the cook was informative. The best place to eat in Myrtle Beach!
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-14-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We arrived at the restaurant at 2pm and waited for the 2:30pm opening. At approximately 2:40pm they opened the doors. As we were seated, the staff was extremely friendly but that is where the pleasantries ended. The food was less than acceptable. Some wasn&apos;t even at a WARM level! Baked spinach had chunks of unmelted cheese in it. Fried food tasted like it had been fried and reheated or fried and refried. And even with a $6 per person discount coupon, it was still almost $100 for the 4 of us and that was with us all drinking just water. My son had eaten here several years ago and had always bragged about it, but not now! Don&apos;t waste your time or your money!
 East Tn, TE 
 
 
Posted:07-25-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have read so many BAD reviews on this restaurant that I really didn&apos;t feel the need to write one. But, I will because I don&apos;t ever remember eating at a place with such horrible food in my life! My husband and I came to MB to enjoy the beach and seafood. This food was worse than any seafood or any other food that I&apos;ve ever eaten. Frozen seafood from the grocery store would have been better! The food was bland, not warm, not cold, the seafood had no taste, etc. Just completely unacceptable!! I tired a few things off the bar and just couldn&apos;t tolarate it. Our bill for two buffets, one ice tea, and one water was $65.00!! We paid the bill and will never go back!! This was the biggest waste of $65.00!! NEVER AGAIN!!! It has taught me to read reviews for all restaurants that I&apos;ve never been too!
 Dawsonville, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:07-25-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: No prices posted anywhere. Went in and ate got the bill and was $94 for two adult and 2 kids buffets. Sticker shock to say the least. Definitely not worth the money. I know it was my fault for not checking the price but wow wasn&apos;t ready for that.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-17-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Over priced buffet. Too much fried and stuffed seafood. Crab legs were too small to bother with and overcooked which made matters worse. People were bumping into each other and they were not at capacity yet. Bathrooms were a joke, dirty, with only two stalls for an establishment that appeared to be capable of seating at least a couple hundred. Will not be returning.
 Burlington, Kentucky 
 
 
Posted:06-30-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We just ate there couple days ago. everythhing smothered in butter. Way too much fat. Too much seasoning. Was not impressed at all. Won&apos;t be back.
 Greenville, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-11-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Decided to eat here Thursday evening (06/09/11) and WOW what a mistake! The service staff was very friendly, but the food was horrible. Some food appeared to have been on the bar for so long it was all crusty and dried out. Alot of the serving utensils were covered in other foods on the handles (gross!) and we had to wait in line for crab legs because they had run out on two occassions. What a disappointment to finally get the crab legs and find they weren&apos;t even as thick as my pinkie finger!! Figured with a name like &quot;Giant Crab&quot; we&apos;d get bigger crab legs than that. Spend five dollars more and eat at Captain George&apos;s!!!! Horrible food.
 Indianapolis, Indiana 
 
 
Posted:06-05-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Really love the food here! If you love seafood, this is the place! They have seafood and fish fixed just about any way you&apos;d want it, a salad bar, dessert bar, comfort foods, prime rib, a hibachi grill and piles of crab legs! I try to eat here everytime I&apos;m in Myrtle Beach. Definitely recommend this restaurant
 Kingston, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:06-05-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Had to give the place a try and will never go back. The food was average and the price wasn&apos;t worth it (family of 3, $100). I&apos;ve had better food at half the cost.
 Fishers, Indiana 
 
 
Posted:05-26-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab in mrytle beach was disgusting ! I love seafood and my family of 8 ( including my parents and grandmother) all went to Giant Crab because I wanted seafood buffet. First we took coupon in and presented it . We were seated and told where everything was. At first I was excitrd to see large variety . Everything was gross! how do u mess up peel and eat shrimp , crab legs or raw oysters?! I kept going back to get more food hopibg to find something deceny enough to eat .. I didnt . Then got check and coupon wasnt taken off ( per person as it says) and my bill for 2 adults and 3 kids was $142! my parents bill for 3 adults was $118! they added 15$ and $20 gratuity to our checks ! and dont waste your time with their &quot;free&quot; photo, lol. Dont eat at Giant Crab! .
 Morganton, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:05-06-2011

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: bad food...i worked there for two weeks..trust me..the handling of the food is really bad..illegal immigrants..re-heated left overs..dropping food on floor..using it anyway..DO NOT EAT THERE.
 Myrtle Beach, SO 
 
 
Posted:09-08-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: One of the better buffets in MB. Even my vegetarian girlfriend was thrilled with Giant Crab. The &apos;hibachi&apos; station lacks the sake that would give the real flavor of hibachi, but you end up with some pretty decent fried rice. The crab legs were great, as were most of the seafood dishes. Desserts were (as usual) weak, but better than most buffetts. I will gladly return to Giant Crab. Even writing this review is making me hungry.
 Brooklyn, New York 
 
 
Posted:08-31-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab was the WORST meal I have ever eaten!! The food was all cold and horrible. My 1 year old (who eats about anything) took one bit and then refused to eat anything else. The crab legs were cold, small, and rubbery. Everything on the buffet looked like you could easily get food poisining from it. Actually my husband barely made it back to the room before getting sick. The staff was RUDE from the time we walked in the door. DO NOT EAT HERE AND WASTE YOUR MONEY!!!!!
 Mars, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:08-25-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We always do the buffet. When we are in town for a weekend visit, we always dine with Giant Crab. The food is delectable.
 Christiansburg, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:08-15-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This was one of the worst meals that I think we have ever eaten in Myrtle Beach. We live just over the border in North Carolina and make day trips to Mrytle Beach often. Some of the food was not even warm and the food was way too spicy or had no taste at all. The prime rib on the carving station was so raw it almost appeared not cooked at all. The strawberry shortcake that I tried for dessert was dried-out cake with strawberry frosting in the middle and a small piece of strawberry on top. The service was very good and the waiter we had was very good. The price (with coupon) was in line with other local restaurants if we would have been able to eat the food. This is one restaurant that we will cross off our list and we didn&apos;t hesitate to tell some other people who asked us in the parking lot what we thought and when we told them they left too.
 Wilmington, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-04-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I was on vacation last week with my girlfriends (7/26-7/31) and we saw the brochure for Giant Crab in our condo. We visited the first time and it was so awesome and delicious we came back two days later. I have never tasted food so good. Everything I selected for my plate was yummy. I only wish there was a Giant Crab near my home town. I would go every weekend!
 Wilmington, Delaware 
 
 
Posted:08-03-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have read some of the reviews above....... I can&apos;t believe the complaints. The Giant Crab is perfect. I&apos;ve eaten there several times&amp;plan on going back in Sept. Was there in April this year. The wait staff was pleasant (always there to help if needed) and the food was delicious. Not cold as some have stated above. The price is in line with the other restaurants there. Hey!!!! You are on vacation. Spend a little money and enjoy it. You only have one life to live................
 Wintergreen, Virgin Islands 
 
 
Posted:07-30-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: WOW! I can&apos;t believe all of these people have had a horribl time. My family and I have been going to this place for a few years now. IT IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING :) I have never had cold food that should have bene warm or warm food that should have been cold. Yes the bathrooms are a little gross but the service is great and food is awesome!!!! price may be high but you only vacation once a year, right? It&apos;s best to only go if you really like crablegs as that is really what you are paying for. GREAT TIME WILL COME BACK AGAIN!
 Lynchburg, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:07-24-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab is an amazing alternative to the over-commercialized Bennetts Calabash... We go there solely for the snow crab legs. You truely get all you can eat. They are delicious and succulent. Every leg you get is full and juicy - no tiny legs with bland morsels of stringy meat that won&apos;t even come out of the shell in one piece. They make you feel like a professional crab cracker! Every one comes out in one huge lump of meat and the servers keep emptying the tray of shells as you keep eating. The selection of additional food is amazing as well. They offer (as advertised) 170 items! That is crazy! I enjoy everything there except the dessert which could use some improvement. I wasn&apos;t impressed with any dessert but the ice cream. They had peach soft serve which was really good but i personally like the crab legs so much that i could eat them as dessert too! Go here above any other buffet style seafood dinner. You won&apos;t regret it. you could easily pay the same price for a pound and a half of crab legs anywhere else!
 Niles, Michigan 
 
 
Posted:07-22-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We are locals and we had family and friends visiting from out of town. Took them to Giant Crab. The food was strewn all over the bar, most of the food appread died out. The apperence of the bar was very poor and dirty. The T-Bones steaks were cut in to 4 pieces. The mac and cheese was very watery. The osyters were very small and over cooked. The food was of low quaility and without seasoning. The floors and rest room were dirty. It was very over priced. I would not recommend this to anyone. It was very embarrrassing for us taking our out of town guest to this place. DON&apos;T GO. AVOID AT ALL COST!!!!!!
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-11-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have been to Myrtle Beach many times. We finally decided to give it a try. The food was fresh and there were many choices for my kids to pick from. When we got our bill, we were shocked that drinks were not included with the meals. Especially for two children that were 8 years old. For the money we were charged with two children of that age you would think that the free photo that was offered would have been the 8X10 and not the one you needed a magnifying glass to see. I just think that people spend their hard-earned money to vacation there that you would not gouge them anymore. Other restraunts in the area were cheaper for the four of us and serve better quality food.
 Baltimore, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:07-11-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have been to Myrtle Beach many times. We finally decided to give it a try. The food was fresh and there were many choices for my kids to pick from. When we got our bill, we were shocked that drinks were not included with the meals. Especially for two children that were 8 years old. For the money we were charged with two children of that age you would think that the free photo that was offered would have been the 8X10 and not the one you needed a magnifying glass to see. I just think that people spend their hard-earned money to vacation there that you would not gouge them anymore. Other restraunts in the area were cheaper for the four of us and serve better quality food.
 Baltimore, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:06-29-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We dined at the Giant Crab while vacationing at Myrtle Beach. The food was really great, but one of us did get sick that night (granted he ate almost 5 plates). The price was ridiculous. We were charged $125 for 4 people on buffet. However, the waitors were friendly and were of good service. When we walked in the door there was a huge line that wrapped around but we were seated in under 10 minutes. From a scale of 1 to 10 I would rate it a 8.5. I was very satisfied. The shrimp and crap legs were fantastic!
 Myrtle Beach, SO 
 
 
Posted:06-26-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: While the food was not spectacular (it was more like eating hot garbage) this establishment gave our family the best memories of our trip to MB. We came here with heavy hearts due to the passing of Michael Jackson and the Giant Crab did indeed lift our spirits, much in the same way it lifted the bile into our throats from the various bad odors in the main dining room. Overall, while we may not be going back..ever...we do talk about this restaurant frequently.
 Williamsburg, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:06-20-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Gave them 2 chances...both times the crab legs were cold and rubbery!!! NEVER AGAIN!!!
 Norwood, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-01-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate here in spring 2010 and it was not worth the money. The food wasn&apos;t good at all and it was pretty pricey.
 Fayetteville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-01-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Giant crab not necessrily mean big crabs. We&apos;ve been eating in so many seafood restaurants and so far this is the least. Snow crabs and shrimps were poor quality..very tiny...paying 22.95 isn&apos;t worth it. I dont like the smell of that room near the tavern either. Sushi looks mushy and not done right. If you are here just for the seafoods, this is not the place for you!!!
 Philly, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:05-30-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We&apos;ve been visiting the Giant Crab for about 3 years now, always excellent food and service, just don&apos;t recommend sitting in the back room, smells musty and moldy. We will continue to visit the Giant Crab. We love the crablegs and hushpuppies.
 Charleston, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:05-26-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab was a delicious experience. The food was very tasty. My favorite was the crab legs, but everything else was very good. The dessert wasn&apos;t my favorite but it was ok. Our server was very nice and imformative.
 Kingsport, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:05-04-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Freezer seafood from the grocery store would have been better than what we had. What should have been hot was cold and what was supposed to be cold was warm. We were all sick that night. It was bad. Very, very bad. And the pilfering in your pockets begin the second you step up to the door. Pass on the souvineer pictures. They are the size of postage stamp. The staff was there. And that s about it. And the bathrooms were nasty. made me wonder about the kitchen. Save your money. Go to a McD&apos;s and have the fish sandwich. Its fine dinning compared to the Giant Crab.
 Dalton, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:04-18-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family&amp;I were in Myrtle Beach for the first time in 25 years. We were so excited about eating at the Giant Crab. Wow....was that for naught. This is the worst place to eat in Myrtle Beach. There was so much artificial crab meat in everything that I couldn,t even eat most of it. Do you know what that stuff is made of? Yuck!!!! The crab cakes were full of filler, the stuffed flounder was like stips of rubber band wrapped around more filler, the oysters and tiny clams were dry as my sense of humor and these rest of the food was over cooked and just plain nasty. Thank goodness we had a coupon or I would have been really mad. In a nutshell,,,,save your time and money....pass on the dreadful Giant Crab. I did,however, like the outside of the building.
 Chattanooga,, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:04-14-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Let&apos;s face it, who cares about the atmosphere? It&apos;s all about the food, right? Well, the food here was awful. It does not matter if you get 150 items or 170 items to choose from when those items are this bad. Worst meal we had on the entire vacation. Price (with $10 off in coupons) was still around $45 for 2 people. 
I wish someone had told us - &quot;Do Not Go Here!&quot;
 North Canton, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:04-09-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family and I have been going to Giant Crab for aboout three years. The food and the service is excellent. I can&apos;t believe some of the poor comments. We come to the beach atleast two to three times a year and we can&apos;t wait for the crablegs. All of the food is good, but the crablegs are our favorite.
 Bennettsville, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:04-08-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We always go to Giant Crab when we visit Myrtle Beach. It was great a few yrs ago but since then, the quality of service has dropped considerably. The waiters and staff are not so friendly.

For the price of a seafood buffet it&apos;s a bit pricey but so is everywhere else. The food is ok but the crab legs are exceptional. Other items on the buffet could use some improvement.
 Durham, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:03-23-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: STAY AWAY! The food is terrible. Tasteless. Expensive. No prive posted! The five star, glowing reviews must be from owners or employees paid to write them. I don&apos;t see how this place stays in business.
 Mills River, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:03-12-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I will start with the food, the food was somewhat cold but they had sushi! The sushi was ok but the sushi had like no meat or vegitables. The crab legs were good, avarage, but we got what they called &quot;butter&quot; but it was obivisly oil! We didn&apos;t belive it so we called over the waiter to ask for acutal butter but he brought us the same stuff! The best part was the dessert the apple cobbler YYYUUUMMM !!!! The kids were very small section of the buffet and it overpriced for kids and adults.
 Allentown, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:03-02-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food was excellent. I love the new Hibachi grill and the made to order steaks!! Had a wonderful time look forward to our next visit!
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-28-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: There was 11 people in our family. Most of the family enjoyed the crab legs and clams, but the other food was not good at all. The service was great the waiter so no nice and friendly. All in all I will not go back we live in brunswick just across the line.
 Shallotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-11-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My fiancee and I always eat at the Giant Crab! We changed our vacation date because the restaurant was closed when we had originally planned to be in Myrtle Beach. We know they food quality is great and the price is not a problem because we plan for it. I agree with another person that the bad reviews were probably written by the competition. We actually celebrated our engagement by heading straight to the Giant Crab! We&apos;ll be in Myrtle Beach next week and look forward to eating there! : )
 Blacksburg, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:01-05-2010

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Excellent! we had such a good time here over the holidays. Everything was wonderful! thank you for such a wonderful experience..
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-26-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Don&apos;t even think of going here. wish I had read the reviews here first! The food was awful. Even with a buy one get one free coupon, it was highway robbery for the cheap not even Captain D&apos;s style seafood. Nasty! Absolutely not worth eating.
 Alabaster, Alabama 
 
 
Posted:10-29-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I LOVED THE GIANT CRAB!!! The staff was great and very helpful, everybody was so happy and smiling. The crablegs were great my husband loved them. The kid&apos;s bar was wonderful for my children with such a variety all geared towards what kids like to eat. There so many items to chose from it was exciting. The made-to-order pasta was outstanding. We will defintely be coming back again next year!!
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:10-23-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food was horrible. And I think that it is way OVERPRICED! Some of the food that was gotten off the bar was cold and disgusting. Have been here many times before and I have to say that this is the worst that it has ever been. So much that I will never eat there again. All I can say is watch out.
 Thomasville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-18-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Me and my family went to giant crab for our first time and will never go again. please go at your own risk. The name of the the restraunt is GIANT CRAB, the name of it should be GIANT CRAP!!! when we steped into the restruant the stinch was almost unbearable.After we were seated, we took a look at the menu and when we saw the outragouse prices we very sirously thought about leaving right then, but my Father insited that we stay. That night we orderd the buffet, and the food was horrible. like i said before please go at your own risk and i insist that you bring some extra money because you might want to go to an diffrent resraunt!!!!!
 Elkin, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-06-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Looks appealing from the outside. Don&apos;t be fooled! Inside is grimey, Staff is indifferent bordering on rudeness. Food may be of adequate quality but it is barely warm and tasteless. It seems that all the fried items are fried together. Far too expensive for what you get. Have a much better meal somewhere else.
 Arden, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-06-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I really have no words on just how awful this place is. The only glimmer was their Crab Legs. My husband loves them so he was happy there. Otherwise I was more than disgusted with everything else. So much so that I wouldn&apos;t eat it and asked for my money back. The staff didn&apos;t care and were rude to me though I gave honest courteous feedback about the most disgusting slop I&apos;ve every had. Do yourself a favor and stay away. You will thank yourself when you save money rather than waste it. Seriously I am appalled that they have ANY repeat customers. DISGUSTING!!!
 Cincinnati, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:08-31-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The crab legs were great,the attitudes of the waiters ,below average. the price wasn&quot;t that reasonable, expecially for kids.
 Zebulon, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-07-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Made the miserable mistake of trying to eat at this restaurant 7/15/09. I say &quot;trying to eat&quot; because the food is terrible. Even the waiter was seemingly apologetic. When I asked for a manager to complain I was met with stoney silence and a request to come back another time. Yeah, right! The great reviews must have been written by management or staff. As you can see most reviews really pan the place. AVOID. AVOID.AVOID!
 Flecther, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-20-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Overpriced, but good food all the same. We went with the early bird coupon and received about six bucks off, so this was good. The crab legs were really huge and plentiful and DELICIOUS. I loved the shrimp and other crab dishes. I didn&apos;t eat anything that I didn&apos;t like. I really liked the peel and eat shrimp. I wanted to try the pasta they made to order, but I was too full! The dessert was a highlight, with baklava and a unique dessert that looked weird but tasted so good! It had shredded wheat, chocolate, whipped cream, nuts, and something else, and it was the perfect ending. I know others are reviewing badly, but we honestly loved our meal, BUT the price is way, way, way too expensive.
 Mount Airy, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-16-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Let me start with this commen, the food was not seasoned and tasted like sea water. Not only was the food was over cooked, it all tasted the same. The chicken tasted like it was fried with the fish, the wait staff acted like they were at a comedy roast featuring me. They were very repulsive and showed no professional conduct to customers as well as my family. There was one bright light in the whole place but it was in the restroom. It was very poorly lit where we were seated. I did manage to get the attention of one of the staff members who stated that he was sorry that every thing was a disaster. My list could go on but the worthiness of my experience prevents me from doing so. Be afraid of this place. Be very afraid....
 Brooklyn Ny, New York 
 
 
Posted:07-02-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We may not have waited to be seated but when we were the waiter wasnt very friendly. The food wasnt that great it was barely warm and it wasnt that tasty and nothing was fresh. and the food is definitely NOT worth the $$$$$ you have to pay!!! my family and i are probably never going back there again!
 Greeneville, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:06-30-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab was OK and that&apos;s it. This restaurants food is nothing special, and is definitely not worth the $$$. The food was not fresh and was just warm. However, the service was great and the atmosphere of the restaurant was excellent. Maybe they had an off night, but i don&apos;t think we will be going back.
 Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:06-27-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family recently went to myrtle beach for one week. We ate at this restuarant and the food was ok. The crab legs had no meat and the food was cold.the only thing we liked was the sweet tea and onion rings and a rasberry and strawberry daquior. I would like to warn everybody how expensive this place is and my father got sick after eating there that night.
 Somerset, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:06-26-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This was the worst restaurant my wife and I have EVER been to and we have eaten all over the US, Canada, Mexico, Bermuda, Bahamas, France, Switzerland and Germany. The fried shrimp, popcorn shrimp and deviled crap cakes all tasted the same. The prime rib was fatty, the crab legs were tasteless and had almost no meat. Definately not worth the money. Basically, the only redeeming value to the meal (and I use that term loosely) was that we could get up and leave. Which we did.
 Oxford, New Jersy 
 
 
Posted:06-23-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Once again, the 6th year in a row is an A+ at The Giant Crab! (2004-2009) We eat there every year when we go down to Myrtle Beach! It&apos;s a tradition now! My oldest son who had never been there before and is stationed in Georgia was very impressed and said he will be going to eat there again in the very near future! Keep up the good work!!
 Cloquet, Minnesota 
 
 
Posted:06-22-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The crab ranged from not-so-good to rotten. Prime rib and roast beef were good. Almost the entire buffet was awful. Trays filled with empty clam shells. Extremely overcooked cold shrimp. Only the shrimp creole was decent, but rice has uncooked or dried bits mixed in. Fake crab everywhere. Really awful. Never go here. Even the staff don&apos;t touch the seafood when they eat.
 Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:06-19-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Avoid this place at all costs. The food is terrible and the buffet bar had the appearance of being quite dirty. My 4 year old complained to us that his chicken nuggets were not good, so he ate fries only.
The front of the restaurant enticed us to give it a try but for $23.95, the food is NOT WORTH IT. I had a salad, and tried the fried chicken and the sweat potatoes, both did not taste good. 
My wife was repulsed by the appearance of the seafood, so she decided not to eat it, and settled on a salad and peach cobbler. Our waiter was nice enough to get our bill modified to soup and salad bars for us and the kids meal.
 Denver, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-17-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We have made the Giant Crab a must do on our yearly vacations to Myrtle Beach. We absoulutely love the variety of food, great service and atmosphere.
 Wheeling, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:06-16-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: All of the food was of very low quality, the fried chicken was really good. Stay away.
 Columbus, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:06-15-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: On June 13th we tried the Giant Crab. First of all the taste and quality of the food was terrible. I tried almost every item on the buffet and the only items edible were the crab legs and the peach cobbler. My husband had to go chase our waiter down to get a refill on our drinks after thirty minutes and he was talking with three other waiters doing nothing. We gave the Giant Crab a try we won&apos;t go back.
 Lexington, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-11-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Been to a lot of restaurants.on 06/09/2009visited Giant Crab good service good food.will go back again.big crablegs prepared just right.price to high but all restaurants on the row are.
 Independence, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:06-08-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I can&apos;t understand the poor reviews I have read about this restaurant. I honestly believe they were written by this fine restaurant&apos;s local competition! I visit Myrtle Beach 2 or 3 times a year and always make it a point to have at least one meal at Giant Crab. The service is &quot;southern-friendly&quot;, the food is flavorful, just like home-cooked, and the over-all dining experience is a joy. EAT AT GIANT CRAB!!
 Falls Church, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:05-20-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Avoid the Giant Crab at all cost... It&apos;s not worth it.... Read below for more details! I am in complete shock at the unprofessional service I received when dealing with the manager at this location. I live in nc and frequent myrtle beach. I decided to take my husband there for his birthday this year and celebrate. He chose to eat at your restaurant because we had heard excellent things and have never been ourselves. We went in on may 12th around 8:30 pm. I was truly disappointed that the food was not as good as we expected, but figured since we were in late that was the cause. I was overlooking this, at first. The prime rib was cold. The salad bar wasn&apos;t available because it was being cleared. Some of the deserts were not there as well. I mentioned this to my server and he offered to get me a salad... But I declined, although now I wish I had. I asked to speak to a manager after we paid for our meal, but was told one wasn&apos;t available right now and was offered to take my name and number. I again declined because I had the phone number on my receipt and planned to call back once I got home. Little did I know that would later be a problem. I had no idea this place was so bad with customer satisfaction. Once home, I called, which was on the following friday and was told I would receive a return call once the situation was looked into. Come monday the 18th, since I had received no return call, I decided to try once again. I am so disappointed in the service I received from the manager I spoke with that I am no longer shocked this restaurant was so bad. I will never eat there again. This meal is not worth the $57 I paid which did not include tip for 2 adults. I was told by the manager that had I dealt with the problem that night something could have been done. She didn&apos;t bother to take notice that I did try to speak with someone that night. She didn&apos;t even bother that I tried to call someone earlier too and this was my second attempt. This manager told me she was sorry this happened but there was nothing she could do because *i* didn&apos;t report it that night. She said I should have let them take my name and number and I should have let my server get me a salad. She kept passing the blame to me. It was my fault she couldn&apos;t do anything about it. I had my receipt, my servers name, the time I was there... What else could she need? I just don&apos;t understand. It was much easier to overlook the food issues I had but it&apos;s impossible to ignore the horrible customer service I received from management. I know this is a long review but I want you to know that I got the worst treatment at this place than i&apos;ve ever gotten else where... To sum it all up: the food was okay, not worth $24 a person. The service was okay until I asked for a manager... It went downhill thereafter. The buffet was sparse some food wasn&apos;t there... They were clearing it. Customer service from management was horrible. Avoid at all cost..
 Ivanhoe, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:05-17-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: AWFUL!!!!! There website is full of crap. There was no pasta bar, the peel and eat shrimp were overcooked, and tiny. You could barely peel them. The crab legs were overdone. They had no roastbeef, prime rib, ribs, only 1 soup. They may have had 50 items, and they were all bad. I live on the chesapeake bay and get good seafood. This was garbage. I think alot of it was premade frozen food. All breading and no meat. For two people with a coke and an ice tea, it was $67.00. I could have gotten one heck of a meal for that somewhere else. Red lobster (which is disgusting and uses microwaves in their kitchen) is better. Go to a nice place and skip the buffets in MB.
 Baltimore, Maryland 
 
 
Posted:05-16-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: YES, YOU CAN BELIEVE THE POSITIVE REVIEWS! Could there be a chance that employees wrote one or more of these? Possibly yes. Me and my wife live in Minnesota so I don&apos;t think we work at The Giant Crab! (too long of a drive each day) :) We&apos;ve eaten there 5 years in a row and have NEVER had a bad experience! Could the Giant Crab have an off day/night? I suppose every restaurant does from time to time! Once upon a time me and my wife had a cafe in Duluth, MN and I know we served good food, but we might have have had an off day once in a while. We&apos;re flying into Myrtle Beach in the middle of June of this year and YES, The Giant Crab is a shoe-in on our agenda! Thanks, and God Bless!
 Cloquet, Minnesota 
 
 
Posted:05-08-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: DO NOT BELIEVE THE POSITIVE REVIEWS, THEY HAVE TO BE POSTED BY THE STAFF. 

1) 25 bucks a piece for an adult.
2) Food was the worst my wife and I have ever had
3) Food was the worst - greasy, cold, all tasted the same (this was worth posting twice.)

Save yourself from the expensive stomach ache, and find another place to eat!!
 Dayton, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:04-05-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My husband and I ate here about a year ago and it will be the last time. The place was dirty, food cold, and the crab legs were the worse around. They need to take the giant crab down outside and turn it backwards.
 Clinton, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:03-30-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family and I enjoyed this buffet so much we dined there 3 times last week. The staff is sooo friendly. There is such a variety of food to choose from. Some of us do not eat seafood and we still had such a variety. The dessert bar was wonderful so many items and specialty desserts. We visited last year and they have done some remodeling it looks great. Keep up the great work and see you next year!!
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:03-29-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate there last year great food cant wait for 2009 vacation we will be back keep up the good work..
 Mcmechen, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:03-21-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My husband and I hadn&apos;t been to the Crab in a long time, but were given a gift certificate. After reading the reviews, we were not expecting much. WRONG. The restaurant was clean, the food hot and delicious, the crablegs plentiful, and the service above par. We spend three months in the winter in Myrtle Beach and have tried most of the &quot;seafood buffets.&quot; I would say the the Giant Crab not only matched the others, but exceeded them in food and service. We were there on a Friday and intend to go one more time before we leave.
 Susquehanna, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:03-19-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Yes I will admit I am a tourist....we visited the Giant Crab on our third night here in Myrtle Beach and the food was THE WORST I HAVE EVER HAD at any buffet. I work in food service and am not sure why this establishment has not been shut down. Nothing was hot. The &quot;prime rib&quot; was cold and very very rare. The food all tasted the same--we had the chicken soup and it tasted like seafood (how do you mess up chicken noodle soup??)! The cheesecake was still frozen when placed on the dessert bar. The crab legs were cold and very overcooked. I am from Wisconsin--it does not take much for me to view seafood as great (since we are lacking it in the midwest). I thought this place was disgusting I would not reccommend it to ANYONE! The fact they do not list their price leaves the customer(s) to have a large &quot;surprise&quot; at the end of their terrible experience. Four of us had dinner and one drink a piece and our bill was $140.00 not including tip! THIS PLACE IS NOT WORTH THE MONEY! IT SUCKS!!!!
 Eau Claire, Wisconsin 
 
 
Posted:03-12-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We recently dined at the Giant Crab and thought it was great!! The atmosphere was so comfortable and kid friendly. We sat near the bufffet with a view of the waterway so my kids could watch to see if any boats went by which they enjoyed. The service was excellent she was very attentive to our needs and was very good with children. We loved the food we filled up on everything there is so much to choose from. I thought for an all you can eat buffet the price was great considering the variety they offered. The kids loved the gift shop and the souvenir pics they offered. Keep up the good work Giant Crab!! We will see you next year!
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:03-07-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We were seated very quickly and our orders were taken quickly. Although that did little to make up for the extremely high prices and poor quality food. For just myself and my husband and our two children it was over $75.00. Most of the food was bland and had little or no flavor. Of course when you walk in you don&apos;t know how much the buffet is until you are seated and you feel it would be rude to just walk out after you ordered your drink and you are then told how much they charge per person. They have very little for kids to eat, hot dogs and chicken tenders and small pieces of cheese pizza. I would suggest going somewhere else and saving your money for something to entertain yourself and any others with you..
 Trinity, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:03-05-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Me and my hubby make it an annual event on our yearly vacation to eat at the Giant Crab! it&apos;s always great! I can&apos;t wait until our vacation this summer! :) .
 Carlton, Minnesota 
 
 
Posted:02-22-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I loved eating at the gaint crab! the food was so good!.
 Myrtlebeach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-22-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: They had the best crablegs ever! Everyone enjoyed them........ my family looks forward to this place every year!...... hopefully if ur looking to eat at this place , that u willl give it a try. if u love some good crablegs then this is the place to go ! ...... or if u want to take ur boyfriend or sumthing to dinner and he really likes crablegs then take him helll love it!
 Morgantown, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:02-19-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Best Seafood Experience!! We loved the crablegs!! Good Price for all u can eat seafood!! I read some of the other reviews and people are crazy these days!! If you are too cheap to go out to eat you should stay home. Crablegs are expensive and too get them at an all you can eat price for $25 is great!! My husband liked the prime rib and the steam bar!! The atmoshere and decor was beautiful! They also offered live music and they were great!!
 Marion, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-16-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Me and my wife first discovered The Giant Crab restaurant when we took a vacation together in 2004. We&apos;ve gone to eat there once every year for a total of 5 times (2004-2008) and have always had a great experience with an excellent waitress and GREAT seafood! My son is currently stationed in Georgia and this summer we plan on meeting and eating at The Giant Crab! Thanks! 
Rich&amp;Kim Wallace, Cloquet, MN
 Cloquet, Minnesota 
 
 
Posted:01-03-2009

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We love seafood......what we got at Giant Crab was more like Giant Crap!! Most of the food was fried. The stuffed mushrooms, crab cakes and deviled crab were all bread and celery. Every piece of fish-swordfish,flounder - was dried out-even the stuff they just brought out.The roast beef that was sliced was tough as shoe leather and could not be cut without a razor. 
Now if imitation crabmeat and lobster are your thing then you&apos;d enjoy this place. The steamed crab legs were hit or miss. I&apos;d guess that one out of every dozen were cooked correctly. The others were mush.
The desserts were like the crab legs-hit or miss. 
All in all I would NOT recommend the Giant Crappy Crab.
 Chase City, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:12-28-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family and I had a great experience at this restaurant! Considering we have 3 children who are picky eaters the price and food selections were excellent! The price of the buffet was also pretty good considering the variety of the items on the buffet. My husband enjoyed all of the seafood while I dined more on the prime rib and the ready to order pasta station.Had a good atmosphere with the live music and the many fish tanks so the children had something to enjoy in addition to the gift shop toys. Overall everything was great and we plan on eating there again on our next visit! I highly recommend it to others!
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:12-25-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The quality is poor and the price is high. I will never go back to the Giant.
 Augusta, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:11-09-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My kids wanted to go to this restaurant because of the crab... Never again! the food was terrible. The bill was too high. I&apos;d rather eat a Fillet O Fish at McDonald&apos;s .
 Huntersville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-02-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: In June of this year I took my daughter&amp;family to MB for a beach treat eating out at multiple restaurants. The night we went to the Giant Crab it was crowded, unbelieveably noisy, the floor was filthy with food&amp;no one cleaning it. I actually felt sorry for the waitress as she was almost tripping over peoples wild kids trying to serve. THEN there was what they call food!! I live at a FL beach&amp;frequently have seafood in a variety of restarants, the seafood at the Crab was absolutely nasty! Most foods were so over cooked or old you couldn&apos;t tell what they were without the sign. Why didn&apos;t we just leave prior to being served? I thought the food had to be great because it was so crowded, WRONG, the bill was $82. for 3 children&amp;2 adults for food that didn&apos;t even measure up to a fish sandwich at McDonalds!! Go there at your own risk!
 St. Petersburg Beach, Florida 
 
 
Posted:10-27-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: It was very delicious and cheap!.
 Eldo, California 
 
 
Posted:09-23-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Recently I planned a trip to Myrtle Beach for the ladies of my family and planned a special dinner here. It WAS a big disappointment for ALL. Over half of the food listed on the website was not available. Some of the food was dried out. We will never go again. Don&apos;t waste your money! Our server was great but that was the only good thing about our experience.
Judith-Jacksonville, NC
Guests from Charleston, SC
 Jacksonville, FL
 Havelock, NC
 Newport News, VA
 St. Augustine, FL
 Mt. Pleasant, SC
 New Bern, NC
 Hampton, VA
 Virginia Beach, VA
 Wilminton, NC
 Jacksonville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-21-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My husband and I always make this our first meal out when in Myrtle Beach! It&apos;s a great deal for the amount of food they offer. We love the she crab soup...to die for!! You can sit near the window overlooking the waterway and it&apos;s just great. I would recommend to anyone looking for a great seafood buffet!
 Galax, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:09-14-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We had a very unpleasant experience here last week. Half of what they advertise on their online menu wasn&apos;t on the buffet no ham, no prime rib, just dried up roast beef. No prices posted at the door $24.99 per person, plus $2 for a drink they charged us 4.99 for our 3yr old plus another 1.99 for her drink. She could have eaten at McDonald&apos;s and got a better meal for less. There is no variety and the food was barely warm at best. The waitress spent all night chatting with a table behind us, so refills on drinks were very few and dirty plates piled up, and we waited a long time for the check. Everyone we asked said how great it was, if you like fried shrimp, and fried fish it&apos;s great but everything is fried, and there is no variety. No oysters rockefella, no scampi, no sword fish, no mahi, just lies and high prices. Spend your money somewhere else....Like Angelo&apos;s Excellent food&amp;service.
 Fayetteville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-15-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My fiance and I dined at the Giant Crab our first night at Myrtle Beach. It was a horrible experience! The food was bland, it wasn&apos;t warm, and there wasn&apos;t a large selection. The marquee states there are over 120 items at the buffet. There is no way! We were really surprised when we got the check; it was $60 for the two of us! The food here is definitely not worth the price, I wouldn&apos;t recommend to anyone!
 High Point, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-13-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This place exists to rip off tourists. I&apos;m not picky but the food was horrible and way over priced. My wife wouldn&apos;t eat and was furious about the food and bad service. The bottom line is that this place doesn&apos;t care. Do yourself a favor and avoid this place.
 Winston-salem, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-11-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Honestly for 25$ a person I would think I would be getting a really good buffet but it sucked big time definetly not 120 items (maybe if you include all pops and alcohol and salad toppings) nothing tasted right and everything was just blah please dont order any mixed drinks they come out over 6$ a drink which is more expensive then toronto --i would rather go to a fast food restaurant.
 Toronto, ON 
 
 
Posted:07-30-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Well we tried the Giant Crab after hearing it was the biggest and best on the strand. Let me say I have been to many other seafood buffets in Myrtle and This is by far the worst. I was more expensive(even with a coupon) and not as good as many of the others. Two nights prior we had been to Crabby Mike&apos;s a much better experience even with a 45 minute wait.
My reasons: The guy at the crab station would only give two sections at a time, and it was not steaming hot. The other fried seafoods all tasted the same and that was not good. Nothing seemed fresh. 
I will say a few good things. They did have a section on the buffet for kids which was nice. Although my kids love the Crab. The Prime Rib was also OK. 
 I would not go to Giant Crab again and wish It had not been our last meal in Myrtle.
 Columbus, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:07-26-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: OMG!! It was the most disguisting food that I have ever had in my life. Everything tasted as if it were prepared in the same pot. This place needs to be shut down.
 Winston-salem, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-21-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This was the WORST restaurant by far that we dined at while at Myrtle Beach. The food was horrible and if I&apos;m going to pay the price we had to pay for this meal (which the price was not posted anywhere, so getting the bill at the end of the meal was a total shock) I expect to be able to eat however much/many crab legs I want and not have someone hand me one set of legs and have to go back and make feel that you are taking something from them. My advice to anyone considering to go to the Giant Crab... DON&apos;T ... you will definitely regret it. If I had to do over I would have complained and asked for our money back. $170. is extremely high for CRAP
 Pikeville, Kentucky 
 
 
Posted:07-13-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: When you walk in there are no prices listed while you wait to be seated. You would think a buffet would be $10-15 per person. We took our nephew for graduating The Ohio State University. Thought I would have to take out a student loan! The bill was just shy of $90 bucks!!! The food was cold and when you asked a staff person for butter you get looked at like you are a freak. After the 3rd time I finally got a pat of butter! Will never be back. You want good seafood at an excellent price to to Captain Nance in Calabash!!
 South Point, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:07-03-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food was luke warm. The service was fairly good. Seemed a bit overpriced for the quality of food. One desert made of shredded wheat was awesome!
 Grand Prairie, Texas 
 
 
Posted:06-22-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We had visited the Giant Crab in Aug of 07. It was about 25.00 dollars a person to eat there. My family and I really enjoyed the food and the atmosphere. Lots of different things to eat and also lots of things that my kids would want to eat as well. It was alot better than Red Lobster considering this is a buffet style resturant. There are alot of buffets in Myrtle Beach, and we went to onw the night before, and it was no comparison to the Giant Crab. Will be back this year!
 Macon, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:06-06-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: YUCK!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! OVERPRICED.... 28 bucks a person....doesn&apos;t include drinks. Rude staff. WILL NEVER EAT HERE AGAIN
 Anderson, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:05-30-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The only buffet we went to, but it was pretty fabulous. The fried scallops, deviled crab and made-to-order shrimp pasta alfredo were to DIE for! Plenty of desserts, nice salad bar and TONS of seafood of every type. We didn&apos;t like the chairs, though. The way the tables were scrunched together getting in and out of your chair (with arm rests) made it somewhat difficult.
 Galion, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:05-26-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The biggest tourest trap I have ever been taken in by. Food was horrible, crab legs with no crab crackers or crab forks. Filet-O-Fish would be a step up to the food you would find on the bar.
 Kingsport, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:05-07-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Based on the reviews, we will pass on dining at the Giant Crab. Thank you for you web site. Wonder what their HEALTH REPORT score is?
 Jacksonville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:05-07-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is by far the best seafood I have had in a long time. The crab legs were excellent. They have a huge selection of food and desserts. My server was so nice and informative. This buffet is worth every penny it made my vacation. Keep up the great work see you next year!!
 Newport News, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:05-03-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Of the large buffet seafood restaurants in Myrtle Beach, this is absolutely the worst I have been to. The restaurant appears old and dingy on the inside, and the food is very plain and without much taste. There is a lot of quantity, but not much quality. I will go to almost any of the others before going to Giant Crab again.
 Eatonton, GE 
 
 
Posted:04-27-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Good food and service for a all you can eat restaurant..
 Lancaster, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:04-15-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family &quot;dined&quot; at the Giant Crab last Thanksgiving. It was terrible. The buffet price is not posted. If you are expecting a reasonable price - forget it. We paid $100 bucks for poorly prepared food in a place with old, dirty carpeting and beat up furniture. The place had a strange, unidentifiable odor - not food, not chemical, just unappetizing. All the seafood tasted the same: bland, unseasoned, and either undercooked or overcooked. Shrimp scampi had one or two shrimp floating in a sea of overcooked watery rice. I will not return here. I wanted to stand outside and warn others going in but I figured I&apos;d be arrested.
 Asheville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:04-15-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I would not recommend this restaurant to my worst enemy. For the price of $24.00 a person the only thing that was good on the buffet was the crab legs. It seemed that everything else was overcooked or had been sitting out for much too long. Go somewhere else!
 Ladson, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:04-11-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: THIS PLACE SUCKS. If you want to toss away 50 bucks on crap then buy some of my horseshit from my barns... it will be a better time than this place will prove out for you. Have a great trip!!!
 Augusta, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:03-28-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: By far the worst seafood place in the country, nevermind mb. Eight of us went for the buffet around 7:30pm midweek, the meat was raw, the seafood&amp;the sides were luke warm and scraps were all that was left. Fortunately I filled up on soft-serve ice cream, because the main course just wasn&apos;t suitable to eat. Also stay away from the caddyshack, sub-par food at an unreasonable price..
 Boston, Massacheusetts 
 
 
Posted:03-21-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This place was the BEST!! My husband and I absolutely LOVED the GIANT Crab! The buffett has endless choices, the food was hot and the make your own pasta was SUPERB!! I&apos;ve eaten at pleny of seafood restaurants and the GIANT Crab was by far the best!!! You even get your picture taken while you wait in line (smile :-)! We will definitely eat here again when we celebrate our 1st anniversary(June 2008)...and we can hardly wait!! If you are in Myrtle Beach, you MUST eat at the GIANT Crab...you will NOT be dissapointed!
 Raleigh, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-18-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family had the buffet bar on 2/16/08 at around 8pm. The seafood had a bland taste compared to the local seafood restaurants around the Charlotte, NC. You would expect better seafood near the coast, however, their are very few that have local catches. The food is all shipped in from other parts of the world. The crab legs were not to bad and at least they had alot to choose from. Pretty much a rip off in regards to how much they charge and the cheap stuff they put out.
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:02-18-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My boyfriend and I were celebrating Valentine&apos;s Day and our 1 year anniversary. He had been wanting some crab legs and was very pleased with the food at the Giant Crab. The service was great and the atmosphere was wonderful. We will definitely be returning to your restaurant in the future
 Blacksburg, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:01-26-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Our group was attending a marriage retreat and this restaurant was suggested to us by our resort. Although now, I don&apos;t know why. The service was great and the atmosphere was okay, but the food was severely subpar. The food didn&apos;t look appetizing, everything was room temperature, and honestly wasn&apos;t prepared well. Several people in our party actually got food poisoning. I wouldn&apos;t recommend going here unless you want to pay too much for bad sea food.
 Fayetteville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:01-09-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food is terrible. No taste. Shrimp scampi consisted of five or six shrimp lazily floating in soup rice (!). The place had an indiscernable smell - not seafood, not disinfectant, just odd. The dining areas are well worn and not clean. Noisy. All the fried seafood tasted alike, i. e. Frymax oil. Fries were soggy. NO PRICE IS POSTED FOR THE BUFFET so bring about $23 per person not including beverage, tax, and tip. This place must stay in business by virtue of new tourists because I cannot imagine anyone willingly returning to this rip off dump.
 Asheville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:01-07-2008

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I&apos;ve travelling to Myrtle Beach for over 25 years, this has to win the award(if there is one) for the VERY worse place to eat in Horry County. As the previous reviewer said, want lots of food, go get it. If you food that you are able to eat, go anywhere else. Food was cold, watery, tasted a lot like rubber. I tried several things thinking that everything couldnt be that bad, but I was wrong. I prefer my lettuce to be green, not brown. Crab legs were rubbery and way over cooked. The best thing I could find was the banana pudding......hard to screw that up I guess. Asked for a slice of prime rib and you would have thought I said something nasty about the guys mother the way he treated me. Gave me a slice of meat that you could read a newspaper through. And it was way overcooked also. In all fairness, my wife did say that the SheCrab soup was good. Not bad i guess, 2 good things out of over 120 items. I hope this helps someone to not spend 50.00 on a bad meal. I really doubt if it will be around long serving food like this if not killing someone before.
 Fairmont, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:12-14-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is by far the worst seafood buffet I&apos;ve ever had. I visited with my family November 23, 07 for a change after Thanksgiving. The restaurant had an unidentifiable strange pungent odor. The place was dirty. Seating was cramped. The buffet was so bad it was practically laughable. &quot;Shrimp scampi&quot; was a pan of white rice in a yellowy liquid with two or three small shrimp floating in it. Fried food was greasy and tastless. Frenh fries were dried out. Crab soup had no crab. Nothing was well presented or attractive. The buffet price is not openly posted so if you don&apos;t ask you will be in for a nasty surprise - $25 a head for food unfit for starving convicts. Don&apos;t be fooled by the number of cars in the parking lot. There are so many fresh tourists there that they surely have to depend on new business as I cannot believe anyone would willingly return!
 Asheville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-14-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I WILL STATE THE TRUTH !!! We were in Myrtle Beach for 3 days, and 2 dinners !! After we ate at The Crab the first night, we went right back for the second. We were here to kill crabs, and that we did with great enthusiasm. We were previously paying about $18 for 1 1/2 crabs in the Outer Banks, so why are people complaining about the $22 price? HELLO...it&apos;s all you can eat..

I ate until I couldn&apos;t crack any more shell. They were the largest and sweetest crabs I&apos;ve EVER EATEN. And I even prefer lobster, but I had two great meals. My wife tried other food and didn&apos;t have any complaints that I heard. Our service was okay, kept clearing crab shell off the table. I tried some desserts, tasted okay for the most part..

Now, to be fair, I must advise that this is not the place to go for a quiet family meal of high quality. If you want a knockout dinner, then go to Ruth&apos;s Chris or Morton&apos;s, of which I am a great enthusiast and pay the $200+ per couple because that&apos;s just what it costs for excellent food and service. But if you want to roll your sleeves up and pack in as many crabs as you can slam into your gut, this is the place to go. They have an extremely large variety of many foods available, but I really couldn&apos;t expand as I never ate any food but the crab..

And as far as the price goes, what do the other reviewers expect to pay for all-you-can-eat crab, $15? Maybe during the civil war !!! It&apos;s 2007, you people are lucky you even have this available for $22. And remember, I&apos;ve paid well over $200 for awesome meals with my wife many times. I&apos;ve eaten across Canada, the U.S., and in other foreign destinations, so I know a thing or two about good food and prices. But you won&apos;t get better crab than this for any amount of money. I don&apos;t know what else to say...if you love crab, eat here.
 Toronto, ON 
 
 
Posted:10-15-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I should have known that any restaurant needing a 20+ foot fake crab to draw in customers wasn&apos;t going to be serving quality seafood. But I was mislead by the number of cars in the parking lot -- which ordinarily is a tip off that it&apos;s a popular spot - and usually popular with good reason. But not in this case. If you&apos;re looking for a lot of food, then go. But if you want it to be served warm to hot, have any flavor, or any actual seafood in it for that matter, stay away. The salmon was tasteless. The she-crab soup was tasty but didn&apos;t contain any crab meat that I could detect. Nor did the large crab cakes - not a spec of crab in it - just finely ground bread stuffing. Didn&apos;t even taste like seafood. My favorite foods were the baked yams with marshmallow topping; a crab diablo - which did taste good and have large chunks of &quot;crab&quot; but was made using those fake sea crab pieces; and a very nice spinach with feta cheese in phyllo dough - which I could have gotten anywhere without spending $22/per person - after the discount coupon - and not counting drink or tax or tip! The crab legs were pretty good - but can be ordered elsewhere for a lot less. Desserts were limited - about 4-5 (including jello - which wasn&apos;t even very good); and forget the salad bar -- it had only iceberg lettuce (no other type of greens) and unmarked dressings. I first tasted one I thought would be bleu cheese - I think it was actually cucumber - so I tried another that did turn out to be bleu cheese - or at least resembled it in mild bleu cheese taste --without any blue cheese actually being in it either. My husband didn&apos;t mind the place -- he managed to fill up on fried chicken and other items. But the taste and the value were definitely not there. About the only half-way decent thing about this place was the service -- they do stop by often to clear plates and check on you. Anyway - for better seafood (tho not an all you can eat - try the very cute Murrel&apos;s Bay Crab Shack - a family-run operation with an &quot;islands&quot; feel. We also enjoyed Damon&apos;s ribs in Mrytle Beach Ocean Ave. I&apos;m sorry we didn&apos;t get a chance to try George&apos;s all-you-can eat seafood - it got great reviews - tho again, we never made it...wonder what we missed...whatever, it had to be better than the Giant Crab.
 Cranford, N. 
 
 
Posted:10-09-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food quality was equal to fast food, would you pay $25.00 for a fast food meal? They do not (as the sign says) serve prime rib, only dried out roast beef. There are better places to eat seafood in Myrtle Beach.
 Springfield, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:09-26-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We have eaten at the Giant Crab for the past two years. The variety of the food is great and everything was tasty and cooked exactly right. The crab legs are the freshest in Myrtle Beach. I would highly recommend the Giant Crab to anyone that wants a great seafood buffet. We look forward to eating there again next year.
 Asheville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-26-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Our family really liked the selection that was available. I believe there were over 20 different seafood selections, over 20 different dessert selections and countless treats for the kiddos in our party. The pasta chef made wonderful noodles for my 2 preschoolers, taking care to make them feel special. The waiter in our section was wonderful and really was attentive.

Our only complaints were that the aisles are quite close together and my husband thought the sweet tea was not as good as it could have been.

We used our 5 dollar coupon and the price was very reasonable (compared to the other seafood places nearby).
 Canton, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:09-21-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Visited in 8/07 while vacationing. We made a terrible choice in selecting one of the many seafood buffet restaurants in Myrtle Beach. My advice: don&apos;t walk, run from this place! The food was horrible. So little seafood to be found in most recipes (stuffed mushrooms, crabcakes, seafood pasta dishes, etc.) The only food that was good were the giant crab legs. Even some of the food from the kids area was better! Try another buffet before selecting this one!
 Mt. Laurel, New Jersy 
 
 
Posted:09-20-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: After reading some reviews I was a little worried when we decided to eat here. It was the best choice we made! The food was outstanding...the waiter was right there on top of everything. I could not have asked for a better experience. I will be looking forward to going next year!
 Hardy, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:09-11-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Just came from &quot;Tommy&quot; the big PHAT crab and as usual everything was just fantastic.More than satisfied. More bang for the buck than the competitor 2 doors away. Gotta love a $5 coupon also - www.giantcrab.com. Relaxing is the word here. Cant wait for Thanksgiving,once again, as my in-laws will be coming to eat at &quot;The Crab&quot;.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-03-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This was definitely one of the more unpleasant dining experiences I&apos;ve ever had.
It started out just fine with the gentleman at the door greeting people as they walked up, and the hostess offered all customers a quick tour of what can be found on what buffet line. Once seated, however, the whole experience went downhill at breakneck speed.
The tables are so close together, I felt like a sardine. Every time I got up, I had to turn this way and that, giving an &quot;excuse me&quot; after every chair I had to pass. The table was wobbly, and leaning directly towards me as the liquid from the crab shells in the basket drained out from the bottom of the basket (no plate!) and ran down the table directly into my lap.
The server came to my table, a party of three, and provided us with only 2 sets of plates to start us off. When it came to tea refills, one almost had to jump up and down to get the server&apos;s attention. And don&apos;t ask for more than one refill! When I&apos;d asked for a second refill, the server brought me a glass of a pale liquid, that looked like it may have simply been weak tea. After one sip, I realized he had given me a glass of extra strength sugar water!!!
At this point, after the mediocre-at-best food, the crab legs, which were far from fresh, being rationed out by an attendant..who incidentally was carrying on a conversation with a fellow employee and made me feel like I was intruding, and the horrendous service and atmosphere, I was ready to go.
Considering this is a buffet restaurant, I expected a modest check for 3 people. The bill came to $85! The ripoff of the year! Needless to say, I will never, ever visit this restaurant again, and caution any of my friends, family, or business associates to avoid it as well.
 Jacksonville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-03-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This place was somewhat a dissapointment. The service was good, our waitress was very nice, and didn&apos;t even charge us for our drinks, but the food wasn&apos;t that great. There was a lot to choose from, but the prices are outrageous!!!
 Fayetteville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-02-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I&apos;ve lived and dined in over 10 different US cities and this is by far the best buffet i have ever been to. the food was perfect and so was the atmosphere. there was plenty of seating. but i dont think i would want to pay the regular price (although well worth it) for the buffet. i had a much appreciated discount from a coupon. but i work in hospitality where i refer people to the Giant Crab every single day. im like a walking advertisement sometimes and I&apos;ve only had the opportunity to go once. next time i go i will bring alot more people with me!
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-30-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This place is a huge RIPOFF! I took a group of 5 and about died when we got the bill! The food was horrible. I left hungry and I knew everyone else did too. The food was inedible and that was on a slow night where they weren&apos;t pumping things out fast from the kitchen. Even the jello was bad! How can you screw that up??! Also, someone in my party did not receive their VIP card back that they paid $10 for. I called the restaurant the next day after we realized but they did nothing about it. I think someone there stole it. Waitstaff wasn&apos;t very good either. Decor was very dated as well.
 West Chester, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:08-30-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I was so looking forward to going to this place but what a complete let down when I got there. The price was outragouse $24.00 a person not including the 18% tip and there was no menu for anyone who did not want the buffet. We had a couple in our party that do not eat seafood but was going to get the prime rib till they saw it sitting there very rare in a puddle of blood. it was a crowded place which made it extremely hard to get near any of the food and when you did get to it they were always out of things. The wait for the crab legs was so long we all thought they were out to sea fishing for the crabs.

The only good thing about the whole experence is that if you ordered a frozen drink it came in a glass you got to take home. I am pretty sure the next time we go to Myrtle Beach we will not be going back there.
 Atlanta, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:08-14-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Me and my family went to the Giant Crab and had a good time. The crab legs were really good and huge but the rest of the food was okay. Two of my Aunts complained about the tea being weak and watery tasting so they switch their drinks to sodas. I continued drinking the tea it was alright after you added some sweet n low. The food was nothing to write home about but our trip was made more memorable because of the pictures one of the staff members took of our group. It was the only group picture we were able to take while vacationing at Myrtle Beach The staff member wore a hat shaped like a crab and was taking pictures of people that were dining together. I thought that was a nice touch. Would I eat there again? Maybe. The next time I visit Myrtle Beach I&apos;ll have to sample some of the other resturants.
 Charlotte, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-11-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I hate seafood, but the rest of my family loves it. And they had no complaints at all. In fact, neither did I. There was plenty of meat and chicken for me. So I enjoyed it too.
 Hagerstown, Maryland 
 
 
Posted:07-30-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is one of our favorite restaurants to eat at every time we go on vacation at the beach. I&apos;ll admit it is a little on the expensive side for a family style buffet but worth the money because of the exceptional taste and unique variety of food selection. The atmosphere is friendly and the service good. We have never had to wait an exceptionaly long time for a table. Even my three kids love this place and they&apos;re pretty picky, lol! I would recommend this restaurant to anyone looking for a truly wonderful seafood buffet experience.
 Taylorsville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-10-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Fairly good seafood.
Amazing crab legs.
Servers worked their tails off.
 Alpharetta, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:07-08-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Excellant for a seafood buffet. My Fiance and I went here becuase she has an unhealth addiction for crablegs. (She ate two at a time and took full shots of butter.) They just kept coming, they were huge, and it was fantastic. The sirlion was fantastic. The crabcakes were good, and the desert was super. We enjoyed this, and when you order a big beer you can keep the glass....it was good and the bill was average for a buffet.
 Manassas, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:07-08-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I live in myrtle beach and go to a lot of restaurants this one was the nastiest and way over priced to sum it up in one word terrible.
 M.B., S. 
 
 
Posted:07-07-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: WHAT A RIP OFF!! We visited this place recently and they were continually running out of crab legs! The waitress said it was due to the large crowd. A long line would form at the empty crab pan then they would bring out a few at a time with a guy that reminded me of the &quot;Soup Nazi&quot; from Seinfeld dishing out small portions to each person. My son waited in the &quot;Crab Line&quot; for 20 min to get a small plate. I have eaten at other AYCE seafood places in MYB but have never been so disappointed. The rest of the food was mostly cold. I asked to speak to the manager but he stayed out of sight. $23.00 a person for a buffet that runs out of crab legs is outragous. There are other places (Capt Georges) that are so much better! Don&apos;t waste your time or money on this place!
 Roanoke, Virginia 
 
 
Posted:06-30-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate at The Giant Crab last week. It was our second time. The crab legs were terrific, as usual, and of all the buffets on the grand strand their roast beef and prime rib is probably the best, probably the most tender. The only disappointment this time around was that they have fallen off a bit on their calabash fried shrimp. It was not as good as last time, and falls behind other top calabash fried shrimp places like Bennetts and Dockside in Calabash, NC. I still think $23 for adult buffet is a bit much, but truth be known it&apos;s more or less market. A very good experience, and a perfect place for family having dinner. They have been very busy both times we&apos;ve gone, and the service has not suffered either time.
 Clemson, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-23-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The wait and service levels for us were very good. Our young server was quick to get us beverages and refills and was a polite server.

Food.......terrible!!! Everything but the crab tasted like mushy cold shoe leather........all of the fried seafood tasted the same, awful and indistinguishable. The soups were yuck and the lettuce awful. Deserts and rolls were edible but nothing worth writing home about.

Prices not listed anywhere in the restaurant or at table, but we paid $23 adults and $17 for one child and $6 for young child. In addition, beverages were several bucks a piece on top of buffet price. Total bill for family of four was over $100 with tip! Certainly not worth it unless you can eat crab in droves!! Folks by us did eat oysters in bunches....may be good but not my thing.

Won&apos;t be back!!
 Indianapolis, Indiana 
 
 
Posted:06-19-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab Restaurant is the best seafood restaurant in Myrtle Beach. We tried a wide variety of food there and all was excellent. If you&apos;re a crab lover this is the place to go. We&apos;ll stop by at every trip to Myrtle Beach!
 Jacksonville, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-14-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: After reading all reviews on seafood restaurants in myrtle beach this one had the best overall reviews; however, after going there it wasn&apos;t as good as everyone says it is. This buffet seems to have the same problem as the other ones in trying to keep the food hot, by the time you get to your table everything is cold. The service was great and everyone was friendly but for $23.00 a person it was average at best. The ladies bathroom had only 3 stalls with 1 broken, for a place this large should&apos;ve been more stalls for the ladies. If you go there make sure you get the coupon for $5.00 off and dig around the servings to make sure it&apos;s hot.!.
 Jacksonville, NO 
 
 
Posted:06-11-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is one of the best seafood buffetts I have ever visited we plan to make it a tradition now, everytime we visit!
 Nicholasville, Kentucky 
 
 
Posted:06-01-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I must say I was looking forward to the Giant Crab, but I was a bit disappointed. The fried shrimp were very tiny, and the clam strips were like rubber. The she-crab soup was the most disappointing. I tasted no crab. I will say the crab legs are excellent and the prime rib was worth it, but the rest was average at best. You better be a die-hard crab lover or you will waste your money here..
 Gainesville, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:05-21-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have visited myrtle beach before and this was the first time at the Giant Crab. This place is great, there is so much to offer and the crab legs are awesome. You cant complain that it is $22 a person because you are getting all you can eat soup, salad, dinner, and dessert. I will definitly make it back to the Giant Crab during every visit in myrtle beach..
 Hamden, Connecticut 
 
 
Posted:05-10-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family and I were visiting Myrtle Beach for the first time and decided to try The Giant Crab. We were very impressed! The food was very good and the atmosphere was phenomenal! We will definitely be back!
 Bloomsburg, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:04-09-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: 2006 was my 3rd time visiting the Mytle Beach area for golf and our group of 8 decided to try the Giant Crab. Well, to say the least the food was atrocious. We all went with the buffet, a huge mistake. The beef at the carving station was still alive, the seafood offerings were probably deceased at least 12 weeks, one might think they were just picked off the beach and warmed-up and served, most everything was dry or undercooked. Needless to say, I ate a lot of soft-serve ice cream that night, the buffet offerings were unedible. This is one place that we will not visit again.
 Needham, Massacheusetts 
 
 
Posted:03-10-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We went here after reading a &quot;Best of the beach&quot; mumbo jumbo in the flyer at the hotel we stayed at so we figured &quot;How bad can it be?&quot; Answer:The WORST!! Even with the &quot;Coupon&quot; we had it still came to about 45.00 which I dont mind at all paying for good food as I am a firm believer that you get what you pay for but in this case it was absolutley not true! Shrimp were like eating breaded bouncy-balls,Fish was the same as deep-fried scour-pads and the crabs leg would rather be bent into a pretzel-shape rather than break(A sure sign of the old/stale crustacean delight).The tarter sauce was so old/yellow that it resembled molded mustard and by &quot;Aged&quot; prime rib they must have meant it was put in a jerky dehydrator for 2 weeks before being served.My family owns a hotel in south myrtle beach so we go there to visit several times a year and more &quot;Local&quot; than &quot;Tourists&quot; This is ABSOLUTLEY the WORST place I have eaten in my life (No,I&apos;m not exaggerating in the least) The restroom resembled a sewer plant (You get the visual)..BEWARE!! If your Even MINUTELY Considering this hole..DONT!! I am not here to bash the &quot;Establishment&quot;, Soley to warn fellow diners about this place as I wish I had taken the time to do some research myself first as this certainly made a &quot;Lasting Impression&quot; On us...TURN BACK NOW!!!
 Knoxville, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:03-09-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My husband and I first ate at the Giant Crab in early February of 2006 and were very pleased with the food. We found some unusual things on the buffet--caramel custard! Very nice!--and the crab legs were terrific. My husband, not a seafood lover, stuck to the beef, pork and pasta offerings and didn&apos;t find ANYTHING to complain about. We were looking forward to enjoying another great meal there during our stay in Myrtle Beach this year...and eagerly awaited the restaurant&apos;s season opening on February 8. We were actually the first customers to be seated, our very polite waitress delivered our drinks, and my husband headed for the food...where he was met by the manager (owner?) who told him that our dinners were on the house as we were the first customers and might bring him luck for the season. The food, once again, was delicious and the desserts were fantastic...especially a scrumptious Greek goody with custard, crispy things, nuts and honey...even better than baklava! I have no recollection of what the meal cost last year, but it wasn&apos;t enough to frighten us away from eating there again. Get over it people... restaurant food costs money!
 Champaign, Illinois 
 
 
Posted:02-23-2007

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The Giant Crab had reopened at the beginning of February,2007 after renovations and my family and I dined there the first night they reopened. We were very unhappy to say the least. To start the price of $ 21.99 per person was quite extavagant. The food was overcooked. Not being a large seafood eater they did have other items on the menu such as chicken tenters, etc. These items were also overcooked to the point of being hard. There was nothing special about the ingredients for the salad. The fresh cooked Alfredo was excellent.
 Smithtown, New York 
 
 
Posted:11-26-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My in-laws come here from Virginia and once again we enjoyed everything about the Giant Crab. Only down side was we didnt go for Thanksgiving. We wish continued success to &quot;Tommy Crab&quot; and hope for another visit.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-09-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I have to say that the only reason we went to this restaurant was because we had the &quot;buy 1 get 1 free buffet&quot; coupon. First complaint was that we arrived at the restaurant within an hour of it opening and the food temps were already COLD!!! I got stuffed mushrooms from the buffet that were actually so cold that they had already congealed on the bottom. The food was horrible!! I have to say that the restaurant appeared clean as well as the waitress was very nice. BUT, the added in 10% gratuity is a bit much considering all the waitress does is hand you a drink and drop in once for a possible refill. I think it&apos;s a &quot;tourist scam&quot; and I NEVER plan to go back again. I think that we could&apos;ve went 2 doors down to McDonald&apos;s&amp;bought 2 happy meals and been better satisfied with the food received!!! I plan to tell everyone that I know NOT to go to this buffet. As well as, it had the usual &quot;time-share&quot; groupies at the door to get you on the way out. NOT A FUN TIME @ THE GIANT CRAB!!!!!
 Castle Hayne, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-08-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Good thing everyone is entitled to their own opinions.If we had never dined here before and we had read these &quot;other&quot; opinions we would hav gone somewhere else.
We eat at the &quot;Crab&quot;-&quot;Who Let The Crab Out&quot; every Aug with visitors from LI,NY who absolutely LOVE Tommy Crab...(He&apos;s soooo cute) and every Thanksgiving with in-laws from Virginia who prefer GC to Original Benjamins...saying...it&apos;s better at the Crab.
Can&apos;t wait for Turkey Day...so glad the owner runs this place like he does...everything tastes so memorable...already tasting the stuffed grape leaves (my fav)...God Bless all and welcome to the Giant Crab and all it&apos;s goodness.
A faithful customer and Family.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-24-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I think the food in myrtle beach restaurants is over all above average, I didn&apos;t find the Giant Crab to be any different. I have been a handful of times over the last 4 years, service has ranged from excellent to average, I like the nautical atmosphere that it shares with every other seafood restaurant, it has never been overly noisy and I have never waited more than five minutes to be seated. I don&apos;t feel it is cheap, but given the selection and the competition, I feel it was about average. I am sure some nights are better than others, and I have to believe some of these reviewers have been like some I have sat beside, who expect the wait staff to bring them things from the buffet because they were too stupid to see it, or too lazy to get it. A bus load of senior citizens takes a while to get seated, that isn&apos;t the restaurant&apos;s fault.
This isn&apos;t the best restaurant I have ever been to, but it is far from the worst. If you are a big eater, you get your money&apos;s worth, if you pick and play with your food, you won&apos;t. I have been a repeat customer, and I will be returning soon.
 Blounts Creek, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-12-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I haven&apos;t actually eaten at the Giant Crab but I am planning to now. All you can eat anything is hard to go past, but all you can eat giant crab legs is unbeatable. And the ice-cream at the dessert bar sounds good too.
 Adelaide, SA 
 
 
Posted:09-01-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We go to the Giant Crab every year and love it. The greeter is a real treat. They cant be paying him enough. They treated my son like a king on his sixth birthday (6-29-06) with about 15 of the staff coming to the table to sing to him. We will always go back and have wonderful memories there. Price be damned! The food is good as well as the service..
 Wheeling, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:09-01-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Went there between Christmas and Newyears (2005/2006). Worst Seafood we ever had, Overpriced for what you get, slow waitstaff - NEVER AGAIN!
 Winston-salem, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-21-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate here once! Never again. We only tried it because it was a little cheaper than the place we usually go (Benjamins). We will stick w/ Benjamin&apos;s thank you! Food was nasty, and we asked to sit by the water and were told no! Was wasted money. Not a great experience.
 Cosby, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:08-10-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Our family of 8 made the decision to try this resteraunt based on the reviews read via internet and t.v. (advertising dollars are working), however we were sorely dissapointed. The level of dissapointment was brought on first by the sticker shock, then by the quality of the food. Although the service and number of choices were a delightful surprise, our dissapointment grew as we ate through several of the buffet items. The Mahi Mahi had the most taste as it was covered with pepper, followed by the crab legs. Although I enjoyed these two selections, given the fact that there were over 150 items and there were only two that were tastey does not rate this restaurant very highly on the quality of food selection. I felt bad for my family as they did not partake in the crab legs, but paid for it in the $22 a plate price. We were actually told by a very accomodating manager that the food was purposefuly made bland for their northern visitors. Southerners be warned, this is not a buffet for the south!
 Hickory, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:08-08-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Reading the reviews it is hard to believe someone could think this was a good place to eat. I would have rather eaten the residue off my shoe. Food was terrible even for a buffet (which I should have known better .... I hate them). I echo that the prices were not posted. Had I known, I would have turned around. OVERPRICED!!!! Never again!
 Findlay, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:07-31-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The worst restaurant on the Grand Strand. To get to the buffet you must get past a wave of people coming in the door from the buses which stop right in front of the door. This is a very over priced restaurant. Will not go there again or recommend it to anyone. The food was at best below average. A place that caters to tourists.
 North Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-24-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family and myself have traveled to Myrtle Beach multiple times but have never visited the Giant Crab until this trip. We had a party of 6 and were all greatly disappointed. As far as the price, we understand the cost of seafood being my husband is a chef but you should get what you are paying for. The food was awful!! I wouldn&apos;t recommed this place to anyone. If anyone is back in Myrtle the best place for a seafood buffet that we have found is only a couple of doors down. If anyone from the Giant Crab would like to see how a good buffet works they should also take the trip. This was the worst money we have every spent!!
 Westerville, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:07-06-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This being our first time at Myrtle Beach my wife and I wanted seafood one night during our vacation. We made the mistake of choosing the &quot;Giant Crab&quot;. As a previous person wrote.. the big crab out front should have been a warning. The food all taste the same- BLAND! The Tuna was horrible, The crab was below average. I consider myself to have excellent taste in seafood. This place would not make my top 100 list. The atmosphere was chaotic, almost tense and the bathrooms... (without me getting too graphic) were disgusting.

I saw a woman (and family of SIX) two tables across from me complaining to the waitress when the bill was given to her, she was very animated and angry. I thought to myself, &quot;It&apos;s a buffet, how much could this cost?&quot; Then I got MY bill. $59 for two people!!! That&apos;s not including the tip! My wife&apos;s exact words to me were &quot;Never Again&quot;. This experience has left us very apprehensive about eating out again on vacation. I thought, &quot;If this place is a tourist trap, what are the chances that we&apos;ll get scammed again?&quot; Giant Crab left a bad taste in our mouths.
 Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:06-27-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My family visited Myrtle Beach for the first time in 2003... My husband normally hates buffets, but the group we were vacationing with decided we wanted to give this place a try, so my husband consented...Food seemed processed, the restaurant was very crowded and chaotic...But the worst part was when a &quot;fresh batch&quot; of crab legs was brought out to the buffet and my husband filled his plate - only to find a used BLUE BANDAGE lying on his plate when he picked up one of the last crab legs on his plate!! From talking to staff, it appears the blue bandage indicated it was from the staff at the restaurant vs. a customer &quot;planting&quot; one in an attempt to get a free meal...Needless to say we were given our meal for free ($300+ for 8 people) but will never visit the Giant Crab or any buffet again!!
 Mannington, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:06-18-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I love the Giant Crab ! It is like a tradition for my dad and I to eat crab legs every year on vacation.The first time we visited The Giant Crab , our whole family came and considering that only two of us like crab legs it was pretty expensive. Now just my dad and I come and we love it! We are always seated quickly and the service is always good. It is typical buffet food, but the all you can eat crab legs are great!
 Barboursville, West Virginia 
 
 
Posted:05-15-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Are people really believing that a $58.00 dinner for two people is expensive? Maybe because I&apos;m from CT, but for seafood (and all you can eat!) that is extremely reasonable! Besides, if you&apos;re on vacation, who cares! In my opinion, if you&apos;re gonna do buffet food, accept that it&apos;s buffet food and not some five star restaurant. I go for the atmosphere, the drinks, and a chance to laugh at the cranky vacationers who think they can feed an entire family for under 50 bucks!
 New Haven, Colorado 
 
 
Posted:04-17-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Absolutely horrible....that&apos;s all I can say. Please do yourself and your family a favor by not eating at the Giant Crab. My family and I just returned from Myrtle Beach and we ate at the Giant Crab on our last night in town.

It appears that my biggest mistake was not reading these reviews before we ate there.

The food was very poor... by far the worst we had during our week-long stay (dry and/or overbreaded fish and flavorless crab legs)....all adding up to the biggest bill we had while eating out in Myrtle Beach! Also, like previous posters had mentioned, we were practically chased to our car by a lady selling time-shares.... by the time I got to my car, I was hoping I would never have to see the Giant Crab again!

Don&apos;t make the same mistake we made... the large crab on the outside of the building should have been warning enough...this place is a tourist trap!
 Knoxville, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:03-27-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: Food and service was decent, but price was pretty high ($55 for two people with no alcohol). I didn&apos;t appreciate getting accosted in the parking lot for a time share (or whatever the lady was shilling).
 Fuquay Varina, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:01-24-2006

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My Bloody Caesar was awesome...should have stuck to the drinks....got extrememly sick and only had crab legs.....not worth the price, but the bartender was very cordial.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:11-13-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The worse restaurant we have ever eaten at. We had a half off coupon and our bill still came to $33.00 for two people, when they automatically added a tip and soft drinks are $2.00 each. The selection was poor, the food was cold, the hush puppies were like little marbles. Everything seemed to be left over from the day before. I would never eat there again or recommend it to anyone. The best thing on the bar was the jello! We have made several trips to Myrtle Beach and have always wanted to try one of the seafood buffets...never again.
 Dayton, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:10-23-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We dined at this facility on October 17, I have never been so disappointed with a buffet in my life. FIrst of all their were no signs informing customers of the meal price. So we figured it had to be a reasonable price because who wants to go on vacation and be ripped off.

Then the food, well, my children are not seafood eaters, so we they went straight for the kids bar, boy was that a mistake. My oldest son is a pizza freak, and he said that was the driest pizza he had ever eaten. My youngest son likes meat, so he went for the hot dogs, but I was afraid for him to eat it, because of the dark coloring, it looked as if it had been on the bar for a couple of days. The mac and cheese was a joke, crusty and dry.

The dessert bar, well, the only good thing was the ice cream.

Then came the shock, the BILL. We had a buy one get one free coupon and the bill was still $59.00, huge rip off. I ask the so called waitress about the bill, and she was rude, she informed us there was a 10% gratuity because we had a coupon, so the tip was $7.65. How can they justify giving a discount coupon when they turn around and add a huge tip on the bill which makes the coupon worthless. Not to mention the fact that the waitress didn&apos;t earn a tip, one refill on drinks, and I asked for straws twice and only got 2 straws when I needed 4. This place is a huge rip off. I even emailed the customer service of the restaurant and I am still awaiting to hear back from them.
 Wildwood, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:10-21-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: What a disappointment. The food, the atmosphere, the service all left something to be desired. Having just eaten the night before at the competitor next door, we were so let down by this restaurant&apos;s poor food quality and less than pleasant atmosphere. Some of the food tasted like it came straight from the freezer and micorwaved. The cost was too high and the server only came twice to the table. We won&apos;t return.
 Sevierville, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:10-12-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We had dinner at the Gian Crab on our first evening in Myrtle Beach. The place had not changed since our last visit a while back, and I had forgotten why it is not our favorite place for dinner. The food was average, and the crab legs were not very good at all. Service was OK, though, and the price was not horrible (approx 45 bucks for two adults). I now remember why it is not our favorite place for dinner,
 Groton, N 
 
 
Posted:09-23-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I think that the Giant Crab Restaurant is a great place to eat. Very clean but a little pricey; but totally worth it.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:09-19-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: I was shocked by the poor reviews of the Giant Crab. My family and I ate there twice during our stay in the Myrtle Beach area. We loved it both times.

The food was excellent, I didn&apos;t think anything was heavily breaded at the time we ate there. The crab legs were hot, fresh, and plentiful.

We used coupons and, although I don&apos;t remember the exact price, I do recall that it was less than most of the other places we dined.

I can&apos;t wait to go back on our next vacation. The desserts alone were worth the price. They are to die for! My kids got plenty to eat from the children&apos;s buffet area, as well. It was refilled constantly.

We chose to have our dinner on the early side, around 5:00, so that may have made a difference.

My only complaint would be the condo solicitors in the parking lot that tried to hook us into a condo tour. I don&apos;t think the Giant Crab should allow that, but we blew them off and kept walking.
 Richmond, Michigan 
 
 
Posted:09-15-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My boyfriend and I ate there on our last night in Myrtle Beach.

We recommend this place highly. The buffet was unbelievable and the crab legs were in plenty, My boyfriend was into oysters although he didn&apos;t like those as much, he certainly enjoyed everything else and was able to even get a Pittsburgh Beer on draft.

The atmosphere was great, and the wait staff was wonderful, we had such great service I had too many sweet teas on my table.

We used a coupon and it was the same price as the smaller and less appetizing Calabash seafood place.

You get more for your buck at the Giant Crab!
 South Park, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:09-10-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: No prices posted. There was not 120 items as advertised on the internet. They advertise pork chops, cakes, etc which were not there. We were seated immediately with no prices posted anywhere. The waitress brought one refill on our pop. We were never asked about the food or checked on. $21.95 was the biggest ripoff and I think they should have to post it somewhere. The atmosphere was not great either. I couldn&apos;t even say the salad dressings were outstanding. There is nothing memorable about this place but an $85 bill with soft drinks only and nothing outstanding to eat. Worst buffet we ever went to. Beware!!
 Iberia, Ohio 
 
 
Posted:08-24-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food was delicious. There was so much to pick from. I am handicapped and the people there were so nice helping me to my table. I came with a tour group out of Louisville, KY and everyone was talking about how good the food was and the service was great.
 Frankfort, Kentucky 
 
 
Posted:08-17-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate there last year. My parents and I had really great drinks but that was about it. The Food was horrible. So full of breading and so lacking individual taste. I will never eat there again. I am from Maryland and I grew up on seafood and let me tell you that whatever was being served there at the giant crab was NOT seafood. I recommend someplace that is a seafood buffet and not A SEAFOOD FLAVORED BREAD BUFFET! Spare yourselves from the epitome of bad food.
 Bryantown, Maryland 
 
 
Posted:08-13-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food here - mediocre at best - it IS a huge buffet so I dont expect huge varied portions to be churned out with great attention - but there was a brackish blandness to everything. It is quite a zoo - lots of disorganized foot traffic to and from the buffet - expect to hear a few collisions and dropping plates of food while you are there. The crab legs are rather sad - soggy on restock - difficult to manage - you shouldnt have to peel them. The stack of clean plates by the buffet often had unidentifiable globs on them. Expect a solid reaming for this divine experience as well - we fed 6 adults who had reactions of dissapointment to mediocre acceptance for $160 - soft drinks only. You&apos;d serve yourself far better elsewhere.

~SecretSquirril
 Valhalla, NO 
 
 
Posted:07-26-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My husband and I wanted to eat seafood for our last night in Myrtle Beach. We thought going to a seafood buffet was a good idea. The food was average but not worth the price. Our total bill was $56.87 for two people at a buffet. Buffets usually provide values for meals but not here.We asked the hostess if the prices for the buffet were visible anywhere. She got defensive and stated that they don&apos;t have to display how much it costs, it isn&apos;t in their policy to say how much it costs, and you have to ask to find out. It&apos;s a clever scam. We will never go back to this establishment again.
 Albany, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:07-18-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We just got back from vacation and I have a story for all of my friends here at home. We went to the Giant Crab and were totally ripped off. My kids hated it and I was furious when i got the bill. I called the manager but it did not do any good. I just wish I had read these reviews before we ate there. I was tempted to stand outside and warn everyone... Don&apos;t eat there!!!!!!!!!!!!!
 Benton, Tennessee 
 
 
Posted:07-14-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: My 5 yr. old, who had only a hotdog, cost $10.95 for the kid&apos;s buffet. There is supposed to be a &quot;kid-friendly&quot; buffet area, but the food there was not being replenished, as was the adult area. If you do not like seafood, there was a wonderful pasta bar, with a chef to cook it to your liking.
 Titusville, Pennsylvania 
 
 
Posted:07-09-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate here one time and that was enough. Food was awful, credit card bill was incorrect. We won&apos;t go back.
 Lexington, Kentucky 
 
 
Posted:07-05-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We had dinner here in November, very expensive for what you get. The food was cold and bad. Don&apos;t waste your money or time.
 Berkley, Michigan 
 
 
Posted:07-05-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is one of the finest restraunts I have been to. The price is actually $22 and not $28. You definitely get more for your money and they also have many coupons that are available. The service is excellent and I would love to come back again.
 Myrtle Beach, South Carolina 
 
 
Posted:07-02-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: We ate here last summer, and were very disappointed. The price was $28 per person, and there was hardly any food on the buffet. Our drinks were watered down and there were far too few waitstaff to go around. Beware of this place!
 High Point, North Carolina 
 
 
Posted:06-23-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: The food is good, but the price is far too high!
 Augusta, Georgia 
 
 
Posted:06-04-2005

 Food: Service: Atmosphere: Value: Seating: Noise: 
 Review: This is another in the long line of buffet restaurants in Myrtle Beach. The food is average, the service is average and the price is a bit high. Nothing about it makes it particularily stand out - good or bad.
 Marion, North Carolina 
 
 Write a Review | Submit a Photo 

 


 

 FAQs 

 RESTAURANT
VIDEOS 

 WIRELESS INTERNET 

 SURVEYS, POLLS
&amp;RESULTS 

 EDITORS
TABLE 

 
WEB SITE STATISTICS 

 ABOUT OUR COMPANY&amp;THIS SITE 



 
 Site Map | Terms&amp;Conditions of Use | Privacy Policy | About Us |1999-2012 Reproduction prohibited.
	</body>
</document>
