<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006622" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/s/CA/LaQuinta/ChineseRestaurants?cs_category=Chinese+Restaurants" time="2012-07-12-23:34" support="1" score="0.0015694100944160007" bingtitle="La Quinta Chinese Restaurants - Insider Pages - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="La Quinta Chinese Restaurants">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>&quot;Tsing Tao is a nice clean little restaurant in a modest storefront. They have tablecloths, linen napkins, and ... typical California low-budget Chinese fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 

 

 

 

 1-10 of 25 
Chinese Restaurants - La Quinta, CA
 
 Distance Within City Within 1 mile Within 2 miles Within 5 miles Within 10 miles Within 20 miles Sort by highest rated first alphabetical order most reviewed first closest first best match 
 ★★★★★ 4 Reviews 
 Soul Of China 
 50855 Washington St # 2f, La Quinta, CA 
&quot;The food there is top knotch. It&apos;s great. It has a lot of flavor. They make you feel like you are eating in China by the way they ...&quot;
 ★★★★★ 3 Reviews 
 Fong Lam Chinese Restaurant 
 49707 Harrison St, Coachella, CA 
&quot;really good i cant get enough of it nice girls awesome service&quot;
 ★★★★☆ 3 Reviews 
 City Wok 
 74970 Country Club Dr # 450, Palm Desert, CA 
&quot;City wok is a fun, delicious dining experience. Sit at the bar if you want to watch them feverishly prepare your stir fry. The food is always cooked ...&quot;
 ★★★★★ 2 Reviews 
 Mulan Chinese Restaurant 
 82005 Us Highway 111, Indio, CA 
&quot;Nice place with great menu. Service is okay. Waiting time can improve. I&apos;ve invited family and friends over and we&apos;ve always had a great time.&quot;
 ★★★★☆ 2 Reviews 
 China Wok 
 77912 Country Club Dr # 31, Palm Desert, CA 
&quot;Since I discoverd China Wok a week ago, I have eaten there four times! The food is great! The Hot and Sour Soup was very distintive and good. ...&quot;
 ★★★☆☆ 3 Reviews 
 Tsing Tao Chinese Cuisine 
 74040 Highway 111 # E, Palm Desert, CA 
&quot;Tsing Tao is a nice clean little restaurant in a modest storefront. They have tablecloths, linen napkins, and pleasant service. This is definately an upscale place, compared to ...&quot;
 ★★★☆☆ 1 Review 
 Li Li&apos;s Chinese Restaurant 
 40100 Washington St # 141, Indio, CA 
&quot;Li Li&apos;s has just average quality Chinese Food at low prices. There are some basic tables and chairs for eat-in, but most of the business is take out. ...&quot;
 ★★☆☆☆ 1 Review 
 China Jo&apos;s 
 78550 Highway 111, La Quinta, CA 
&quot;This place is just a typical California low-budget Chinese fast food restaurant. The food is only passible. The prices are low. (About $6 for a plate of food.) ...&quot;
 
 mulan 
 Indio, CA 
 Dragon Gate 
 44491 Town Center Way # E, Palm Desert, CA Page: 1 2 3 next Add a New Business Report Duplicates View Larger Map 
Related La Quinta, CA searches
 
 Food Catering Companies Restaurants Asian Restaurants 
 Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
