<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006276" url="http://mommypoppins.com/ny-kids/can-fast-food-be-part-of-a-healthy-pregnancy-diet" time="2012-07-12-22:57" support="4" score="0.015185209607717607" bingtitle="Can Fast Food Be Part of A Healthy Pregnancy Diet? | Mommy Poppins ..." webtitle="Can Fast Food Be Part of A Healthy Pregnancy Diet? | Mommy Poppins - Things to Do in NYC with Kids">
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>But there are some healthier picks at the chain restaurants. Here&apos;s ... and unfortunately, those amounts won’t be listed on the menu board. But nearly all fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		NYC NJ LI CT Boston LA 
 
 Travel 
 Mommy Poppins - Things to Do in NYC with Kids 
 advertise submit an event contact 
 
 Baby Preschoolers Kids Tweens 
 
 Manhattan 
 Uptown Downtown 
 Brooklyn Queens Bronx Staten Island Hudson Valley Long Island New Jersey 
 Follow me on twitter Friend on facebook Subscribe to this feed 
 Classes Camps 
 Day Camps Sleep Away Camps 
 Preschools Indoor Parties Parks Museums Visitors Things to do 
 Winter Spring Summer Fall Halloween Holiday Farms Water Fun 
 Day Trips Event Calendar 
 
 Free&amp;Fun Things to Do This Weekend for NYC Kids: City of Water Day, Come Out... New York City Kids Summer Activities Guide This Week: New Public Pools, Pay for the Day Private Pools, Free Summer Play Streets New Pier 2 Pop-Up Pool in Brooklyn Bridge Park: What to Know Before You Go Free Summer Play Streets Programs: No-Cost Sports, Arts and More for NYC Kids Horseback Riding: Top Picks for Horseback Riding in NYC A-Maze-Ing Water at the New York Aquarium: Water Conservation Made Fun for NYC Kids News: New Literacy Screening Program, Is Your Child Spoiled, Playgrounds for Adults,... Things to Do in McCarren Park with Kids Potted Potter: The Harry Potter Parody Keeps Muggles in Stitches Pay for the Day: Best Private New York City Swimming Pools Brooklyn Kids Shoe Stores: Where to Buy Children&apos;s Shoes in NYC This Week: Ways to Cool Off, More Fireworks, Playgrounds with Shade, Summer Museum Ex... What&quot;Obamacare&quot;Could Mean For You and Your Family 
 
Free Things To Do in NYC
 
A free activity for every day of the summer.
 
Read our guide:
 


 Follow me on twitter Friend on facebook Subscribe to this feed 
 
Recent Comments
 
We&apos;ve been featured:
 
 
 
Can Fast Food Be Part of A Healthy Pregnancy Diet?
 Jun 11 2009 
 mommy&apos;s blog 
 By mommy 
 

 You’re pregnant, nauseous, working on a deadline, and oh-yeah, trying to cut back on food costs in the middle of a recession. You know that you’re supposed to be eating really healthy right now, but lack of time and energy, and the need to save cash have been pushing you towards some not-so-healthy food sources lately. Plus, hangover food seems to be the only thing that calms your morning sickness. All is not lost! Our guest poster, Frances Largeman-Roth, and author of the  new book, Feed the Belly: The Pregnant Mom&apos;s Healthy Eating Guide , will show you how you can actually eat on the run without breaking too many nutrition rules. Hey, these are tips that we can all use, whether we&apos;re pregnant or not. Thanks, Frances! 

 

It’s always healthiest to make your own food. That way you’re in charge of how much fat, sodium, and preservatives are involved. But there are some healthier picks at the chain restaurants. Here&apos;s the skinny on avoiding the fat (and other bad stuff) at the top fast food chains, what to order and what to avoid, for a healthier diet during pregnancy:

 

1. Downsize : Fast food is probably the only arena where this word is still welcome. As tempting as all the deals are right now, never go for the up-sell. You don’t need the biggie fries or drink—even if they seem like a good deal. Stick with the small. And hey, to satisfy an occasional salty craving, a small McDonald’s fry is a virtual calorie bargain at TK calories.

 

2. Skip the sauce : Most fast food places offer salads these days, but the croutons and the dressing can turn your greens into a sodium nightmare. Drop the croutons and only use half of the dressing to keep those veggies on the virtuous side.

 

3. Know your numbers : New Yorkers are lucky in the sense that all fast food chains must post the calorie info for every menu item, but it’s often not the whole story. The 450 calories in Au Bon Pain’s Egg and Cheddar Salsa Verde Sandwich aren’t too steep for an expectant mamma (you need 300 extra calories a day in the second and third trimesters), but the 12 grams of saturated fat and 1080 milligrams (about½of your limit for the whole day) of sodium aren’t doing you any favors, and unfortunately, those amounts won’t be listed on the menu board. But nearly all fast food places list their nutrition info online these days, and much to their credit, Au Bon Pain has nutrition kiosks in many of their locations. And they also offer better options like a regular old egg on a bagel, which has only 360 calories, 1 grams of saturated fat, and a reasonable 780 mg of sodium.

 

4. Go halfsies : If you’re craving a Big Mac or a colossal sandwich on focaccia, go for it. But to cut down on the sodium impact, lose half the bread. I don’t have anything against carbs; it’s just that bread (and anything bread-like) that has any flavor is loaded up with sodium. Skip half of it and you’ll considerably lower how much salt you’re getting, with the added bonus of shaving off a few hundred empty calories.

 

 SMARTER GRAB AND GOS 

 McDonald’s: 

 Egg McMuffin (order it without the Canadian-style bacon and the liquid margarine and you’ll save on sodium and fat):
300 calories, 12 g fat (5 g saturated), 260 mg cholesterol, 820 mg sodium, 18g protein, 160 mg calcium, 2 mg iron 

 Fruit’n’Yogurt Parfait with Granola 
160 calories, 2 g fat (1 g saturated), 5 mg cholesterol, 85 mg cholesterol, 4 g protein, 130 mg calcium 

 

 Wendy’s: 

 Grilled Chicken Go Wrap
2 60 calories, 11 g fat (3.5 g saturated), 45 mg cholesterol, 760 mg cholesterol, 17 g protein 

 

 Burger King: 

 Whopper Junior without mayo (BK does offer veggie burgers, but they’re actually higher in calories and sodium, which is a bummer)
290 calories, 12 g fat (4.5 saturated, 0.5 trans), 35 mg cholesterol, 500 mg sodium, 2 g fiber, 16 g protein, 3.6 mg iron 

 

 Chipotle:
 Go for a burrito bowl instead of a regular burrito and you’ll cut 330 calories right off the bat. Load up on the fajita veggies, lean meat and beans, and then top with either the sour cream or cheese. 

 

 Starbucks and Jamba Juice: 

Both of these chains have gone back to basics and are offering oatmeal for breakfast. A package from a box is going to be much cheaper, but if you ran out of the house with nothing more than your purse, hit up one of these places for some nutritious, whole grain oats, and you can feel good about what you’re feeding your belly with.

 

For more information on pregnancy nutrition, plus yummy recipes, check out www.feedthebellybook.com .

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
 Tags:
 Baby Books Food Healthy Kids 
 
 mommy&apos;s blog 
 Print this page 
Similar
 
 Summer Reading List: 5 Great Books for Kids Where to trick or treat in Long Island Find the Free Gelato Truck this Week apple seeds day camp 
 
 &lt;&lt;Previous
 Get Your Game On at Come Out and Play Festival Next&gt;&gt;
	</body>
</document>
