<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006514" url="http://www.ksl.com/?nid=148&amp;sid=955986" time="2012-07-12-23:27" support="1" score="0.00010673424514491328" bingtitle="Eminent Domain Law Bill Being Reviewed | ksl.com" webtitle="Eminent Domain Law Bill Being Reviewed | ksl.com">
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>... has not tipped his hand yet on whether he&apos;ll sign a bill that restores the power of cities to buy your home ... Robbing Peter to pay Paul.&quot; Governor Huntsman hasn&apos;t said if ...</description>
	<body>
		Login    Feedback    Contact Us KSL TV       KSL Newsradio       iWitness    » Utah all of KSL Classifieds Local Web Keyword 
 Utah Page Two U.S. World Sports Weather Traffic Biz Entertainment Shows More 
 
 Deals Local Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds 
 
 Local Stories KSL 5 News Investigations Tough Times Survival Bank Staying Safe Statecraft: Government&amp;Politics Sunday Edition 
 About this ad Eminent Domain Law Bill Being Reviewed   March 5th, 2007 @ 6:00pm 0 Comments Post or read comments Video 
 John Hollenhorst Reporting 
The governor has not tipped his hand yet on whether he&apos;ll sign a bill that restores the power of cities to buy your home, even if you don&apos;t want to sell. The legislation partially reverses a win by angry property owners two years ago.
The legislature undercut the power of eminent domain two years ago. But now they&apos;re bringing back a modified version as tool for urban development.

 
Some Ogden homeowners believe it benefits commercial interests at the property owners&apos; expense.
This collection of modest homes is the neighborhood that stopped Wal-Mart in its tracks a couple of years ago. Some homeowners refused to sell.
Donna Marti, Ogden resident: &quot;I mean it isn&apos;t a new, gorgeous home, but it&apos;s home.&quot;
Evo Marti was literally born in his house 83 years ago.
Evo Marti, Ogden resident: &quot;All our life lived here, raised our kids, and grandkids and great-grandkids. It&apos;s home!&quot;
In that old fight, the city wanted to force the deal, using the power of eminent domain to condemn blighted properties for resale to commercial development.
Mark Johnson, management services director, Ogden: &quot;Increased revenues from property tax and sales tax benefit the entire community.&quot;

 
Wal-Mart eventually threw in the towel. The legislature two years ago banned eminent domain for commercial redevelopment projects. But the new bill brings it back in modified form. A homeowner could be forced to sell if 80 percent of his neighbors say &quot;yes&quot;.
Mark Johnson: &quot;So if there are 10 properties, of those, eight have to sign the petition.&quot;
The legislation sets the stage for a potential battle here where the city eventually expects to take out blighted homes and businesses and build the Ogden River project.
Mark Johnson: &quot;We are trying to rebirth that area, to bring in some new housing projects, some new commercial and some retail.&quot;
A councilman from neighboring North Ogden opposes the new bill.
Steve Huntsman, member, North Ogden City Council: &quot;The minute the government steps over and starts taking property, it affects all of us. I just think that it&apos;s wrong from a constitutional standpoint.&quot;
The Martis say it&apos;s wrong for a city to forcibly buy a property and then resell it to the highest bidder.
Donna Marti: &quot;That&apos;s like stealing. Robbing Peter to pay Paul.&quot;
Governor Huntsman hasn&apos;t said if he&apos;ll sign or veto the bill.
 A spokesman said today he&apos;s still reviewing it.
 Advertisement About this ad About this ad Most Popular 
 Read Video Commented Sports Deseret News 
 
 
 1. Explosion reported at Alpine factory 
 
 2. Woman fights off attacker on jogging trail 
 
 3. Thief steals camera, pictures of ... 
 
 4. Have You Seen This? All for some crackers 
 
 5. Jabari Parker names his &apos;college list&apos;, ... 
 
 
 
 1. Thief steals camera, pictures of ... 
 
 2. Juan Diego athlete dies in accident 
 
 3. Explaining tragedy to your children is ... 
 
 4. High school students learn to fight sex ... 
 
 5. Cougarettes win international dance ... 
 
 
 
 1. Families of both victim and suspect in ... 
 
 2. Thief steals camera, pictures of family&apos;s ... 
 
 3. Matheson votes to repeal Obamacare, joins ... 
 
 4. Viacom blocks online episodes in DirecTV ... 
 
 5. 5 quick and easy ways to save $1,500 per year 
 
 
 
 1. LDS Church issues statement on Mormon ... 
 
 2. State report: Red Butte Creek is now safe ... 
 
 3. Blue roundup: Jabari Parker releases list ... 
 
 4. Sierra Newbold&apos;s family thanks police, ... 
 
 5. Sen. Orrin Hatch calls for end of estate ... 
 
 
 
 1. Jabari Parker names his &apos;college list&apos;, ... 
 
 2. Penn State probe accuses Paterno of ... 
 
 3. Jordan: 1992 Dream Team better than 2012 ... 
 
 4. Juan Diego athlete dies in accident 
 
 5. BYU fan perspective: Chris Hill, Tom ... 
 
 Latest Videos Penn State probe accuses Paterno of cover-up
 Posted 20 minutes ago 
 Tweet/Share High speed chase caught on camera ends with arrest
 Posted Jul 12th - 12:26pm 
 Tweet/Share Jell-O iconic part of Utah culture, cuisine
 Posted Jul 12th - 11:45am 
 Tweet/Share Lightning starts new fire in Tooele County
 Posted Jul 12th - 11:08am 
 Tweet/Share Charges filed against man for sexually abusing grandchildren
 Posted Jul 12th - 10:10am 
 Tweet/Share Debris found in hydrant during apartment fire
 Posted Jul 12th - 8:42am 
 Tweet/Share About this ad Site Index 
 
 News 

 Utah 
 News Investigations Tough Times Survival Bank Staying Safe Statecraft Sunday Edition 


 Page Two 
 Motherhood Matters Happy Living Pic&amp;Flix Science&amp;Innovation Tech&amp;Gadgets Gamer&apos;s Guide Religion Odds&amp;Ends Have you seen this? Video of the Day 

 National World Entertainment Biz/Finance Consumer Sci/Tech Health Education 
 KSL Schools 

 
 Weather 

 Forecasts Current Conditions VORTEX Microcast Water Watch 
 Snowpack totals Ramp reports Lawn Watering guide Flood/Water Flow 
 Photo Galleries Weather Planner Weather Lab Ask the Meteorologist Ski Report Weather on 5.3 


 Traffic 

 Traffic Cams 


 Special Features 

 General Conference Mission Guide 


 Opinion 

 Sunday Edition 
 
 Sports 

 BYU 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Coach&apos;s Show Cougar Tracks My Cougar Stories CougarNation Polls/Rankings 
 U of U 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Crimson Corner Polls/Rankings 
 USU 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Polls/Rankings Blog 
 Jazz/NBA 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Blog 
 RSL 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Blog 
 Prep 
 Schedule / Scoreboard / Standings KSL Coaches Poll 
 NFL Golf Utah Stats/Scores 
 
 Shows 

 Studio 5 KSL Outdoors w/ Adam Eakle Sunday Edition Mormon Times Utah&apos;s Morning News Doug Wright Show The Browser Utah&apos;s Afternoon News Nightside Project KSL Movie Show KSL Outdoors KSL Greenhouse Show Matt Townsend Show KSL Travel Show 


 Classifieds 

 General Homes Cars Utah Jobs Help 


 Movies 

 Movie/Theater Listings 
 
 TV 

 Bios Schedule Contests More on the Web Studio 5 


 Radio 

 Listen LIVE Podcasts Lineup Bios Staff Blog Shows Features 
 Speaking on Biz Teacher Feature Metro Business Reports 
 Contests Events 
 
 Advertise with KSL 


Other Resources

 Contact Us / Phone Numbers Careers with KSL Careers with DDM Web Resources Charity Account Form 


Mobile

 ksl.com mobile text alerts 


Legal

 Terms of Use Privacy Statement DMCA Notice EEO Public File Report DTV Quarterly Activity Closed Captioning Assistance 


Sister Sites

 FM100 / Arrow 103.5 Deseret News Deseret Book 

 
 KSL&apos;s public inspection files, including the Children&apos;s Television Programming Reports and the DTV Quarterly Activity Station Report, are available for viewing during regular office hours at the KSL Broadcast House. ©2012 ksl.com | KSL Broadcasting Salt Lake City UT | Site hosted&amp;managed by Deseret Digital Media - a Deseret Media Company  v22
	</body>
</document>
