<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006021" url="http://www.nypost.com/p/news/opinion/opedcolumnists/fixing_the_wrong_disease_Tl4EcEMX2ZQVU05x6l7GCM" time="2012-07-12-22:42" support="2" score="0.0011118783323056578" bingtitle="Fixing the wrong disease - NYPOST.com - New York News | Gossip ..." webtitle="Fixing the wrong disease - NYPOST.com">
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>As the City Council debates a bill to force ... regulations, including those that award sick pay ... an average franchise business -- typically a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		85° 
 Today&apos;s Paper Newsletters Classifieds 
 Cars&amp;Vehicles Real Estate For Rent Jobs Pets Buy/Sell/Trade Tickets&amp;Events Services Legal Notices 
 Archives Subscribe 
 

 
 PHOTOS VIDEOS BLOGS 
 
 News 
 
 On the mend Coast Guard frees tangled sea turtle in NY Qatari investors buy Valentino 
 
 Page Six 
 Extra beef Has a beef between Channing Tatum and Alex Pettyfer on the set of...  
 Gossip Celeb Photos Cindy Adams 
 
 Sports 
 Dwight&apos;s out The Nets’abysmally long Dwightmare is over. The Nets finally...  
 Teams 
 Yankees Mets Giants Jets Knicks Nets Rangers Devils Red Bulls Tickets 
 High Schools 
 Baseball Boys Basketball Girls Basketball Football Boys Soccer Girls Soccer Softball Volleyball More Sports 
 Scores 
 MLB NFL NBA NHL NCAA Football NCAA Basketball 
 
 
 Entertainment 
 The hot sex text Fifteen-year-old Jessie loves Zumba, biology and classic Disney...  
 TV Movies Fashion Travel 
 
 Home Local 
 Manhattan Brooklyn Queens Bronx Staten Island 
 Business Opinion Columnists 
 Adam Brodsky Peter Brookes John Crudele Steve Cuozzo Fredric U. Dicker Leonard Greene Nicole Gelinas Michael Goodwin Terry Keenan Jennifer Gould Keil Keith J. Kelly Bob McManus Andrea Peyser David Seifman Amir Taheri Lois Weiss George F. Will Arthur Herman Benny Avni Michael A. Walsh John Podhoretz 
 Politics Metro US News World News Real Estate 
 Residential Commercial 
 Weird But True Crime Lottery 
 
 Opinion Editorials Columnists Letters Books Capitol Punishment Send A Letter Delonas Cartoon Ramirez Cartoon 
 
 Story 
 
Fixing the wrong disease

 Bad bills on paid sick leave 

By DIANA FURCHTGOTT-ROTH

 Last Updated: 2:45 AM, November 20, 2009

 Posted: 1:04 AM, November 20, 2009
 Tweet More Print 
As the City Council debates a bill to force employers to offer paid sick leave, Dem ocrats in Congress aim to pass a similar federal law.

Sen. Chris Dodd and Rep. Rosa DeLauro (both D-Conn.) on Tuesday released the Pandemic Protection for Workers, Families, and Businesses Act, which would require all employers with more than 15 workers to give full-time workers seven days of paid sick leave (and part-time employees a pro-rated benefit).

&quot;This isn&apos;t just a workers&apos; rights issue -- it&apos;s a public-health emergency,&quot; Dodd claimed. &quot;Families shouldn&apos;t have to choose between staying healthy and making ends meet.&quot;
 Dodd: Pushing another jobs-killer. 
The New York City bill would force firms with 10 or more employees to offer nine days of paid sick leave a year. Smaller businesses would only have to grant five days.

But with city unemployment rate at almost 9 percent and rising, the added cost of paid sick leave would discourage hiring, lower some workers&apos; wages and cost others with low skills to lose their jobs.

Both bills require paid &quot;sick&quot; time not just when an employee is sick, but also to stay home with sick children (or even take them to the doctor for routine visit), or even to babysit if schools are closed due to the sickness of other kids. The Dodd bill restricts use of sick time to contagious diseases -- but it&apos;s a fair bet that, once Congress hears from breast-cancer patients, HIV/AIDS sufferers and car-accident victims, it would extend the law to cover all sickness.

The Dodd bill is just the latest version of legislation introduced by other Democrats over the years. These bills have never passed Congress for a simple reason: They don&apos;t make sense.

More than three-fourths of workers already have sick leave; those who don&apos;t often hold entry-level jobs that they might lose if the law mandates leave.

There&apos;s also the problem of abuse. The Dodd bill states, &quot;Paid sick time shall be provided upon the oral or written request of a covered employee&quot; without medical certification needed, and would let employers take potential abuse of sick leave into account when considering promotions or raises. Sick workers mean others have to pick up the slack.

Economists such as Harvard&apos;s Alberto Alesina and MIT&apos;s Olivier Blanchard, now International Monetary Fund chief economist, have reached the same conclusion: European labor market regulations, including those that award sick pay, have resulted in higher unemployment because employers substituted labor-saving machines as the cost of low-skill workers went up.

With the US unemployment rate at a 26-year high, this is no time to price American workers out of jobs.

The Labor Department estimates that 77 percent of full-time private-sector workers and 89 percent of state and local government employees have some paid sick leave; still others have access to nonspecific, personal time off -- days they can use for vacation, illness or other purposes. And many employers without formal policies grant leave on a case-by-case basis, to prevent contagion.

Yes, it can be tough for workers without paid leave to stay home when they are ill and for single parents, often mothers in low-wage jobs, to look after sick kids. But it&apos;d be even harder for them to lose their jobs altogether. (In October, 36 percent of the unemployed had been out of work for over six months.)

The International Franchise Association estimates that Dodd&apos;s bill would cost an average franchise business -- typically a fast-food restaurant or motel -- $800 to $1,000 a year for each employee, plus added costs for &quot;temporary staff, additional record-keeping, burdening co-workers with increased workloads or the loss of business due to decreased productivity caused by absent staff.&quot;

Local restaurants, clothing stores and computer-repair shops are just the sort of businesses that might not give sick leave today, and would offer fewer jobs tomorrow if sick leave were mandated. Teen unemployment stands at 27 percent; if Congress passes a sick-leave bill, teenagers and others looking for entry-level jobs will have even more difficulty finding a job.

The real crisis gripping most New Yorkers isn&apos;t swine flu, it&apos;s the economy -- and the fear that jobs will vanish. Lawmakers should drop the idea of mandating sick leave, and instead focus on how to put their constituents back to work.

 Diana Furchtgott-Roth, former chief economist of the US Department of Labor, is a senior fellow at the Hudson Institute. 
 Follow @NYPostOpinion 
 Have a comment on this PostOpinion column? Send it in to LETTERS@NYPOST.COM! 
 
 Comments 
 
Get NEW YORK POST Emails&amp;Alerts
 
By clicking ‘SIGN-UP’ you agree to our Terms of Use &amp; Privacy Policy 
 
 Post Pics 
 Today in Pictures 
 Celebrity photos: July 12, 2012 Allen&amp;Co. retreat Celebrities wearing orange lipstick Manhattanhenge Day in photos: July 11, 2012 
 More in photos 
Click on Each Photo
 
Video
 More in videos 
 News Gossip Sports Weird Entertainment 
 
Post Sections
 
 News :

 Business Opinion Columnists Local News Real Estate 
 
 Sports :

 Columnists Scores Post Tickets 
 
 PageSix :

 Celeb Photos Cindy Adams Page Six Magazine 
 
 Entertainment :

 TV Movies Music 
 
 Classifieds :

 Rentals Jobs Cars Real Estate NY Apartments 
 
 Multimedia :

 Photos Video 
 
 Specials :

 Contests/Sweepstakes 
 
Customer Care

 Contact Us FAQ Today&apos;s Paper Archives Covers Back Issues Reprints Sitemap Help 
 
Subscribe

 Home Delivery iPad Daily Newsletter iPhone Android Kindle E-Edition Mobile RSS 
 
Advertising/Partners

 Media Kit Parade Magazine Coupons 
 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Try searching: 
NEW YORK POST is a registered trademark of NYP Holdings, Inc.

 nypost.com , nypostonline.com , and newyorkpost.com are trademarks of NYP Holdings, Inc.

Copyright 2012 NYP Holdings, Inc. All rights reserved. Privacy | Terms of Use | Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
