<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006899" url="http://lacrossetribune.com/business/march-foreclosure-activity-down-to-near--year-low/article_5045c6c2-acb9-500c-ae42-e7ae5007bd3e.html" time="2012-07-12-23:53" support="1" score="0.0006979892565881803" bingtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low" webtitle="More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Cars more. Cars; RVs, Boats, Motorcycles, etc; Place an Ad ... March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low ... Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscriber Services E-Edition Place an Ad More 
 Photo Reprints Public Notices 2 Weeks Free Magazines RSS Contact Us About Us APPs 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 My Account 
 Edit Profile Subscriptions Logout 
 
 91° Clear 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 92° 70° Saturday 95° 68° Sunday 89° 70° Monday 92° 73° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 Local WI News MN News World National News Strange Police Blotter WI Lottery Restaurant Inspection Business Weather 
 
The Latest
 
 Thousands fall victim to utility payment scam 

MADISON, Wis. (AP) — As much as President Barack Obama wants your vote, he&apos;s not actually offering to pay your monthly bills.
 
 La Crosse man sentenced to 15 years for domestic assault 

A La Crosse man who beat his girlfriend and her friend to the point of permanent injuries was sentenced today to 15 years in prison.
 
Recent

 Thousands fall victim to utility payment scam Fewer people attended Milwaukee&apos;s Summerfest Father charged in 3 daughters&apos; deaths in Wisconsin Father charged in 3 daughters’ deaths in River Falls U of M regents approve beer at TCF Bank Stadium 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 High School Sports College NFL NBA MLB NHL Loggers Outdoors Golf 
 
The Latest
 
 First Chinese-born driver tests in Formula 1 

Ma Qing Hua has become the first Chinese-born driver to test in Formula One, completing 82 laps of the British Grand Prix circuit Thursday at…
 
 Reggie Jackson says he made mistake naming players 

Reggie Jackson says he made a mistake by disparaging specific players in recent remarks.
 
Recent

 Mickelson cuts short holiday to find some form Kite has record-breaking 28 in 9 at US Senior Open Molinari rips up Scottish Open with 1st-round 62 Nike taking Paterno&apos;s name off child care center Legion Juniors execute pair of sweeps 
 
 Opinion 
 Letters to the Editor Editorials Columnists Blogs Submit a letter 
 Obituaries Celebrations 
 Anniversaries Births Birthdays Congratulations Engagements Misc Retirements Thank You Weddings Submission Form 
 Entertainment 
 Local Calendar Comics TV Listings Movie Listings Horoscope Movienews 
 Calendar 
 Submit Event 
 Get It! 
 Newspaper Ads Classifieds Get-It Today Business Directory Coupons Place an Ad Auctions 
 Homes 
 7riversrentals.com Homes for Sale Open Houses Find an Agent 
 Jobs 
 Local Jobs Work for the Newspaper Post Resume 
 Cars 
 Automobiles Motorcycle, Boats, RVs, etc Place an Ad 
 
 
 Home / Business 
 
More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June
 Print Email 2012-07-12T06:59:59Z 2012-07-12T09:04:27Z More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June By ALEX VEIGA lacrossetribune.com 9 hours ago  •  By ALEX VEIGA (0) Comments 
Banks are increasingly placing homes with unpaid mortgages on a countdown that could deliver a swell of new foreclosed properties onto the market by early next year, potentially weighing further on home values.

June provided the latest evidence of this trend, as the number of U.S. homes entering the foreclosure process for the first time increased on an annual basis for the second month in a row, foreclosure listing firm RealtyTrac Inc. said Thursday.

California in particular saw a big spike in foreclosure starts, or homes placed on the foreclosure path for the first time. They increased 18 percent versus June last year, the firm said.

The increase in foreclosure starts comes as banks make up for time lost last year as the mortgage-lending industry grappled with allegations that it had processed foreclosures without verifying documents.

The nation&apos;s biggest mortgage lenders reached a $25 billion settlement in February with state officials. And that&apos;s cleared the way for banks to address their backlog of unpaid mortgages.

Lenders initiated foreclosure on 12 percent of the loans behind in payment in June _ the highest level since the first half of 2009, according to Fitch Ratings.

&quot;These properties that are starting the foreclosure process are mostly homeowners who likely have been missing their payments for a year or more and just now are officially starting the foreclosure process,&quot; said Daren Blomquist, a vice president at RealtyTrac.

That means the latest crop of homes entering the foreclosure process does not signal that there is a fresh wave of homeowners in distress and missing payments.

Still, the increase in foreclosure starts sets the stage for a potential increase in homes sold at a discount via short sale, when the lender agrees to accept less than what is owed on the seller&apos;s mortgage. Others could end up taken back by banks and placed on the market also at a sharp discount.

Either way, short of homeowners obtaining loan modifications or otherwise arranging to exit the foreclosure process, many of these properties could end up adding to the inventory of foreclosed homes on the market, dragging down the values of nearby homes.

Those homes may not hit the market for many months, however.

In the second quarter, it took an average of 378 days for a U.S. home to complete the foreclosure process, or the point when a bank takes over the property, RealtyTrac said. That&apos;s up from an average of 370 days in the first three months of the year and a record going back to the first quarter of 2007, the firm said.

In New York, it took an average of 1,001 days for the foreclosure process to run its course in the second quarter, down from 1,056 days in the first quarter.

Of the homes that entered the foreclosure process in June, those that end up as bank-owned properties would likely hit the market a year from now, Blomquist said.

&quot;However, if they take the short sale route, it may be sooner,&quot; he said.

Short sales take, on average, 319 days to sell from the time they enter foreclosure.

A stronger housing market could mitigate the impact of future foreclosures on home prices, and home sales are expected to end up ahead of last year. But many economists still say the market is years away from a full recovery.

There are some 3 million U.S. homes behind on their mortgages, according to the Mortgage Bankers Association.

An additional 629,000 homes were on banks&apos; books as of June, but not yet sold. That translates into a 15-month supply, at the current pace of sales, according to RealtyTrac.

And nearly 13 million home loans are underwater, or owing more than the house is worth. Those properties could be at higher risk for entering the foreclosure process.

Even so, the backlog in foreclosures that banks are still dealing with has slowed the pace of home repossessions.

RealtyTrac forecasts some 700,000 homes will be repossessed by lenders this year, down from about 1 million last year.
 View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
More Business stories
 
 
 FDA plans database for identifying foodborne germs 
 
 China&apos;s economic slowdown painful despite stimulus 
 
 Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight day 
 
 4 questions for JPMorgan during Friday report 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 lacrossetribune.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
 

 


Hot Jobs

 
Popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 
 1 Police: Man pulls gun in downtown La Crosse 2 Police stand together as charges filed in pursuit that injured officer 3 Police: 13-year-old arrested for attempted homicide in stabbing of brother 4 Hot waters suffocate fish 5 Samuel Laurence Schams 
 
 1 Police stand together as charges filed in pursuit that injured officer (32) 2 Galesville officer on leave after altercation (27) 3 E.J. Dionne Jr.: Obama must tap into national pride to win (18) 4 Kevin Horrigan: Things getting tougher for us global-warming deniers (18) 5 Ed Neumann: World overflowing with holy hardware (16) 
 
Featured Businesses
 
 Westby Cooperative Creamery 
 
 Ship Shape Car Wash 
 
 Traditional Trades 
 
 Kneaded Health Massage and Wellness 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
Latest Local Offers
 
 2007 Chevy Colorado LT 

2007 Chevy Colorado LT. 5 cyl, auto, Tonneau cover. $8,977. Se…
 
 Be Prepared!! 

Get ready for the cold weather and stop in today to check out…
 
 Thursdays Pizza and Pasta 

Pizza and Salad Buffet 11am - 2pm
 
 $10.00 OFF 

Bring in this coupon and receive $10.00 off all over color!
 JOB BOARD 
 
 

 VIEW ADS  &gt; 
 JOBS SENT TO YOUR EMAIL SEARCH ALL ADS
	</body>
</document>
