<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006136" url="http://www.lowsaltfoods.com/food_center/dining_out/best_choices.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:49" support="5" score="0.017600422008401992" bingtitle="Dining Out - Best Menu Choices - Low Salt Foods Your Resource for ..." webtitle="Dining Out - Best Menu Choices">
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>When you are about to order from the menu, do you know which items are ... Condiments Choose au jus, honey mustard, cranberry sauce, fruit relishes and ...</description>
	<body>
		Low Salt Foods.com Raising Sodium Awareness 
 
 
 
   Food Center 
 Basic Info 
 Dining Out 
 Fast Food Quick Reference 
 Best Menu Choices 
 Low Salt Products Product Reviews Recipes Substitutions 
 
 Health Center Reviews Links 
 
 Low-Salt Books from InData Publishing 

 
 Pocket Guide to Low Sodium Foods 
 
2nd Edition
 BUY NOW! 



 
The Hasty Gourmet Low Salt Favorites 
 
 BUY NOW! 
and get a signed copy 


 
 See other products
from InData     
 
   Home &gt; Food Center &gt; Dining Out &gt;Best Menu Choices 
 
   
DINING OUT -
Best Menu Choices
     
 
   
 
 General Selections Asian Cuisine Fast Foods 
   
 French Cuisine Italian Cuisine Mexican Cuisine 
 
           
The most difficult time to control salt consumption is 
 when dining out. Making good nutritional choices can often 
 be difficult, particularly when you don&apos;t know what has been 
 added to the foods you order. For example, a healthy garden 
 salad with low-fat dressing oftentimes has more sodium than 
 a hamburger and french fries. Hard to believe, but what we 
 think is healthy may not be low in sodium.

When you are about to order from the menu, do you know 
 which items are typically lower in sodium? The following are your best choices from appetizers to 
 desserts and by cuisine, including Asian, Mexican and 
 other specialty restaurants.

 General Selections

 Appetizers 
Choose fresh fruits and vegetables, unsalted nuts, dried 
 fruits or banana chips
 Avoid crackers, cheese dips, pates, 
 cocktail sauce and meatballs 

 Cheeses 
Choose Swiss or goat cheese
 Avoid feta, brie and most other 
 cheeses 

 Beverages 
Choose beer, wine, champagne, apple cider, tea, or coffee
 Avoid eggnog, Bloody Marys and Pina 
 Coladas 

 Salads 
Choose tossed greens, carrot/raisin and gelatin salads
 Avoid three-bean and mayo-based salads 

 Salad Dressings 
Choose a vinaigrette or oil and vinegar
 Avoid creamy dressings and Zesty Italian 

 Soups 
 Avoid soups 

 Entrees 
Choose grilled poultry, beef, pork, fish, or dishes without 
 sauces.
 Avoid ham, sausage, breaded or fried dishes, 
 and entrees with creamy sauces. 

 Side Dishes 
Choose vegetables without sauces, candied yams, glazed 
 carrots, applesauce, or mashed potatoes
 Avoid stuffing, rice pilaf and cottage cheese 

 Breads 
Choose matzos or small dinner rolls
 Avoid biscuits, muffins, cornbread, 
 focaccia bread and bread sticks 

 Condiments 
Choose au jus, honey mustard, cranberry sauce, fruit 
 relishes and chutneys, jams and jellies
 Avoid olives, pickles, ketchup, 
 Dijon-type mustards, gravies and most sauces 

 Desserts 
Choose meringue cookies, apple strudel, sponge cake, 
 fruitcake, sherbet, sorbet, custard, or fruit tarts
 Avoid pies, pastries, gingerbread, 
 angel food and frosted cakes 

 Asian Cuisine

 Although 
 full of delicious flavors, Asian cuisine is loaded with 
 sodium. Here are ways to lessen the salt.

 Limit your intake of sauces by 
 using chopsticks and leaving the sauce on the plate. Ask that salt and MSG 
 not be added to your selections, however, many are made 
 with sauces that contain soy sauce which is high is 
 sodium. Request more vegetables be 
 substituted for some of the meat or fish in dishes. Do not add soy sauce to your 
 meal. 

 Best Choices: 

 Bean curd or tofu items Steamed rice Steamed or stir-fried dishes with vegetables Sweet and sour, chili, or garlic sauces (although still high in salt, these have 
 the lowest amounts) 

 Avoid: 

 Soy sauce and MSG Black bean, hoisin, plum, fish and oyster sauces Deep fried or battered dishes (i.e. tempura) Chow mein and lo mein Pickled foods Soups 

 Fast Foods

 Even 
 though the majority of fast foods are high in sodium, most 
 eateries have some lower salt choices.

 Best Choices: 

 Unsalted fries Veggie sandwiches Burgers (remove half the bun, hold the cheese, mayo and pickles) Yogurt or fresh fruit 

 Avoid: 

 Breaded fish and poultry Subs and wraps Salty chips Ketchup with your fries Condiments and cheese Pies or cookies 

 French Cuisine

 If 
 you stay away from creamy entrees and sauces, you can enjoy 
 many French dishes.

 Best Choices: 

 Dishes with wine-based sauces Vinaigrette dressings Sorbet Fresh fruit desserts or tarts 

 Avoid: 

 Creamy sauces (like 
 hollandaise, morney, bechamel, or bernaise) Creamy soups 

 Italian Cuisine

 Many 
 salty dishes have spicy meats or creamy sauces, here are 
 some alternatives.

 Best Choices: 

 Pastas with marinara sauce Pasta/fagoli or marsala dishes Primavera Piccata (hold the capers) Oil and vinegar dressing Italian ices 

 Avoid: 

 Antipasto platters Cheese or cream sauces Adding grated cheese Breads and rolls 

 Mexican Cuisine

 Although 
 heavy in sodium-laden cheeses and sauces, you have many 
 choices to keep your salt in check.

 Request sauces on the side Ask that cheese not be added 
 to your meal Substitute corn tortillas for 
 flour 

 Best Choices: 

 Ceviche Grilled fish or chicken Beef or chicken tacos or tostadas Corn tortillas Fresh salsa or pico de gallo Guacamole Flan 

 Avoid: 

 Salty chips Cheesy dishes, like enchiladas and quesadillas Burritos Beans and rice Chorizo (Mexican sausage) Flour tortillas 
   
 
     
 
 
 This page last updated:08/01/10 
 
   
    InData
 Publishing About Us  l  Contact Us l  Media  l  Site Map  l  Disclaimer  l  Policies l
	</body>
</document>
