<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006731" url="http://www.dailygames.com/games/winter-pedicure.html" time="2012-07-12-23:43" support="2" score="0.007740926602380034" bingtitle="Winter Pedicure - Dailygames.com" webtitle="Winter Pedicure - Dailygames.com">
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>Create the most amazing designs fot your pedicure. You have many colors to pick. Use your mouse and try them all!</description>
	<body>
		yes  
 89.3% no  
 10.7% 

 


 
 Winter Pedicure 
 Girls 
 Description 
 Create the most amazing designs fot your pedicure. You have many colors to pick. Use your mouse and try them all! 
 Related Games Help these twins create their own style and make them look different. Pick their clothes and accessories from the menu on the right. You need to make them look stunning! Use your mouse. 
 
Happy Twins
 Make delicious doughnuts with cream or jam and serve them with coffee or milk before the time runs out. Use the mouse to choose the ingredients. 
 
Johnny Donut
 Help the couple kiss while the teacher is not watching. Keep the mouse clicked to kiss and let go to stop. Get the bar full and don&apos;t let them be caught! 
 
Class Kiss 1
 Follow the directions and make a delicious sandwich. Use your mouse to cut the ham and the veggies, and fry the eggs. Yummy! 
 
Deli Sandwiches
 
 Sweet Potato fries is something served in the US for Thankgiving. Learn how to cook it by following the directions of the game, and then you can even try it at home with your parents&apos; help. Use your mouse. 
 
Sweet Potato Pie
 Help the farmers take care of the watermelons. You gotta get the farm ready, plant the seeds, water them and protect them from the moles. Use your mouse to play. 
 
Happy Watermellon Farm
 Sara has found a new job after getting fired for wasting her time in the office. Help her to complete all her activities in less than three minutes, but watch out with her boss. 
 
office Slacking 3
 Clean u this hotel and make it look amazing before the people get there. Drag the mouse to interact. 
 
Hotel Clean Up
 All rights reserved Copyright©2012 DailyGames.com | Wiju España | Free Online Games
	</body>
</document>
