<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006750" url="http://www.foodservice-index.com/PriceOrder.aspx" time="2012-07-12-23:45" support="3" score="0.02768979084365026" bingtitle="Foodservice Price &amp; Order - Food Service operators in Europe" webtitle="Foodservice Price&amp;Order">
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Price and Order Information. Food Service-Index is a unique and new database supplying you ... P ayment can be done by bank transfer or credit card. Your subscription will end ...</description>
	<body>
		Food Service Europe   
 
 
 
   You are here:  Price&amp;Order       Login   English (United States) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 
 
 Price and Order Information 

 Food Service-Index is a unique and new database supplying you with up-to-date information on food service operators in Europe and some major countries outside Europe. Data is reported in a transparent and easy-to-use way with profiles of all operators and rankings of all sectors and countries. By subscribing to Food Service-Index you will obtain the most recent information throughout the year. Some data are accessible for free (see Portgal under Home&amp;Search) however; full access to the database is restricted to subscribed users. Full sector subscribers will also have access to data on more countries outside Europe without extra charges throughout 2009. Upon request we will supply the key data as an Excel file for your convenience. 
 In addition to the database all subscribers have access to our subscriber service desk for further assistance or information exceeding the database. Veraart-Research makes a continuous research commitment on the data in Retail-Index. 
 
 Full access to all countries and all sectors for 1 year   Euro 1675

 Access to all sectors in one country for 1 year 
 Access to one sector in all countries Euro 300 
 Euro 375 
        ORDER FORM (Pdf) These prices are very low compared to other research sources and certainly cheaper than collecting the data on your own. If you have doubt before ordering full access just order one country as a test. Should you decide to upgrade your access within 2 weeks we will deduct the price of the first invoice.

Order your database access now by completing the order form  which can be printed and faxed to us. Alternatively you can order by sending an email to mail@veraart-research.com   indicating your name, company name, address and phone number . P ayment can be done by bank transfer or credit card. Your subscription will end automatically after one year without any further commitment. 
 Please check our Examples of food service rankings and profiles by selecting Portugal and any sector under Home&amp;Search .     
 
 
 

 
 
   
 
 Examples  /   Price&amp;Order 

 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Home&amp;Search | Examples | Price&amp;Order | Service Desk | F.A.Q. | About Us | Statistics Copyright 2003-2012 Veraart Research Terms Of Use Privacy Statement
	</body>
</document>
