<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006336" url="http://www.dailyspark.com/blog.asp?post=food_on_the_run_are_your_favorites_in_the_healthy_or_unhealthy_top_10" time="2012-07-12-23:02" support="1" score="0.002141976272411034" bingtitle="Food on the Run: Are Your Favorites in the Healthy or Unhealthy ..." webtitle="Food on the Run: Are Your Favorites in the Healthy or Unhealthy Top 10?">
			<query id="000787" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>... to see that many of the top 10 chains are places ... for example, posts calorie counts on the menu board. ... are legit: you can find health food at ANY fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Psst, can you keep a secret? I have a confession ! 
 
 
 Stuff We Love Chef Meg Yoga Restaurants Habits Of Fit People Weight Loss News In The News Motivation Healthy Cooking 
 
 My Trackers 
 Start my Nutrition my Fitness Other Goals SparkStreaks Reports Planner SparkMail my SparkPoints Web Search 
 Healthy Lifestyle 
 Healthy Lifestyle Home Nutrition Fitness Motivation Wellness SparkDiet Lifestyle Centers Videos SparkRecipes.com 
 Health Conditions 
 Health Conditions Home Health A-Z Condition Centers Health News 
 Community 
 Community Home Message Boards SparkTeams SparkPages Blogs Success Stories SparkAmerica 
 
 
 About DailySpark Submit a Story Press Contact 
 
 Email RSS 
 
 
 
Food on the Run: Are Your Favorites in the Healthy or Unhealthy Top 10?
 Tweet Pin It Share on Tumblr 
By: Tanya Jolliffe : 4/20/2009 6:01 AM   271 comments Recently Health Magazine created a list of the 100 largest quick-serve chains in America. &quot;Largest chains&quot; was based on the number of locations throughout the nation. An expert panel consisting of Registered Dietitians, a physician and a certified nutritionist, scored the list of 100. They used criteria such as the use of healthy fats and preparation, sodium content of entrees, availability of nutrition information for the foods served and the inclusion of organic produce to determine a list of the top 10 healthiest chains. A couple Nutrition Health Experts from Men&apos;s Health Eat This Not That review identified America&apos;s unhealthiest restaurants.

Where does your favorite fit?

It was great to see that many of the top 10 chains are places we have already reviewed in our ongoing
	</body>
</document>
