<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006353" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20070626102013AAcfnEP" time="2012-07-12-23:03" support="1" score="0.001642582594574651" bingtitle="Worst food at Disney World? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="Worst food at Disney World? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>... there are over 300 places to eat ... both table service as well as counter service and never found a meal ... Restaurants&quot; which resemble a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Travel &gt; United States &gt; Orlando &gt; Resolved Question 
 Disney Newbie Member since: June 25, 2007 Total points: 87 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Worst food at Disney World?

 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by tweetyma... Member since: April 07, 2006 Total points: 12,338 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Honestly, I have never been disappointed with ANY meal at Disney World.

I have tried many different ones (of couse I haven&apos;t made it to all of them yet, there are over 300 places to eat there!!) 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 50% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (11)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by lilly Member since: May 29, 2007 Total points: 673 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 the first person is SOO wrong! mexico is good! it has nachos, buritos tacos and all! i guess she doesnt like taco bell then! well the worst food is in epcot and thats u.k. DI-SGUS-TING! EWWWW! and their hot dogs arent to great either. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Natterja... Member since: July 10, 2006 Total points: 6,277 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 There are only two places that I have ever been to in Disney where I thought the food was under Disney standards. The USA pavillion in Epcot center was bad when we ate there, which is pretty ironic when you think about it. Also, Cosmic Ray&apos;s Starlight Cafe was not that great, depending on what you ordered. The chicken sandwich was o.k., but the burgers my kids ordered, not so good. Other than that we have eaten at many, many of the Disney restaurants, both table service as well as counter service and never found a meal we didn&apos;t like.

If you want some more info, I would suggest checking out the disboards. The disboards is a message board website that is all about going to Disney. You will find a dining review section, trip reports, resort reviews, and just about anything else you can think of. You can ask questions and get responses back from people who go to Disney often and know what they are talking about. I put the link below.

I hope this helps! 
Source(s):
 http://www.disboards.com 

Disney Vacation Club member 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 25% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Beach Gal Member since: June 13, 2006 Total points: 12,153 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Interesting question. I&apos;m used to answering about the best! The worst food on Walt Disney Property can be found at EPCOT in the U.S.A. Pavilion, ironically. Their food is awful. Someone mentioned Casey&apos;s Corner at the Magic Kingdom as being bad and I disagree! Casey&apos;s has great hot dogs and Polish Sausages!
Be sure to visit http://www.easybreezyplanning.com 
There you can sign up for a free Disney E-newsletter, read up on fun tips and advice, watch fun Disney movie previews, purchase discounted Disney park merchandise and receive assistance with planning your Disney vacation! Have a wonderful trip! 
Source(s):
 Former Disney Cast Member 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by The Doctor 46 Member since: September 25, 2006 Total points: 594 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Umm i don&apos;t know the worst food but i know the best food.

(This is only a list of the places we eat at)

Magic Kingdom®
Casey&apos;s Corner
Pecos Bill Cafe
Columbia Harbor House

Epcot®
There is a place in Germany i don&apos;t know the name but my dad loves it you cant miss it when your in Germany i think its on the right of the fountain.

Disney-MGM Studio&apos;s
ABC Commissary
and then snack on the vendors/McDonald&apos;s Fries.

Disney&apos;s Animal Kingdom®
We usually don&apos;t eat just snack. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by &lt;3 Member since: June 13, 2007 Total points: 4,764 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 definitly not the maxican restraunt in epcot...that was so good!! i think the worst is the food in morrocco in epcot...but the best food is the churros!! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by gingers_... Member since: December 21, 2006 Total points: 364 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Coral Reef hands down. We&apos;ve been to many of the restaurants since Disney World opened in 1971, having visited over 50 times. We were the most disappointed in Coral Reef, it&apos;s a never again restaurant, in our opinion. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 25% 1 Vote by mottthed... Member since: November 30, 2006 Total points: 12,504 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I&apos;m guessing that you&apos;re asking which is the worst food in the parks. While it might be hard to give an exact answer, as sometimes to me, it&apos;s what I pay for what I get. For example, just about any of the fast food places offer the exact same hamburger&amp;fries, etc., for about the same inflated price.

If you go to a character breakfast, the only place that I would not recommend is at the animal park...it&apos;s at the McDonald&apos;s and while it&apos;s all you can eat...it&apos;s pretty much all McDonald&apos;s food. I think the last time we ate there it was around $15 a head for the character breakfast...and there is no way in the world my stomach could stand $15 worth of McDonald&apos;s food.

I agree with one of the other writers, forget the Mexican food at Epcot...no WOW at all. I did enjoy the food at the British&amp;German restaurants however. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by itchiann... Member since: January 14, 2007 Total points: 9,340 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 In all our trips and all the meals we have ordered, we have always been satisfied are well pleased. I have not heard of any problems with food. In regards to the comment about the Animal Park, if they are referring to Animal Kindgom&apos;s character breakfast, there is an option for McDonalds food, but it is only an option. I think all the character breakfast serve basically the same food. We have eaten at most of them and again, always been more than satisfied. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by DCM Member since: January 24, 2006 Total points: 4,288 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Im not sure what your question is. I assume you are asking what is the worst food at Walt disney World? It really depends on what kind of food you are talking about, what type of restaurant, and how picky of an eater you are.

In general, the highest quality foods are served at the table-service restaurants. And of course, the more expensive the more likely you will get a finer dining experience, the Signature Dining restaurants which are Disney&apos;s finest restaurants have the finest food selections.

In the parks, you will find that all the&quot;Quick Service Restaurants&quot;which resemble a fast-food restaurant or food court all have very similar foods which are not of the best quality, many of these&quot;Quick Service&quot;foods are frozen and pre-processed foods such as the hot dogs, turkey legs, burgers, fries, etc.. This is why sometimes people with a sensitive appetite do not fair very well with these foods and can end up with an upset stomach.

Of course you will most likely not be able afford to eat at a table-service restaurant for every meal, but try to balance your meals and do not rely on only&quot;Quick Service&quot;meals as your only food option or you may get an upset stomach. Many of the resorts have gift shops and marketplace-style eateries that serve sandwiches and other grocery-style foods that are much healthier. Many of the parks also have select restaurants that serve healthier food options for health-minded guests, these locations are usually labled with an apple symbol on the park map.

Have Fun! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by maccrew6 Member since: April 05, 2006 Total points: 18,385 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The restaurant in&quot;Mexico&quot;in Epcot.. HORRIBLE!!!!!! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by reds_424 Member since: March 02, 2007 Total points: 875 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I love all the food a disney so there is no worst food

the best food is the turkey legs 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Orlando 

 I&apos;m going to Universal Orlando and Islands of Adventure with my roller coaster junkie mom next week.? Fun stuff to collect while at Disney World? Bad experiences at Disney? What characters appear at Chef Mickey&apos;s? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 What are the best places to eat in DisneyWorld? Where are the best places to eat in Disney World? Best places to eat at disneyworld on dine plan? Best places to eat at Disney World on the meal plan? Where should we eat right outside of Disney World? How do we… 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Travel 
 United States 
 Atlanta Austin Boston Chicago Cincinnati Cleveland Dallas Denver Detroit Honolulu Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Miami New Orleans New York City Orlando Other - United States Philadelphia Phoenix Portland Sacramento San Antonio San Diego San Francisco San Jose Seattle St. Louis Washington, D.C. 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
