<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006164" url="http://www.temeculazone.com/promenade-mall-temecula.html" time="2012-07-12-22:51" support="4" score="0.009333898071313712" bingtitle="Promenade Mall Temecula - Over 140 Shops &amp; 15 Screen Theater" webtitle="Promenade Mall Temecula - Over 140 Shops15 Screen Theater">
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000931" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>... will fix you that perfect cup of coffee and let you get back to your shopping experience. With your cup ... Both Pretzels and Hot Dog offer perfect grab and go food to get ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Wineries Hot air balloon Real Estate Equestrian City of temecula 
 
 business directory restaurants temecula events spas schools hotels 
 
 
 
 
 Temecula Events Temecula Events Temecula Balloon Rides Hot Air Balloon Rides Invention ~ Hot Air Balloon Temecula From The Sky Research And Questions Our Favorite Activity Wine&amp;Balloon Festival The Festival @ Lake Skinner Temecula&apos;s Greatest Fun! A Trip For Everyone What&apos;s The Temecula Hot Air Balloon Festival About? Temecula Hot Air Balloon Festival Old Town Temecula ~ Events The Temecula Rod Run Temecula&apos;s Western Days Temecula Community Theater Temecula&apos;s Farmers Market Temecula Golf Courses Courses For Your Itinerary Great Golfers&apos; Destination&apos;s Temecula Transportation World-Class Limousines Temecula&apos;s Limousine Tours Transportation Options Limo&apos;s For Comfort&amp;Style Traveling In The City In Style Edward&apos;s Movie Theater A Technical Look At IMAX Insight ~ Edwards Theather Ticket And Concession Info Temecula Promenade Mall The Creation Of The Mall Your Shopping Experience Over 140 Shops For You Getting Married At The Mall? Regular Scheduled Events Other Related Links Soccer For All Ages Synchronized Christmas Lights in Murrieta Planing&amp;Budgeting Wedding Temecula Dance Company Pechanga Casino And Resort Area Attractions Temecula Motorsports 
 
 
 
 

Promenade Mall Temecula

The Promenade Mall In Temecula Is A Shoppers Dream!
 With over 140 shops - The Promenade Mall Temecula is here waiting for you.
The Promenade Mall is one of the best two story malls in California, if not in the entire United States.

With over 140 shops and a magnificent 15-screen theater complete with stadium seating, it is the perfect destination for enjoyment.

One of the best draws about the Promenade Mall Temecula is the dining experience. With seven fine dining establishments and 11 quick fix food locations you can find anything your heart desires to munch on while you are shopping, or taking a break.



 

Let’s face it, when you are shopping you need to keep your energy high. Finding the best deals in the mall doesn’t happen with a quick walk through the shops. It takes browsing and careful decisions being made. But when you get hungry, it is difficult to figure out if you are getting a great deal or not.

Need A Caffeine Boost For More Shopping?
If a dose of caffeine is exactly what you need, the solution is simple.
The Promenade Mall Temecula offers a great coffee location that will fix you that perfect cup of coffee and let you get back to your shopping experience.
 With your cup of coffee, you might find yourself wanting a snack to go along with it.
Both Pretzels and Hot Dog offer perfect grab and go food to get you back among the shops. You have over 140 to make it through, so this gives you the perfect chance to eat on the go.

But if it is a short break you need, you can handle some of the recognizable food chains in the Food Court as well. Restaurants here will offer quick and filling food for your lunch break. They are among the eateries you will find during your shopping experience.

As they day moves on, you can continue shopping and enjoying a vast array of stores. Macy’s, JC Penny’s and others will certainly fill your bags with great treasures of stuff that you can only find at the mall.

Looking For Good Quality Food At The Temecula Mall?
 If you’re looking for good quality food but aren’t ready to leave just yet, you can still handle that at the Promenade Mall Temecula. With 7 fine dining facilities, your dinner is served.
You can enjoy the great taste of Mongolian food, or an upscale pizza kitchen. Perhaps Asian inspired food is what your stomach is craving you can get some Chinese food or some sushi.

But if what you really want is some great barbecue, then head on over to the best barbecue smokehouse around.

No matter what you are hungry for, the Promenade Mall offer’s the best shopping and dining experiences in the county.


Next time you are at the mall, check them out one of the several restaurants located outside near the Edward&apos;s 15 Theater.

Be sure to check out the bottom of the Temecula Events Home Pag e for more great links. We have several great topics that would include: Balloon Rides, Limousine Wine Tours, Party Busses, Golf Courses, Edwards Movie Theater and The Promenade Mall. Also, a look at Pechenga Casino, Kids Soccer, Weddings, the Temecula Dance Company and much, much more!


 
Support Local Business In Our

 Temecula On-Line Directory 

Shop Temecula First!




 Return From Promenade Mall Temecula to Temecula Home Page 



 

 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Disclamier | Site Map | Advertise with us | Contact Us All rights Reserved TemeculaZone.com©Copy rights 2011 .
	</body>
</document>
