<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006567" url="http://www.writingyourlife.org/?show=free3" time="2012-07-12-23:29" support="3" score="0.0035018413285485025" bingtitle="321-279-1791 Writing Your Life" webtitle="Writing Your Life —">
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>No TV trays for us today! The roast was still in the ... I feel put upon if I get a lower-end rental car ... the nerve to dress up as a cow and go to the fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home July 12, 2012 
 
 Writing Your Life 
 
 Home Patricia I Can Help Calendar Love to Write Spotlight Photos Cruise Bookstore Contact 
 
Home
 
 Why Write Your Life Story ? 

Funny you should ask, this is why I got started:

 When I was in my twenties, my mother handed me a copy of our family tree that dated back to 1648 when my ancestors came from France to settle in an area known as “Acadie,” now Nova Scotia. “That’s nice,” I replied and put the papers away in a drawer. 

In a move some twenty years later, I came across the yellowed sheets held together by a rusty staple. Looking at the names and tracing the path down to my own name, I now longed to know more about the people whose births, marriages and deaths were listed before me. Unfortunately, by that time, all those who held pieces of our family story were long gone. I missed my opportunity. My ancestors’ stories died with them.

Since then I’ve devoted much time and effort to helping others avoid the mistake I made, assisting them in preserving their stories for themselves and their families.

Through ghostwriting memoirs on behalf of others, co-authoring, editing and teaching, I have assisted hundreds of people in creating a written legacy for their children, grandchildren, great-grandchildren and generations to come. I hold an M.A. in creative writing from the University of Central Florida and a B.A. in journalism from Louisiana State University and have worked as a memoirist, writing coach, editor, writing instructor, journalist and photographer.

Share and Enjoy
 
Comments

 Mabel June Cantley Wilson says: May 29, 2012 at 2:15 pm 
I want to write some stories and try to get them in order.
 Reply Carolyn (&quot; Caroline&quot;) Crawford says: June 18, 2012 at 11:22 am 
This is just what I’ve been looking for.! I look forward to meeting you and being in your classes.
I’ve relocated from Houston and still use my Houston-based cell phone number as well as my Houston billing address so having told you this I hope I clear up any potential confusion.
See you at class.
Caroline
 Reply 
 Patricia says: June 18, 2012 at 3:00 pm 
Hi Carolyn. I’m so glad you found us. We have a great group of people who love to have a good time and write great stories. You’ll fit right in. I’m from South Louisiana, so I’ve spent a good bit of time in Houston. Welcome to Florida.
 Reply 
 Carolyn (&quot; Caroline&quot;) Crawford says: June 24, 2012 at 9:11 am 
I loved your class and look forward to the next one.
Warm regards,
Carolyn (”Caroline”) Crawford
 Reply 
 
 this site says: June 19, 2012 at 4:51 am 
Great article! We are linking to this great article on our site.
Keep up the great writing.
 Reply article says: July 1, 2012 at 3:49 pm 
Hey There. I found your blog using msn. This is an extremely
well written article. I will make sure to bookmark it and return to read
more of your useful information. Thanks for the post.
I’ll certainly comeback.
 Reply vitamin c says: July 11, 2012 at 4:14 pm 
This publication has inspired me to start writing on my own blog
 Reply 
 
Speak Your Mind Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 
 
CLICK ON THE BOOK TO ORDER
 Love to write? Sign up for exciting updates For Email Marketing you can trust 
Calendar of Events
 
 July 19, 2012 9:30 am Third Thursday Writing Workshop July 21, 2012 3:00 pm Patricia on the Growing Bolder Radio Show July 23, 2012 10:00 am Write Your Life Story at Village on the Green July 24, 2012 9:00 am Writing Your Life at Orlando Lutheran Towers 
 AEC v1.0.2 
Mini Calendar
 AEC v1.0.2 
Copyright©2012· Proudly created by Your Cyber Office 
 
 Return to top of page
	</body>
</document>
