<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006243" url="http://amesfanclub.com/forum/index.php?topic=1974.75" time="2012-07-12-22:55" support="1" score="0.000858283212168965" bingtitle="What song always seems to play inside a store" webtitle="What song always seems to play inside a store">
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... of Love&quot; was the song I was looking for, and all I could get out of the Musak at the store ... It&quot; by &quot;Weird Al&quot; Yankovic (fitting because we are in a fast-food restaurant)</description>
	<body>
		July 12, 2012, 02:55:36 PM 
 Welcome, Guest . Please login or register .
Did you miss your activation email? 1 Hour 1 Day 1 Week 1 Month Forever 
 Login with username, password and session length 
 

 News : Under Constructiooooooon   
 
   Home   Forum   Help Arcade Search Gallery Calendar Login Register   
 
 My Community  &gt;  Retail  &gt;  Stores  &gt;  What song always seems to play inside a store 

 Pages: 1 2 3 [ 4 ] «previous next» 
   Print   
 

 Author Topic: What song always seems to play inside a store (Read 6973 times) 
 
 
 
 Mobil Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 468


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #75 on: November 14, 2008, 10:52:35 PM» 
 Please help!!! I am looking for a song that is always playing at A.C. Moore, an instrumental 50&apos;s soul song, sounds like a waltz of some sort. :huh: 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 Mobil Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 468


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #76 on: November 14, 2008, 11:03:35 PM» 
 On the Red Lobster site in the FAQs section, one of the questions was about the music played there! :holysh: It said that their collection is only licensed for their use, and is only designed for their stereo equipment. They often play good music too.

I went to a new CVS twice a few months ago, and they played You&apos;re So Vain both times. :insane: 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 powersbt Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 333

 
 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #77 on: November 15, 2008, 06:09:29 PM» 
 I just found a song that has been playing on our Muzak for years. It&apos;s sometimes so hard to hear the words in the store. Listen to it on YouTube, and you can understand everything. The song was by Tears for Fear.

If you want to know a song coming from a Muzak source, and if you know the Muzak Station it was on, and approximately when it was on, you can email them about it, and they may be able to get you the answer. It&apos;s worth a try. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 AmesNewington Hero Member
 

Karma: 2
 Offline 

Posts: 559


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #78 on: November 15, 2008, 07:35:48 PM» 
 Stores play really good music. Unfortuneatly, it&apos;s not audible enough for you to figure the name of the song out. There&apos;s a few songs that play in Waldbaum&apos;s that I like and they are played many times, but being at the register, I can&apos;t hear anything.

I wish I had access to Musak&apos;s FM1 station. DISH Network offers Musak channels (I think it&apos;s Musak), but FM1 isn&apos;t a part of the line-up. There&apos;s not one internet stream I have found that resembles the variety of music playing in stores. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 powersbt Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 333

 
 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #79 on: November 16, 2008, 06:04:35 AM» 
 LOL, where were you the past 2 weeks when I was looking all over for my song. &quot;Sowing the Seeds of Love&quot; was the song I was looking for, and all I could get out of the Musak at the store was &quot;See the Love, See the Love.&quot; One of my Coworkers just found the song that he wanted to get last night at work. He used his Cell Phone to listen to the song, and then grab the Information about the song from it. One of those &apos;80&apos;s hits, I can&apos;t even remember what it is now. I&apos;ll keep you in mind, the next time I hear a song that I want to get. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 Mobil Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 468


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #80 on: November 26, 2008, 10:21:02 PM» 
 I heard the Rickroll song at Acme back before Rickrolling was invented! :insane: That is one of my favorite songs though. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 kendra Full Member
 

Karma: 2
 Offline 

Posts: 236

 

 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #81 on: November 27, 2008, 09:54:08 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by powersbt 
LOL, where were you the past 2 weeks when I was looking all over for my song. &quot;Sowing the Seeds of Love&quot; was the song I was looking for, and all I could get out of the Musak at the store was &quot;See the Love, See the Love.&quot; 

Ah yes -- 1989, from The Seeds of Love . Excellent track and excellent album. :dizzy: 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 Neel Guest
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #82 on: December 24, 2008, 12:52:17 AM» 
 When I first started working for Ralphs (Kroger&apos;s division in So Cal) they had the Muzak system. The first store I got had a nice upbeat mix of music, which I later learned it was Hot FM. When I transferred to another store in town, they had slow boring music, IMO (FM1). Then I learned that you can change the station...so one day i went up in the manager&apos;s office and changed it to the same one as the other store.

A year later, Kroger changed from Muzak to InStore Radio or something like that. Instead of satellite, it was music downloaded to a hard drive and controlled by them. What I didn&apos;t like about that was the songs were very repetitive and for some reason we got easy listening/adult contemporary playlist while some of the other Ralphs had a pop format. They said the researched the demographics and provided music that fit those demographs. But the funny thing was our store had a lot of younger shoppers so I never understood why they put that format in the store.

I gotta say tho, Muzak was must better than the new one we got, but I guess it was a cost cutting measure to get rid of it. The other disadvantage to Muzak was the ads would cut into the music. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #83 on: December 28, 2008, 05:57:46 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by Mobil 
I heard the Rickroll song at Acme back before Rickrolling was invented! :insane: That is one of my favorite songs though. 

You heard &quot;Never Gonna Give You Up&quot; by Rick Astley. :roll: 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 nims57 Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 475


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #84 on: March 22, 2009, 06:56:01 PM» 
 I heard &quot;Missing&quot; by Everything But The Girl (1994) at Sears yesterday. 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #85 on: March 22, 2009, 07:47:02 PM» 
 I heard &quot;Take on Me&quot; by A-Ha at Toys &quot;R&quot; Us, and &quot;Gypsy&quot; by Fleetwood Mac and &quot;Kiss N&apos; Tell&quot; by Bryan Ferry at ShopKo. 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 Ameskid Sr. Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 469

 
That one brony


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #86 on: May 05, 2009, 05:43:22 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by ShopKoFan 
 Quote Originally posted by Mobil 
I heard the Rickroll song at Acme back before Rickrolling was invented! :insane: That is one of my favorite songs though. 

You heard &quot;Never Gonna Give You Up&quot; by Rick Astley. :roll: 
I heard the same song at CVS the other day. Small world isn&apos;t it? 
 Logged 
 Proud to have been a member of this forum for 6 years. Let&apos;s make it 6 more! 
 
 
 
 Caldor1999 Expert Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 4048

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #87 on: May 13, 2009, 02:39:19 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by Ameskid 
 Quote Originally posted by ShopKoFan 
 Quote Originally posted by Mobil 
I heard the Rickroll song at Acme back before Rickrolling was invented! :insane: That is one of my favorite songs though. 

You heard &quot;Never Gonna Give You Up&quot; by Rick Astley. :roll: 
I heard the same song at CVS the other day. Small world isn&apos;t it? 
they play that song at the A&amp;P by me alot along with Together Forever another song from that album 
 Logged 
 Caldor Forever!


Caldor Ames Bradlees Jamesway Venture Woolwrth Montgomery Ward Service Merchandise Pergament Grand Union Macys Bloomingdales JC Penny Nordstrom Lord&amp;Taylor Kohls Filene&apos;s Filene&apos;s Basment CVS H&amp;M; Hot Topic staples Taregt Kmart Best Buy Borders Shop Rite Waldbaums Silo Nobody Beats The Wiz Lechmere Jefferson Ward Barkers Zayer Woolco Woolworth A&amp;P;Wendys Burger King Sub Way Henchgers Bulders Squre Lowes Clover Kaffmans Dillards Toy Works KB Toys Toys R Us Kids R Us Babies R Us Cost Co BJ&apos;s Amarican Egael Friendleys Ruby Tusday Chrismas Tree Shops Fun Co Land Discovery Zone Pharmore Filenes Basment TJ Maxx Home Goods Marshles Jordan Marsh Media Play Office Max Offc Depot Staples Rich&apos;s JM Feilds Electric AVE&amp;More Stop&amp;Shop Price Chopper Sage&amp;allen Ann&amp;Hope Neman Marcus Pizza Hut Olive Gardan Fortan Off Bed Bath&amp;Beyond Spencers Foleys May C.O. Kaffmans Robson May Sakes Fith Ave Applebees KFC Barns&amp;Noble Big Lots ACE True Value Sears Best Models Basken Robens Carvel TCBY Roy Rogers Starbucks Ben&amp;Jerys CVS Ride Aid Strawbrigs Tower Records Pets Mart Annie Sez Party City Strawberries Dress barn Fashon Bug Huffman Koos Franks Nursey Banna Republic Tanno Turn Style TGY Two Guys Taco Bell Jo Ann Linenes&amp;Things Tempo Sam Goody Syems Howard Johnsons HQ Alexzanders Ikea Shaws Bobs Discount AC More Curit City Korvetties Gap Crate&amp;Barrle Mrs Greens Chessecake Factory 
 
 
 
 Caldor1999 Expert Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 4048

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #88 on: May 13, 2009, 02:41:39 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by nims57 
I heard &quot;Missing&quot; by Everything But The Girl (1994) at Sears yesterday. 

they played that alot at the shop rite i worked at but they dont play the remixed version whitch was a hit in late 1995 early 1996 
 Logged 
 Caldor Forever!


Caldor Ames Bradlees Jamesway Venture Woolwrth Montgomery Ward Service Merchandise Pergament Grand Union Macys Bloomingdales JC Penny Nordstrom Lord&amp;Taylor Kohls Filene&apos;s Filene&apos;s Basment CVS H&amp;M; Hot Topic staples Taregt Kmart Best Buy Borders Shop Rite Waldbaums Silo Nobody Beats The Wiz Lechmere Jefferson Ward Barkers Zayer Woolco Woolworth A&amp;P;Wendys Burger King Sub Way Henchgers Bulders Squre Lowes Clover Kaffmans Dillards Toy Works KB Toys Toys R Us Kids R Us Babies R Us Cost Co BJ&apos;s Amarican Egael Friendleys Ruby Tusday Chrismas Tree Shops Fun Co Land Discovery Zone Pharmore Filenes Basment TJ Maxx Home Goods Marshles Jordan Marsh Media Play Office Max Offc Depot Staples Rich&apos;s JM Feilds Electric AVE&amp;More Stop&amp;Shop Price Chopper Sage&amp;allen Ann&amp;Hope Neman Marcus Pizza Hut Olive Gardan Fortan Off Bed Bath&amp;Beyond Spencers Foleys May C.O. Kaffmans Robson May Sakes Fith Ave Applebees KFC Barns&amp;Noble Big Lots ACE True Value Sears Best Models Basken Robens Carvel TCBY Roy Rogers Starbucks Ben&amp;Jerys CVS Ride Aid Strawbrigs Tower Records Pets Mart Annie Sez Party City Strawberries Dress barn Fashon Bug Huffman Koos Franks Nursey Banna Republic Tanno Turn Style TGY Two Guys Taco Bell Jo Ann Linenes&amp;Things Tempo Sam Goody Syems Howard Johnsons HQ Alexzanders Ikea Shaws Bobs Discount AC More Curit City Korvetties Gap Crate&amp;Barrle Mrs Greens Chessecake Factory 
 
 
 
 nims57 Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 475


 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #89 on: July 18, 2009, 08:29:30 PM» 
 A few months ago, Walgreens transferred my prescription to CVS. I had to wait a long time for it there, and I heard &quot;How Will I Know&quot; by Whitney Houston. The audio quality was bad. It felt like I was shopping at CVS (or Walgreens) in 1984! 
 Logged 
 
 
 
 
 Zayre88 Sub-Administrators
Expert Member
 

Karma: 3
 Offline 

Posts: 1699

 

 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #90 on: July 18, 2009, 08:32:30 PM» 
 Quote Originally posted by nims57 
A few months ago, Walgreens transferred my prescription to CVS. I had to wait a long time for it there, and I heard &quot;How Will I Know&quot; by Whitney Houston. The audio quality was bad. It felt like I was shopping at CVS (or Walgreens) in 1984! 

I can clearly imagine this particular song playing at Kmart today with their old 1974 speakers 
 Logged 
 http://sites.google.com/site/zayre88 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #91 on: September 12, 2009, 10:41:22 PM» 
 I heard &quot;Africa&quot; by Toto at the ShopKo store featured in my signature a few weeks ago.

I heard &quot;Always&quot; by Erasure at TJ Maxx back in 2004.

I heard &quot;Sunrise&quot; by Simply Red at McDonald&apos;s in 2005, and again at Goodwill in 2008. 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #92 on: November 21, 2009, 03:26:05 PM» 
 I&apos;ve heard &quot;We Don&apos;t Have to Take Our Clothes Off&quot; by Jermaine Stewart at Woodman&apos;s (a Wisconsin supermarket)
I&apos;ve heard &quot;Islands in the Stream&quot; by Kenny Rogers and Dolly Parton at Walmart Supercenter
I&apos;ve heard &quot;Someday&quot; by Sugar Ray at Burger King
I&apos;ve heard &quot;Fireflies&quot; by Owl City at Taco Bell
I&apos;ve heard &quot;The Reason&quot; by Hoobastank at ShopKo 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 nims57 Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 475


 
 Re: The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #93 on: March 07, 2010, 03:54:33 PM» 
 A few years back, I heard&quot;Promises Promises&quot;by I think Tears for Fears at Pathmark. That was right before A&amp;P bought them. I miss the days when Pathmark was Pathmark, before the&quot;save save save&quot;crap started. There was no&quot;Sav-a-Center&quot;, just&quot;Super Center&quot;. I miss the days of regular Pathmark the most though. In fact, when one Super Fresh converted (in the city of Philadelphia!) there was an outcry. People thought their property values would go down.

A&amp;P should have gone under years ago. The only reason they still exist is the unions. 
 « Last Edit: March 07, 2010, 04:03:31 PM by nims57 » Logged 
 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 Re: The ESSENCE of all stores « Reply #94 on: March 07, 2010, 06:23:12 PM» 
 Quote from: nims57 on March 07, 2010, 03:54:33 PM A few years back, I heard&quot;Promises Promises&quot;by I think Tears for Fears at Pathmark. That was right before A&amp;P bought them. I miss the days when Pathmark was Pathmark, before the&quot;save save save&quot;crap started. There was no&quot;Sav-a-Center&quot;, just&quot;Super Center&quot;. I miss the days of regular Pathmark the most though. In fact, when one Super Fresh converted (in the city of Philadelphia!) there was an outcry. People thought their property values would go down.

A&amp;P should have gone under years ago. The only reason they still exist is the unions.
 &quot;Promises Promises&quot;is performed by Naked Eyes

A&amp;P left the Midwest years ago. 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 jmcnamara96 Expert Member
 

Karma: 6
 Offline 

Posts: 1010

 
 

 
 
 Re: What song always seems to play inside a store « Reply #95 on: April 19, 2010, 03:52:55 PM» 
 Ive gone to Savers about 5 times and about 3 of those times ive heard Lady in Red 
 Logged 
 Joseph M Gilbert

FaceBook
 http://www.facebook.com/index.php?lh=7c1aa6731e6f8d339ae954d81bf44a0b&amp;#/profile.php?ref=profile&amp;id=100000411097502 
/ 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 Re: What song always seems to play inside a store « Reply #96 on: July 25, 2010, 04:28:32 PM» 
 I&apos;ve been to Burger King recently and they played:

&quot;Eat It&quot;by&quot;Weird Al&quot;Yankovic (fitting because we are in a fast-food restaurant)
&quot;The Flintstones theme song&quot;by Hanna-Barbera
&quot;The Drake&amp;Josh theme song (I Found A Way)&quot;by Drake Bell
 
 « Last Edit: July 25, 2010, 05:31:41 PM by ShopKoFan » Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 ShopKoFan Sr. Member
 

Karma: 1
 Offline 

Posts: 388

 
Knows ShopKo too well.

 
 
 Re: What song always seems to play inside a store « Reply #97 on: May 02, 2011, 12:14:01 PM» 
 I recently heard&quot;IGY (What a Beautiful World)&quot;by Donald Fagen when I was at Shopko the other day. It was a great song by a great artist (in this case, a former member of Steely Dan). 
 Logged 
 ShopKo Forever!

Green Bay Packers Superbowl Champions
I - II -XXXI - XLV 
 
 
 
 Caldor1999 Expert Member
 

Karma: 0
 Offline 

Posts: 4048

 
 
 Re: What song always seems to play inside a store « Reply #98 on: May 02, 2011, 10:12:26 PM» 
 i use to work at an a&amp;p for awhile and the music there would be a mix of things depending on what the manger changes it too sometimes it would be on 90&apos;s and nothing but 90s and you would get sometimes get songs that you wouldn&apos;t hear in a super market like im to sexy or i touch myself sometimes it would be on nothing but 80&apos;s music country and new music 
 Logged 
 Caldor Forever!


Caldor Ames Bradlees Jamesway Venture Woolwrth Montgomery Ward Service Merchandise Pergament Grand Union Macys Bloomingdales JC Penny Nordstrom Lord&amp;Taylor Kohls Filene&apos;s Filene&apos;s Basment CVS H&amp;M; Hot Topic staples Taregt Kmart Best Buy Borders Shop Rite Waldbaums Silo Nobody Beats The Wiz Lechmere Jefferson Ward Barkers Zayer Woolco Woolworth A&amp;P;Wendys Burger King Sub Way Henchgers Bulders Squre Lowes Clover Kaffmans Dillards Toy Works KB Toys Toys R Us Kids R Us Babies R Us Cost Co BJ&apos;s Amarican Egael Friendleys Ruby Tusday Chrismas Tree Shops Fun Co Land Discovery Zone Pharmore Filenes Basment TJ Maxx Home Goods Marshles Jordan Marsh Media Play Office Max Offc Depot Staples Rich&apos;s JM Feilds Electric AVE&amp;More Stop&amp;Shop Price Chopper Sage&amp;allen Ann&amp;Hope Neman Marcus Pizza Hut Olive Gardan Fortan Off Bed Bath&amp;Beyond Spencers Foleys May C.O. Kaffmans Robson May Sakes Fith Ave Applebees KFC Barns&amp;Noble Big Lots ACE True Value Sears Best Models Basken Robens Carvel TCBY Roy Rogers Starbucks Ben&amp;Jerys CVS Ride Aid Strawbrigs Tower Records Pets Mart Annie Sez Party City Strawberries Dress barn Fashon Bug Huffman Koos Franks Nursey Banna Republic Tanno Turn Style TGY Two Guys Taco Bell Jo Ann Linenes&amp;Things Tempo Sam Goody Syems Howard Johnsons HQ Alexzanders Ikea Shaws Bobs Discount AC More Curit City Korvetties Gap Crate&amp;Barrle Mrs Greens Chessecake Factory 
 
 
 
 Pages: 1 2 3 [ 4 ] 
   Print   
 

 «previous next» 
 
   
 Jump to: Please select a destination: ----------------------------- Ames ----------------------------- =&gt; Ames =&gt; Business =&gt; Stores =&gt; Back in the day =&gt; Associates ----------------------------- Retail ----------------------------- =&gt; Closed Chains =&gt; Stores Shutting Down This Year =&gt; Closed Chain Misc. ===&gt; Store Receipts ===&gt; Commercials =&gt; Stores =&gt; Grocery/Supermarkets =&gt; Restaurants =&gt; Malls =&gt; Gas Stations =&gt; Hotels/Motels =&gt; Shopping Cart Sightings =&gt; Department Store Bashing =&gt; Urban Retail Strategizing ----------------------------- Everything Else ----------------------------- =&gt; General ===&gt; Art ===&gt; Car Manufacturers =&gt; Photography =&gt; Books =&gt; Gamers Only =&gt; Announcements =&gt; Website Support&amp;Updates ===&gt; Updates ===&gt; Support   

 
 
 Powered by SMF 1.1.11 | SMF©2006-2009, Simple Machines LLC 
 SimplePortal 2.3.1©2008-2009, SimplePortal 
 Loading...
	</body>
</document>
