<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006466" url="http://forum.couponmom.com/have-question-ask-help/349-fast-food-restaurant-question.html" time="2012-07-12-23:24" support="2" score="0.0022478882026865355" bingtitle="fast food/restaurant question - CouponMom Forum" webtitle="fast food/restaurant question">
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>buy a coffee for a 1.00 cal the number on the back of the receipt they give you a ... anyone else have any fast food restaurant tips I do use restaurants.com and the 40% ...</description>
	<body>
		Cut Your Grocery Bill In Half! 
 with Stephanie Nelson, The Coupon Mom 
 Printable Coupons Grocery Deals By State Drugstore Deals
National Deals Learn to
Coupon Coupon
Database Restaurant
Coupons Online
Coupons Free
Samples Forum
Facebook 
 
 
 Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Forum 
 New Posts FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 Today&apos;s Posts View Site Leaders 
 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum Have a Question? Ask for help! fast food/restaurant question 
 Results 1 to 5 of 5 
Thread: fast food/restaurant question 
 
 
 LinkBack 

 LinkBack URL About LinkBacks 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 09-02-2008,  07:28 AM #1 floridafinn Master Strategic Shopper Join Date Aug 2008 Location Palm Beach, Florida Posts 657 
 fast food/restaurant question
 I have a friend of mine that doesn&apos;t cook and loves fast food
here is her suggestin from burger king to get a free whopper bogo
buy a coffee for a 1.00 cal the number on the back of the receipt they give you a code and you can purchase free food

note: something I have done here, we have a restaurant called buds (fried chicken)
go before 11am and you get a bucket of chicken (big) for 5.00

anyone else have any fast food restaurant tips I do use restaurants.com and the 40% from coupon mom was great 

   09-02-2008,  02:40 PM #2 paige Master Strategic Shopper Join Date Aug 2008 Location murfreesboro tn Posts 500 
 
 no but ill be watching!!! 09-02-2008,  03:18 PM #3 lizandsasa Master Strategic Shopper Join Date Aug 2008 Location Sunny California Posts 549 
 
 thnx for the tip - will be watching out at my local places for deals like these... With much Aloha and Blessings! 
Great group to join if you want to learn and share - click the link: http://forum.couponmom.com/groups/learn-share.html 09-02-2008,  10:03 PM #4 Maddy&apos;sMom Strategic Shopper Join Date Aug 2008 Location Ohio Posts 95 
 
 Thanks for the tip, I&apos;ll be watching for this one! 09-03-2008,  04:36 PM #5 coupondad Master Strategic Shopper Join Date Aug 2008 Location New York Posts 540 
 wendys
 at our local wendys if you go in right when they are changing between breakfast and lunch (around 11 a.m.) you can get the breakfast items at 1/2 price... so the cinnamon bun which normally costs 2 dollars, cost 1 dollar... and if you sign up for wendys coupons... you can sometimes get it for free! 
&quot;People will not remember what you said, or how you acted. But how you made them feel.&quot;~ Maya Angelou 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 del.icio.us Digg StumbleUpon Google 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts   
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On [VIDEO] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On 
 
 Forum Rules 
 -- vB4 Default Style -- Default Mobile Style 
 Contact Us CouponMom.com Home Archive Top 
 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 04:15 PM . Powered by vBulletin® Version 4.2.0
Copyright©2012 vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
SEO by vBSEO 3.6.0 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77
	</body>
</document>
