<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006829" url="http://www.hotfrog.ca/Products/Restaurant/11" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="8" score="0.027231959539230542" bingtitle="Restaurant - Page 11 - Hotfrog Canada - free local business directory" webtitle="Restaurant - Page 11">
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>... catering bakery party trays pastries ... alternatives then your typical fast food restaurant ... Cactus for the first time, our menu will certainly entice you to return ...</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 Oops, you forgot to enter a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Restaurant - Page 11
 401 - 440 of 22189 businesses results BC Restaurant Equipment 
Pitt Meadows, BC
 6044590011 
Welcome to BC Restaurant Equipment. We are a restaurant supply company with your business in mind. With great names like Mercer, Steelite China, Wolf Equipment and Libbey Glassware: we can give you the price that makes…
 
 Restaurant Supply restaurant supplies restaurant equipment bar supplies 
 Squirrel Systems 
Burnaby, BC
 604-412-3300 
Squirrel Systems develops restaurant POS systems and point of sale software for the food service industry. Our restaurant management systems are used in establishments worldwide.
 
 Restaurant Point Of Sale restaurant pos systems restaurant pos Restaurant Management 
 Sherbrooke Village Inn, Restaurant, Cot… 
Sherbrooke, NS
 902-522-2235 
Nova Scotia&apos;s Sherbrooke Village Inn Restaurant &amp;Cottages on the Marine Trail. We offer a variety of choices for accommodation: rooms with king or double beds, efficiency units, bed and breakfast and housekeeping c…
 
 Seafood dining room Double Beds lobster 
 Fairwinds Motel&amp;Restaurant, Sheet Har… 
Sheet Harbour, NS
 902-885-2502 
FAIRWINDS MOTEL&amp; RESTAURANT - Sheet Harbour on the Marine Trail Nova Scotia. Open year-round, the Fairwinds Motel&amp;Restaurant is located on the oceanfront in Sheet Harbour, Nova Scotia. Our Restaurant is casua…
 
 Double Beds Motel inn lodging 
 Shiki Japanese Restaurant, London Ontar… 
London, ON
 5196687407 
Authentic Japanese Restaurant in London Ontario. Open Seven Days a Week. Lunch. Dinner. See the website for hours and menu. Sushi. Classic Japanese Entrees. Samplers. Fine Dining. Located on Wellington near Southdale on…
 
 Japanese Restaurant fine dining sushi Japanese 
 Fujiya Japanese Foods Victoria 
Victoria, BC
 250-598-3711 
Order sushi and other Japanese food online with Fujiya. The Fujiya location in Victoria, BC is a Japanese restaurant that serves sushi, sashimi, tempura, and more.
 
 Japanese Restaurant japanese food sushi Food 
 Fujiya Japanese Foods Richmond 
Richmond, BC
 604-270-3715 
Order sushi and other Japanese food online with Fujiya. The Fujiya location in Richmond, BC is a Japanese restaurant that serves sushi, sashimi, tempura, and more.
 
 Japanese Restaurant japanese food sushi Food 
 Fujiya Japanese Foods Vancouver 
Vancouver, BC
 604-608-1050 
Order sushi and other Japanese food online with Fujiya. The Fujiya location in downtown Vancouver is a Japanese restaurant that serves sushi , sashimi , tempura , and more.
 
 Japanese Restaurant japanese food sushi Food 
 Fujiya Japanese Foods Vancouver 
Vancouver, BC
 604-251-3711 
Order sushi and other Japanese food online with Fujiya. The Fujiya location at Clark is a Vancouver Japanese restaurant that serves sushi , sashimi , tempura , and more.
 
 Japanese Restaurant japanese food sushi Food 
 The Wingery 
Oakville, ON
 905.842.3388 
Better Chicken, Better Sauces... Best Tasting Wings! The Wingery uses only fresh, huge, plump chicken wings coated in our special blend of spices and herbs then cooked in a blend of vegetable oils at the optimum tempera…
 
 Chicken Wings 
   Bistro Sous Le Fort 
Québec, QC
 4186940852 
Nestling in the middle of historical and splendid Quartier Petit-Champlain, a hidden secret…Le Bistro Sous le Fort. Discreet, apprehensive, this cozy resto charms ourselves with a nice and welcoming staff, the warmth of…
 
 bistro Restaurants Fort Christmas Parties 
 Apres Restaurant 
Whistler, BC
 6049350200 
Whistler&apos;s only French Contemporary Restaurant . Relax
with friends at aprés, this chic, elegant, 50 seat restaurant is where
you want to spend an evening that you will remember for a long time to
come. Seasonally cha…
 
 Restaurants 
 Crestview Family Restaurant 
Parry Sound, ON
 7053785000 
We are a family restaurant located in the heart of cottage country, Parry Sound Ontario. We have a wide variety of menu items from fresh homemade pies and deserts to full couse dinners. We serve breakfast dailly from 7a…
 
 family restaurant dining room Restaurants 
 IDEAL AUCTIONS 
Surrey, BC
 604-831-4796 
BUY - SELL - TRADE - LEASE NEW AND USED FOOD EQUIPMENT - RESTAURANT S, BAKERIES, MEAT SHOPS, CAFES, ESPRESSO BARS, LOTS OF EQUIPMENT BEING LIQUIDATED DAILY AT OUR WAREHOUSES AND ON THE WEB  at   www.ideal-auctions.com…
 
 Cooking Equipment Smallwares Commercial Cooking Pots And Pans 
 Simply Zoup 
Toronto, ON
 416-915-9990 
SIMPLY ZOUP is the premier source of upscale soups, gourmet sandwiches salads with personal touch service. The goal in SIMPLY ZOUP is to provide customers with a wide variety of soups and to promote healthy eating. …
 
 Gourmet Sandwiches Soups Business District 
 Ice Cream Patio 
Woodbridge, ON
 (905)850-3302 
Ice Cream Patio is an italian family restaurant that serves pasta Wood oven pizzas italian gelato and desserts, this restaurant is great for the whole family and also corporate and family events.
 
 family restaurant dinner lunch dining 
 Shoeless Joes Cambridge 
Cambridge, ON
 5196209800 
shoeless joes restaurant casual dining sports bar cambridge ontario wings ribs canadian food events ufc hockey football baseball playoffs now
 
 Entertainment Accessories Catering Catering Services Decorating Tips 
 Municipalitéde 
Saint-Faustin-Lac-Carré, QC
 (819) 688 2161 
Saint-Faustin-Lac-Carr, destination Quatre Saisons pour toute la famille! Situé à quelques minutes de Mont-Tremblant au coeur des Laurentides dans la province de Qubec au Canada dans une des plus belle rgion de villgiat…
 
 Hotel 
 Maya Hotel 

 9021251133 
Maya Istanbul Hotel is a new boutique hotel built from scratch and opened in 2006 following the historical style of Sehzadebasi area. We designed our hotel by paying attention to all the details.
 
 boutique hotel Private Bathroom Hotel Hotels 
 La Maison De Pierres 
Ile D&apos;Orléans, QC
 4188291166 
Bienvenue à la Maison de pierres! La Maison de pierres est une construction bicentenaire avec foyer central, planchers d’époque et murs de pierre Nous sommes heureux de vous accueillir sur la page web de la…
 
 
 Watauga Village And B&amp;B 
Clearwater, 0
 (01) 250-674-0085 
We are a unique place to come eat, shop, sleep and relax at in beautiful Clearwater, BC the gateway to Well&apos;s Gray Provincial Park. We have some stores so you can come shop and look around, eat at the cafe with the pati…
 
 Cafe Hiking lodging Tourism 
 Stinker 

 (208) 375 0942 
Stinker Station. Stinker has positions itself to be a leader in marketing environmentally friendly alternative energy fuel such as E-10 and E-85 gasoline and Bio Diesel
 
 Food Store 
 Lubavitch Bc 
Vancouver, BC
 6042661313 
Lubavitch of B.C. offers a wide array of Torah Classes and Events. Check out our new full service Kosher Restaurant for take-out and eat-in gourmet lunch and dinners
 
 Kosher 
 Live Food Bar 
Toronto, ON
 4165152002 
We believe that quality and flavor come first and that vegan foods are a healthy and satisfying choice with which to create a gourmet dining experience”
 
 Brunch Gourmet Dining drinks Catering 
 Island Scales 
Nanaimo, BC
 1 888 999 0822 
Island Scales was founded in 1994 by Rob and Lionel Carter We&apos;re located at 21 Cadillac Place, Nanaimo, BC With regularly scheduled calibration, and our recommendations for replacement parts or upgrades, …
 
 
 Globaltech Pos 

 1 877 244 9449 
GlobalTech POS has extensive experience in providing technology solutions to the hospitality industry GlobalTech POS is the sales and service leader of the renowned Restaurant Manager POS system From a grou…
 
 restaurant pos Hospitality Industry Pos 
 Chef Nigel 

 1 519 312 8329 
Established Chef Nigel, Personal Chef Service.Started the business on a part time basis doing in home dinner parties and prepared meal packages for clients while working at a local hotel
 
 cuisine chef Meals Hotel 
 American Mussel 

 02852401294 
American Mussel Harvesters : - Mussels Oysters Clams, Shellfish and Oysters in rhode island
 
 seafood restaurant Mussels Seafood Oysters 
 istaffsolution.com 
Burnaby, 0
 
…online recruitment solution. Job Seekers can discover career opportunities including hotel jobs, restaurant jobs, tourism jobs and other jobs in the hospitality sector located in British Columbia, Alberta, Ontario and…
 
 Restaurant Jobs hospitality jobs Hotel Jobs Hospitality Industry 
 Scrubs Canada 
Charlottetown, PE
 
Offers nursing uniforms, medical scrubs and lab coats. Medical uniforms also available in tall or petite pant length.
 
 Work Clothes lab coats 
 Jc Scott 
Victoria, BC
 2503859545 
JC Scott Design Associates - Based in Victoria BC Canada - Specializes in interior design for resorts and golf clubhouse decor to custom residential layout
 
 Golf Hotel Hospitality Hotel Hotels 
 Humanbeans Coffee 
Ottawa, ON
 6137624581 
Human Beans Coffee Co. of Ottawa, Canada. Fair Trade organic coffee service for offices, cafeterias, restaurant s and catered events
 
 Fair Trade Coffee espresso Coffee Services espresso machine 
 Ubbelea 
Millgrove, ON
 9056898610 
Ubbelea, a privately owned mushroom farm, was established in 1969. In 1974, Ubbelea became a Limited Company owned and operated by Cornelis, Johanna and Richard Ubbels
 
 Restaurant Supply Food Service Mushrooms 
 Orange Gorilla 

 1(250) 318 1980 
Welcome to Orange Gorilla Commercial Interiors. At Orange Gorilla, we provide furnishings, design and consulting services for commercial enviroments
 
 restaurant design Restaurant Furniture Hospitality Furniture Hotel Furniture 
 Pacific Restaurant 
Victoria, BC
 1 800 663 7550 
Pacific Restaurant Menus: Breakfast MenuLunch MenuDim SumDinner MenuDessertsWest Coast Afternoon TeaPalate TEAsersThanksgivingLocated on the Lobby Level. Open for breakfast, lunch and dinner. Specializing in Pacific Nort…
 
 casual dining cuisine luxury hotel Hotel 
 Peacock Billiards 
Victoria, BC
 250 384 3332 
Peacock Billiards and James Joyce Bistro Peacock&apos;s has gone through some serious changes, but when adversity rears its ugly head, our resilience stands like a beacon in the night Well, we&apos;ve had an exciting…
 
 pool hall bistro Corporate Functions Retirement Parties 
 Le Thurso 
Thurso, QC
 819 985 2701 
Site officiel de la municipalité de Thurso en Outaouais, près des Laurentides au Québec. Les informations sur la municipalité, le tourisme, lhébergement, le plein air, les activités et la culture
 
 
 First Choice Upholstery 
Mount arl NL, PE
 709 368 5858 
First Choice Upholstery caters to both residential and commercial customers including restaurant , health care, offshore and recreational marine clientelle with quality reupholstery, repair and custom furniture services…
 
 
 Crown Food Equipment 
Calgary, AB
 (403) 253 4888 
 Fryers Food Service Equipment Food Equipment Food Service 
 Spring Lake Resort 
Dwight, ON
 7056359995 
 dining Motel rooms Hotel Rooms 
 First page Prev 10 pages   11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 Last Page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (22189) 
 Related keywords 
 Restaurants Pizza Restaurants Accommodation family restaurant Bar 
 Restaurant by state 
 ON BC QC AB NS MB SK NB NL PE YT NT 
 Restaurant by region 
 Western Canada Prairies Pacific Coast Central AB Central Canada Southern AB Vancouver&amp;Coast Metro Edmonton Central Foothills Greater Calgary North Western AB Lower Mainland Calgary Metropolitan Area Metro Calgary Metro Vancouver Greater Vancouver Greater Toronto Atlantic Canada Lower Fraser Valley Maritimes 
 Restaurant by suburb 
 TORONTO, ON VANCOUVER, BC CALGARY, AB Montréal, QC EDMONTON, AB OTTAWA, ON MISSISSAUGA, ON WINNIPEG, MB VICTORIA, BC SCARBOROUGH, ON LONDON, ON NORTH YORK, ON SURREY, BC MONTREAL, QC RICHMOND, BC WINDSOR, ON HAMILTON, ON BRAMPTON, ON MARKHAM, ON ETOBICOKE, ON 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog search results pages. Upgrade today to get your message in front of potential customers before they see the competition.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 Oops, you forgot to enter a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of use Privacy policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.3mvt.004 )
	</body>
</document>
