<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006315" url="http://www.wlbt.com/story/15093687/200-rc-racers-gather-in-flowood-for-tournament" time="2012-07-12-23:00" support="1" score="0.0013296532182849876" bingtitle="200 RC Racers gather in Flowood for tournament - WLBT.com ..." webtitle="200 RC Racers gather in Flowood for tournament - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Four arrested for credit card fraud and identity theft ... Jackson fast food restaurant armed robbery ... The city owned RC indoor park is host to the ...</description>
	<body>
		WLBT.com - Jackson, MS200 RC Racers gather in Flowood for tournament
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 St. Jude Dream Home Video Landing Page Decision 2012 Jackson Gas Prices Editorials America Now Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts Contact Us 
 
 Decision 2012 Editorials MDOT Traffic Cams Wednesday&apos;s Child Look Around Mississippi Most Wanted Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Olympic Zone Sign up for Alerts 
 
 MedNOW Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 SkyCopter 3 Community Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Sign up for Alerts Contact Us Closed Captioning This TV Network 
 
 WLBT Community St. Jude Dream Home SkyCopter 3 Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Contact Us Fresh from the Flame 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
200 RC Racers gather in Flowood for tournament
 Posted: Saturday, July 16, 2011 7:27 PM EST Updated: Saturday, July 16, 2011 11:29 PM EST By Julie Straw - bio | email 
 
 Most Popular Stories Most Read More&gt;&gt; 
 
 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 

 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:34 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:34:44 GMT A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl that he met on Facebook. More &gt;&gt; A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl whom he met on Facebook, according to police. More &gt;&gt; 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:53 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:53:55 GMT The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 
 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 

 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 9:48 AM EDT 2012-07-10 13:48:25 GMT A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Sponsored Information More&gt;&gt; 
 
 sponsored information: 

 Personal Injury Attorney 

 Personal Injury Attorney 
 
 FLOWOOD, MS (WLBT) - 
More than 200 remote control car racers from across the country were gathered in Flowood. The city owned RC indoor park is host to the first &quot;Bring the Heat&quot; race that spans the entire weekend. These aren&apos;t your average remote control cars and can travel at highway speeds.

&quot;They&apos;ll do probably top end 40 or 50 miles per hour, but they get there in a hurry. We have some jumps here. They have to hit and have a lot of low end power,&quot; said Flowood RC Indoor Park General Manager Bubba Burham. It opened in December and &quot;Beat the Heat&quot; is its first major event.

RC enthusiasts from California, Nevada, Virginia and other states, more than 200 of them, attended the tournament.

&quot;It&apos;s just a larger scale, racing from Nascar formula one down to 1/10 scale size,&quot; said RC Pro World Champion Mark Pavidis.

Although remote control cars seem to be more of a mans toy there is plenty of room for pink. Ronda Drake of Ontario, California has been racing for 21 years. The hobby led her to her husband, two time National champion Adam Drake.

&quot;We were friends for 8 years.  We met doing this and I guess everyone calls us the Brad and Angelina of RC,&quot; said Drake.

The champions travel the world, competing in races. They said Flowood&apos;s course ranks near the top.

&quot;It&apos;s great to have a city like Flowood involved in our industry. Hopefully we can bring more events like this to Flowood,&quot; said Pavidis.

 ©2011 WLBT. All rights reserved. 
 
 
Explore WLBT.com
 Home Local News Decision 2011 Gas Prices America Now Point of View Sound Off News Most Read Local News Skycopter 3 Most Wanted Look Around Mississippi 3 On Your Side Wednesday’s Child Taking Back our Neighborhoods Red Blue Review Medical Matters Weather Local Weather Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Interactive Radar 4-Day Pollen Forecast Sports Sports National Sports Mississippi Sports Friday Nite Lites Video Latest Videos Most Watched Video Center Contact Us Contact Us Sign Up for Email Alerts Our Team Birthday Club All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WLBT, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
