<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006817" url="http://reviews.opentable.com/0938/79567/reviews.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="1" score="0.0027796049410047817" bingtitle="Cowell &amp; Hubbard Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners" webtitle="CowellHubbard Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners">
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>&quot;The tables were packed so tight, the table elbow to us had to retrieve their plates from their waiter over my husbands shoulder. Not sure if we&apos;ll try again.</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Reservations - Free•Instant•Confirmed Home Mobile Help Learn More Print this page Restaurant Reviews Restaurant reviews by area Alabama Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Akron (269) Canton (629) Cleveland (13,691) Avon / Avon Lake (220) Beachwood (1,588) Bratenahl (37) Brecksville (117) Broadview Heights (55) Chagrin Falls (394) Chardon (70) Cleveland (2,928) American (567) Argentinean (13) Brazilian (207) Brewery (131) Comfort Food (323) Contemporary American (390) French (654) International (92) Italian (211) Japanese (7) Mexican (95) Middle Eastern (43) Spanish (156) Steak (39) Cleveland Heights (164) Concord (42) Downtown Cleveland (2,583) Hudson (280) Independence (116) Lakewood (455) Little Italy (226) Lyndhurst (193) Mentor (189) Moreland Hills (214) Ohio City (401) Pepper Pike (76) Rocky River (147) Sandusky (96) Shaker Heights (450) Solon (34) Strongsville (417) Tremont (718) Twinsburg (285) University Circle (676) Valley View (159) Vermilion (223) Westlake (56) Willoughby (82) Wooster (159) Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin Find Restaurants in Your Area Select a Location 
 Alabama Amsterdam Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Beirut Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Chihuahua Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Malaysia Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Villa de Muerte Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin 
 Reserve now: Reserve Now on OpenTable.com Cowell&amp;amp; Hubbard Reservations Restaurant Reviews List &gt; Cleveland / Akron / Canton Restaurant Reviews &gt; Cleveland Restaurant Reviews &gt; Cleveland Restaurant Reviews &gt; French Restaurant Reviews 
 Cowell&amp;Hubbard Reviews List 
 
 Cowell&amp;Hubbard 
 1305 Euclid Ave
Cleveland, OH 44115

The new Zach Bruell restaurant.

 Dining Style: Fine Dining
 Price: $30 and under
 Parking: Valet
 Cross Street: 44115
 See more Cowell&amp;Hubbard details 654 Current Reviews Summary of Diner Ratings&amp;Reviews Overall (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 (654 Reviews) Rating Breakdown 654 reviews 5 stars (302) 4 stars (265) 3 stars (66) 2 stars (19) 1 star (2) Food (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic Read all 654 reviews Write a review Filter Reviews By: Diners classify this restaurant as: 
 fit for foodies (448) special occasion (306) hot spot (250) 

 neighborhood gem (179) good for groups (168) notable wine list (144) 
 see more Sort By Featured Reviews Newest Oldest Highest Rating Lowest Rating Longest Shortest Cowell&amp;Hubbard Reviews List Review 1 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The endive salad was amazing! 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/10/2012 2008 Dined on 07/10/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The endive salad was amazing! A must-try if you&apos;ve never had it. The food is exquisitely done. &quot; Dined on 07/10/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 2 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 One is never disappointed 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/07/2012 2012 Dined on 07/07/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; One is never disappointed at a Zach Bruell restaurant. Cowell&amp;Huubard lived up to our expectations with its unique menu items, and excellent service in a beautifully renovated space. &quot; Dined on 07/07/2012 2012 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 3 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Good but pricey 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The food was very good. Waiter was not as knowlegeable of the food or wine suggestions as I would have expected for this type of restaurant. It was an expensive meal and while good, not sure I would go back at that price. I had the special of the day which was fish priced at $30. They did a nice job renovating the building. Wait staff was friendly and the service was prompt. &quot; Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 4 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 The service was iffy, several 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The service was iffy, several miscommunications on orders. Food was offbeat, but enjoyable. Wine list had many good selections and was reasonably priced. Will give it another chance. &quot; Dined on 07/07/2012 2011 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 5 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Dinner at Cowell was an outstanding 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/06/2012 2012 Dined on 07/06/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Dinner at Cowell was an outstanding choice. We enjoyed the endive salad. My husband had the rock fish as his entree while I enjoy the white fish. Both excellent choices. We shared the cream puff for dessert. Amazing. The service was outstanding. Water glasses were continually refilled, as well as the bread. Our server was very attentive and gave very good descriptions of the specials. He answered our questions politely and returned appropriately to see if we required anything. We never felt rushed even when we lingered a while to chat after dessert. &quot; Dined on 07/06/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , late-night find , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 6 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Playhouse Square was in sore 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/06/2012 2005 Dined on 07/06/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Playhouse Square was in sore need of new, quality restaurants and this one fills the bill nicely. Imaginative offerings in a swank environment. Will DEFINITELY be returning ... especially during our season of theatre this fall/winter. Can&apos;t wait to try other dishes!! &quot; Dined on 07/06/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 7 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Still yummy but portions too big! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Been here several times since C&amp;H opened... it&apos;s still good, but not as memorable as before. The portions have gotten bigger (not always a good thing). Ordered the bacon and eggs (was literally twice as big as the order last time I was here), and lox and eggs (yummy, but could easily have been my entree). For dinner, we had the beef shoulder (did not disappoint) and tried the red fish (good, but I liked the trout I had last time better). Too full for dessert this time (and I mean REALLY full). We were going to a show so couldn&apos;t take home leftovers, and I don&apos;t like to waste food, so no dessert tonite! I will return!! &quot; Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 8 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 my first time at cowell and 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/03/2012 2012 Dined on 07/03/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; my first time at cowell and hubbard and my first time using open table. great to make reservations quickly online and our lunch was PHENOMINAL! highly recommend this great spot. &quot; Dined on 07/03/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 9 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 My favorite restaurant in 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/03/2012 2011 Dined on 07/03/2012 2011 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; My favorite restaurant in Cleveland. &quot; Dined on 07/03/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 10 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 well worth a try 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/02/2012 2007 Dined on 07/02/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; located just slightly away from revitalized downtown center. Loved the food and service. Our group was from across the country and crossed generations...everyone enjoyed the relaxed yet elegant vibe. Big plus, we could actually dine&amp;talk (not too loud). Menu was diverse yet approachable. &quot; Dined on 07/02/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , romantic Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 11 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Another Zack Bruell hit. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Another Zack Bruell hit. The restaurant did not disappoint! Great drink list. &quot; Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 12 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Great food and service. Would 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/30/2012 2010 Dined on 06/30/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Great food and service. Would be nice if they could add some outdoor dining. &quot; Dined on 06/30/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 13 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Once again OUTSTANDING..both 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/30/2012 2011 Dined on 06/30/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Once again OUTSTANDING..both service and food top notch.... &quot; Dined on 06/30/2012 2011 Special Features: neighborhood gem , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 14 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Fair) 2 / 5 
 We didn&apos;t love Cowell and 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Food (Fair) 2 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We didn&apos;t love Cowell and Hubbard. We ate in the middle of summer, and the menu was full of winter vegetables, hard squashes and cold weather preparations. The portions were large but the composition of the plates wasn&apos;t great. Apps and salads were good, but we lost interest in our entrees. Gnocchi were rubbery, flavored mayo with the pork shank was a head-scratcher and ambiance was borderline sterile. Service staff was very good but we&apos;re not psyched to go back any time soon. &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , good for groups , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 15 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 great service, told the waiter 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/28/2012 2010 Dined on 06/28/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; great service, told the waiter we had to be out by a certain time and he made sure we were. Food was delicious, everyone enjoyed what they ordered. Always made sure our water and bread were refilled. Finally an upscale restaurant for before or after a play or any night you want a great meal. &quot; Dined on 06/28/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 16 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 We absolutely love Zach Brul&apos;s 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/28/2012 2006 Dined on 06/28/2012 2006 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We absolutely love Zach Brul&apos;s restaurants; this was our first visit at C&amp;H and we were not impressed. It did not meet our expectations. Consider offering more entree&apos;s for vegans and vegetarians and/or make sure what they put on the menu is outstanding and not something you can create at home; less than average overcooked spinach and tofu in what appeared to be a red sauce does not cut the mustard for a Zach Brul Restaurant. Overall, the other dishes were good along with friendly but slow service on a night where more than half the tables were empty- they must of been short staffed. &quot; Dined on 06/28/2012 2006 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 17 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Food was great but our table 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/28/2012 2007 Dined on 06/28/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Food was great but our table placement was poor. Not enough room for servers to access other tables near us. &quot; Dined on 06/28/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 18 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 OMG! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/27/2012 2006 Dined on 06/27/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; My husband and I visit many restaurants here at home in Cleveland&amp;everywhere we travel to. We are serious foodies. Out of all of the restaurants we have been to inside Cleveland&amp;out, this is definitely in the TOP 5 hands down!! Service is above&amp;beyond, Bartender is an artist, and may I say that the Lox&amp;Eggs with the truffle oil....there are no words!!!! That was only one dish! Zack Bruell is a food genius! &quot; Dined on 06/27/2012 2006 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 19 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The food was very good although 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/27/2012 2007 Dined on 06/27/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The food was very good although the veal could have used a bit less breading. Also, the wine list, while extensive, was quite pricey, very few wines under $40. &quot; Dined on 06/27/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 20 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Great service food and experience 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/25/2012 2011 Dined on 06/25/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Great service food and experience delivered from the top down &quot; Dined on 06/25/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 21 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 This is our second time dining 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; This is our second time dining at C&amp;H and it was great once again. &quot; Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 22 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 great meal, good service, 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/22/2012 2009 Dined on 06/22/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; great meal, good service, lots of fun &quot; Dined on 06/22/2012 2009 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 23 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The food an service were exceptiona 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2005 Dined on 06/23/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The food an service were exceptional. I am glad to see that the playhouse district has a restaurant of this caliber. &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2005 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 24 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Third time at Cowell&amp;Hubbard 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Third time at Cowell&amp;Hubbard - some of the early glitches have been resolved. Servers are more aware of their tables and attentive. Secondary staff was excellent i.e kept water and bread basket filled. Think the menu is too long and overly complicated. Whatever Mr. Bruel does is very good and there is always enought to please any taste. &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 25 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Was VERY disappointed in the 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Was VERY disappointed in the service. Took at least 10 minutes after sitting for someone to get our drink orders and greet us. Waiter then proceeded to give us a 10 minute sales pitch/contest about eating at all of Zack&apos;s restaurants which i felt was totally uncalled for and is better left for email or facebook marketing. She also had a very poor presentation of the food specials. I thought it was perhaps her first night but it wasn&apos;t. At the end of the meal, the waiter wished the wrong person a Happy Birthday..very underwhelmed! &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 26 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Menu offered good array of 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Menu offered good array of choices for non-meat eaters. Imaginative seasonings. Loved the preparation for the Lake Superior white fish. Suggest early reservation, since restaurant became quite noisy as it filled because of high ceilings that carry sound. &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2012 Special Features: special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 27 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Husband thought his salmon 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/22/2012 2007 Dined on 06/22/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Husband thought his salmon was the best presentation he has EVER tasted. Decor a bit austere but well done. &quot; Dined on 06/22/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 28 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 will not go back 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Food (Fair) 2 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; &quot;Bacon and eggs&quot;for an appetizer was outstanding. My salad with fried chicken livers had way too much vinegar. The butternut squash ravioli was disapointing... where was the butternut squash? it was mostly&quot;greens&quot;...very coarse greens...not delicate spinach...and jalapenos and pancetta??? strange pairing of foods. It didnt work. &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2007 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 29 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 $32 for two lunches that could 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/20/2012 2007 Dined on 06/20/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; $32 for two lunches that could have cost twice that and we would have been happy. Just superb. &quot; Dined on 06/20/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 30 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Excellent service when attending 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/20/2012 2006 Dined on 06/20/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Excellent service when attending a play. &quot; Dined on 06/20/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 31 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The food was excellent and 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/17/2012 2012 Dined on 06/17/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; The food was excellent and except for one incident, the servers were very attentive. Our water glasses were filled with warm water. When we asked for ice, the server brought glasses filled with ice and placed them on the table next to the warm water glasses. We waited, thinking someone would fill the glasses for us, rather than us trying to pour from the warm water glasses into the new ice-filled glasses and possibly spilling it. We finally had to call a server over and request the glasses be filled. &quot; Dined on 06/17/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 32 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The menu was different in 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2007 Dined on 06/16/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The menu was different in a good way. Interesting appetizers, unusual salads and some of the entrees were unique. Wine selection wasn&apos;t terrific but we did find a really nice petit syrah, but a little pricey. Portions are just right. Th escargot was possibly the best I ever had. &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 33 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 My family and I are big fans 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2009 Dined on 06/16/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; My family and I are big fans of Bruell&apos;s restaurants. Golden trout was one of the best meals I&apos;ve had. &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2009 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , late-night find , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 34 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We felt this restaurant was 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; We felt this restaurant was exceptional...no hurrying thru the meal. Wonderfully paced. Great service from valet to host, waitress, bus and managers all wanting to see that you were satisfied. Food was exceptional! &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 35 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Food was amazing!!!! Run here 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Food was amazing!!!! Run here and try anything on the menu! &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 36 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Overall the food was excellent 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2008 Dined on 06/15/2012 2008 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Overall the food was excellent and the service was good. I&apos;ve never been a fan for large open seating areas but it wasn&apos;t horrible. We had the beef ceviche (excellent), beef cheeks entree (really tasty), and the entree special of halibut (this was outstanding). All of the staff were very nice and helpful. &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 37 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Appetizers and Desserts were 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/14/2012 2007 Dined on 06/14/2012 2007 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Appetizers and Desserts were excellent; however I selected the wrong entree - breaded frogs legs which were very heavily breaded leaving not much flavor on the actual flesh of the legs. My best experience with frogs legs has been Paris and there was no heavy breading. But the other entrees seemed quite good and interesting; will try on our next visit. &quot; Dined on 06/14/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 38 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Zack B. does it again! great 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/07/2012 2003 Dined on 06/07/2012 2003 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Zack B. does it again! great food, cool ambiance and fantastic service.....the triple crown of restaurants! &quot; Dined on 06/07/2012 2003 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 39 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Imaginative, delicious food! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/13/2012 2010 Dined on 06/13/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Imaginative, delicious food! Friendly, attentive service. A much needed addition to Playhouse Square. Great for pre-theater or as a destination. &quot; Dined on 06/13/2012 2010 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 40 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 3 People 1 Entree? We had 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; 3 People 1 Entree? We had a group of three dining at the restaurant on June 9, which was our third dining experience there. We ordered three appetizers and shared them. When our server came to take our dinner order, we ordered the same- three frog leg dinners and the same sides. After waiting for our dinner, she brought us one order of frog legs and&quot;thought&quot;we were going to share it. It seems that diners who order (4) cocktails and (3) appetizers are not the type to share a dinner. Bad move on her part and an inconvenience for us. If she was unsure, she should have asked for clarification. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 41 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Terrific Restaurant 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2011 Dined on 06/09/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; One of the best restaurants in Cleveland. The food was outstanding, and the service was terrific. Enjoyable experience. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2011 Special Features: good for groups , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 42 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The food and service was very 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2010 Dined on 06/09/2012 2010 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The food and service was very good. This is my third time at the restaurant in the last few months. The menu is very imaginative and comprehensive. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 43 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We REALLY enjoyed our visit 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/08/2012 2006 Dined on 06/08/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We REALLY enjoyed our visit and we will be back soon. &quot; Dined on 06/08/2012 2006 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 44 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Minimalism style, high ceiling, 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Minimalism style, high ceiling, open kitchen restaurant format. Fish prepared perfectly, appetizing presentation and interesting blends, using fresh ingredients, nuts, and rich sauces. We went on a&quot;slow&quot;night and received great, but not charming, wait staff attention. Efficiently run restaurant that can turn around meals quickly for theater crowd. Mostly older patrons/foodies with time and money to enjoy Zach Bruell&apos;s creations. Pitches given for summer tour of restaurants card/drawings. A great blend of best restaurant/business practices; however, not cozy or romantic for our 33rd anniversary dinner. Spent most of the time looking at the other diners, no wall art or views, one TV above bar showing Belmont Race. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 45 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We had really good food. The 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/07/2012 2012 Dined on 06/07/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 &quot; We had really good food. The waiter staff was always there. Spoke with the manager. He was very informative and answered all our questions. &quot; Dined on 06/07/2012 2012 Special Features: good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 46 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The food was wonderful! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2009 Dined on 06/09/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The food was wonderful! The building is just a beautiful environment. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 47 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 This was our first visit. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; This was our first visit. We are vegetarian but went as a colleague reported good veggie choices. We tried the fried bean appetizer -decent but needs a little salt. The noodles were excellent. The squash pizza was average. The chunks of squash are just too large and the taste too bold. In fact, a purée of squash (almost like a substitue for tomato paste) might work better ( with onion etc embedded). The wine and waitress were excellent. Finally, I think the individuals passing put bread in the beginning are too aggressive. After the first 2 pieces, it is best to ask instead of just repetitively loading the plates. This applies to L&apos;albatrose as well. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2012 Special Features: good for groups Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 48 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Bruell does it again with C&amp;H 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/07/2012 2007 Dined on 06/07/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; this was our first time to Cowell&amp;Hubbard for dinner and it was a wonderful experience. We&apos;ve long been fans of Zack Bruell going back to Z in the mid 80s. Zack has raised the bar for fine dining in Cleveland and Cowell&amp;Hubbard was no exception to Zack&apos;s other restaurants. Our servers were attentive and personable but not to the point of being intrusive. There when we needed them and ready to offer helpful information or answer questions. The food was exceptional! The dishes that we ordered included salmon, trout, noodles and risotto. All were prepared to perfection the flavors/seasoning made each dish special and memorable. A new favorite in Cleveland - we will be back! &quot; Dined on 06/07/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 49 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Our waitress was terrific 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/02/2012 2009 Dined on 06/02/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Our waitress was terrific - don&apos;t remember her name but she is a student at YSU - she is a classy young woman and gives the restaurant a heightened level of class. The food was terrific and the service and great wine added to the delightful evening. &quot; Dined on 06/02/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 50 for Cowell&amp;Hubbard Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 impeccable, the service is 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/02/2012 2010 Dined on 06/02/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 &quot; impeccable, the service is perfect. will definitely be back here. &quot; Dined on 06/02/2012 2010 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , great for lunch , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. 1 2 3 4 5 6 next &gt;&gt;
	</body>
</document>
