<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006555" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/203/1047492/restaurant/Rosas-Cafe-Tortilla-Factory-Lubbock" time="2012-07-12-23:29" support="28" score="0.08891862326726535" bingtitle="Rosa&apos;s Cafe &amp; Tortilla Factory - Lubbock | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Rosa&apos;s CafeTortilla Factory - Lubbock | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000653" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000014" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000639" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>... prices for what amounts to a hybrid fast food restaurant. ... condiments etc...try to find a place to sit, pick up ... feel you aren&apos;t spitting out your order ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Lubbock » Lubbock » Rosa&apos;s Cafe&amp;Tortilla... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Albuquerque Austin Dallas/Fort Worth Los Angeles New York Oklahoma City San Antonio More... 
 
Rosa&apos;s Cafe&amp;Tortilla Factory

 View all 3 Rosa&apos;s Cafe&amp;Tortilla Factory locations 
 
(806) 794-2285
 Lubbock 5103 82nd St 
 Lubbock , TX 79424 See all 15 reviews Cuisine Mexican Menu $ Under $10 per entree Sour cream chicken enchiladas, tacos View menu   274 people have voted 85 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Abuelo&apos;s Mexican Food... 82% $$$ Lubbock - Mexican 4401 82nd St 
 
 Chick-fil-A 89% $ Lubbock - Fast Food, Chicken 6820 Slide Rd 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 June 29, 2012 Likes it Speed and Service by ElJefe ( 4 reviews ) These employees are trained very well and get food to you super fast. It&apos;s kinda the Chick Fil A model but for Mexican food. I see lots of familiar faces behind the counter as well. They like working there! I love eating there! March 30, 2012 Likes it Fast and Cheap by Kris ( 8 reviews ) The first time that I had Rosa&apos;s I fell in love. I got my food so quickly and the prices are amazing... especially on Taco Tuesday. I do find, however, that they are inconsistent. It is a fast food place after all, and sometimes I go and get disappointed. Rosa&apos;s is by no mean restaurant quality food, but it is good fast tex-mex that satisfies my cravings for a good taco. October 12, 2011 Rosa&apos;s makes me see red by RedRaiderZ ( 45 reviews ) The parking here tends to be atrocious and you better be mindful of the people winding through the parking lot for to-go orders. It galls me a little that you stand in line, get your own drinks, condiments, silverware, etc. and are paying regular sit-down restaurant prices. That all said, their fajita meat is tender, mesquite grilled, and the taste is outstanding. To avoid feeling wallet raped, I take the family on&quot;Taco Tuesdays&quot;where you can get a 3 taco platter for about $3.50. This is a pretty good deal. However, it still irks me that I am paying meal prices for what amounts to a hybrid fast food restaurant. Good food, but a bit pricey for what it is. May 16, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it This place has YOU figured out!! by Trust Me Food Critic ( 118 reviews ) I am still trying to figure out what the huge attraction is with this place? Yes it is very popular and busy all the time. lets break this down: Stand in line, pay regular sit down restaurant prices, get all your own drinks, condiments etc...try to find a place to sit, pick up your food at the counter...and eat what I think is kinda crummy Mexican food?! Yes my kids love it and I have to eat here at least once a week and yes it burns me every time I see how much I pay for 4. Geez. April 16, 2011 Likes it Good chain food by Purist ( 36 reviews ) We go to this location once a month. The food is consistantly good. We enjoy the fresh made tortillas. They do have a few cashiers up front who tend to get a bit impatient when they feel you aren&apos;t spitting out your order fast enough. We&apos;ve taken family here to eat and they loved the fresh tortillas and the atmosphere. December 25, 2010 Really likes it Mobile review by J. M. Clark IV ( 26 reviews ) Will always be one if my favorite places to eat of all time!! September 12, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Ally15 ( 88 reviews ) Tortillas are the only saving grace. Otherwise it&apos;s like Taco Villa, only more expensive. I think the beer attracts some, too. May 2, 2010 Likes it It is what it is by Lost in Lubbock ( 37 reviews ) This is Lubbock&apos;s version of Taco Cabana. March 27, 2010 Likes it A Better Fast Food Option by KY Connection ( 337 reviews ) OK, OK, OK...not top notch mexican food, but it is better than going to McD&apos;s or BK. Tortilla&apos;s are really good. December 28, 2009 Likes it Fresh Tortillas by slcfoodie ( 51 reviews ) There is just no comparison to the fresh flour tortillas they make here. Especially dipped in their queso or honey. I come here just for the tortillas although they also have good tamales and chicken tacos. May 11, 2009 Mobile review by rebecca ( 43 reviews ) If I&apos;m gonna do fast food I&apos;ll pick Rosa&apos;s over burger chains. The beef fajita plate is kind of a guilty pleasure. September 14, 2009 Mobile review by Colby Heatwole ( 1 review ) The most bland food in Lubbock. Everything tastes the same. Not a good plce to eat if you actually like tasting different flavors. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 10, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by A. ( 14 reviews ) great tortillas but it stops there...the rest of the food is pretty sub par July 8, 2011 82nd Street location by Mary ( 2 reviews ) Usually go to the location on 50th Street. Never had any problems there. Went to 82nd street last night. Order was incorrect and had to correct. Had to explain 3 times what was incorrect. Got home the food was cold (only a 3 minute drive) Cheese enchildas were tough and one plate has liquid water or grease floating. Even the chips tasted old and were not even warm. I will stick to the 50th street location. September 29, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Someone needs to be introduced to spices. by BigD ( 5 reviews ) Tortillas are good... the rest is terribly bland. I have no idea why Rosa&apos;s is always so packed. I drive by and all I can think is how some people have no taste. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos
 Be the first to contribute a photo for this restaurant. View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Noble Roman&apos;s Lubbock - Pizza Pizza Hut 76% $ Lubbock - Pizza, Fast Food Shrimp Galley 80% $$ Lubbock - Seafood Sheridan&apos;s Lattes&amp;Frozen... 91% $ Lubbock - Desserts/Ice Cream Taco Villa 78% $ Lubbock - Tacos, Mexican 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 grilled chicken platters a rosas cafe t how much is a beef&amp;chicken fajitas plate cost in lubbock tx rosa&apos;s cafe lubbock rosa&apos;s lubbock rosa&apos;s restaurant lubbock tx 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
