<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006635" url="http://www.oberbeckfarm.org/oberbeck-hoa/dues.html" time="2012-07-12-23:35" support="1" score="0.0005469696011534891" bingtitle="Dues &amp; Membership Information - Oberbeck Neighborhood Association ..." webtitle="Dues&amp;Membership Information - Oberbeck Neighborhood Association | Oberbeck Farm Neighborhood">
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>To make payment, please send $50 per ... with your Name, Address, Phone Number and Email Address. Please make ... What Fast-Food Restaurant Would You Like to Have at ...</description>
	<body>
		Oberbeck Farm Neighborhood Events and news within the area. Skip to content 
 Home About Us Contact Us HOA Info 
 Dues/Membership Officers 2012 HOA Meeting Minutes Rezoning Petition 
 Downloads Area Info 
 Local Schools Local Neighborhoods Oberbeck Handyman Resources 
 Safety Lost&amp;Found Photos 
 Browse Photos Upload Photos! 
 Site Map 
 
Dues and Membership
 
Membership and participation in our Neighborhood Association is on a volunteer basis. All neighbors are highly encouraged to join and participate.

 Annual dues are $50. To make payment, please send $50 per household to Patty Madigan along with your Name, Address, Phone Number and Email Address. Please make checks payable to“Oberbeck Neighbors”and mail payment to the following address:

Oberbeck Neighbors
c/o Patty Madigan
2616 Heidleburg Lane
Charlotte, NC  28210

 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
 
Site Search
 Search for: 
Latest Poll
 
 

 

 What Fast-Food Restaurant Would You Like to Have at Quail Corners Shopping Center? (Choose Two) 
 
 Chick-Fil-A Bojangles McDonald&apos;s Zaxby&apos;s 

 

 View Results 
  Loading ... 
 Polls Archive 
 
Subscribe for Updates!
 

   Subscribe For Updates! 

 

 

 
 
About Oberbeck Farm
 Oberbeck Farm is a Crosland Home development built in the late 70&apos;s and early 80&apos;s. It is a lovely, quiet, wooded neighborhood consisting of 160 homes, all built on cul de sacs. The two entrances to our neighborhood are from Sharon Road West and an indirect entrance from Lytham Road in Brandon Forest. 
 
 
Neighborhood Handy Man
 
 
Cell:(704) 293-2502
Home:(704) 554-8447
 juluka@aol.com 
 Click Here for More Info 
 
Recent Posts

 McDonald’s Coming to Quail Corners CMPD South Division Response Area 1 April Newsletter Two Dogs Found on Heidleburg Lane Found Item–Black CD Case Pinestraw Orders for 2012 
 
Article Categories

 Lost&amp;Found Neighborhood Association Neighborhood News Newsletter Redevelopment Plan Safety 
 
 
 
 South Charlotte News 

 SouthPark neighbors fight for changes to new apartment complex July 12, 2012 Neighbors in South Park are frustrated and taking their fight to City Council after developers began moving forward with plans for a nearly ten-story high apartment complex. It&apos;s planned for the vacant lot at Morrison and Barclay Downs Road. […] Restaurant Inspections | SouthPark Mall bistro earns low grade July 5, 2012 These are the best and worst restaurant health inspection scores for June 20 -26 filed by the Mecklenburg County Health Department. The scores are in percentages. […] Cam Newton to hold autograph session at SouthPark Mall July 2, 2012 For the first time in Charlotte, Carolina Panthers quarterback Cam Newton will hold an autograph appearance later this month. […] Police: Wrestler Ric Flair, wife involved in fight June 26, 2012 Ric Flair and his wife were involved in an altercation at the couple&apos;s SouthPark condo Monday night, according to a Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department report. […] 
 
 
 
Calendar
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Apr       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
 
 
Login/Subscribe

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org [Un]Subscribe to Posts 
 
 
 
Local Links

 Cameron Wood Huntingtowne Farms Park Crossing Quail Hollow Quail Hollow Estates 
 
 
 
 Oberbeck Farm Neighborhood Proudly powered by WordPress. 
 Site Maintained by Ferguson SEO - Charlotte SEO Firm
	</body>
</document>
