<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006017" url="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/fast-food-fix-devin-alexander/1007464267" time="2012-07-12-22:41" support="11" score="0.028753163451123644" bingtitle="Fast Food Fix: 75+ Amazing Recipe Makeovers of Your Fast Food ..." webtitle="BARNES&amp;NOBLE | Fast Food Fix: 75+ Amazing Recipe Makeovers of Your Fast Food Restaurant Favorites by Devin Alexander, Rodale Press, Inc. | Paperback">
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>Kane Chronicles: Pre-Order The Serpent&apos;s ... Fix: 75+ Amazing Recipe Makeovers of Your Fast Food Restaurant ... Tell the world what you think of this product.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Content Sign in My Account 
 Account Settings Wish List 
 Order Status My NOOK Stores&amp;Events Help 
 
 FREE Express Shipping with Membership Criterion Collection and More: 50% Off DVDs and Blu-ray Summer at B&amp;N: Book Recommendations for All 
 
 All Products Books NOOK Store NOOK Books Movies&amp;TV Music Kids&apos; Books Marketplace Rare Books Newsstand Calendars Home&amp;Gifts Toys&amp;Games 
 Search Over 30 Million Products Search 
 Shopping Bag ( 0
 items ) Spend $25, Get FREE SHIPPING 
 
 Books 
 
Customer Favorites
 B&amp;N Top 100 NY Times Bestsellers Best Books of the Month Trending Books New Releases Coming Soon Recommended Discover Great New Writers Award Winners Bestsellers by Subject Barnes&amp;Noble Classics 
Subjects
 Biography Business Cookbooks Fiction Graphic Novels History Mystery Religion&amp;Inspiration Science Fiction/Fantasy Self-Improvement See More 
Departments
 NOOK Books Bargain Books Calendars The Paperback Store Professional Books Rare&amp;Collectible Libros en español Audio&amp;MP3 Books 
B&amp;N Exclusives
 B&amp;N Review Blogs&amp;Forums Promotions Best of the Month Explore our hand-picked list of new books that stand out as the best of the best in July. Shop Now 
 NOOK Books 
 
Customer Favorites
 B&amp;N Top 100 NY Times Bestsellers Trending NOOK Books New Releases Coming Soon NOOK Books Deals NOOK Books en español B&amp;N Classics LendMe™ Books PubIt!™ Books NOOK Snaps 
Subjects
 Biography Fiction Health&amp;Fitness History Mystery Politics&amp;Current Affairs Religion&amp;Inspiration Romance Sci-Fi&amp;Fantasy Self-Improvement Teen Books See More 
Departments
 NOOK Comics Kids&apos; Books NOOK Kids Read To Me™ NOOK Kids Read and Play™ Newsstand NOOK Apps 
NOOK Store
 Shop NOOK Free Reading Apps My NOOK Library NOOK Daily Find A great read at a great price! Don&apos;t miss out on today&apos;s irresistible deal. Buy Now 
 NOOK 
 
NOOK Tablet
 Overview Features Accessories Support 
NOOK Color
 Overview Features Accessories Support 
NOOK Simple Touch with GlowLight
 Overview Features Accessories Support 
NOOK Simple Touch
 Overview Features Accessories Support 
Free Reading Apps
 NOOK for Android™ NOOK for iPhone® NOOK for iPad® NOOK for PC™ NOOK for Mac™ See More 
NOOK Store
 Books Newsstand Kids&apos; Books Apps Accessories Compare Our NOOKs Introducing NOOK Simple Touch™ with GlowLight™ Learn More 
 Textbooks 
 
Departments
 Used Rental eTextbooks New Sell Your Textbooks FAQ 
Subjects
 Business Computer Education History Medicine Philosophy Politics&amp;Current Affairs Psychology Science See More 
NOOK Study
 Overview Download for Free Reviews For Professors Support 
 Newsstand 
 
NOOK Newsstand
 NOOK Magazines NOOK Newspapers All NOOK Periodicals Top Free Trials Hot New Titles Special Issues 
Print Newsstand
 Over 900 Print Subscriptions Dozens of Categories Bestselling Subscriptions Subscriptions Under $10 
NOOK Favorites
 Women&apos;s Magazines Men&apos;s Magazines Business Publications 
Print Favorites
 Women&apos;s Magazines Men&apos;s Magazines 
 
 Summer Reading Favorites Try any NOOK Newsstand Title FREE for 14 Days! Start a Free Trial 
 Teens 
 
Customer Favorites
 Bestsellers Must-Reads New Releases Coming Soon NOOK Books Best Books of 2011 
Popular Authors
 Sarah Dessen Ellen Hopkins Michael Scott Cassandra Clare Scott Westerfeld 
Subjects
 Edgy Stories for Teens Fantasy&amp;Adventure Girls&amp;Young Women Paranormal Romance Reference&amp;Study Guides Romance&amp;Friendship See More 
Award Winners
 Michael L. Printz Awards National Book Awards Agatha Awards Edgar Awards 
Bestselling Series
 Inheritance Cycle Hunger Games Twilight Pretty Little Liars Wolves of Mercy House of Night Vampire Academy 
 Kids 
 
Customer Favorites
 Bestsellers Staff Picks New Releases Coming Soon NOOK Kids 
Age Groups
 0-2 3-5 6-8 9-12 Teens 
Bestselling Series
 Diary of a Wimpy Kid Harry Potter The Worlds of Rick Riordan Dr. Seuss American Girl 
Formats
 Picture Books Board Books Early Readers Paperbacks Read to Me 
More for Kids
 Summer Reading Program NOOK Kids for iPad Toys&amp;Games Online Storytime B&amp;N Parents&apos; Expert Circle B&amp;N Kids&apos; Club B&amp;N @ School Kids&apos; DVD Kids&apos; Music 
 Toys&amp;Games 
 
Popular Categories
 Bestsellers Building&amp;LEGO Games for Grown-ups Baby&amp;Toddler Toys Baby Boutique Dolls&amp;Stuffed Animals Electronic Toys See More 
Brands&amp;Characters
 LeapFrog LEGO Melissa&amp;Doug Star Wars Barbie 
Age Groups
 0 - 12 Months 1-2 3-5 6-8 9-11 12-14 Tween Girl Boutique 15&amp;Up 
Price
 Hot Deals $25 and Under $25 - $50 $50 - $100 
More for Kids
 NOOK Kids for iPad Toys&amp;Games Online Storytime B&amp;N Parents&apos; Expert Circle B&amp;N Kids&apos; Club B&amp;N @ School Kids&apos; DVD Kids&apos; Music 
 Home&amp;Gifts 
 
Popular Categories
 Electronics Journals&amp;Planners Bags&amp;Totes Decorative Accents Reading Aids Stationery&amp;Writing Desk&amp;Office Accessories Food&amp;Gourmet Gifts Entertaining&amp;Partyware See More 
Gift Giving
 Bestsellers What&apos;s New For Her For Him 
Favorite Brands
 Moleskine Vera Bradley Ecosystem Jonathan Adler 
Favorite Shops
 Hot Deals Experiential Gifts Eco-Friendly Gifts 
Price
 On Sale $25 and Under $25 - $50 $50 - $100 $100 and Up Summer Tote Just $9.95 with Purchase
(Reg. $24.95) Shop Now 
 DVDs 
 
Customer Favorites
 Bestsellers New Releases Coming Soon Blu-ray Box Sets 
Deals
 Girls&apos; Night In DVDs Under $10 Blu-ray Under $15 See All Deals 
Genres
 TV on DVD Action Art House/ Foreign Classics Comedy Documentary Drama Fitness/ Instructional Kids Music&amp;Musicals Sci-Fi/ Horror See More 
Special Collections
 As Seen on Public TV BBC British Television Criterion Disney HBO Yoga Lifestyle 
Related Categories
 Electronics Music Art House Sale Save 50% on Hundreds of DVDs and Blu-rays, including the Criterion Collection. Shop Now 
 Music 
 
Customer Favorites
 Bestsellers New Releases Coming Soon Box Sets 
Deals
 Music Deals B&amp;N Exclusives $4.99 CD Sale 
Genres
 Blues&amp;Folk Music Broadway&amp;Vocal Children&apos;s Music Classical Country Music Jazz Pop Music Rock Soundtracks See More 
Special Collections
 Artists Den Beatles Discover Great New Music Vinyl LPs 
Related Categories
 Audio&amp;MP3 Books Electronics 
 Gift Cards 
 
Gift Cards
 Gift Cards eGift Cards Customize Your Gift Cards Corporate Sales 
Instant Gifting
 Send Nook Books™ and Nook Apps™ 
Popular Gift Cards
 B&amp;N Green NOOK Birthday Kids Birthday See More 
FAQs
 Check your balance Redeem eBooks Gift Card Gift Card Help Delivery Schedule 
 
 Close 
 1 / 6 
 
 
 
Fast Food Fix: 75+ Amazing Recipe Makeovers of Your Fast Food Restaurant Favorites

 by Devin Alexander 
 Add to List + Add to List + 
 My B&amp;N Library My Favorites My Wish List Reading Now 
 New Essential List Create a new Essential List 
Please name your Essential List:

 New Essential List 

You may add a description of the list:

 
 Submit Cancel New Wish List Create a new Wish List 
Please name your Wish List:

 New Wish List 

You may add a description of the list:

 
 Submit Cancel 
 
 ( 7 ) Add to Bag Pick Up In Store 
Pick Up in Store

Reserve and pick up in 60 minutes at your local store
 Find In-store Enter your zip code Paperback $12.78 BN.com price $17.99 List Price (Save 0.29) Eligible for FREE SHIPPING details Usually ships within 24 hours - Same Day delivery in Manhattan details Marketplace (New and Used) from $0.43 $17.99 List Price (Save 0.976097832128960534000074382865533031825558088301552078) Usually ships in 1-2 business days All (37)    Used (19)    New (18)    Close Sort by Price (Low to High) Price (High to Low) Condition Seller Rating Page 1 of 4 Next Showing 1–10 of 37 (4 pages) Add to Bag $0.43 GreenEarthBooks Seller since Thu Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2009 
Feedback rating:

 ( 4946 )
 Condition: 
 New —never opened or used in original packaging.

 Like New —packaging may have been opened. A &quot;Like New&quot; item is suitable to give as a gift.

 Very Good —may have minor signs of wear on packaging but item works perfectly and has no damage.

 Good —item is in good condition but packaging may have signs of shelf wear/aging or torn packaging. All specific defects should be noted in the Comments section associated with each item.

 Acceptable —item is in working order but may show signs of wear such as scratches or torn packaging. All specific defects should be noted in the Comments section associated with each item.

 Used —An item that has been opened and may show signs of wear. All specific defects should be noted in the Comments section associated with each item.

 Refurbished —A used item that has been renewed or updated and verified to be in proper working condition. Not necessarily completed by the original manufacturer.
 Good Light shelving wear with minimal damage to cover and bindings. Pages show minor use. Help save a tree. Buy all your used books from Green Earth Books. Read. Recycle and ... Reuse! Read more Show Less 
 Ships from: Portland, OR

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $0.99 Better World Books Seller since Sun Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2006 
Feedback rating:

 ( 51254 )
 Condition: Very Good Great condition for a used book! Minimal wear. 100% Money Back Guarantee. Shipped to over one million happy customers. Your purchase benefits world literacy! 
 Ships from: Mishawaka, IN

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.00 Goodwillnyonline Seller since Thu Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2009 
Feedback rating:

 ( 565 )
 Condition: Good Good 
 Ships from: Astoria, NY

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.97 Ebooksweb Seller since Thu Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2009 
Feedback rating:

 ( 1816 )
 Condition: New 4/18/2006 Paperback New 1594863105 Ships Within 24 Hours. Tracking Number available for all USA orders. Excellent Customer Service. Upto 15 Days 100% Money Back Gurantee. Try ... Our Fast! ! ! ! Shipping With Tracking Number. Read more Show Less 
 Ships from: Bensalem, PA

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.97 Vitalbooks PA Seller since Fri Jan 06 15:05:44 EST 2012 
Feedback rating:

 ( 127 )
 Condition: Like New PAPERBACK Fine 1594863105 Ships Fast. All standard orders delivered within 5 to 12 business days. May have a remainder mark. 
 Ships from: Southampton, PA

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.98 Vitalbooks PA Seller since Fri Jan 06 15:05:44 EST 2012 
Feedback rating:

 ( 127 )
 Condition: New PAPERBACK New 1594863105 Ships Fast. All standard orders delivered within 5 to 12 business days. 
 Ships from: Southampton, PA

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.99 RiverCityBooks Seller since Tue Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2008 
Feedback rating:

 ( 2263 )
 Condition: Good GOOD with average wear to cover, pages and binding. We ship quickly and work hard to earn your confidence. Orders are generally shipped no later than next business day. We offer a ... no hassle guarantee on all our items. Read more Show Less 
 Ships from: Tualatin, OR

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.99 New Chapter Recycling Seller since Fri Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2010 
Feedback rating:

 ( 3530 )
 Condition: Very Good 
 Ships from: Lakewood, WA

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $1.99 GIANTBOOKSALE Seller since Tue Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2008 
Feedback rating:

 ( 3671 )
 Condition: New 1594863105 SHIPS TODAY!! GREAT BOOK!! 
 Ships from: BAY SHORE, NY

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Canadian • International • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Add to Bag $3.60 Paper_Tiger_Books Seller since Mon Jan 01 01:01:01 EST 2007 
Feedback rating:

 ( 3724 )
 Condition: Acceptable 1594863105 Cover is partially torn from book. Moderate-heavy wear to edges/binding. 
 Ships from: Pittsburgh, PA

Usually ships in 1-2 business days

 • Standard, 48 States • Standard (AK, HI) • Express, 48 States • Express (AK, HI) 
 Page 1 of 4 Next Showing 1–10 of 37 (4 pages) Close Sort by Price (Low to High) Price (High to Low) Condition Seller Rating 
Overview

Indulge your fast food cravings without guilt—with recipes that deliver the same great taste without putting your health at risk or inches on your hips

Americans all want to &quot;eat healthy,&quot; but when they yearn for the fast foods they love, what they want most are the fabulous flavors that have made them favorites in the first place. That&apos;s what makes this collection of recipe makeovers so exceptional. Los Angeles food writer, chef, and caterer Devin Alexander specializes in low-fat, high-flavor, scrumptious cuisine. In Fast Food Fix, she shows the reader how to transform 75 fast food favorites into healthier versions that are even more flavorful ...
 See more details below 
 Want to read this on your NOOK? Request as NOOK Book from the publisher Thank you for requesting this book as a NOOK book from the publisher. 
 Sending request ... 
Customers Who Bought This Also Bought
 
 I Can&apos;t Believe It&apos;s Not... Devin Alexander Paperback $15.98 Buy Now Six O&apos;Clock Scramble: Quick,... Aviva Goldfarb Paperback $11.80 Buy Now Top Secret Recipes: Creating... Todd Wilbur Paperback $14.00 Buy Now Real Simple: Meals Made Easy Real Simple Magazine Editors Hardcover $16.41 Buy Now Top Secret Restaurant Recipes:... Todd Wilbur Paperback $13.98 Buy Now Sam the Cooking Guy: Just a... Sam Zien Paperback $12.38 Buy Now Rachael Ray Express Lane... Rachael Ray Paperback $12.98 Buy Now Top Secret Restaurant Recipes... Todd Wilbur Paperback $13.98 Buy Now Dream Dinners: Turn Dinner... Stephanie Allen Paperback $15.98 Buy Now Even More Top Secret Recipes:... Todd Wilbur Paperback $14.00 Buy Now 
 
More About
 This Book
 
 Overview Editorial Reviews Product Details Meet the Author 
 Advertising 
Overview

Indulge your fast food cravings without guilt—with recipes that deliver the same great taste without putting your health at risk or inches on your hips

Americans all want to &quot;eat healthy,&quot; but when they yearn for the fast foods they love, what they want most are the fabulous flavors that have made them favorites in the first place. That&apos;s what makes this collection of recipe makeovers so exceptional. Los Angeles food writer, chef, and caterer Devin Alexander specializes in low-fat, high-flavor, scrumptious cuisine. In Fast Food Fix, she shows the reader how to transform 75 fast food favorites into healthier versions that are even more flavorful than the originals. Fast Food Fix:

• demystifies the special seasonings and secret sauces of choice fast foods—showing how to reproduce their flavors quickly and easily from common ingredients

• teaches how to lighten many dishes with new cooking techniques, such as the oven-frying method that yields incredibly crunchy popcorn chicken with 35 fewer fat grams than the original version from KFC

• reveals simplified cooking methods that save time in the kitchen, proving that &quot;fast food&quot; can still be fast even when prepared at home

For Americans hooked on fast food flavors, these recipe makeovers by a chef with an impressive repertoire of culinary tricks will quickly become a kitchen staple.
 
Related Subjects

 Diets - Better Health Quick&amp;Easy Cooking 
 
Editorial Reviews
 
Library Journal
Alexander, a Los Angeles caterer, gave up eating fast food years ago-and eventually lost more than 50 pounds. However, she knows that Americans love their Big Macs, KFC Popcorn Chicken, and Pizza Hut Pan Pizzas, so she set out to create lower-fat renditions of these and other fast-food standards that would still be flavorful and satisfying. Each recipe includes a careful nutritional analysis of &quot;before and after,&quot; and many recipes offer a &quot;Drive-Thru&quot; tip, make-ahead information to make preparation easier. Todd Wilbur&apos;s &quot;Top Secret&quot; series provides templates for duplicating fast-food favorites (loaded with fat or not) at home; Alexander&apos;s book is for cooks who want a healthier approach. For most collections. Copyright 2006 Reed Business Information. 
Product Details
 
 ISBN-13: 9781594863103 Publisher: Rodale Press, Inc. Publication date: 4/18/2006 Pages: 240 Sales rank: 336427 Product dimensions: 7.10 (w) x 10.03 (h) x 0.67 (d) 
 
Meet the Author
 
DEVIN ALEXANDER is the owner and executive chef of Café Renée Catering in Los Angeles. Having lost 55 pounds herself (and kept it off), she specializes in delicious, flavorful, low-fat cuisine. Devin has made numerous television appearances and has written more than 60 food-related articles for popular magazines. She lives in Los Angeles.
 
Customer Reviews
 Average Rating 3.5 ( 7 ) 
Rating Distribution
 
5 Star
 (3) 
4 Star
 (0) 
3 Star
 (2) 
2 Star
 (2) 
1 Star
 (0) 
Your Rating:
 Review Guidelines Tell the world what you think of this product. 
Your Recommendations:
 Add Recommendations 
   
 Your Name: Create a Pen Name or Leave Anonymously Submit 
Barnes&amp;Noble.com Review Rules

Our reader reviews allow you to share your comments on titles you liked,
 or didn&apos;t, with others. By submitting an online review, you are representing to
 Barnes&amp;Noble.com that all information contained in your review is original
 and accurate in all respects, and that the submission of such content by you
 and the posting of such content by Barnes&amp;Noble.com does not and will not
 violate the rights of any third party. Please follow the rules below to help
 ensure that your review can be posted.

Reviews by Our Customers Under the Age of 13

We highly value and respect everyone&apos;s opinion concerning the titles we offer.
 However, we cannot allow persons under the age of 13 to have accounts at BN.com or
 to post customer reviews. Please see our Terms of Use for more details.

What to exclude from your review:

Please do not write about reviews, commentary, or information posted on the product page. If you see any errors in the
 information on the product page, please send us an email.

Reviews should not contain any of the following:

 - HTML tags, profanity, obscenities, vulgarities, or comments that defame anyone - Time-sensitive information such as tour dates, signings, lectures, etc. - Single-word reviews. Other people will read your review to discover why you liked or didn&apos;t like the title. Be descriptive. - Comments focusing on the author or that may ruin the ending for others - Phone numbers, addresses, URLs - Pricing and availability information or alternative ordering information - Advertisements or commercial solicitation 

Reminder:

 - By submitting a review, you grant to Barnes&amp;Noble.com and its
 sublicensees the royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable right and license to use the
 review in accordance with the Barnes&amp;Noble.com Terms of Use . - Barnes&amp;Noble.com reserves the right not to post any review -- particularly
 those that do not follow the terms and conditions of these Rules. Barnes&amp;Noble.com
 also reserves the right to remove any review at any time without notice. - See Terms of Use for other conditions and disclaimers. 
 Search for Products You&apos;d Like to Recommend 
Recommend other products that relate to your review. Just search for them below and share!
 Search Over 30 Million Products Search Create a Pen Name 
Your Pen Name is your unique identiy on BN.com. It will appear on the reviews you write and other website activities. Your Pen Name cannot be edited, changed or deleted once submitted. 

 Pen Name Your Pen Name can be any combination of alphanumeric characters (plus - and _), and must be at least two characters long. 

 

 Continue Anonymously 
 {value} 
 We&apos;re sorry, but penname is already taken. 
Please select one of the following: Or choose another Pen Name Your Pen Name can be any combination of alphanumeric characters (plus - and _), and must be at least two characters long. 
 

 Continue Anonymously 
 
 penname is available! 

By visiting the BN.com website or marking a purchase on BN.com, a User is deemed to have accepted the Terms of Use. 

 

 Continue Anonymously 
 
 Welcome, penname 

You have successfully created your Pen Name. Start enjoying the benefits of the BN.com Community today.

 
 Sort by: Most Helpful Most Recent Highest to Lowest Star Rating Lowest to Highest Star Rating Showing all of 7 Customer Reviews 
 
Bookloverco

Posted Wed Feb 24 00:00:00 EST 2010

I Also Recommend:
 
 YUMMY 

This is a good cookbook to have on hand, I have given this book several times and I am always thanked. The pictures are what the finished product will look like. This is food we eat not food that is to exotic We truly enjoy- Greek Roasted Tilapia Fillets at our home, also Lemon BlueBerry Oatmeal, this book works well with a weight watchers type progam.

 2 out of 2 people found this review helpful.
 Was this review helpful? Yes   No Thank you for your feedback.   Report this review Thank you, this review has been flagged. 
Anonymous

Posted Sun Dec 13 00:00:00 EST 2009
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
Anonymous

Posted Thu Jul 09 00:00:00 EDT 2009
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
Anonymous

Posted Mon Dec 21 00:00:00 EST 2009
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
Anonymous

Posted Thu Mar 25 00:00:00 EDT 2010
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
Anonymous

Posted Wed Dec 02 00:00:00 EST 2009
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
Anonymous

Posted Thu Jan 28 00:00:00 EST 2010
 
 

No text was provided for this review.
 
 Sort by: Most Helpful Most Recent Highest to Lowest Star Rating Lowest to Highest Star Rating Showing all of 7 Customer Reviews If you find inappropriate content, please report it to Barnes&amp;Noble Why is this product inappropriate? Publisher doesn&apos;t hold rights to book Publisher doesn&apos;t hold rights to cover image Inaccurate description Objectionable content Other Comments (optional) 500 character limit Submit Cancel 
Find a B&amp;N Store

Store Hours, Directions, Events&amp;More
 Store Locator 
Read What You Love.

Anywhere You Like.
 NOOK for iPad™ 
 NOOK for iPhone® NOOK for Android™ 
 NOOK for PC™ NOOK for Mac™ 
 Learn More 
Keep Up with BN&apos;s Buzz.
 
B&amp;N Services
 About B&amp;N Investor Relations Barnes&amp;Noble, Inc. Careers at BN.com Advertise Publisher&amp;Author Guidelines B&amp;N Membership Advanced Search B&amp;N MasterCard Bulk Order Discounts B&amp;N Bookfairs My B&amp;N 
Shipping&amp;Delivery
 About Free Shipping About Shipping Shipping Rates Store Returns 
Quick Help
 Customer Service Order Status Easy Returns Product Recalls All Help Topics Sitemap Accessibility Terms of Use , Copyright , and Privacy Policy ©1997-2012 Barnesandnoble.com llc
	</body>
</document>
