<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006507" url="http://www.bedbreakfasttraveler.com/Costa-Rica-bed-and-breakfasts/Hotel-Paseo-Colon_San-Pedro.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:26" support="2" score="0.0015733086447351468" bingtitle="Hotel Paseo Colon, San Pedro - bed and breakfast and hotel reviews ..." webtitle="Hotel Paseo Colon, San Pedro, Costa Rica - Hotel holiday reservations, quality holidays (BedBreakfastTraveler.com)">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>Next To Budget Rent A Car San Pedro San José ... Fast Food Restaurant: Grano De Oro: French &amp; International Cuisine ... Cancellation policy: (booking payments are non ...</description>
	<body>
		Bed Breakfast Traveler .com Hotel Paseo Colon, San Pedro - Secure, fast, easy ... reserve San Pedro and the world with Instant World Booking San Pedro Hotel and Travel Information 
 Rates from $ 50 - 80    
 
 
 
 
 
 
Book Hotel Paseo Colon right online. Check real-time rates and availability in San Pedro. Where instant booking is not available, submit an online request.
 
 
 
 
 
 Hotel Paseo Colon
 San Pedro, Costa Rica 
 Calle 30, Entre Ave 0 Y 2
Next To Budget Rent A Car
San Pedro
San José (Provincia de San José), Costa Rica 827-1000 
 
 

Your best choice in San Jose

 0 Reviews Write a review 

Property type: Hotel      8 guest rooms/units   Built: 1940 , renovated: 2009 
 
 
 
 


 English Cesky-Czech Chinese Deutsch-German Espanol-Spanish Francais-French Greek Hrvatski-Croatian Italiano-Italian Japanese Korean Nederlands-Dutch Polski-Polish Portugues-Portuguese Russian 
 Share 
 
 Welcome 


 Travelers 


 Popular B&amp;Bs 


 Best B&amp;Bs 


 Cheapest B&amp;Bs 


 Work with Us 


 Search B&amp;Bs 


 Read Reviews 



 Find more: 
 Bed&amp;breakfasts&amp;hotels in San Pedro 

 Popular b&amp;bs in San Pedro 

 Best b&amp;bs in San Pedro 

 Cheapest b&amp;bs in San Pedro 

 Bed&amp;breakfasts&amp;hotels in Costa Rica 


 Get more: 
 Availability&amp;rates in San Pedro 


 Read more: 
 B&amp;b reviews in San Pedro 

 B&amp;b reviews in Costa Rica 



 
 Click on photo to enlarge 
 
 show map hide map 
Map
 
 Location is approximate.
 This property has not yet provided their exact GPS location. 
 Find more places: 
 near Hotel Paseo Colon 

 Find nearby accommodation Find accommodations in San José (Provincia de San José) Find tourist spots Find other places of interest Find geographic places Find airports Find transportation hubs Clear all 
 Tip: Click the yellow button on the map.  Then, click to find the nearest accommodation to the pointer. Search in Costa Rica or anywhere in the world. 
 Enable Search by Click 
Overview
 
 
If you need a safe, clean, affordable and comfortable place to stay right in the very heart of the city, our hotel is the best choice for you in our Capital city of San José.
 
Conveniently located just 25 meters away from main street, you will find everything our Capital has to offer: good restaurants, live entertainment, cultural events, museums, stores, recreational facilities, spas, etc.
 
We are located just 20 kilometers away from Juan Santamaría International Airport and 5 kilometers away from our main local airport, Tobias Bolaños, where you can cath a flight to our mayor turistic attractions.
 
If you want to travel within our country and get to the beach, volcanoes or rainforests you can book a tour with us at our tour desk or if you need a car you can rent it with us and it will be delivered right to our front door.
 
 
Location&amp;Transportation
 
   Directions We are located on Street Number 30, between Ave 0 and Ave 2, just 25 meters away from Paseo Colon, right beside Budget Rent a Car.   Transportation There is a bus stop 75 meters away from the hotel and the main bus staion (La Coca Cola) is within walking distance from the hotel (5 blocks away) where you can catch a bus to most beaches and to the country side.   Airport The Juan Santamaria International Airport is 20 kilometers away. 
 
Amenities&amp;Attractions
 
   Local Attractions 
 National Art Museum 700 m. Central Park 1.5 Km. Main Terminal Bus Staion 600 m Sala Garbo Cinema 150 m. National Theater 1.5 Km La Sabana Recreational Park 700 m Public Hospitals 400 m. Fast Food Restaurants within 300 m National Stadium at La Sabana Gold&amp;Coin Museums 1.5 km USA Embassy 3 Km. Multi Plaza Shopping Mall 5 km. National Museum 1.9 Km. Pueblo Antiguo (Typical Town) 9 km. 4 Car Rentals within 100 m. 
   Amenities 
 24-hr front desk Airport pickup Breakfast included Car rental Children permitted Free local phonecalls Icemaker Internet access Internet wireless (free) Laundry/valet service Linen included Multi-lingual staff Newspapers/magazines No curfew Open 24 Hours Parking (free) Pets allowed Taxi service Tour/sightseeing assistance WIFI (free) 
 
 
Guest Room Amenities
 
 
 
We have 7 double rooms, 5 of them have twin beds and 2 have queen beds. We also have 1 Quad room. All of the rooms have private bathrooms with hot water and a small closet with hangers.
 
We have one room accesible by wheelchairs.
 
All of our rooms have free internet Wi-Fi access. We also offer internet access in our computer at the front desk as a courtesy to our clients.
 
We have free coffe and cookies all day as a courtesy to our guests.
 
   Room Types 
 Double Quad Queen Single Twin 
   Room Amenities 
 Ensuite Fax service Handicap facilities Internet access Maid service daily Private bathroom Refrigerator Telephone Television Television (cable/satellite) Wake-up calls 
 
 
Food&amp;Restaurants
 
   Local Restaurants 
 Pizza Hut Fast Food Restaurant Grano De Oro French&amp;International Cuisine KFC Fast Food Restaurant Fogo Brasil Churrascaria Style and International Cuisine Il Pacchino Italian Restaurant 
 
 
Payment Information
 
 Available Discounts: Yes we offer discounts for longer stays and groups. Credit cards accepted on location:   Visa  Visa Electron  MasterCard  Discover  Cancellation policy: (booking payments are non-refundable, unless specified otherwise)
We will accept credit card payments. If you cancel with less than 48 hours upon arrival, the first night will be charged to your credit card. You will have a 50% refund if you cancel within 72 hours prior to arrival and a full refund if you cancel within 15 days prior to arrival during low season (April-November), you will have a full refund if you cancel within 21 days prior to arrival during high season (December-March). 
 
Translate This Page
 
 
  Read about  Hotel Paseo Colon  in your own language
 
 Hotel Paseo Colon information in English Hotel Paseo Colon information in Czech Hotel Paseo Colon information in Chinese Hotel Paseo Colon information in German Hotel Paseo Colon information in Spanish Hotel Paseo Colon information in French Greek Croatian Italian Japanese Korean Dutch Polish Portuguese Russian 
 


 
 
 BedBreakfastTraveler Links:    Bed Breakfast Traveler Homepage   |   Support   |   Suggest B&amp;Bs   |   Search B&amp;Bs   |   B&amp;B Reviews   |   Write a review   |   Guest Sign-in   |   Subscribe to Newsletter   |   Unsubscribe   |   Join us on Facebook   |   Follow us on Twitter Using our Services:    Terms&amp;Conditions   |   Privacy&amp;Security Policy   |   How it Works   |   Add Your Bed&amp;Breakfast   |   Work with Us   |   Booking engine   |   Affiliate Programs   |   Link to Us   |   Payments System   |   Property Management System   |   XML Feeds 
 Instant World Booking Global:    San Pedro Hotels - Bookings   |   San Pedro Hostels - Bookings   |   ©2002-12 bedbreakfasttraveler.com
All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
