<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006531" url="http://www.hotfrog.co.uk/Products/restaurant-menus/11" time="2012-07-12-23:27" support="7" score="0.01775746548257814" bingtitle="Restaurant Menus - Page 11 - Hotfrog - your UK business directory" webtitle="Restaurant Menus - Page 11">
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... takeaway food for all UK. Order from local Indian, Chinese, Thai, Pizza takeaways. Delivery from over 4000 fast food restaurant menus ... we do all the things you would expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Restaurant Menus - Page 11
 401 - 440 of 1119 businesses results Sponsored links Quick Menu Templates 
 www.musthavemenus.com/ 1000s of Templates to Edit Online! Menus&amp;Flyers for all Restaurants 
 Restaurant Menus   Simple Menus Cafe Menus   Restaurant Flyers 
 Restaurant Menu Online 
 www.fisherscateringsupplies.co.uk/ Quality Commercial Menus Online Ideal For Hotels, Restaurants Etc 
 Churchill Crockery   Dudson Crockery Wholesale Cutlery   Kings Cutlery 
 Restaurant Menus 
 uk.ask.com/Restaurant+Menus Look up Restaurant Menus . Get Trusted Answers Now! Stand Up to Cancer Today 
 www.facebook.com/MasterCard Find out how you can join those who are Standing Up To Cancer. Prezzo 

 
Our popular restaurants, many of them recognised for their architectural value, provide the ideal backdrop to enjoy our food and friendly service
 
 Dining Pasta Eating Out Italian food 
 Belvedere Restaurant 
London
 02076021238 
The Belvedere Restaurant, Holland Park, London W8. The ever popular Belvedere Restaurant for fine dining, exclusive events, private dining and weddings. Chef Billy Reid&apos;s menu enjoys a British hearland core with fine Fr…
 
 Dining 
 George And Dragon Sandwich 

 01304 613106 
Welcome to The George&amp;Dragon, Sandwich, Kent. This inn known by the name and sign of the George and Dragon Inn was built in the 24th year of the 1st reign of Henry VI, in 1446.In May 2008 the George and Dragon Inn, Sa…
 
 
 Jem And I Restaurant 
Didsbury
 0161 445 3996 
Award-winning chef-patron Jem O&apos;Sullivan returned to his Didsbury roots to set up Jem&amp;I. Formerly a bank, it retains the original dark wood flooring and January 2006 saw a new look with modern, sleek surroundings and …
 
 Dine Food starters desserts recipe 
 Wyboston Waterfront 

 01480 223033 
Our hotel service offers best rates for accommodation with access to restaurant and option to book accommodation / rooms online, book leisure packages, accommodation in Bedford and Cambridgeshire
 
 Dining 
 Orchard Restaurant 
Paignton Devon
 01803 556185 
The Orchard Restaurant in Paignton Devon offers high quality carefully balanced menus, using seasonal ingredients, locally sourced to ensure the best possible quality
 
 cuisine 
 Three Cottages 

 01692 403819 
Award winning, top quality fish and chips to take away or eat in in North Walsham near North Norfolk coast
 
 
 Tabbs 
Ely, Cambridgeshire
 01353688437 
…sunnier climes, they made their move to Portreath. In 1991 the idea of Tabbs was born. The original 30 cover restaurant was situated in the seaside village of Portreath on the North coast of Cornwall. A challenging…
 
 Dine Food starters desserts recipe 
 Mount Pleasant Golf Club 
Henlow, Bedfordshire
 01462 810100 
Established in 1992, Mount Pleasant Golf Club is a Bedfordshire based very attractive 9 hole Golf Course, with 18 different tees, and has a reputation for its excellent condition&amp;presentation. The club offers memb…
 
 bistro restuarant 
 Amber Restaurant 
Edinburgh, MIDLOTHIAN
 0131 477 8477 
Amber Restaurant - Edinburgh Scotland - Fine dining at the Scotch Whisky Experience, Edinburgh, Scotland
 
 
   Everything Write 

 01506 412453 
Based in Livingston, central Scotland, Everything Write is operated on a freelance basis and services clients irrespective of location
 
 
 English House 

 01803 325196 
The English Table caters for all types of weddings, private parties and special events but specialises in contemporary catering - gorgeous food with a contemporary presentation
 
 
 Frascati 

 
Italian restaurant, trattoria, with an extensive menu offering fine quality traditional italian dishes and a warm, welcoming service
 
 spaghetti Italian Restaurant Pasta Eating Out 
 Beachcomber Cafe 
New Milton, Hampshire
 01425611599 
With Woolacombe beach a matter of feet away .. The Beachcomber Restaurant is situated as close to Woolacombe Beach as it could get, offering a wide selection of meals and refreshments
 
 meal family restaurant 
 Find Me The Menu 

 
Find Indian Restaurants in Morpeth, Northumberland, find takeaways in Morpeth, Northumberland, restaurants in Morpeth, Northumberland, restaurant and takeaway menus online
 
 takeaway menus Menus Online restaurant guide 
 London Takeaways 
, London
 
London Takeaways - Discounts on all restaurant menus with teh EatEasy online ordering system for takeaway delivery
 
 restaurant delivery Takeaway delivery 
 Rumbling Belly 

 0191 3869933 
View takeaway menus, download italian menus, indian take away menus and chinese restaurant menus in the UK
 
 Menus Online chinese restaurant 
 Sam&apos;s Heera Indian Restaurant 

 0141 886 3222 
Please note in our menu our House Specialty dishes which we hope will tempt your palate
 
 
 H2o Bar&amp;Restaurant 

 01896 750888 
H2O Bar Restaurant is your local place to eat and drink in Galashiels, Scottish Borders. The only Galashiels bar selling Continental lagers
 
 Italian Restaurant 
 Urbanspoon 
East Kilbride
 (01355) 248888 
Inn on the Stroud, Pub in East Kilbride. See the menu, 2 photos and 6 user reviews. Reviews from critics, food blogs and fellow diners
 
 restaurant reviews 
 Sponsored links Restaurant Online Menu 
 All About Restaurant Online Menu Restaurant Online Menu in One Site! 
 www.peeplo.com/Restaurant+Online+Menu I Luv Food 

 08443 578801 
I Luv Food - Restaurant Directory for West Yorkshire Bradford restaurant list. Find restaurants in Bradford, Bradford. Read independent restaurant reviews, view menus, find telephone numbers and maps to new and favourit…
 
 restaurant reviews 
 Istarvin 
Sleaford, Lincolnshire
 
An independent guide to London restaurants, pubs, bars, cafes&amp;take-aways. Venue info, reviews, restaurant offers and free online booking at participating restaurants
 
 dining guide restaurant reviews Restaurant offers restaurant guide 
 Proudrestaurants 

 +44(0) 1273 329 001 
Brighton Table is a collection of the best restaurants Reservations, guide, Offers, bookings and eating establishments in Brighton, Hove
 
 Restaurant offers British Restaurant restaurant guide Italian Restaurant 
 Abdanksigns 

 07796 657 696 
abDanksigns are creative design specialists, we specialise in graphic design to suit your needs. Our designers create professional signs whatever your needs. Our signs are unique for your business logo and business stat…
 
 dinner menus 
 Food In My Town 

 
Find the perfect restaurant or pub food anywhere in the UK. Read real menus. Write reviews or leave your own recommendations. Search for your ideal place to eat by postcode, town name and more
 
 restaurant delivery restaurant reviews 
 La Tandoor 

 01706 642037 
La Tandoor - Indian Restaurant and Takeaway - Bamford Precinct, Martlet Avenue, Bamford, Rochdale OL11 5QY
 
 desserts tandoor recipe bistro 
 Tangipan 

 01723 355633 
Tangipan makes all the decisions at Tangipan&apos;s Kitchen King of the equipment and Sous Chef, Dave organises and plans our events, and makes a mean flapjack
 
 Eating Out 
 Bouchon Bistrot 
Hexham, Northumberland
 01434 609 943 
Bouchon Bistrot serves simply cooked food in French country style at attractive prices. Located opposite Hexham swimming pool on Gilesgate. Enjoy an informal and family friendly atmosphere in the heart of Hexham. Call i…
 
 Bistrot bistro cuisine 
 White Swan Deighton 
, North Yorkshire
 01904 728287 
The White Swan Deighton. Between Selby and York, offers a wonderful choice of home cooked food and an excellent choice of deserts, Welcome to the White Swan from Liz and Richard Milnes. We look forward to greating you i…
 
 White Swan 
 The Railway Honiton 
Honiton, DEVON
 
…passionate about treating the environment with respect – we use methods that are groundbreaking within the restaurant trade Currently 80% of all our fresh produce comes from the South West, and we’re striving to…
 
 
 Tony Roma&apos;s 
Kingston upon Thames, Surrey
 020 8546 5446 
The first Tony Roma’s restaurant was in North Miami, Florida and since then there are now more than 260 restaurants worldwide with 3 in the UK
 
 Restaurant Staff seafood restaurant Pasta Eating Out 
 Lost My Menu 
Wakefield, WEST YORKSHIRE
 07704 193567 
Takeaway delivery - Looking for your favourite takeaway delivery menu look no further, www.lostmymenu.com has all your menu needs. If you can not find your favourite Pizza, Indian, Chinese or Asian cuisine menu either s…
 
 Takeaway delivery Pasta 
 Aldo&apos;s Pizzeria 
Bradford, WEST YORKSHIRE
 01274 861508 
Established in 1983, Aldo&apos;s was the first Italian restaurant to open in the Cleckheaton area. Nearly a quarter century later this lively and traditional pizzeria is still going strong. It&apos;s always busy with a great atmo…
 
 House Wine desserts recipe bistro 
 Chinawok 

 32936 0307 
The visitors will find their favorite Chinese recipes from our best collection of free Chinese recipes sorted by cuisine styles
 
 recipe Chinese Food chinese restaurant cuisine 
 Low Cost Chinese Menus 

 0845 884 4040 
Low Cost Chinese Menus are a UK based printers offering quality restaurant and Chinese takeaway printing. All prices can be found on our website
 
 takeaway menus Based Printers chinese restaurant 
 Low Cost Pizza Menus 

 0845 884 4040 
Low Cost Pizza Menus are a UK based printers offering quality restaurant, Pizza and kebab takeaway printing. All prices can be found on our website
 
 takeaway menus Based Printers Italian Pizza Pizza Takeaway 
 Hollywood Bowl 
Gillingham, Kent
 01634 574 772 
The Hollywood Bowl Restaurant in Gillingham offers service that is out of this world within a recently refurbished and extended restaurant which celebrates the magic of the movies..
 
 
 Kebabishkarahi 
Pinner, Middlesex
 020 8537 5050 
Kebabish Karahi House, an Indian restaurant based in the Rayners Lane Middlesex specialising in halal traditional tandoori and curry dishes as well as halal chinese
 
 bistro Chinese Food Thai restaurant chinese restaurant 
 Othello&apos;s 
Liverpool, Merseyside
 0151 2807700 
 desserts recipe bistro vegetarian dishes 
 Medi Lounge and Grill 
London, London
 02084468444 
 Turkish Restaurant Prawn Italian restaurants 
 Sponsored links Menus price 
 Menus - special offers Make your choice and save money. 
 uk.price-testr.net/Menus Allmenus 
 Discount on Allmenus Save up to 73% while stocks last ! 
 allmenus.pricedumper.co.uk/Sale Top Local Restaurants 
 Sign Up To LivingSocial&amp;Save On Your Favourite Local Restaurants 
 www.livingsocial.com/ First page Prev 10 pages   11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (1119) 
 Related keywords 
 restaurants Eating and Drinking Places restaurant food wine bar Accommodation self catering apartments cuisine catering 
 restaurant menus by county 
 Lancashire London Hampshire Cheshire West-Yorkshire Middlesex North-Yorkshire Surrey West-Midlands Dorset 
 restaurant menus by region 
 North-West England West Country East of England Yorkshire and the Humber East Anglia Greater Manchester Heart of England Peak District East Midlands Thames Valley 
 restaurant menus by city/town 
 MANCHESTER, Lancashire LONDON, London BRISTOL, Avon GLASGOW, Lanarkshire WARRINGTON, Cheshire CAMBRIDGE, Cambridgeshire LIVERPOOL, Merseyside BOLTON, Lancashire BLACKPOOL, Lancashire EDINBURGH, Midlothian 
 Sponsored links Restaurant Menu Covers 
 Get Info On Restaurant Menu Covers.
Access 6 Search Engines At Once. 
 www.info.co.uk/RestaurantMenuCovers All in one Menu Boards 
 Update using USB SD or CF Cards
Stylish design.Ready to go solution 
 www.digitalmediasystems.co.uk/ Restaurant Menus 
 Search restaurant menus 
View restaurant menus 
 uk.zapmeta.com/Restaurant+Menus Resturant Menu 
 Looking for Resturant Menu?
Find it here! 
 www.5earch.com/Resturant+Menu 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.7mvt.009 )
	</body>
</document>
