<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006727" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/olive-garden-restaurant-complaint-rude-customer-service-and-a-horrible-experience/" time="2012-07-12-23:43" support="1" score="0.001473969028168978" bingtitle="Olive Garden Restaurant Complaint - Rude Customer Service and A ..." webtitle="Olive Garden Restaurant Complaint - Rude Customer Service and A Horrible Experience! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>When we got to our table, the hostesses brought ... on Wednesday 10/5/11, I started as a host in store ... Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from our ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Coors light beer cans are not made the way beer cans used to be. Wave Energy Drink Complaint - Energy Drink That Tastes Worse Than Red Bull!! Crown Honda car dealership complaint - a very bad car buying experience! Portfolio Recovery Associates and Highly Illegal, Fraudulent Debt Collection Practices! Glaceau VitaminWater review – does it taste better than Gatorade or Powerade and is it healthier for you? Food Lion Supermarket Complaint - Discriminative Security Guards That Are Rude And Unjust! Starbucks Natural Fusions Caramel Coffee Review - Coffee that doesn&apos;t smell nor taste like caramel, but instead tastes like acidic mud! Best Buy Geek Squad Accidental Warranty Complaint - Is It Worth The Extra Money To Purchase The Accidental Warranty? Aéropostale Clothing Stores Complaint - Clothing Sizes That Are Meant For Small Sized People Only! Brickell Honda car dealer of Miami Florida - a review of shady and illegal business tactics and rude and obnoxious employees! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Olive Garden Restaurant Complaint–Rude Customer Service and A Horrible Experience!
 By latenightrider 
 






When I was younger my parents used to take the family to Olive Garden every Christmas Eve. It was a special treat and we always had a great time. We decided to go last night as a special occasion because we were all getting together since my brother, sister-in-law and new nephew were in town.

I live in Lexington, so it took around 45 minutes for my husband and kids to get there. My mother booked ‘reservations’ for a party of 16 at 6:00pm on a Saturday. They were booked a week and a half prior to the date.

 Stop identity theft cold! Surf the internet with complete anonymity! Get past political restrictions on the internet! Click here to learn how now! 

When we got there, we waited approximately 30 minutes or more before one of the hostesses came to seat us. The majority of our party was seated when another hostess came up and told us we had to get up because another party was there before us. When my brother questioned her, she told him that it wasn’t her problem. We went back to the waiting area which was entirely too small. We had four very small children ranging from 2 1/2 months to 2 1/2 years old.

When we were waiting for the second time, my neice overheard the hostesses making rude comments about our family and using profanity. She went up to them and explained that if they had an issue with our family, they needed to say it to our face. One of the girls cursed at her and called her a psycho.


 Your Ad Here 


We waiting a total of over an hour on a reservation made a week and a half early. When we got to our table, the hostesses brought another family to sit with us which took two chairs away from our party. I had to have my daughter sit on my lap for a while and when we worked out the chair situation, we weren’t even offered booster seats or high chairs. We had to get our own.

We had a very nice server who was doing a very good job. He took our drink orders and went to get them and when he came back to get our dressing for the salads, another server came up and said something in his ear. Whatever he was told embarrassed him because the expression on his face was horrible. She made him read off what he had already taken down from us. I was very angry because I was really thirsty. I had to wait even longer because apparently she wanted to serve us.

 Learn how our readers are downloading the latest movies, music, software and more 100% free and safe! 

The hostesses were both very young and rude. They were unprofessional. My mother had to explain that they represent the business and that they need to behave professionally.

The manager was called multiple times during our visit for many different reasons. This was a horrible experience and I will NEVER go back to that place. I will tell everyone I know about our experience and hope that they dont go there. They really need to get their act together.





 
Posts Related to Olive Garden Restaurant Complaint - Rude Customer Service and A Horrible Experience!

 
 Olive Garden Complaint–Rude Co Workers Forced Me To Resign In Store Number 1776 

// To whom it may concern: Back on Wednesday 10/5/11, I started as a host in store 1776.  I worked there for only 2 weeks.  ...
 
 Asian Garden Chinese restaurant review–great Chinese food and they give you big servings! 

// I love great Chinese food and lately I have found a new Chinese restaurant here in Charlotte, NC that just makes me have to ...
 
 Dave and Busters Hanover Maryland restaurant review–terrible customer service experience! 

// On 6/26/2011, I experienced the worst customer experience at Dave and Busters located at Arundel Mills in Hanover Maryland. My wife and I invited ...
 
 Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! 

Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from our readers and contributors here on ReportYourComplaint.com! // Here are some of the latest and ...
 
 J Pasta’s Pizzeria Complaint–Horrible Customer Service, Rude Owner, and Horrible Experience! 

// Are you one of those people that likes to have family get-togethers, but hate all the clean-up afterwards?  I know the clean-up is my ...
 
 
 Tags: chain restaurant , complaint , horrible customer service , italian food , italian restaurant , Not recommended , olive garden , olive garden restaurant , restaurat , salisbury nc location , salisbury nc olive garden 
 
3 Responses to Olive Garden Restaurant Complaint–Rude Customer Service and A Horrible Experience! 

 Sybil M on February 12, 2011 at 5:24 PM 

I totally agree! Last Mother’s Day my daughter took my Mom and me to the Olive Garden. The waitress looked like she had been up all night. When she grated the cheese into my soup, it also went into my glass of Coca Cola, she didn’t offer to get me another glass of pop or anything, and to top it off, she did it again. That was the first and last time I went to Olive Garden. This restaurant is located in Yakima, WA on Yakima Ave.

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 Cheryl Sawyer on February 27, 2012 at 2:54 PM 

I live in Montgomery Alabama, my sister, mom and I went to Olive Garden for a pleasant evening lunch. The waitress was prompt in taking our orders; however, we ordered two appetizers and soup and salad. My mom had the three course special. We did receive the soup and salad, but the appetizers never made it to the table. After we finished the first bowl of soup and salad we wanted more, but they came and just picked up all the dishes without inquiring as to whether we were interested in getting more. Which the restraurant advertise all the soup and salad you can eat. And since we did not receive the appetizers we did want more. Afterwards I decided to order your golden margarita, we waited for approximately 10 minutes, it never arrived. But the waitress brought the check without one word mentioned about the margarita. It was completely unprofessional they way the whole incident occured. Instead of having a relaxing lucheon, we left feeling as though we were not only rushed out but the service was awful. Also, while we were there the chef came to a table behind us three times to flirt with the customer seated there. This I also found to be unprofessional. My family and I eat out quite a bit, and we have never experienced anything like this before. We expected much more hospitality than we received and was very dissatisified.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Dr. L. Miller on March 23, 2012 at 2:13 AM 

Dear fellow victims of restaurant harassment,

I just came back from what was to be a pleasant evening with my lovely lady. We went to Olive Garden in Salt lake City where the food and atmosphere is nice and I politely asked that, since I am LDS and totally against the use of alcohol, would they please not blatantly affix a bottle of deadly booze right in front of me on the table so we could have a pleasant unperturbed dinner.

The waitress became huffy and crass stating like an SS officer“it’s our policy; we have to put it on your table.”I responded that we were not drunks and did not want people witnessing a bottle on our table because we are Mormons and are completely against it. No one, not even a manager, would listen to me but kept affirming that it was their policy. Of course we had to leave very angry, hungry and committed to oppose their dictatorial policy. Of course they could care less.

Usually the customer is always right and they should be able to successfully protest if someone doesn’t want a waiter to plop a basket of cigars on their table or a waitress to come bear-chested and offer sexual services or someone to set a box of rat poison on a table and try to force you to put it in the soup, or slam a plate in front of a vegetarian with a roasted human body part on in it. Especially if a customer who is a reformed former alcoholic 50 years ago asks that they please don’t harass and torment their non-drinking customers with liquor, they should allow people not to be insulted.

If Olive Garden didn’t have such nice food and a mellow atmosphere with non-intrusive music, I would not be so infuriated. I feel that Mothers Against Drunk Driving, all anti-alcohol Mormons and other Christian groups, all Moslems everywhere and anyone else who believes in respect for customers’religious beliefs, should unite and boycott Olive Garden until the enforced insulting booze pushing policy be abandoned forever. If we have to picket, if we have to occupy their parking lots so no one can eat there, whatever needs to be done, let’s stop this tyranny once and for all. They don’t care a bit for customers; so we need to show that we don’t care about them.

It doesn’t bother me if others drink themselves to death at tables all over Olive Garden, just don’t push that poison on me at my table in front of everyone and my family; don’t belligerently fix it on the table right in front of me as if I approve of it or ordered a whole bottle. If Olive Garden wants to be part of the problem of deaths on the highway and in the home because of alcohol, if they want to heedlessly promote something that has put a large portion of violent criminals in prison, if they want to destroy family values in the presence of children in what used to be a family restaurant, let’s close those dictators down forever everywhere.

If we have to unite in a federal Civil Rights class action because of their anti-religion, their anti-customer policy and blatant arrogance, let’s do it! Let’s not let them get away with treating customers with distain and disregard so they can push poison for the huge money-grubbing booze companies and their master the devil. If they hate Mormons so much that they continually insult us this way, then they should notice that the Marriotts, Mitt Romney and many other big money people would also agree that forcing alcohol on everyone when they barely sit down is not allowing people their rights. People can drink if they wish; but shouldn’t people can also be left alone if they wish not to be booze-bullied, right? Or is this now a Commie country?

These obnoxious bullies ruined what was to be a beautiful evening out with a kind and caring lady and making her cry late into the night; they need to be stopped or closed down permanently. Please forward this to all and everyone, religious leaders and all their members of any faith which abhors drunkenness and Civil rights violations. Everyone should forward this message onward so we can peacefully protest Olive Garden’s haughty and mercenary policy and their lack of respect for others who don’t agree with their tyranny.

Dr. L. Miller

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
