<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006020" url="http://www.innewstoday.net/starbucks-31-oz-trenta-cup-size-coming-soon/" time="2012-07-12-22:42" support="1" score="0.0006452311771412947" bingtitle="Starbucks 31-oz &quot;Trenta&quot; cup size coming soon! | In News Today" webtitle="Starbucks 31-oz &quot;Trenta&quot; cup size coming soon! | In News Today">
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>McDonald’s Corp, the world’s biggest fast-food restaurant ... U.S. convenience stores, which have been taking on ... Leave a Reply Cancel reply</description>
	<body>
		In News Today The Hottest Stories and Trends In News Today 
FREE Report Reveals The Exact System
And Strategy A Young Panel Beater From Tasmania Used To Make 1.8 Million Dollars In One Trade. ( All Details inside).

Fill in your email below to get instant access

 
 
 We will never sell , rent or give away your information.
You may unsubscribe anytime. 
 
 Skip to content 
 Home About Contact Us Most Popular Info Products Privacy Policy 
 ← Jane Krakowski: Pregnancy Won’t Be Written Into 30 Rock Golden Globe Awards 2011: The Best and Worst Dressed → 
Starbucks 31-oz“Trenta”cup size coming soon!
 
 Posted on January 17, 2011 by 
Starbucks Corp will roll out its biggest drink size yet

–the 31-ounce“Trenta”–in all of its U.S. coffee shops by May 3,

the company said Sunday

The new size will be available only for iced coffee, iced tea and iced tea lemonade drinks in the United States.

The Trenta is 7 ounces larger than Starbucks’“Venti”cup for iced drinks, which currently is its largest size on offer.

Drinks in the Trenta size will cost 50 cents more than similar Venti-sized iced drinks, the company said.

 

Seattle-based Starbucks tested the new size in several U.S. markets last year, saying it was responding to customer demand for larger cold beverages.

The Trenta size will debut in 14 states, including Virginia, Georgia, Florida, Texas, Hawaii and Arizona, on Jan. 18 and in California on Feb. 1.

The world’s biggest coffee chain said unsweetened drinks in the new size will have fewer than 90 calories and that sweetened versions will have less than 230 calories.

McDonald’s Corp, the world’s biggest fast-food restaurant chain, has taken direct aim at Starbucks with frappes, fruit smoothies and espresso drinks such as lattes and cappuccino. It also has lured customers by selling 32-ounce (946.4 ml) sweet tea drinks for $1 each.

U.S. convenience stores, which have been taking on restaurant chains with an expanded selection of low-cost, quick-serve fare, for years have sold fountain drinks in large sizes, including 32 ounces and 64 ounces.

 Read more: http://www.foxnews.com/health/2011/01/16/starbucks-roll-biggest-drink-size/#ixzz1BJIQJDlB 

 
 
 
Related Posts :
 
 Starbucks Changing Logo&amp;Selling Girl Scout Cookies 

 Gossip Girl Jessica Szohr Gets Body Painted To Sell Drink 

 Credit Cards to Become Obsolete? 

 Duke Energy Corp. Buys Progress Energy to Create America&apos;s Largest Utility Company 

 Drunk Jennifer Aniston Presents the People’s Choice Awards! 

 Hot Jennifer Aniston Pics: Allure Magazine Sexy Photoshoot (PHOTOS) 

 Donald Trump Network Marketing Review 

 Eva Longoria Uses Her Bankrupt Restaurant for Sexy Photo Shoot 

 Hot N Cold Ringtone by Katy Perry | Hot N Cold Ringtone 

 Mega Millions Jackpot Fuels Dreams&amp;Ticket Sales 

 
 By Blogsdna This entry was posted in Uncategorized. Bookmark the permalink . ← Jane Krakowski: Pregnancy Won’t Be Written Into 30 Rock Golden Globe Awards 2011: The Best and Worst Dressed → 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 
 
 
 
 
Pages

 About Contact Us Most Popular Info Products Privacy Policy 
 
Categories

 No categories 
 
 
Meta

 Log in 
 
 ©Copyright In News Today 
Zone Theme by 100K Blueprint
	</body>
</document>
