<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006119" url="http://www.copykat.com/2010/04/29/wendys-chili-2/" time="2012-07-12-22:48" support="3" score="0.009349471737698945" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s Chili Recipe | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes" webtitle="Wendy&apos;s Chili Recipe | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes">
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Please note, no restaurant recipes are actually used, these recipes have been inspired by the restaurant originals. Unless otherwise noted, all recipes have been created ...</description>
	<body>
		You loved it at the restaurant, now make it at home Try It Out 
 
 Search from over 1500 recipes... 
 Home About Contact Press Contests Links to Love Dining Out At Home Recipe Box Videos 
 This recipe is filed in 
 Copycat Restaurant Recipes CopyKat Recipes Soup Recipes Video 
 and has these ingredients 
 Fast Food Recipes Gluten Free 
 
Wendy’s Chili Recipe
 April 29, 2010 37 Comments 
Share the recipe
 Tweet Print Add this recipe to ZipList! Next Recipe&gt; &lt;Previous Recipe 
Wendy’s® makes this classic recipe fresh every day, and you can do the same. Tomato juice really enhances the flavor of this chili , as does the chili powder, though you may want to start off with a little less chili powder. I find that ¼ cup isn’t too hot, but is very flavorful.
 
 

Wendy’s Chili

Now it is said that Wendy’s Chili is made from grilled hamburger patties that didn’t make it into their burgers. We don’t have you start out with hamburger patties, but the ground beef. We think it is easier to start out this way when you make your own chili this way. If you like, we suggest that you brown this hamburger very throroughly before making your chili.

 
 Add this recipe to ZipList! 
Wendy&apos;s Chili
 Author: CopyKat Recipes Recipe Type: Wendy&apos;s, soup, chili recipe, copy cat recipe Prep time: 15 min Cook time: 1 hr 30 min Total time: 1 hr 45 min Serves: 1 Ingredients 
 2 pounds freshly ground beef 4 cups (1 quart) tomato juice 1 (29-ounce) can tomato purée 1 (15-ounce) can red kidney beans, drained 1 (15-ounce) can pinto beans, drained ** note new addition 1 medium onion, chopped (about 1½ cups) 1/2 cup celery, diced 1/4 cup green bell pepper, diced 1/4 cup chili powder (you may want to use less) 1 teaspoon cumin (if you like real flavor, add more) 1 1/2 teaspoons garlic powder 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon black pepper 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon sugar 1/8 teaspoon cayenne pepper 
 Instructions 
In a frying pan, brown the ground beef, then drain off the fat. Put the beef and the remaining ingredients into a 6-quart pot. Cover the pot and let the chili simmer for 1 to 1½ hours, stirring every 15 minutes. You an also put this in the crock pot on low for 3 to 4 hours while the chili simmers.

You can find this recipe in my book CopyKat.com&apos;s Dining Out in the Home 
 Print Recipe 
 
 
Wendy’s Chili 
Quick Chili – a tried and true family recipe. 
Indiana Style Chili – you can made Midwest style chili with this recipe. 
Hackney’s Inside-Out Burger 
Steak and Shake 5 way Chili 
 
 http://frantasticfood.com Fran 
I haven’t made chili in a long time and have some ground beef calling to me in the fridge. Looks like Wendy’s Chili is in my future!
 carole 
Doesn’t Wendy’s chili have more than one kind of beans?
 Anonymous 
Yes, Wendy’s Chili does have more than one type of beans, but I can not remember what they are (as it’s been a while since i worked there).
 Meg 
pinto beans
 http://ssecretrestaurantrecipesite.com Frugal Diner 
If it weren’t for Wendy’s Chili, my wife and I would never go to Wendy’s. I like the chili, as well any any, but my wife won’t eat anything else at Wendy’s. If she’s not hungry for Chili…we don’t go.
 tk 
“Cover the pot and let the chili simmer for 1 to 1½ hours”

pretty sure on the cups it says Wendy’s chili simmers for 4+ hours. also, you didn’t include chopped up bits of yesterday’s hamburgers.

 You are right I do not include the pre grilled hamburgers, I don’t think most of us have those at home–stephanie 
 Ryan 
I’d definitely add more cumin, because I know when it’s real!
 Scott 
I made this this weekend. Pretty good. Used a little extra cumin and a little less chili powder and used V8 instead of tomato juice. Not quite Wendy’s anymore but it’s a nice place to start. Love this web site.
 Bernie Lane 
Not only does Wendy’s chili have more than one bean it also has fresh tomatoes.
 Frank Thompson 
Thier chili has Chili beans in it. comes from there website
 Cindy 
They sure do use patties that haven’t sold in the appropriate amount of time. I worked at Wendy’s for a few years and their chili is the best. They also use leftover grilled chicken, to top their salads.
 Cindy 
No fresh tomatoes, only canned. Unless they’ve changed the recipe in the last few years.
 John 
It has kidney beans AND Pinto beans
 http://www.copykat.com Stephanie 
I understand the recipe now has kidney beans and pinto beans, when it was developed, the chili had one type of bean.
 mara 
14 oz can tomatoes
1 ¼ oz mild chili seasoning (McCormick brand nicer)
2 lb ground beef mince meat.
32 oz can tomato sauce
14 oz can ranch style beans
14 oz can pinto beans
14 oz can kidney beans
10 oz can Rotel diced tomatoes
1 diced onion
1 diced bell pepper
 Matt 
You really want to make this taste like wendys chilli. I worked at Wendys.. Use that burger meat and burn it.. Not like charcoal it to the points its no good just burn it enough so that its black on the outside. Then freeze it over night. The next day boil the meat til its tender, drain and then chop. This is how its done in the store.
 umsalman 
please please please i need the recipe of hardees chilli lava thaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaanks
 Bunn 
Love Wendy Chili! Fairly easy to almost duplicate their taste. Always fun to just fool with the basic recipe and change it up.
 Nadean 
I was just thinking abt. Wendy’s Chili yesterday! This sounds soooo delish! I plan on trying it soon.
 http://www.copykat.com Stephanie 
I hope you enjoy the copy cat recipe.
 http://www.copykat.com/2011/09/19/wendys-chili-3/ Wendy’s Chili Video | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes 
[...] can watch and see how to make your own Wendy’s Chili at home. Pick up the recipe right here Wendy’s Chili. This is the perfect recipe to make during the cooler months. This chili can be made in a crock [...]
 Alisha 
I learned how to cook from watching my mom and then recalling as an adult. I have never been able to quite get the chili right and I always think everyone else’s chili is better than mine anyway. I do love Wendy’s chili and I cannot wait to try this recipe. Thanks for sharing Miss Stephanie.
 Stephanie Manley 
I hope you enjoyed this one! Let me know how your own personal chili making went.
 Rutti Luck 
Way too rich–I had fresh chili powder and we almost choked on the chili because there was too much of it! Did not taste like Wendy’s chili because of the overwhelming richness!
 Stephanie Manley 
You can watch a training video on youtube, look up Wendy’s training video, they talk about how burger patties can turn into chili.
 Hll E 
good stuff. in the crock pot now–so far it tastes just like Wendy’s
 Stephanie Manley 
I hope you enjoy the chilly, did you brown the meat in the crockpot, or did you start it on the stove top?
 Janet 
I added 3 T. brown sugar and 1 tsp. granulated sugar the second time i made it (not sure why) but I loved the outcome!
 http://www.copykat.com/2011/12/28/2011-top-ten-copykat-recipes/ 2011 Top Ten CopyKat Recipes | CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes 
[...] Wendy’s Chili–Looking for a hearty meal? This version of chili doesn’t use any pre-cooked [...]
 Yum! 
Tried this recipe today, I added 1 habanero and one jalapeno (chopped) to the mix and added slightly more sugar. I also used a mix of ground turkey and ground sirloin. DELICIOUS!!! (tasted like Wendy’s but BETTER!)
 Jlester30 
Trying this recipe right now. Taste amazing so far! I like it spicy so I added some fresh jalapeno and serrano peppers along with red pepper flakes. Thanks for the recipe!
 MJT 
Have you even been told that sarcasm does not translate well in type form? You sound so angry. I do believe it says stovetop for 1 to 1 1/2 hours, crockpot 3-4 hours.
Anyone that has ever made chili knows that it tastes better the longer it cooks! Thats why its best leftover!
 MamaMia 
Sugar always makes things taste different. During the middle ages sugar was considered a spice.
 mmm..mmm..good 
Just got done making this and it is is jus like wendys, the aroma in my house is amazing right now! I could put it in a wendys chilli bowl and nobody would even know it wasnt the real deal! My new favorite chili recipe hands down!
 http://www.copykat.com Stephanie 
I hope your chili is just a little better than Wendy’s!!
 Judybudy75 
Serving size says serves 1- I don’t think so.
 Anonymous 
It now has both. A canned base which is paste and they add water to it and then they add a whole bunch of mashed up tomatoes.
 
 CopyKat.com&apos;s Dining Out at Home Cookbook Recipes for the Most Delicious Dishes from America&apos;s Most Popular Restaurants Buy on Amazon I’d definitely recommend adding Dining Out at Home to your collection. It’s a great way to add some variety into your meals at home and give you the feeling of dining out even when you stay in. FrugalNovice 
 
Welcome to CopyKat Recipes
 
CopyKat.com is the creation of Stephanie Manley. Stephanie started publishing recipes on the web in 1995 as a means to capture her family recipes in a format that they would not be thrown away. Over the years she has developed many recipes that
taste just like restaurant recipes.
 read more 
10 FREE Copykat Recipes
 Want 10 free Copy Cat recipes? 
Sign up for the Free newsletter. Policy: We won&apos;t share your email with any 3rd party and won&apos;t send you any spam 
 
Categories

 52 Weeks of Cream Cheese (22) Appetizer Recipes (211) Book Review (1) Bread Recipes (114) Cake Recipes (34) Candy Recipes (26) Casserole Recipes (121) Chicken Recipes (92) Contest (4) Cookie Recipes (60) Copycat Restaurant Recipes (713) CopyKat Recipes (903) Dessert Recipes (322) Dips/Sauces (122) Drink Recipes (68) Favorite Recipes (82) Giveaway (5) Holiday Recipes (8) Main dish Recipes (202) Meat Recipes (63) Menu Plan (23) Miscellanous (52) New (4) Pasta Recipes (89) Reader&apos;s Recipes (194) Salad Dressings (56) Salad Recipes (100) Seafood Recipes (84) Side Dish Recipes (81) Snack Recipes (62) Soup Recipes (122) Tweet (16) Video (32) 
 
Recent Posts

 Bacon Beer and Cheese Cupcakes Star Pizza Roasted Garlic and Goat Cheese Red Lobster Shrimp Nachos Quick and Easy Broccoli Rice Casserole Outback Steakhouse Green Beans Video 
 To place this on your site, select the code below and then press &quot;Ctrl+C&quot; to copy 
Video
 Panera&apos;s Broccoli Cheese Soup Broccoli Rice Cheese Casserole Outback Steakhouse Green Beans Red Lobster Cheddar Bay Biscuits Chocolate Pretzel Bites More Videos 
Recent Comments

 I worked at sonic in highschoo... Tomara Armstrong Jul 12, 2012 you needed to scroll down a l... Dmchensky Jul 12, 2012 my son had this when we went o... Sweetheart4270 Jul 12, 2012 ummm, the temp of the oven to... Lenriz Jul 12, 2012 Can&apos;t be true. Worked at McDon... Dweyer Jul 12, 2012 
 (C) 2011 CopyKat Recipes | Restaurant Recipes WordPress Design by Blog Design Studio
 Graphic Design by Lakia Ross Creative 
Please note, no restaurant recipes are actually used, these recipes have been inspired by the restaurant originals. Unless otherwise noted, all recipes have been created by CopyKat.com.
	</body>
</document>
