<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006815" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/226437-list-of-foods-to-avoid-while-on-the-renal-diet/" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="1" score="0.0009489201620165879" bingtitle="List Of Foods To Avoid While On The Renal Diet | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="List Of Foods To Avoid While On The Renal Diet | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>... restrictions on the amount of protein you consume, because when your kidneys do not function well, urea---a waste ... of the phosphorus content for many popular fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Weight Management Weight Loss Diets M-Z Renal Diet Food List List of Foods to Avoid While on the Renal Diet 
 
 List of Foods to Avoid While on the Renal Diet 
 Mar 29, 2011 | By Carol Luther Photo Credit salt jars image by Horticulture from Fotolia.com 
Your diet plays an essential role in management of your kidney disease and successful dialysis, if required. After your physician confirms that you have kidney problems or renal insufficiency, a dietician will design a renal diet that provides proper nutrition and supports your treatment plan. These diets keep your electrolytes balanced, reduce stress on your kidneys from waste and keep your blood pressure and heart rhythms at optimal levels. To follow a renal diet, reduce or eliminate specific foods from your daily diet.
 
Protein

Many renal diets have restrictions on the amount of protein you consume, because when your kidneys do not function well, urea---a waste from processing proteins--can build up in your blood. Your physician and dietician will decide how much protein intake is best for your condition. Reducing your protein intake decreases your kidneys&apos; workload, but you must include some protein in your diet. Expect to have smaller portions of eggs, dairy products, red meat, poultry and some grains that have high protein content.

According to the American Association of Kidney Patients, a 3-oz. serving of veal sirloin, at 28.7 g, leads the list of high- protein selections you should avoid, followed closely by soybeans at 28.6 g. Similarly sized servings of liver, turkey breast, chicken, pork loin and lamb also have more than 20 g per serving. Lower protein foods that will help conserve your kidneys include black-eyed peas and lima beans, which have only 50 percent of the amount of protein in soybeans and veal.
 
Sodium

Since diseased kidneys cannot process and eliminate the fluids that build up in your tissues, your dietician may suggest avoiding high-sodium foods that can cause fluid retention. You will need to stop adding salt from a shaker and avoid prepared and canned soups, cheese, bacon, sausage and hot dogs, deli meats, roasted nuts, crackers and snack chips. These and other processed foods often contain a high percentage of sodium. Read the nutrition labels on food products and replace high-sodium products with foods that contain no more than 5 percent per serving, unless your dietician recommends less. Substitute fresh or dried herbs, garlic and lemons for salt, or buy salt-free seasoning to add spice to your foods.
 
Potassium

Consuming too much potassium can cause an imbalance that makes your heart work harder, creating an irregular heartbeat. Avoid salt substitutes unless your dietician, kidney team and physician allow them. All these substitutes have high potassium content. The USDA&apos;s nutrient data chart for potassium shows that canned tomato paste has more than 2,000 g of potassium per 1-cup serving. Other high-potassium foods that you should avoid include oranges, avocados, beet tops, white beans, pureed tomatoes, raisins, potatoes and grapefruit juice. Each of these foods packs more than 1,000 g of potassium per serving. The Medical College of Wisconsin suggests watermelon, carrots, noodles, rice, pears, lettuce and cherries for low-potassium diets.
 
Phosphorus

The Medical College of Wisconsin reports that renal diets often restrict your intake of other minerals and electrolytes. Your dietician may suggest that you decrease your intake of phosphorus, which is difficult for your body to excrete when your kidneys do not function well. You will need to avoid most cheeses, colas, ice cream, peanut butter and nuts, along with beer. Choose sherbet, broccoli and ginger ale or other clear sodas.

Like sodium, phosphorus hides in some prepared foods, including selections from your favorite fast-food chains. The Case Western Reserve University&apos;s website has a list of the phosphorus content for many popular fast-food restaurant menu selections and a printable list that helps you avoid phosphorus food additives in grocery products.
 
References

 U.S. Department of Agriculture: Nutrient Data List-Potassium American Association of Kidney Patients: Nutrition Counter Case Western Reserve University: Fast Food, Phosphorus Containing Food Additives, and the Renal Diet Medical College of Wisconsin: Diet for Renal Patient 
 
Article reviewed by Paula Martinac Last updated on: Mar 29, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading 
 
 Renal Diet Guidelines 
 
 Foods to Avoid When You Have Renal Failure 
 
 Nutrition and Acute Renal Failure 
 
 List of Health Foods for Renal Diet 
 
 Renal Diet Foods to Avoid 
 
 What Foods Are Allowed in a Renal Diet? 
 
 Renal Food Shopping List 
 
 Renal Diet Food List 
 
 Chronic Renal Insufficiency Diet 
 
 Renal Diet Issues 
 
 Renal Diet Definition 
 
 Good Foods&amp;Foods to Avoid on a Renal Diet 
 
 List of Foods to Avoid With Renal Problems 
 
 List of Foods for Renal Patients 
 
 Diets for Renal&amp;Diabetic Patients 
 
 Salt Restriction on a Renal Diet 
 
 Fruit Juices for a Renal Diet 
 
 Tasty Renal Diet Foods 
 
 Diabetic Renal Diet Patient Information 
 
 Diet Meal Plans for Limited Renal Function 
 Show More advertisement Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
