<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006767" url="http://members.shaw.ca/calgaryrestaurantsforsale/" time="2012-07-12-23:45" support="2" score="0.0008190890638064666" bingtitle="Calgary Restaurants For Sale - DT Real Estate Ltd." webtitle="Calgary Restaurants For Sale - DT Real Estate Ltd.">
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>... simple confidentiality agreement to receive ... C062: Vietnamese Fast Food Restaurant - $99,900 E019: Restaurant and Lounge w/ 180 seats and 2 patios - $599,900</description>
	<body>
		DT DAVID THOMPSON REAL ESTATE LTD. 

 
 Home 

 About Us 

 News 

 Contact Info 

 Listings 

 Printing 

 Congratulations 


 

 Home A Little About Us 

David Thompson Real Estate was established in 1994 to sell restaurants
 and bars in the Calgary area. During the past 15 years we have sold over
 325 restaurant and bar businesses.
 Welcome Buyers 

If you are interested in buying a business, please review our Listings page and click on the category 
 that closest matches your requirement. You will then be presented with a list of businesses for sale in that category. 
 Click on any link and you will be brought to a detailed information sheet on that business. Then consult us if you are 
 interested in learning more details on the business including the name and address. You will be required to sign a simple 
 confidentiality agreement to receive further details. No fee or commision will be paid by buyers. The seller will pay the fee.
 Welcome Sellers 

If you are considering selling your business, please call us for a confidential meeting to discuss your situation. 
 At that time we will discuss the value of your business and our fee. There is no charge for this meeting. 
 You will only pay a fee if we sell your business.
 Welcome Realtors 

We are pleased to cooperate with realtors. Please call to discuss your requirements. 
 You and your customer will be required to sign a confidentiality agreement to receive further details of a business for sale. 
 If you have a business for sale we would be pleased to assist you with the sale of that business also.
 Name, Address and Photographs 

We regret that due to the confidential nature of these listings we are unable to provide these particular details at this time. 
 Once a confidentiality agreement is signed by a buyer, the name, address and other sensitive information will be disclosed.
 Listing Prices 

The prices shown for these listings do not include inventory, cash on hand, deposits etc. 
 The price includes the business assets including furniture, equipment and goodwill. 
 The shares of the company owning the business are not for sale unless specifically stated.
 Guest Comments 

If you have any comments or suggestions regarding our website, we would be pleased to receive an email from you.
 Printing 

Please feel free to print off any one of our listings.
See our Printing page for more details. 
 :: 
 site updates :: 
 For Current Listings Click Below:
 Full Listings 
 Current: 20 Check our new listings below 
 06/19/2012: 

2 New listings added.

 C066: Gourmet Diner Cafe with Ice Cream Counter - $199,000 

 E022: Best location on 17 Ave SW - $799,000 

 
 06/10/2012: 

2 New listings added.

 A042: Established Neighbourhood Pub in S West Retail Mall - $499,900 

 C065: Profitable Fast Food Franchise N West Calgary - $429,000 

 
 05/16/2012: 

2 New listings added.

 A050: Neighborhood Pub - $229,900 


 
 04/26/2012: 

2 New listings added.

 I003: Profitable Canmore Restaurant - $175,000 

 E021: Large Freestanding Restaurant and Lounge on 3 levels - $1.2 million 

 
 04/03/2012: 

2 New listings added.

 C063: Central Bakery Cafe with seating - $175,000 

 I002: Close To Calgary Bar and Grill - $120,000 


 Contact Us At The Following : DavidThompsonRealEstate@shaw.ca 
 
 
 
 
 

   copyright - 
 Sieko Efekt™-©2003®David Thompson Real Estate Ltd. - All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
