<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006508" url="http://www.raysahelian.com/newsletter2008.html" time="2012-07-12-23:26" support="1" score="0.001819212724513481" bingtitle="Newsletter 2008" webtitle="Newsletter 2008">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>Comments: To be honest, I stop at a fast food restaurant a few ... purist in the sense that 100 percent of my food ... The number of positive tender points declined ...</description>
	<body>
		Newsletter 2008 - Supplement Research 
Update Newsletter 2008 by Ray Sahelian, M.D .

 See Newsletter 2006 back 
issues.
 See Newsletter 
2007 back issues.
See Newsletter 
2009 newer issues.
 
 What readers of this 
website are saying 
 If I have doubts about alternative health practices, I consider your website to 
be the most authoritative because it contains the most exhaustive research and 
references. I deeply appreciate the tone of your website---give people enough 
accurate information then they can make their own informed decisions. In the era 
of nanny-government to include the FDA, your candor and expertise are deeply 
appreciated. I had been on the verge of making poorly informed decisions about 
the use and dosage of supplements, which can be harmful, and was prevented from 
doing so by the comprehensive information on your website. Thank you.

 I 
have never seen a website like this in the way of being helpful as it relates to&quot;REAL&quot;valuable information, it&apos;s one of a kind. Thanks and please keep up the 
good work as it relates the the information you provide. 

 Thank you for your website which gives a very 
balance opinion of the pro and cons of supplements which are deemed perfectly 
safe by others. 

 I&apos;ve been a big fan of 
your newsletter and holistic approach to the healthcare profession. I&apos;ve 
always believed that doctor&apos;s like yourself would be the leading force in 
change in our current medical system. 

 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 15 -- December 10, 2008
===================================
 In the prior issue of the newsletter I 
reviewed the overly hyped cholesterol drug study that showed Crestor, an 
expensive statin drug similar to Lipitor and Zocor, could reduce blood 
levels of C-reactive protein, a marker that indicates inflammation and a possible risk for heart 
disease. Doctors are being encouraged to prescribe Crestor to patients 
with high levels of C-reactive protein (CRP) in order to reduce the levels 
of this marker and thus potentially reduce the risk for cardiovascular 
problems. I also mentioned that simple and inexpensive vitamins, such as 
vitamin C, can reduce the levels of CRP. This past week I came across an 
interesting study that even dark chocolate can lower CRP levels. The 
problem with chocolate is the calories, sugar and fat that may negate some 
of the positive benefits of the polyphenol antioxidants present in high 
amounts in cacao.
  As a holiday gift to our subscribers, we are offering a free bottle 
of a cacao supplement. All you do is pay the shipping cost, and if you are 
buying other supplements, anyway, the shipping cost will not change. 

 1. Dark Chocolate benefit for cardiovascular 
system
Researchers at Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore, MD tested the effect of 
dark chocolate on p latelet activity, C-reactive protein and 
lipid profile in 28 healthy volunteers. For one week the volunteers ate 
dark chocolate (providing 700 mg of flavonoids per day). After seven days 
of regular dark chocolate ingestion, LDL cholesterol fell by 6% and HDL 
cholesterol rose by 9%. Dark chocolate reduced CRP levels. See http://www.raysahelian.com/cacao.html 
  My comments: It&apos;s okay to eat small amounts of dark chocolate, but 
larger portions can lead to weight gain and excessive exposure to sugars 
and fats. An alternative is taking a capsule of a cacao supplement in 
the morning with breakfast. 

 2. Garlic lowers blood pressure
Did you know that if you have high blood pressure and you eat garlic or 
perhaps take garlic pills your blood pressure could be reduced? Doctors at 
Hartford Hospital, in Hartford, CT, reviewed several studies with garlic 
done in the last few years and concluded that the use of this herb, on 
average, can help systolic blood pressure drop by 16 mm Hg and diastolic 
blood pressure by 9 mmHg. The use of garlic apparently did not 
reduce blood pressure in those with normal blood pressure. A review by 
another team of researchers at The University of Adelaide in South Australia found 
garlic reduced systolic blood pressure by 8 mm Hg, on average, and 
diastolic blood pressure by 7 mm Hg. The amount of garlic used in the 
studies was about a gram, providing about 5 mg of allicin, one of the 
active ingredients in this herb.
  My comments: If you have hypertension you may consider eating more 
garlic or taking a garlic supplement. Sulfides present in garlic are 
converted by red blood cells into hydrogen sulfide which helps to dilate 
blood vessels. Each garlic clove weighs about 3 to 5 grams. See http://www.raysahelian.com/garlic.html 

3. Pharmaceutical new drug studies: unfavorable outcomes often not published
Drug companies are more likely to submit for publication to medical 
journals outcomes of studies that favor benefits of the new drugs they are 
promoting. Many trials that showed poor outcomes were still not published 
several years after FDA approval of the new drug. An independent review of these studies 
concludes,&quot;The information that is readily available in the scientific 
literature to health care professionals is incomplete and potentially 
biased.&quot;
  My comments: This should make people even more skeptical about the 
benefits often touted by drug companies for the new medications they 
promote. They tend to selectively choose to hype the studies that show 
good outcomes. 

 Emails
Q. In a recent email from Physorg dot com 
was an article on anti-oxidants stating that the&quot;Fifty year old theory 
about the causes of ageing is wrong.&quot;The article went on to say that the 
original theory proposed by Dr. Denham Harmon in 1956 that antioxidants reduce 
the rate of ageing is probably incorrect. The article did not convince me 
that oxidation is not relative to ageing in the human body. Do you, Dr. 
Sahelian, believe the conclusion by the folks at Physorg dot com?
  A. There are literally thousands of vitamins, nutrients, herbal 
compounds, fruit and vegetable extracts that have antioxidant potential. 
Most studies testing the influence of antioxidants as anti-aging 
supplements test high doses of vitamins C and E and sometimes beta-carotene or the 
mineral selenium. These studies do not take into account the thousands of 
potential beneficial antioxidants that are available. Giving a high dose 
of one or two antioxidant supplements and making a generalization 
regarding the anti-aging benefits of various antioxidants does not appear to me to 
be a reliable way to come to an understanding of their influence on aging. Perhaps 
taking too high a dosage of one or two or three antioxidants is not the 
proper approach to living longer. I think that ingesting a variety of herbal, fruit and vegetable extracts that contain 
small amounts of hundreds of different flavonoids, carotenoids and other 
beneficial substances is more likely 
to provide a benefit than a massive daily dose of vitamins C or E. 
However, this field is very complicated and it is not easy to give 
definitive answers at this time. Drinking a mix of fresh vegetable juices 
would allow ingestion of dozens or hundreds of carotenoids and flavonoids. I 
personally alternate between different supplements such as acai, mangosteen, 
graviola, cranberry, bilberry, acerola, basil, fennel, pomegranate, goji, 
curcumin, barley greens, acetylcysteine, acetylcarnitine, alpha lipoic acid, and 
others. I try not to take too high an amount of just one or two.
See http://www.raysahelian.com/antioxidant.html   

 Q. Thanks for all you do in the field of 
nutritional supplements. Just curious why you recommend such a lower 
daily amount of alpha lipoic acid. The below article is 
from Life Extension Research Institute.&quot;The 
amount of alpha lipoic acid produced internally in the body decreases 
naturally with age, which could set the stage for free radical-induced 
damage. Although small amounts of alpha lipoic acid are available in food 
sources, such as dark leafy greens like spinach and collards, broccoli, 
beef, and organ meats, supplementation may be needed to achieve 
significant intake levels. Scientific studies showing the health 
benefits of alpha lipoic acid have used doses ranging from 300 mg to 1,800 
mg per day. Alpha lipoic acid has generally been found to be safe when administered in 
recommended doses.&quot;
  A. Since long term human research with nutritional supplements is not extensive, there are 
a number of opinions regarding the best supplements to take for long term 
health and what the ideal dosages should be. Different doctors and scientists have different 
viewpoints. In my personal experience, 
high dosages of alpha lipoic acid can cause insomnia and ALA may cause 
heart rhythm disturbances in dosages greater than 100 mg. Sleep problems 
certainly do not lead to better health. Until we know more about the long term side 
effects of these supplements, I prefer to take low dosages and to take days 
off. See http://www.raysahelian.com/lipoic.html 

Q. Are you aware of problems with taking SAM-e or 5HTP while trying to wean from Prozac? 
Do you recommend a&quot;weaning program.&quot;I 
understand that 5HTP does not mix well with Prozac. What about 5HTP alone? 
I don&apos;t want to encourage a&quot;serotonin syndrome.&quot;
   A. Each person taking Prozac or a similar SSRI medication responds in a different way and 
needs a different dosage of the drug. Each person weaning off Prozac or a 
SSRI medication while switching to 
natural supplements will respond in a different way depending on many 
variables including drug dosage, severity of depression, length of time taking 
the medication, etc. There is no simple answer that would apply to 
everyone. The best one can say is 
to reduce the medication dosage gradually while beginning a low 
dosage of the supplements although if the depression is mild a person 
could lower the dosage and stop the Prozac within a few days. If a 
person is taking 20 mg of Prozac, the dosage could be reduced to 10 mg 
while adding 25 or 50 mg of 5-HTP. 
Ideally one should try each natural supplement by itself for a week or two 
rather than combining them. For instance it is a good idea to try 5-HTP by 
itself and SAM-e supplement by itself rather than initially taking them together. 
If you take two supplements together and you get a side effect, you 
would not know which one caused it. Please inform and consult with your 
doctor regarding your plans. See http://www.raysahelian.com/5-htp.html 

Q. I am currently weaning off of Lexapro and Klonopin after 3 yrs, with 
the advice of my doctor, but I would like to know if it is ok to take 
something else like St. John&apos;s wort or 5HTP while weaning off so that I 
do not have the withdrawal symptoms and or have a relapse, I have done so 
much research on the net and find so many suggestions that it all gets 
confusing, so some info regarding the use of St. John&apos;s wort or 5-HTP 
would be helpful for me and I can pass it along to the doctor,
  A. The use of 5HTP, St. John&apos;s wort or any natural anti-depressant for 
medication withdrawal has not been well-studied by scientists. There are 
no easy answers since each person is likely to have a different response. 
It is not possible to predict any one person&apos;s reaction. Therefore, the 
best one can do is trial and error, using 5-HTP or St. John&apos;s wort 
beginning with low dosages under medical guidance. The 5-HTP dosage 
required is likely to vary and can range from 25 mg to 50 mg, or to 100 mg or 
more. The St. John&apos;s wort dosage could range from 300 mg every other day 
to 300 mg twice daily. The time of use as far as days or weeks can also 
vary. Some people may only need to take these supplements for a week or 
two whereas others may need a longer time period. Each person is unique. 
See www.raysahelian.com/stjohn.html 

 Q. This it to inform you of a statin drug danger. My wife, 67, never smoked, no alcohol, very active physically (non 
stop gardening and ceramicist who hunks and throws clay up to 10kg at a a 
time) was started on 20mg pravastatin (Pravachol) ten weeks ago for high 
cholesterol. Two weeks ago she felt sensitivity at upper right abdomen unabated 
for 7 days. Then weakness / loss of appetite/ reduced drinking during a 
day. Early that day a doctor muttered about gall bladder after consulting 
current diagnosis software: she proposed ultrasound; queue, 4 weeks. Later 
in day, weaker and weaker, no temp. yet, back to a different general 
doctor. He was concerned: to ER. Passed out sitting! amylase already 
3300! Statin stopped immediately; no food, no statin, pain stopped in 15 
hours. Four days in ward; starvation, iv water/salts. After four days amylase down to 100. Liver function 
fine apart from elevated LDH. Ultrasound was negative as also CT, no sign of biliary 
deposits problem. Other exclusions: hepatitis etc etc. As in many 
cases of pancreatitis, the doctors have no suggestions. After 3 days back 
home wife seems herself, eating carefully; we hope that this is first/last 
time. Statins can have very wide &apos;mild&apos; effects over a range 
of systems. So damage can be slight but slow, unnoticed till the cart tips 
suddenly. This is a particularly dangerous kind of situation. My wife is 
lucky - we hope; another week to diagnosis and the pancreatitis could 
have led to permanent pancreatic damage (at least cartilage and muscle 
effects are noticeable). Not only is the public very unaware of the danger 
to the pancreas, but it seems most GPs too! This is unacceptable. Is the 
FDA unaware too? Thanks for keeping an eye out for an unsatisfactorily 
protected public. 

 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 14 -- November 20, 2008
===================================
&quot;Wider cholesterol drug use may save lives.
Study might lead far more Americans to consider taking statin drugs.&quot;
  Have you read or heard of this widely reported study regarding the 
use of a statin drug called Crestor? The media has been promoting the 
benefits of this drug for use by those who have normal cholesterol levels 
as a way to reduce the risk of heart disease and stroke. IRRESPONSIBLE. That is 
how I would describe the reporting of the Crestor study by news organizations. 
The vast majority of reporters did not offer another 
interpretation of the study, or interview a researcher with a contrary opinion, but just went along with the pharmaceutical 
company press release. Later I will discuss the flaws of this study. You 
can then decide if you want to take the risk of using a drug for years and 
decades whose side effects and dangers may be far reaching. 

 1. Maca herb helps women 
after menopause 
 Researchers at Victoria University, St. Albans, Victoria, Australia gave fourteen postmenopausal women 3.5 grams a day of maca for 6 weeks and 
compared them to a group receiving placebo pills. No differences 
were seen in blood concentrations of estradiol, follicle-stimulating 
hormone, luteinizing hormone, and sex hormone-binding globulin between 
 
maca treatment and placebo. The women who received the maca pills had a significant reduction in anxiety and depression 
and had improved sexual function. The researchers conclude,&quot;Preliminary findings show that 
maca reduces 
psychological symptoms, including anxiety and depression, and lowers 
measures of sexual dysfunction in postmenopausal women independent of 
estrogenic and androgenic activity.&quot;
  My comments: Maca is an interesting herb that grows in the Andes 
mountains in Peru and other other countries in South America. Even though 
this study used 3.5 grams (3500 milligrams) a day, I would suggest using 
less, such as 500 to 2000 mg a day if you plan to take the herb for long 
term use. See http://www.raysahelian.com/maca.html 
  I like maca herb. I have personally noticed more energy, improved 
wellbeing, and mild sexual enhancement after a few days of maca use. There 
are more potent herbs than maca in terms of sexual enhancement including 
tongkat ali, mucuna pruriens, tribulus, muira puama, the combination 
formula Passion Rx, and others. They all work in men and women. See http://www.raysahelian.com/libido.html 

 2. Will taking the statin drug Crestor help you live 
longer? CAUTION 
Here is a basic summary of this study funded by AstraZeneca, the maker of 
Crestor (rosuvastatin):
  About 18,000 healthy men and women with normal cholesterol levels but 
with elevated levels of&quot;high-sensitivity C-reactive protein&quot;or hs-CRP 
-- a marker that indicates inflammation in the body -- took 20 milligrams of Crestor 
a day and were compared to 
a group taking a placebo pill. Designed to last up to five years, the 
study was stopped after less than two years because endpoints were 
apparently met. According to the statistical interpretations, participants taking Crestor reduced their risk of heart 
attack, stroke and death compared with those taking the placebo pills. LDL cholesterol levels and hs-CRP levels were 
reduced by Crestor. Interestingly, at the time the study was stopped, 
it appeared that those who were taking Crestor were starting to have 
higher blood sugar levels. You would think 
the study would have continued to see if diabetes would set in after a few 
more months or years of use.
  Hardly any news organizations reported the potential downside of 
taking this drug, flaws in the study, or misinterpretation of the results. The rate of muscle 
aches and liver damage by statins is much higher in clinical practice than 
what is reported in studies. There may also be potential mental decline 
from the use of statins. I still have not seen any studies where the use 
of statins in those who have low or moderate cholesterol elevation has led 
to a decrease in overall mortality. it is quite possible that a statin 
drug can reduce cholesterol levels, reduce CRP levels, reduce the risk of heart attack 
and 
stroke, yet lead to a shorter lifespan. How could this happen you ask? This could be due to several 
factors including muscle damage that leads a patient doing less 
exercise, mental decline leading to a higher rate of dementia, lower mood or depression 
leading to a higher rate of suicides, liver damage, kidney damage, and 
other unknown and potentially serious side effects that could harm the 
body.
 A DOCTOR I CAN RESPECT. Fortunately, the website of ABC News had an 
article by Dr. Nortin Hadler which reviewed the flaws of the study. Dr. 
Nortin Hadler is professor of medicine at the University of North Carolina 
at Chapel Hill. If 
your doctor advises you to take Crestor or another statin drug as a 
consequence of the results of this study, you MUST read this article and 
you MUST request that your doctor read it, too. The reduction in heart 
attack or stroke was minimal, almost insignificant, not as high as the 
news media made it seem. Plus, the cost of Crestor, blood tests, and 
doctor visits can be several thousand dollars a year. Practically speaking 
our health care system, particularly during these tough economic times, 
cannot afford this heavy cost for minimal gain, it any gain at all. See
http://abcnews.go.com/Health/HeartDiseaseNews/story?id=6207285&amp;page=1
  The headlines by news organizations are sometimes misleading. If you are a 
regular reader of my newsletter you are aware that I have warned you not 
to trust headlines and to be critical of what you read or hear. The media is not 
sophisticated enough to understand and interpret studies. They often 
believe and regurgitate whatever the drug companies tell them.
  As a medical doctor who has studied natural ways to decrease 
inflammation and heart disease, it saddens me that more natural and safer 
approaches are not discussed or promoted as aggressively as studies 
involving expensive and unsafe medications. There are so many natural ways to 
reduce cholesterol, heart disease and inflammation including fish oils, psyllium and other 
natural fibers, and 
potentially the addition of spices such as curcumin, ginger, etc. I will 
continue researching this topic and updating the latest research on 
natural ways to improve cardiovascular health. See http://www.raysahelian.com/inflammation.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/cholesterol.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/statins.html 

 3. Vitamin C lowers 
C-reactive protein levels 
Do you want to lower your CRP levels naturally? Rather than taking Crestor 
which can cost a couple of thousand dollars a year and cause potential 
harm to your body, you may be able to reduce your C-reactive protein 
levels by adding more fruits and vegetables to your diet and by taking 
vitamin C, a safe and natural supplement. One recent study showed taking 
1000 mg of vitamin C lowered CRP levels. I don&apos;t think there is a need to 
take 1,000 mg every single day. Even 100 to 500 mg could be helpful or you 
can take the 1000 mg a few days a week. See http://www.raysahelian.com/creactiveprotein.html for details. 

 Emails 
Q. I am just writing to express enormous gratitude. 
I am a doctor in London and have intermittently suffered from depression 
since my 20s. I am now 52. I have been taking amitriptyline 150mg a day 
for the last 10 years after my psychiatrist and I went through almost the 
entire pharmacopoeia, including SSRIs, SNRIs, MAOIs, lithium, sodium valproate etc. The side effects from all of those drugs were severe 
enough for me to be unable to tolerate any of them and amitriptyline 
appeared to suit me, though I still had breakthrough depressions, often 
quite severe, and I could do nothing about them drug wise because of my 
intolerances. At the moment cognitive behavioural therapy is flavour of 
the month here in the UK but it never had the slightest beneficial effect on me. In 
addition, every non-prescription chemical I tried, including St. Johns 
wort, produced no beneficial effect. During my most recent depressive 
episode I searched the internet in desperation for any possible treatment 
I might have missed out on, and I came across your articles on 5 HTP. I 
ordered some online and the effect has been spectacular. After the second 
dose I felt better than I have felt in so many years that my only regret 
is that I didnt discover this supplement years ago. I appreciate that it is 
early for me (I have been on 100mg a day for the last 4 weeks) 
but I know that I am remarkably better. My friends and family have also 
noticed the positive change in my behaviour and for the first time in so 
many years I have positive feelings about the future.
  I also suffer from ulcerative colitis and interestingly, or rather 
unfortunately, my gastroenterologist started me on methotrexate 7.5mg and 
folic acid 5mg once weekly as my condition deteriorated over the last few 
months. After the second dose I started to feel extremely depressed and 
very tired. Surprisingly the gastroenterologist denied the possibility of 
methotrexate being the cause but I discovered a few reports suggesting 
that in some animal studies methotrexate has been shown to lower brain 
serotonin levels. I stopped the medication and within about 10 days I felt 
well again. There is no doubt in my mind that methotrexate caused this 
recent problem. Anyway, Im extremely grateful to you. I feel like I have 
my life back after many difficult years. I worked for 7 years as a 
consultant in emergency medicine. I loved the work but had to leave that 
job because of the crippling depression I had and for the last 8 years I 
have worked as a general practitioner in private practice which is far 
less stressful. I will continue to take the 5 HTP I am a skeptic and 
dont believe in miracle-cures but in this case....
  A. Wow. I truly hope your improvement continues. There are several 
other natural options to consider in treating depression. See http://www.raysahelian.com/depression.html 

Q. I want to say thank you for your product Eyesight Rx. My vision improved a 
lot with the first bottle and now I am on the second bottle. However, I 
have a couple of questions. Why is the dose of so low, are there any side effects to prevent?
  A. The ideal Eyesight Rx dosage varies among individuals. Some people do well on 
higher amounts, others do well on lower dosages. We also found that taking 
too much actually makes vision more fuzzy since it is possible that 
supplying too high dosages of lutein or other ingredients in eye formulas 
may throw off the delicate balance in the retina. Taking a day off every 2 
or 3 days or taking a tiny amount -- a sixth, fifth, quarter or third of a tablet daily 
-- once vision has improved is likely to work better than taking a full 
tablet. Taking a fish oil supplement in the morning helps vision and helps 
Eyesight Rx work better. The fish oil dosage could be 2 to 4 or 5 softgels 
a day. Consult with your health care provider if you plan to take more 
than 2 fish oil softgels a day. Use a lower dosage of Eyesight Rx if you 
are past age 55. One common side effect with Eyesight Rx is shallow 
sleep if one tablet is taken daily for several days in a row.
  

 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 13 -- November, 2008
===================================
 We recently received a very interesting email: &quot;I am a medical doctor working for a major pharmaceutical 
company. First, I speak for myself here, not them. I think we as an 
industry save lives and that some natural medicine oriented people bash 
the industry too much. That being said, I am very open to and 
use/experiment with many supplements that truly complement my standard 
meds. We docs who develop pharmaceutical meds are just 
like those on the front lines of practice. We work tirelessly to save 
lives. I beg you and others to bash our industry less. We add years to 
life and life to years--truly. But in return, I say your web site does, too. 
Let me tell you my experiences with some of your products.&quot;
 My problem with the pharmaceutical industry has to do with the excessive 
promotion of drugs for the treatment of conditions where safer, and just 
as effective, natural supplements are available. For instance, a recent 
review published on St. John&apos;s wort herb found it to be just as effective 
as prescription anti-depressants and with fewer side effects. A few 
paragraphs below you will find my full reply to his email and I include 
his personal reviews and comments regarding some of the supplements I have 
formulated. 

 1. St. John&apos;s wort for depression
 German researchers at the Centre for 
Complementary Medicine in Munich in Germany, reviewed 29 studies involving a total of 
5,500 patients with depression that compared treatment with extracts of 
St. John&apos;s wort with placebo treatment or standard 
antidepressant medications.
The studies were done in a variety of countries and tested several different St. 
John&apos;s wort extracts. They write,&quot;Overall, we found that the St. John&apos;s wort extracts tested in the trials 
were superior to placebos and as effective as standard antidepressants, 
with fewer side effects.&quot; See http://www.raysahelian.com/stjohn.html for details.
  Comments: Here is an example of a natural supplement underused by 
the medical profession. There are several other herbs and nutrients that 
could be effective as natural treatments for mild to moderate depression 
including 5-HTP and SAM-e. See http://www.raysahelian.com/depression.html for details. 5-HTP is 
useful in those who have depression associated with anxiety. SAM-e is 
useful in those whose depression is associated with low energy. High doses 
of SAM-e can cause anxiety. St. John&apos;s wort can be used in several types 
of depression. My general advice is to use low dosages for a few days and 
then adjust the amounts higher if needed. 5-HTP is often taken in the 
evening on an empty stomach whereas SAM-e and St. John&apos;s wort are taken in 
the morning a few minutes before breakfast. If you use high dosages of 
SAM-e or St. John&apos;s wort, it could lead to insomnia. Lack of adequate 
sleep contributes to low mood and energy. If you notice shallow sleep 
after taking either SAM-e or St. John&apos;s wort, skip a dose the next day or 
take a lesser dose. Discuss with your health care provider regarding the 
use of natural supplements, particularly if you have a health issue or 
taking medications. 

 2. Artichoke leaf extract slightly reduces 
cholesterol 
British researchers at the University of Reading, Reading, UK gave 130 
adults who had high total cholesterol levels 1280 mg of a standardized 
artichoke leaf extract daily for 12 weeks and compared the results to a 
control group. Plasma total cholesterol decreased in the treatment group 
by an average of 4 percent and increased in the control group by an 
average of 2 percent. No significant differences between groups were 
observed for LDL cholesterol, HDL cholesterol or triglyceride levels.
  Comments: If someone has a cholesterol level of 250 mg, a 4 percent 
drop would be 10 mg, which is not bad. There are several natural 
supplements that could be helpful in those with high cholesterol levels. 
In my opinion many patients can avoid the use of statin drugs, or reduce 
the required dosage, with the 
appropriate use and combination of dietary approaches and supplement 
usage. See http://www.raysahelian.com/cholesterol.html . 
See also http://www.raysahelian.com/artichoke.html 

 Emails from readers 
Q. I see magnesium stearate is found in many supplement capsules. I read 
on a web site that it may not be safe. What is your opinion of magnesium stearate?
  A. Magnesium stearate is basically a fatty acid called 
stearic acid, or stearate, attached to the mineral magnesium. In my opinion, there is misleading information on some websites that 
claim magnesium stearate, even in miniscule amounts, is dangerous. There 
is no evidence this is true. Most capsules that include magnesium stearate 
use an amount ranging from 10 to 20 milligrams. One gram equals 1000 milligrams. You can see 
the insignificance of this amount. If you eat chocolate, you will consume 
a very high amount of stearic acid, hundreds or thousands or times more 
than in the capsules. Chocolate contains cocoa butter, which has a number 
of fatty acids. One-third of chocolate&apos;s fat comes from the fatty acid 
stearic acid. Yet, hardly anyone worries about the stearic acid found in chocolate yet we get emails from people overly 
concerned about a tiny amount found in capsules. I am not aware of any studies that show 
magnesium stearate, in the small amounts found in capsules, has any side 
effects or causes any harm. If anyone knows of a study that indicates that 
this substance, in the small amounts found in capsules, has shown to 
have harmful effects, email me. I have searched extensively and not seen 
any such studies. I believe there is misinformation on web sites that 
claim this substance is harmful . If 
anyone tells you magnesium stearate in the small amounts found in capsules 
is harmful, challenge them to provide you with a human trial that proves 
their point. See http://www.raysahelian.com/magnesiumstearate.html for reviews and 
studies regarding stearic acid ingestion.

Q. This email was by a medical doctor who works for a major 
pharmaceutical industry mentioned at the beginning of the newsletter. He reviews some of the products I have 
formulated. My comments follow each of his reviews and then I have a final 
comment about the pharmaceutical industry.

1. Mind Power Rx: Definitely more mental energy and focus. I have to 
take days off or it either wears off or I get very emotionally tense,&quot;keyed up.&quot;
  Dr. Sahelian comments: Yes, most people notice improved mental concentration, 
focus and more mental energy, generally the same day, often within hours. I suggest not using it more than 3 days 
a week. 

 2. Eyesight Rx: This one is really amazing. Pastel colors came to life for 
me within hours of the first dose. I somehow liked and appreciated earth 
tones again after I had begun finding them dull and boring. The appearance 
of some floaters I have decreased in intensity. Complement with some fish 
oils which also helps the Eyesight Rx as you note on your site.
  Dr. S comments: I find the combination of several fish oils capsules in 
the morning on an empty stomach along with about a half of 
an Eyesight Rx melted under the tongue works quite well after a few days to 
improve day and night vision, close and distance vision, and enhancement 
of color perception. Some people need a full tablet, at least initially. The dosage needs to be adjusted 
up or down on a regular basis and it is a good idea to take a day off from 
the Eyesight Rx every 3 days or so. As to fish oils, about three to 
five softgels are helpful taken on an empty stomach in the morning a few 
minutes before breakfast..

3. Diet Rx: Definitely works, but not consistently. I wonder if it is due 
to what I eat with breakfast and how well it gets absorbed or not.
  Comments: Diet Rx works best when taken on an empty stomach at least 45 
minutes to an hour before breakfast. When taken with food it may not be as 
effective. Some people do well on one capsule a day, others 
require two or three, and a few people may need four capsules a day split 
into 2 before breakfast and 2 before lunch. The vast majority of Diet Rx 
users notice appetite suppression and have more will power in regards to 
eating less.

4. Passion Rx: Slightly increased libido. Most notable effect is that it 
sort of gives me&quot;beer goggles.&quot;Almost any woman looks more attractive to 
me in some way that they would not have before.
  Comments: I have formulated two versions of Passion Rx, with and 
without yohimbe. If one version does not work well, the other may work 
better. It normally takes a few days to appreciate the full benefits. 
An increase in libido is one of the first benefits followed by enhanced 
sensation, and a few days later by enhanced erectile function. Passion Rx is taken on an empty stomach at least an hour before breakfast 
two days on, one day off and less frequently when it starts working. 
The effects are noticed even on the days when it is not taken. In the long 
run many people only take Passion Rx 2 days a week. Sometimes if Passion Rx does not work as well as one wishes, individual 
herbs may. These include tribulus terrestris, tongkat ali, mucuna pruriens, 
catuaba, muira puama, horny goat weed, maca etc. It is not possible to 
predict which formula or single herb will work in any one individual. I 
suggest not taking Passion Rx the same day as Mind Power Rx or Eyesight Rx 
or any supplement that increases energy.

5. Good Night Rx: Two capsules calm me down some and help with a deeper 
sleep. Sometimes I take it with melatonin, and that works 
incredibly well, like a synergistic effect.
  Comments: Good Night Rx works well even with one capsule if taken at 
least 2 or 3 hours before bed on a completely empty stomach. If you eat 
late in the evening, take the Good Night Rx at least a half hour before 
dinner. The combination of melatonin may work better, but could enhance the intensity of dreams 
which can make nightmares more prominent.

I am a medical doctor working for a major pharmaceutical company. I think 
we as an industry save lives and that some natural medicine oriented 
people bash the industry too much. We docs who develop pharmaceutical meds 
are just like those on the front lines of practice. We work tirelessly to 
save lives. I beg you and others to bash our industry less. We add years 
to life and life to years--truly. But in return, I say your site does, 
too.
  Dr. Sahelian comments: Few people would deny the significant contributions made by 
the pharmaceutical industry in developing medications that have saved 
lives and reduced suffering. Almost everyone, at some point in their life, has 
benefited from the availability of vaccines, antibiotics, pain 
medications, anesthesia drugs, and a number of other drugs. My problem is 
with the excessive promotion of drugs for the treatment of chronic 
conditions where safer, and just as effective, natural supplements are 
available. For instance in the treatment of mild to moderately elevated 
cholesterol levels. I have not seen any evidence that the use of statin 
drugs for cholesterol management in those with mild or moderately high 
cholesterol levels improves longevity. Yet, I see so many people who get 
side effects from these drugs including severe muscle aches. Statins can 
cause damage to muscle tissue. Another area 
that natural supplements can help is with sexual enhancement. Although 
drugs such as Cialis, Viagra, and Levitra work very well in terms of 
erectile dysfunction, they do little in terms of libido enhancement, 
sensation, and overall sexual pleasure. The proper use of natural 
supplements can enhance erectile function (not necessarily as potently and 
quickly as the drugs), improve sexual drive, sexual stamina, and enhance 
genital sensation. Vision improvement and treatment of mood disorders are 
other areas where natural 
supplements are underused. The virtual monopoly of the pharmaceutical 
industry in terms of medication research and journal publications makes it 
difficult for the public, and doctors, to find out about the natural options that can 
work quite well in the treatment of degenerative and chronic conditions 
such as hypertension, high cholesterol, diabetes, heart disease, 
osteoarthritis, etc. 

 
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 12 -- October, 2008
===================================
The soy controversy continues. A newsletter reader writes,&quot;Your 
September newsletter regarding soy products leaves me a bit confused. This 
morning I got a newsletter from an osteopathic doctor. In it he warns against the use
of soy products, listing a number of serious afflictions that can be linked
to it. I am not sure what to do as far as eating soy.&quot;
  As I mentioned in the last newsletter, there are a few web sites 
and health writers who happen to have extreme viewpoints on the topic of 
soy. Whose opinion should you trust? This is a dilemma many people have 
when they read conflicting information on different web sites. We are 
exposed to a number of viewpoints by experts on a variety of topics such as 
nutrition, the economy, the war in Iraq, abortion, global warming, etc. It is up to the 
individual to decide, after evaluating opinions by several experts, which 
one they are most comfortable with. Japanese women live longer than any other people on the planet while 
consuming 60 g or more of soy products a day.
   This is my viewpoint on soy and if you are a member of the media 
receiving this newsletter, you can quote me:&quot; A small amount of soy (preferably organic) a few days a 
week or a few days a month in the form of tofu, natto, miso, soy sauce, 
unsweetened soy milk, or boiled soybeans, as part of a healthy diet that 
includes a wide variety of vegetables, fruits, whole grains, nuts, seeds, 
legumes, chicken, meat, fish, dairy, etc, should not pose any health 
concerns.&quot;I am not encouraging anyone to eat or not to eat soy products. 
I am just saying that if you want to eat soy products but have been afraid 
to do so, I do not believe small amounts are harmful. 
  We received quite a few interesting emails 
about the soy controversy that you will find below.
  In this issue I also 
discuss the potential benefit of a pine bark extract for arthritis, and acetylcysteine for chemotherapy-induced brain fog. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at Physician Formulas -- For the 
next few days the following products are on sale. Mind Power Rx 
helps improve mental alertness and wakefulness along with boosting mental 
stamina.
Broccoli sprouts contain sulforaphane. Chondroitin sulfate is a nutrient that helps with joint health. 
Chondroitin is often found in combination with glucosamine and other 
nutrients in joint formulas. One such popular formula is Joint Power Rx. Carnosine is a potent antioxidant that can also provide a 
subtle energy and 
mood lift in some users. Graviola is a popular fruit from South America 
with quite a 
number of interesting compounds.
LJ100 is a potent tongkat ali extract used in Malaysia as an aphrodisiac. 
LJ100 is also found in Passion Rx, a bestselling libido formula.
Green tea extract has EGCG, a compound becoming more and more popular. 

 1. Pine bark extract good for arthritis pain? 
Pycnogenol is an extract derived from the bark of the French maritime pine tree. 
Many lab studies have shown Pycnogenol to have strong antioxidant and anti-inflammatory 
properties. One study included 100 Slovakian adults with mild knee 
arthritis who were randomly assigned to take either 150 milligrams of pine 
bark extract or a placebo every day. According to Dr. 
Peter Rohdewald, of the University of Munster in Germany, knee arthritis 
patients who took Pycnogenol pine bark 
extract for three months reported an improvement in their pain, while 
those given a placebo had no improvement. The pain relief persisted for an 
additional two weeks after the patients stopped taking Pycnogenol. 
Switzerland-based Horphag Research Ltd., maker of 
Pycnogenol, funded the study.
 
For 
more info, see http://www.raysahelian.com/pycnogenol.html 
  Comments: There are several supplements that have been shown to be 
helpful for arthritis, including glucosamine and chondroitin. Joint Power 
Rx contains a number of beneficial nutrients including glucosamine, 
chondroitin, CMO, turmeric, MSM, boswellia extract, and others. Many 
people who have arthritis already take natural supplements for joint 
health support. Would the addition of Pycnogenol or another type of pine bark 
extract provide added benefits? Would the combination lead to unexpected 
side effects? There are no easy answers at this time. If your doctor 
approves, you could add Pycnogenol to your daily regimen. The dosage used 
in study was 150 mg a day. This may be an appropriate dosage in the 
beginning, but for long term use you may consider a maintenance dosage of 30 or 60 
mg a day. Just keep in mind that we don&apos;t know the effects of Pycnogenol 
supplement use if taken for many years, or how this product interacts with 
other supplements or medications, including NSAIDs such as aspirin, 
naproxen or ibuprofen. 

 2. N-Acetylcysteine and chemotherapy 
There is a condition called&quot;chemo-brain,&quot;which effects a large 
number of cancer patients receiving chemotherapy. Patients with 
this condition suffer from memory loss and have difficulty with focus and 
concentration. Dr. Gregory W. Konat and colleagues at West Virginia University School of 
Medicine in Morgantown first gave one group of rats two drugs commonly 
used to treat cancer, Adriamycin and Cytoxan. These drugs led to memory 
problems.
However, memory loss was prevented when the researchers 
gave the rats N-acetyl cysteine, or NAC, during chemotherapy.
  Comments: Since it is still not fully clear whether antioxidant 
treatment influences the effectiveness of cancer drugs during treatment, 
one option is to begin therapy with acetylcysteine, or other antioxdiants, a week 
after the last chemotherapy dose. The appropriate dosage of NAC for 
post-chemotherapy antioxidant treatment is not known, but a dosage of 500 
mg three times a week seems reasonable and prudent. See http://www.raysahelian.com/acetylcysteine.html for more info. 

Emails
 Q. Dear Dr. Sahelian, I was just reading the 
controversy on your site regarding soy consumption, and I just had to 
offer some anecdotal counter-evidence to all the alarmist discourse. My 
mother is from Japan, and our family was raised on quite a bit of 
soy-based foods: Tofu, natto, miso, cooked soy beans, soy sauce, etc. In 
terms of volume, tofu (an unfermented product) was probably the largest 
source of soy in our home. My little brother had no problem developing 
into a very masculine young man, and all of us were extremely healthy (I 
wish the soy would have boosted my breast development, but no such luck!). 
Anyone who says that Japanese people don&apos;t eat much soy have obviously 
never spent much time around traditional Japanese! Trust me: They eat LOADS of soy! I&apos;m not claiming that eating huge amounts of soy is ideal, 
but given how much they (and I) have consumed, it just doesn&apos;t make sense 
to talk about soy as though it is some kind of toxin. Even today, nearing 
40, I eat soy foods daily (I love tofu!). I am extremely healthy, have a 
strong libido, and an IQ of 160. Granted I do not consume much soy milk, 
as most of it is way too high in sugars, and I eat very little soy 
protein, because intuitively it just seems overly-processed and denatured 
to me. Honestly, I think that Americans are trying to find an easy answer 
for why they don&apos;t feel good. The problem is they don&apos;t eat their veggies
(because of my mom&apos;s good influence, I probably consume 20 times more 
vegetables than the average American--and mostly organic), they over- 
consume refined carbohydrates and processed foods, don&apos;t exercise enough, 
and are stressed out beyond belief! Americans want a quick fix:&quot;Just take 
that new supplement,&quot;&quot;Just stop eating soy!&quot;But building real health 
doesn&apos;t work that way. Dr. Sahelian, I applaud you for keeping it all in 
perspective. Your grounded and reasonable approach to health is a breath 
of fresh air in a sea of alarmists. Warm Regards, Robin H., Los Angeles, 
CA.
  A. I hope your email will help to ease the concern of many people 
who have been unduly afraid of eating even a small amount of soy due to 
certain websites and newsletters 
promoting extreme viewpoints on this topic. Soy is neither the healthiest 
food on the planet, nor is it a toxin. Soy 
is a legume that, when used in moderation, has health benefits and when 
used excessively may cause harm in some users. 

 Q. I was advised by my medical oncologist 
not to eat soy products because of estrogen fed breast cancer which 
did not spread into the lymph glands. It is difficult to find any products 
which do not contain soybean oil. I like tofu and soy sauce.
  A. I am not aware of any human studies that indicate eating small 
amounts of soy products has a negative influence on breast cancer. Studies 
show that eating soy does not have a major influence on hormone levels. 
See the above link for details and research papers on this topic. 

 Q. I have been purchasing Prostate Power Rx. Do 
you intend to add to this product selenium, zinc and pumpkin seed oil 
extract?
  A. Zinc and selenium are minerals that accumulate in the body and many 
people get adequate amounts of these through their multivitamins or their 
diet. Excess levels of these minerals can be harmful to health. The amount 
of pumpkin seed extract needed to be effective for prostate health in human is not well know. 
The small space in a prostate formula capsule that already has several others herbs does 
not allow for pumpkin seed oil to be added in adequate amounts. 
Furthermore, I am not aware of any extensive human studies that pumpkin 
seed oil shrinks an enlarged prostate. And if it does, the required dosage is 
not known. Not everything can fit in one pill, therefore those who wish to 
have pumpkin seed oil can buy and use this supplement as an addition to a 
prostate formula. See  http://www.raysahelian.com/pumpkinseed.html 

  Q. Your position on soy is based on the latest 
research and sound, even-mindedness. I agree with you; unless one can 
produce data to support the (often) hysterical claims by health extremists 
in the popular press, there is nothing to discuss. Unfortunately, too many 
Americans have a knee-jerk approach to mass media pronouncements. This 
does not mean that I am not in sympathy with those whose personal 
experiences don&apos;t follow the usual outcome. Everybody is different and 
some people may indeed respond differently to certain foods or 
supplements. But whatever happened to personal instinct and common sense? Sheesh! Thank you for your excellent newsletter and advice. I always enjoy 
reading your perspective and thoughts on current research.
All the best. 

 Q. Dear Dr. Sahelian, thank you so much for the 
Eyesight Rx formula! In September 2007, my eye care professional told me I 
needed to have cataract surgery on my right eye, and the left one was not 
far behind. I was having much difficulty reading, but at the time, I just 
didn&apos;t see how I could take even a week to take care of this situation. I 
ran a search, and came upon your web site, and decided to try your 
Eyesight Rx, and was thrilled when it arrived so quickly. I immediately 
put half a tablet under my tongue and let it dissolve, then swallowed the 
other half with a glass of water. I couldn&apos;t believe I was seeing more 
clearly within hours. I continued on the program, taking breaks on the 
week-ends, and my eyes just kept getting better! I&apos;ve been near-sighted 
for years, was having difficulty with night vision, floaters, and then the 
cataracts. I recently went in to get new glasses, and my doctor was&quot;blown 
away&quot;when he saw the improvement in my vision! I am no longer a candidate 
for cataract surgery, and just wanted to let you know! Thank you so very 
much for your work, and the help you give to others. I am still required 
to wear my glasses for driving, but I do not need them for reading, 
working at the computer, or other close vision at this time.
  A. I am thrilled when we receive such positive feedback about 
the products I formulate. I put so much effort and heart into making sure 
I develops supplement that can help people and when we gets emails such as 
yours, I become real happy. Many people find the required dosage of 
Eyesight Rx is less with time since the nutrients accumulate in the eyes. 
Taking two to four fish oil softgels in the morning on an empty stomach 
can help Eyesight Rx work even better and would reduce the needed dosage 
of Eyesight Rx. As a maintenance dose for long term use, many people do 
well taking a third of a tablet 2 days on, one day off. Some may need a 
higher dosage, others less. 

 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 11 -- September, 2008
===================================
In the August issue of the newsletter I wrote that 
eating small amounts of soy, as part of a diet that has a wide range of 
foods, was acceptable. Since then we received a number of emails 
from people who adamantly felt that including even a tiny amount of soy in 
the diet was harmful. When asked for research papers that support their 
position, they referred us to certain web sites maintained by people with 
extreme viewpoints. You will find some of the correspondence at the bottom 
of this newsletter. Apparently there are a few websites that are scaring 
people from consuming any type of soy. Japanese women live longer than 
women from any other country in the world. I looked into how much 
soy Japanese eat a day. On average, a Japanese man or woman eats between 
50 to 100 grams of soy products a day in a variety of forms including tofu, natto, 
and boiled soybeans in a pod (edamame). If soy is supposed to be so bad for you, how come Japanese 
women live so long? How can anyone with a rational mind argue that my 
viewpoint that eating a small amount of soy foods such as tofu or 
boiled soybeans -- 
a fraction of what Japanese eat -- can be harmful? The discussion 
continues at the bottom of the page. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted:
 
Passion Rx and Passion Rx with Yohimbe are on sale. 
They are top selling herbal sexual enhancers. Some prefer regular Passion 
Rx, 
others prefer the formula with yohimbe bark extract, both are popular. 
Please read the info on dosages and how to best take these 
supplements. The website gives a detailed explanation. We now carry a 
sample size bottle of Passion Rx with Yohimbe that has 8 capsules. 
Passion Rx is one of the most popular products on the internet for 
the purposes of sexual enhancement. It takes a few days or a week (one 
capsule every other day or two days on, one day off) for the full benefits 
to be apparent.
Fish oils are one of our favorite supplements. Fish oils are always 
popular and a great addition to those whose diets lack adequate intake of 
fish or omega-3 fatty acids. Acidophilus is 
a supplement containing beneficial bacteria for colon health. Artichoke 
extract contains a number of beneficial flavonoids useful for gut health 
and cholesterol management. CMO, also known as cetyl myristoleate, 
contains a concentrated extract of a fatty acid used for joint health. CMO 
is also found in Joint Power Rx.
Lutein is a nutrient used for eye health and is also found in the popular 
formula Eyesight Rx. 
This lutein product has 20 mg and need only be taken 2 or 3 times a week. 
Pomegranate has substances, such as polyphenols that have a number of 
health benefits.

 1. Brazil nuts -- great source 
of selenium 
Researchers at the University of Otago, in Dunedin, New Zealand split 69 New Zealand adults 
into three groups. For a period of 12 weeks, one group was asked to eat 2 Brazil nuts 
a day, another group took 100 
mcg of a selenium supplement, and the third group got a placebo pill. The 2 Brazil nuts provided about 50 mcg of selenium. 
The selenium level in the blood increased by 64 percent in the Brazil nut 
group, 61 percent in those who took the supplement, and hardly at all in 
the placebo group. The conclusion was that consumption of 
2 Brazil nuts daily was as effective for increasing selenium status and 
enhancing glutathione peroxidase activity as taking 100 mcg of selenium. Glutathione peroxidase is one 
of many important antioxidant enzymes in the body. See http://www.raysahelian.com/selenium.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/glutathione.html 
  Comments: There is no need to consume Brazil nuts every day since 
we get selenium from other food sources. However, rather than taking a 
selenium supplement by itself, you may consider eating one or two Brazil 
nuts a few times a week. One shortcoming of Brazil nuts is that they 
are quite high in calories. if you put a flame to a Brazil nut you will be 
amazed on how well it burns. 

 2. Curcumin may help Alzheimer&apos;s 
patients
 Curcumin, a prominent 
antioxidant and anti-inflammatory substance found in the spice turmeric, may increase the clearance of amyloid plaques in the brain. 
Amyloids are insoluble protein aggregates found in the brain tissue of 
patients with Alzheimer&apos;s disease. Amyloid accumulation in organs leads 
to amyloidosis. Dr. Milan Fiala, from the Greater Los Angeles Veteran&apos;s 
Affairs Medical Center, found in test tube studies that immune cells called 
macrophages taken from patients with Alzheimer&apos;s disease cannot 
efficiently eliminate amyloid. Treating these cells with curcumin enhances macrophage function.
Dr. Milan Fiala says,&quot;Further studies are needed to determine if increasing blood levels of 
macrophages using an oral curcumin agent clear the amyloid plaques, and 
produce therapeutic effects, in patients with Alzheimer&apos;s disease.&quot;See http://www.raysahelian.com/curcumin.html 
  Comments: It is too early to tell whether taking one or two 
curcumin capsules a day will help reduce the incidence of Alzheimer&apos;s 
disease, but since curcumin has many health benefits, I don&apos;t see any harm 
in taking a capsule a day or a capsule a few times a week. Discuss with 
your doctor if you are taking other supplements or medications. 

 3. Should you have a PSA test 
for prostate cancer 
if you are over 75? 
A few years ago my dad was found to have a high PSA test. He was 74 at the 
time. He underwent multiple visits to the doctor over the next few months 
with repeated PSA tests and prostate exams, and eventually a prostate biopsy indicated he 
had a small, localized, prostate cancer. I remember my dad calling me several times a 
month during that period constantly asking for my thoughts on whether he should 
proceed with surgery, radiation or other treatments for his cancer. My dad had a 
preexisting heart condition known as atrial fibrillation. I suggested he 
not undergo any treatment for the small cancer but just to follow the PSA 
levels. His doctor agreed with my opinion. His PSA level stayed 
relatively the same over the next few years and the prostate cancer did 
not grow larger. My dad died at 78 from a heart rhythm problem. Ever since 
the discovery of the high PSA level, he was constantly worried about this 
prostate gland. What good did it do to have this PSA test at his age? It 
only led to more doctor visits, a painful prostate gland biopsy, 
additional medical bills and insurance forms to fill out, and 
constant worry. Maybe the constant worry even made his heart weaker.
  Recently the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force advised that&quot;The benefits of 
prostate cancer treatment based on 
routine PSA screening in men over age 75 are small to none. However, 
treatment often causes moderate-to-substantial harms, including erectile 
dysfunction and bladder control and bowel problems. Doctors should stop routine prostate cancer 
screening of men over age 75 because there is more evidence of harm than 
benefit.&quot;
  A study has found that older men who already have early-stage 
prostate cancer are not taking a big risk by not treating it right away. 
The vast majority are alive 10 years later without significantly worsening 
symptoms, or die of other causes. See http://www.raysahelian.com/psa.html and also http://www.raysahelian.com/prostatecancer.html 

 4. Longevity fact 
Japanese girls born in 2007 can expect to live until they are 86 years 
old, which would make them the longest survivors in the world. Boys born 
in 2007 can expect to live to the age of 79, ranking third after Iceland 
and Hong Kong. See http://www.raysahelian.com/longevity.html 

 Emails
 Q. I have 
been taking SAM-e tablets for approximately three weeks and have had no 
urges to gamble or drink. I am a recovering compulsive gambler and 
alcoholic and have had recent bouts with depression. My counselor thought 
that giving SAM-e tablets a try would help, as she found it to help other 
gamblers and alcoholics such as myself. It is a blessing for me, as I can 
focus more clearly on rational thinking day to day instead of the 
delusional thoughts that compulsive gambling had led me to believe. I will 
not admit that I am cured but the relief I am experiencing has been 
amazing to say the least!.
  A. The effects of 
SAM-e supplements accumulate, therefore it is best to reduce the dosage 
with time in order to avoid SAM-e side effects. http://www.raysahelian.com/sam-e.html 

 Q. I have been using the Joint Power Rx formula for 
over 2-months and am quite happy with the results. We have several 
dogs (50-60 pounds) that have hip joint problems and I am curious if this joint 
formula can be used for them, and, if so, what dosage would be recommended. I 
take two caps, twice daily.
  A. This is a good question. Joint Power Rx was formulated with the 
intention that it be used by older men and women for joint health but we have 
had some positive reports from people who have given it to their dogs. It is 
difficult to know the appropriate dosage for a dog, but it would seem a dog of 
50 pounds would tolerate two capsules a day. The capsules can be opened and 
sprinkle on food. Please have approval by the 
vet. I am aware of a vet clinic that has purchased Joint Power Rx and continues 
to re-order on a regular basis. http://www.raysahelian.com/jointpowerrx.html 

 Q. First I should tell you that I have deep 
respect for you and I appreciate both the products you sell, and your 
articles. I don&apos;t understand though how you can go on, year after year, 
advocating that people consume soy products, while the evidence mounts of 
the damage soy does. It&apos;s true, as you write, that the Japanese eat a lot 
of soy. But (as you know), almost all of the soy they eat is fermented. 
Fermentation reduces the toxicity of soy. I have friends from Japan who 
are shocked at the amount of soy that is eaten in the U.S. Here in the 
U.S. soy is in everything. It&apos;s almost impossible to find processed foods 
without it. We eat far more soy than the Japanese do or ever did, and we 
eat it in its most noxious form, the form that, when fed to animals, has 
been shown to disrupt their hormones, speed up their body cycles, cause 
early sexual maturity, and cause animals fed large doses of it to become 
unable to reproduce. In the U.S. today, girls are coming to sexual 
maturity earlier than they ever did. Boys and men have precipitously low 
sperm counts. It&apos;s interesting that as the amount of this pollutant has 
increased in our diet, we are experiencing the same symptoms animals 
exhibit when fed this noxious&quot;health food.&quot;I spent years eating large 
amounts of soy, thinking I was doing something&quot;healthful&quot;and beneficial 
for myself. I ate soy cereal in the morning, drank soy milk instead of 
cow&apos;s milk, mixed tofu in my scrambled eggs, ate Tofutti for dessert. I 
was a&quot;soy believer&quot;like you. As the months went by I developed a myriad 
of health conditions. I felt mentally dull and lost interest in sex. I was 
the sickest I&apos;ve ever been in my life. Finally I did some research and 
started wondering if soy might be contributing to my problems. I had a 
hard time believing it, I was so convinced it must be&quot;good for you,&quot;but 
I finally tried removing it from my diet for a trial period. Within two 
months after I stopped eating soy, I regained my health. Virtually every 
health condition I was suffering from improved or disappeared. My mind is 
sharp and clear again. I&apos;m in my fifties, but feel like I&apos;m in my 
twenties.
  A. Your symptoms may have been due to overconsumption of soy 
products and this is not a good argument against my position that small 
amounts of soy, in the form of tofu, natto, and boiled soybeans, as part of a healthy diet that includes a variety of 
foods, is acceptable. Furthermore, most soy milk products have lots of 
added sugar. People should keep consumption of processed foods to a 
minimum. If soy consumption reduces fertility, it apparently has not had 
much effect in China or Japan. Can you provide factual data or research studies that shed light on your claims 
regarding:
What is the amount of soy eaten by the average Japanese?
What is the amount of soy eaten by an average American?
What is the evidence that eating small amounts of soy is harmful to 
health?
Which country has the longest living humans on average?
Please let us know the evidence in humans that fermentation reduces the 
toxicity of soy. Are you implying that eating boiled soybeans is harmful?
Please provide research studies that eating soy products reduces 
longevity.
  We would appreciate you referring to us the research studies you 
have come across that would help us understand your point of view.
  For the replies and additional communications, see http://www.raysahelian.com/soyprotein.html 

 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 10 -- August, 2008
===================================
Just about every food we consume, at some time, has had 
a negative review or caution. Eggs have been blamed for high 
cholesterol; Meats for increasing cancer risk; Fish for having high 
amounts of mercury; Milk for having hormones or causing allergies; Fruits 
and vegetables for high pesticide levels or bacterial contamination; Bread 
and baked goods for 
a cancer causing agent called acrylamide; Fruit juices for raising blood 
sugar in diabetics. The latest caution seems to focus on soy products. A study 
found that men who eat soy have a lower sperm count. We&apos;ve had a few 
emails this week from men who are now worried about eating soy. What is a person to 
do? There seems to be few safe foods left to eat. My comments later.
  For the month of August, we are offering a free bottle of choline 
supplement. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted:
MultiVit Rx enhances mood, energy, vision, mental clarity, and wellbeing. 
It is quite potent, and even though it says to take up to 4 
capsules a day, two capsules work well for most people. Some may only need 
one, others take three capsules. Curcumin continues to get a lot of press for its many health 
benefits reported in studies; Maca is an herb from the Andes Mountains in South America used for energy 
and sexual vitality.
Lyprinol is an extract from New Zealand green-lipped mussel used for joint 
health;
Cacao supplements are an excellent choice for those who want to get the 
benefits of dark chocolate but do not wish to ingest calories from fat and 
sugar.

 1. Soy products and sperm count
 Researchers at the Harvard School of Public Health in 
Boston found that men who consumed high amounts of soy foods had a 
lower sperm count compared to those who did not consume soy foods. Soy products 
contain plant-derived estrogens known as phytoestrogens. Some animal 
studies have linked high consumption of phytoestrogens with infertility. The researchers evaluated the intake of 
soy-based foods in men who went to a fertility clinic. They were asked how 
much they had eaten of soy-rich foods including: tofu, tempeh, tofu or soy 
sausages, bacon, burgers and mince, soy milk, cheese, yogurt and ice cream, and 
other soy products such as drinks, powders and energy bars. Men in the highest 
intake category of soy products had a lower sperm count compared to those in the 
lowest intake category. For details, see http://www.raysahelian.com/sperm.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/phytoestrogens.html 
  My comments: A couple of decades ago soy products started becoming 
popular and many people switched from meat to tofu and from milk to soy 
drinks. More soy-based products appeared on the market and I personally 
know many people, particularly vegetarians, who eat a variety of soy-based 
foods a day, including soy-based burgers and ice cream. Based on the study 
presented above regarding the influence of soy on sperm count, a friend of 
mine now tells me he will stop eating all soy products. I think this is an 
overreaction. A better approach is to have a wide variety of foods in the 
diet rather than to completely shun some. I mentioned at the beginning of the 
newsletter that most foods have had some bad press at some time. Just keep 
in mind that if you eliminate one type of food you are more likely to overconsume 
another type that may not be healthy when eaten in larger amounts.
  Unless a man has a low sperm 
count and issues with fertility, I don&apos;t see the need to eliminate soy products from the diet. 
People in Japan consume a good amount of soy products yet they do not 
appear to have any problems with reproductive health or longevity. 

 2. Safety of saw palmetto herb
 The Saw palmetto for Treatment of Enlarged Prostates study was a 
randomized clinical trial performed among 225 men with moderate-to-severe 
symptoms of benign prostatic hyperplasia, comparing a standardized extract 
of the saw palmetto berry (160mg twice daily) with a placebo over a 1-year 
period. No evidence for 
serious side effects or dangers of saw palmetto was observed in this 12 
month long clinical trial. 
For details, see http://www.raysahelian.com/saw.html 
  My comments: This is reassuring since saw palmetto is a supplement 
used by men for many months and years. I hope in a few years we can have 
results of a longer study, such as five years. 

 3. Drug money influences the American Psychiatric 
Association
 The APA is the voice of establishment 
psychiatry. This organization publishes major journals in psychiatry and its standard 
diagnostic manual. Is the APA fully independent or are some of its 
positions influenced by the drug industry? The senate has demanded that 
the American Psychiatric Association give an accounting of its financing. 

 Email questions and 
comments
 Q. Thanks for your honesty and responsible behavior on your website 
and in your newsletters. Very rare indeed especially when the comments are 
coming from someone that formulates the products they are discussing. I can 
honestly say that I dont think I have ever read anything from a 
supplements related company that wasnt somewhat cluttered with their bias 
and desire to sell their products. You would be the exception. Thank you.
  A. I appreciate your comments. I grew up in a culture and family 
that valued honesty and integrity. It is possible to help people, and make 
a living, by providing honest information and good products. I can&apos;t claim 
that every bit of information I write about is accurate or every product I 
formulate will help everyone, but I honestly do my best. 

 Q. I understand there are different extracts of tongkat ali, the sexual 
enhancing herb. Is a100 to 1 
extract more 
powerful than 20 to1 extract? But what does it mean if a product has 25 mg of 100:1 
compared to 200 mg of 20:1? How do I know which one works better or is 
more potent?
  A. It is very difficult to compare tongkat ali products since there are 
many companies that make tongkat ali in different potencies and one 
company&apos;s 100 to 1 extract may be weaker or stronger than another company&apos;s 
100 to 1 extract. Also, a 100 to 1 extract may not necessarily be exactly 
5 times more potent as a 20 to 1 extract since different extraction 
processes are used and the quality of the herbs can vary among raw 
material suppliers. Also, it is possible that, for marketing purposes, 
certain companies will attempt to make it seem that their product is a very high 
concentration, such as 100 to 1 or 200 to 1 whereas in actuality it is not as 
concentrated as they claim.
  With tongkat ali, as with most herbs, it is best to try and learn how each 
product works for you at different dosages, always starting with low 
amounts since this herb is quite potent and does have side effects when 
high amounts are ingested. High dosages and potencies are not always better 
since side effects can take away from the benefits of the sexual enhancement. I 
have formulated a regular tongkat ali powder at 200 mg 
and a high concentration extract called LJ100 at 25 mg. Some people prefer taking 
just tongkat ali powder, whereas others prefer taking LJ100 or other extracts. It is not 
possible to predict which product a person will best respond to without first trying it. 
Passion Rx has a combination of regular tongkat ali powder and LJ100, along with 
a number of other herbs. See http://www.raysahelian.com/tongkat_ali.html 

 Q. Does eating chocolate influence blood 
pressure?
  A. Most studies indicate that eating dark chocolate lowers blood pressure. The 
high sugar content in chocolate reduces the benefits while low sugar, or sugar-free, 
preparations have an even better effect on lowering blood pressure. See http://www.raysahelian.com/cacao.html 

 Q. I am 59 years of age (male) and have to say that 
Dr. Sahelian was right on the dosage of DHEA and the cautions. Before I read his website I started out taking 50mg a 
day which made me feel anxious and moody along with heart palpitations. I 
kept backing down on the daily dosage until I reached one that made me 
feel more normal at 10mg per day. I take DHEA because it actually gives 
me a mental and physical feeling of well being. I have experimented over 
the years with this substance until I had reached an optimal dosage for 
myself. I guess we are all different to a certain degree as to what we can 
tolerate.
  A. Even 10 mg may be too high for many people and could cause side 
effects in the long run. I often suggest people take breaks from the use 
of hormones. 

 Q. Is it true that eating certain spices in the 
evening can disrupt sleep?
  A. Yes. Certain spices elevate body temperature and cause 
alertness. The body likes to be cool at night for optimal sleep. 
Therefore, eat most of your spicy foods at breakfast or lunch so that the 
body temperature elevation is reduced by bedtime. 

 Q. I have a question about Passion Rx. I 
have read the ingredients in this product and I have seen the same 
ingredients in other formulas or just slightly different than Passion Rx. 
Now what makes this product work so well, and other products that I have 
tried, not work so well. The ingredients you have in this product have 
been around for a long time. If the ingredients are that potent wouldnt 
customers try more of this product than Viagra? I am just trying to figure 
out what&apos;s so special about this Passion Rx product.
  A. There are many factors that influence the effectiveness of a 
sexual enhancing product. The actual ingredients, whether the ingredients are just the 
powders or concentrated extracts, the amounts of the ingredients, the 
quality of the raw material, the interactions of the various herbs within the 
formula, etc. Also, the product may not work well if 
the dosages are too low, or too high. Viagra works rather quickly and many 
people want a quick effect and prefer a drug. However, Viagra only works for 
erection enhancement, not for sensation or libido. Passion Rx works in a 
more comprehensive manner and supports many aspects of the sexual 
response, including sensation, libido, stamina, and erectile function, but it does not work 
quickly in an hour like Viagra. Normally it takes a 
few days for the full benefits to be noticed although a few people notice 
the effects the same day or the second day. Some men only want a stronger erection, and they only want to take a product 
shortly before sexual activity. For these individuals, Viagra or its cousins Cialis 
and Levitra are good options. For those who wish to have a more 
comprehensive sexual enhancement, and can wait a few days for the full 
benefits, the herbal formulas are great options. Also, the herbs have 
fewer and less serious side effects than the prescription medications. If 
you are sensitive to herbs, or over the age of 50, use half a capsule or 
3/4 of a capsule. Passion Rx is taken on an empty stomach in the morning, 
at least a half hour before breakfast. 

 
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE
 Vol. 5, Issue 9 -- July 10, 2008
===================================
I have been nearsighted since I was a child. I am not sure if it was 
purely genetic or because of excessive reading, or both. I was an avid 
reader as a child, sometimes going through several books a week, even 
reading in dim light late into the night and under the bed covers with a 
small flashlight so my parents would not see me break curfew. At age 10 I 
was fitted with eyeglasses but could not stand wearing them especially 
while involved in sports activities. In my early twenties I started 
wearing contact lenses which were a big help but still made my eyes 
uncomfortable. In my mid thirties I had radial keratotomy surgery and this 
helped to bring my vision to about 20/30, but over the following years 
this weakened to 20/40 or even 20/50 if my eyes were tired or if I was 
stressed. I was hoping my eyes would correct to 20/20 after the surgery 
but the final result was not as good as I had hoped for, but better than 
my original 20/100. For the last decade or more I have been trying to find 
natural ways to improve my vision. I tried several eye exercise programs 
but none seemed to help to any extent. A few years ago, while writing my 
book Mind Boosters , I was experimenting with dozens of nutrients 
and herbs to see if they had any mind enhancing effects. Surprisingly I 
found some that improved my vision. This gave me the idea to formulate a 
product for vision enhancement. After years of experimenting with various 
herbal extracts and nutrients, alone and in combination, I developed 
Eyesight Rx, a formula with a couple of dozen ingredients. People who take 
Eyesight Rx notice improved day and night vision, colors being richer, and 
improved close and distance vision. Objects are in more focus and reading 
becomes easier. Each time we create a new batch I tweak the formula to 
improve the benefits. This latest version is my favorite and we have had 
great feedback. Below I discuss a new study regarding the role of lutein 
and DHA in eye health.

===================================
 1. Lutein and DHA are both needed for optimal vision 
Lutein is a carotenoid found in some vegetables and fruits that, after 
ingestion, finds itself to the retina of the eye. DHA is a type of omega-3 
fatty acid also found in the retina. Researchers at Jean Mayer US 
Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at 
Tufts University, Boston, Massachusetts did a study 
 
to determine the influence of lutein and DHA supplements on macular 
pigment optical density. Forty-nine women (aged 60-80 years) were randomly assigned to placebo, DHA, 
lutein, or lutein plus DHA supplement. Lutein 
supplementation increased macular pigment density eccentrically (beyond 
the center of the retina). DHA resulted in central 
increases.
  Comments: It appears that both lutein and DHA are needed for 
optimal vision since they influence different parts of the retina. 
Eyesight Rx has an appropriate amount of lutein along with two dozen 
additional nutrients and herbs that work synergistically to improve 
vision. If you wish to improve your eyesight, I suggest you take fish oils 
in addition to Eyesight Rx. Fish oils have the fatty acids EPA and DHA. 
DHA alone is also available as a vegetarian source from algae.
  If you eat at Japanese restaurants, you may consider ordering Ikura 
or salmon eggs. Or, you can buy salmon eggs or roe at your grocery store. 
I find fish eggs help with vision but they are quite expensive. My ideal 
program for vision enhancement is half a tablet of Eyesight Rx two or 
three mornings in a row with a day off along with two to three fish oil 
softgels before or with breakfast. One benefit of Eyesight Rx is that it 
comes in a tablet form that you can melt under the tongue for direct 
absorption into the bloodstream. 

 ===================================
 2. Vitamin D - Can You Take Too Much?
 Dr. Martha E. Payne of Duke University, Durham, 
North Carolina, thinks high intakes of vitamin D and calcium may lead to 
vascular calcification in the brain since calcium is taken up into the blood vessel 
walls. She and her colleagues evaluated calcium and vitamin D intakes by food 
frequency questionnaires and performed MRI scans in more than 200 elderly men and women 
(average age, 71 years). All of the participants had some brain lesions 
of varying sizes but those reporting the highest intakes of calcium and 
vitamin D were more likely to have higher total volume of brain lesions. 
There is a concern that excessively high intakes of calcium, either 
through food or supplements, may end up in the brain along blood vessel 
walls, in addition to that of bone. This has the potential to result in 
cognitive decline. For an excellent article on this topic, see
http://bacteriality.com/2007/10/24/brain_lesions/
   My comments: Recently a medical 
doctor emailed us criticizing my cautious approach on calcium and vitamin 
D use. He said he places his patients with osteoporosis on 1500 mg of 
calcium and 2000 units of vitamin D. I think one has to balance the 
benefits and risks of supplements. Too high dosages can have effects on 
parts of the body that are not easily evaluated. For instance, even though 
high dosages of calcium and vitamin D may help bones become stronger and 
reduce the risk for fractures, they could also potentially raise the risk 
of brain calcifications leading to mental decline. I, personally, don&apos;t 
recommend more than 800 mg of calcium a day and more than 400 units of 
vitamin D a day in the form of supplements. Some supplement companies sell 
vitamin D products that are 1000 units or even 2000 units. Most people do 
not require these high dosages and it is quite possible they could be 
harmful in the long run. See http://www.raysahelian.com/vitamind.html 

 ===================================
 3. Does watermelon have effects similar to Viagra? 
The media has made a big story of watermelon having Viagra-like effects 
since watermelons contain a substance called citrulline which converts 
into the amino acid arginine. Arginine helps dilate blood vessels. Because 
of this biochemical connection, Bhimu Patil, a researcher and director of 
Texas A&amp;M&apos;s Fruit and Vegetable Improvement Center was quoted saying,&quot;Arginine 
boosts nitric oxide, which relaxes blood vessels, the same basic effect 
that Viagra has, to treat erectile dysfunction and maybe even prevent it.&quot;Well, this is all the media needed to hype this story. But, does eating 
watermelon flesh or rind have any sexual enhancing effects?
  Comments: I love watermelon, it is one of my favorite fruits. I 
actually love the combination of watermelon and feta cheese. I have been 
known to eat half a large watermelon at one sitting. I have not noticed 
any Viagra-like effects from eating watermelon or drinking watermelon 
juice. I have also tried citrulline supplements and arginine supplements 
and have not noticed a significant effect on erectile function. Even if 
citrulline and arginine dilate blood vessels, their effects are brief. If 
you really want to enhance libido, sensation and sexual stamina, Passion 
Rx with Yohimbe is one of your best options or consider a number of sexual 
herbs that are quite potent. See http://www.raysahelian.com/watermelon.html or, for citrulline 
information, see http://www.raysahelian.com/citrulline.html . To learn about herbs that 
increase sexual urge, see http://www.raysahelian.com/libido.html . 

 ===================================
 Email questions

 Foot pad scam? 
Q. D o you have an 
opinion about Kinoki foot pads? Do detox foot pads work or are they a fraud?
  A. I have not studied foot pads in great detail, but my current 
opinion 
is that Kinoki foot pads or other pads promoted for&quot;detox&quot;purposes are not effective. 
I tend to consider these products in the&quot;scam&quot;category. 
Medically, I can&apos;t see how putting on a foot pad before bed will&quot;draw 
toxins&quot;from the body. I have not seen any studies that support the claim 
that wearing these foot pads overnight leads to improved health. If anyone 
knows about such studies, I would be glad to review them. 

 Toe nail fungus cure 
Q. Thanks for your informative newsletter! About eight months ago I began 
soaking my toes in a solution of Epson Salt and water for my toe fungus. I 
had read about a toe nail fungus cure in your email newsletter and had put 
up with the toenail fungus for about 15 years, keeping it under some 
control with Tea Tree Oil applications. However, it never went away and 
had recently gotten much worse and painful. I thought when I read your 
suggestion,&quot;Why not?&quot;with a nothing to lose attitude. I am writing to 
tell you that IT WORKED! I tried to be consistent in the beginning, did 
not measure the Epson Salt, but put a few tablespoons in a half-full 
shallow basin 
of warm water and soaked for approximately ten to twenty minutes daily. As the 
toenails grew out they looked well and healthy! I now do this about once a 
week, just to be safe, but feel I can now tell you that IT WORKED and 
thank you. I am very grateful. PS. I am a 69 yr. old diabetic (type 2) 
woman who is in otherwise excellent health, exercise several times a day 
and am very active.
  A. I get a thrill when the readers of my newsletters are able to 
treat or cure their medical condition in a natural manner, particularly if 
modern medicine does not have a good solution. See http://www.raysahelian.com/nailfungus.html for details on how to get 
rid of toe nail fungus and athlete&apos;s foot. 

 Passion Rx fan - 
effective for sexual enhancement 
Q. I just thought I would share my experiences 
with Passion Rx. Over two months ago, I chanced upon this sexual enhancing 
product. I was impressed by its list of ingredients, including maca, 
tribulus, muira puama and yohimbe, and many others. Until this time, I have been 
dependent on Cialis - there was no way I could perform without it. 
Sometimes, even with Cialis, I had to have the greatest concentration 
else, I will lose it. I have been on testosterone patches and got no 
relief. So, I decided to take the plunge and ordered one Passion Rx with 
Yohimbe. Around the 3rd week, I noticed that i started having spontaneous 
hard-ons. One night, during that week, my wife took me by surprise in the 
morning (I left the new pack of Cialis I just bought in my office and 
couldn&apos;t run downstairs before the action, so I decided to go ahead. I was 
surprised -- we did it. In the past, this would not have been possible, i 
would have lost my erection half-way.. But now I realized that I had so 
much libido -- the desire was strong. I decided to take the capsules for 
one more week. By the 4th week, I could have sex with my woman without 
taking the Cialis. In fact, I have used only 8 out of the 100 Cialis tabs 
that had arrived about 3 months ago. Interestingly, I noticed differences 
in how I feel even with a condom. Previously, I could not sustain an 
erection with a condom on, even when I take the Cialis. But now, without 
the Cialis and on this supplement alone, I can use a condom and still 
complete the act without losing it. I am so happy with your product that I 
reordered a second bottle and taking it now. I don&apos;t know when I would 
have to stop -- but realized that I can skip a couple of days and still 
have a long term effect. Thanks for a great product.
  Comments: We love getting these types of testimonials. For long 
term use, Passion Rx is only needed 2 or 3 days a week. It is a good idea 
to take a full week off after each month of use. Most people notice a 
benefit within days rather than weeks. 

 

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 8 -- June 20th, 2008
===================================
 With food prices going higher, particularly for 
produce, some Americans are cutting back on fresh fruits and vegetables. I 
am concerned that more people on low incomes may turn to buying high-calorie 
packaged foods and visiting fast food restaurants where a meal consisting of a burger, fries 
and soda is still under 6 dollars. But the health risks of consuming these 
foods are significant. Some people think that the effects on the liver, 
heart, and other tissues from regular consumption of these fast foods 
takes years or decades to develop. Actually, the harm may occur within weeks. 
See below. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at Physician Formulas -- For the 
next few days all the items are on 
sale for an additional 10 percent off on top of the existing discounts, 
including the bestselling formulas Passion Rx, Diet Rx, Mind Power Rx, 
Joint Power Rx, Prostate Power Rx, MultiVit Rx, Eyesight Rx, and Veg Rx. 
As a newsletter subscriber you are eligible to get this discount. After 
you add the products to your cart, type the word summer in the discount 
code provided and then click update below it. If you have questions, call 
the customer care representatives at the number listed on the 
www.physicianformulas.com website. 

 ===================================
 1. Fast food damages the liver
 Eating fast foods for one month has a harmful effect on the liver 
indicated by an elevation of certain liver enzymes. Researchers in Sweden 
followed 12 men and six women in their twenties for one month. All 
volunteers were slim and in good health and ate two meals per day at 
McDonalds, Burger King or other fast-food restaurants. The goal of the study was to increase body weight by 10 to 15 percent. 
Levels of a liver enzyme called ALT increased after only one week, and quadrupled on average 
over the entire period. When your doctor does a routine blood study, 
certain liver enzymes are evaluated, including ALT which stands for alanine aminotransferase. In the majority of the volunteers, ALT rose to 
levels that would normally reflect liver damage. Two of the individuals 
had liver steatosis. Steatosis (also called fatty degeneration) is the 
process of abnormal accumulation of fats within a cell. It 
reflects an impairment of the normal processes of synthesis and 
elimination of triglyceride fat. This study clearly showed that high ALT levels can 
occur 
due to unhealthy food intake alone.
  Comments: To be honest, I stop at a fast food restaurant a few 
times a year when I am taking a long road trip and there are few options 
on the road except for a highway exit that leads to a fast food restaurant. I order a burger with diet 
soda but I eat very little of the bun. I am not a purist in the sense 
that 100 percent of my food consumption has to be perfectly fresh and healthy. It&apos;s too 
stressful to be a perfectionist. I don&apos;t think there&apos;s any harm in 
eating fast foods a few times a year. My concern involves people who eat 
these types of foods several times a week and habituate their children to 
these meals.
  If you would like to see an entertaining movie regarding this 
topic, consider renting the 2004 movie Super Size Me. See also www.raysahelian.com/alt.html 

 ===================================
 2 . 
Cod liver oil reduces the risk of diabetes in children 
 Recently while perusing Medline, a source of original medical 
research publications, I came across a study from 2003 that caught my 
interest. The title said,&quot; Use of cod liver oil during the 
first year of life is associated with lower risk of childhood-onset type 1 
diabetes.
   Researchers at the Ulleval University Hospital, 
Oslo, Norway found that when infants were given cod liver oil in the first year of life, 
they later had a significantly lower risk for type 1 diabetes. Use of other vitamin D 
supplements during the first year of life and maternal use of cod liver 
oil or other vitamin D supplements during pregnancy were not associated 
with reduced type 1 diabetes. Therefore, it does not appear the vitamin D in cod 
liver oil is making the difference, but more likely the fish oils or some 
other factor. The 
researchers conclude: Cod liver oil may reduce the risk of 
type 1 diabetes, perhaps through the anti-inflammatory effects of 
long-chain n-3 fatty acids. See www.raysahelian.com/codliveroil.html 

 ===================================
 3. Practical advice regarding taking brain boosting supplements 
We recently received an email from a reporter from a national health 
magazine. I would like to share with you my responses to the questions.

 I am writing a short article about memory 
supplements. I see you have written a book on the topic called Mind 
Boosters and have a strong background in supplements, so I was hoping you 
would have some time to answer a few questions.
  
Q. There are so many memory supplements on the market now. How 
would a man or woman start to sift through the options and find one that may 
benefit? Are there certain things you can suggest to look out for?
  A. It is not possible to predict which nutrient, herb, or combination formula, will be effective until one 
takes the supplement for a few days or a couple of weeks. There are quite 
a number of supplements that are worth trying including acetyl l-carnitine, 
ginkgo biloba, DMAE, trimethylglycine, vinpocetine, fish oils, choline, cdp-choline, and bacopa monnieri. A popular combination formula is Mind Power Rx which has 
a small amount of more than a dozen brain nutrients and herbs. 
One option is to buy three of four of these supplements. Then, each 
morning, 
for a period of one week, take one capsule of a particular supplement. Next, 
take 3 or 4 days off and resume your experiment with a different supplement for a week. 
After you have experimented with each supplement you have purchased, you 
will have a better idea which one, or which ones, work for you. I am not 
aware of any other way to determine which product will be effective for 
any one person without actually trying it. Note: Some of these supplements 
are potent, so if you are over the age of 50, or are taking hormones, 
medications, or other supplements, discuss with your health care provider 
who may suggest you begin with half a capsule or a tablet rather than the full 
dose.
  
Q. I know some herbs, like ginkgo biloba, have a lot of research 
behind them in terms of being beneficial for improving blood flow to the 
brain and improving cognition in older subjects, but do you think it can 
be beneficial for a healthy man or woman in their 30s or 40s to take on an 
ongoing basis to prevent cognitive decline?
  A. In my opinion, mind and memory supplements, 
such as ginkgo biloba and others, are best reserved for occasional use in 
those who are in their 30s and 40s. These supplements can be taken on days 
when one wishes to be more alert, focus better, and have more mental 
stamina. But I do not recommend non-stop daily use of these brain boosters 
for years or decades since we don&apos;t know the long term consequences. For 
more information, see www.raysahelian.com/memory.html 

 ===================================
 Email questions
 Q. I have been using psyllium fiber and/or ground flaxseeds on a 
daily basis to keep regular. The info on psyllium fiber containers state that it 
may interfere with absorption of 
vitamin supplements and not to take such products at the same time. In 
researching, I have found information that tells me all fibers (including 
ground flaxseeds) interfere with vitamin absorption. I know you have 
addressed this issue about psyllium fiber before and wonder if you still 
have the same thinking that in taking psyllium at approximately the same 
time as vitamin supplements is not a major issue.
  A. Most vitamin supplements, including multivitamins, contain more than necessary dosages 
needed by the body, therefore, even if less is absorbed due to psyllium 
fiber use (and the decrease in absorption in many cases may not be 
too significant), the body is still likely to absorb sufficient amounts. For 
practical purposes, one can sometimes take the psyllium fiber the same 
time as the vitamin supplements, and others times at a different time of 
the day. 

 Q. I started taking a 
SAM-e product that had 400 mg. The first two 
days I had very bad headaches then for 2 days I had stomach cramps. This is 
day 5 and I&apos;m vomiting. i just thought my body needed to get used to it. Can a 
person have such severe multiple reactions to a product with natural 
ingredients.
  A. Yes, natural products do have side effects, not as severe as 
drugs but nevertheless they can be quite unpleasant. SAM-e does have dangers when taken in high dosages. In 
my opinion, for long term use, SAM-e 
supplements work better at a dosage of 50 to 100 mg a day, with a day or 
two off a week. 


 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 7 -- June, 2008
===================================
 I just returned from a visit to Brazil, a beautiful 
country with people who are warm and friendly. One of the things I enjoyed 
most about my stay in Rio de Janeiro were the juice bars. Many of them 
don&apos;t even have a store front. You just walk in off the street and there 
are bar stools where you sit and take a look at the signs on the wall of 
all the juices they offer with enticing pictures of the fruits. At least 
one of these juice bars, a block away from Copacabana beach hotel I was 
staying at, was open 24 hours a day!
  During my stay I had the pleasure of tasting the juices of acai, 
acerola, graviola, passion fruit, cupuacu, guava, mango, cacao, and 
others. Yes, even cacao juice. The cacao tree is a medium sized tree that 
grows in the tropics. 
The cacao fruit ranges from 5 to 12 inches long, is the shape of an 
elongated egg with deep ridges on its surface and has a hard shell that 
you break open by hitting on a rock or hard surface. Inside is a white, 
creamy pulp along with lots of cacao seeds the size of fava beans. The pulp is made into a 
delicious juice. I had a chance to eat the cacao seeds which are slightly 
bitter but I did enjoy them. 
After cacao is processed, it is called cocoa.
  Unfortunately, many of these juices, such as acai juice, 
have sugar added to make them more palatable. A large glass of acai juice 
with sugar added can have several hundred calories. One time I ordered acai juice 
(it has a beautiful purple color) without added sugar and mixed the contents 
with calorie-free stevia packets I had brought with me. The stevia helped 
sweeten it to a pleasant taste.
  Many of these tropical fruits and their extracts are starting to 
make their way to the US market and over the next few years you will see a 
greater number of these fruits in stores or as herbal extracts. Already 
some of these are already available in extract form in capsules including acai, 
graviola, cacao, etc. The advantage of the capsules is that they 
have hardly any calories. If you do drink the juices, consider sweetening 
them with stevia rather than sugar. Some juices, such as mango, do not 
need to be sweetened. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted: 
Joint Power Rx with glucosamine, chondroitin, msm, cmo, and other 
nutrients is formulated to support healthy joints. Good Night Rx with kava, valerian, melatonin, 5-HTP, and 
several other relaxation and sleep inducing herbs and nutrients is ideal 
for occasional sleepless nights.
Acerola Powder is derived from acerola cherries, one of nature&apos;s highest 
sources of vitamin C. R Alpha Lipoic Acid is a powerful antioxidant used 
by those with blood sugar problems.
Ashwagandha is an herb used in Ayurveda for relaxation and stress reduction. Most people find half a capsule works to their 
satisfaction.
Krill oil is similar to fish oil but has additional vitamin A and astaxanthin, a potent carotenoid antioxidant.
DHA is an omega-3 fatty acid derived from kelp and suitable for 
vegetarians who do not wish to take fish oil capsules.
Maitake mushroom extract has beta-glucan fraction which can influence the 
immune system. Rose Hips are round red 
fruits found on natural roses. Rose hips are a great source of Vitamin C 
and bioflavonoids. 

 ===================================
 1. 
Astaxanthin, as antioxidant, protects fatty acids from oxidation 
 Researchers at the University of Kuopio in Finland gave young 
Finnish men astaxanthin capsules daily for 3 months. Absorption 
of the astaxanthin from supplements was good and the supplement was found 
to be effective in decreasing oxidation of fatty acids in the blood. 
Astaxanthin is a carotenoid that is found in marine mammals, and is found 
in high concentrations in krill oil.
  Comments: Astaxanthin is becoming more popular as a potent 
antioxidant. Most supplements provide astaxanthin in a 2 mg dosage. 
Another option is krill oil which supplies 2.7 mg in 2 softgels. For more information, see http://www.raysahelian.com/astaxanthin.html and the krill oil page is http://www.raysahelian.com/krilloil.html 

 ===================================
 2. Bitter melon and blood sugar 
Dcotors at the Chinese Academy of 
Sciences in Shanghai have found several compounds from 
bitter melon known as cucurbitane triterpenoids. They tested the effects 
of these compounds on glucose (sugar) and fat metabolism in cells and in mice. When tested in 
muscle and fat cells, the compounds stimulated a glucose receptor to move 
from the cell interior to the cell surface, thus promoting more effective 
glucose metabolism. Several of the tested compounds had effects comparable 
to those of insulin. Tests in mice of two of the compounds found that they 
promoted both glucose tolerance and fat burning, and one was particularly 
effective in promoting glucose tolerance in animals consuming high fat 
diets. 
   My thoughts: B itter 
melon is a plant eaten and used 
medicinally in parts of Asia for the 
treatment of diabetes . Bitter melon 
supplements are starting to become more popular. See http://www.raysahelian.com/bittermelon.html 

 ===================================
 3. Drugs that increase the risk 
for bone fracture 
 Two drugs prescribed by doctors to lower blood sugar and treat 
diabetes -- pioglitazone and rosiglitazone -- increase the risk of bone 
fractures. Patients who use these drugs for a 
year or longer are more than twice as likely as nonusers to 
fracture a bone. Pioglitazone and rosiglitazone, also known by the trade names 
Actos and Avandia, respectively, belong to a drug class called 
thiazolidinediones. The use of these drugs is linked to bone fractures of 
the hip and wrist, and the elevated risk is seen in both men and women, 
independent of age.
  My comments: I am nervous about using new drugs in my practice 
since we often find out the full range of the dangers or side effects of 
these medications after they are introduced to the public and hundreds of 
thousands of people start taking them. For someone who has type 2 
diabetes, all attempts should be made to use diet, exercise, herbs and 
natural supplements before 
resorting to drugs. I much prefer using the older diabetes drugs such as metformin, rather than the new ones such as Avandia, that have not been 
proven to be safe. For more information, see http://www.raysahelian.com/thiazolidinediones.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/avandia.html 

 ============================ 
 Emails
CpQ10 dosage
 Q. Dr. Sahelian, you seem to be concerned about using high dosages of CoQ10 
as mentioned in your website. I see a lot of 
people with cancer and a Danish Doctor who has been doing a lot of 
research with Coq10 and cancer found that they needed 400mg daily to get 
any real benefit from the supplement. I have had people on CoQ10 for at least 2 years 
on that dosage and ahve not seen a serious side effect. All my adult cancer 
patients 
take this CoQ10 dosage.
  A. When people take CoQ10 in high dosages as a daily supplement for many 
years or decades, we have no idea how this will interfere with their 
metabolism. It is unnatural to expose the body to such high dosages. What 
if we learn 20 years from now that people taking more than 200 mg a day of 
CoQ10 actually live a few years shorter or somehow their mitochondria are 
not functioning as well? As with hormone replacement therapy, it took 
decades for the scientific community to find out that it caused more 
problems than in solved. Initially hormone replacement therapy appeared to 
provide many health benefits to women. CoQ10 appears to be a healthy supplement, but who 
knows for certain that taking more than 100 mg is healthier than taking 
less? If there is no such proof, then one should be cautious and 
take less, not more. Many people who take CoQ10 also take other 
supplements or medicines and we have no idea of all the interactions that could 
occur. Plus, what if someone who is used to taking 400 mg a day goes 
on a trip and forgets their bottle and in the foreign country they can&apos;t 
find CoQ10? If, after years of taking 400 mg their body is used to it, 
what happens if they stop? What if when they are older and they are on a 
limited budget they can&apos;t afford buying CoQ10 anymore? There are many 
answers about high dose CoQ10 use that we don&apos;t know yet. We also have 
reports from quite a few people who actually feel fatigued when they take 
more than 100 mg of CoQ10. Perhaps high doses of CoQ10 for cancer or other 
conditions is appropriate, but, for the general public taking CoQ10 as a supplement 
for health promotion, there is no proof that taking high dosages is 
beneficial. We also have to consider the cost, CoQ10 is expensive. For the time 
being I suggest 30 or 50 mg most days of the week for those who wish to 
take this supplement.
  See http://www.raysahelian.com/coq10.html 

 Milk or cream with tea and coffee 
Q. I have read and seen it 
written a number of times on various websites that milk can almost 
completely inhibit the uptake of the various antioxidants in cocoa and 
also tea. Apparently the milk proteins combine with the antioxidants to 
prevent their absorption. Im sure the majority of people tend to drink 
cocoa made with the addition of milk, and certainly here in the UK tea is also 
drunk mainly with milk. I wonder about your opinion on this and whether it 
might be important to stress that milk should be avoided in order to 
enhance absorption.
  A. Yes, there was one recent study that indicated consuming tea with 
milk reduced the benefits from some of the antioxidants in the tea. 
 
It may be a good idea to drink herbal teas without milk until 
further research confirms or negates the early reports. Or, another 
approach is to just enjoy the tea with the 
milk and get antioxidants at a different time of day from different 
supplements, foods and drinks rather than relying 
on tea. If you really enjoy tea and coffee with cream or milk, don&apos;t deny 
yourself the pleasure. 

 Regulation of supplements 
Q. Given that you personally feel that high 
dosages of tyrosine or DHEA and certain other supplements cause adverse 
affects, is there any regulation or FDA recommended dosage? I have had 
enormous problems with tyrosine in the past that are too dramatic to even 
begin to tell you. Where, if anywhere are the dangers of supplements 
mentioned or how are they regulated?
  A. You ask a good question that deserves a somewhat philosophical 
answer. There are no official supplement dosage guidelines 
(except for certain well-known vitamins and minerals) 
since many such guidelines would be somewhat arbitrary and open to 
significant differences of opinion among various scientists. And how 
do we know that government officials are any more knowledgeable (or 
honest) than certain doctors and nutritionists who have first hand 
knowledge of these supplements in their clinical practice? There are 
thousands of herbs and individual supplements, and tens of thousands of combination formulas. How can any independent or 
governmental organization ever keep up knowing the appropriate 
dosages of these supplements, herbs, and combination formulas?
  If strict governmental guidelines are placed on supplements dosages 
(whether it be tyrosine, alpha lipoic acid, curcumin, mangosteen, noni, coq10, 
melatonin, 
and others), why not then follow the same logic and limit hard liquor 
bottle sizes 
to only six ounces and forbid the sale of more than one bottle at a time 
since there are serious risks 
in drinking excess alcohol? What about limiting sales of sugar-laden sodas that 
cause obesity and diabetes? Drinking more than one soda a 
day is associated with an increased incidence of metabolic syndrome. We 
live in a society that should accept the fact that there are risks to some of the 
products and foods we consume. If we were to tightly regulate every little 
detail of a citizen&apos;s life and what or how much they can ingest of a food, 
drink, or supplement, we would no longer have the freedoms we currently 
enjoy. Each citizen is responsible for their own health and to learn as 
much about a food, drink, or supplement before they ingest it. 

 

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 6 -- May 20, 2008
===================================
 Does taking a multivitamin/mineral supplement help 
you live longer, shorter, or make no difference at all? Over the years 
there have been conflicting reports regarding the benefits of taking a 
multivitamin supplement. Some studies indicate heart and immune system 
benefits, and perhaps reduction in cancer, while other studies report the 
opposite -- taking a multivitamin supplement reduces longevity. Which is 
right? I discuss this in more detail below. 

   Over the years I have formulated 
products for a number of different companies. One of the reasons I really 
like working with Physician Formulas is that I have the freedom to modify and 
improve the formulas as I wish. Other companies that I previously 
formulated products for did not allow me this option. It takes time and 
costs money to change labels, flyers, etc. I am glad to report that I now 
have reformulated Eyesight Rx, adding several new ingredients such as 
resveratrol, acetylcysteine, carnosine, taurine, and others. I really, 
really like this newest version. The benefits are noticed quicker and the 
side effects are minimal. Users notice improved day and night vision, 
better color perception, and improved distance and close vision. Seeing 
clearer gives us pleasure. Later on I discuss how to best use this 
product. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted: Eyesight Rx 
provides many antioxidants and can be used for long term vision support, 
it can also be used for a quick improvement in vision within a few days. 
Many people notice colors becoming brighter. Objects become sharper and in 
better focus. Paintings, artwork, or nature become more enjoyable to look 
at. 5-HTP is a nutrient that converts into serotonin. This batch is an 
extremely high quality 5-HTP product independently tested by HPLC for 
purity.
Banaba has been used in the Philippines for blood sugar control. CoQ10 30 
mg is an antioxidant used for energy and cardiovascular health. CoQ10 at 
30 mg is a good dose for those who wish to take this popular nutrient on a 
regular basis without overdosing.
Avena sativa is an herb used for sexual enhancement. It is also found in 
Passion Rx, a product that continues to grow in popularity.
Arginine is a precursor to nitric oxide, a neurotransmitter that acts as a 
vasodilator.
Royal Jelly is a beehive product that many people find provides a sense of 
energy and vitality.

 ===================================
 1. Multivitamin supplements - multiple points of 
view 
Although it is tempting to cite statistics regarding the hundreds of 
studies done over the years to determine whether taking a multivitamin is 
beneficial or harmful, I will spare you all the boring numbers and 
details. I prefer to look at things from a larger perspective. Although 
the following statement may be controversial, I will come out and say it.&quot;The majority of the studies that have been done to date regarding the 
influence of multivitamins on health and disease are worthless.&quot;Why? 
Because many of the epidemiological studies evaluating millions of 
multivitamin users did not bother to differentiate the fact that there are 
thousands of different multivitamin products and each has a different 
composition and dosage of vitamins and minerals. It&apos;s like grouping all 
wine drinkers together whether they drink white wine, rose, red wine, or 
whether they drink an ounce a day or a bottle a day.
  Most of the studies do not differentiate the type of vitamin E 
present in the supplement products. Vitamin E comes in a synthetic version 
and in a natural version, i.e, dl-alpha tocopherol or d-alpha tocopherol. 
Just this difference alone could have an effect on health. Plus, there are 
many other forms of tocopherols, including alpha, delta, gamma, etc. The 
majority of multivitamin products only have the synthetic dl-alpha 
tocopherol version of vitamin E. It is possible that taking a high dose of 
a synthetic form of vitamin E could be harmful whereas taking a vitamin E 
complex that includes the full range of tocopherols could be beneficial. 
One additional point to keep in mind is dosage. It is possible that low 
amounts of vitamin E complex could have a beneficial effect on longevity 
whereas very high dosages could have the reverse effect.
  Multivitamin and mineral supplements also contain vitamins A, B, C, 
D, minerals such as calcium, magnesium, chromium, selenium, etc. Over the 
past few years more multivitamin products now include a number of other 
nutrients and herbal extracts such as CoQ10, choline, bioflavonoids, green 
tea, etc. Therefore, a researcher who does a study lumping together all 
types of multivitamin products even though each product is different does 
not really understand supplements that well.
  One additional point I would like to make is the role of selenium. 
In the April 2008 issue of the newsletter I briefly mentioned that some 
early reports indicate that having a too low intake of selenium or taking 
too high a dosage of selenium could reduce longevity whereas having a 
normal intake was optimal. Here is another reason why these multivitamin 
studies could be flawed. Perhaps some of the multivitamin products people 
were taking had too much selenium.
  Bottom line: I personally take MultiVit Rx on days when I wish to 
have more energy. I take MultiVit Rx 2 or 3 days a week since it provides 
me with a sense of vitality and wellbeing. I feel more motivated and can 
get more work done. I have no idea how it influences longevity but I don&apos;t 
take it for that purpose. I don&apos;t think we are going to find out about the 
risks and benefits of multivitamins until several different formulas, 
developed by experienced nutritional experts, are tested for at least 10 
to 20 years on a large group of people. 

 ===================================
 2 . 
Ketogenic diet reduces the risk for seizures in children 
 A ketogenic diet is a high-fat, low-carbohydrate diet 
that induces excess production of ketone bodies, which are incompletely burned 
fat molecules. Since the 1920s this diet 
has been proposed as a way to reduce seizures and most recent studies have 
found it to be beneficial. In this latest one, Dr. Elizabeth G. Neal, from 
University College London, randomly assigned a group of children who were 
having at least seven seizures per week despite anti-seizure 
medication treatment to a standard diet or a ketogenic one. After three 
months children on the ketogenic diet had a third fewer seizures, while 
seizure frequency increased in children on the standard diet.
     My thoughts and hypothesis: I am aware that fish 
oils help reduce the risk of cardiac arrhythmias by helping stabilize 
neuronal excitability in heart tissue. I wonder if fish oils or eating 
fish could have the same benefits in brain tissue, helping reduce neuronal 
excitability and thus reducing the occurrence of seizures. I would be 
interested in getting feedback from neurologists or other experts would 
have studied this topic. For more information on the ketogenic diet, see http://www.raysahelian.com/ketogenicdiet.html 

 ===================================
 3. How to take Eyesight Rx 
If you are middle aged or older you probably have noticed some 
degree of visual decline. Fine print is more difficult to read, colors are 
not as bright, and distant objects are not in focus as much. Some of you 
may have already started wearing glasses. Eyesight Rx is ideally suited to 
help those with age-related visual decline although it could easily offer 
a benefit to those who have been wearing glasses for a long time.
  I have been experimenting with the Eyesight Rx formula for several 
years, adding different herbs and nutrients, changing the dosages, etc. 
The latest version now available is the one I am extremely satisfied with. 
It comes as a tablet that melts under the tongue and it is taken first 
thing in the morning. Some people may notice the benefits the first day, 
for others it may take several days. The vast majority will notice visual 
enhancement by the end of the first week. Once you notice a visual 
enhancement, take less the next day. Once the nutrients replace the 
shortages in your retina, your requirement will be less and you can reduce 
the dosage to half a tablet, and over time, to a third or even a quarter. 
Once or twice a week you may wish not to take it at all. If you take a 
high dosage all the time, it may not work as well or even make your 
eyesight fuzzy since too many of these nutrients would be supplied to your 
retina and cause the carotenoids or other substances in the retina to be 
out of balance. If this happens, just take a day or two off and resume 
taking the Eyesight Rx again at a lower dosage. If you are over the age of 
50, use only half a tablet initially rather than a full tablet and after 
several days lower your amount to a third or a quarter of a tablet.
  Eyesight Rx does not supply omega-3 fish oils which are crucial to 
optimal vision. You may take one to three fish oil capsules a day to 
supply the fatty acid DHA to the retina. For more information, see http://www.raysahelian.com/eyesight.html   

 ===================================
 Question from a reader
 Are eggs healthy or not healthy to eat?
 Q. I heard on TV that those who eat a lot of eggs have a 
higher rate of heart disease and die sooner since eggs have a high amount 
of cholesterol. What are your thoughts about eggs?
  A. The media has a way to sensationalize and distort nutritional 
research. Eggs are a healthy addition to the diet if consumed in 
reasonable amounts. I don&apos;t see any harm when egg consumption is limited to half a dozen a week. 
Eggs are a great protein source and also provide phospholipids. Buy eggs 
by chickens that are raised in a cage free environment.
  

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 5 -- April 20, 2008
===================================
 A study published 
in 2006 in the New England Journal of Medicine (supposedly the most 
prestigious medical journal in America) emphatically reported that smokers 
undergoing lung scans would have a higher risk of detection of early 
cancers. The study, performed at Weill Cornell Medical College, indicated 
that if CT scans were used to evaluate smoker&apos;s lungs rather than plain 
X-rays, a significantly higher rate of early diagnoses could occur since 
the CT scans could detect much smaller tumors which could be removed 
through surgery. Finding a cancer early by CT scans could reassure smokers 
to continue their habit since early diagnosis could potentially cure their 
condition. The cancer society does not currently recommend CT scans, and 
most insurers dont pay for them.
  To the shock of many people, it was discovered in March of 2008 
that this lung cancer study was partly funded by a tobacco company, 
raising serious suspicions about its accuracy. Furthermore, the lead 
researcher has a financial interest in lung cancer CT scan patent 
technology. http://www.time.com/time/health/article/0,8599,1725719,00.html
  As a reader of my newsletter I suspect that you pay attention to 
news about health issues in the media. The reason I mention this topic is 
for you to be aware that there is a complex underworld of motivations that 
are not apparent when you read or see on TV the final headlines of study 
results. Science is, unfortunately, not pure. Personal motivations and big 
money influence outcomes or influence interpretations of the statistics 
not only on medical topics, but on nutritional supplements. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - 
FREE Saw Palmetto product for the first 300 people who order. For the next 
few days the following items are highly discounted: Within a few months 
Diet Rx has become our second best selling product only surpassed by 
Passion Rx. Diet Rx provides effective appetite suppression. Most people 
do fine with 2 capsules a day although some people prefer one a day 
whereas others need three or four. Acetyl cysteine is a precursor in the 
body to the antioxidant glutathione, which is produced within cells, 
particularly by the liver. Horny goat weed is a popular herb from China 
touted as a sexual and energy enhancer. Horny goat weed extract is found 
in Passion Rx. Bilberry is an excellent antioxidant often used for eye 
health. Bilberry extract is found in Eyesight Rx. Maitake mushroom extract 
has beta-glucan fraction which can influence the immune system. Grapefruit 
Pectin is a natural substance derived from the pulp and peel of the 
grapefruit. It is an excellent source of water-soluble fiber that has a 
gel-forming effect when mixed with water. 

 ===================================
 Melatonin and 
morning sun exposure 
 Sun exposure or bright light along with an evening dose of 
melatonin help normalize the sleep-wake cycle in elderly adults with 
Alzheimer&apos;s disease. Dr. Glenna A. Dowling, of the University of 
California, San Francisco evaluated whether light therapy -- alone or 
along with melatonin supplements -- could restore a more natural 
sleep-wake cycle. She randomly assigned 50 nursing home patients with 
Alzheimer&apos;s disease to one of three groups for a period of ten weeks. 
Patients in the first group were given light therapy for one hour 
consisting of either natural light alone, or additional artificial light 
when needed. Patients in the second group received both morning light 
therapy as well as a 5mg melatonin supplement a few hours before bedtime. 
Those in the third group were exposed to only normal indoor light and were 
not given melatonin. The combination of light therapy and melatonin 
reduced daytime sleepiness and increased patients&apos; activity during the 
day.
  Comments: The ideal long term melatonin dosage for patients with 
Alzheimer&apos;s disease is not clear but my thought is that 1 mg or 2 mg every 
other night is a good option. http://www.raysahelian.com/melatonin.html 

 ===================================
 How 
much water to drink every day
 I recently had a question from a reader regarding the ideal daily 
water intake.
Q. I read reports that many scientists don&apos;t think 8 glasses of water are 
needed daily but health articles are constantly promoting the idea of 
drinking lots of water. I trust your opinion and wanted your thoughts on 
this topic. My wife is always carrying around a water bottle and goes 
through several a day.
  A. There are claims that people should drink 8 glasses of water a 
day but there are no studies that indicate that the human body requires 
this much daily water unless a person lives in a hot and dry climate and 
does a lot of outdoor physical activity. Some people claim that drinking 
lots of water improves skin hydration, clears toxins, and helps suppress 
appetite. Some individuals drink lots of water before or during meals to 
suppress appetite, but water is quickly absorbed from the intestinal tract 
and does not stay around like fiber-rich foods to cause satiation or 
fullness. Drinking a reasonable amount of water by a healthy person, such as about 4 
to 6 glasses a 
day rather than 8, is enough to flush out toxins. As to skin, drinking 
lots of water does not necessarily increase the water content of the skin. 

 =================================== 
 Fish oil as good as 
Prozac? 
Researchers at the Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran compared the effects of eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), fluoxetine and a 
combination of the two in major depression. EPA and DHA are the fatty 
acids found in fish. Fluoxetine is the generic name for Prozac, the SSRI 
type antidepressant.
  Sixty outpatients with a diagnosis of major depressive disorder 
were randomly allocated to receive daily either 1000 mg EPA or 20 mg 
fluoxetine, or their combination for 8 weeks. (Each fish oil capsule 
generally has about 180 mg of EPA and hence to get 1000 one would need 
five or six fish oil capsules daily.) Fluoxetine and EPA appeared to be 
equally effective in controlling depressive symptoms. The EPA and 
fluoxetine combination was significantly better than fluoxetine or EPA 
alone.
  Comments: Perhaps doctors who treat their patients with SSRI drugs 
should consider adding fish oils which may help reduce the necessary 
dosage for the SSRIs. There are several other nutrients that are helpful 
for depression, see http://www.raysahelian.com/depression.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/fishoils.html . 

 ===================================
 Emails
 Q. I read somewhere that garlic helps with blood 
vessels. How does garlic work to dilate blood vessels?
  A. Human red blood cells convert garlic-derived organic 
polysulfides into hydrogen sulfide, a vascular cell signaling molecule. 
The blood vessel activity of garlic compounds is related to hydrogen 
sulfide production, and their potency to induce blood vessel relaxation 
increases with the hydrogen sulfide content of the garlic . http://www.raysahelian.com/garlic.html 

 Q. I wanted to mention a Diet Rx 
side effect I experienced after taking this product non-stop 2 capsules a 
day for three months. I started feeling fatigued. When I stopped the 
capsules, within a few days my energy came back. Now I am taking one 
capsule a day and that is perfect. I feel appetite suppression without side 
effects. I love the benefits I have experienced and so have all my 
girlfriends.
  A. It is a good idea to take a week off after each bottle is 
finished. Initially 2 capsules a day may be required, but, for long term 
use, one capsule a day is sufficient. This way Diet Rx side effects would 
be minimized yet still provide the desired benefits. http://www.raysahelian.com/diet.html 

 Q. I have been using stevia for several years now 
and love it, knowing it doesn&apos;t have the chemical issues as other sugar 
substitutes such as saccharin. However, I am concerned about a Time 
magazine article I read about&quot;artificial&quot;sweeteners, such as saccharin, 
whose long term use researchers think may have a link to overeating and 
hence,
obesity. I would appreciate your response to this article. From a 
scientific standpoint, would stevia cause the same metabolic reaction to 
the sugar effect as saccharin, potentially causing overeating and weight 
gain?
http://www.time.com/time/health/article/0,8599,1711763,00.html?cnn=yes
  A. When these types of studies are done in animals, animals are fed 
meals almost exclusively sweetened with an artificial sweetener and the 
amount of artificial sweeteners fed to them as a percentage of their food 
intake is quite high. In contrast, most humans who consume stevia do so in 
small amounts, adding stevia to tea or coffee, but continue to eat other 
foods throughout the day that have other forms of sugars. The rodent 
studies are not likely to be applicable to us humans eating a regular diet 
with a little bit of stevia used as a sweetener. http://www.raysahelian.com/stevia.html 

 Q. I&apos;m wondering about the benefits of taking 
so called&quot;stress&quot;formula B vitamins which contain 250 mg B-12, 100 mg 
thiamine, 100 mg Riboflavin, etc. Much higher than the recommended adult 
daily dose. Are there side effects to watch out for?
  A. Even though B vitamins are water soluble rather than fat 
soluble, meaning they are not stored in the body but excreted, they could 
still have an undesirable physiologic effect before they are excreted 
through the kidneys. It is possible taking too much can throw off the 
delicate body biochemistry for a while until the B vitamins are excreted. 
They could alter the enzymatic processes in cells, cause rapid heart beat, 
overstimulation and restlessness, and perhaps insomnia and fatigue. There 
is no evidence that taking very high amounts of B vitamins improves 
health. High dosages of vitamin B6 for several months can cause nerve 
damage. http://www.raysahelian.com/multivitrx.html and http://www.raysahelian.com/bvitamins.html 

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 4 -- April 2008
===================================
 I recently saw a TV program where one of the topics 
was on human 
longevity. The&quot;anti-aging&quot;doctor interviewed in the program had 
prescribed one of his patients 250 supplement pills a day and recommended 
drinking eight cups 
of green tea for the purpose of improving longevity. Just a day after I 
saw this program, I came across a study regarding the mineral 
selenium. Apparently moderate levels of selenium intake are 
associated with longevity but when selenium levels are too low, or 
too high, the odds of dying from any cause begin to go 
upward. Even though each vitamin, mineral, or supplement is different as 
to its ideal dosage, in general this study indicates that excessive intake 
of certain supplements, particularly certain minerals, has negative health 
consequences. I think drinking eight cups of green tea a day 
could well interfere with sleep. Not having a deep sleep can actually reduce 
lifespan even if there are substances in green tea that are beneficial to 
the body. The point I want to make is to be reasonable in your use of 
supplements and not to go overboard. Too much of a good thing is not so 
good. Some&quot;anti-aging&quot;doctors recommend their patients take high dosages of 
hormones such as DHEA. I wonder if these doctors really know what they are 
doing. For details on the selenium study, see http://www.raysahelian.com/selenium.html 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted: Prostate Power Rx 
contains key herbs and nutrients for prostate health including saw palmetto, pygeum, beta 
sitosterol, stinging nettle, lycopene, and others.
Veg Rx is a daily supplement for those who are vegetarian and may be 
missing certain key nutrients in their diet, such as CoQ10, carnitine, Vitamin B12, and 
others required for optimal health and energy. Tryptophan is an essential amino 
acid that converts in the body into 5-HTP and then to 
serotonin. Both the 60 count and the 120 count are on sale. Tribulus terrestris is an herb commonly appreciated for its sexual 
enhancement benefits in men and women. Tribulus extract is found in 
Passion Rx, which is becoming one of the best known natural sexual 
enhancers on the market.
Stevia clear liquid is a great supplement to add to your morning coffee or 
tea as an alternative to less beneficial substances.
Grape seed extract has beneficial compounds called procyanidolic oligomers (PCOs). 
Other sources of PCOs are berries, green and black teas, and red wine. Spirulina is a special blue-green algae that is a good source of numerous 
vitamins, minerals, carotenoids, and essential fatty acids. Click on the images 
to your left. 

 =================================== 
1. Acetylcarnitine as an 
alternative treatment for ADHD
 Acetylcarnitine, also spelled as acetyl-l carniitne, may help with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder 
(ADHD) in children with the genetic disorder known as fragile X syndrome. 
Fragile X syndrome results from an inherited genetic defect on the X 
chromosome. It is associated with mental retardation and may also 
cause autism and ADHD. Italian researchers gave acetylcarnitine supplements to boys 
between 6 and 13 years old for a period one year and compared them to a 
group who took placebo pills. Those who took acetylcarnitine had a much 
better outcome. See http://www.raysahelian.com/adhd.html 
  Comments: I have not seen any studies 
regarding the use of acetyl l carnitine in children with ADHD who do not 
have fragile X syndrome, but I think the use of an acetyl l-carnitine 
supplement is a safer option to prescription stimulants and is 
certainly worth a try. I am not sure 
what the ideal dosage of acetyl carnitine for long term treatment would be 
in children, but a dosage of 5 to 10 mg per kilo is a reasonable one to 
begin with This dosage can be adjusted higher or lower as needed. For a 30 
kg child, (66 pounds), this would be about 200 to 300 mg per day. Inform 
your child&apos;s doctor about this study and both of you can agree on an 
appropriate dosage. 

 ===================================
 2. Living in sunny states no 
guarantee that vitamin D deficiency won&apos;t occur 
 Despite residing in a constantly sunny region, a study in adults 
who live in southern Arizona found many of them are deficient in vitamin 
D, particularly blacks and Hispanics.
  Comments: It appears that even if you live in a sunny state, you 
should evaluate whether you are getting at least 20 minutes of sun 
exposure a day. Many people may spend almost all their day indoors and thus 
may not be getting enough vitamin D. See http://www.raysahelian.com/vitamind.html 

 =================================== 
3. DHA supplements and eczema 
German researchers evaluated the benefit of omega 3 fatty acids, such as DHA, in patients with atopic eczema. 
DHA and EPA are the two fatty acids that are found in high quantities in 
fish oils. Fifty-three patients with atopic eczema aged 18-40 years were 
given either DHA 5 grams daily or saturated fatty acids for a period of 8 
weeks. DHA, but 
not the control treatment, resulted in a significant clinical improvement 
of the atopic eczema.
  Comments: Fish oils which have the combination of EPA and DHA act 
as anti-inflammatory agents and may be beneficial in many skin conditions 
that involve an inflammatory reaction by the body. Along with taking fish 
oils or DHA, people with atopic excema or acne should consume a higher 
intake of fish and vegetables, and reduce the consumption of sugar and bad 
fats such as trans fats. See http://www.raysahelian.com/dha.html 

 ===================================
 4. Caution combining nattokinase and 
aspirin
 Nattokinase is a natural supplement 
used as a blood thinner. Doctors in Taiwan report a 
patient who had a bleeding stroke after taking a nattokinase supplement in 
addition to aspirin. Using nattokinase together with aspirin, Coumadin, Plavix, and 
other blood thinners should be done only under close medical supervision. 
Actually, it is preferable to take nattokinase only with the guidance of a 
medical doctor and to have regular blood coagulation studies. I have not 
seen comparisons regarding the potency of nattokinase versus Coumadin or 
aspirin so I don&apos;t know whether nattokinase is an effective and acceptable 
substitute to these drugs in those who require blood thinning, for 
instance in those who have atrial fibrillation. See http://www.raysahelian.com/nattokinase.html 

 ===================================
 Emails
Prune juice for constipation
 Q. Does prune juice really work for constipation. 
If so, how many ounces is needed?
  A. Yes, definitely. Prune juice is an excellent choice to help with 
constipation. Depending on the severity of the constipation, one to six 
ounces is beneficial. You may consider drinking about two or three ounces late in 
the evening and when you wake up in the morning drink a glass or two of 
cool water. This will help you eliminate. Some people notice a slight mood 
elevation by having an empty distal colon, and even a mild sexual enhancement. 
Prune juice also has tons of great antioxidants. See http://www.raysahelian.com/constipation.html 

 Diet Rx dosage 
Q. I experimented with Diet Rx at two capsules a day and one capsule a 
day. I find that if I take one capsule a day, it takes 3 or 4 days before 
I notice the appetite suppression. If I take 2 capsules a day, it starts 
working the second day. Is this what others have reported? When I take 2 
capsules a day sometimes it gives me more energy than I need.
  A. Yes, we have had feedback from users who find one capsule a day 
works, but much slower. The majority of users take 2 capsules a day, and a 
few need 3 or 4 a day. There is a natural energy enhancement that comes on with 2 
or 3 capsules 
that makes people want to take a walk, or take a longer walk, which burns 
up more calories. 

 

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 3 -- March 2008
===================================
Recently there was an article in the New York Times 
which caught my interest. The article begins,&quot; Statins 
[drugs like Lipitor] are among the most prescribed drugs in the world, and there is no 
doubt that they lower not only cholesterol but also the risk for heart 
attack.
Do they prolong your life? For many users, the surprising answer appears to be no.&quot;
  If you have a been a long time reader of my newsletter you know my 
opinion on the topic of statin drugs. I agree with the viewpoint of the 
NYT article. Although statin drugs do lower cholesterol levels, there is 
no good evidence that they prolong lifespan to any significant extent. At a cost of two thousand 
dollars a year and the unpleasant side effects they induce such as muscle 
aches, liver damage, and potential memory loss, I question the wisdom of doctors who prescribe them to those with 
mild or moderate cholesterol elevation, particularly to patients who do 
not have heart disease. Over the years I have had many medical doctors 
email my research staff in an angry tone claiming that I was misleading my 
readers by advising 
limiting the use of these drugs. I think these medical doctors should 
rather apologize to their patients if they have been overly aggressive in 
prescribing statin drugs. Perhaps statins are helpful in those with 
excessively high cholesterol levels or patients who have already had a heart 
attack. But, as of now, I see no reason to subject those who are healthy 
but have a mild cholesterol elevation to these dangerous and costly drugs. 
More on this later. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the 
next few days the following items are highly discounted: Mind 
Power Rx improves mental clarity and focus within hours, Mind Power Rx helps 
improve mental alertness and wakefulness along with boosting mental 
stamina. Hoodia is a diet pill that helps reduce appetite, hoodia is also 
found in Diet Rx, a highly effective appetite suppressant.
Beta sitosterol is a phytosterol used by those for prostate health and 
those with cholesterol issues.
Choline, a nutrient that converts into the neurotransmitter acetylcholine, 
has brain boosting potential, while some say choline lowers homocysteine 
levels. Choline is a nutrient precursor to acetylcholine which functions 
as a neurotransmitter. Chrysin is a potent flavonoid extracted from plants and bee propolis. 
Mangosteen is becoming more popular in the form of mangosteen juice. To avoid the 
calories in the juice, consider mangosteen capsules. 

 ===================================
 1. Statin drugs are not likely to prolong your life 
The article in the NYT continues,&quot;Some patients do receive significant benefits from statins, like Lipitor 
(from Pfizer), Crestor (AstraZeneca) and Pravachol (Bristol-Myers Squibb). 
In studies of middle-aged men with cardiovascular disease, statin users 
were less likely to die than those who were given a placebo.
But many statin users dont have established heart disease; they simply 
have high cholesterol. For healthy men, for women with or without heart 
disease and for people over 70, there is little evidence, if any, that 
taking a statin will make a meaningful difference in how long they live.
In many statin studies that show lower heart attack risk, the same number 
of patients end up dying, whether they are taking statins or not.&quot;
  I was really happy to see this issue addressed in a fair manner. 
There are many natural and safer ways to lower cholesterol and lipid 
levels and to reduce the risk for heart disease. See www.raysahelian.com/heartdisease.html . For the complete NYT article, 
go to http://www.nytimes.com/2008/01/29/health/29well.html?_r=1&amp;oref=slogin

===================================
 2. Are fish oils capsules as good as eating fish? 
Does the body process fatty 
acids from fish oil capsules and fish in a similar way? To investigate, 
Dr. William S. Harris, at the University of South Dakota in Sioux Falls 
asked women to eat two servings of tuna or salmon each 
week, while other women took in the same amount of omega-3s, an 
estimated 485 milligrams daily, in capsule form.
After four months, the amount of omega-3 fatty acids in the red blood 
cells of women had risen by a similar amount in both 
groups. Apparently it did not make much of a difference whether the 
healthy omega 3 fatty acids came from a capsule or from fish.

===================================
 3. Mucuna pruriens herb for fertility problems 
Investigators at King George&apos;s Medical University, Lucknow, India 
looked into the role of mucuna pruriens on semen profiles and biochemical 
levels in seminal fluid of infertile men. Sixty normal healthy fertile 
men undergoing infertility screening were given mucuna pruriens. 
The herbal supplement increased sperm production and improved sperm 
motility. They investigators say,&quot;The present study is likely to open new vistas on the possible role of mucuna pruriens seed powder as a restorative and invigorating agent for 
infertile men.&quot;
  Comments: For long term use, I suggest not using more than one 
capsule of mucuna pruiriens extract 400 mg three times a week. For more 
info, see http://www.raysahelian.com/mucunapruriens.html . 

 ===================================
 My personal experimentation with
CDP-Choline supplement 
CDP-choline stands for cytidine 5-diphosphocholine, an intermediate in the 
biosynthesis of membrane phospholipids and brain acetylcholine. I started 
one morning with a 250 mg pill. Within two hours I was more alert and 
focused with a slightly enhanced vision. The next day I took 500 mg and 
noticed even more alertness and focus, with a slight vision enhancement 
and perhaps a slight erectile enhancement. There was a mild improvement in 
mood. The side effects were increased body temperature and a little bit of 
underarm sweating. I like CDP-choline and 
I take it once in a while for a quick mental enhancement. The 
increased concentration and focus last several hours and then fade away. 
I also like Mind Power Rx a lot. If you wish, you can alternate CDP-choline one day and Mind Power Rx another day. For 
more info, see http://www.raysahelian.com/cdp.html . 

 =================================== 
 Emails
Passion Rx 
I purchased a bottle of both Passion Rx and Passion Rx with Yohimbe last 
month and I am quite pleased with the results. 
It re-awakened a part of me that I had thought was gone forever, and I am 
so
thankful that my libido has reached a level that I have not experienced 
for literally decades. I cannot tell any difference between the formula 
with yohimbe and that which does not. The one side effect that I have 
noticed is that, if I drink a cup of coffee on the same day that I take a 
capsule (or one-half of one), I have a difficult time falling asleep. For 
that reason, I am limiting my coffee intake on the days that I take the 
herbal formula (which is not a great problem, 
given the outstanding effects of taking Passion
Rx). I began taking Passion Rx right after the first of the year, one-half 
capsule every second or third day (although on several occasions I took 
an entire capsule). I felt the effects after about a week of taking them. 
I am 54 years old, six feet tall, and healthy.
  A. Thank you for the feedback. I prefer the low dose approach using 
the supplement every other day and being patient rather than taking this 
formula every day. To minimize side effects even more, one should consider 
using a third or half of a capsule every other day or two days on, one or 
more days off. the lower dosages are appropriate for women or those 
over the age of 50. 

 DHEA caution 
Q. I&apos;m a 32 y/o male, in overall good health status. I started to take 
DHEA hormone due to the advertised positive effects such 
as increased libido, feeling of wellness and testosterone boost to improve 
my training performance at the gym. The dose I&apos;ve been taking is 50 mg per 
day for about a month. In the first days i immediately noticed a 
considerable improvement in my mood. I also felt more alert and a bit more 
aggressive (something which didn&apos;t bother me though). I also felt a 
certain itchiness in my scalp. However after about 3 weeks i started 
experiencing occasional heaert palpitations and moderate hair loss, I didn&apos;t have 
any aesthetic damage (yet), but i was scared by the perspective, so I 
began phasing it off, now after 2 weeks I do not take it all anymore, and 
 
the side effects seem to have stopped. However, i seriously enjoyed 
its positive effects, I wonder if a dosage of 5 mg per day would still 
produce any tangible result, and be safe? I also would like to denounce 
that the company I bought the 50 mg DHEA from advertised DHEA as being 
completely side-effect free, and recommended a daily dosage of 25 mg a day 
for women, 50mg a day for men. I think this is totally unethical.
  A. For several years I have placed a warning on my website regarding DHEA 
side effects and asked that vitamin companies limit 
the DHEA dosage they make available to the public. There are still many 
companies who are careless and promote capsules that contain 50 and 100 mg. DHEA should only be used in 
a 5 to 
10 mg dosage and only for a few days a month. There are many other 
alternatives to DHEA for energy enhancement, feelings of wellness and 
increased libido. For instance, MultiVit Rx increases wellbeing and energy 
while Passion Rx or other aphrodisiac herbs increase libido. DHEA at 5 
mg could still cause side effects if used daily. I suggest not using it 
more than 10 days a month. 

 Stevia and weight gain concern 
Q. I have been using the no calorie natural sweetener stevia for several 
years now and love it, knowing it doesn&apos;t have the chemical issues as 
other sugar substitutes such as saccharin. However, I am concerned about a 
Time article I read about&quot;artificial&quot;sweeteners, such as saccharin, 
whose long term use researchers think may have a link to overreating and 
hence, obesity. I would appreciate your response to this article. From a 
scientific standpoint, would stevia cause the same metabolic reaction to 
the sugar effect as saccharin, potentially causing overreating and weight 
gain? http://www.time.com/time/health/article/0,8599,1711763,00.html?cnn=yes
  A. When these types of studies are done in animals, they are fed 
foods almost exclusively sweetened with an artificial sweetener. In 
contrast, most humans who consume stevia do so in small amounts, adding 
stevia to tea or coffee, but continue to eat other foods throughout the 
day that have sugars. Therefore, unless a person uses stevia or an 
artificial sweetener in large quantities in every food at every meal, the 
rodent studies are not likely to be applicable to us humans eating a 
regular diet with a little bit of stevia used as a sweetener. See http://www.raysahelian.com/stevia.html 
  

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D.
 Vol. 5, Issue 2 -- February 2008
=================================== 
Do calcium supplements increase the risk for heart attacks? I recently had 
a spirited discussion with a friend who happens to be a gynecologist. She 
insisted that calcium citrate was better than calcium carbonate for women 
after menopause since she claimed calcium citrate was better absorbed. 
Although I agreed with her that a couple of brief studies had shown that 
calcium citrate was better absorbed, for practical purposes I did not 
think one could emphatically say one form was better for overall health 
than the other since no long term head to head comparisons had been done. 
I mentioned to her that one has to balance the benefits and risks of 
supplements. In the case of calcium, although higher dosages have been 
found to increase bone strength, one drawback is that higher calcium 
intake through supplements increases the risk for kidney stones. And just 
recently, a study came out that high intake of calcium through supplements 
could increase the risk for heart attacks. See below for a review of this 
study and my thoughts on absorption. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at www.PhysicianFormulas.com - For the next few 
days the following items 
will be highly discounted: Passion Rx has become one of the most popular 
products on the internet for the purposes of sexual enhancement. It takes 
a few days or a week (one capsule every other day or two days on, one day 
off) for the full benefits to be apparent. Detailed instructions are 
available on the web site.
Serrapeptase or Serratiopeptidase - is an enzyme isolated from a 
microorganism in silkworm.
Fish oils are one of our favorite supplements. Fish oils are always 
popular and a great addition to those whose diets lack adequate intake of fish. Acai is a fruit extract from South America getting a lot of media 
attention for its potent antioxidant content;
Fennel is a gentle and soothing herb;
Niacin no flush is used for blood lipid management. Arjuna is an Ayurvedic herb that may be helpful in supporting cardiovascular 
health. 

 ===================================
 1. No need to be obsessed about absorption of 
supplements 
Have you come across advertisements for supplements where the company 
claims their product is better absorbed than others on the market? I see 
this often, particularly in regards to CoQ10 supplements. We receive 
emails from consumers who ask us whether the claims they read about are 
true. Many people get overly concerned regarding the issue of absorption. 
Unless you have a serious digestive problem, this should not be a major 
concern for you. Of course, the issue of absorption is important, but one 
has to realize that in some cases, the dosages of supplements or herbs 
that are sold are very high. For instance, some companies market CoQ10 
products and as part of the sales pitch they claim their CoQ10 is absorbed 
better than other brands (often without providing any proof). Well, most 
people only need 10 to 30 mg of CoQ10 a day. If a person takes a 100 mg 
CoQ10 capsule, they may not need all the 100 mg. If they take a product 
that is 95% percent absorbed versus one that is 98% percent absorbed, 
practically, what&apos;s the real difference? Perhaps the lower absorbing 
supplement is healthier since excess levels of certain supplements can 
throw the body&apos;s chemistry out of balance. In the case of calcium 
mentioned at the beginning of the newsletter, perhaps women who take a 
form of calcium that is not as well absorbed would have a lower risk of 
kidney stones and hardening of the arteries.
  Therefore, don&apos;t overly concern yourself with the absorption issue 
unless you are being treated for a particular medical condition with 
certain supplements and it is imperative that your body gets the right 
dosage. If you are taking supplements routinely for long term health, the 
minor absorption differences between different supplement products should 
not be a concern. 

 ===================================
 2. When we all thought calcium supplements were 
relatively safe 
Did you see this worrisome headline?&quot;Older women who take calcium 
supplements to maintain bone strength may have an increased risk of heart 
attack.&quot;Researchers at the University of Auckland in New Zealand 
evaluated 1,471 healthy post-menopausal women, average age 74, for a 
period of five years. Half were given a daily calcium supplement and half 
were given a placebo. Participants received either 1 gram of elemental 
calcium daily as the citrate (Citracal) or identical placebo. They were 
asked to take two tablets (each containing 200 mg elemental calcium) 
before breakfast and three in the evening. Over the next few years, heart 
attacks were more common in the women taking the calcium supplements. For 
details, see www.raysahelian.com/calcium.html 
  Comments: Many women take calcium supplements to try to prevent 
osteoporosis. Calcium supplements elevate blood calcium levels possibly 
accelerating vascular calcification. Doctors and patients are now 
presented with a very difficult challenge. At what level of calcium 
supplement intake do the benefits of osteoporosis prevention or treatment 
outweigh the possible risks of kidney stones and heart attacks? I would 
like to see a few more studies regarding the role of calcium supplements 
and heart attack rate. Perhaps the results of this study were a fluke and 
other studies may not find the same association. Assuming that there is 
such an association, recommending calcium supplements for post menopausal 
osteoporosis prevention becomes quite difficult. I don&apos;t have absolute 
answers on this issue, but, for the time being, a reasonable balance would 
be to reduce one&apos;s calcium intake from supplements. If you are taking 
1,200 mg a day, you may wish to drop to 800 or 1,000 mg. If you are taking 
800 a day, you may wish to drop to 600 mg. Discuss with your doctor the 
results of this study and both of you could come to a mutually satisfying 
decision regarding the appropriate dosage in your particular case. 
Different doctors and scientists are likely to have different 
interpretations and suggestions. 

 ===================================
 3. Acetyl l carnitine supplement for 
fibromyalgia 
At the University of Verona in Italy. patients with fibromyalgia took 3 
capsules daily containing 500 mg acetyl l carnitine and were compared to a 
group receiving placebo. The number of positive tender points declined 
significantly and equally in both groups until the 6th week of treatment. 
At the 10th week pain remained unchanged in the placebo group but 
continued to decline in the acetyl l carnitine group. Those taking the 
supplements were less depressed and had less musculoskeletal pain. The 
researchers say,&quot;These results indicate that acetyl l carnitine may be of benefit in patients with fibromyalgia, providing 
improvement in pain as well as the general and mental health of these 
patients.&quot;
  Comments: You may first try a smaller dosage of 300 mg a day before 
increasing to higher dosages. I find that amounts greater than 500 or 600 
mg a day cause nausea, restlessness, and sometimes shallow sleep. There 
are other natural options for reducing symptoms of fibromyalgia. See http://www.raysahelian.com/acetylcarnitine.html and  http://www.raysahelian.com/fibromyalgia.html 

 ===================================
 My experience with supplements 
In each newsletter I describe my personal experiences with herbs and 
supplements. Please keep in mind that your reaction may be different. 
Plus, the short term effects of a supplement may be different when the 
supplement is taken for weeks or months. Since there are hundreds of herbs 
and supplements that I would still like to try over the next few years, I 
don&apos;t have the luxury to take any particular ones for too long. When I 
test supplements I take them on an empty stomach in the morning and take 
no other supplements or medicines that day. This month I describe my 
experience with mangosteen. In the coming issues I will review inositol, acai, resveratrol, mucuna pruriens, 
cdp-choline, newest batches of Passion Rx and Eyesight Rx and others. 

 Mangosteen supplement 
Mangosteen is a fruit grown in Thailand. Mangosteen juice and supplements 
have become very popular as potent antioxidants and perhaps anti-cancer 
agents. But is mangosteen safe? Does it have side effects? I started with 
one capsule of mangosteen 500 mg the first day, and took two the next day. 
No side effects. I increased the dosage on subsequent days to 3 and 4 a 
day. Still no side effects. After a week of taking 4 capsules a day, I 
feel comfortable that this supplement does not have short term adverse 
effects and a capsule or two a day can probably be combined with other 
supplements without untoward reactions. See http://www.raysahelian.com/mangosteen.html 

 =================================== 
Emails 
Q. Are there any male sex herbs that are safe enough to be taken for those 
with high blood pressure or taking blood pressure medicines like 
Lisinopril?
  A. One has to consider the whole person when making 
recommendations, not just the fact that they have one medical condition or 
taking one medication. Age, sex, diet, activity level, blood study 
results, EKG result, other supplements taken, other medications (otc and 
prescription), etc all play a role in the decision making process, 
particularly the dosages of herbs and medications. Having said all 
this, a general statement can be made that low dosages of sex herbs, for 
instance half a capsule of tribulus, tongkat ali, Passion Rx, muira puama, 
catuaba, mucuna pruriens, horny goat weed, etc., are generally safe when 
used every other day. The sexual enhancement would be slower when using 
these low dosages, but it would be a safer approach in those with 
hypertension or non serious medical conditions. It may take a week or two 
to notice the sexual benefits. Another option is Prostate Power Rx one 
capsule every other day which many people like. Please have approval by 
your doctor before taking sexual herbs particularly if you have 
cardiovascular issues. Many of these herbs speed heart rate and the side 
effects of these herbs are dose dependent. 

 Q. I think your Diet Rx pills are fantastic. I took 
two capsules in the morning and by lunch time I had very little appetite. 
The benefits of appetite suppression continued every day that I took the 
pills, even a day or two after I stopped. The only side effect was more 
energy and I used it to take a long walk each evening. I am 44 SWF, and I 
have been telling all my friends about this product. I have tried other 
diet products in the past but they either did not work or caused anxiety 
and speediness. 

 ===================================
 SUPPLEMENT RESEARCH UPDATE - by Ray Sahelian, M.D. 
Vol. 5, Issue 1 -- January 2008
===================================
I wish all of you a new year blessed with optimal health and wellbeing. In 
the coming year I plan to continue providing you my honest opinion on the 
latest natural medicine research along with which supplements work, which 
don&apos;t, their benefits and side effects. I will also let you know about my 
personal experiences trying a number of supplements. Each month I will 
take at least one or two new products and let you know what effect they 
have on me.
  It has only been a little over 3 years that I have been writing 
this newsletter and we already have more than 80,000 subscribers. Many 
write to us to let us know they appreciate the straightforward, clear and 
honest reviews.
  The holiday gift giving season is not over. For the first time 
Physician Formulas web site is giving away a free product, a bottle 
of Diet Rx with 15 capsules. The response to Diet Rx has been so 
encouraging that we feel more people should be aware of this natural 
product. You, too, can now try a FREE sample all natural diet pill that curbs your 
appetite... especially if you had a hearty appetite over the holiday 
season. Click on the bottle to your left for your free product. Later I 
discuss my experience with Diet Rx. 

 PRODUCT DISCOUNTS at Physician Formulas web site - For the next few 
days the following items 
will be highly discounted: MultiVit Rx enhances mood, energy, mental clarity, and wellbeing. 
This multivitamin is quite potent, and even though it says on the label to take up to 4 
capsules a day, two capsules work well for most people. Some may only need 
one capsule, others take two or three.
CoQ10 is an antioxidant used for energy and cardiovascular 
health. CoQ10 at 50 mg is a good dose for those who wish to take this 
popular nutrient a few times a week without overdosing; Muira Puama is an herb from the Amazon forest used traditionally for 
sexual enhancement, often combined with catuaba;
Passion Flower herb is used for its relaxing and calming effect;
Milk Thistle herb has liver protecting antioxidant functions;
Mind Boosters is a best selling book regarding 
 
natural supplements that enhance mood, memory, and mind. Cinnamon extract has the potential 
to help maintain healthy blood sugar levels.

 1. 100 year olds benefit from Carnitine supplements 
Even a hundred year old may benefit from supplements. Italian researchers 
at the University of Catania gave sixty-six centenarians 2 grams carnitine daily 
for six months. At the end of the study period, the carnitine supplement treated centenarians, compared with 
the placebo group, showed significant improvements in total fat mass and 
total muscle mass. They were also less likely to have 
physical and mental 
fatigue. Cholesterol levels fell among the individuals taking the 
supplement. Carnitine takers also gained on average 3.8 kilograms (8.4 pounds) 
of muscle mass and lost 1.8 kg (4 pounds) of fat mass. People given carnitine 
were able to walk several meters further during a 6-minute walking test.
  Comments: This study shows how much we still can learn about the 
benefits of supplements in the aged. My preference would be to use a lower 
amount of carnitine, such as 250 mg or 500 mg. Sometimes when high dosages of 
energy enhancing pills are taken for prolonged periods, they can accumulate and 
interfere with sleep or cause rapid heart beat. Another study indicates that 
carnitine could be helpful in those who have the blood disorder thalassemia. For more information on the benefits of carnitine, see http://www.raysahelian.com/carnitine.html 

 2. Glucomannan and Psyllium help with weight 
loss and cholesterol
 If you have been a long term reader of my newsletter, you are aware 
of my hesitancy in using statin drugs such as Lipitor or Zocor for 
cholesterol reduction, or the use of pharmaceutical drugs for weight loss. 
Drugs should be reserved when safer methods fail. A study completed in 
Spain found the use of two simple and inexpensive fibers, psyllium and 
glucomannan, to be helpful not only in weight reduction, but also in 
lowering LDL cholesterol levels. For a period of 16 
weeks, obese individuals at a university center in Spain were asked to 
consume additional fiber consisting of 3 grams psyllium husk and 1 gram of glucomannan 
two or three times daily. Those taking the fiber supplements had a weight 
loss of more than 4 kilos compared to the placebo group. The fiber 
supplements led to lower LDL-cholesterol levels. No side effects were 
reported.
  My comments: It&apos;s sad that doctors prescribe statin drugs to their 
patients with mild cholesterol level elevations when there are are simple 
and safe alternatives. I can understand using statin drugs when all 
natural options fail, but most doctors don&apos;t even suggest additional fiber 
supplements. They are quick to the draw to write a prescription for a 
statin drug or a prescription weight loss drug. See http://www.raysahelian.com/fiber.html for more information. See also http://www.raysahelian.com/weightloss.html 

 3. Alpha 
lipoic acid for Alzheimer&apos;s disease 
One of the most worrisome aspects of aging is the fear of losing one&apos;s 
mind and memory. We are learning that the incidence of dementia or 
Alzheimer&apos;s disease can be reduced with life long healthy eating patterns 
and also by the use of certain supplements. A study recently 
completed in Germany found alpha lipoic acid, a potent antioxidant, was 
able to slow the progression of Alzheimer&apos;s disease. Patients with Alzheimer&apos;s disease received 600 mg of alpha lipoic 
acid daily for several years. The researchers concluded that the rate of 
progression of the disease was slower in comparison to normal 
progression of Alzheimer&apos;s disease.
  Comments: I prefer using lower amounts of alpha lipoic acid in a 
range of 10 to 50 mg of the more potent R alpha lipoic acid a few times a week. There are many 
supplements that could help mental decline. See http://www.raysahelian.com/alzheimer.html for more details. 

 4. Kava and liver concern 
 Kava is a plant that grows in the Pacific islands whose roots 
contain kavalactones which are potent anti-anxiety agents. However, there 
is a concern that chronic kava ingestion may harm the liver. University of 
Hawaii scientists tested the effects of traditionally prepared kava beverages on 
liver function tests of regular kava beverage consumers. The liver 
function tests of healthy adult kava drinkers were compared against a 
control group of healthy adult non kava drinkers. Chronic kava beverage consumption was associated with elevation of 
certain liver enzymes. This indicates that daily kava consumption for 
prolonged periods can be stressful to the liver.
  Comments: Kava is a great herb for reducing anxiety and helping 
with sleep. However, it should only be used in small amounts at most three 
times a week with a full week off a month. Serious liver damage has 
occurred in rare cases when kava supplement users have taken it daily and 
in high dosages. Kava is found in Good Night Rx, a product that helps with 
sleep. We suggest using this sleep formula no more than three nights a 
week. See http://www.raysahelian.com/kava.html 

 My experience with supplements 
In each newsletter I will describe my personal experiences with herbs and 
supplements. Please keep in mind that your reaction may be different. 
Plus, the short term effects of a supplement may be different when the 
supplement is taken for weeks or months. Since there are hundreds of herbs 
and supplements that I would still like to try over the next few years, I 
don&apos;t have the luxury to take any particular ones for too long. When I 
test supplements, I take them on an empty stomach in the morning and take 
no other supplements or medicines that day. This month I describe Diet Rx 
and alpha GPC. In the coming issues I will review inositol, mangosteen, 
acai, resveratrol, the newest batches of Passion Rx, mucuna pruriens, and 
others. 

 How Diet Rx was formulated 
and my experience 
One of my close friends insisted that I give him suggestions on 
supplements to take for weight loss. Over the past few years I had been 
reluctant to formulate a diet pill since I was skeptical that it would 
work. However, since he insisted, I asked him to take a combination of 
several key herbs. I had tried these herbs before by themselves and had noticed a 
mild appetite suppressing effect from some of them. I thought perhaps the 
combination would have some benefit. Within a week he called me to say his 
appetite had been significantly reduced and he had lost a few pounds. This 
encouraged me and I started further experimenting with each ingredient 
separately and then together. I then had my research staff and any friends 
and patients I could recruit try the combination of ingredients. The 
feedback was tremendous. Everyone reported that they were eating less. The 
first batch of Diet Rx was finalized by the manufacturer in October 2007 
and I eagerly tested the final product on myself. I took two capsules the 
first morning and forgot I had taken them since it was a busy day. At 2 pm 
in the afternoon I realized that I had only eaten a light breakfast and 
had little interest in eating lunch. The effects mostly wore off by 
evening and I had a normal dinner but did not feel the urge to have 
dessert or a fruit salad. The next day I again took two capsules and this 
time the effects were more pronounced. I also felt that I had a lot of 
natural energy which motivated me to take a long walk. After 7 days of 
taking 2 capsules of Diet Rx (one day I took 4 but it gave me too much 
energy), I had lost three pounds. I really don&apos;t need to lose weight but 
it is reassuring to know that if I ever add a few extra pounds, there is 
an effective appetite suppressant that I can rely on.
  Interestingly, many people have said that, after they stopped or 
ran out of the pills, the appetite suppression lasted a day or two more. 
If you tend to consume most of your calories late at night, you may 
consider taking the Diet Rx pills mid morning or early afternoon as 
opposed to first thing in the morning. 

 Alpha GPC is promoted as a mind booster 
Alpha GPC is a newcomer in the mind boosting supplement field. Alpha GPC 
stands for alpha-glycerylphosphorylcholine and is chemically related to 
choline and lecithin. The first morning I took one capsule at a dosage of 
300 mg. By mid morning I had not felt much, so I took another capsule. 
Except for slight alertness, I can&apos;t say I noticed much of a positive or 
negative effect. A few days later, I took 3 capsules in the morning. By 
midday I noticed being more alert and there was a very mild relaxing 
effect, unlike other brain boosters which often make me feel stimulated. 
It seemed the alertness became more prominent in early evening. The third 
day I took 2 capsules and again the effects were subtle. Overall I did not 
find alpha GPC to be very potent. I don&apos;t have a strong urge to take it 
again any time soon, although I can see it being useful as a subtle mental 
enhancer in those who find acetyl-carnitine, gingko biloba, choline, DMAE, 
TMG, or other brain boosters too stimulating and would prefer a gentler 
brain enhancer. Alpha GPC may offer long term benefits as discussed in the 
research studies listed at http://www.raysahelian.com/alphagpc.html . As to side effects, I did 
not notice any nausea, headache, increased body temperature, or rapid 
heart rate. 

 If you have experiences with supplements you would 
like to share, please visit http://www.raysahelian.com/contactus.html and you will find an email 
address.
	</body>
</document>
