<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006277" url="http://www.patentstorm.us/patents/7077571/description.html" time="2012-07-12-22:57" support="16" score="0.016390849609996237" bingtitle="Collapsible and disposable trash receptacle - US Patent 7077571 ..." webtitle="Collapsible and disposable trash receptacle - US Patent 7077571 Description">
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000633" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000539" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... of performing table trash disposal has been used in a self-service &quot;fast food ... Accordingly, a need remains for a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle in order to ...</description>
	<body>
		PatentStorm 
 
 Home Browse by Inventor Browse by Examiner Browse by Date FAQ Contact Us 
 U.S. patents available from 1976 to present.
U.S. patent applications available from 2005 to present. or try Advanced search 
 Collapsible and disposable trash receptacle 

 Patent 7077571 Issued on July 18, 2006 . Estimated Expiration Date:  June 23, 2025. Estimated Expiration Date is calculated based on simple USPTO term provisions. It does not account for terminal disclaimers, term adjustments, failure to pay maintenance fees, or other factors which might affect the term of a patent. Abstract   Claims   Description   Full Text 
 
 
Patent References
 
2796517


2833460


 Combined trash receptacle for table use 
 Patent #: 4166572
Issued on: 09/04/1979
Inventor: Leeds 

 Trash bag insert 
 Patent #: 4628007
Issued on: 12/09/1986
Inventor: Ledsham 

 Waste separator-receptacle for recycling of materials with environmental control dispenser and holder 
 Patent #: 4660758
Issued on: 04/28/1987
Inventor: Tavel ,   et al. 

 Table apparatus with disposal assembly 
 Patent #: 4747352
Issued on: 05/31/1988
Inventor: Guidry ,   et al. 

 Disposable and collapsible trash receptacle 
 Patent #: 4764029
Issued on: 08/16/1988
Inventor: Abblett 

 Inflatable self-supporting bag Patent #: 4941754
Issued on: 07/17/1990
Inventor: Murdock 
 

Inventor

 Wilson, Patricia B. 






Application
No. 11158631 filed on 06/23/2005


US Classes:
 383/120 , Pleated or gusseted 383/907 , PECULIAR, PARTICULAR SHAPE 220/908 , TRASH CONTAINER 362/352 , Collapsible or folding 383/36 , WITH INTEGRAL FUNNEL 383/3 INFLATABLE 


Examiners
Primary: Hylton, Robin A. 



International Class
B65D 30/20
 

Description


 
CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS

Not Applicable.

STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT

Not Applicable.

REFERENCE TO A MICROFICHE APPENDIX

Not Applicable.

BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION

1. Technical Field

This invention relates to trash receptacles and, more particularly, to a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle sized and shaped to be seated on a dining table.

2. Prior Art

An attractive public restaurant is characterized by an appearance of neatness and cleanliness. This is difficult to maintain when dining tables quickly become cluttered with various paper and plastic items provided largely in conformance withsanitary regulations. Such items consist of paper envelopes for sugar, waxed paper covers for wafers, paper covers for drinking straws, waxed paper covers for butter pats, plastic jelly containers, tooth picks used with hors d&apos;oeuvres, notwithstandingtrash associated with smoking, such as plastic cigar covers and paper cigar bands, empty match covers and tops of cigarette packages.

One example to this approach provides a convenient trash receptacle in which diners can dispose of these pieces of paper and plastic as they appear so as to keep them out of sight, at the same time avoiding the possibility of creating a smallblaze resulting from trash being carelessly dropped in an ashtray containing a lit cigarette. Another prior means of performing table trash disposal has been used in a self-service &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant by providing a large slot in the top of thetable, giving access to a container beneath the table. It is obvious that this solution is hardly suitable for an attractive restaurant with cloth-covered tables.

Accordingly, a need remains for a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle in order to overcome the above-noted shortcomings. The present invention satisfies such a need by providing a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle that isconvenient, sanitary, disposable, lightweight, compact, durable, practical, inexpensive, and easy to use. The collapsible and disposable trash receptacle appeals to the food service industry, homeowners, and the like, or those concerned with overallcleanliness and sanitation.

BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION

In view of the foregoing background, it is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a device for a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle. These and other objects, features, and advantages of the invention are provided by atrash receptacle sized and shaped to be seated on a dining table.

The device includes a base member formed from flexible material including an inner layer and an outer layer abutted thereagainst and an upper body monolithically formed with the base member and extending upwardly therefrom. The upper body has anopen top end portion centrally aligned about a longitudinal axis of the receptacle and further has a deformably resilient outer surface including a plurality of coextensive pleats equidistantly spaced about a circumference of the upper body wherein thelongitudinal length of the pleats is greater than the width of the pleats. The pleats extend along a longitudinal length of the upper body and is simultaneously adaptable during operating conditions.

The base member and the upper body are adaptable between compressed and expanded positions. The base member has a substantially cylindrical shape when adapted to an expanded position. The upper body has a spherical shape when adapted to anexpanded position such that the upper body has a circumference greater than the circumference of the base member.

The pleats preferably include a plurality of monolithically formed coextensive side portions radially extending away from the longitudinal axis and conveniently adjustable between expanded and compressed positions such that a volume of the upperbody can be selectively expanded when the side portions are adapted to a position tangential to the circumference of the upper body. Such a bottom surface of the base member may have a plurality of coextensive lines of weakness so that the base membercan be effectively compressed to a planar position.

The upper body defines a width equal to a width of the base member when at a compressed position such that the receptacle can be readily stored, and defines a spherical cavity therein when adapted to the expanded position.

There has thus been outlined, rather broadly, the more important features of the invention in order that the detailed description thereof that follows may be better understood, and in order that the present contribution to the art may be betterappreciated. There are additional features of the invention that will be described hereinafter and which will form the subject matter of the claims appended hereto.

It is noted the purpose of the foregoing abstract is to enable the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office and the public generally, especially the scientists, engineers and practitioners in the art who are not familiar with patent or legal terms orphraseology, to determine quickly from a cursory inspection the nature and essence of the technical disclosure of the application. The abstract is neither intended to define the invention of the application, which is measured by the claims, nor is itintended to be limiting as to the scope of the invention in any way.

BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING

The novel features believed to be characteristic of this invention are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention itself, however, both as to its organization and method of operation, together with further objects andadvantages thereof, may best be understood by reference to the following description taken in connection with the accompanying drawings in which:

FIG. 1 is a perspective view of the device showing a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle, in accordance with the present invention;

FIG. 2 is a top plan view of the device shown in FIG. 1, at a compressed position;

FIG. 3 is a cross-sectional view of the pleats shown in FIG. 2, taken along lines 3--3;

FIG. 4 is a cross-sectional view of the device shown in FIG. 1 taken along lines 4--4; and

FIG. 5 is an enlarged cross-sectional view of the wall in FIG. 4 shown in section 5.

DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION

The present invention will now be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which a preferred embodiment of the invention is shown. This invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms andshould not be construed as limited to the embodiment set forth herein. Rather, this embodiment is provided so that this application will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the true scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. Likenumbers refer to like elements throughout the figures.

The device of this invention is referred to generally in FIGS. 1 5 by the reference numeral 10 and is intended to provide a collapsible and disposable trash receptacle. It should be understood that the device 10 may be used as a receptacle inmany different types of environments and should not be limited in use only for refuse.

Referring initially to FIGS. 1, 2, 3, and 5, the device 10 includes a base member 20 formed from flexible material including an inner layer 23 and an outer layer 24 abutted thereagainst. The device 10 further includes an upper body 21monolithically formed with the base member 20 and extending upwardly therefrom. Such an upper body 21 has an open top end portion 22 centrally aligned about a longitudinal axis of the receptacle 10 and further has a deformably resilient outer surface 25including a plurality of critical and coextensive pleats 26 equidistantly spaced about a circumference of the upper body 21 wherein the longitudinal length of the pleats 26 is greater than the width of the pleats 26. Such pleats 26 extend along alongitudinal length of the upper body 21 and are simultaneously adaptable during operating conditions. The device 10 provides a receptacle for empty cellophane wrappers, gum, condiment packets, stir sticks, sugar packets, creamer containers, etc, as isobvious to one having ordinary skill in the art.

Now referring to FIGS. 1, 2 and 3, a base member 20 and the upper body 21 are adaptable between compressed and expanded positions. The base member 20 has a substantially cylindrical shape when adapted to an expanded position. The upper body 21has a spherical shape when adapted to an expanded position such that the upper body 21 has a circumference greater than the circumference of the base member. When full, the device 10 could be easily removed and simply thrown away. Of course, the device10 could be produced in a wide range of colors, shapes, designs, styles, and sizes, as is obvious to one having ordinary skill in the art. In addition, the outer layer 24 could be imprinted with various logos, names, trivia, fun facts, etc.

Referring to FIGS. 1, 2, 3, and 4, the pleats 26 include a plurality of monolithically formed coextensive side portions 27 radially extending away from the longitudinal axis and adjustable between expanded and compressed positions such that avolume of the upper body 21 can be selectively expanded when the side portions 27 are adapted to a position tangential to the circumference of the upper body 21. Such side portions 27 are essential to the operation of the device 10 so that the pleats 26can be easily expanded and compressed. The bottom surface 28 of the base member 20 has a plurality of essential coextensive lines of weakness 29 so that the base member 20 can be effectively compressed to a planar position for easy storage. Inoperation, a user could simply open the base member 20 to expand upper body 21. Trash, such as lettuce, tomato, shrimp tails, salt and pepper packets, chicken wings, tea bags, and the like could be deposited into the device 10.

Referring to FIGS. 1 and 2, the upper body 21 defines a width equal to a width of the base member 20 when at a compressed position that is necessary such that the receptacle 10 can be readily stored, and further defines a spherical cavity 30therein when adapted to the expanded position.

The device 10 provides an easy to use depository for empty food packets and other types of trash that accumulates on table in restaurants. Accordingly, such tables could be kept neat and tidy during a meal, and customers would not be embarrassedby clutter. Thus, the time to clean up would be greatly reduced, benefiting servers and busboys. Because the device 10 is disposable, it could simply be thrown away, saving time and space.

While the invention has been described with respect to a certain specific embodiment, it will be appreciated that many modifications and changes may be made by those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit of the invention. It isintended, therefore, by the appended claims to cover all such modifications and changes as fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention.

In particular, with respect to the above description, it is to be realized that the optimum dimensional relationships for the parts of the present invention may include variations in size, materials, shape, form, function and manner of operation. The assembly and use of the present invention are deemed readily apparent and obvious to one skilled in the art.

* * * * *
 

Field of Search
 Pleated or gusseted 

 Multi-layer or ply 

 END STRUCTURE (E.G. BOTTOM) 

 HAVING NONBAG USE 

 PECULIAR, PARTICULAR SHAPE 

 Removable bag liner 

 Decorative layer 

 TRASH CONTAINER 

 Bag liner 

 Collapsible or folding 

 Curved surface 
 
 
 PatentsPlus Images 
 Enhanced PDF formats 
 loading... 
 
 
 Search-enhanced full patent PDF image $9.95 more info 
 
 
 
 Intelligent turbocharged patent PDFs with marked up images $16.95 more info 
 
 
 
 
   Home | Browse by Inventor | Browse by Examiner | Browse by Date | Resources | Contact Us | Legal Notices 
©2004-2012 PatentStorm LLC. All rights reserved. Username  Password   forgot password?
	</body>
</document>
