<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006684" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Greasecars-Fill-up-For-Free-on-Waste-Vegetable-Oil&amp;id=153219" time="2012-07-12-23:40" support="1" score="0.0008698726901082557" bingtitle="Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil" webtitle="Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil">
			<query id="001060" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>... have to pay ... of the waste oil going into a landfill you could be using it in a greasecar to commute to work. Instead of all of that oil from the local fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Automotive Kristopher Setchfield 
 Basic Author |   1 Article 
 Joined: February 27, 2006 Was this article helpful? 1 0 
Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil

 By Kristopher Setchfield 
 
How much did you spend on your last tank of gas?

If you are like most people in the US, then you probably are spending between $30 to $40 per tank of gas these days. Now most of us fill up at least once a week, and if you do the math, that can add up to over $1,000 per year on just gas!

What if there was a way that you could run on free fuel?

What if there was a way that you could reduce the effects of global warming at the same time by using an alternative fuel, like biodiesel--but better and way, way cheaper...(how much cheaper can you get than FREE!)...

Would you be interested?

Few people know that there is a readily available alternative fuel to gasoline that is available right now for FREE all over the country and is better than biodiesel.

Sound too good to be true?

I was originally very skeptical that this technology could actually work, so I read everything I could get my hands on. After years of research I finally took the plunge and converted my car to run on this free alternative fuel, and now--thousands of FREE miles later--I can unabashedly state that if you are paying for gasoline at the pump, then you are THROWING YOUR MONEY OUT THE WINDOW!

You don&apos;t have to pay $2.00 or more per gallon to drive a car!

By using vegetable oil fuel technology, you can literally drive on a waste product that other people are throwing away!

My friends tell me that this all sounds like &quot;Back to the Future,&quot; and I admit that it is kind of similar, but let me ask you a question.

If you could drive for free and help the environment at the same time, would you?

Back in the early 1900&apos;s a man by the name of Rudolph Diesel invented an engine that could run on any type of oil or grease. Petroleum oil, peanut oil, canola oil, you name it--his engine could run on it. Not only was his engine versatile, but many of his original prototypes are still in operation today, almost a hundred years later!

This engine was named the Diesel engine after its inventor, and shortly after its premier the petroleum oil industry developed a type of fuel specifically for the engine and named it Diesel fuel. An environmentally-friendly version that was made from plant based oils rather than petroleum also became available called BioDiesel.

The world then promptly forgot that the Diesel engine could run on vegetable oils, since Diesel fuel was so cheap and easy to get at the pump.

But today, with the soaring prices of Gasoline, Diesel, Biodiesel, Kerosene, and home heating fuel, this alternative fuel technology has been rediscovered!

It is possible to run any Diesel engine with straight waste vegetable oil (also known as WVO or SVO) if a conversion kit is installed to make it a &quot;GreaseCar.&quot; Vegetable oil or fryer grease is usuall free and it is readily available since many businesses and farmers throw it away as a waste product!

Isn&apos;t that weird?

I mean, can you imagine people throwing away gasoline? Can you imagine anyone throwing away home heating oil or kerosene?

It&apos;s absolutely ludicrous!

Every year in the US, the fast food industry alone throws away over six billion gallons of waste vegetable oil!

If you had a Diesel engine, you could use some of that as FREE FUEL!

Just imagine not having to pay for fuel again...you and your greasecar could take those long trips that you have been putting off because gas costs too much these days...

You could take the money you&apos;d save on gas and use it to buy those sweet tires or that awesome stereo you&apos;ve been wanting...

AND, at the same time you would actually be recycling! You see, using waste vegetable oil or grease as an alternative fuel is actually recycling a waste product. Instead of the waste oil going into a landfill you could be using it in a greasecar to commute to work. Instead of all of that oil from the local fast food restaurant going down the drain, you could use it to drive to the beach in your greasecar!

Since I converted my car to run on straight vegetable oil with a GreaseCar kit, I have driven literally thousands of miles without having to buy gas at a gas station. My friends are all amazed that it actually works, and they are all begging me to help them convert their cars!

There just aren&apos;t enough hours in the day for me to help them all personally, so I am publishing articles and information like this to help everyone save money and the world. Do a Google search for WVO or for greasecar, or visit your local library to find out how you can join the revolution. It doesn&apos;t take much and you can reduce your ecological footprint and be the envy of every gas-guzzling friend around you!
 
Kristopher T. Setchfield -Vegetable oil expert, lecturer, and founder of http://www.fillup4free.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Kristopher_Setchfield 
 Did you find this article helpful? 1 0 Get Involved 1 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Automotive 
 Kristopher Setchfield 
 Email Address: Subscribe Automotive Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 The Law Might Not Let You Make Your Own Biodiesel My Grease Car Is A School Bus 
 
Recent Articles

 Is the Pontiac Solstice Worth Your Time and Hard-Earned Money? Roads That Delivery Drivers May Like to Avoid Is It Wiser To Buy Cars From Fleet Vehicle Sales? What You Should Know About Car Shipping Rates How to Find the Best Auto Transport Rates? Looking for Exhaust Accessories? Here&apos;s a Variety Is Mandrel Bent Tubing Really the Best for Your Muffler? Opt For Remanufactured Engines Over New Ones! About Carports and Their Various Types and Uses Seek Professional Assistance for Custom License Plate Frames 
 
Submitted On February 27, 2006. Viewed 1,139 time. Word count: 843.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Setchfield, Kristopher &quot;Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil.&quot; Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil .
 27 Feb. 2006 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Greasecars-­Fill-­up-­For-­Free-­on-­Waste-­Vegetable-­Oil&amp;id=153219 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Setchfield, K. (2006, February 27). Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Greasecars-­Fill-­up-­For-­Free-­on-­Waste-­Vegetable-­Oil&amp;id=153219 Chicago Style Citation: 
Setchfield, Kristopher &quot;Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil.&quot; Greasecars Fill up For Free on Waste Vegetable Oil EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Greasecars-­Fill-­up-­For-­Free-­on-­Waste-­Vegetable-­Oil&amp;id=153219 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
