<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006958" url="http://www.yelp.com/c/cincinnati-oh/italian" time="2012-07-12-23:56" support="1" score="0.0013049103810556506" bingtitle="Cincinnati » Restaurants » Italian - Yelp" webtitle="CincinnatiRestaurantsItalian - Yelp">
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>So now, I only have a select few places that makes… ... Okay, people. Recognize this place for what it is. A fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk Events 

 Member Search 
   
Yelp Cincinnati

 San Francisco New York San Jose Los Angeles Chicago Palo Alto More Cities» 
 
Browsing: Cincinnati » Restaurants »Italian
 
 Best of Yelp 
 
 
 Bouchard&apos;s Anything&apos;s Pastable 
 16 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Over-the-Rhine Category: Italian 
 
We got the pizza dough and pesto for about $6 and it was one of the best pizzas I have ever had. Something about that dough! And the pesto.   I&apos;ve also tried their lunch. They give you a list of options you want in your pasta, salad, or flatbread pizza. I chose a linguini pasta. Unlimited toppings for $7! I waited less than 10 minutes and it was ready. And I couldn&apos;t finish it because the portion…
 
 
 
 Nicola&apos;s Ristorante 
 56 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Over-the-Rhine Category: Italian 
 
 Primavista 
 45 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Downtown Category: Italian 
 
 Bella Luna Restaurant 
 53 reviews 
 Category: Italian 
 
 Scotti&apos;s Italian Restaurant 
 26 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Downtown Category: Italian 
 
 Trattoria Roma Ristorante 
 27 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Downtown Category: Italian 
 
 More 
By Neighborhood
 
 Clifton Corryville Downtown 

 Hyde Park Norwood O&apos;Bryonville 

 Over-the-Rhine Walnut Hills Westwood 
 
Related Searches
 
Pizza

 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
 2 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Corryville Categories: Italian, Pizza 
 
(I&apos;m writing this review in relation to other Domino&apos;s locations - not as a general comparison to most restaurants.)  This Domino&apos;s location has to be…
 
 Guiseppe&apos;s Neighborhood… 
 1 review 
 Categories: Italian, Pizza 
 
UPDATE:  We just got pizza from these guys last night: good news!  Fresh mushrooms are now being served!  That is a major improvement.   Two things…
 
 Mio&apos;s Pizza 
 4 reviews 
 Categories: Italian, Pizza 
 
Mio&apos;s just opened last week right along the main shopping district in Fort Thomas. Located across the street from Subway, Mio&apos;s serves home…
 
 Betta&apos;s Italian Oven 
 23 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Norwood Category: Italian 
 
A great family run italian place near Xavier! Pros: 1) The service is always great 2) The Pizza is delicious and cooked in a wood oven, you can&apos;t go…
 
 Enoteca Emilia 
 41 reviews 
 Neighborhood: O&apos;Bryonville Category: Italian 
 
As a vegetarian, I don&apos;t really get fine dining, because most of it isn&apos;t geared toward me. Oh, your steak dinner cost $100 a plate? That&apos;s... great…
 
 
Pasta

 
 Bouchard&apos;s Anything&apos;s… 
 16 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Over-the-Rhine Category: Italian 
 
We got the pizza dough and pesto for about $6 and it was one of the best pizzas I have ever had. Something about that dough! And the pesto.   I&apos;ve…
 
 Brio Tuscan Grill 
 34 reviews 
 Category: Italian 
 
This place is a little over-priced, but they have one of my favorite dishes ever.  I am in love with the shrimp scampi and angel hair... YUM!  It is…
 
 Nicola&apos;s Ristorante 
 57 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Over-the-Rhine Category: Italian 
 
WOW...let&apos;s just start there. Without a doubt, Nicola&apos;s is one of the best places to get pasta in Cincinnati! Once you get over the odd and slightly…
 
 Al Dente 
 1 review 
 Category: Italian 
 
Who doesn&apos;t crave a big plate of pasta every now and then? At Al Dente, you start off with a simple pasta and sauce, then have the option of adding…
 
 Via Vite 
 112 reviews 
 Neighborhood: Downtown Category: Italian 
 
We ended up here as there are so few restaurants open downtown on Monday evenings (Bakersfield had a 2 hour wait and all the other OTR restaurants…
 
 
Fresh Lists

The newest of our users&apos; favorites
 
 
 The Best Non-Restaurant Reviews 

Yelp! can do more than help you find delicious grub.  Check out this list for other worthy businesses and services.
 
 Yelp 100 in 2012 Challenge 
 
 L&apos;hotels. 

All the hotels I&apos;ve stayed at... or at least reviewed.
 
 My Yelp 100 Challenge for 2012 

One year.  One hundred reviews.  Ten tired fingers.
 
 Late Night Cincinnati 

Place that are great and stay open late.
 
 
Recent Reviews
 More 
 
 View Cucina 

6 hours ago

Disclaimer: I live at the Edgecliff Private Residences. The View Cucina is on the fifth…
 
 Ferrari&apos;s Little Italy&amp;Bakery 

Yesterday

Went there for a Saturday afternoon lunch. I had the eggplant parm, excellent dish though…
 
 Trattoria Roma Ristorante 

2 days ago

What a gem. Although Cincy isn&apos;t known for Italian food, this place is definitely worth a…
 
 Enoteca Emilia 

3 days ago

My wife and I went here for dinner with some friends.  The food was good and the service…
 
 Barresi&apos;s Italian American Restrnt 

3 days ago

This is a huge favorite of my husband&apos;s and mine.  We stumbled on it when we first moved…
 
 
Recent Photos
 
 Via Vite Trattoria Roma… Bouchard&apos;s… Pompilios… Scotti&apos;s Italian… Sbarro 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Cincinnati Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
