<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006033" url="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/topics/Subject-Food_and_Drink.html" time="2012-07-12-22:42" support="1" score="0.002255332841453596" bingtitle="Food and Drink | Smithsonian Magazine - History, Travel, Arts ..." webtitle="Food and Drink   | Smithsonian Magazine">
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>Food and Drink Articles from the Smithsonian ... In 1982, a Chinese fast-food restaurant hired a curious-looking ... MoMA&apos;s Counter Space Exhibit</description>
	<body>
		Smithsonian
Institution Smithsonian
Journeys Smithsonian
Store Smithsonian
Channel goSmithsonian
Visitors Guide Air&amp;Space
magazine 
 
 Smithsonian.com 
 
 Subscribe 
 
 History&amp;Archaeology People&amp;Places Science&amp;Nature Arts&amp;Culture Travel Photos Videos Games&amp;Puzzles Blogs Shop 
 

 Topic: Subject » Society » Culture »Food and Drink 
Food and Drink
 Results 1 - 20 of 972 
 Explore more» 

 Desserts 

 Drink 

 Recipes 
 
 Return of the King Salmon 

In the ocean waters just off California&apos;s Central Coast, the fish are swarming this summer like they haven&apos;t in years
 July 12, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 Climate Change Will Mean the World Eats Rice 

The future under climate change indicates that rice will soon become an even more abundant staple, thanks to a boost in carbon dioxide that make crops like rice thrive
 July 11, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 A Short Walking Tour of New York’s Lower East Side 

In the 1860’s the Lower East Side was deluged in a wave of immigrants from Germany; known as Klein Deutschland, it had the 5th largest German-speaking population among cities in the world at the time
 July 11, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Susan Spano 
 
 Hungry? Pull Over. Here’s Your Guide to the Best Bets of Roadside Foraging 

All along the roadways of America—and the world—there&apos;s figs, avocados and wild berries ripe for the picking
 July 10, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 Why Store-Bought Popsicles Drip Less 

Just in time for another scorching July day, the history of the modern popsicle - and why the store-bought ones are less drippy than the DIY kind.
 July 09, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 Meet Edith and Fanny, Thomas Jefferson’s Enslaved Master Chefs 

Monticello research historian Leni Sorensen offers an impression of what life was like for these early White House chefs
 July 09, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Jesse Rhodes 
 
 How Our Food System Could Be Radically Better in 2032 

Fast forward 20 years. How will we get our food? What delicacies will stock our fridges and appear on restaurant menus? Will our diets be significantly different, or will we have simply found new things to stuff in yet-undiscovered pockets of our pizzas? Andrew Purvis of Green Futures Magazine ponders the question, with an optimistic slant: [...]
 July 07, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 The Tallest, Strongest and Most Iconic Trees in the World 

Its bark is fire resistant. Its fruit is edible. It scoffs at the driest droughts. It shrugs, and another decade has passed. It is the baobab tree, one of the longest-living, strangest looking plants in the world
 July 05, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 How Maker Culture is Reshaping Retail Design 

A San Francisco coffee shop pulls back the curtain to expose the process behind each cup served in their expansive warehouse space
 July 05, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Sarah C. Rich 
 
 Doctoring the Dog: The Stunt that Launched Nathan’s Famous Stand on Coney Island 

The hot dog eating contest is Nathan&apos;s claim to fame now, but in 1916, vacationers to the New York City landmark needed something more appealing to convince them to eat a cut-rate frankfurter
 July 03, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Peter Smith 
 
 A Midsummer Night’s Surströmming 

The salty Baltic herring ferment inside a sealed can thanks to salt-loving, anaerobic bacteria that produce distinctive organic acids found in sweat and rotting butter
 June 29, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Peter Smith 
 
 Mom Keeps Kid Out of Cookie Jar, Forever 

Should you raise a sugar-free baby? One mother makes a case for this radical move.
 June 28, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 Cork Trees: Soft-Skinned Monarchs of the Mediterranean 

A cork tree stripped of its bark will be harvested again in nine years—if people are still using cork by then
 June 28, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 Mining an Oyster Midden 

The Damariscotta River was an epicenter of oyster shucking between 2,200 and 1,000 years ago
 June 28, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Peter Smith 
 
 Not All Calories Are the Same, Says Harvard Study 

A new Harvard study challenges the traditional understanding of calories, postulating that it’s all about quality and not quantity. For those looking to lose weight, the source of those calories is more influential than the sheer number. ABC News reports on the results: The kind of calories the body gets may affect how efficiently people [...]
 June 27, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 Coffee Pods, An Instant Classic 

Single-serving coffee pods are the most recent form of instant coffee. Its history is much shorter than the espresso shot, though in its own way, just as inventive
 June 27, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Jimmy Stamp 
 
 The Hunt for a Bottle of Asturias Cider and the Stories of More Drinks From Northern Spain 

In this part of Europe, a glass of rioja is nice, but nothing beats apple cider, a way of life
 June 27, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 Things That Are Surprisingly New: Forks, Lunch, Huge Drinks 

Who knew that there existed a time when some of our staples of modern eating habits — the use of forks, the existence of lunch, and, unfortunately, the ubiquitous super-sized drinks found at every fast food chain around the U.S — did not exist. Forks are taken for granted in modern western eating, yet relatively [...]
 June 27, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Rachel Nuwer 
 
 The Once and Future Coffeehouses of Vienna 

Coffee is one of Vienna&apos;s legacies, but how will the city hold onto its past while adapting to the changing culture? New furniture may be the answer
 June 21, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Jimmy Stamp 
 
 Spain: Of Sun, Siestas — and Salmon? 

About a dozen Spanish streams support native runs of Atlantic salmon, but anglers are deeply divided about how to fish for them
 June 21, 2012 | 
 
 
 By Alastair Bland 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next» 
 
Advertisement
 
 
 Related Video 
 
 
 A Taste of Tradition 

 (23:15) 
 
 A Brief History of Chocolate 

 (01:22) 
 
 A Tomato Trail 

 (04:07) 
 
 Cupcake Presidents 

 (05:27) 
 
 Smithsonian Associates: Did New Orleans Invent the Cocktail? 

 (06:22) 
 
 
 Related Photo Galleries 
 
 
 MoMA&apos;s Counter Space Exhibit 
 
 
 Most Popular 

 Topics Articles 
 
 Hominids Fossils 
 
 The 20 Best Small Towns in America Seven Famous People Who Missed the Titanic When Did Girls Start Wearing Pink? The Top 10 Biggest Sports #Fails of All Time The 20 Best Food Trucks in the United States The Long and Winding History of the Thames The Ten Most Disturbing Scientific Discoveries Unraveling the Mysteries of the Ocean Sunfish Announcing the Winners of Our 9th Annual Photo Contest 28 Places to See Before You Die—the Taj Mahal, Grand Canyon and More 
 
 View All Most Popular» 
 
Advertisement
 

 
 View full archive Recent Issues

 
 
Jul 2012 
 
 
Jun 2012 
 
 
May 2012 
 
 
Newsletter

Sign up for regular email updates from Smithsonian magazine, including free newsletters, special offers and current news updates.

Subscribe Now
 
 
 
About Us

Smithsonian.com expands on Smithsonian magazine&apos;s in-depth coverage of history, science, nature, the arts, travel, world culture and technology. Join us regularly as we take a dynamic and interactive approach to exploring modern and historic perspectives on the arts, sciences, nature, world culture and travel, including videos, blogs and a reader forum.
 
Explore our Brands

 goSmithsonian.com Smithsonian Air&amp;Space Museum Smithsonian Student Travel Smithsonian Catalogue Smithsonian Journeys Smithsonian Channel 
 
 About Smithsonian Contact Us Advertising Subscribe RSS Topics Member Services Copyright Site Map Privacy Policy Ad Choices 
 
 Smithsonian Institution
	</body>
</document>
