<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006002" url="http://www.beyond.com/jobs/macy-s-state-street-chicago-il-food-service-caterer-flex-chicago-il-36991350-job.html" time="2012-07-12-22:41" support="1" score="0.005928800569837362" bingtitle="Macy&apos;s State Street Chicago IL Food - Jobs in Chicago, IL - Travel ..." webtitle="Macy&apos;s State Street Chicago IL Food - Jobs in Chicago, IL - Travel Jobs, Hospitality Jobs and Restaurant Jobs">
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>YOU&apos;VE COME TO THE RIGHT PLACE! At Panda we all share a common mission: &apos;deliver ... Fast Food Restaurant General Manager</description>
	<body>
		The Career Network ™ Sign In Join Now 
 Search 
 Jobs Companies Career Articles 
 Communities 
 Healthcare Technology Finance Accounting Sales Engineering Manufacturing Administrative Retail View All » 
 Resources 
 Featured Resume Listing Resume Distribution Service Resume Writing Help Career Consultation Continuing Education Personality Assessment Salary Calculator View All» 
 Help 
 F.A.Q. Contact Us 
 
 
 
 (Select Industry) Accounting&amp;Finance Arts, Entertainment&amp;Gaming Clerical&amp;Administrative Construction&amp;Extraction Customer Service Education, Training,&amp;Library Engineering&amp;Architecture Healthcare&amp;Medical Human Resources Information Technology Insurance Legal Services Management&amp;Business Manufacturing&amp;Production Marketing&amp;Advertising Media&amp;Communication Merchandising, Purchasing&amp;Retail Military&amp;Government Other Personal&amp;Home Services Public Relations Public Utilities&amp;Services Real Estate&amp;Building Maintenance Research Sales&amp;Sales Management Science&amp;Biotech Transportation&amp;Logistics Travel, Hospitality&amp;Restaurant Radius 40 miles 
 10 miles 20 miles 30 miles 40 miles 50 miles 60 miles 70 miles 80 miles 90 miles 100 miles 150 miles 200 miles 
 Alert Me 
 
We apologize for the inconvenience but the job you are looking for has been filled or it has been removed by the recruiter. For your reference, the original listing is shown at the bottom of this page.


 Listed below are the top 10 out of 247 listings that are in the same industry and location as the job you were looking for. To see more than 10 listings, click here to search similar jobs in Chicago, IL 

 
 
     
 
 

 
 
 
 Food Service Specialist Jul 3 
 Army National Guard - NORTH RIVERSIDE, IL US 
It&apos;s said that an army marches on its stomach. If that&apos;s the case, you can be the Soldier who keeps the Army National Guard marching on. In the Army National ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Career Opportunity in Sales and Service Management Jun 8 
 Aerus LLC - Madison, WI US 
Aerus of Madison Our locally owned franchise locations provide extraordinary opportunities for personal growth, career and financial success. Career Opportunity ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Seeking Customer Service Experts at Mariano&apos;s Fresh Market! Jun 29 
 Mariano&apos;s Fresh Market - Chicago, IL US 
Fresh opportunities coming to Chicago. Join us! Mariano&apos;s Fresh Market is opening an extraordinary new grocery store this summer on Chicago&apos;s north side!. If ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Food Preparer Jun 29 
 HMSHost - Chicago, IL US 
Summary: The Food Preparer is responsible the preparing various food products; ensuring proper food handling procedures are followed; arranging necessary supplies ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Fast Food Attendant Jun 29 
 HMSHost - Chicago, IL US 
Summary: The Fast Food Attendant is responsible for performing a variety of duties within a fast food / snack bar establishment which may include completing ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 FOOD SERVICE Jul 1 
 MARIANO&apos;S - Chicago Northwest, IL US 
Food Service MARIANO&apos;S FRESH MARKET IS OPENING A NEW LOCATION IN HOFFMAN ESTATES! Mariano&apos;s Fresh Market is hiring Customer Service Superstars at our extraordinary ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 NEW CHICAGO AREA RESTAURANT MANAGER OPENINGS - NEW RESTAURANT OPENINGS Jun 24 
 Gecko Hospitality - Chicago, IL US 
General Manager, Sous Chef / Kitchen Manager and Assistant General Manager for New Restaurant Opening Soon!!!! $43,000 $66,000 plus bonus!!! Join a Growing ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Restaurant Manager - Chicago, IL Jun 22 
 Panera - Chicago, IL US 
As a Restaurant Manager at Panera Bread you would be responsible for providing outstanding leadership to your team. You should be passionate about the industry, ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Restaurant Manager - Chicago, IL-South Suburbs Jun 22 
 Panera - Chicago, IL US 
As a Restaurant Manager at Panera Bread you would be responsible for providing outstanding leadership to your team. You should be passionate about the industry, ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email 
 Restaurant Manager - Chicago, IL-North Suburbs Jun 22 
 Panera - Chicago North, IL US 
As a Restaurant Manager at Panera Bread you would be responsible for providing outstanding leadership to your team. You should be passionate about the industry, ... View  |  Save SAVED  |  Email   

 
 
 To view more listings click here to search Travel&amp;Hospitality Jobs in Chicago, IL 


For your reference, we have included the original job posting below.

 
 

 

 
Macy&apos;s State Street, Chicago, IL: Food Service Caterer, Flex
 

 

 
 Job Number: 36991350 Company Name: Macy&apos;s Job Location: Chicago, IL US Job Category: Travel, Hospitality&amp;Restaurant   



 Macy&apos;s State Street, Chicago, IL: Food Service Caterer, Flex
 Overview: The Food Service Caterer is responsible for providing outstanding customer service at catering events. Key Accountabilities: 
 
 Adhere to company policy and State and Federal regulations regarding service of alcohol including taking all steps necessary to ensure proper age of all persons consuming alcohol served on and off premise and refusing to serve any person who appears to be intoxicated or might become intoxicated from consuming additional alcohol Follow Food Division Standards and Best Practices Execute each catering event following event plan Follow food safety standards and maintain work area and equipment in accordance with Health Department standards Follow catering steps of service and service standards Demonstrate MAGIC selling skills Educate, sample, and serve customers food products Effectively balance multiple customers and communicate customer requests or concerns to other servers and Manager on Duty Account for all product served by balancing and recording all sales Open and close each event following appropriate checklist, verifying completion with Manager on Duty prior to leaving the area Follow production guides, maintain stock levels and standards in product presentation Maintain personal hygiene and professional dress code to comply with company and Health Department standards Other duties as assigned 
 Skills Summary : 
 At least one year of catering hospitality experience is preferred but not required Ability to read, write, and interpret instructional documents such as safety rules, reports, manuals, and recipes Ability to communicate effectively with peers, managers, and the general public Must be able to use mathematics when measuring quantities. Basic math functions such as addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. Must be able to understand and compute rates, ratios, and percentages and use a calculator Must be able to follow instructions and recipes Must be able to anticipate and solve problems Extended periods of standing in areas of high heat are required. Some kneeling, stooping, crouching, or crawling may be required Must be able to move and/or lift at least 30 lbs. Must be able to work in close quarters Must possess excellent customer service skills Must be able to work effectively in a fast-paced environment Must be able to delegate tasks 
 Macy&apos;s is an Equal Opportunity Employer, committed to a diverse and inclusive work environment. 



 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Job Seekers Search Jobs Join Now Career Resources Career Articles Job Seeker F.A.Q. 
 
 Employers&amp;Agencies Hire with Beyond.com Post Jobs Search People Current Specials Applicant Tracking Employer F.A.Q. 
 
 Site Tools Terms of Service Privacy Policy Contact Us 
 
 The Beyond.com Network About Beyond.com View Communities Advertise with Beyond.com Affiliates Beyond.com Blog Careers at Beyond.com 
 
 The Career Network ™ 

Your Life. Your Career. Your Network.
 
Beyond.com is a Registered Trademark of Beyond.com, Inc.

Beyond.com Career Network©2001 - 2012 Beyond.com, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
