<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006584" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pal%27s" time="2012-07-12-23:30" support="1" score="0.02381994341912603" bingtitle="Pal&apos;s - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia" webtitle="Pal&apos;s - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>... normally called Pal&apos;s for short, is a regional fast food ... becoming the only restaurant company to receive the award. ... decorated by a Big Pal (Hamburger), Hot Dog, an Order ...</description>
	<body>
		Pal&apos;s 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Jump to: navigation , search 
 Pal&apos;s Sudden Service , normally called Pal&apos;s for short, is a regional fast food restaurant chain located in northeast Tennessee and southwestern Virginia , with stores concentrated in the Tri-Cities, Tennessee metro region. The first Pal&apos;s opened in 1956 in Kingsport, Tennessee a year after the founder of Pal&apos;s, Fred &quot;Pal&quot; Barger, attended a National Restaurant Convention in Chicago and met Ray Kroc and Fred Turner, observing the construction and equipment they used for the first McDonald&apos;s restaurant.

In 2001, Pal&apos;s won the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award , becoming the only restaurant company to receive the award. [ 1 ] 
 Pal&apos;s Sudden Service at night 
 
Contents
 
 1 Menu 2 Architecture 3 Company history 4 External links 5 References 
 

 [ edit ] Menu 

Pal&apos;s has always featured a limited menu. Items must not only be popular, but efficient to make. Lunch items are served open to close. Some of the most popular items are:

 Tea – Called &quot;Pal&apos;s Tea&quot; locally, a quart-sized cup of sweet tea. This is Pal&apos;s most popular item, served from open to close, largely because area workers can buy it in the morning and drink on it all day at work. Made using JFG brand black tea. Milkshake; Vanilla, Strawberry, Chocolate (Peanut Butter and Peanut Butter+Chocolat Mix at Pal&apos;s #1) Big Pal – A 1/3 lb hamburger on a large bun with mayonnaise, onions, lettuce and tomato. (Also with Cheese and as Double Big Pal) Sauce Burger – a standard fast food burger with &quot;sauce&quot;: a ketchup, relish, and mustard based sauce. [ 2 ] Jr. Burger – small version of the Big Pal. Frenchie Fries – French fries sprinkled with seasoning salt. Hot Dog – a hot dog bun with a weiner, mustard, onions, and chili [ 3 ] Chili Bun – a hot dog bun with chili and no weiner. Chili Burger (also as a Jr.) – 1/3 lb. cheeseburger topped with Chili Chipped Ham Sandwich – A chipped ham sandwich on the Big Pal bun. Toasted Cheese Sandwich – A Big Pal bun flipped inside out with two slices of melted cheese. 

Pal&apos;s serves Breakfast biscuits and other breakfast fast food items such as Cheddar Rounds, cheesy potatoes also popular with fry salt, plus offers the entire dinner menu in the morning. Also, during breakfast hours at all locations and all day at some locations, a cup of coffee can accompany any item on the menu.

Pal&apos;s is also noted for their health scores which predominantly run between 95-99 which are also inspected on a monthly basis by their own in-house inspectors to ensure quality and cleanliness.

 [ edit ] Architecture 

At Pal&apos;s #1, the exterior is covered with red and white tiling, and has a large red sign that is lit up every night. The neon glow shows up saying &apos;Burgers, Shakes, 19 cents (the original cost for a Pal&apos;s Burger). One of the notable features of Pal&apos;s is the architecture of the buildings. Pal&apos;s #2 has long featured a &quot; Muffler Man &quot; called Big Pal holding a hamburger on the roof. The newer Pal&apos;s restaurants are box-shaped with a tiered front decorated by a Big Pal (Hamburger), Hot Dog, an Order of Frenchie Fries and drink cup. Until recently, Pal&apos;s #2 also featured a 50&apos;s-style lighted sign. The sign was replaced because it became too expensive to operate and maintain. Originally Pal&apos;s #1 had a stone front and you didn&apos;t come inside, you had to go to a window under a cement awning.

Pal Barger created his vision of a fast food chain built on quality, speed of service and delighting every customer in 1956. Today, his vision lives in an organization that is recognized as the leading fast food chain in America based on these metrics.

Pal&apos;s Sudden Service outperforms all national burger chains in customer satisfaction, health scores, customer retention, order accuracy, drive through wait times and profitability. The company employs more than 900 people who are engaged in fulfilling Pal Barger&apos;s vision of delighting every customer – one transaction at a time.

 [ edit ] Company history 

 1956 - First Pal’s opened Kingsport # 1 1958 - Lynn Garden Pal&apos;s #2 1985 - First drive thrus open in Kingsport 1990 - Pal&apos;s #5 opened in Johnson City 1991 - Greeneville #6 and Gate City #7 1992 - Pal&apos;s Johnson City Mall #8 and Elizabethton #9 1993 - Pal&apos;s #10 Volunteer Parkway 1994 - Pal&apos;s #11 Bristol Highway 1995 - Pal&apos;s Brook&apos;s Circle #12 and Rogersville #13 1997 - Pal&apos;s Morristown #14 1998 - Pal&apos;s #15 and Big Breakfast Introduced 1999 - Pal&apos;s opens in Bristol at Exit 7 2001 - Pal&apos;s Wins Baldrige National Quality Award 2002 - President Bush presents Pal&apos;s the Baldrige Award 2003 - Two new Pal&apos;s, Gray and Blountville 2006 - Pal&apos;s opens in Jonesborough 2007 - Pal&apos;s celebrates the 20th year of the &quot;big tea&quot; 2008 - Pal&apos;s opens in Lebanon, Virginia 2008 - Founder Pal Barger is on board the MS Nautica when it is attacked by pirates in the Gulf of Aden . [ 4 ] 2009 - Pal&apos;s opens in Greeneville 2009 - Pal&apos;s introduces Razzie Tea 2009 - Neon sign at Pal&apos;s #2 taken down due to high costs of operation 2010 - Pal&apos;s opens in Norton, Virginia. It has the biggest opening in Pal&apos;s history. 2012 - Pal&apos;s introduces new 3D website http://palsweb.com 

 [ edit ] External links 

 Pal&apos;s official website 

 [ edit ] References 
 
 ^ Reuters: Pal&apos;s Sudden Service Shares Secret of its Success ^ GoTricities: For me, it&apos;s the sauce, man ^ The chili contains meat but not beans. ^ Kingsport Times-News: Pal&apos;s founder aboard cruise liner targeted by pirates 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Pal%27s&amp;oldid=496058011 &quot; Categories :
 Regional restaurant chains in the United States Fast-food hamburger restaurants Companies based in Tennessee Kingsport, Tennessee Restaurants in Tennessee Restaurants in Virginia Restaurants established in 1956 
 
Personal tools

 Create account Log in 
 
Namespaces

 Article Talk 
 


 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to Wikipedia 
 
Interaction
 
 Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact Wikipedia 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Cite this page 
 
Print/export
 
 Create a book Download as PDF Printable version 
 
 This page was last modified on 5 June 2012 at 04:13.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License ;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc. , a non-profit organization.
 Contact us 

 Privacy policy About Wikipedia Disclaimers Mobile view
	</body>
</document>
