<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006700" url="http://www.nrc.gov/reading-rm/basic-ref/teachers/unit4.html" time="2012-07-12-23:41" support="4" score="0.005787887342521753" bingtitle="NRC: Lesson Plans- Unit 4: Radioactive Waste" webtitle="NRC: Lesson Plans- Unit 4: Radioactive Waste">
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000405" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="11"/>
	<description>Think of how much trash results from just one visit to a fast-food restaurant -- from bags, to straws, to soft drink containers. Industries also have trash and ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Page Content Skip to Search Skip to Site Map Navigation Skip to Footer Links 
 Home 
 
 FAQ Glossary Facility Locator What&apos;s New Site Help Index A-Z Contact Us Browse Aloud Email Updates 
 Search NRC Report a Safety Concern 
 Nuclear Reactors 
 Power Reactors Research&amp;Test Reactors Operating Reactors Operator Licensing 

 New Reactors Advanced Reactors Operator Licensing for New Reactors 

 Nuclear Reactor Quick Links 
 Nuclear Materials 
 Special Nuclear Material Source Material Byproduct Material Med, Ind,&amp;Academic Uses 

 Source Materials Facilities Uranium Recovery Fuel Cycle Facilities Materials Transportation 

 Nuclear Materials Quick Links 
 Radioactive Waste 
 Low-Level Waste Waste Incidental to Reprocessing High-Level Waste Uranium Mill Tailings 

 Low-Level Waste Disposal High-Level Waste Disposal Storage of Spent Nuclear Fuel Transporation of Spent Nuclear Fuel 

 Radioactive Waste Quick Links 
 Nuclear Security 
 Domestic Safeguards Information Security 

 Radioactive Material Security Contact Us 
 Public Meetings&amp;Involvement 
 The NRC Approach to Open Government About Meetings Open to the Public Conferences &amp; Symposia 

 Documents for Comment Facilitating Stakeholder Involvement NRC Information Quality Guidelines Subscribe to E-mail Updates 

 Commission Schedule Public Meeting Schedule Adjudications (Hearings) 
 NRC Library 
 Basic References Document Collections ADAMS Public Documents Public Document Room Get Copies of Documents 

 FOIA&amp;Privacy Act Requests Photos&amp;Video Records Management Withholding of Sensitive Information FAQ Index 

 Electronic Hearing Docket 
 About NRC 
 The Commission Governing Legislation Plans, Budget, &amp; Performance Organization&amp;Functions Locations History Values 

 Direction-Setting&amp;Policymaking Radiation Protection Fire Protection How We Regulate Emergency Preparedness&amp;Response Public Affairs Congressional Affairs 

 International Programs State&amp;Tribal Programs Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs Employment Opportunities Contracting Opportunities Grant Opportunities Civil Rights 
 
 Print 
 Teachers&apos; Lesson Plans 
 Unit 1- Radiation Unit 2 - Uses of Radiation Unit 3 - Nuclear Reactors Energy Generation Unit 4 - Radiation Waste Unit 5 - Transportation of Radioactive Materials 
 
 
Spotlight
 Choose a Section 
 Japan Nuclear Accident–NRC Actions SONGS Steam Generator Tube Degradation NRC Safety Culture Policy Statement Radiation Protection Emergency Preparedness New Reactors Underground Reactor Pipes and Tritium For the Record 
 Home &gt; NRC Library &gt; Basic References &gt; Teachers&apos; Lesson Plans &gt;Unit 4: Radioactive Waste 
Lesson Plans- Unit 4: Radioactive Waste
 Classroom Activities 
 The Cloud Chamber Using a Geiger Counter Personal Radiation Dose Power Plant Diagram Boiling Water Reactor Power Plant Diagram Pressurized Water Reactor Nuclear Waste Cube 
 
 Radiation Uses of Radiation Nuclear Reactors Energy Generation Radioactive Waste Transportation of Radioactive Materials 
 
Unit 4: Radioactive Waste Time: Two hour s

 Objectives | Questions | Reference | Lesson Plan | Classroom Activities 

Time: Two hours

 Printable Version 

Objectives

A. Teacher:

 To make students aware of nuclear waste shipments and the safeguards
 in place. To help students become more familiar with the Federal agencies involved
 in waste transportation. To fully educate youngsters on nuclear waste transportation as a public
 policy issue. 

B. At the conclusion of this unit the student should be able to --

 Describe the sources, handling, and disposal of radioactive wastes
 generated by nuclear power plants. Distinguish between high- and low-level radioactive waste. Identify the agencies having oversight responsibilities in the designation
 and storage of radioactive waste. 

 Investigation and Building Background 

 1. Introduce term: 

Students have little or no accurate knowledge of radioactive waste (i.e.,
 sources, handling, and/or disposal).

 2. Resources: 

 Radioactive Waste &quot;Nuclear Reactor Concepts&quot;Workshop Manual, U.S. NRC. Department of Energy’s Yucca Mountain Web site . Backgrounder on Dry Cask Storage of Spent Nuclear Fuel . 

 3. Experiment: 

Student assembly of the nuclear waste cube . In the U.S. one person&apos;s
 share of high-level radioactive waste from nuclear power plants for a 20-year period could be placed inside the cube. This is the amount
 of waste that would be left over after all stable materials had been recycled.

 4. Generalizing: 

Radioactive waste is material that is radioactive that is no longer needed
 at the plant and can be disposed of.

 

Questions

 Would a small leak of radioactive waste from a nuclear repository
 be detected? Why or why not? How would immediate detection of even a very small leak of radioactive
 waste differ from leak detection of other types of industrial toxic
 wastes? Why are there special sites for disposal of low-level wastes? Why have some States formed coalitions to support a single nuclear
 waste site that would serve several States? Why is there a controversy over the selection of a high-level nuclear
 waste disposal site? How would it affect health care in your State (e.g., Maryland) if there
 were no low-level waste disposal sites available? Are special packaging containers built to protect the contents or
 keep the contents from getting in contact with the environment? How are liquids processed to remove radioactive impurities? 

 

Reference

 The Harnessed Atom , Teacher&apos;s Edition, U.S. Department of
 Energy.

 

Lesson Plan

Greeting...

Today we&apos;re going to look into waste -- generally speaking and specifically -- nuclear. This subject, like everything else in life, generates a lot of
 questions. I&apos;m sure you have a few about the topic. Hopefully, we&apos;ll find
 answers to most if not all of your questions.

 What is waste? 

In the process of day-to-day living, people produce garbage and trash.
 Think of how much garbage and trash your family collects in a day or
 in a week. Think of how much trash results from just one visit to a fast-food
 restaurant -- from bags, to straws, to soft drink containers.

Industries also have trash and garbage as a result of doing or making
 something. The leftovers of an industrial process are called wastes.

Like all industries, nuclear power plants produce waste. One of the main
 concerns about nuclear power plants is what to do with the waste. This brings us to our second question.

 Why is this such a problem? 

The problem with nuclear power plants is not the amount of waste
 they make, which is quite small compared to other industries.
 The problem is that some nuclear power plants wastes are radioactive. Nuclear
 power plants are not the only producers of radioactive waste. A large
 amount of radioactive waste is produced by hospitals and other industrial
 processes. The central concern is that all producers of radioactive waste
 must ensure that special care is taken to dispose of these materials and
 also to protect workers, the public, and the environment.

The way it is disposed of depends on how radioactive the waste is, the
 half-life of the waste, and the physical and chemical form of the waste.
 These considerations help identify appropriate ways for disposing of nuclear
 waste.

 Introduce the class activity&quot;nuclear waste cube.&quot; [ Classroom Activity 6 ]

Student assembly of the nuclear waste cube . In the U.S. one person&apos;s
 share of high-level radioactive waste from nuclear power plants for a period
 of 20 years could be placed inside the cube. This is the amount of waste
 that would be left over after all stable materials had been recycled.

Radioactive waste is material (solid, liquid, and/or gaseous) that is
 no longer needed at the plant, has no further value, and can be disposed
 of. Let me give you some examples of radioactive waste:

 Radioactive fission products inside the cladding of fuel assemblies Radioactive activation products that are collected in filters and
 demineralizers in the reactor cleanup systems Paper towels or rags used to wipe up radioactive water Contaminated pieces of equipment The pressure vessel, plumbing, and containment structures from a closed
 or decommissioned facility 

Radioactive waste from nuclear power plants is classified as being
 either low- or high-level waste.

 What is low-level waste? 

Waste that is only slightly radioactive and gives off small amounts of
 radiation is called low-level waste. Low-level waste is produced in virtually
 every state by hospitals, universities, companies, and nuclear energy
 plants. This waste includes such things as filters, cleanup rags, lab
 supplies, and discarded protective clothing.

Most radioactive waste from a nuclear power plant is low-level. The principle
 sources of low-level radioactive waste are the reactor coolant (water)
 and the components and equipment that come in contact with the coolant.
 The major constituents of low-level waste from a nuclear power plant are
 activation products and a very small percentage of fission products (if
 any leaks out of the fuel rods). It does not include used fuel from the
 reactor fuel assembly.

Because it emits only small amounts of radiation, low-level waste is
 usually sealed in steel drums and buried at special sites. Today, most
 of the low-level waste from nuclear power plants in the U.S. is disposed
 of at two sites: Barnwell, South Carolina, and Hanford, Washington. Drums
 containing low-level waste are placed in specially designed trenches and
 are covered with at least six feet of soil and packed clay. To ensure that
 the materials remain undisturbed, the trenches are constantly monitored
 to detect radiation.

In this transparency, we see a typical radioactive
 waste handling system . (Note: Trace the waste paths.) 

The radioactive particles in low-level waste emit the same types of radiation
 that everyone receives from nature. Most low-level waste fades away to
 natural levels of radioactivity in months or years. Virtually all of it
 diminishes to natural levels in less than 300 years. In the U.S. there
 is strict regulation of low-level waste.

The U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, for example, licenses many of
 the facilities that produce low-level waste, including nuclear power plants.
 It also regulates low-level waste disposal. The U.S. Environmental Protection
 Agency, on the other hand, develops general standards to protect the public
 from radiation.

The U.S. Department of Energy coordinates national planning with the
 states for managing low-level waste.The U.S. Geological Survey offers
 technical assistance with studies of hydrology and geology of proposed
 sites.

Legislation passed by Congress requires state governments to be responsible
 for disposing of the low-level waste generated in their states or for
 joining a regional compact. State governments are also responsible for
 selecting and licensing a site according to Federal standards and monitoring
 its operation.

 What is high-level waste? 

Waste from power plants that is highly radioactive is called high-level
 waste. For example, about 99 percent of high-level waste from
 commercial nuclear power plants comes from used or spent nuclear fuel
 (uranium pellets inside metal fuel rods) that has released much of its
 energy. Certain changes take place in the fuel during the fission process.

Most of the fragments of fission -- the pieces left over after the atom
 has split -- are radioactive. Over time, these trapped fission fragments
 reduce the efficiency of the chain reaction. So, about every 18 months
 or so, the oldest fuel assemblies, which have already released their energy,
 are removed and replaced with fresh fuel.

Fuel that has been removed from the reactor is called spent fuel. Spent
 fuel is highly radioactive, and this radioactivity produces a lot of heat.
 Spent fuel, after being removed from the reactor, is stored at nuclear
 plant sites in steel-lined, concrete vaults filled with water (or in dry
 storage casks that are air cooled). The water cools the used fuel and
 acts as a shield to protect workers from radiation.

During storage, the spent fuel cools down and also begins to lose most
 of its radioactivity through radioactive decay, which we&apos;ve already discussed.
 In three months, for example, the spent fuel will have lost 50 percent
 of its radiation; in one year it will have lost about 80 percent; and
 in 10 years it will have lost 90 percent. Nevertheless, because some radioactivity
 remains hazardous for thousands of years, the waste must be carefully
 and permanently isolated from the environment.

While storage on site has been environmentally safe, what is needed today
 is a permanent disposal site, or repository, for existing and future high-level
 waste. To date, scientists around the world agree that deep underground
 disposal is the way to solve the high-level waste storage problem.

In fact, deep underground geologic repositories, have been endorsed by
 independent scientific organizations such as the National Academy of Sciences. [Instructor
 might wish to identify these organizations.] 

In 1982, the U.S. Congress passed the Nuclear Waste Policy Act. This
 law set up a schedule for selecting a site, constructing, and operating America&apos;s first high-level nuclear waste storage facility. In 1987, Congress directed DOE to explore Yucca Mountain for
 a repository. In February 2002, DOE recommended that Yucca Mountain be
 developed as such a use.

However, before the site can be approved, or a repository built and operated,
 there must be scientific proof that public health and safety will be protected
 for thousands of years. The facility must meet strict safety requirements
 of the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Additional oversight would
 be provided by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, the State of
 Nevada, and a Technical Review Board appointed by the President of the
 United States.

This high-level waste will most likely be converted into a ceramic material
 that will not rust, melt, or dissolve, even over very long periods. This ceramic waste will then be sealed in heavy metal canisters
 which will be buried deep underground in solid rock formations. Repositories
 may be located in stable, dry types of rock formations because it is absolutely
 necessary that radioactive substances do not leak into underground water.

However, before the site can be approved, there must be scientific proof
 that public health and safety will be protected for thousands of years.
 The facility must meet strict safety requirements of the Nuclear Regulatory
 Commission. Additional oversight will be provided by the Environmental
 Protection Agency, by the state of Nevada, and a Technical Review Board
 appointed by the President of the United States.

Nuclear energy, a powerful force that should never be treated lightly,
 requires a high degree of professional and technical care. But neither
 should its risks be exaggerated. The technology exists to isolate high-level
 waste safely and responsibly, without harm to humans or the environment.
 Creating a permanent repository will help ensure that. And, with the help
 of nuclear energy, America will have clean, abundant electricity in the
 years ahead.

Answers to Questions from Radioactive Waste Unit Outline:

 1. Q: Would a small leak of radioactive waste from
 a nuclear repository be detected? Why or why not? A: Yes, radiation can be detected with devices similar
 to and including Geiger counters. 2. Q: How would immediate detection of even a very
 small leak of radioactive waste differ from leak detection of other
 types of industrial toxic wastes? A: Because radioactivity can be easily detected with Geiger
 counters, it would be easier to detect than most other hazardous or
 toxic wastes. Leaks of hazardous or toxic wastes other than radioactive
 wastes are often detected by smell, color, or sensitive chemical analytical
 methods which take time to perform. 3. Q: Why are there special sites for disposal of
 low-level waste? A: Because it must be isolated from the environment. 4. Q: Why have some states formed compacts to support
 a single nuclear waste disposal site that would serve several states? A: The Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act passed by
 the U.S. Congress in 1980 requires each State to provide for disposal
 of the low-level waste produced within its borders. 5. Q: Why is there a controversy over the selection
 of a high-level nuclear waste disposal site? A: Because the waste that will be stored in these sites
 is highly radioactive and will remain so for thousands of years, many
 people don&apos;t want it located near them. They are worried that some
 of the radioactive material may somehow get (leak) into the environment. 6. Q: How would it affect health care in your State
 (e.g., Maryland) if there were no low-level waste disposal sites available? A: If no low-level waste site is available, radioactive
 materials may not be used in the state. 7. Q: Are special packaging containers built to protect
 the contents or keep the contents from getting in contact with the
 environment? How are containers or a burial site designed to prevent
 the contents from entering the environment? A: They are designed to keep the contents from getting
 in contact with the environment. 8. Q: How are liquids processed to remove radioactive
 impurities? A: a. filtering
b. routing through demineralizers
c. boiling off the water and leaving the solid impurities to be processed
 as solid waste
d. storing the liquid to allow the radioactive material to decay 

 Classroom Activity 6
Nuclear Waste Cube 

Photocopy the nuclear
 waste cube activity handout for use with this lesson.

 Unit
 3: Nuclear Reactors/Energy Generation Top 
 Unit
 5: Transportation of Radioactive Materials 
 Page Last Reviewed/Updated Thursday, March 29, 2012 
Home

 News Releases Event Reports ADAMS Open Gov Students&amp;Teachers Photos&amp;Video 
 
About Us

 Strategic Plan Budget&amp;Performance Perf&amp;Accountability Rept History of the NRC Employment NRC Ethics Agency Status Contact Us 
 
Popular Documents

 Info Digest Factsheets&amp;Brochures Forms Electronic Submittals NRC Reports–NUREG NRC Regulations–10-CFR Inspection Reports Plain Writing Enforcement Actions 
 
Stay Connected

 Blog Flickr Twitter YouTube RSS 
 Regulations.gov USA.gov Recovery FOIA No Fear EEO Inspector General Site Map Accessibility Privacy Policy Site Disclaimer For Employees
	</body>
</document>
