<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006456" url="http://spectrum.diabetesjournals.org/content/20/1/33.full" time="2012-07-12-23:23" support="1" score="0.006968854972554359" bingtitle="Food Practices and Preferences in Youth With Diabetes" webtitle="Food Practices and Preferences in Youth With Diabetes">
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="205"/>
	<description>... to enhance ease of use and accuracy of data collection. ... frequency of using measuring utensils, and knowledge of ... Neumark-Sztainer D, Fulkerson JA, Hannan P: Fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Diabetes Spectrum 

 Skip to main page content 

 Home Current Issue Archive Contact Us Subscribe Help Alerts Podcasts 
 Search GO Advanced Search » User Name Password Sign In 
 
 Advertisement 
Food Practices and Preferences in Youth With Diabetes
 
 Nedra K. Christensen , PhD, RD , Elaine Boswell King , MSN, APRN, CDE , Sherrie Hardy , RD, MS, CDE and Roxane Pfister , MS 

 Address correspondence to Nedra K. Christensen, PhD, RD, Utah State
 University, Nutrition and Food Science Department, 1213 E. 2100 S., Salt Lake
 City, UT 84106 
 Next Section 
Abstract

 Objectives. To determine where children with type 1 diabetes eat and
 with whom, how foods are prepared, their favorite foods, and food issues or
 conflicts regarding both portioning foods and types of food eaten and to
 examine the multiple factors that influence food intake in this
 population.

 Methods. Parent-child pairs ( n = 299) completed a
 questionnaire that focused on where and with whom children eat and how their
 food is prepared. χ 2 tests and ANOVA were calculated to
 determine differences between child and parent responses.

 Results. As reported by parents, children (78%) eat meals at home
 with the family 4–6 or more meals per week; 21% eat at home alone
 4–6 or more meals per week; 27% eat at fastfood restaurants 2–3 or
 more meals per week, and 72% eat school lunch 2–3 or more times per week
 (58% almost every day). Confusion regarding portion skills was reported by
 13%, 52% measure by “eye balling” only (estimating portions
 sizes), and 47% would like more information on portioning. Among parents, 37%
 reported disagreements with children over choices of food, and 28% reported
 disagreements over food portion sizes; 5% did not care about food portioning
 at all. Cooking from scratch was reported by 71% to occur ≥ 4 times per
 week (out of 21 meals per week), and 65% reported cooking prepackaged meals at
 least 2–3 times per week.

 Conclusion s. Suggestions for eating at fast-food restaurants and
 schools; food-portioning skills for home, school, restaurants, and homes of
 friends; cooking from scratch and from prepackaged foods; incorporating
 favorite foods; and reading labels on prepackaged foods should be addressed
 for effective educational sessions.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Medical nutrition therapy (MNT) is an important aspect of diabetes
 self-care management and diabetes self-care
 education. 1 The
 American Diabetes Association position statement on MNT includes the following
 goals: 1 ) attaining/maintaining optimal metabolic outcomes (glucose
 and lipid levels); 2 ) prevention and treatment of chronic
 complications of diabetes; 3 ) improvement of health through healthy
 food choices and physical activity; and 4 ) taking individual
 nutritional needs into
 consideration. 1 Choosing appropriate foods and food portion sizes is integral to achieving
 these goals, as is meeting the individual needs of clients. The Nutrition
 Subcommittee of the Diabetes Care Advisory Committee of Diabetes
 UK 2 concurs with its
 American counterpart and adds that advice in counseling must respect an
 individual&apos;s wishes and willingness to change.

Many factors influence an individual&apos;s choice of foods. Food choices and
 managing healthy eating was studied by Falk et
 al., 3 who
 categorized seven themes for healthy eating: low-fat, natural/unprocessed
 foods, balance, prevention of disease, nutrient balance, disease management,
 and weight control. Besides health considerations, other values influencing
 food choices are convenience, taste, and cultural preferences.

When considering which factors influence a child&apos;s choice of foods,
 short-term gratification may be more important than long-term health
 outcomes. 4 When
 adolescents&apos; choices of foods were
 studied, 5 the
 influences they reported were hunger, food cravings, food appeal, convenience
 of food, food availability, parental influence (culture or religion of the
 family), health benefits of food, body image, habit, cost, media, and
 vegetarian beliefs.

Because of the importance of nutrition for growth and long-term health
 promotion, nutrition programs need to be effective. Suggestions for effective
 education programs are to address a broad range of factors, including
 environmental factors such as food availability, and consideration of
 individual schedules, as well as acquiring knowledge and skills to
 appropriately choose appealing, convenient foods within homes, restaurants,
 and
 schools. 4 , 6 

Although there have been studies on nutrient consumption to help assess the
 epidemic of obesity in
 youth, 7 , 8 research is lacking on food choices, attitudes about portioning foods, and
 techniques used for cooking in the childhood or adolescent population with
 diabetes. Cole et
 al. 7 collected
 dietary recalls from 50 high school students on the Zuni Indian reservation.
 Meat, low-fiber grains, and sugared beverages were major contributors to
 adolescents&apos; total energy intakes. Soft drinks contributed 27% of total
 carbohydrate intake for females and 21% for males. Williams et
 al. 8 reported that
 in a group of 165 nondiabetic Pima Indians, the risk of developing diabetes
 was 2.5 times higher for the group consuming a western or Anglo diet instead
 of the traditional Indian diet (e.g., legumes, chili stew, tortillas, and
 squash). The influence of the food environment on preventing childhood obesity
 was reviewed by Haire-Joshu and
 Nanney, 9 with the
 conclusion that parent modeling and availability of foods in the home, school,
 and at fast-food restaurants are critical to food choices for children. These
 studies did not examine food portioning or cooking techniques for the child
 and adolescent age groups.

Diabetes educators need to learn where they should focus their efforts in
 nutrition education. Diabetes educators have limited interaction time
 (especially time reimbursed by insurance) with patients to teach the numerous
 aspects of diabetes care. It is essential that diabetes educators focus on the
 important and useful aspects of nutrition that will be helpful to improving
 diabetes control.

The purposes of this study were to identify current eating habits of youth
 with type 1 diabetes by 1 ) determining where food is eaten, how food
 portioning is conducted and by whom, how often children/adolescents eat
 traditional versus convenience foods, favorite foods eaten, and food issues or
 conflicts in the home and 2 ) examining the multiple factors that
 influence food intake in this population.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Methodology

 Questionnaire. A questionnaire was developed to determine
 favorite food choices of children with type 1 diabetes, where they eat, and
 what type of cooking techniques are used. The open-ended questionnaire asked
 by frequency category (&lt;1 per month, 1 per month, 1 per week, 2–3
 times per week, 4–6 times per week, or every day), where and with whom
 the children eat meals, how the food is cooked, and what measuring techniques
 are used. There was also an open-ended question asking for a list of favorite
 foods. Three test questions were included to assess knowledge of portion sizes
 (correct portion size to obtain a 15-g carbohydrate serving). The
 questionnaire for the child was worded to obtain information on their own
 behaviors, and the one for parents was worded to obtain information regarding
 their child&apos;s behavior.

Two nutritional epidemiologists critiqued the format of the questionnaire
 to enhance ease of use and accuracy of data collection. The questionnaire was
 then administered to 30 clinic patients in Utah to determine ease of use and
 face validity. Revisions were made to the questionnaire based on the feedback
 received to create the final form used for the study. It took approximately
 10–15 minutes for parents to complete the questionnaire and 15–20
 minutes for children to complete, unless the children needed assistance with
 reading. The questionnaire was administered to children and parents at the
 beginning of a diabetes camp session. This project was reviewed by the first
 author&apos;s institutional review board.

 Subjects. Children with type 1 diabetes and their parents
 ( n = 299) who attended summer diabetes camps in Tennessee, Utah, and
 Idaho participated in the study. Administering the questionnaire was
 incorporated into the camp check-in process, and no parent or child refused to
 complete it. A few children and their parents who arranged to come late to
 camp did not complete the questionnaire. Incorporating this study into the
 check-in process resulted in a high response rate.

The Tennessee camp was a 2-week overnight summer experience for children
 with diabetes between the ages of 9 and 15 years. The Utah and Idaho camps
 were 1-week overnight camps (four camp sessions per summer with campers
 separated by age group), with campers ranging in ages from 8 to 18 years. The
 average duration of diabetes for campers at all three locations was 5.1 ± 3.5 years, with 47% being male and 53% female.

Parents and children were asked to fill out the questionnaire in separate
 locations at camp check-in. Both parents and children were asked to fill out
 the questionnaire to compare differences in their responses. As calculated
 through the SMOG (simplified measure of gobbledygook) readability formula, the
 questionnaire was written at a 7.7-grade reading level (with long words, such
 as hypoglycemia, increasing the reading
 level). 10 This
 knowledge prepared the researchers in advance to be ready to help younger
 children complete the questionnaire if required.

Counselors at the camps also filled out the questionnaire. Counselor ages
 ranged from 16 to 41 years, with a mean of 18.25 years and a median age of 17
 years ( n = 39, with 35 having diabetes). This counselor group was to
 serve as a control group to compare the effect of age on the response to
 questions. However, the sample size was small, and statistical comparisons
 were not possible to calculate.

 Statistics. The questionnaires were matched for parent and
 child and were analyzed using Pearson&apos;s χ 2 calculation.
 ANOVA was conducted between geographic locations and age groups to determine
 any differences. Correlations were calculated between the knowledge of portion
 sizes and frequency of measuring foods, cooking from scratch, cooking with
 prepackaged foods, and location of eating.

 Results. The statistical analysis showed that there were no
 differences between parents&apos; and children&apos;s responses when analyzed by
 geographic location (Tennessee, Utah, and Idaho) or younger versus older age
 groups of children. Specific results, as shown in Table 1 , revealed that when
 parents and children were asked the frequency of where children eat meals, 78%
 of the parents (parents&apos; responses are listed here, but all participant
 responses are listed in the tables) reported eating meals at home with the
 family 4–6 or more meals per week, whereas 21% eat at home alone
 4–6 meals per week (43% eat alone at home 2–3 or more times per
 week). The frequency of eating at fast-food restaurants was 27% for 2–3
 or more per week, and 6% reported eating in sit-down restaurants 2–3 or
 more times per week. A high percentage of meals were eaten at school, with 72%
 eating school lunch 2–3 or more times per week (58% almost every day),
 and 34% bringing a brown-bag lunch 2–3 or more times per week (only 22%
 almost every day).


 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 Table 1. 
 Frequency of Eating at Various Locations Summarized by
 Percentages 
 
There were statistically significant differences between child and parent
 responses on the questions regarding meal frequency at home and eating at a
 friend&apos;s home, with parents reporting a higher frequency of eating at home and
 children reporting a higher frequency of eating at a friend&apos;s home. There were
 also statistically significant differences between parent and child responses
 when reporting the frequency of eating at ball parks, from vending machines,
 or at a quick stop store. The practical importance of this is unknown,
 considering that parents reported eating ≥ 1 time per week at the ball
 park, from a vending machine, or from a quick stop store only 7, 12, and 13%
 of the time, respectively.

 Table 2 lists the specific
 responses of parents to attitudes, skills, and knowledge of food portioning.
 Thirteen percent reported being confused about food portion skills, 52%
 measured by “eye balling” only (guessing portion sizes), and 47%
 perceived the need for more education on portioning. Regarding conflicts over
 food between parents and children, 37% reported fighting/disagreeing about
 types of food the child should eat, and 28% reported fighting/disagreeing over
 food portion sizes. Also, 5% of parents stated that they did not care about
 food portioning at all. There was a statistical difference between child and
 parent responses for all questions related to attitudes, skills, and knowledge
 about food portions.


 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 Table 2. 
 Self-Report of Attitudes, Skills, and Knowledge About Food Portions by
 Percentages 
 
Responses to the cooking methods question are reported in Table 3 . Among parents, 71%
 reported cooking from scratch (questionnaire examples included mashed or baked
 potatoes, broiled chicken breasts, and steamed broccoli) in the home 4 or more
 times per week (out of 21 meals per week) compared with 46% of children, and
 65% cooked prepackaged meals (examples on the questionnaire were frozen pizza,
 microwave dinners, frozen burritos, and canned soups) 2–3 or more times
 per week.


 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 Table 3. 
 Self-Report of Cooking Methods and Measuring Techniques by
 Percentages 
 
 Table 3 also lists responses
 to questions about the use of measuring tools. The following tools were used
 at least 4–6 times per week: measuring cups (39%), scales (8%), diabetes
 exchange books (21%), and label reading (88%). There was a statistical
 difference between child and parent responses for frequency of cooking from
 scratch, cooking from prepackaged foods, and reading food labels.
 Carbohydrate-counting books were mislabeled as calorie-counting books on the
 questionnaire, which resulted in both parent and child reporting infrequent
 use.

When asked how often their child with diabetes has an appointment with a
 dietitian, parents&apos; responses were: every 3 months (36%); every 6 months
 (27%); once a year (13%); one time ever (23%); and never (nutrition
 information given by doctor or nurse) (2%). There was no significant
 difference between parents and children regarding the number of times per year
 the child had an appointment with the dietitian.

Responses regarding where measuring skills are used are shown in Table 4 . When eating at home,
 parents reported that the child measures foods 97% of the time; 34% when at
 school; 40% at restaurants; and 51% of the time at a friend&apos;s home. Table 5 shows that the mother
 is the person who does the cooking at home most of the time (66%).


 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 Table 4. 
 Percentage of Parents and Children Reporting “Yes” to
 Whether the Child Measures Foods at Various Locations 
 

 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 Table 5. 
 Person in the Family Who Usually Prepares Food at Home Reported in
 Percentages 
 
χ 2 tests between 299 matched parent-to-child questionnaires
 revealed that parents reported eating more meals at home with the family. In
 contrast, the children reported eating more frequently at a friend&apos;s home, the
 ball park, out of vending machines, and at quick stop stores. Parents reported
 reading labels more frequently, more conflicts in choosing/eating various
 types of foods and in choosing portion sizes for food, and cooking from
 scratch and cooking from prepackaged foods more frequently. Parents were also
 significantly more likely to request additional education on portioning
 skills.

Counselors ( n = 39) reported more frequent use of measuring cups
 but less use of food labels than parents or children, as assessed from the raw
 data. Although the sample size for counselors was too small to include in the
 statistical analysis, responses are included in the tables. The counselor data
 are provided to show any differences (trends in raw data) that age may
 contribute in food-portioning habits and attitude differences between older
 adolescents/young adults with diabetes and younger people with diabetes.

Responding to an open-ended question, children reported their eight
 favorite foods in order of preference as pizza, chicken, noodles, potatoes,
 fruit, ice cream, spaghetti, and hamburgers. Parents listed the same favorite
 foods for their children in the same order, except ice cream was displaced to
 the end of the list.

Knowledge on portion sizes was assessed by asking for the correct portion
 size to provide 15 g of carbohydrate for rice, vanilla wafers, and potato
 chips (camp favorites). One-third–cup or 1/2-cup servings were scored as
 correct for rice, 5 or 6 as correct for vanilla wafers, and 1 oz or 15 potato
 chips as correct serving sizes for chips. Incorrect answers were 3/4 cup or 1
 cup of rice, 8 or 10 vanilla wafers, and 1/2, 2, or 3 oz of potato chips. The
 percentage of correct answers for parents was 88.5, 80.2, and 87.2% for rice,
 vanilla wafers, and potato chips, respectively. The corresponding percentage
 of correct responses for children ages 12–18 years was 77.8, 83.4, and
 77.0 %, respectively, and, for children ages 8–11 years, 61.7, 72.5, and
 66.4%, respectively. χ 2 analysis showed parents scored
 significantly higher on the portion size questions than both the older and
 younger children except for the older children on vanilla wafers. Adolescents
 scored higher, but not statistically higher, for the vanilla wafer portion
 size question. Older children scored significantly higher than younger
 children on all three food portion questions.

When asked whether the children adjust insulin for extra carbohydrate in
 their meal (use insulin-to-carbohydrate ratios and correction factors), 85% of
 the children and 90% of the parents reported that they did.

There was no correlation between the portion sizes knowledge score and
 frequency of measuring foods, cooking from scratch or prepackaged foods, or
 places of eating. There was a negative correlation between frequency of visits
 to the dietitian and increased perception of confusion regarding portion sizes
 ( r = – 0.134, P = 0.018).
 Previous Section Next Section 
Discussion

Regularly using the skill of accurate food portioning has been shown to be
 cost-effective in managing
 diabetes. 11 The
 community diabetes
 program, 11 which
 emphasized food portioning skills, label reading, and cooking skills, showed a
 significant decrease in hemoglobin A 1c and a significant cost
 savings in hospital charges according to the scale set by Gilmer et
 al. 12 

In addition to accurate portioning skills, it is also important to consider
 convenience and family influences on dietary, caloric, and carbohydrate
 intake. The results of this study were similar to one assessing the nutrient
 intake and food choices of adolescents when frequently eating at fast-food
 restaurants. 13 In
 the current study, 25% of parents reported that the child ate at a fast-food
 restaurant 2–3 times per week, which is comparable to French et
 al.&apos;s 13 study, in
 which 26% of 8th grade boys and 22% of 8th grade girls reported this habit.
 The results of French&apos;s nutrient analysis revealed that total energy intake
 was 40% higher for males and 37% higher for females, and energy from fat was
 9% higher for males and 13% higher in females when they frequented fast-food
 restaurants 2–3 times per week compared with those who seldom ate at a
 fast-food restaurant. In this study, 78% of parents and 60% of children
 reported eating at home with the family 4–6 or more times per week,
 which compares to Fulkerson et
 al.&apos;s 14 findings.
 She reported 75% of parents and 68% of adolescents in grades 7–12
 consumed family meals 3 or more times per week.

An additional reason education on food portion skills continues to be an
 important factor in diabetes education and diabetes control is that the
 frequency of snacking in children is
 increasing. 15 Children with diabetes will engage in social snacking with friends (with and
 without diabetes) more frequently than they might have 20–30 years ago.
 Using the Continuing Survey of Food Intake by
 Individuals, 15 , 16 the frequency of snacking increased from 1.56 to 1.99 times per day, and the
 caloric intake increased ∼ 150 calories per day for children ages
 2–18 years between 1977 and 1996. Snacks are encouraged in diabetes
 management and have the potential to alter diabetes and weight control.
 Results from this study included parents reporting that their child eats meals
 or snacks at the ball park at least once per week 7% of the time, from a
 vending machine 12% of the time, and at a quick stop store 13% of the time.
 Frequency and total snack calories should be considered along with the
 carbohydrate from full meals, blood glucose readings, exercise, and medication
 adjustments to achieve tight control of diabetes.

The increasing portion sizes of food offered at restaurants and in the home
 is another reason children with diabetes should be taught food portioning
 skills. The results of this survey of campers at three diabetes camps showed
 that 52% used visual estimation (eye balling) of portion sizes only. Stated in
 another format in a subsequent question, 43% of the parents reported that
 their child used a measuring cup once per week or less. The ability to
 accurately portion foods should be valued highly, considering how serving
 sizes delivered or offered at restaurants have increased. The American Cancer
 Institute commissioned a survey in 1999 (called the “Eyeball
 Method” Survey) to raise awareness of how large portion sizes had
 become. 17 Although
 restaurant portion sizes have increased from 25% to three times what they were
 a decade ago, 62% of the 1,003 respondents believed restaurant food portions
 were the same size or smaller during the specified time frame. In addition,
 80% of responders perceived that portion sizes at home were the same size or
 smaller than they were a decade before. Survey respondents were aware that the
 rate of obesity was increasing but were blind to the higher consumption of
 calories.

Data from this questionnaire were obtained from children with type 1
 diabetes and their parents, with results in frequency of family meals and the
 number of times eating at fast-food restaurants being similar to other
 reported
 studies. 13 , 14 Using this information for children with type 2 diabetes or for children with
 type 1 diabetes plus insulin resistance may also be helpful because it
 provides a better understanding of where food is eaten and with whom, the
 frequency of using measuring utensils, and knowledge of correct portion sizes.
 Certified diabetes educators should address the ease of obtaining large
 portion sizes, ease of convenience food, eating away from home (often at
 fast-food restaurants), caloric load from soft
 drinks, 5 , 7 – 9 , 13 – 15 and importance of physical activity.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Study Limitations

Data for this study were collected from a self-reported survey of eating
 behaviors. Memory of usual habits may be skewed by recall of previous teaching
 and knowledge or the desire to report good behavior. Camper data may have been
 affected by the desire to begin participation in camp activities rather than
 spend time filling out a questionnaire. The questionnaire was read to younger
 campers if there was any indication that they were having trouble answering
 the questions.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Conclusion

As children become more self-reliant, appropriate skills in diabetes
 management should be taught. Children are independently making food choices
 and food portioning decisions at school and at the homes of friends. Along
 with blood glucose monitoring and adjusting insulin for blood glucose levels
 out of target range, food portioning skills should be taught to both parents
 and children to aid in their decision-making process. Carbohydrate counting
 can only be done with accurate food portioning. Because a child or adolescent
 may value short-term gratification when making food choices over long-term
 benefits of good blood glucose control, nutrition and food education should
 include instruction and problem solving for eating at fast-food restaurants
 and schools; food portioning skills for home and at school, restaurants, and
 homes of friends; cooking from scratch and from prepackages; and reading
 labels from prepackaged food. Favorite foods and family preferences should be
 considered in educational sessions.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Footnotes

 
 Nedra K. Christensen, PhD, RD, is a professor in the Utah State
 University Nutrition and Food Science Department in Salt Lake City. Elaine
 Boswell King, MSN, APRN, CDE, is an instructor in the practice of nursing in
 the Vanderbilt Diabetes Research and Training Center in Nashville, Tenn.
 Sherrie Hardy, RD, MS, CDE, is a clinical dietitian at Primary Children&apos;s
 Medical Center in Salt Lake City. Roxane Pfister, MS, is data manager of
 epidemiologic studies at Utah State University in Logan. 
 American Diabetes Association 
 Previous Section 
References

 ↵ American Diabetes
 Association : Nutrition principles and recommendations in
 diabetes. Diabetes Care 27 (Suppl. 1): S36 –S46, 2004 ↵ Nutrition Subcommittee of the Diabetes Care
 Advisory Committee of Diabetes UK : The implementation of
 nutritional advice for people with diabetes. Diabet
 Med 20 : 786 –807, 2003 CrossRef Medline ↵ Falk LW , Sobal J,
 Bisogni CA, Connors M, Devine CM: Managing healthy eating: definitions,
 classifications, and strategies. Health Ed Behav 28 : 425 –439, 2001 ↵ Day JL : Diabetic
 patient education: determinants of success. Diabetes Metab Res
 Rev 16 : S70 –S74, 2000 ↵ Neumark-SztainerD , Story M, Perry C, Casey MA: Factors influencing
 food choices of adolescents: findings from focus-group discussions with
 adolescents. J Am Diet Assoc 99 : 929 –938, 1999 CrossRef Medline ↵ Travis T : Patient
 perceptions of factors that affect adherence to dietary regimens for diabetes
 mellitus. Diabetes Educ 23 : 152 –156, 1997 FREE Full Text ↵ Cole SM ,
 Teufel-Shone T, Ritenbaugh CK, Yzenbaard MD, Cockerhan DL: Dietary intake and
 food patterns of Zuni adolescents. J Am Diet Assoc 101 : 802 –806, 2001 Medline ↵ Williams DE ,
 Knowler WC, Smith CJ, Hanson RL, Roumain J, Saremi A, Kriska AM, Bennett PH,
 Nelson RG: The effect of Indian or Anglo dietary preference on the incidence
 of diabetes in Pima Indians. Diabetes Care 24 : 811 –816, 2001 Abstract / FREE Full Text ↵ Haire-Joshu D ,
 Nanney MS: Prevention of overweight and obesity in children: influences on the
 food environment. Diabetes Educ 28 : 415 –423, 2002 Abstract / FREE Full Text ↵ McLauaghlin G :
 SMOG grading: a new readability formula. J Reading 12 : 639 –646, 1969 ↵ Christensen NK ,
 Williams P, Pfister R: Cost savings and clinical effectiveness of an Extension
 Service diabetes program. Diabetes Spectrum 17 : 171 –175, 2004 Abstract / FREE Full Text ↵ Gilmer TP ,
 O&apos;Connor PJ, Manning WG, Rush WA: The cost to health plans of poor glycemic
 control. Diabetes Care 20 : 1847 –1853, 1997 Abstract / FREE Full Text ↵ French SA , Story,
 M, Neumark-Sztainer D, Fulkerson JA, Hannan P: Fast food restaurant use among
 adolescents: associations with nutrient intake, food choices and behavioral
 and psychosocial variables. Obesity 25 : 1823 –1833, 2001 ↵ Fulkerson JA ,
 Newmark-Sztainer D, Story M: Adolescent and parent views of family meals. J Am Diet Assoc 106 : 526 –533, 2006 CrossRef Medline ↵ Jahns L , Siega-Riz
 AM, Popkin BM: The increasing prevalence of snacking among U.S. children from
 1977–1996. J Pediatr 138 : 493 –498, 2001 CrossRef Medline ↵ Tippett KS , Cypel
 YS: Design and Operation: the Continuing Survey of Food Intakes by
 Individuals and the Diet and Health Knowledge Survey 1994-1996. Nationwide Food Surveys Rep. no. 96-1, U.S. Department of Agriculture,
 Agriculture Research Service, 1997 ↵ Prince JR : Why all
 the fuss about portion size? Designing the New American Plate. Nutr
 Today 39 : 59 –64, 2004 CrossRef Medline 
 
 CiteULike Delicious Digg Facebook Google+ Reddit Technorati Twitter 

 What&apos;s this? 
 « Previous | Next Article » Table of Contents 
 This Article 
 
 doi: 10.2337/diaspect.20.1.33 Diabetes Spectrum January 2007 vol. 20 no. 1 33-39 
 
 Abstract Free » Full Text Full Text (PDF) 
 
 Purchase Article View Shopping Cart 
 
 Services 

 Email this article to a colleague Alert me when this article is cited Alert me if a correction is posted Similar articles in this journal Download to citation manager Load patient INFORMation 
 
 Citing Articles 

 Load citing article information Citing articles via Google Scholar 
 
 Google Scholar 

 Articles by Christensen, N. K. Articles by Pfister, R. Search for related content 
 
 PubMed 

 Articles by Christensen, N. K. Articles by Pfister, R. 
 
 Social Bookmarking 

 
 CiteULike Delicious Digg Facebook Google+ Reddit Technorati Twitter 

 What&apos;s this? 
 
 
 Navigate This Article 
 
 Top Abstract Methodology Discussion Study Limitations Conclusion Footnotes References 
 
 Current Issue 
 
 Spring 2012, 25 (2) 
 
 
 
 From the Cover 

 Shared Medical Appointments: A Literature Review Evaluating a Culturally and Linguistically Competent Health Coach Intervention for Chinese-American Patents With Diabetes Nutrition FYI: Nonnutritive Sweeteners: Where Are We Today? Pharmacy and Therapeutics: Improved Disposable Insulin Pen Devices Provide an Alternative to Vials and Syringes for Insulin
 Administration 
 
 Alert me to new issues of Diabetes Spectrum 
 
 About Diabetes Spectrum Editorial Board Instructions for Authors Subscriptions Advertising&amp;Reprints ADA Mobile ADA&apos;s DiabetesPro ADA Member Directory 
 More ADA Publications 
 Diabetes Diabetes Care Clinical Diabetes ADA Clinical Practice Recommendations Scientific Sessions Abstracts Books&amp;Other Publications 
 Advertisement 
 DiabetesJournals.org 
 American Diabetes Association • National Office 1701 N. Beauregard St. • Alexandria VA 22311 
 Print ISSN: 0149-5992 Online ISSN: 1935-5548 

Copyright © 2012 by the American Diabetes Association
	</body>
</document>
