<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006120" url="http://www.wikihow.com/Eat-Healthy-on-a-Budget" time="2012-07-12-22:48" support="1" score="0.003859981259999683" bingtitle="9 Tips on How to Eat Healthy on a Budget - wikiHow" webtitle="9 Tips on How to Eat Healthy on a Budget - wikiHow">
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant; How to Eat Healthy and Excercise ... Cars and Other Vehicles; Computers and Electronics; Education and ...</description>
	<body>
		the how to manual that you can edit 
 Sign Up or Log In or Log In via 
 Follow us on Pinterest 
 Home Articles Community My Profile Edit 
 Home » Categories » Food and Entertaining » Food Preparation » Meal Planning 
 
 How to Eat Healthy on a Budget 

Edited by Jack Herrick and 15 others 
 Pin It Article Edit Discuss History 
A visit to a health food store can convince anyone that eating healthy is a luxury rather than choice. To the contrary, eating healthy does not require buying the hottest new diet food or piles of exotic fruit. Nor does eating cheaply limit you to a menu of pre-packaged pastas. The exact items that make up cheap, healthy diets vary greatly by location, but the methods to creating these diets vary little. Since most of what you pay for in food is convenience, you can save money and maintain your health by investing time and planning into your diet. 
 
 Edit Steps 
 
 1 Determine what kind of diet is healthy for you . Generally, a diverse diet that is heavily based on unprocessed plant products is healthy. Fortunately, grains, fruits and vegetables can be bought for low prices, if you know where and when to look. Potatoes and carrots, for instance, are very beneficial for most people and are often very cheap. Meat, unprocessed vegetables and eggs are the main foods you should be buying. Meat and dairy products should be treated as side dishes (or eliminated altogether) and prepared foods should be avoided. 2 Get an idea of what kinds of foods are inexpensive in your area . Check your local grocery store(s) and other food vendors such as farmers&apos; markets, bakeries, and specialty stores. For best results, explore with an educated mind and adventurous palate. Generally, foods that grow well and sell well in your area will be the cheapest. The more willing you are to substitute new foods for your regular purchases, the more likely you are to lower the total cost of your shopping list while still eating healthy. 3 Eat seasonally . Harvests come in waves, showering consumers with abundance that results in cheap prices. You&apos;ll not only save money by eating what&apos;s in season, but you&apos;ll also eat food that&apos;s fresh . Find local farmers&apos; markets and strike bargains with the farmers . Many times, they&apos;ll be thrilled to sell at a discount if you buy regularly and in bulk. 4 Invest in food storage facilities . If you&apos;re purchasing foods that are in season and you&apos;re buying them in bulk to realize savings, then you&apos;ll need to take measures to store all that food. It&apos;s best to have a cool, dark cellar or pantry as well as a large freezer for meat and vegetables. 5 Buy the least expensive variation of any type of food . Some foods come in pre-seasoned frozen packages, in cans, and dried in bags. Establish which forms of foods are available in each store and at what prices. 6 Stop eating out . On those rare occasions that you do go out to eat, choose the simplest item on the menu, which is often the cheapest, too. Eat only half or one third of what is served (most restaurant portions are enormous) and take the rest home to eat later, combined with healthy side dishes. 7 Learn to cook from scratch . Cooking from scratch is the cheapest (and best) way to eat. Get in the habit of using leftovers. Manage your refrigerator: never let anything go bad. Eat it or use it as an ingredient in a sauce, casserole, or soup. For example, old lettuce can be chopped and put into a soup, old salsa can be added to a curry, and old milk can be turned into a quiche. (Of course, don&apos;t use anything that has actually gone sour or rancid!) Make your own pasta. 8 Use greater quantities of cheap food than of expensive food in cooking . Use a base of enriched or whole-grain rice, whole-wheat pasta or bread, or cooked oats to provide cheap, healthy bulk to more expensive, flavorful foods. For example, you can use less beef in some chili recipes by halving the amount of ground beef called for and adding water and instant plain oats instead. Be original and try your own variations. 9 Cut down on the amount of meat you consume . Meat is one of the most expensive food items you can buy, so by going meatless once or twice a week, you can save a lot of money. Meatless Monday is a national public health campaign and their site has a bunch of meatless recipes that you can try. 

 
 
 Edit Video Demonstration 
 
Eating healthy on a budget, as demonstrated by Natalie.

 
 
 Edit Tips 
 
 If it&apos;s in a box or in a metallic bag, don&apos;t buy it. Consider giving up dairy products. Not only are they expensive, but they are also suspected to be associated with chronic conditions and diseases. If you can get your calcium elsewhere, it&apos;ll likely benefit both your health and your wallet. Replace soda with tap water. If you prefer, you can also purchase an inexpensive water filter that will provide you with gallons of the same quality water that is found in bottles. Make your own snacks and bring them with you whenever you go out, along with a bottle of water. To save time set aside one day a week and cook in bulk. Then get creative and package it in a way you would buy at the store. 

Examples: Put a meal on a three portion dish cellophane it and freeze it for a quick TV dinner later. Cook waffles or pancakes ahead of time and freeze them, later you can toast them like Ego&apos;s. Pre-cook many of your different foods, then seal them so that you can heat them up later. Pop large amounts of popcorn on the stove (not the microwave kind the kernels are more expensive) and store in individual sandwich bags for a grab and go snack.

 Learn to substitute. Often home cooked meals do not get cooked because ingredients are missing. If you are running short on butter learn the appropriate water-to-Crisco substitute instead. Keep powdered milk for cooking purposes or invest in boxed milk that stays fresh on the shelf. (In dire cases of need we have used coffee creamer in place of milk for cooking; works fine and you will not know the difference.) You will never know what will not work until you try it out. Soon you will find plenty of frugal alternatives to common cooking ingredients. If all you have is elbow noodles and you want to make spaghetti, try it out. There are no laws against using alternatives -- you might discover that you like it more! The web is a plethora of information. If you don’t know what to try Google it! Book mark pages like http://hillbillyhousewife.com/ 

 
 
 Edit Warnings 
 
 In order to eat healthy on a budget, you must sacrifice convenience, which means you&apos;ll have to spend a lot more time shopping around and cooking than others do. You can&apos;t have it all! 




 
 
 Edit Related wikiHows 
 
 How to Cook Healthily How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant How to Eat Healthy and Excercise How to Choose Healthy Snacks How to Eat Healthy on Vacation Dilute Canned Soup How to Shop for Healthy Foods How to Maintain a Budget for Personal Use 

 
 
 Edit Sources and Citations 
 
 hillbillyhousewife.com 
 
Articles for You to Write
 Here is a list of suggested articles that have not yet been written. You can help by researching and writing one of these articles. To get started writing one of these articles, click on the red link of a title below.


 How to Buy Restaurant Food in Bulk How to Buy and Sell at Farmers&apos; Markets How to Make Pancakes From Scratch Without Milk How to Buy Freeze Dried Foods in Bulk How to Create Frugal Recipes 
 
Article Info
 
Last edited:
 April 27, 2012 by Jmuddy95 

Categories:
 Meal Planning 

Recent edits by: Narashiman , Teresa , Tryme2 ( see all )

In other languages
Deutsch:  Wie man sich günstig gesund ernährt 
 
Article Tools
 Share this Article: Tweet 
 
 Discuss Print Email Edit Send fan mail to authors 
 + Embed this: Republish this entire article on your blog or website. 


 Thanks to all authors for creating a page that has been read 28,728 times. 
 
Was this article accurate?

 Yes No 
 

 Write An Article Random Article Follow wikiHow on facebook 
Related Articles

 Cook for Just Yourself Make April Fool&apos;s Food Do Once a Month Cooking Make Homemade Food 
 
 Featured Articles 

 Make a Baby Sling Teach Kids to Garden Recognize a Potentially Abusive Relationship Throw a Lego Party (for Adults) 
 
Meet a Community Member
 
Meet Twoscompany , a community member from California who&apos;s been writing articles, patrolling recent changes, and helping new wikiHow members for over a year. Her favorite thing about wikiHow? &quot;The awesome community!&quot; Her proudest achievement thus far is having become a New Article Booster , which requires the skills to make great edits like this .
 
 Join The Community 
 
 - collapse Things to Do 

 Write an Article Edit this Article Request a New Article Answer a Request Login for more! 

 + expand Places to Visit 

 Recent Changes Forums Community Portal 
 
Follow Us On...

 
 
 
the how to manual that you can edit

 Home About wikiHow Terms of Use RSS Site map 
 

Explore Categories
 
 Arts and Entertainment Cars and Other Vehicles Computers and Electronics Education and Communications Family Life Finance and Business Food and Entertaining Health Hobbies and Crafts Holidays and Traditions Home and Garden Other Personal Care and Style Pets and Animals Philosophy and Religion Relationships Sports and Fitness Travel wikiHow Work World Youth 
 All text shared under a Creative Commons License . Powered by Mediawiki. 
 x 
Thank Our Volunteer Authors.

Give this article a +1.
	</body>
</document>
