<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006041" url="http://www.collegehumor.com/girl/6547610/chelsea" time="2012-07-12-22:43" support="1" score="0.0019408633377751053" bingtitle="Chelsea is the Cute College Girl for September 19, 2011 - CollegeHumor" webtitle="Chelsea - CollegeHumor Girl">
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="134"/>
	<description>Which fast food restaurant is sexier? Taco Juan&apos;s is a sexy Latin ... Maru hiding in boxes What&apos;s your favorite Salman ... I wait until you throw the first punch and duck to ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Videos 
 All Recent Video Playlists Most Viewed Sketch Comedy TV/Movies Originals All Originals Sketch Celebrities Animation Jake and Amir Troopers Hardly Working Very Mary-Kate Dinosaur Office The Six 
 x Pictures 
 All Recent Picture Galleries Most Viewed TV/Movies Categories Animals Art Cars College Epic Facebook Food Foreign Gross Holidays Nerdy People Politics Pop Culture Pranks Relationships Religion Sexy Signs Sports The Internet Words WTF Girls Cute College Girl Hottest College Girl 
 x Articles 
 All Recent Most Viewed TV/Movies Columns CollegeHumor Interview The Graphic Truth Caption Contest TLDNR Exclusive Leaks Axe Cop Almost Reading HumorUs The Troll 
 x uPick 
 uPick Categories Beach Rants News .GIFs WTF Fail Win Classroom Screencap Rough Love Text Mess Pet Stories Jokes Idiotech Work Sucks Roommate Confessions Polidicks Pranks I Fought the Law 
 x Politics 
 Electoral CollegeHumor Political Timeline Election Cheat Sheet 
 More 
 More CollegeHumor Recent Toplists Surveys Topics CH Live Tour Best of CH CH LiveCast Hotlinks TV/Movies Stalk Us Facebook Twitter Youtube CH Staff Blog Subscribe (RSS) Recent Videos CH Originals Recent Pictures Recent Articles 
 x 
 Submit↑ 
 Sign in | Sign up | 
   Signing in... 
Sign in to CollegeHumor
 

 Use Your CollegeHumor Account Forgot your password? Use Your Facebook Account 
You&apos;ll also be able to post your CollegeHumor activity to your Facebook feed.
 Not registered? Create an account Signing in via Facebook Connect... 
 Cute College Girls 
 
 Chelsea from Brooklyn Park, MN

 School: University of Minnesota, Twin Cities Year: Junior Major: Spanish
 1 / 8 Start slideshow 
 
 See More Cute College Girls Like this Girl Share this Girl Share on Tumblr 43 Share on Facebook Tweet Email to a friend URL http://www.collegehumor.com/girl/6547610/chelsea Close 
 Send this page to a friend 
 

 
 Your Name 
 Your Email 
 Friends&apos; Emails (Separate multiple addresses with commas) 
 Send 
 
Get to know Chelsea
 What are some pick up lines that work? What definitely doesn&apos;t work? No pick up lines work unless your willing to pay for her romantic services, sorry to inform you. Tell us an original joke. Isn&apos;t that your job? How many pushups can you do - real ones, not those fake &quot;I&apos;m a girl so I can do them on my knees&quot; pushups? About 50 if i&apos;m motivated. Have you ever made a guy cry, why? Oh yes. I once threw an unfortunately misplaced kick in a sparring match with a boy when I was younger. Poor thing. What&apos;s your favorite song to sing in the shower? Birdhouse in Your Soul by They Might Be Giants If you were to dance, would you do it like no one was watching? That depends...are people watching? Underwear choice: Thong What&apos;s your REAL hair color? Brunette If you could live anywhere, where wouldn&apos;t it be? Saudi Arabia Favorite Smell: The smell of people grilling outside :) Least favorite band: Not really a band... but Kesha can go die. How do you get to the highway from here? Take a left on Brookdale Dr. and it&apos;ll be the first road you come to. Weirdest dream: I got turned into a vampire. I was generally upset to learn this until I was given the opportunity to kill Hilary Duff. What would you do with 10,000 dollars? Pay off my student loans! Describe your perfect date. A good concert followed by dinner and then my place for...a movie ;) What&apos;s one thing all guys do that they shouldn&apos;t? Dance rape girls at clubs. It isn&apos;t very gentlemanly to grab me by the waist and put your junk in contact with my backside before introducing yourself. What&apos;s worse on a guy, yellow teeth or BO? Neither will get you far. Worst state in the union: Texas Let me guess, you&apos;re a tomboy right? Why are you lying to me? Let me guess, a tomboy burned you right? Why are you projecting onto me? What&apos;s the funniest thing in the world to you? Freshman hipsters How much money is in your savings account? Around $1,000 I believe Favorite look on a guy: Any guy who works on their &quot;look&quot; is trying to hard. If I can see you a lot of money/time on your outfit and man-cessories, i&apos;m not interested. What&apos;s your beauty secret? I use a tablespoon of apple cider vinegar in my hair during my shower about twice a week. It makes my hair feel like silk :) Snuggling, spooning or butterfly kisses? All of the above please Most awkward sex move: Crab walk Funniest sex term: Santorum Favorite position. For sitting: I very much enjoy &quot;sitting&quot; in the down dog position. Would you rather have you back rubbed or your hair played with? Back rubbed. Quit messing with my hair! Do you fart? Who told you? What&apos;s the worst movie you ever paid to see in theaters? The Happening What is your favorite online video? Sassy Gay Friend What is your favorite 80&apos;s song? None of them What do you get on your pizza? All meat! What Disney character would you be and why? Pocahontas. F*ck you, thats why. What game show do you think you would do the best on and why? Legends of the Hidden Temple because I watched that shit daily as a child. What is your favorite superhero movie? All of the X Men movies and V for Vendetta if that counts What is the grossest thing you ever ate? Your mothers cupcakes Have you ever voted for President? For American Idol? No and No Describe your fantasy wedding. If it&apos;s too girly you lose. I&apos;d like to get married in Spain. Thats my only preference. Is it ever okay for the girl to be the big spoon? Sure, whatever gets you off! What&apos;s your biggest fear that isn&apos;t something boring like spiders? Having a limb severed or being burned alive. What&apos;s the most embarrassing song you know all the words to? Any stupid Kesha song that repeatedly plays at work. What is your favorite kind of gum and why do all girls fall for dick heads? Juicy Fruit and why do guys fall for ditsy skanks? How many chicken nuggets could you eat in one sitting? That all depends on the incentive for eating a larger than average amount. Breast implants, for or against? For them if you want them I suppose. If it was legal and socially acceptable, would you try human meat? I&apos;d probably try it if I could eat Michelle Bachmann. I&apos;m sure it&apos;d taste awful...but nothing tastes better than justice. If you had to eliminate one food group, you could never eat it again, which one would you choose? Vegetables, duh What would be your favorite part about being a guy if you were one? I never stop hearing about the benefits of a penis. If the two short sides of a right triangle are three and four what is the length of the longest side? Your mom What is the closest you&apos;ve ever been to death? Pre-conception What is your favorite jerky and why? Buffalo jerky. Mostly &apos;cause I just made some. What is the earliest time of day you&apos;re ever started drinking and why? Me drink? I&apos;m 20. That would be illegal, my good sir. What&apos;s the most awkward sexual experience you&apos;ve ever had? I&apos;m in my dark place at the moment, i&apos;ll tell you later. Which of your boobs do you like better? Lefty!!! If you could be any insect (excluding a butterfly) what would you be? PRAYING MANTIS! You have to choose one state in the U.S. to get rid of, which one? Texas Describe your ideal Sunday morning. Sleep in late, make poptarts and watch an unhealthy amount of cartoons until reality starts to become a difficult concept to grasp. You have to pitch a completely original show to a huge network. Go. An astronaut is given the mission of finding planets capable of sustaining life and planting the elements necessary to begin life/evolution. He has the technology to design the evolution before hand and therefore becomes a god like figure to several planets in the universe. The show follows his craaaazy antics. If the moon became an independent nation what do you think would be a good name for the moon country? Moonhio or the Moonited satellites of the universe Boxers or briefs? Why? Boxer briefs, comfort AND support Can a girl look hot in glasses? No shit What would you say your secret talent is? Everyone has one. Just think. I can roar! Have you ever hooked up with someone way less attractive than you? If so, why? Yes. My gender occasionally has pity on your feeble kind. If any fantasy creature could be real, what would you choose? A Griffin! What&apos;s the fattest fat person food you like? BACON Where is the worst place to have a zit? Right above your lip What&apos;s the TV show you&apos;re most embarrassed to admit you love? 16 and pregnant...funniest shit ever Do your boobs have names? If so what are they? No but I&apos;m willing to listen to suggestions. Define &quot;antithetical&quot;. Don&apos;t cheat. Adjective: Word often used to describe your parents relationship Where was your first date with a boy? First of all, you shouldn&apos;t assumed my first date was with a boy. Second, the county fair. What is your dumper/dumpee ratio? 1:2 :&apos;( Have you ever gotten arrested? Maybe once What was your senior superlative? Senior quote? I got Toughest Girl and Most Artistic. I don&apos;t recall my quote but I think it was from Fight Club If we all had novelty gravestones, what would yours say? The cake is a lie. Come up with a raunchy color name for a new Crayola crayon. Stinky Pink What&apos;s your favorite color (keeping in mind pink isn&apos;t a real color, it&apos;s just a gay red)? Green. Gay red is so a color. Straight red has no right to spread just lies. Are you hot? No, you&apos;re just getting desperate. Be honest with yourself. What&apos;re you wearing right now, baby? Definitely not some sweet moccasins, if thats what your implying. Worst injury: I cut my hand open with a machete at work once!! What&apos;s something you do if you really like a guy? Get super shy, quiet and bashful whenever I&apos;m hanging out with him. What&apos;s up? My boy Trey is having like, this beach Beer BQ thing at his house with a couple close friends, you doing anything tonight? o.O I Like Turtles Did you ever go to a summer camp and hook-up? Sadly I&apos;ve never had such an awesome, teen movie, fantasy come true for me. Geekiest thing about you: I suppose an unhealthy love for cartoons might now count.... What&apos;s the worst/best rumor you&apos;ve ever heard about someone you know? That my friend had genital warts, lol Have you ever made out in a movie theater? Indeed When you use public restrooms do you hover over the toilet? Lol no, wtf? Hidden talent: I&apos;m a black belt Have you ever been grounded? Yea What&apos;s a good hangover cure? Emergen-C and greasy food What&apos;s something all your past boyfriends have had in common? They were mistakes What grade were you in for first base? second? third? fourth? Sophmore, Junior, Senior in Highschool Define all the bases. 1rst: Kissing 2: Side boob/fingering 3: Blowies 4: Success!! Have you ever been more attracted to a boyfriend&apos;s brother? Lol no, most of them have been small children. Worst/best Truth or Dare? Show us your boobs/hold hands with your crush for ten whole minutes Have you ever gotten/given a wedgie? Yes/yes Have you ever seen your parents naked? I have to go now. Most masculine attribute: Deep voice Do you have any tattoos? If not, what would you get? Yes, one on my shoulder. And no its not a shitty butterfly. Dream job: Nude art class modeling!! Bars or clubs? Clubs...I&apos;m only 20 sooo... Shower or bath? Shower&gt; Batch -- Shower&lt;Bubble Bath Write an excerpt from your middle school diary. Oh my, I burned that thing a long time ago. Too much angst. Have you ever ran away from a cop or campus police? Nope Current ringtone: Birdhouse in Your Soul by They Might Be Giants Have you ever shot a gun? Yes, I used to hunt geese and pheasants with my Dad. Ideal drunk food: Buffalo Wwwiiinnnnnngssss! Worst job you&apos;ve ever had: Cashier at a hardware store with a racist/sexist boss. Have you ever been fired from a job? Nope :) Movie everyone loves except you: James Bond movies Movie everyone hates but you love: Teeth Guilty pleasure (not something lame like cookie dough): shhhhh.....I sorta like dubstep What&apos;s the most epic way to die? Parachute failing during a skydiving session If you had to choose your last words right now: I don&apos;t want to die! Do you legitimately hate anyone? Yes. Rush Limbaugh Can you unwrap a Starburst with your tongue? Yes sir I have a theory that girls can&apos;t whistle, can you? Not very well, actually. But I don&apos;t promote that stereo type! When was the last time you spit? This morning after brushing my teeth. One thing you&apos;d change about yourself: I&apos;d probably like it if I spoke seven languages. Would you ever ask a guy out? No, I&apos;m too scared! Have you ever hooked up with someone you met on the internet? Ew no! Pet peeve: Vague bumper stickers Have you ever had a crush on a teacher? Yes (o^ - ^o) Do you think you could survive in the woods for a week? Shit yeah If you were stuck on a deserted island what 3 things would you bring? A pocket flint knife/swiss army knife, a machete and some sort of radioing device. What was your first ever screenname? You don&apos;t have to say it if you still use it. I honestly do not remember Most embarrassing moment: Being caught singing to a musical (quite awfully) by my mother who I thought had left. What&apos;s the girliest thing you&apos;ve ever seen a guy do in person? Get excited and squeal When are you going to tell your parents you&apos;re on birth control? They have a right to know, they raised you for God&apos;s sake! I told my mom right before I went to my senior prom. Democrat, Republican or Green? Democrat Why is that one girlfriend from high school such a stupid bitch now who you hate? Such gender stereotyped driven questions! Explain the different forms of to, two and too all in the same sentence: To define more than two words would cause me too much stress. Definitely or definately? Definitely not definately When a guy cries do you think he&apos;s weak? Depends on if he&apos;s crying over something big or small. Your football team lost is not something big. Was there ever a nerdy/geeky/smart kid in high school you thought was kind of cute but never told him? I actually ended up dating him in college. Girl&apos;s worst fear: Rape :l Do you think you could eat all of your own hair without barfing? Nnnoooo....? What&apos;s your favorite videogame, if any? Devil May Cry 4!!! How many Twinkies could you eat? Half of one before I switch to Swiss miss rolls Which celebrity do you think you look like? Kate Beckinsale What is the worst song in the world and why? She-Wolf by Shakira...do I really have to say why? Which canceled TV show would you bring back if you had the power? Boy Meets World, bitch What&apos;s the most awkward thing you&apos;ve ever said to a professor? Can I add you on facebook? What&apos;s worse, an annoying laugh or a really loud snore? Loud snore X100 What is the one thing you wish you could do better than anyone? Paint Who is the hottest female Disney character? Pocahontas How many years were there between your first kiss and your first time? I think about three? Would you rather eat a tarantula or a snake? Snake, that actually doesn&apos;t sound bad if it were cooked. What&apos;s one male fashion accessory you could do without? Those single rhinestone rings in your ears. Ew, bro. What&apos;s the grossest habit you have? I mixed chocolate syrup in Pepsi because this one restaurant I ate at did it for me. What&apos;s the meanest thing you ever said to another girl? You&apos;re fat and scratchy. What&apos;s something no one knows about you? I think theres a good reason why no one knows. What&apos;s the most original thing a guy can do on a date? If I can predict it then its no too original. What&apos;s the most uncomfortable move a guy has ever made on you? Confessing his desire to hook up with me and have it be &quot;our secret&quot; via a grammatically appalling Facebook message. Have you ever hooked up with someone directly because of Facebook? Explain. No, who do you know who does that? Do you ever just look at yourself naked in the mirror? Indeed I do. Favorite pastime Who is, in your opinion, the sexiest woman alive? Would you make out with her? Well Emma Stone was crazy hot in Easy A. I would def take a crack at that. What was the last book you read? Catcher in the Rye What clich pick-up line would work on you? Not too cliche but &quot;After spending the night with me you&apos;ll have to change your name to Moaning Myrtle&quot;. I&apos;m a sucker for HP What was your favorite cartoon as a kid? Rugrats and Recess!! Have you ever hooked-up with more than one person in a night? No What was your shortest relationship and why did you break up? A week long and because I only said yes out of pity. Who would win in a fight: Batman or Superman? Superman. Batman is just angsty. Who was your first celebrity crush? Edward Norton! Straight up, what&apos;s the scariest color? Colors can be scary? What&apos;s more important to you, your brains or your looks? Brains.... What&apos;s your favorite noise? Also, try and spell it. BWAAA BWA BWAB WA BWAAAAA *dupstep* Describe one time when you barfed. One time, I had this flue. . What&apos;s the most dangerous thing you&apos;ve ever done, and survived? Skinny dipped in a thunderstorm. The moon is beautiful, right? Would you sacrifice your favorite pet to save the moon? That is a horrible question. Describe the first time you ever made out with someone. I met this cute boy with some mutual friends and we hit it off. We all went to go watch a movie and we ended up kissing. Supposing they aren&apos;t fugly, is there anything anyone could say to you that would automatically get you to hook up with them? &quot;I won&apos;t high five my bros over my sexual conquest later&quot; How much more beautiful are you compared to other girls at your school? I don&apos;t really stand out too much lol. When was the last time you sat on Santa&apos;s lap? When I was about 5 You&apos;re hot. That&apos;s a given. But can you do math? What&apos;s the quadratic formula? X= {-b +or- SQRT(b^2-4ac)/2a} Thats college algebra. Don&apos;t be fooled, math is my worst subject. What&apos;s the most dangerous thing you&apos;ve ever done? Didn&apos;t you just ask me this? If you could live in any fantasy world, which one would it be and why? Harry Potter What would it take for you to shave your head right now? Answer in something other than money. Probably an end hunger/violence in third world countries and my tuition paid. What&apos;re your thoughts on Lindsey Lohan? She has no direct effect on my life. So thats one good thing. Why do girls use ellipsis (...) so often? Most of the time they don&apos;t even use them correctly and a comma (,) is really the punctuation they&apos;re looking for. Commas don&apos;t look as much like polka dots. Bitches love polka dots. What&apos;s your favorite Eleanor Roosevelt quotation? I&apos;d tell you but then I&apos;d have to Google it. My time is valuable. Did you ever want to be a Spice Girl, and, if so, which one? Noooo....they be crazy. You have traveled back in time to kill Hitler. What will be your method of killing him? An oven Can I cheat off of you on this test? Tilt your ScanTron toward me. You&apos;ll have to give me your pack of gum. Would you ever keep a friend around who is less attractive entirely for the purpose of making yourself look even more attractive? Nooooo..... Do you, uh, know where the, uh, weight room is? Yea its downstairs. Take a left, good luck. What dinosaur, fictional or real, was the best? Would make the best pet? Would be the tastiest? Pterodactyl on all three accounts. How many pounds is &quot;fat&quot; to a girl? Thats up to the girl to decide. Which fast food restaurant is sexier? Taco Juan&apos;s is a sexy Latin Lover Who would you rather hook up with Kermit or Elmo? Kermit has more swag Is there an age you don&apos;t want to reach? How old is too old? 29 Be honest: do you exercise? When I feel like it, but not regularly How many piercings do you have? 6 What do you want to be when you grow up? Spanish translator First CD ever bought? I think it was a P!nk album Have you ever cheated on a test/boyfriend? Test = yes, Boyfriend = no Favorite day of the week? Caturday Do you wear a helmet when you bike? Not unless its a motorcyle What&apos;s your favorite article of clothing? Shirts, def Coffee or tea? Tea Are you sugar, or spice? Spice Favorite comedian? Streeter!!! Have you ever had to use crutches? Nope Do you collect anything? Nope How many 5-year-olds could you beat in a fight? AT ONCE! I could easy take 10. People who say &quot;Reesies Piecies&quot; instead of Reese&apos;s Pieces: What up with that? Like people who say ATM Machines....sheesh Who would be your ideal mate if you were a dinosaur? Another dinosaur who, like, gets me ya know? Boxers or briefs or loin cloths? Loins cloths would switch things up a bit. If given the opportunity to travel back in time to the 80s, would you rock a pantsuit? Def What do you think is Abraham Lincoln&apos;s sexiest quality? I love how confidently he freed those slaves. Seriously. Hot. What&apos;s the thing that makes you laugh every time you see it? Maru hiding in boxes What&apos;s your favorite Salman Rushdie novel? I&apos;ve never read any. I&apos;ll check them out out though lol Would you rather date Legolas or Aragorn? Why? Aragorn...way more manly What is your snuggle policy? Are you adamantly against being big spoon? Yea I&apos;d really rather not be. Is it the size of the ship or the motion in the ocean? Both are definitely important. Sorry, but you have to be endowed and in practice. If you had to burn bras, books, or witches, which would you burn and why? Bras, because the other two would be much more tragic. Drawing from your personal experience, state why you think all girls suck except for you. You&apos;re very assuming, aren&apos;t you? If you HAD to get a tattoo on your face, what would it be of? Nyan Cat What&apos;s the best dance song of all time? Juice Box by Gorilla Zoe Imagine we were about to get into a physical fight. What&apos;s your move for taking me down? I wait until you throw the first punch and duck to the side grabbing your arm in one motion. I&apos;d palm strike your back so you&apos;d fall and then I&apos;d put you in an arm lock until you cry uncle. Have you ever been straight up rejected when you went in to kiss someone? No, i&apos;m no confident enough to make such first moves. What&apos;s the least attractive piece of clothing you own? My socks aren&apos;t too sexy I guess If you could punch one person in the face with no repercussions, who would it be and why? Michelle Bachmann What one food would you choose to live off for the rest of your life? Pizza If you could live anywhere in the world, where would you live? Spain What is one show you wished you were really into while it was on TV? Scrubs What movie do you quote from the most? Fight Club What movie will you stop and watch on TV, regardless of what you were doing? Harry Potter What famous person do you hear yourself compared to most? Kate Beckinsale for some reason Besides model or actress, what&apos;s one career you wish you could pursue? A famous painter! What is the oldest age you can be a virgin without it being weird? About 19 or 20 If no one would ever find out, who is someone embarrassing you would like to make out with? I can&apos;t tell you! This is the internet!! Why do girls like elliptical machines so much? Well I don&apos;t much care for them soooo What was your best halloween costume? Little Dead Riding Hood!! How many days can I go without showering before you consider me undateable? About 4 Describe your ideal worst date. Someone who is awkward, rude or self centered makes me spend time with them. You&apos;re on an asteroid and your daughter&apos;s fiancee draws the short straw to sacrifice his life to divert it from destroying the Earth. What do you do? Let him, it will protect out families honor. Why does Nickelback suck so hard? Probably because we keep encouraging them. What&apos;s the last lie you were caught in? I don&apos;t know. Either I&apos;m a good liar or just super honest. You&apos;ll never know. Which Rocky opponent would you fight if you had to fight one? None...I&apos;d die. If you HAD to pick one, which of the following would you say is most-likely real: Leprechauns, Bigfoot, or the Lochness Monster? Lochness Monster Rollercoasters or waterslides? Rollercoasters Have you ever made an online purchase you regret? A non-refundable t-shirt that was the wrong size. How good would a guy have to be at videogames for you to be impressed? I don&apos;t you realize how this works. How hot is CollegeHumor&apos;s Jeff Rubin? Really hot, right? Super adorable&lt;3 Did you like Avatar? The cartoon or the blue Pocahontas? Yes and Yes What was the last book your read twice? Brave New World Are your friends mostly guys or mostly girls? Guys, for some reason Is your mom on Facebook, and what does she do with it? Yes and she just uses to it see what I&apos;m up too :P What&apos;s the point of really fancy underwear? I&apos;m talking like the really high end stuff. For when sexy times are anticipated for the evening What&apos;s the strangest food you&apos;ve ever eaten? Squid If you could create your own mythical animal, what would you make, and what would you name it? A giant lion the could be ridden like a horse. It could fly and shoot lasers. If bananas were another color, what color would they be? Any other color than yellow. What band are you most ashamed of liking? Adele How long have you been a hot girl? I don&apos;t know, this is sort of news to me. Ever done a master cleanse? Noooo Would you gain 25 pounds for $2500? I don&apos;t think so. Would you rather have sex once a day for the rest of your life or once a week for the rest of your life? Once a week. I&apos;d get way to sore but I like a steady diet :P More Cute College Girls 02.03 Fiona Senior Toronto English 01.05 Katie Senior MIT Physics 
Newsletter Weekly Roundup 
 
 The best CollegeHumor content delivered directly to your face! 

Enter your email to receive a weekly newsletter of the best videos, girls, and more.
 Subscribe 

 
RSS Subscribe 
 RSS 
 Recent Videos Recent Pictures Recent Articles CollegeHumor Originals 
 
Friends BFF 
 
 Failblog AdultSwim Uproxx HerCampus HollywoodTuna Popoholic BroBible GorillaMask I Am Bored Smosh Caveman Circus The Smoking Gun 
 
 The Stuff Funny Videos / Funny Pictures / Funny Articles / Newsletter / Our Book / Mobile / FAQ 
 
 Seriously About / Site Map / Site Index / Advertise / Jobs / Contact / Privacy Policy / Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 CH Network Jest / SportsPickle / Dorkly / Hardly Working / Bleep Bloop / Jake and Amir / CH Media 
 
©2012 Connected Ventures, LLC. All rights reserved. | Brought to you by CollegeHumor
	</body>
</document>
