<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006458" url="http://garciascafe.com/welcome-to-garcias/" time="2012-07-12-23:23" support="1" score="0.0021055234381395717" bingtitle="Garcia’s | Garcia&apos;s Cafe" webtitle="Garcias | Garcias Cafe (970) 984-2415">
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>... Garcia’s offers a large selection of baked goods, delicious menu ... added a variety of items to make it a more convenient by including a bakery, fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Garcia&apos;s Cafe (970) 984-2415 

Open everyday from 7:30AM to 9:30PM
 
Main menu
 Skip to content 
 Home Contact Us Garcia’s Tres Leches Cake 
 
Garcia’s
 
Garcia’s Cafe has been a part of Garfield County for over 10 years, and proudly caters to the New Castle community. Located in the Historic Downtown, Garcia’s offers a large selection of baked goods, delicious menu items, fresh cut meats, produce and a little bit of everything.

The goal behind Garcia’s has always been to be the“one stop shop”for all Mexican products. As years went by we added a variety of items to make it a more  convenient by including baked goods, fast food, green produce, and a selection of fresh meats.

All of the menu items use ingredients sold at Garcia’s.

Garcia’s Cafe is open 7 days a week.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
Pages

 Contact Us Garcia’s Garcia’s Cafe Menu Tres Leches Cake 
 Search for: 
 
 
 July 2012 S M T W T F S «May     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Rusty Grunge by Chris Wallace . Follow 
 Follow“Garcia&apos;s Cafe (970) 984-2415” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
