<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006813" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20070725141254AAS6Wgr" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="1" score="0.0008988619070942259" bingtitle="Why do people eat at fast food restaurants when they can&apos;t afford ..." webtitle="Why do people eat at fast food restaurants when they cant afford to? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>And knowing that if one meal is ... the menu, and having the kids eat what they know, plus throwing away trash (zero clean up at home) the fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 huskergo Member since: December 24, 2006 Total points: 2,879 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Why do people eat at fast food restaurants when they can&apos;t afford to?
 I&apos;ve been a supervisor at a fast food chain (I currently don&apos;t work there anymore) and have seen people that complain they don&apos;t have enough money to buy their children good food, clothes, and their income level is low enough that they qualify for food stamps, but they are loyal customers. They eat out every night dropping $20-30 each night? I know why...because they are ignorant on how to manage their money. I&apos;m just asking this question, and perhaps someone who does do this and has very little money will have a good answer for themselves and this question. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 AJLsfo: sorry you can&apos;t replace convience with sloppy and poor parenting styles. Not providing for your family and children first is just plain selfishness. $60-$90 a week can buy you plenty of good food and good clothes and if you eat out more often then it could possibly get you off the tax payers payroll. And the clean up can be done by the whole family and the kids will develop responsibility and skills that you are teaching them....wow what a concept!! 
 5 years ago 
 by Lori L O^O Member since: May 04, 2007 Total points: 13,458 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 I agree with you so way! I was a single parent with little hlep for a long time. I worked a good job but lived very meagerly becuase life is expensive. I budgeted my grocery money. We had no cable, no internet, no cell phone, not silly things that do not relaly matter. My daughters&quot;treet&quot;on Payday was to be able to do a Video night....we rented a movie from the chepie rental store, bought take out and had a picnic on the floor. That is still her favorite thing to do and we are no longer in the need for that kind of frugalty. She is 18 and still manages money well from the example. It can be done. We ate simple and healthy things. I used a crock pot religiously, sometimes two, and saved leftovers by freezing or in the fridge for later in the week. Fruits and vegetables are amazingly cheap compared to the other stuff people buy! 
Source(s):
 Optician and mom. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: How refreshing it is to see a family teach their children about values and skills to use later in life!!! 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 1 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 Scott S No one is stating the obvious; quit having kids you cannot afford. Use birth control, get sterilized or quit screwing. It&apos;s not uncommon to see run down shacks and trailer&apos;s with satellite dishs out front. I remember seeing the more expensive c band types n front of the same types of dwellings.
 Report Abuse 
 
* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (9)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Tabitha Member since: January 02, 2007 Total points: 1,483 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Your SO right!
I work in a bookshop and have customers complain they have no money for food or clothes but but three or four books to read (fiction)..use your money more wisly..buy food not something to entertain yourself. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by AJLsfo Member since: December 10, 2005 Total points: 283 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Dropping $20-30 cash on high-fat, quickly served food versus spending the same amount on buying items in the grocery store then preparing it... these folks may be best served by eating fast food. There&apos;s the hidden cost of the electricity burned by cooking and cleaning up (water to wash, prep, clean up). And knowing that if one meal is served at home, not all the kids would like it (finicky eaters). So, unforturnately, because of the familiarity of the menu, and having the kids eat what they know, plus throwing away trash (zero clean up at home) the fast food restaurant wins this round.

edit: Huskergo, I totally see your point... I was under the assumption that these folks were buying off the dollar menu or cheaper... 20-30 a night per week? Outrageous. And ordering&quot;value meals&quot;and happy meals all around the table? Yeesh. I agree on the poor parenting skills and probable lack of basic home economic skills. I don&apos;t defend the use of fast-fooding as the way to keep a family fed, just that giving credit to a parent or parents to get their kids fed, albeit with some kind of nutrition. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by SAChicky Member since: April 20, 2006 Total points: 6,878 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I agree with you, I have seen people who cannot even afford their rent eat out w/a bunch of kids at fast food restaurants. You would think they would get more for their money by buying food at the grocery store. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Ryan&apos;s mom Member since: April 24, 2006 Total points: 40,844 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The sad thing is that the healthy foods are so over-priced that some low-income people cannot get them at a regular store. My husband recently was laid off from his job and I am working two jobs and still not making what he did. We rarely go out. Even if it is mac&amp;cheese, it can be healthy with a can of tuna and some peas added to it. Takes 10 minutes...which is faster than loading everyone in the car and going to the drive-thru. There are discount grocery stores also where you can get off brands, and some name brand items at sometimes more than half the price, and they have meat, fresh/frozen veggies, cereal, dairy, etc. It can be done. I still have enough money to buy my son clothes, shoes, etc. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by jfrench4 Member since: June 04, 2007 Total points: 3,554 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I know what your talking about... it should be that all fast food for anyone not just low income be a&quot;treat&quot;instead of every other night... too bad things in this world have changed so much... as for an answer... idk maybe they have kids and well when you have kids you cant just not get them a happy meal once in a while... so maybe they feel the pressure there... otherwise maybe they eat all other meals at home and they eat out a few nights b/c of their work schedules (not all people receiving assistance..{which is what it is..it doesn&apos;t cover for all meals just to help with the cost of a portion/majority} are low lifes w/o a job, the economy sucks, maybe they do work even 2jobs and cant make ends meet) perhaps after working all day they are too tried to cook, I know Ive felt like that many nights... so there are many reasons for it... ignorant or not 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by babyrhee... Member since: June 03, 2007 Total points: 1,036 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It is a total lack of knowledge.
People don&apos;t understand moderation, they can&apos;t control themselves and feel that they deserve the treat after they work so hard, they are also in survival mode...focusing on right now and unable to see past right now.
This survival mode puts them in a position where they are just unable to do the wise thing for the future because they need to survive the moment. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by csi7472 Member since: May 22, 2007 Total points: 1,476 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i agree, they cannot manage their money. And they are probabley to lazy to shop right and cook. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Bethany Member since: July 22, 2006 Total points: 5,998 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I blame this on our society. You have teenage parents who have never been taught to budget and/or cook. They don&apos;t know how to budget their money. They don&apos;t know how to keep house, how to cook food, and they are overwhelmed. They don&apos;t know what else to do. This is not an excuse by any means, but I have seen it happen to so many young families. This did happen with my sister. She was a very young teenager who got married, had a child, and our mother had shown us NOTHING about how to run a household. Finally she came to me in tears. We sat down, made a budget, made out menus, grocery list, and even a sort of schedule for house work. It worked for her...she just had to be shown that there was a way. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by cherry Member since: November 03, 2006 Total points: 1,281 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You&apos;re right.... 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Do you work at a fast food place? What is it like working at a fast food restaurant? Any tips on handling rude and clueless customers without… why fast food customers are so annoying? Is it bad to eat fast food everyday? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
