<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006147" url="http://my-ecoach.com/modules/custombuilder/popup_printable.php?id=17288" time="2012-07-12-22:50" support="6" score="0.005121017106788171" bingtitle="Percentages can Save or Make You Money!" webtitle="Percentages can Save or Make You Money!">
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="90"/>
	<description>You stop for a quick meal at your favorite fast food restaurant. ... space below explain the process of your selection. ... Make tables of equivalent ratios relating quantities ...</description>
	<body>
		Percentages can Save or Make You Money! 
 How do you calculate percentages and discounts? 

 By
Ken Bakken
Abigail Paske
 

 Table of Contents: 
Overview
Calculating a Percentage
     
Discounts
     Vocabulary
     Calculating Discounts
     Problems
Sales Tax
     Vocabulary
     Calculating Sales Tax
     Problems
Tips
     Vocabulary
     Calculating Tips
     Problems
Discount- Sales Tax Video
     
Extended Learning
     Create your Own Problem
     Go Shopping
     More Complex Problem Practice
Standards
     
 

 Overview: 

 

Learning how to take a percent of a number can help save money when you are shopping, going out to dinner, or leaving a tip. In this project, you will learn how to take a percent of a number, and apply that knowledge to real world problems that you will encounter. The project is broken up into five parts which are located on the left navigation bar of this page. The sixth category relates to the standards that you will be meeting completing this project.

 

Navigate through this project by clicking on the categories on the left navigation bar. If you prefer, click on Next at the bottom of the page to navigate to the project pages in order.

 Next 


 Calculating a Percentage: 

 


A percentage is a fraction or ratio of a number with the denominator (the bottom number of a fraction) being 100. For example 25% is the ratio 25/100 which is equivalent to the decimal 0.25. Any percentage can be converted to a decimal by moving the decimal point two places to the left of the decimal if there is one. For example 37% or 37.0% is equivalent to 0.37, or 58.9% is equivalent to 0.589. Notice how the decimal point was moved.

Here are some examples of how to take a percent of a number.

Example A

14% of 200 

When you take a percentage of a number, it is a multiplication problem. So, you can see the multiplication problem that is created in step #2.

 Convert 14% to a decimal:             14% = 0.14 or .14 Write out the new problem:            0.14 x 200 Do the multiplication:                    0.14 x 200= 28.00 or 28 

 

 

Example B

33.3% of 1,000

 Convert 33.3% to a decimal:            33.3% = 0.333 or .333 Write out the new problem:            0.333 x 1,000 Do the multiplication:                    0..333 x 1,00= 333 

Below is another way of looking at the examples above:

 Next 




 Discounts: 

 Vocabulary 


 

 You have been wanting to purchase a Wii for months, and one day you are walking through a store and notice that the Wii is on sale. How much can you save if it is 25% off the regular price. To calculate the sale price you need to understand some terms and know how to calculate that price. 

 

 When an item is purchased at a price less than the regular price, that is known as the sale price .     The discount is the amount of money deducted from the regular price.  The lower price is also referred to as the discounted price or sale price . 

 

 Some stores offer discounts every day, weekly, or monthly. So, you don’t always need to purchase an item for the regular price. When you decide to purchase an item like the Wii remember that besides checking the price, you should also check the item’s quality, since there may be a reason you are getting that item at a discount or on sale. Always keep in mind the saying, &quot;Buyer beware!&quot; 
 

 

 To calculate the discount, click on the   Calculating a Percentage   page on the left side of this page to learn the process. 

 Next 





 Calculating Discounts 


 

 

 

So you have decided to purchase the Wii. Below is the process in which you calculate the sale price. Remember that the sale price is usually not the final price that you will pay for the Wii since most states charge some type of sales tax; you will learn to do that next after learning to calculate the sale price. For this example the regular price of the Wii is $200.00, and it is on sale for 25% off.

 

 Since the Wii is on sale for 25% off, you first must calculate the discount . To do that, multiply 25% times $200. Translate the problem: 25% x $200= .25 x 200 Do the multiplication: .25 x 200= 50 which is the discount or the amount of money taken off the regular price . To calculate the sale price , subtract the discount from the regular price .               $200 - $50 = $150. $150 is the sale price which is a savings of $50. That is quite a deal! 

Below is another way of looking at the example above:

 Next 





 Problems 


 

 

 Below is a quiz (It isn’t really a quiz, but that’s what we are calling it). The following is an example of how to answer questions using this site. 

 

 

 

A pair of jeans that regularly cost $28.00 go on sale for 25% off the regular price. What is the sale price for purchasing one pair of those jeans?

 $7.00 $14.75 $21.00 $27.75 none of the above 

 In the space below explain the process of your selection. 

 You should choose response c for the correct answer.   
 

 Additional Comments: 

 The sale price for the jeans is $21.00. To solve it, I converted 25% to a decimal by dropping the % sign and moving the decimal two places to the left. Next I translated the word problem into an arithmetic problem: .25 x $28.00= $7.00 which is the discount or the money taken off the regular price. Finally, I subtracted $7.00 from $28.00 which is $21.00 the sale price.
 

 

 In the problems below, please put your first name and last intial plus your math period. 

 
 

 Example: John S. Per.2 

 

 Next 




 Sales Tax: 

 Vocabulary 


 

 Sales tax is a consumption (purchasing goods) tax that is c   harged at stores or places of business.  Sales Tax is the amount of money collected from a business that is sent to the state government. The funds or money is usually calculated by applying a percentage rate to the taxable price of a sale. The sales tax collected is used to pay for functions (pay for schools, roads, etc.) that the government provides for its citizens.

 

 

 

 

 Next 





 Calculating Sales Tax 


 

If you have forgotten how to take a percentage of a number, go to the Calculating a Percentage page which is on the left side of this page.

So, you have decided to purchase the Wii which is unfortunately not on sale. Below is the process in which you calculate the sales tax. Remember that the that the regular price of the Wii is $200.00. Since most states charge a sales tax, $200.00 is not the final price that you will pay for the Wii. For this example the tax rate in this particular state is 6.0%.

Example A

 Since the Wii’s purchase price is $200.00 the tax collected will be 6.0% of that amount. To calculate that, multiply 6% times $200.00. Translate the problem: 6% x $200= .06 x 200 Do the multiplication: .06 x $200= $12.00 which is the sales tax or the amount of money added to the purchase. To calculate the total purchase price, add the regular price of the Wii ($200.00) and the sales tax ($12.00) together for a total purchase price of $212.00. 

Example B

For this example the price of the Wii is the same, but the sales tax rate is 6.9%.

 Since the Wii’s purchase price is $200.00 the tax collected will be 6.9% of that amount. To calculate that, multiply 6.9% times $200.00. Translate the problem: 6.9% x $200= .069 x 200 Do the multiplication: .069 x $200= $13.80 which is the sales tax or the amount of money added to the purchase. To calculate the total purchase price, add the regular price of the Wii ($200.00) and the sales tax ($13.80) together for a total purchase price of $213.80. The increase of 0.9% makes the total purchase price of the Wii increase of $1.80. 

Below is another way of looking at the example above:

 Next 





 Problems 


 

 

 Below is a quiz (It isn’t really a quiz, but that’s what we are calling it). The following is an example of how to answer questions using this site. 

 

 

 

A pair of jeans that regularly cost $29.00. What is the total purchasing price for one pair of in a state with a sales tax rate of 7.5%?

 $29.75 $31.18 $31.75 $32.18 none of the above 

 In the space below explain the process of your selection. 

 You should choose response b for the correct answer.   
 

 Additional Comments: 

 To solve it, I converted 7.5% to a decimal by dropping the % sign and moving the decimal two places to the left (.075). Next I translated the word problem into an arithmetic problem: .075 x $29.00= $2.175 which needs to be rounded to $2.18. Finally, I added $2.18 to $29.00 for a total of $31.18 which is the total purchase price.
 

 

 In the problems below, please put your first name and last intial plus your math period. 

 
 

 Example: John S. Per.2 

 

 Next 

   
 




 Tips: 

 Vocabulary 


 

A tip which is also known as a gratuity is a small amount of money received by some service sector professionals, like a waitress, hair stylist, or taxi drivers from persons they serve, in addition to required payment. These tips or gratuities are governed by social custom. Although tipping is optional, many tip at a rate of 15% to 20% of the total bill.

 

 

 

 

 

 Next 





 Calculating Tips 


 

 

You have just finished a wonderful dinner and the waitress has done a great job serving you. She brings you your final bill and the total is $35.75. You want to leave a tip since the service was so great. You decide to leave her a 15% tip. How do you do that?

 

Although people in general usually estimate the tip, but for these examples we will calculate them exactly so that you will learn the process. The process is straight forward.

 Multiply the total bill in this case by 15%. Translate the problem: 15% x $35.75 = .15 x $35.75 Do the arithmetic: .15 x $35.75 = $5.3625; since this is money, you need to round to the nearest cent which is $5.36 Finally, add $35.00 + $5.36 to get the total payment which is $40.36. If you were paying in cash, most people would leave $40 or $41.  

Below is another way of looking at the example above:

 Next 





 Problems 


 

 

 Below is a quiz (It isn’t really a quiz, but that’s what we are calling it). The following is an example of how to answer questions using this site. 

 

 You stop for a quick meal at your favorite fast food restaurant. You get your bill and it was $6.29. Since it is a fast food restaurant, tips are usually smaller, in this case 10%. Calculate the exact tip and then choose the most accurate answer.

 $0.43 $0.53 $0.63 $0.73 none of the above 

 In the space below explain the process of your selection. 

 You should choose response c for the correct answer. 

 

 In the problems below, please put your first name and last intial plus your math period. 

 
 

 Example: John S. Per.2 

 
 

 Next 
 




 Discount- Sales Tax Video: 

 


Below is a video of two students and their teacher from Nebraska demonstrating how to calculate discounts and sales tax.

 Next 




 Extended Learning: 

 Create your Own Problem 


Using the following numbers, create your own problem and post it below in the comment section.

Your problem must meet the following conditions:

 You must use all of the following numbers in your problem: 2, 5, 7.2, 30, and 40. You may use these numbers to fit your needs. For example 7.2 could be used for 7.2% or $7.20 and 40 might be 40 items, 40% or $40.00. Your answer does not need to be one of the preceeding numbers (For example, your answer might end up being $45.22 which is not on the list.). The problem needs to be a discount, sales tax, or a problem with both. Write your problem with complete sentences. Explain the solution to your problem using complete sentences. 

 Example 

A student wants to buy the following items at a regular price: 2 notebooks for $5.00 each, and a new pair of jeans for $40.00. All of the items are on sale for 30% off the regular price. The state sales tax is 7.2% What is the total cost of the purchase?

The cost of the two notebooks is $10.00. Add $10.00 and $40.00 for the jeans and the total is $50.00. Next calculate the discount 30% times $50.00 which is the same as .30 x $50.00 = $15.00. Then, subtract the discount $15.00 from the regular price of the items $50.00 -$15.00 which is $35.00. Last of all, multiply $35.00 x 7.2%, and add that to the price of the items for the final purchase price. $35.00 x .072 = $2.52 which is the sales tax. Add $35.00 + $2.52 = $37.52 the final purchase price.

 Next 





 Go Shopping 


Go to a store like you are shopping and select something that you might want to buy that is on sale. Write the price of the item down, the discount rate, and the sales tax rate on a piece of paper. You may need to ask the salesperson what the sales tax rate is. Save that information and describe it the comment below. If you want to make it more difficult, pretend that you are buying more than one item at different discount rates, although it is not required. 

   Your description should include the following:

 List the items and the associated prices and discounts. Explain how you calculated the total purchase price. Use complete sentences. 

 Example 

I purchased two T-shirts which were regularly priced at $5.50 each that were on sale for 30% off and a pair of jeans that were regularly priced at $20.00 for 20% off. The sales tax rate is 5.2%.

T- shirts - The cost ot the T-shirts is $5.50 x 2 = $11.00. Calculate the discount by multiplying the cost of the shirts by 30%. $11.00 x .30 (30%)= $3.30 - the discount. The sale price of the T-shirts is $11.00 - $3.30 = $7.70

Jeans - The cost of the jeans is $20.00. Calculate the discount by multiplying the cost of the jeans by 20%. $20.00 x .20(20%)= $4.00 - the discount. The sale price for the jeans is $20.00- $4.00 = $16.00.

The total price for the items is $7.70 + $16.00 = $23.70 plus sales tax.

Sales tax is equal to the sales tax rate times the cost of the items. $23.70 x .052 (5.2%) = 1.2324 which when rounded is $1.23. The total price of the purchase is $23.40 + $1.23 = $24.93.

 Next 





 More Complex Problem Practice 


 

 

 

 Below is a quiz (It isn’t really a quiz, but that’s what we are calling it). The following is an example of how to answer questions using this site. 

Example

A new light that regularly cost $30 is on sale for 40% off. The sales tax is 5%. What is the final purchase price including sales tax?

 $18.00 $18.04 $18.90 $28.55 none of the above 

 In the space below explain the process of your selection. 

 You should choose response c for the correct answer. 

 To calculate the sale price, multiply $30 times 40% and subtract that from regular price. $30.00 x .40 (40%)= $12.00. Next subtract $12.00 from $30.00= $18.00 (sale price). Calculate the tax by multiplying $18.00 x .05 (5%) = $0.90 (sales tax). Lastly, add $18.00 + $0.90 = $18.90 which is the final purchase price. 

 

 In the problems below, please put your first name and last intial plus your math period. 

 
 

 Example: John S. Per.2 

 

 

 Next 
 




 Standards: 

 


 Back to Overview 



 
 California Content Standards Mathematics Grade Six Algebra and Functions MA.6.2.0 Students analyze and use tables, graphs, and rules to solve problems involving rates and proportions: MA.6.2.3. Solve problems involving rates, average speed, distance, and time.
 


 Common Core Standards Mathematics Grade 6 Ratios&amp;Proportional Relationships Understand ratio concepts and use ratio reasoning to solve problems. MATH-RPR.6.3. Use ratio and rate reasoning to solve real-world and mathematical problems, e.g., by reasoning about tables of equivalent ratios, tape diagrams, double number line diagrams, or equations.
Make tables of equivalent ratios relating quantities with whole-number measurements, find missing values in the tables, and plot the pairs of values on the coordinate plane. Use tables to compare ratios.
Solve unit rate problems including those involving unit pricing and constant speed. For example, if it took 7 hours to mow 4 lawns, then at that rate, how many lawns could be mowed in 35 hours? At what rate were lawns being mowed?
Find a percent of a quantity as a rate per 100 (e.g., 30% of a quantity means 30/100 times the quantity); solve problems involving finding the whole, given a part and the percent.
Use ratio reasoning to convert measurement units; manipulate and transform units appropriately when multiplying or dividing quantities.
	</body>
</document>
