<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006773" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/436718-dangers-of-fast-food-restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="3" score="0.015911516920251827" bingtitle="Dangers Of Fast-food Restaurants | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Dangers Of Fast-food Restaurants | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>Eating at fast-food restaurant regularly can increase ... nutritional information about its meals and pick ... Avoid piling too many condiments on your foods; going light on the ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Weight Management Weight Loss Diets D-F Fast Food&amp;Diets Dangers of Fast-Food Restaurants 
 
 Dangers of Fast-Food Restaurants 
 May 6, 2011 | By Christa Miller Photo Credit Jupiterimages/Brand X Pictures/Getty Images 
If you&apos;re too busy to prepare a home-cooked meal, hitting the drive-through at your favorite fast-food restaurant is an easy, affordable and quick alternative. Even though fast-food restaurants might fit conveniently into your hectic lifestyle, many of their meal options pose dangers to your family&apos;s health.
 
Proximity Linked to Obesity

Being near a fast-food restaurant may increase some people&apos;s risk of obesity. According to a 2009 study by the University of California-Berkeley, the state&apos;s ninth graders had a 5.2-percent higher chance of being obese if their school was within 1/10th of a mile of a fast-food restaurant. Ninth graders who attended schools 1/4 mile away from a fast-food restaurant were 4.4-percent more likely to be obese, meanwhile, and students 1/2 mile away were 2.5-percent more likely to be obese.
 
Ingredients and Cooking Methods Linked to Heart Disease

Some fast-food restaurants prepare fried foods with partially hydrogenated oils. Hydrogenated oils, which contain harmful fats called trans fats, can boost your risk of heart disease by lowering your levels of good cholesterol and increasing your levels of bad cholesterol. Many restaurants have stopped using these oils in recent decades as a result of increased public awareness and some local bans, but other aspects of fast food are also unhealthy. For example, many fast foods are rich in saturated fat and sodium, which also can increase your risk of heart disease if they comprise a large part of your diet, the American Heart Association warns.
 
High Calorie Content Linked to Diabetes

Eating at fast-food restaurant regularly can increase your risk of type 2 diabetes. According to a long-term study published in 2005 in medical journal &quot;The Lancet,&quot; people who ate at fast-food restaurants more than twice weekly for 15 years gained an average of 10 extra pounds and were twice as likely to develop insulin resistance as people who ate fast food less than once per week. The major culprit for the weight problems and increased risk for diabetes is the calorie content in fast food. Some fast-food restaurants serve items that offer more than a day&apos;s worth of calories in a single serving.
 
Healthy Tips

While you might allow yourself the convenience and enjoyment of fast food every once in a while, avoid making fast-food restaurant trips a habit. If you still plan to eat fast food on a regular basis, find ways to make your meals healthier. Ask the restaurant where you can find nutritional information about its meals and pick the options that are lower in fat, calories and sodium, the MedlinePlus online medical encyclopedia recommends. These foods tend to be grilled rather than fried and are smaller in size, or are salads and soups. Avoid piling too many condiments on your foods; going light on the cheese when you order a pizza, staying away from cream-based soups and dressings, cutting the mayonnaise and avoiding gravies can save you hundreds of calories.
 
References

 National Institutes of Health; Eating at Fast-Food Restaurants More Than Twice Per Week Is Associated With More Weight Gain and Insulin Resistance in Otherwise Healthy Young Adults; Dec. 30, 2004 MedlinePlus; Fast Food Tips; Oct. 6, 2010 &quot;The Lancet&quot;; Fast-Food Habits, Weight Gain and Insulin Resistance: 15-Year Prospective Analysis; M.A. Pereira, et al; Jan. 1-7, 2005 MedlinePlus; Fast Food; Nov. 18, 2009 University of California-Berkeley: Linking Fast Food Proximity to Obesity; Kathleen Maclay; March 4, 2009 University of California-Berkeley; The Effect of Fast-Food Restaurants on Obesity and Weight Gain; Janet Currie, et al.; 2009 
 
Article reviewed by Will McCahill Last updated on: May 6, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Fast Food Causing Obesity Problems 
 
 The Negative Effects of Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Effects of Fast Food Restaurants on Diabetes 
 
 Explain the Effects of Eating at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Risks of Fast Foods 
 
 What Are the Consequences of Eating Too Much Fast Food? 
 
 Obesity&amp;Fast Food Companies 
 
 Obesity&amp;Fast Food Chains 
 
 Nutrition Facts for Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Disadvantages of Fast Foods 
 
 Facts About the Dangers of Eating Fast Food 
 
 How Do Fast Foods Affect Health? 
 
 Healthy Meals at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 How to Eat Healthy at Fast-Food Restaurants 
 
 How to Compare the Nutrition of Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 How Do You Eat Low Carb at Fast Food Restaurants? 
 
 How Is Fast Food Contributing to Obesity in America? 
 
 How to Get Nutrition Information for Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Heart Disease as a Result of Eating Fast Food 
 
 Effects of Fast Food on People 
 more Restaurant Food advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Dangers of Hand Sanitizer&amp;Toddlers 
 
 Health Dangers of Fast Foods 
 
 What Are the Dangers of Running in Excessive Heat? 
 
 What Are the Dangers of Fast Foods? 
 
 Is Inhaling Natural Gas Dangerous for Pregnant Women? 
 
 What Are the Dangers of Ingesting Calcium Chloride? 
 
 Gluten-Free Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Are Fast Food Fries Dangerous to Eat? 
 
 Superdrol Dangers 
 
 Why Fast Food Is Dangerous for Health 
 
 Dangerous Chemicals in Fast Food Other Than MSG 
 
 Dangers of CO2 Tanks 
 
 The Top 10 Healthy Fast Foods 
 
 How Dangerous Are Broken Asbestos Floor Tiles? 
 
 10 Worst Fast Foods 
 
 What Are the Dangers of Eating Fast Food? 
 
 What are the Dangers of Smoking ? 
 
 What Are the Dangers of Chewing Food Too Fast? 
 
 Fast Food Vs. Healthy Foods 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
