<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006115" url="http://www.coursehero.com/keyword/excel-spreadsheet/" time="2012-07-12-22:47" support="8" score="0.009110421046396268" bingtitle="Excel Spreadsheet - Course Hero | Study Guides, Lecture Notes ..." webtitle="Excel Spreadsheet">
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... is: v = C n e polynomial function of order n ... analyst working on a simulation study of a fast food restaurant. ... number of employees that need to work the front counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Course Hero Sign up Log-in 
 Home Study Documents 
 Find Documents Textbook Help 
 Tutors 
 Ask a Question Browse Questions 
 Courses 
 Find Courses Create a Course Suggest a Course About Courses 
 Flashcards 
 Find Flashcards Create Flashcards About Flashcards 
 Support 
 Contact Us FAQ 
 
 
Documents about Excel Spreadsheet
 
 
 EXCEL Assignment 
 UAB, CE 395 Excerpt: ... University of Alabama at Birmingham CE 395, Summer 2005 EXCEL Spreadsheet s Homework Exercise General. We have studied the use of EXCEL spreadsheet s for Engineering Economics Problems in class. It is not possible for us to conduct individual exercises in the classroom with EXCEL or to test your skills. Therefore it is important that you complete this assignment on an individual basis. You are welcome to collaborate with others on how EXCEL works, but you are responsible to accomplish the assigned problems individually and to turn in your personal work. A printout of the assignment described below is due at the beginning of class on Tuesday, August 2, 2005. In addition to turning in a printed copy, NLT the beginning of class on the same date, email to me a copy of your EXCEL spreadsheet solutions. My email address is wah@uab.edu. Assignment: Exam 2 was a large array of Engineering Economics Problems which in combination covered all of the foundation concepts we have discussed so far in CE 395. Solve the Exam 2 ... 
 A DESCRIPTION OF 
 Oakwood, FIN 301 Excerpt: ... A DESCRIPTION OF FOUNDATIONS OF FINANCE SUPPLEMENTS For the student: 1. A Study Guide, which provides the following: a. b. c. d. e. 2. An orientation of each chapter, along with an outline of the important topics being addressed. Sample problems for the student to complete, with the worked-out solutions. Self-test questions (true/false and multiple choice) with answers. A tutorial on understanding the internal rate of return. An in-depth self-teaching supplement on capital-budgeting techniques. Companion Website online study guide for the student includes true/false, multiple choice, and short answer quizzes for each chapter. From www.prenhall.com/keown students can also access the internet exercises, current events articles with questions, and Excel spreadsheet s for the end-of-chapter problems. ix For the teacher: 1. A Test Item File provides more than 1600 multiple-choice, true/false, and short-answer questions with complete and detailed answers. It is designed for use with the Prentice Hall Custom Tes ... 
 excelfinance 
 Coastal Carolina University, MATH 242 Excerpt: ... MATH 242 / Lab 13: Financial Modeling Using Excel Spreadsheet s 1 Lab 13: Financial Modeling Using Excel Spreadsheet s October 4, 2007 Objectives Practice making Excel spreadsheet s to make financial predictions. Recognize the use of recurrence relations in financial modeling. Procedure Attached is a copy from COMAP, For All Practical Purposes: Mathematics Literacy In Today&apos;s World, 6th ed., W. H. Freeman and Company, 2003. 1. Solve problems 1320 by making Excel spreadsheet s. Note: For some of these problems, Problem 13 for instance, you will need to take a&quot;guess and check&quot;approach. On&quot;guess and check&quot;problems, consider only whole dollar amounts. 2. To be turned in: (a) Save your spreadsheets on a USB drive. Bring the files to my office for me to copy onto my computer. (b) Make an answer sheet that summarizes your final answer for each problem. ... 
 lab3b_crane_coversheetl 
 Rose-Hulman, ES 204 Excerpt: ... ES 204 Mechanical Systems Crane Lab Write-up (Due Friday, Week 10) Names _ _ _ Objective You will examine the swinging crane problem in three different ways: 1. Working Model (Lab 9) 2. Analytically (HW 4.48, Lecture 25) 3. Experimentally (Lab 10) You will be required to submit the following: 1. 2. 3. 4. The Excel spreadsheet used in the experiment. The Excel spreadsheet used with Working Model A snapshot of your Working Model Simulation A copy of your analytical solution. Discuss these below or attach a discussion: Overhead Crane Lab 1 ... 
 Lecture_9 
 Michigan, ECON 472 Excerpt: ... ice Button&quot;in the upper left of the computer screen Click on&quot;Excel Options&quot;at the bottom center Click on&quot;Add-Ins&quot;in the toolbar located on the left-hand column Click on the&quot;Go&quot;button near the bottom center Check the&quot;Solver Add-In&quot;and then click the&quot;OK&quot;button The Solver software should now be available on the&quot;Data&quot;tab in Excel. See the&quot;Solver&quot;option on the right? Tackling a math problem using Solver Step 1: Prepare the data and the algebraic functions in an Excel spreadsheet Step 2: Run Solver using the data and functions Step 3: Save your results! Step 1: Prepare the data and the algebraic functions in an Excel spreadsheet Columns B C D A E 1 2 3 4 5 Rows 6 7 8 9 10 Math Application Solver Math Objective Function Choice Variables Constraint Application Aggregate Profit () Water Allocations (Wi ) i Wi = WCR Solver terms&quot;Target Cell&quot;&quot;Changing Cells&quot;&quot;Constraints&quot;Step 2: Running Solver Solver either will be an option directly, or you ... 
 HW2_solns 
 Mich Tech, FW 4260 Excerpt: ... FW4260 Population Ecology Solution Set #1 Exponential Growth 1. A graph comparing the discrete and continuous formulas of exponential growth. Make a table showing the parameters given in the problem statement. In an Excel spreadsheet , this could appear as: The equation for discrete population growth is Nt = r(Nt-1). In an Excel spreadsheet , this could appear as: The equation for continuous population growth is Nt = N0ert. In an Excel spreadsheet , this could appear as: Copy and paste that formula to the rest of the cells in your table. In an Excel spreadsheet , this could appear as: Follow directions provided above to create and format you graph to look like this: 2. Human population growth part 1 To calculate r, begin with the equation for doubling time, which is: tdouble = ln(2)/r. The second step is to algebraically rearrange that equation to solve for r, which gives: r = ln(2)/ tdouble. The problem statement indicated that one should expect a doubling time of 50 years (i.e., tdouble = 50). In ... 
 Homework3_updated 
 N.C. State, MEA 719 Excerpt: ... DUE April 14, 2009 2 H n ( y ) . H n ( y ) is the Hermite Matsuno solutions for the north-south velocity is: v = C n e polynomial function of order n. Derive the formula for the solutions for u and . Make line plots (e.g., in excel spreadsheet ) for u, v and for n=0&amp;k=0.5. Note H n = 0 ( y ) = 1 - y2 ... 
 ME345_Lecture_04 
 Penn State, ME 345 Excerpt: ... M E 345 Spring 2008 Professor John M. Cimbala Lecture 04 01/23/2008 Today, we will: Review the pdf module: Histograms Do some example problems histograms Review the pdf module: Probability Density Functions (PDFs) Do some example problems PDFs Example Given: To do: Solution: Several length readings are taken in the lab [See Excel spreadsheet ]. Draw a nice-looking histogram of the data. To be done&quot;on-line&quot;in class, using Excel. ... 
 C220 
 Wisc Whitewater, D 220 Excerpt: ... C220: Importing Glossary Items The Import Multiple Terms screen allows you to add many terms to the glossary at once. Fig 1 - Importing glossary items Fig 2 - Click Glossary to enter the glossary Fig 3 - Click Administration to edit the glossary Fig 4 - Click Import Multiple Items Fig 5 - Click Browse to locate the Excel Spreadsheet on your computer Fig 6 - Click on the excel spreadsheet file Fig 7 - Click Open button Fig 8 - Click Upload Fig 9 - After reviewing the terms and definitions, click the Confirmed button Fig 10 - Click OK Fig 11 - Note: The Excel Spreadsheet must have this layout Fig 12 - A column labeled term Fig 13 - A column labeled definition Fig 14 - All term names must be in the term column Fig 15 - All definitions must be in the definition column This concludes: Importing glossary items ... 
 FIN 3424 U01A SUA08- 1248462 
 FIU, FIN 3424 Excerpt: ... FIN 3424 U01A: INTERMEDIATE FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT Monday and Wednesday: 9:30 to 12:15, CBC 252 fgfgfgf GENERAL INFORMATION Instructor: Chun-Hao Chang Office: RB 207A Office Hours: Wednesday 14:00 16:00 Link to professor&apos;s site: http:/www.fiu.edu/~changch fgfgfgf Phone: (305) 348-2845 Fax: (305) 348-4245 E-mail: changch@fiu.edu COURSE DESCRIPTION The purpose of the course is to develop and use quantitative and actuarial methods to solve problems in financial decision making and to better prepare students for future applications in finance and possibly other areas. You will study and learn various financial models in financial decision making through lectures, Excel spreadsheet exercises, and individual Excel spreadsheet project. At the end of the course, you are expected to be proficient in applying Excel financial functions to model and solve financial problems. fgfgfgf COURSE LEARNING OBJECTIVES The major objectives to be accomplished in this course are: 1. Understand the following topics: a. Tim ... 
 Lecture 13 Computer Applications and Inflation ... 
 UAB, CE 395 Excerpt: ... CE 395 Engineering Economics UAB Summer 2005 W. Hitchcock Computer Applications Excel Spreadsheet s Computer Applications Excel Functions and Spreadsheets Time value of money calculations are greatly simplified with the aid of computers. Hand held calculators and personal computers are the tools used by practitioners. Some of you have already learned to use the business functions on your hand held calculators. Now is an excellent time in the course to again demonstrate the utility of Excel in business calculations. Knowledge Objective The desired outcomes: 1. You will be knowledgeable about the basic business functions contained in Excel 2. You are able to build Excel Spreadsheet s for typical Engineering Economics problems encountered in CE 395. Demonstration of competence: 1. Use Excel to solve the assigned problems from Exam 2 (separate assignment sheet) 2. Turn in results in well organized spreadsheets Solving Problems With Excel You should all be familiar with the basic ... 
 assignment01 
 Wisconsin, ENGR 320 Excerpt: ... Assignment 01 (Due Feb. 11, 2003 11am, Weight: 150 points) You are an analyst working on a simulation study of a fast food restaurant. The restaurant is concerned with the customers that arrive during the lunch period of 11am 1pm on weekdays. The objective of the simulation study is to determine the optimal number of employees that need to work the front counter during this time period. When modeling this system, the company is concerned about the quality of service the customers receive. In creating this simulation, you must first know the arrival rate of the customers. Before the simulation can be built, you must first model this as a random variable drawn from a distribution that you will specify. In order to know what this distribution should be, you have collected data associated with the inter-arrival times of the customers. These data (scaled to a convenient size) are given in the Microsoft Excel spreadsheet , Assignment01Data.xls, on the IE 320 course web page. You first decide what distribution to u ... 
 midtermreview 
 CSU San Marcos, CS 301 Excerpt: ... CS 301J Midterm Review (Exam Time: 14:30 15:45, Monday, 03/13/06) The midterm exam will cover materials up to the class on 03/06/06: All lectures Chapter 1 11 and 18 of the textbook&quot;Fluency with Information Technology&quot;All in-class labs, includ ... 
 Thematic_unit_template 
 NMSU, EDLT 368 Excerpt: ... ed the development of New Mexico up to the present day. Rubric Write a Describe the Scoring for factual characteristics one research statement of other find about how indigenous New Mexico peoples that has been have had an impacted by affect upon Indigenous NM. tribes. Rubric Students do a Explain the Scoring on Worksheet significance of worksheet on the trails and trade similarities routes within and NM differences between the different trails Web based research on Rubric Students Explain how internet Scoring on would do a New Mexicans www.geoinfo.nmt.edu/ MS poster poster have adapted to Excel Spreadsheet showing the their physical different environment Rubric Scoring on paper and presentation Presentation on the life and contributions of famous New Mexicans natural resources History How have different cultures influenced New Mexico&apos;s environment? Ofelia Delgadillo Students would research different cultures in NM and present findings. percentages over time. of natural resources found in New Mexico We ... 
 MKTG 485 A 
 Washington, MKTG 485 Excerpt: ... MKTG 485 A Strategic Marketing Management MW 10:30-12:20 Balmer 408 Professor Gary Erickson 308 Mackenzie Hall erick@u.washington.edu office hours Th 12:30-1:20 In this course, you will learn how to solve marketing issues with tools that are readily available: models of marketing problems, Excel spreadsheet s, and your own intelligence in solving problems. Various marketing models, to which you will be exposed over the quarter, have been developed over the years to deal with important marketing analysis and decision problems. Excel spreadsheet s provide a consistent and useful format for implementation of the models. Finally, your interest and intelligence in problem solving allows you to use marketing models in Excel spreadsheet s to deal effectively with important marketing problems. This is a course that emphasizes application. Lectures and textbook readings expose you to the marketing models, and, importantly, several case exercises have you apply the models to marketing situations. You are required to pre ... 
 Exam 2 study guide 
 Kent State, CS 10001 Excerpt: ... Exam 2 Study Guide Dean Zeller CS10001 Fall, 2008 Wednesday, November 19th 50 points Test instructions Use the Microsoft Excel spreadsheet and the class wiki to complete the following questions. You may use the course textbook or class notes to help with questions. When complete with the questions, email your spreadsheet to the instructor. Leave the spreadsheet and wiki open on your computer for grading. Question 1: ACM speaker (10 points) Attend the ACM guest speaker Vicki Anderson on December 1st during class time in room 228. (Note: this replaces the lab requirement indicated on the Final Presentation writeup.) Question 2: Spreadsheet I (10 points) Complete the following task using MicroSoft Excel. (Question will require the use of entering and formatting data.) Question 3: Spreadsheet II (10 points) Complete the following task using MicroSoft Excel. (Question will require the use of the following functions: AVERAGE, MIN, MAX, IF, and absolute referencing.) Question 4: Spreadsheet III (10 points) ... 
 ME345_Lecture_03 
 Penn State, ME 345 Excerpt: ... M E 345 Spring 2008 Professor John M. Cimbala Lecture 03 01/18/2008 Today, we will: Review the pdf module: Errors and Calibration Do some example problems errors and calibration Discuss an additional item not in the pdf notes: Mean Bias Error Review the pdf module: Basic Statistics Do some example problems basic statistics Discuss an additional item not in the pdf notes: Root Mean Square Error Do Candy Questions for Candy Friday Example Given: The actual (true) temperature is 22.100oC. Six thermometer readings are taken: 22.15, 22.22, 22.09, 22.21, 22.18, and 22.24oC. To do: Calculate the systematic error for this set of measurements, and calculate the accuracy error (inaccuracy) and the precision error for each measurement. Solution: Ti (oC) 22.15 22.22 22.09 22.21 22.18 22.24 Inaccuracy = Ti Ttrue (oC) Precision error = Ti T (oC) [See also Excel spreadsheet on the website for this same problem] Example Given: Ten houses are sold in the State College ar ... 
 ORIE_3150_Homework__10_ProblemSet 
 Cornell, ORIE 3150 Excerpt: ... ORIE 3150 Homework #10 Due Thursday, December 4, 2008 Please use an Excel spreadsheet for the IRR and NPV problems. Note that the NPV function in Excel provides incorrect answers; use the method demonstrated in class. 1. Satina Corporation is considering the purchase of a new factory machine. The machine will cost $420,000 today. It will have a useful life of 10 years, with a $20,000 salvage value. Satina plans to use straight line depreciation. The machine will produce annual net income of $60,000 over the useful life. a) Compute the payback period. b) Compute the internal rate of return (IRR). 2. Lamar Company is studying a project that would have an eight-year useful life and require a $2,400,000 investment. At the end of eight years, the project would terminate and the equipment would have no salvage value. The project would provide the same amount of net income each year, as follows: Sales Revenue Variable Expenses Contribution Margin Fixed Expenses: Advertising Depreciation Net Operating Income Income T ... 
 MA103 Lesson 6 
 West Point, MA 103 Excerpt: ... MA103 Lesson 06 As you gather. Open Excel Spreadsheet Exponential Decay Log onto wireless net (Cranite WirelessWall) Start SynchronEyes When prompted for Teacher: usmawkdamath312 MA103 Lesson 06 Admin Notes I will be available WED, 23 AUG during normal class hours for Q&amp;A (DO problems, class work, etc.): G Period TH312 I Period TH324 J Period TH 324 PSL 2 MA103 Course Lecture,&quot;How Math Science and Engineering Affects your Life&quot;. (FRI, Dean&apos;s Hour) Fundamentals of Calculus Exam will be given FRI, Dean&apos;s Hour MA103 Lesson 06 Basic Concept Problem Solve for unknowns a&amp;b given: eqn1: eqn2: 3.04 = a*b^0.1 0.315 = a*b^0.5 MA103 Lesson 06 Modeling with the Exponential Functions (cont) f(x) = a*b^(x+c) + d MA103 Lesson 06 MA103 Lesson 06 Modeling with the Trigonometric Functions f(x) = a*sin[b*(x+c)] + d a = adjusts amplitude b = adjusts period c = adjusts horizontal (phase) shift d = adjusts vertical shift ... 
 How much needed to retire team assignment 
 High Point, BUA 234 Excerpt: ... Team Assignment: How much do you need to retire? To estimate living needs during retirement, an individual must analyze where expenses may increase and where expenses may decrease. 1. What are some examples of additional expense an individual may have during retirement? 2. What are some examples of fewer expenses an individual may have during retirement? 3. An individual must also assume a certain inflation rate or cost of living increase. Why? 4. An individual must also assume a certain rate of return on investments. Why? 5. Complete the following task using the appropriate Excel spreadsheet on my webpage. How much would you need at retirement assuming the following: a. Retirement Goal: 25 years; current age: 45 b. Assume: No Social Security c. For simplification, assume no end-of-life heath care, assisted living, nursing home costs d. Years to live in retirement: spreadsheet manageable. e. Annual after-tax return during retirement: 6 percent 5-this is a low number just to make the f. Annual living ... 
 Excel Header&amp;Footer 
 University of Montana, CS 172 Excerpt: ... CS172-00 Spring 2005 Excel Header Notes In Excel, click View on the tool bar; Select Header/Footer. We will use the custom header footer in this class. Select Custom Header and fill in the different areas as needed with the usual information for headers for this class. Remember, this will not show on an Excel spreadsheet until you print it. It can be viewed or screen captured in Print View. So if you do screen captures for a Word doc, go to Print View to get the header and/or footer. N_excelHeader.doc 1/1 ... 
 Bar and Circle Exercise 
 Maryland, GEOG 170 Excerpt: ... Bar and Circle Maps 1- If the difference between the ratio of the smallest to the largest number is about less than 10, use bars to indicate magnitude. 2- If the difference is&gt;than 10, then use circle to indicate magnitude. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 1037 222 1207 982 1022 1328 791 5 1 5 4 5 6 4 These figures and calculations come from a spreadsheet. Examine the spreadsheet and learn how the figures were derived: Excel Spreadsheet Copy bars from the next slide and insert them on this map. Copy and paste on to your map. Make sure the width of the bar stays the same. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Population South America 1995 (in millions) 22 35 0.8 0.5 not available 12 You will make a circle map of this same data, but because your scale differs from mine your map will slightly differ from this illustrative map. 24 8 5 161 35 14 3 I originally used this scale 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1 10 50 100 175 million Population South America 1995 (in millions) Copy and paste circles from the next slid ... 
 
Subjects

 Math Physics Chemistry History Statistics Biology Engineering Economics Computer Science Education Psychology Law Philosophy English View All 
 
Learning Resources

 Study Guides Reference Materials Practice Exams Labs Lecture Notes Practice Problems Syllabi Textbook Help Tutors Video Lectures Flashcards 
 
Locations

 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas Australia Brazil California Canada China Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida France Georgia Germany Hawaii Idaho Illinois India Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Malaysia Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Other International Pennsylvania Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas United Kingdom Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Yukon Territory 
 
 Sitemap Tutors Educational Concepts Textbooks Blog Study Skills 
 Course Hero is not sponsored or endorsed by any college or university.
Copyright©2012. Course Hero, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
