<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006957" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20110731123249AAoEZzJ" time="2012-07-12-23:56" support="2" score="0.0015238239110035158" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Would you take a job in retail or fast ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Would you take a job in retail or fast food restaurant?">
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>Select &quot;Yes&quot; from the pop up window. ... you take a job in retail or fast food restaurant? ... If the rate of pay and number of hours are the same for each place take ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Other - Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Resolved Question 
 Smile Member since: July 17, 2010 Total points: 280 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Would you take a job in retail or fast food restaurant?
 So long story story short I got offered two jobs one at Burger King and another at Ross. I don&apos;t know which to choose. I&apos;ve never worked in retail or fast food. I have pros and cons for both jobs one being Burger King is really close to my house I don&apos;t even need to drive I could just walk there and Ross it&apos;s a bit far. Another is that Ross seems like a more fun place to work at and you get discounts in clothing:) Which do you think is better to work at? 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by Musicall... Member since: July 30, 2011 Total points: 160 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 I would work retail. Working in the fast food industry is one of the least gratifying jobs out there- I would know, I do it every day- the work is hard, long and tiring. You have to deal with people and food. Those two things don&apos;t mix well. People get very angry over their food. Also, their demeanor towards you is quite negative. I was an honors student in high school and am going to college in the fall. Simply because I work in fast food does not mean I am an idiot. So yeah, given the choice between the two I would definitely work at a clothing store. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: thanks! all were good answers:) and yeah everyone seems to say that even my family and friends so I think I will be taking the job at Ross. I am also going to start college this fall and I would never think someone working at a fast food place would be considered dumb at least that person has a job. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Would you take a job… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (4)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Crazy Babe Member since: April 07, 2009 Total points: 43,515 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I work in retail, it isn&apos;t anything great but I just can&apos;t imagine working in fast food, It just doesn&apos;t appeal to me at all, and I know someone who use to work at Burger King who has made claims they will send employees home if they aren&apos;t busy, even if they are scheduled to work that day, which could kind of suck if you need the hours and pay!

Good Luck to you!! 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by ✮ White Buddha ✮ aka Phoenyx ✮ Member since: November 21, 2008 Total points: 1,318 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I&apos;m working in Dollar General (retail) and so far it is just hell for me. But I can&apos;t imagine a place like Burger King would be any better. A place like Ross sounds like it would be a good option for you. Working with food and people....that could get hectic. Ross seems like it would be less stressful. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by 3 Guesses Member since: May 19, 2011 Total points: 15,667 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If the rate of pay and number of hours are the same for each place take the fast food job. The money you will save not having to travel will be like a hidden bonus. If the extra money isn&apos;t important go for the retail job, the overall climate comfort and lack of greasy floors is great. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Leon Member since: February 13, 2011 Total points: 2,390 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I&apos;d say retail will be more useful on a resume&apos;. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Careers&amp;Employment 

 What career should I choose? Why cant I get a job? Where can a 16 year old who loves animals work? I NEED to quit my job...Help? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Careers&amp;Employment 
 Administrative and Office Support Financial Services Food Service Government&amp;Non-Profit Health Care Law&amp;Legal Marketing&amp;Sales Other - Careers&amp;Employment Technology 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 reed.co.uk Official Site For Job Seekers&amp;Recruiters. Find Jobs or Staff at the UK&apos;s... www.reed.co.uk Job Clab - Work at home. Administrative suport, busines, sales, marketing,... Ordergig.com Job Vacancies Check Our Free Directory And Find A Job That&apos;s Right For You . WowJob.co.uk See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
