<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006460" url="http://www.merchantcircle.com/business/Chickens.Gone.Wild.Inc.914-235-4010" time="2012-07-12-23:23" support="5" score="0.01061093220117037" bingtitle="Chickens Gone Wild Inc, New Rochelle NY 10801" webtitle="Chickens Gone Wild Inc, New Rochelle NY 10801">
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>My family loves this place.We order it once a week. ... loyal customer for 10 years but if their credit card ... Best Fast Food Restaurant. Ttheir food is fresh, has great taste ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading... Autos Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Health&amp;Beauty Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining All Join Now Login Help Dashboard Sign Out Autos Business to Business Community Education Electronics Entertainment and Arts Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Find A Merchant Find A Deal Get Advice 
Find
 Merchants Deals Advice 
In or Around
 I&apos;m Insured I&apos;m Uninsured National  NY  New Rochelle  10801 
 Info Map Blog Products Offers Newsletter 
 View gallery page 
 Chickens Gone Wild Inc 
 
           
 ( 5 ) reviews Write a Review 211 Main St Ste 8 , New Rochelle , NY 10801 914-235-4010 www.chickensgonewild.net 
Member since September 2010
 Hours: Monday-Friday 11-10
Saturday and Sunday 12-10 Payment: Mastercard, Visa Book Appointment Get Directions Connect to Merchant Report Abuse Follow Follow 
5
 Reviews 
&quot;My family loves this place.We order it once a week. The food is amazing. Our favorite is the ribs and the mac and cheese. The staff is wonderful. They are very helpful and friendly. Usually we pick it up but its nice that they have deliervy service incase were not wanting to come out of the house.&quot;
 Mary 
About Chickens Gone Wild Inc
 

The healthier choice for take-out and deliveries. Our food is always cooked fresh!
You&apos;ll go wild for our chicken and ribs



Tags: newrochelle ,
 Sponsored Links 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed 
 0.0 Aji Enterprises 914-633-6822 New Rochelle, NY, 10804 0.0 Soul2Spirit` 914-484-3203 New Rochelle, NY, 10805 0.0 Daniel&apos;s Landscaping 914-652-8443 New Rochelle, NY, 10801 0.0 Agapito Shirley P 9143653522 New Rochelle, NY, 10802 
Related Businesses
 
Write a review about Chickens Gone Wild Inc
   Rate:
           
 Review I would recommend Chickens Gone Wild Inc to my Facebook Friends 
 

 
 
Reviews about Chickens Gone Wild Inc
 Sort by:  Most Helpful | Highest Rated | Most Recent Chickens Gone Wild Inc 5 
gREAT
 
i call 3 times a week for delivery the food is always cooked fresh as you order it and worth the wait.. The young lady that always answers the phone is great and if she tells me its busty and is going to take a while i just go and pick it up myself. The employees are always friendly and i always leave laughing with them. A great place overall
 By tom on September 14, 2010 at 08:25 AM Chickens Gone Wild Inc 5 
Awesome!!!
 
My family loves this place.We order it once a week. The food is amazing. Our favorite is the ribs and the mac and cheese. The staff is wonderful. They are very helpful and friendly. Usually we pick it up but its nice that they have deliervy service incase were not wanting to come out of the house.
 By Mary on September 13, 2010 at 05:13 PM Chickens Gone Wild Inc 5 
Outstanding!
 
Best grilled food in town! We&apos;re originally from Ohio, where most weekends are spent grilling the most delicious food. Normally, New Yorkers can&apos;t replicate the good grilled cuisine (and wholesome side dishes), but Chickens Gone Wild has perfected the art! When our out-of-town relatives and friends come to visit, it is at the top of the restaurants we take them. Delicious! A tad expensive, but worth every cent.
 By RCharlton on September 22, 2009 at 02:47 PM Chickens Gone Wild Inc 2 
Food A+ Customer Appreciation D-
 
You can be a loyal customer for 10 years but if their credit card machine goes down you won&apos;t get a meal on credit til the next day or if you don&apos;t have the cash to get a desert with your meal, you won&apos;t get a desert that day.. all because their credit card machine was down. Not too nice, uhm guys.
 By anonymous on September 20, 2009 at 06:12 PM Chickens Gone Wild Inc 5 
Best Fast Food Restaurant
 
Ttheir food is fresh, has great taste and to make it a much better place - the staff is friendly and polite.
 By Miryam V. on July 17, 2009 at 08:34 AM Chickens Gone Wild Inc 4.4000000000000000 out of 5 5 5 
Browse By Category 
 Autos Electronics Education Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Dining Community Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Legal&amp;Financial Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Business to Business view more 
Get in touch with Chickens Gone Wild Inc
 Get in touch with Chickens Gone Wild Inc (20 Characters Min, 140 Characters Max) Ask Me 
we want free chicken, not free range!


doc

 
Anonymous, March 18, 2010
 
 Read all comments 
 See my entire network 
2 In My Network
 See all my Neighbors 
My Neighbors
 
Related Businesses
 
Sponsored Links
 
Other Local Businesses 
 
Follow Us
 MerchantCircle on Facebook Twitter @merchantcircle MerchantCircle Blog Home | About Us | Blog | Forums | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Support | Answers | Advertise with Us | Developers | Expert Articles Our Partners: Ask Answers  |  Life 123  |  Citysearch  |  Insider Pages  |  Urbanspoon MerchantCircle is a Reply! Inc. property. Other Reply! sites include: Bloglines | iMotors | Contractors.com | EducationHub ©2012 Reply! Inc. All Rights Reserved. CLOSE
	</body>
</document>
