<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006915" url="http://www.businessnameusa.com/Answers/Seafood%20Place.aspx" time="2012-07-12-23:54" support="1" score="0.0036461622708957265" bingtitle="Seafood Place Restaurant" webtitle="Seafood Place Restaurant">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>Seafood Place Home-Based Restaurant. ... you may want to get a federal tax id number. You can obtain all these documents, on this site, online.</description>
	<body>
		Afrikaans (South Africa) Amharic (Ethiopia) Arabic Bengali (Bangladesh) Chinese (Simplified) Chinese (Traditional) English English (United States) French German Hindi (India) Indonesian Italian Japanese (Japan) Korean Malay Marathi (India) Persian Portuguese Portuguese (Brazil) Punjabi Russian Spanish Spanish (United States) Telugu (India) Thai Turkish Vietnamese 
 You are not signed-in. 
 Live Chat * Phone: (310) 455-6675 * Fax (800) 473-2038 
 ** ***** _____________________________________ 
 
 
 
 Home 
 
 Services 
 
 FAQs 
 
 Free Licenses Report 
 
 How Long? 
 
 Pricing 
 
 Get It Now! 
 
 
 
 Get Business License 
 
 Obtain Seller&apos;s Permit 
 
 Register DBA Business Name 
 
 Federal Tax ID Number Application 
 
 Form LLC Limited Liability Company 
 
 Incorporate Your Business Online 
 
 Apply for State Employer ID Number 
 
 
 
 Legal Advice 
 
 FAQ Videos 
 
 Contacts Us 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Seafood Place * * * * Home | Back | | * | * | Next 
 
 
 
 Question:______________________________________________________________________________________ ___________________________________________________________________________ 
 
Wednesday, January 25, 2012 12:31:25 PM 

 
 Cleveland ,



 OH. Seafood Place | 1 Of 5 | Previous | Next | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 
 Question # 304074: Seafood Place
 Starting a(n) 
Restaurant 
Home-Based 

 
with 

Helpers. 

DeJohn Doestch Royal

ZYXCo. 
Start my own 
Cuyahoga County 
Restaurant 
business. 
 
Where to get a 
Cleveland 
Home-Based 
business plan template. 
How do I protect my 
Restaurant 
small business? 
 
Ohio 
44105 
 
Starting a 
OH 
Restaurant 
business. 
Cleveland Cuyahoga County , OH 
44105. 
 Get Started 
 


 
 
 
 # 304074 : In Cleveland, 
Ohio, Here&apos;s What Restaurant Licensing You Need in Cleveland for your 

Home-Based 44105 Business. 


 Required Business Licenses&amp;Tax IDs VIDEO: Frequently Asked Questions 
 
 
 
 

Start my own business.

 

 Answer: Click on tabs 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 for more information. ______________________________________________ Business License Seller&apos;s Permit DBA Biz Name Tax ID Number

 LLC / Corporation

 
 
 
 
 You Need a Business License
 
Starting businesses in the city of Cleveland 
 need to register a(n), OH business permit. Factors a business license is based are 

 Home-Based 
type of business, number of employees, gross income, and or location. 
E.g., you start a
 Restaurant 
business. You will need a businesss license because even home based businesses need a business license and or a home occupation permit.

 Getting a business license is required for Home-Based 
 Restaurant businesses.
 
If your services or products and it includes touchable objects, you will need to obtain a
 Seller&apos;s Permit 
 to use it to buy your merchandise tax exempt.

Also, note that businesses using a company name in 
 Cuyahoga County 
 need to get a(n) 
 DBA Doing Business As Trade Name Registration.

 
 
 You May Need To Get A Seller&apos;s Permit A business license and a DBA is ncessary for most businesses but if your business sells any taxable items, you will need a sales tax ID number. Seller&apos;s Permit (A.K.A Ohio seller&apos;s permit, seller&apos;s license, state id, wholesale, resale, reseller certificate). 

 If you provide 
 Restaurant
 services or products and it includes touchable objects, you will need to obtain a
 Seller&apos;s Permit 
 to use it to buy your merchandise tax exempt. 
 
 You May Need To Apply For a Fictitious Business Name Regisration 



Starting your own Restaurant 
 businesses using a company name in Cuyahoga County need to get a(n) DBA Doing Business As Trade Name Registration. For example, your are a home based business doing busines as your website domain name &quot;www.AA
 Restaurant
 Merchant. com &quot;. The domain name must be registered as a DBA Doing Business As Name or if you are using another trade name that one you will need to file as well.. 
 

If you are thinking of hiring help, you will need a state employer ID and an IRS number employer ID. 
 I.e., a OH Federal Tax Id Number and a(n) OH State Employer Tax Number Note that there are two state tax IDs: a state employer tax ID (EIN) and a sales tax ID ( seller&apos;s permit).
 
 
Instead of filing a fictitious business name DBA Filing in 
 Cleveland, Incorporate in OH or form a(n) OH LLC 
Most likely, you will need to file a trade name certificate. If you incorporate or form an LLC, you don&apos;t need to get a trade name unless the LLC or Corporation Name is different from the trade name. So, for example, your LLC is called &quot;XYZ&quot; LLC but you do business as &quot;Electronics Discount Haven&quot;. You will need to file a fictitious business name under the LLC for that DBA name. _______________________________________________________________________________________________________________ 
 
Instead of filing a Cuyahoga County fictitious business name (our service fee includes dba business name filing and legal paper publication) you can elect to incorporate in 
 Ohio or form an OH LLC (starts @ $199 for most states&amp;includes bylaws and LLC operating agreement).. 

 
 If you do form an Home-Based llc or incorporate your Restaurant business instead of just filing a fictitious business name (dba), 
 it will help you avoid legal and financial personal liability arising out of business transactions and you will not have to register the Cleveland business name.
If you employ workers, you will need a federal EIN and a State EIN tax ID number.
 Note that there are 3 tax ID numbers: A federal tax ID number, a state employer tax ID number and a 
 sales tax ID number ( seller&apos;s permit).

Partnerships, corporations and llcs are required to get a federal tax Id number in addition to other tax ids above. Click on the tabs ( 1,2,3,4,and 5, above ) for more information
 or take this easy and quick quiz ( about 3 minutes) to find out what exactly is required for your business. Click below to take the quiz. 44105,



 
 Get Started 
 





 These Info Also Applies About This Business Type About This Article 
 

 
 
 



 Comments/Questions/Answers 

 
 

 
 Thursday, July 12, 2012 3:24:46 PM Question by Biz Star Up :
 
What licenses do I need for a Business Start Up for an ebay shop?
 

 Thursday, July 12, 2012 12:00:00 AM Answer by B usiness N ameU S A .com: 
 
 Business Start Up 

  Business Consignment eBay 

 Business Start Up Grants 
 
 more... Thursday, July 12, 2012 3:03:46 PM Question by Biz Planner :
 
Do I really need a business plan to start my own small new business from home selling on the internet?  It will be basically an online business.
 

 Thursday, July 12, 2012 12:00:00 AM Answer by B usiness N ameU S A .com: 
 
  Business Plan - How To Get a Business Plan 

  Business Plan Writer 
 
 more... 
 
 


 Enter Comments Or Ask A Question 
 
 
 Add Comments 
 
 
 
 User   * Email   * Privacy Guaranteed 

Email will NOT be published! Date 
 
 
   * 
 Enter Comment or Question 
 Submit Question or Comment 
 
 
 




 
 

 
 
 Description 
 Starting a restaurant business is perhaps a good idea because most people today want to eat out or take food home.  Even though we have about 1,000,000 food service establishments as of 2012, there may still be some opportunity out there.
Most consumers want to have a fast and tasty meal, quickly.  That makes the to go food industry more attractive but some say, even despite  that, the restaurant business is not the easiest to make a lot of money.
If you can provide real good food and service coupled with great people to serve it, as well as a good a simple operation, you may have a good chance of succeeding in this business.  However, if you don’t know about serving or cooking food, a restaurant may not be for you.
But who your clients are going to be?  
Those from 15 to 25 year old eat out and usually they eat to go or fast foods.  So a fast food restaurant may be a good idea to target them.  The 25 to 45 crowd likes a more gourmet but yet fast type of service.  So a regular, not so formal restaurant may be ok If you want to cater to this group.  To serve the crowd from 45 and above, you may want to have an upscale restaurant and or a family upscale restaurant.    
Finally, keep everything clean, smelling well and elegant and you may be able to make some money operating a restaurant.

 
 
 
 
 
 
Restaurant Permit Cleveland Business License
 44105 Restaurant Business Plan Template Ohio Business License Restaurant Cuyahoga County DBA Fictitious Business Name 
 Get Started 
 Seafood Place | 1 Of 4 | Previous | Next 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 
 
 
 
 

 

 





 
 
 
 
 Home 
 
 Services 
 
 FAQs 
 
 Free Licenses Report 
 
 How Long? 
 
 Pricing 
 
 Get It Now! 
 
 
 
 Get Business License 
 
 Obtain Seller&apos;s Permit 
 
 Register DBA Business Name 
 
 Federal Tax ID Number Application 
 
 Form LLC Limited Liability Company 
 
 Incorporate Your Business Online 
 
 Apply for State Employer ID Number 
 
 
 
 Legal Advice 
 
 FAQ Videos 
 
 Contacts Us 
 
 
 
 



 
 
 

 
 
 Dirt Pitt How Do I Start A Business In Hidalgo Tx Thursday, July 12, 2012 4:41:08 PM SEW MACHINE REPAIR DO I NEED A LICENSE TO REPAIR SEWING MACHINES Thursday, July 12, 2012 4:28:03 PM 
 
 
 
 
 
 






 View BusinessNameUSA.com in: Mobile | Desktop 
 
 Contacts | About Us | Terms | Testimonials | Privacy Policy | Articles | Questions&amp;Answers | Sitemap 
 Copyright
	</body>
</document>
