<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006387" url="http://hot-trends.noduplicatecontent.com/chill-soda/" time="2012-07-12-23:15" support="6" score="0.01716222328713301" bingtitle="Information about chill soda" webtitle="Information about   chill soda">
			<query id="000079" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000088" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000063" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>FAST FOOD RESTAURANT CARD US $15.00 Civil War Antique ... US $117.49 Dry Topping Dispenser US $400.00 ... in this are pretty concentrated so the club soda ...</description>
	<body>
		Hot Trend Research Tool 
 from NoDuplicateContent.com 
 Home How to Use This Site Privacy Policy 
 Home &gt; Hot Search Trends &gt;chill soda 
chill soda
 October 14th, 2009 
Related Amazon Products
 
 
 Top Secret Recipes: Sodas, Smoothies, Spirits,&amp;Shakes 
 List Price: $15.00 
 Sale Price: $6.15 
 You save: $8.85 (59%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 
 Can It, Bottle It, Smoke It: And Other Kitchen Projects 
 List Price: $24.99 
 Sale Price: $15.31 
 You save: $9.68 (39%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 

 
 A History of the World in 6 Glasses 
 List Price: $15.95 
 Sale Price: $10.20 
 You save: $5.75 (36%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 
 Vacu Vin Rapid Ice Silver Can Chillers, Set of 2 
 Sale Price: $9.99 
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 

 
 Smart Planet 16-Ounce Double-Wall Plastic Cold-Drink Cup with Reusable Straw 
 Sale Price: $5.23 
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 
 Just Chill Tropical 4-Pack 
 List Price: $8.00 
 Sale Price: $6.00 
 You save: $2.00 (25%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 24 hours
 
 

 
 Sparkling ICE Spring Water, Orange Mango, 17-Ounce Bottles (Pack of 12) 
 List Price: $14.28 
 Sale Price: $8.99 
 You save: $5.29 (37%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 
 Firefly Tonics Chill out, 330ml 
 List Price: $37.99 
 
 

 
 Chill N&apos; Soda 
 List Price: $11.98 
 Sale Price: $6.15 
 You save: $5.83 (49%)
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 1-2 business days
 
 
 Chill N&apos; Soda - A Chill Out Tribute To Soda Stereo 
 Sale Price: $15.99 
    Eligible for free shipping! 
 Availability: Usually ships in 24 hours
 
 
 

 «Previous 1 2 3 4 5 ... 17 18 Next» 
Related EBay Products
 
 US Auctions Australian Auctions Austrian Auctions Belgian Auctions Canadian Auctions French Auctions German Auctions Hong Kong Auctions Indian Auctions Irish Auctions Italian Auctions Dutch Auctions Polish Auctions Singapore Auctions Spanish Auctions Swiss Auctions UK Auctions Best Match Time: ending soonest Time: newly listed Price: lowest first Price: highest first Price + Shipping: lowest first Price + Shipping: highest first 

 
 USI Wittern Chill Center combo vending machine Mercado Styling 
    US $2,295.00 
 
Yahoo Answers - Resolved Questions

 Resolved Question: A student put a bottle of water and a can of sugared soda in the freezer to chill them quickly.? - 
 When she took them out, the bottle of water was frozen but the can of soda was not. Explain why this happened. 
Please help!! Resolved Question: Chilling soda outside? - 
 OK so we are having a small party on Monday in the Chicago area the overnight temperature is going to be 23 degrees. The question is: If I place the soda outside right next to the building or on the back deck. It will chill them yet it will freeze them if left out all night, the party is at 12 noon would first thing in the morning make them cold enough? OH they are cans of soda, any and all help is welcomed, Thank you. Resolved Question: How long in the freezer does it take to chill a soda? - 
 Don&apos;t reply, &quot;Go home Steve&quot;

it&apos;s getting old. Resolved Question: How long would it take for a soda to be ice cold if I chilled it in a freezer? - 
 I have a bunch of room temperature sodas, and I have a party to set up. Estimated how long would it take for a soda to be ice cold if it was chilled in a freezer? Resolved Question: What goes well with chilled soda ? Resolved Question: Why can soda be chilled below 32 degrees and not freeze? Resolved Question: Why does warm soda go flat faster than chilled soda? - 
 A) Gas molecules stay dissolved in warm soda. 

B) Gas molecules move slower in warm soda. 

C) Gas molecules move faster in warm soda. 

D) Gas molecules cannot escape in warm soda. 

E) Gas molecules stay trapped with the solvent in warm soda. Resolved Question: Why does warm soda go flat faster than chilled soda? Resolved Question: how long to chill a glass bottled soda in the freezer? - 
 It is at room temp.now.How long do you think that it will take it to be nice and chilled once placed in the freezer?Thanks guys. Resolved Question: i get chills, dizziness, and an urge to vomit after drinking soda or coffee, what do you think is the problem? 

Forum Search - Exact Match



Blog Search - Exact Match



News Search



YouTube Search - Exact Match

 Super Chill Soda - 
 Super Chill Soda 
 Commercial project for Super Chill soda From: TeamRocketFDM Views: 7 0 ratings Time: 01:05 More in Comedy 
 Shark Tank&apos;s AfterShark: Dan Mackey of Chill Soda - 
 Shark Tank&apos;s AfterShark: Dan Mackey of Chill Soda 
 An episode of AfterShark, post-show video interviews with the people who appear on the ABC show&quot;Shark Tank.&quot; From: bastablejc Views: 2533 3 ratings Time: 05:26 More in Entertainment 
 Super Mr Chill Soda?! - 
 Super Mr Chill Soda?! 
 This soda isn&apos;t too bad for an experiment. From: AvastYeFailboat Views: 2149 235 ratings Time: 06:13 More in People&amp;Blogs 
 Chill n soda &quot;Tratame Suavemente&quot; Soda Stereo - 
 Chill n soda&quot;Tratame Suavemente&quot;Soda Stereo 
 Tributo a Soda Stereo version Lounge artista=Mai Kai (BBA Mix) From: rokanraver Views: 187019 290 ratings Time: 03:20 More in Music 
 Two-minute Soda Chill - 
 Two-minute Soda Chill 
 time rebate: 1 month of your life. .:from waitless.org:. From: guitaraddict29 Views: 20902 13 ratings Time: 00:29 More in Education 
 How to Chill Soda Fast - 
 How to Chill Soda Fast 
 From: Rehantts Views: 1145 8 ratings Time: 01:29 More in Howto&amp;Style 
 Chill A Coke In 2 Minutes! - 
 Chill A Coke In 2 Minutes! 
 Superchill soda, beer and other drinks quickly! Here&apos;s the secret! If you don&apos;t want ice in your drink, this is the way to do it! Check out my&apos;secret&apos;classic videos: www.kipkay.com Laser Videos: bit.ly Easy Projects: bit.ly Pranks&amp;Jokes: bit.ly Hacks&amp;Mods: bit.ly Spy Gadgets&amp;Devices: bit.ly Explosions&amp;Loud Things: bit.ly From: kipkay Views: 6854275 11732 ratings Time: 00:57 More in Science&amp;Technology 
 DILL CHILL SODA - 
 DILL CHILL SODA 
 Ad for Dill Chill Soda ToomuchFilms Commentary: This one was fun to do, we got better in later videos on our editing,our early works are what they are and we leave them as is. From: ToomuchFilms Views: 697 6 ratings Time: 01:51 More in Comedy 
 how to chill soda - 
 how to chill soda 
 this is how to make soda (or beer) really cold really fast From: cody739 Views: 849 4 ratings Time: 02:10 More in Howto&amp;Style 
 Chill n&apos; Soda - Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) - 
 Chill n&apos;Soda - Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) 
 A Chill Out Tribute To Soda Stereo Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) Año: 2006 Artista: Adä From: Languis3207 Views: 27284 91 ratings Time: 05:14 More in Music 
 

Forum Search - Broad Match



Blog Search - Broad Match



YouTube Search - Broad Match

 Shark Tank&apos;s AfterShark: Dan Mackey of Chill Soda - 
 Shark Tank&apos;s AfterShark: Dan Mackey of Chill Soda 
 An episode of AfterShark, post-show video interviews with the people who appear on the ABC show&quot;Shark Tank.&quot; From: bastablejc Views: 2533 3 ratings Time: 05:26 More in Entertainment 
 Super Mr Chill Soda?! - 
 Super Mr Chill Soda?! 
 This soda isn&apos;t too bad for an experiment. From: AvastYeFailboat Views: 2149 235 ratings Time: 06:13 More in People&amp;Blogs 
 Chill n soda &quot;Tratame Suavemente&quot; Soda Stereo - 
 Chill n soda&quot;Tratame Suavemente&quot;Soda Stereo 
 Tributo a Soda Stereo version Lounge artista=Mai Kai (BBA Mix) From: rokanraver Views: 187019 290 ratings Time: 03:20 More in Music 
 Two-minute Soda Chill - 
 Two-minute Soda Chill 
 time rebate: 1 month of your life. .:from waitless.org:. From: guitaraddict29 Views: 20902 13 ratings Time: 00:29 More in Education 
 Chill A Coke In 2 Minutes! - 
 Chill A Coke In 2 Minutes! 
 Superchill soda, beer and other drinks quickly! Here&apos;s the secret! If you don&apos;t want ice in your drink, this is the way to do it! Check out my&apos;secret&apos;classic videos: www.kipkay.com Laser Videos: bit.ly Easy Projects: bit.ly Pranks&amp;Jokes: bit.ly Hacks&amp;Mods: bit.ly Spy Gadgets&amp;Devices: bit.ly Explosions&amp;Loud Things: bit.ly From: kipkay Views: 6854275 11732 ratings Time: 00:57 More in Science&amp;Technology 
 The Chills - Juicy Creaming Soda (live at the Windsor Castle, Auckland, 10 May 1985) - 
 The Chills - Juicy Creaming Soda (live at the Windsor Castle, Auckland, 10 May 1985) 
 &quot;Juicy Creaming Soda&quot;was among the first generation of songs that Martin Phillipps wrote for The Chills, along with other compositions such as&quot;I Saw Your Silhouette&quot;,&quot;Rolling Moon&quot;,&quot;16 Heart Throbs&quot;and&quot;Lost In Space&quot;, among others. It was first performed in early 1981 and remained in the band&apos;s set until the demise of the Phase 9 line up in February 1986, however it has been occasionally performed by Martin Phillipps at solo shows since then. Unfortunately the song was never properly recorded in a studio, and eventually a live recording of the song, recorded at a concert in Dunedin from the mixing desk onto a cassette recorder under a month before this performance was filmed, was included on disk one of the 3CD&quot;Secret Box&quot;compilation, released in 2000. This concert was filmed by Bob Sutton on a Panasonic video camera, the same video camera that was used to film the Doublehappys&quot;Needles and Plastic&quot;video (with negative effect seen briefly at the start) the following month. This was digitised from the original master tape in December 2010. The Chills lineup at this point was Martin Phillipps (guitars/vocals), Terry Moore (bass/vocals), Peter Allison (keyboards/vocals), Alan Haig (drums). From: GreenEyedOwl Views: 567 9 ratings Time: 04:16 More in Music 
 DILL CHILL SODA - 
 DILL CHILL SODA 
 Ad for Dill Chill Soda ToomuchFilms Commentary: This one was fun to do, we got better in later videos on our editing,our early works are what they are and we leave them as is. From: ToomuchFilms Views: 697 6 ratings Time: 01:51 More in Comedy 
 how to chill soda - 
 how to chill soda 
 this is how to make soda (or beer) really cold really fast From: cody739 Views: 849 4 ratings Time: 02:10 More in Howto&amp;Style 
 Cooper Cooler rapid beverage&amp;wine chiller, chill beer, soda, wine in minutes faster than peltier - 
 Cooper Cooler rapid beverage&amp;wine chiller, chill beer, soda, wine in minutes faster than peltier 
 Please view our Cooper Cooler-rapid beverage&amp;wine chiller video. Our Cooper Cooler is the fastest way to chill your warm beverages to refrigerator or ice cold in minutes. Great for chilling wine to the proper serving temperature without the guesswork of an ice bucket or placing it in the freezer and much faster too. For more information visit www.CooperCooler.com From: StockChiller Views: 16547 6 ratings Time: 02:08 More in Science&amp;Technology 
 Chill n&apos; Soda - Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) - 
 Chill n&apos;Soda - Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) 
 A Chill Out Tribute To Soda Stereo Persiana Americana (+ Natural Mix) Año: 2006 Artista: Adä From: Languis3207 Views: 27284 91 ratings Time: 05:14 More in Music 
 

Image Search



Google Insight - Related and Rising Searches

Yahoo Answers - Open Questions



Related Keyword Suggestions
(Hit Submit to see the list of suggested Keywords.)
 Enter Keyword (Theme) 
 
 Comments are closed. jaycee dugard people magazine gayla bentley RSS 
 Google Youdao Xian Guo Zhua Xia My Yahoo! newsgator Bloglines iNezha 
 
Write UNIQUE Content, FAST!
 
Tons of strategies and tools to help you break writer&apos;s block, and crank out articles or blog posts for your internet marketing campaigns:

 

 --&gt; &quot;Uniquification&quot; Tool Kit&lt;-- 

 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 
 
Meta

 Log in 
 Top WordPress Copyright©2009-2012 Hot Trend Research Tool Theme by NeoEase . Valid XHTML 1.1 and CSS 3 .
	</body>
</document>
