<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006468" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/how-eat-healthy-fast-food-restaurant-25223.html" time="2012-07-12-23:24" support="5" score="0.10028812423932894" bingtitle="How to Eat &quot;Healthy&quot; at a Fast Food Restaurant - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="How to Eat &quot;Healthy&quot; at a Fast Food Restaurant - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>How to Eat &quot;Healthy&quot; at a Fast Food Restaurant The Old Saying &quot;Think Before Opening Your Mouth&quot; is Also Appropriate when Eating</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
How to Eat &quot;Healthy&quot; at a Fast Food Restaurant

The Old Saying &quot;Think Before Opening Your Mouth&quot; is Also Appropriate when Eating
 Gary Picariello , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Mar 22, 2006 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food Eating Healthy Fast Food Restaurants Eat Healthier 
 Flag Close I was in Naples, Italy recently, standing in line with my family at the Italian equivalent to a McDonalds, and wondering how many years of my life I was canceling out by ordering their advertised &quot;Double-Happy Burger&quot; and &quot;Fun Fries&quot; combo.
I wonder why they even call it &quot;fast food&quot; when I&apos;ve been standing in line for 20 minutes! But the issue here isn&apos;t speed, its health. More to the issue, Can &quot;fast food&quot; really be healthy?

Whether or not fast food is good for us for us remains a tough question. I imagine families who care about their health and healthy fast food meals usually avoid eating in fast food restaurants to begin with. I glance down at my daughter. She doesn&apos;t look like a small Sumo wrestler. That&apos;s got to count for something.

I have read the rap sheet about fast food and it&apos;s a mile long: high in calories, saturated fats and sodium. The big three that will put you in an early grave. But I&apos;m convinced you can eat &quot;healthy&quot; at a fast food restaurant. It takes a little imagination and will power but it can be done. If a chow-hound like me can do it, then so can you.

The big challenge to eating &quot;healthy&quot; fast food comes down to one word: F-A-T.
Remember, there are &quot;healthy&quot; fats and &quot;unhealthy&quot; fats. Guess which one clogs your arteries like Friday traffic on the Chicago beltway?

Healthy fat lowers your cholesterol level, and in the process decreases the risk of heart disease. The healthiest fats are derived from olive oil. And you don&apos;t need to live in Italy to find some (although it doesn&apos;t hurt). Saturated fats belong to the unhealthy fat group. This is the fat that we find in so-called fast food restaurants. Food items that are fried are full of saturated fat.

Right next door to fat content is calorie content. It&apos;s difficult to distribute your minimum calorie intake of 3500 calories a day when 1900 of those babies are sitting on your plate in the form of a double-bacon-cheeseburger, large fries and a shake. Trust me - you are kidding yourself if you wolf it all down and think &quot;you&apos;ll burn it off at the gym&quot;.

If you sock away the majority of calories at one meal this can cause the body to store fat. It&apos;s actually better to consume a larger amount of calories during breakfast and lunch. It will also be easier to keep calories in check if you eat a SMALL MEAL and that goes for fast food restaurants. There in lies the secret. Well, our secret anyway.

I&apos;m honest enough to admit that I didn&apos;t go to Happy-Burger to get a salad. I want to experience the pleasure of eating a hamburger and feeling the grease dribble down my chin. So the solution is for us to order &quot;small&quot;. Kind of like someone who smokes, and takes a drag or two off their cigarette before putting it out. The psychological effect of eating a hamburger was met. (And we didn&apos;t overdo it and I now I have some money left over for a movie).

Eating &quot;healthy&quot; at a fast food restaurant doesn&apos;t always mean eating salads. It means eating &quot;smart&quot;. Small helpings and stop when you feel full. And by the way, eating chicken nuggets or any other kind of deep-fried chicken kind of defeats the purpose of eating chicken in the first place. Sorry if I spoiled your fun.

So the majority of restaurants, including quite a few in Europe are going out of their way to offer healthy fast food choices. &quot;Healthy Menus&quot; are the norm, and every fast food establishment posts a breakdown of what the calorie content is on all their items. it was bound to happen. And it shouldn&apos;t have taken someone sueing McDonalds to be the impetus of such a move.

I&apos;m no nutritionist, but even I was able to connect the dots eventually when it came to eating healthy in a fast food restaurant.

Eat smart. Eat Healthy. Live longer. It&apos;s that simple.
 
Published by Gary Picariello 

I&apos;ve traveled the world as a Broadcast Journalist working for the American Forces Radio&amp;Television Service in the United States Air Force. Now happily retired after 23 years of service, and currently livin...  View profile 
 
 How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants Most of us have eaten inside a fast food restaurant at least once in our lives, if only to drop in for a quick lunch while traveling cross-country with the family. Staying safe... Healthy Fast Food Choices When we must eat fast food, we can still choose healthy fast food options that will help us keep our calories, fat content, and salt intake at healthy levels. Healthier Fast Food Options...They Really Do Exist Using the Weight Watchers Points Plan takes the guesswork out of what not to eat at a fast food restaurant. How to Eat Healthy on the Go Picking healthy food choices is not hard, even if you are on the go and away from the comforts of home. &quot;Healthy&quot; Fast Food: America&apos;s Biggest Oxymoron Seldom today can one go anywhere without being bombarded by food advertisements. Whether it&apos;s a high-rise billboard or a ten second radio commercial, food has worked its way into the everyday lives of Americans. 
 
 How to Eat Healthy at Arby&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Can You Really Eat Healthy Fast Food? Ways to Eat Healthy at the Mall Food Court How to Eat Healthy at Boston Market Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 
 Resources Takeaways Did You Know 
 
 www.inch-aweigh.comwww.leehayward.comwww.shapefit.com 
 
 small portions are SMART portions, stay away from condiments, fried foods will kill you 
 Adequate protein intake will keep your metabolism high, prevent muscle loss, and help your add lean muscle while you lose bodyfat. Every gram of protein contains 4 calories. You should eat 1 gram of protein per pound of bodyweight each day. 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Health and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
