<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006974" url="http://www.shopping.com/1-87-scale-model-bus/products" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="3" score="0.004054369606055713" bingtitle="&quot;1 87 scale model bus&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="1 87 scale model bus- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>... After purchasing, pay instantly with your credit card ... is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant ... MIB -- you will receive a new item in its original ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Model bus ,  1 76 bus ,  Bus model scale metal ,  Scale model gm buses more»    less» Shopping 
 1 87 scale model bus 
 Showing results for &quot;
1 87 scale model bus
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ 
 Detecto T-25-SB (T25SB) Top Loading Dial Scale with Bowl-Stainless Steel Finish 
 Detecto T-25-SB (T25SB) Top Loading Dial Scale with Bowl-Stainless Steel Finish from $192.99 Free Shipping 5 stores See Details 
 Model Car Display Case That Is For 1:24 Scale Cars Model Car Display Case That Is For 1:24 Scale Cars 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This model car display case is for showcasing 1:24 scale models. The lift-up clear plastic displayer is for tabletop use only. This model car display case has a black base to focus... More 

This model car display case is for showcasing 1:24 scale models. The lift-up clear plastic displayer is for tabletop use only. This model car display case has a black base to focus attention on a displayed car. The unit is 9.375&quot;w x 3&quot;h x 3.875&quot;d. This model car display case is a necessity for miniature car collectors! The entire showcase measures 9-3/8&quot;w x 3&quot;h x 3-7/8&quot;d, enabling diecast collectors to exhibit 1:24 scale vehicles. This model car display case features a see-through top casing with a black platform to easily coordinate with any settings. Each unit is fabricated from injection-molded plastic for affordability. As a result, this inexpensive model car display case is perfect for diecast fans looking to purchase a showcase on a budget! Your collectibles will remain virtually dust free within this plastic casing. This model car display case that has a black platform highlights your collectibles in style. The see-through casing also allows visitors to view the displayed items from all angles. This model car display case features a lift-off top. Users can easily access the displayed items with no tools required. As a result, this model car display case that is not lockable is ideal for use in toy stores, for displaying newly released automobiles like trucks, buses, trains and motorcycles. However, they are not recommended for museum or gallery use. This model car display case, such as a countertop displayer, is often used to exhibit limited edition model vehicles in auto dealership on a countertop. Besides using these showcases to exhibit collectibles, they can also be given as gifts on special occasions to collectors of Nascar (R) models. Dimensions: Overall Size: 9-1/2&quot;w x 3-3/4&quot;h x 4&quot;d Inside Size: 9-3/8&quot;w x 3&quot;h x 3-7/8&quot;d Material: Injection-Molded Polystyrene Weight: less than 1 lb. Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /model-car-display-case/fSIz-M2FpAuh7NJ2korOSA==/info $11.60 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Top Loader Scale 16 Oz X 1/4 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Top Loader Scale 16 Oz X 1/4 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial 
 New ( In stock ) 
Top Loader Scale 16 Oz X 1/4 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of... More 

Top Loader Scale 16 Oz X 1/4 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of capacities listed below. Sturdy construction, stability, convenient viewing angle, temperature compensation for dependable accuracy in environments with fluctuating temperatures and easy readability make these the petite top loaders of choice. Whether the operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant, formulating paint mixtures by weight, verifying parcel weights in a shipping department, portioning in service areas, or counting by weight, there is a Detecto Top Loader right for the task. 12.00 L. 9.00 W. 9.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /top-loader-scale-16-oz-x/bQKY11ua7QvNf2HFo1rK-Q==/info $49.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Top Loader Scale 32 Oz X 1/8 Oz Enamel Finish 8&quot; Rotating Dial Top Loader Scale 32 Oz X 1/8 Oz Enamel Finish 8&quot; Rotating Dial 
 New ( In stock ) 
Top Loader Scale 32 Oz X 1/8 Oz Enamel Finish 8&quot; Rotating Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The T Series comes in a variety of... More 

Top Loader Scale 32 Oz X 1/8 Oz Enamel Finish 8&quot; Rotating Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The T Series comes in a variety of capacities listed below with your choice of stainless steel or enamel finishes. An easy-to-clean surface, sturdy construction, stability, convenient viewing angle, and easy readability make these attractive top loaders an ideal choice for your weighing needs. Whether the operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant, formulating paint mixtures by weight, verifying parcel weights in a shipping department, portioning in service areas, or counting by weight, there is a Detecto Top Loader right for the task. 17.00 L. 15.00 W. 11.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /top-loader-scale-32-oz-x/g1P--nwNIHfVFDQ_1DxJmQ==/info $131.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Detecto Pt 5r (pt5r) Petite Top Loading Dial Scale 
 Detecto Pt 5r (pt5r) Petite Top Loading Dial Scale from $59.11 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details -20% 
 1:18 Display Case for Scale Model Car 1:18 Display Case for Scale Model Car 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This 1:18 display case perfectly showcases a model car or vehicles. The clear, injection-molded polystyrene plastic casing has a lift-off cover to easy setup. This 1:18 display case... More 

This 1:18 display case perfectly showcases a model car or vehicles. The clear, injection-molded polystyrene plastic casing has a lift-off cover to easy setup. This 1:18 display case measures 13.25&quot;w x 5.5&quot;h x 5.75&quot;d. Sold as a case pack of 6 units. This cheap 1:18 display case is a necessity for car lovers to keep their collectible in spotless condition. The plastic displayer is designed to hold a 1/18 scale model car. Each 1:18 display case can also be used to exhibit replicas of ships, trucks, motorcycles, planes and other collectibles that can fit in the showcase. The clear finish of this plastic displayer enables the unit to easily blend in with any countertop area it is placed in. This 1:18 display case that is see-through provides an unobstructed view of the displayed items. The casing can be used at home or in an office, to present classic muscle automobile models. This plastic 1:18 display case, called a countertop showcase, is also great for advertising new model cars for sale in collectible stores. A clear displayer, like the one seen here, is also ideal for use in souvenir stores, for displaying limited edition collectibles as well. This 1:18 display case that features a lift-up top enables users to easily access the displayed item. To exhibit items, simply lift the top of the casing, and place your collectibles on the base. This 1:18 display case that is sold at an affordable price is made from injection molded polystyrene plastic. As a result, these units are less expensive than comparable models crafted from acrylic or glass. This unit is also available in many other sizes to accommodate different model vehicles (see related products). Purchase this clear showcase and keep your model car free from dust, finger prints and other harmful elements. This plastic countertop displayer ships fully assembled to customers. Click here for instruction on how to secure the model car to the base. Dimensions: Overall Size: 13-1/4&quot;w x 5-1/2&quot;h x 5-3/4&quot;d Inside Size: 13&quot;w x 5&quot;h x 5-1/2&quot;d Material: Injection-Molded Polystyrene Weight: less than 1 lb. Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /118-display-case-for/uzHFuL2UgQs4OiUEL2A0LA==/info $29.70 $23.76 20% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial 
 New ( In stock ) 
Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of... More 

Top Loader Scale 5 Lb X 1/2 Oz Enamel Finish 6&quot; Fixed Dial Whatever your need in a top-loading dial scale, Detecto has a model to handle the job. The PT Series comes in a variety of capacities listed below. Sturdy construction, stability, convenient viewing angle, temperature compensation for dependable accuracy in environments with fluctuating temperatures and easy readability make these the petite top loaders of choice. Whether the operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant, formulating paint mixtures by weight, verifying parcel weights in a shipping department, portioning in service areas, or counting by weight, there is a Detecto Top Loader right for the task. 12.00 L. 9.00 W. 9.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /top-loader-scale-5-lb-x/vd5xO_9x839C2_qRXrRn3Q==/info $54.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Ho 1:87 Scale Motorart Volvo Nettbus Model Bus 18199 Ho 1:87 Scale Motorart Volvo Nettbus Model Bus 18199 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
quareTrade AP6.0 NEW IN BOX.Hard to find mint.Quality Motorart #18199 Volvo NETTBUS.Detailed interior. A beauty. ( HO 1:87 Model Railroad Scale). Fully assembled and painted. Die-cast... More 

quareTrade AP6.0 NEW IN BOX.Hard to find mint.Quality Motorart #18199 Volvo NETTBUS.Detailed interior. A beauty. ( HO 1:87 Model Railroad Scale). Fully assembled and painted. Die-cast metal.This is 1:87 scale collectors model... NOT a child&apos;s toy.Bus measures about 6-1/2 inches &quot; bumper to bumper &quot;. A good value. We accept PayPal for payment. Payment DUE SEVEN DAYS from purchase or item is relisted and NPB filed with eBay.Buyer pays ONLY 4.95 USPS Domestic Shipping. International shipping is Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /ho-187-scale-motorart/jnqpbotVZwMs2Mtc0WLIhA==/info $14.95 +$4.95 shipping Visit Store http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/4d/c5/7a/119443431-100x100-0-0_detecto+detecto+t+1+kp+t1kp+top+loading+scales+lar.jpg 
 Detecto T-1-KP (T1KP) Top Loading Scales Large Mechanical 
 Detecto T-1-KP (T1KP) Top Loading Scales Large Mechanical from $93.95 Free Shipping 3 stores See Details http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/8d/05/1d/51947957-100x100-0-0_Daron+Daron+Worldwide+Trading+B5310+B+2+Stealth+Bo.jpg 
 Daron Worldwide Trading B5310 B-2 Stealth Bomber 1/100 AIRCRAFT 
 Daron Worldwide Trading B5310 B-2 Stealth Bomber 1/100 AIRCRAFT from $112.47 Free Shipping 5 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/55/55/73/6837677837395f5231726c6d785f652d325941-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Model Display Case for 1:18 Scale Diecast Car Model Display Case for 1:18 Scale Diecast Car 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This model display case is designed specifically to hold a model car. The clear acrylic container includes a locking mechanism to keep expensive items safe. This model display case has a... More 

This model display case is designed specifically to hold a model car. The clear acrylic container includes a locking mechanism to keep expensive items safe. This model display case has a black aluminum frame and measures 13.5&quot;w x 6.75&quot;h x 7.5&quot;d. This model display case that holds 1:18 models is designed to keep your collectibles and diecast cars in mint condition! Each acrylic box features a lift off top, enabling users to have easy access to the displayed items. The black acrylic platform makes your collectible items stand out, ensuring they get noticed. This countertop plastic holder, model display case can be used to present replicas of military vehicles or war ships. Car lovers also use these items to show off their classic, 1:18 scale collectible muscle cars. This acrylic display case can also be used to showcase model trains, buses or other objects that can fit into the casing. This model display case that holds 1:18 model cars is constructed from acrylic with a smooth, beveled aluminum frame. This design creates a flawless presentation, where visitors can view the displayed items from every perspective. Crafted from acrylic, these units are less inexpensive than custom-made glass showcases, and are more durable than those crafted from cheap plastic. This model display case, also called a diecast car displayer, is ideal for showcasing miniature car replicas at an auto show. These units can also be used to hold antiques or sculptures in your living room. Retail stores also use this countertop showcase to display new collectible toy arrivals. Each of these plastic cases features a locking mechanism (with Allen key included) to protect your valuable collections from dust and unwanted handling. Dimensions: Overall: 13-1/2&quot;w x 6-3/4&quot;h x 7-1/2&quot;d Inside Size: 12-3/4&quot;w x 5-1/2&quot;h x 6-3/4&quot;d Weight: 5.5 lbs. Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /model-display-case-for/UUsh7gx79_R1rlmx_e-2YA==/info $89.65 No Shipping Info Visit Store -39% http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/5a/5f/72702d623861315152796850476b5256442d51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 A&amp;D Weighing Portion Control Scale - 44 lb x 1 oz Capacity A&amp;D Weighing Portion Control Scale - 44 lb x 1 oz Capacity 
 Portion Control ScaleThe SKWPZ Series of stainless steel washdown portion control scales are accurate, fast, and portable. All SKWPZ models are NSF certified and built to withstand the toughest foodservice and food processing environments. Capacity 44 lb x 0.02 lb, 20 kg x 0.01 kg, 44 lb x 1 oz Waterproof and dustproof to IP-65 standards Battery powered (6 D Cells) Optional AC Adaptor Large (25mm), Easy to read LCD display Removable Stainless Steel Weigh Pan Temperature Compensated 2-year Warranty Full range tare/zero Net Weight and Stability Indicators Low Battery Indicator Auto Power OffNote: The picture shown may only be similar to the product being sold. Please refer to this description for specific details regarding this product. ( In stock ) 
Portion Control ScaleThe SKWPZ Series of stainless steel washdown portion control scales are accurate, fast, and portable. All SKWPZ models are NSF certified and built to withstand the... More 

Portion Control ScaleThe SKWPZ Series of stainless steel washdown portion control scales are accurate, fast, and portable. All SKWPZ models are NSF certified and built to withstand the toughest foodservice and food processing environments. Capacity 44 lb x 0.02 lb, 20 kg x 0.01 kg, 44 lb x 1 oz Waterproof and dustproof to IP-65 standards Battery powered (6 D Cells) Optional AC Adaptor Large (25mm), Easy to read LCD display Removable Stainless Steel Weigh Pan Temperature Compensated 2-year Warranty Full range tare/zero Net Weight and Stability Indicators Low Battery Indicator Auto Power OffNote: The picture shown may only be similar to the product being sold. Please refer to this description for specific details regarding this product. Less 
 Instawares, LLC 371 store reviews See Store Info /a-d-weighing-portion/PZ_rp-b8a1QRyhPGkRVD-Q==/info $420.00 $255.99 39% Off +$23.04 shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/42/30/42/527a484c6651617a4d78545435776d69447767-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Imex Ho Scale Greyhound Bus Station Resin Built-up Building Imex Ho Scale Greyhound Bus Station Resin Built-up Building 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
IMEX MODEL COMPANY, INC. GREYHOUND BUS STATION HO SCALE BUILDING ... 1/87 RESIN BUILT-UP by PERMA-SCENE Pre-colored Dimensions: 6-1/2&quot; x 7&quot; x 4-1/2&quot; NIB IMEX 6119 Multiple purchases will be... More 

IMEX MODEL COMPANY, INC. GREYHOUND BUS STATION HO SCALE BUILDING ... 1/87 RESIN BUILT-UP by PERMA-SCENE Pre-colored Dimensions: 6-1/2&quot; x 7&quot; x 4-1/2&quot; NIB IMEX 6119 Multiple purchases will be combined to save on shipping Visit my eBay store for additional N scale items After purchasing, pay instantly with your credit card through PayPal! International Buyers Please Note: Import duties, taxes, and charges are not included in the item price or shipping cost. These charges are the buyer&apos;s respon Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /imex-ho-scale-greyhound/B0BRzHLfQazMxTT5wmiDwg==/info $31.49 +$6.80 shipping Visit Store http://di1.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/49/30/59/324a71576461303555346f4e47576b586e6267-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 AWS BT2-1KG 1000 gram Digital Pocket Scale 1000 x 0.1 g AWS BT2-1KG 1000 gram Digital Pocket Scale 1000 x 0.1 g 
 ( In stock ) 
American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: BT2-500 The new BT2-Series improves on the original BT-Series touchscreen scale by adding a flip-open protective cover which can also be removed to use as... More 

American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: BT2-500 The new BT2-Series improves on the original BT-Series touchscreen scale by adding a flip-open protective cover which can also be removed to use as an expansion tray. The rubberized black and silver exterior also give the scale a much more elegant look. Features: 1000 x 0.1g The flip-open removable cover can be used as an expansion tray. Includes vinyl pouch to keep the scale in. Back-lit touchscreen LCD display. Calibrates with a 500 gram weight or a 100g weight (not included) can be added here. Backed by a 10 year American Weigh Warranty! Capacity1000g / 35.27oz / 32.15ozt / 643.0dwt / 5000ct / 15432gn Readability 0.1g / 0.01oz / 0.01ozt / 0.1dwt / 0.5ct / 2gn Scale Dimensions 4.9 x 3.0 x 0.75 Platform Dimensions 2.7 x 2.5 &quot; Power2 x AAA (included) Warranty10 Year Limited Warranty BT2-Series Manual Thank you for purchasing the American Weigh BT2-Series digital pocket scale. Please read all operating instructions carefully before use. This electronic scale is a precision instrument. With normal care and proper treatment it will provide years of reliable service. Never load the scale with more than the maximum capacity. Overloading the scale will permanently damage it! Avoid any exposure to extreme heat or cold. Your scale works better when operated at normal room temperature. Always allow the scale to acclimate to normal room temperature for at least one hour before use. Give your scale sufficient warm up time. Usually Keep your scale in a clean environment. Dust dirt moisture vibration air currents and a close distance to other electronic equipment can all cause an adverse effect on the reliability and accuracy of your scale. Handle with care. Gently apply all items to be weighed onto tray top. Although this scale is designed to be quite durable try to avoid rough treatment as this may permanently damage the internal sensor. Avoid shaking dropping or otherwise shocking the scale. This is a precision instrument and must be handled with extreme care. Only operate the scale on a stable vibration free surface. I. OPERATION Place the scale on a flat and level surface. Note: This scale features a removable protective cover which can also be used as a weighing tray. To remove the tray flip the hinge release switch on the side of the scale. 1. Press the [ I/O ] key. 2. Wait until &quot;0.0g&quot; or &quot;0.00g&quot; is displayed. 3. Place the object(s) to be weighed on the weighing platform. 4. Using the [ M ] key you can switch between weighing units. II. TARE WEIGHING Using Tare you can subtract the weight of a container. 1. Turn the scale on as described above. 2. Place the &quot;tare item&quot; on the platform such as a tray or container. 3. Press [ T ] and wait until &quot;0.0g&quot; or 0.00g&quot; is displayed. 4. You can now add items to the tray or container. III. CALIBRATION Calibration is NOT required before first use. Only calibrate if scale is not weighing properly. BT2-500 - Use a 500g calibration weight BT2-201 - Use a 200g calibration weight 1. Turn the scale on as described above. 2. Once the scale is at zero press and hold the [ M ] key for about 3 seconds. The display will show &quot;CAL&quot;. 3. Press the [ M ] key again and the display will show the required calibration weight (ie 500g or 200g). If you wish to use a 100g calibration weight instead press the T key. The display will change to show 100g. 4. Place the calibration weight on the center of the platform and wait for the display to show &quot;PASS&quot;. 5. The scale will return to normal weighing mode. Calibration is complete! IV. TROUBLESHOOTING The primary reasons for inaccuracy or malfunction are low batteries incorrect calibration overload or operating on an unstable surface. Please keep this in mind and maintain and operate your scale properly. This scale is a precise instrument and must be handled with the utmost care and caution. [Display] Elimination of errors [88888] Use the scale in a more stable position. [EEEE] You are overloading the scale. Remove the excess agai Less 
 Scales n Tools Store not rated See Store Info /aws-bt21kg-1000-gram/I0Y2JqWda05U4oNGWkXnbg==/info Scales n Tools $19.99 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6b/56/74/67527a7779744237706f7738536d502d587141-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Model Display Cases That Hold 1:18 Scale Cars Model Display Cases That Hold 1:18 Scale Cars 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
These model display cases are constructed from clear plastic and black MDF for the base. The 14.5&quot;w x 6&quot;h x 7&quot;d figurine holders are ideally meant for showcasing a model car, train or... More 

These model display cases are constructed from clear plastic and black MDF for the base. The 14.5&quot;w x 6&quot;h x 7&quot;d figurine holders are ideally meant for showcasing a model car, train or sports memorabilia. These model display cases have a lift-off design. These plastic model display cases provide a safe place to both store and showcase prized collectibles! The economically- priced holders are the perfect choice for home collectors, in addition to some retail environments. Model display cases that have a clear plastic top, also known as scale train or car displays, allow a collector or enthusiast to highlight their favorite pieces, rather than keeping them packed away in a box or other packaging. These units are excellent for a wide variety of other items, including figurines, coins, sports memorabilia, weapons and more! These diecast car, scale ship or train holders, non-locking model display cases are an affordable choice for custom displaying. They are crafted from relatively cheap, but very strong plastic, offering an inexpensive and safe alternative to glass showcases. The model display cases that are great for the collection enthusiast are still clear (though the plastic may have a very slight bluish haze), and do not have any extrusions, to offer an unobstructed view of displayed collectibles. The base is constructed from MDF, or medium-density fiberboard, with a black coating. This simple and non-ornate showcase is designed to highlight the displayed items, rather than take away from their beauty. Small foam feet are found on the underside of the base, preventing scratches on the surface upon which the showcase is placed. The main showcasing area is accessed by simply lifting off the plastic top. There is no locking mechanism or feature to this holder, so it is not recommended for use in high-end or public areas, such as museums. Dimensions: Overall: 14-1/2&quot;w x 6&quot;h x 7&quot;d Inner Dimensions: 12-1/2&quot;w x 5&quot;h x 5&quot;d Material: Injection-Molded Polystyrene Weight: 2.5 lbs. Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /model-display-cases-that/kVtgRzwytB7pow8SmP-XqA==/info $26.50 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6d/51/73/3059363272447755795a764b555f6265467277-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Car Display for 1:18&amp;1:35 Scale Replica Car Display for 1:18&amp;1:35 Scale Replica 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This car display case is for 1:18 and 1:35 scale replicas. The tabletop showcase is constructed from polystyrene and features a lift-off lid design. The car display case has a black base to... More 

This car display case is for 1:18 and 1:35 scale replicas. The tabletop showcase is constructed from polystyrene and features a lift-off lid design. The car display case has a black base to perfectly highlight a displayed model or figurine. Stackable! This car display with black base has a crystal clear polystyrene top allowing full vision of the collectible. This case is manufactured to hold a diecast model of any type including auto, plane, military, Sprint Cup (R) and Pixar (R) replicas. Unlike many of vehicle showcases, this car display that is made from clear polystyrene is light-weight and stackable (each unit sold individually). A plastic case is the economical choice when deciding how to exhibit a diecast model, and this particular unit is one of the most affordable economy-style units sold online. A car display that stacks is optimal for several pieces in a series or just making the most of restricted space. This unit is great for home collections, store presentations, or trade show spreads of scale auto and diecast models. This car display for Nascar (R) replicas is just over 7 inches at its deepest point thus enabling the case to fit in a myriad of locations. This versatile unit is the easiest way to keep collectibles dust free for the see-through lid simply lifts off the black plastic base with no hinges or locks. This car display, also known as a plastic showcase, has a flat black base which does not draw attention away from the showcased item. A diecast model case like the one offered is great for tire shops, auto dealerships and keeping a small version of a dream vehicle in the office. A car display that can be used for scale trucks, boats, motorcycles and military vehicles is found in hobby shops and trophy rooms alike! Dimensions: Overall: 11-13/16&quot;w x 5-1/4&quot;h x 7-5/16&quot;d Interior: 11-9/16&quot;w x 4-13/16&quot;h x 7-1/16&quot;d Weight: 1.5 lbs. Material: Injection Molded Polystyrene Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /car-display-for-118/mQs0Y62rDwUyZvKU_beFrw==/info $20.59 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/66/38/64/6574345a714668775656753872575832624651-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Upgrade Version Metal Track Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Control Model Upgrade Version Metal Track Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Control Model 
 Orders received before 10am pacific ship out the same day. ( In stock ) 
New Page 1 Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Remote Control Air Soft BB Bullet Battle RC Tank( Upgrade Version w/ Metal Gear&amp;Tracks ) This tank can move forward, accelerating speed... More 

New Page 1 Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Remote Control Air Soft BB Bullet Battle RC Tank( Upgrade Version w/ Metal Gear&amp;Tracks ) This tank can move forward, accelerating speed forward, backward, accelerating speed backward, rotating, barrel can be raised 30 degree. Turret can turn 320 degree. Six groups of automotive demonstration function and auto-programming function. This is a 1/16 scale fully painted and assembled replica t ank with the long gun barrel featuring radio-controlled of all movement including turret rotation and gun elevation. It features full suspension and a main gun that fires BB pellets up to 25 meters! Excellent value for money and a big improvement on the previous version. A great introduction to large scale radio controlled tanks. Key Specifications/Sp ecial Features: Features: Maximum side turning angel of turret (left/right) approximately 320-degree Maximum vertical turning angel of gun (up/down) approximately 30-degree Maximum climbing gradient (changeable on different road surfaces) approximately 35-degree Product size: 54.5 x 23.5 x 27.5cm Function: forward high-speed forward, backward, high-speed backward and spin   The barrel moves up and down 30. the turret turns 320 emulation music and action effect Full scale R/C function, frequency-free to change for any frequencies as you like, Multi-players and tanks are allowed Realistic functions, supper chassis, Realistic suspension system The model comes with a dedicated control transmitter unit with its own on/off switch and an &apos;On&apos; indicator light. The transmitter requires 8 AA alkaline batteries (not included). Interchangeable crystals allow more than one tanks to be operated at the same time This tank actually shoots 6mm plastic BBs from a fully automatic motorized firing system using self-generated compressed air. These can hit a target up to 25m away. The tank can fire while on the move or stationary and can hold up to 40 BBs in the turret. A box of pellets is included to get you started. The turret is able to turn left and right to almost a complete circle (320 degrees). Push the left joy stock left or right to rotate the turret. The BB gun can be fired at the same time while the tank is moving. The gun can move up and down at the same time as the turret is turning. The barrel has an approximately 20 degree tilt up&amp;down. Push the left joy stock down to move the gun up&amp;down. Independent suspension and proportional speeds allow it to climb gradient of 35 degrees and overcome most terrains and minor obstacles. The right joy stock is used to control all movement including forward, backward, left turn, right turn, left spin, right spin, backward left turn and backward right turn. The two trim levers for the right joy stick can be used to fine tune the joy stick This tank comes with a 7.2V Ni-Cad rechargeable battery and charger. Oversea customers will need a converter/transfo rmer. The charger need about 7 to 8 hours for a full charge. Running time per full charge can be as long as 30 minutes depending on pattern of play. Less 
 Raidentech.com 235 store reviews See Store Info /upgrade-version-metal/f8det4ZqFhwVVu8rWX2bFQ==/info $129.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ba/f2/8d/92943679-100x100-0-0_Salter+Salter+Brecknell+B220+60+B22060+Digital+Ele.jpg 
 Salter -Brecknell-B220-60 (B22060) Digital Electronic Counting Scale 
 Salter -Brecknell-B220-60 (B22060) Digital Electronic Counting Scale from $295.00 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/49/72/6a/654b654c585268575944563367364741766577-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Zoo bus scale table Zoo bus scale table 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Zoo bus scale tableFun Series Pediatric TablesScale Table Features• Comfortable work height of 36“ • Top is rimmed on three sides for safety• Top&apos;&apos;s front and back rim edges are beveled and... More 

Zoo bus scale tableFun Series Pediatric TablesScale Table Features• Comfortable work height of 36“ • Top is rimmed on three sides for safety• Top&apos;&apos;s front and back rim edges are beveled and the corners rounded for safety• Easy-clean, replaceable center pad• Built-in infantometer with folding ends for measuring height• Easy access to weight, measurement and storage• Built-in concealed paper dispenser and cutter• Adjustable built-in levelers provide a stable surface• Easy-clean all laminate base• Optional storage area locks available• Ample 2-door storage• 3 innovative tables to choose fromScale Features• Dependable, accurate Tanita scale • Easy-read digital display• Auto calibration on start-up• Auto shut-off• Electric or battery operation (6 AA batteries required)• Weights in increments of lbs., ozs. or kilos• Maximum weight 40 lbs. Scale Table/Zoo Bus with Jungle FriendsTable features one end door and one side door with one adjustable shelf.7822 Top: 43“ L x 24“ W Base: 47“ L x 36“ H x 21“ W Table Options004 - Drawer: Euro-style drawer with metal sides and laminate bottom and ends. Holds up to 75 lbs. (mounted under frame)*006 - Special Length: 78“ maximum, 48“ minimum length. When ordering state desired length (table top).020 - Small Pillow: Dimensions: 14“ x 12“ x 3“ 060 - Large Pillow: Dimensions: 14“ x 21“ x 3“ 075 - Rim Top with Removable Pad: 3-sided rim top with Slate Gray or Gray laminate sides and a 1 1/2“ round stainless steel rail on top, plus a 2“ thick foam padding on a removable, replaceable top.077 - Safety Strap: 2“ x 92“ strap secures with quick fasten hook and loop fastener. *Available for all Select Series tables.NOTE: Some options may change the manner of shipping. Color Selector ABOUT OUR UPHOLSTERYClinton uses only premium, woven knit-backed upholstery, that re Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /zoo-bus-scale-table/IrjeKeLXRhWYDV3g6GAvew==/info $3,551.14 +$409.34 shipping Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6f/71/34/7364737368715142427946666e31534d416f67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 County Sheriff Department Bus Mint Diecast 5&quot; Long 1/64 Scale Mint County Sheriff Department Bus Mint Diecast 5&quot; Long 1/64 Scale Mint 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
County Sheriff Department Bus Mint Diecast 5&quot; long 1/87 Scale This County Sheriff Department Bus 5&quot;L x 1.5&quot;W x 1.8&quot;H diecast metal bus with openable door Mint condition, no box. This model... More 

County Sheriff Department Bus Mint Diecast 5&quot; long 1/87 Scale This County Sheriff Department Bus 5&quot;L x 1.5&quot;W x 1.8&quot;H diecast metal bus with openable door Mint condition, no box. This model was never offered in a retail box or package Not suitable for children under 3 years old Each model is meticulously finished for unsurpassed quality. Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /county-sheriff-department/oq4sdsshqQBByFfn1SMAog==/info $16.79 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/d3/bc/80/52003322-100x100-0-0_Daron+Daron+Worldwide+Trading+E1240+X+29A+1+40+AIR.jpg 
 Daron Worldwide Trading E1240 X-29A 1/40 AIRCRAFT 
 Daron Worldwide Trading E1240 X-29A 1/40 AIRCRAFT from $113.99 Free Shipping 3 stores See Details -30% http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/47/77/47/4b78567a517444485350623548446e35655441-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Toys and Models F-86F Sabre - 1/48 Scale Toys and Models F-86F Sabre - 1/48 Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
With nearly 10 000 examples built the F-86 Sabre is one of the most numerous jet-powered fighters ever built. The Sabre made its major combat debut in 1949 during the Korean War where it... More 

With nearly 10 000 examples built the F-86 Sabre is one of the most numerous jet-powered fighters ever built. The Sabre made its major combat debut in 1949 during the Korean War where it was America&apos;s primary jet air superiority fighter. A series of modifications brought the F-86 to a competitive level of performance with its primary opponent the MiG-15. The F-86 was also used as a ground-attack fighter in the Korean conflict and it continued to see combat service with other nations long after the United States had retired the type from service.Depicted here is an F-86F Sabre the last major air-superiority production variant. Extensive care has been taken to ensure that this high-quality model is as accurate and realistic as possible something that any collector or aviation enthusiast can appreciate. Less 
 Hayneedle 887 store reviews See Store Info /toys-and-models-f86f/GwGKxVzQtDHSPb5HDn5eTA==/info Hayneedle $181.99 $127.99 30% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/30/49/4d/49645258686b33794e396f5351627243785551-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Hand Post 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Hand Post 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform 
 New ( In stock ) 
Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Hand Post 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2491 features a height rod in inches and centimeters and a handpost, which... More 

Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Hand Post 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2491 features a height rod in inches and centimeters and a handpost, which is an important aid for the elderly or weak individuals. The platform cover is easily removed for cleaning. The die-cast beam can be easily read from either side. Now available in 500 lb / 220 kg capacities by using the optional counterweights. Detecto continues to set the pace in the clinical scale industry, backed by over a century of leadership. Every Detecto physician scale features a time-honored reputation for rigid construction and precision engineering. This assures an unbeatably rugged product that guarantees accuracy and durability. All Detecto scales are tested with weights traceable to the U.S. Bureau of Standards. 58.00 L. 20.00 W. 6.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /eye-level-physician-scale/0IMIdRXhk3yN9oSQbrCxUQ==/info $362.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/38/38/39/4e3749737341626538394e4b72535141627267-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform 
 New ( In stock ) 
Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2391 features a height rod in inches and centimeters. The platform cover is easily... More 

Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2391 features a height rod in inches and centimeters. The platform cover is easily removed for cleaning. The die-cast beam can be easily read from either side. Now available in 500 lb / 220 kg capacities by using the optional counterweights. Detecto continues to set the pace in the clinical scale industry, backed by over a century of leadership. Every Detecto physician scale features a time-honored reputation for rigid construction and precision engineering. This assures an unbeatably rugged product that guarantees accuracy and durability. All Detecto scales are tested with weights traceable to the U.S. Bureau of Standards. 58.00 L. 20.00 W. 6.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /eye-level-physician-scale/889N7IssAbe89NKrSQAbrg==/info $374.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/33/38/57/54395a7336416c7171304f2d6a33674d774a67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Ho 1:87 Walthers Scene Master International School Bus For Model Railroad Layout Ho 1:87 Walthers Scene Master International School Bus For Model Railroad Layout 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
HO SCALE MODEL TRUCKS WALTHERS SCENE MASTER INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL BUS FOR HO SCALE TRAIN LAYOUT OR DIORAMAS We are offering an immediate purchase opportunity on these International school... More 

HO SCALE MODEL TRUCKS WALTHERS SCENE MASTER INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL BUS FOR HO SCALE TRAIN LAYOUT OR DIORAMAS We are offering an immediate purchase opportunity on these International school buses from the Walthers Scene Master series. This is a brand new product, and will be shipped in its original packaging from the manufacturer. This product contains small parts that may pose a choking hazard for small children. We do not recommend this or any of our products for children less than 8 years of ag Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /ho-187-walthers-scene/38WT9Zs6Alqq0O-j3gMwJg==/info $16.98 +$4.75 shipping Visit Store http://di1.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/56/54/6a/35394c717a7171746d67676571363336335641-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 American Weigh SR-1KG Digital Hanging Scale 1000g x 1g American Weigh SR-1KG Digital Hanging Scale 1000g x 1g 
 ( In stock ) 
American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: SR-1KG The NEW SR-1KG Digital Hanging Scale from American Weigh is the perfect for weighing small items up to 1000 grams. With a retractable handle and a... More 

American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: SR-1KG The NEW SR-1KG Digital Hanging Scale from American Weigh is the perfect for weighing small items up to 1000 grams. With a retractable handle and a hook which stores behind the scale the SR-Series is also super portable.   Featu res: Retractable Handle Back-lit LCD Display Hook can be folded up behind the scale. Powered by two (2) AAA batteries (included) Tare Feature Auto Shut-Off 10 Year American Weigh Warranty  Capacit y1000g / 35.30oz Readability 1g / 0.05oz Scale Dimensions 4.0 x 2.3 x 0.7&quot; Calibration Mass1000g (1kg) Power2 x AAA batteries (included) Warranty10 Year Limited Warranty Less 
 Scales n Tools Store not rated See Store Info /american-weigh-sr1kg/VTj59Lqzqqtmggeq6363VA==/info Scales n Tools $28.46 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/6f/20/b8/89933303-100x100-0-0_Avanquest+Command+Module+1+48+scale.jpg 
 Avanquest Software Command Module - 1/48 scale 
 Avanquest Software Command Module - 1/48 scale from $47.97 Free Shipping 6 stores See Details http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/96/b4/f2/46496955-100x100-0-0_Warehouse+36+1+10+Scale+Working+Miniature+Pedal+Ca.jpg 
 Warehouse 36 1/10 Scale Working Miniature Pedal Cars (Display Set Of 16) 
 Warehouse 36 1/10 Scale Working Miniature Pedal Cars (Display Set Of 16) $119.00 Free Shipping 1 store See Details http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/69/32/43/4f7a4138735853333653624135355076673067-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Holland Otto Vanhool Greyhound (latest Paint Scheme) 1/87 Holland Otto Vanhool Greyhound (latest Paint Scheme) 1/87 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
This is an auction for 1/87th or HO scale model of a Vanhool bus/coach decorated for Greyhound (latest paint scheme). The model is made from diecast metal and plastic and is produced by... More 

This is an auction for 1/87th or HO scale model of a Vanhool bus/coach decorated for Greyhound (latest paint scheme). The model is made from diecast metal and plastic and is produced by Holland Otto. This is a special limited run from Awesome Diecast ordered from Holland Otto.The photos are of a model that has been taken out of the box. The auction is for a model that is new and still in the original carton. Model features tinted windows with detailed interior. Item is approx. 6-1/2&quot; long PLEAS Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /holland-otto-vanhool/i2COzA8sXS36SbA55Pvg0g==/info $26.95 +$6.00 shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6f/59/66/3648336b344c64366d326166387954412d7277-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Wheels 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Wheels 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform 
 New ( In stock ) 
Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Wheels 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2381 features a height rod in inches and centimeters, and wheels in back for... More 

Eye Level Physician Scale 180 Kg X 100 G With Height Rod And Wheels 10 1/2&quot; X 14 1/2&quot; Platform Detecto&apos;s model 2381 features a height rod in inches and centimeters, and wheels in back for easy transport. The platform cover is easily removed for cleaning. The die-cast beam can be easily read from either side. Now available in 500 lb / 220 kg capacities by using the optional counterweights. Detecto continues to set the pace in the clinical scale industry, backed by over a century of leadership. Every Detecto physician scale features a time-honored reputation for rigid construction and precision engineering. This assures an unbeatably rugged product that guarantees accuracy and durability. All Detecto scales are tested with weights traceable to the U.S. Bureau of Standards. 58.00 L. 20.00 W. 6.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /eye-level-physician-scale/oYf6H3k4Ld6m2af8yTA-rw==/info $403.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store -17% http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/78/af/2d/92897429-100x100-0-0_Detecto+Detecto+Run+a+weigh+Floor+Scale+Portable+D.jpg 
 Detecto Run-A-Weigh Floor Scale - Portable - Digital 
 Detecto Run-A-Weigh Floor Scale - Portable - Digital from $254.00 17% Off Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/d3/be/28/96543226-100x100-0-0_Learjet+60+1+35+scale+model+1+35+scale+model.jpg 
 Learjet 60 - 1/35 scale model - 1/35 scale 
 Learjet 60 - 1/35 scale model - 1/35 scale model from $170.98 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details -29% http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/54/36/2d4244496e6e74795f6c7370656177684c4a51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Toys and Models B-36J Peacemaker 1/125 Scale Toys and Models B-36J Peacemaker 1/125 Scale 
 ( In stock ) 
A record-breaking aircraft the B-36 Peacemaker was built for the sole purpose of strategic bombing in the early days of the Cold War. The B-36 was the first intercontinental bomber with a... More 

A record-breaking aircraft the B-36 Peacemaker was built for the sole purpose of strategic bombing in the early days of the Cold War. The B-36 was the first intercontinental bomber with a range greater than 6 000 miles and a payload exceeding 36 standard tons. The B-36 was also the first bomber capable of delivering nuclear weaponry from a fully enclosed bomb bay due mainly to the fact that the Peacemaker is also one of the largest combat aircraft with the widest wingspan of any combat aircraft ever built. The B-36 design project actually began before America entered World War Two but during the war the project was given low priority delaying first flight until just after the war. Despite being a prop-driven aircraft in a jet age the B-36 was the primary bomber for Strategic Air Command until the B-52 came into mainstream service.The B-36 is rendered here in a superbly detailed model of the J variant with a fine silver finish that will make this aircraft a centerpiece in any collection. Less 
 Hayneedle 887 store reviews See Store Info /toys-and-models-b36j/gT6-BDInnty_lspeawhLJQ==/info Hayneedle $239.99 $169.99 29% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/34/14/60/110506416-100x100-0-0_toys+and+models+toys+and+models+gulfstream+iv.jpg 
 Toys and Models Gulfstream IV 
 Toys and Models Gulfstream IV from $182.35 Free Shipping 3 stores See Details http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/b2/e5/f1/75955029-100x100-0-0_Hagen+Detecto+PT+25+Petite+Top+Loading+Dial+Kitche.jpg 
 Hagen Detecto PT-25 Petite Top Loading Dial Kitchen - Food Scale, 25 lb. x 1/8 lb., Fixed Dial 
 Hagen Detecto PT-25 Petite Top Loading Dial Kitchen - Food Scale, 25 lb. x 1/8 lb., Fixed Dial from $58.95 Free Shipping 3 stores See Details http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/66/78/51/453852377a795a4565494478565a737a576177-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Upgrade Version Metal Track Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Control Model w/... Upgrade Version Metal Track Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Control Model w/ Smoke&amp;Sounds 
 Orders received before 10am pacific ship out the same day. ( In stock ) 
New Page 1 Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Remote Control Air Soft BB Bullet Battle RC Tank w/ Smoke&amp;Sound( Upgrade Version w/ Metal Gear&amp;Tracks ) This tank can move forward,... More 

New Page 1 Russian Tank KV-1 1/16 Scale Radio Remote Control Air Soft BB Bullet Battle RC Tank w/ Smoke&amp;Sound( Upgrade Version w/ Metal Gear&amp;Tracks ) This tank can move forward, accelerating speed forward, backward, accelerating speed backward, rotating, barrel can be raised 30 degree. Turret can turn 320 degree. Six groups of automotive demonstration function and auto-programming function. This is a 1/16 scale fully painted and assembled replica t ank with the long gun barrel featuring radio-controlled of all movement including turret rotation and gun elevation. It features full suspension and a main gun that fires BB pellets up to 25 meters! Excellent value for money and a big improvement on the previous version. A great introduction to large scale radio controlled tanks. Key Specifications/Sp ecial Features: Features: Maximum side turning angel of turret (left/right) approximately 320-degree Maximum vertical turning angel of gun (up/down) approximately 30-degree Maximum climbing gradient (changeable on different road surfaces) approximately 35-degree Product size: 54.5 x 23.5 x 27.5cm Function: forward high-speed forward, backward, high-speed backward and spin   The barrel moves up and down 30. the turret turns 320 emulation music and action effect Full scale R/C function, frequency-free to change for any frequencies as you like, Multi-players and tanks are allowed Realistic functions, supper chassis, Realistic suspension system Full scale R/C function simulative motor start-up sound Engine sound, machine-gun sound Cannonball sound Emulation action effect The model comes with a dedicated control transmitter unit with its own on/off switch and an &apos;On&apos; indicator light. The transmitter requires 8 AA alkaline batteries (not included). Interchangeable crystals allow more than one tanks to be operated at the same time This tank actually shoots 6mm plastic BBs from a fully automatic motorized firing system using self-generated compressed air. These can hit a target up to 25m away. The tank can fire while on the move or stationary and can hold up to 40 BBs in the turret. A box of pellets is included to get you started. The turret is able to turn left and right to almost a complete circle (320 degrees). Push the left joy stock left or right to rotate the turret. The BB gun can be fired at the same time while the tank is moving. The gun can move up and down at the same time as the turret is turning. The barrel has an approximately 20 degree tilt up&amp;down. Push the left joy stock down to move the gun up&amp;down. Independent suspension and proportional speeds allow it to climb gradient of 35 degrees and overcome most terrains and minor obstacles. The right joy stock is used to control all movement including forward, backward, left turn, right turn, left spin, right spin, backward left turn and backward right turn. The two trim levers for the right joy stick can be used to fine tune the joy stick This tank comes with a 7.2V Ni-Cad rechargeable battery and charger. Oversea customers will need a converter/transfo rmer. The charger need about 7 to 8 hours for a full charge. Running time per full charge can be as long as 30 minutes depending on pattern of play. Less 
 Raidentech.com 235 store reviews See Store Info /upgrade-version-metal/fxQE8R7zyZEeIDxVZszWaw==/info $139.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/5b/b6/ca/45165192-100x100-0-0_Pacific+International+P+6E+Wood+Model+Airplane.jpg 
 Pacific International P 6E Wood Model Airplane 
 Pacific International P 6E Wood Model Airplane from $148.99 Free Shipping 4 stores See Details http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/24/b5/37/51985534-100x100-0-0_Daron+Daron+Worldwide+Trading+C1032+F6F+3+Hellcat+.jpg 
 Daron Worldwide Trading C1032 F6F-3 Hellcat Usn 1/32 AIRCRAFT 
 Daron Worldwide Trading C1032 F6F-3 Hellcat Usn 1/32 AIRCRAFT from $113.74 Free Shipping 5 stores See Details http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/fc/1f/6c/109963991-100x100-0-0_kenroy+home+kenroy+home+basis+1+light+desk+lamp+in.jpg 
 Kenroy Home Basis 1 Light Desk Lamp in Brushed Steel Finish - 20971BS 
 Kenroy Home Basis 1 Light Desk Lamp in Brushed Steel Finish - 20971BS from $40.75 Free Shipping 13 stores See Details http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6c/4b/6e/6670542d39747174514768394b6e3556786d51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 American Weigh SR-20 Digital Hanging Scale 44 lb x 1 oz American Weigh SR-20 Digital Hanging Scale 44 lb x 1 oz 
 ( In stock ) 
American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: SR-20 The NEW SR-Series Digital Hanging Scale from American Weigh is the perfect companion for fishing trips. With a retractable handle and a hook which... More 

American Weigh Scales Inc. Model: SR-20 The NEW SR-Series Digital Hanging Scale from American Weigh is the perfect companion for fishing trips. With a retractable handle and a hook which stores behind the scale the SR-Series is also super portable. Use it to check your luggage weight before incurring heavy fines at the airlines.   Featu res: Retractable Handle Back-lit LCD Display Hold Feature Hook can be folded up behind the scale. Powered by 2 AAA batteries (included) 10 Year American Weigh Warranty    Capac ity20kg / 44lb Readability 0.01kg / 1oz Scale Dimensions 4.0 x 2.3 x 0.7 Calibration Mass1000g (1kg) To Purchase Click Here Power2 x AAA batteries (included) Warranty10 Year Limited Warranty Less 
 Scales n Tools Store not rated See Store Info /american-weigh-sr20/lKnfpT-9tqtQGh9Kn5VxmQ==/info Scales n Tools $27.97 No Shipping Info Visit Store 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Modellautos in 1:87 
 Fertigmodelle, Bausätze, Zubehör und vieles mehr im Maßstab 1:87 
 www.minicar87.de/ 
 Model bus Preis 
 Model Bus Preisvergleich Model Bus Top Angebote. 
 www.hit-preis.biz/Model+bus 
 Bus Modell 
 Infos über Bus Modell Bus modell - Auf Zapmeta 
 www.zapmeta.de/Bus+modell 
 1 87 Model 
 Fragen zu 1 87 Model? Ask.com Findet die Antwort! 
 www.ask.com/1+87+Model 
 Bus Models 
 Sie sind auf Bus Models? Hier werden Sie fündig! 
 www.5earch.com/Bus+Models 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 Top 10 Luggage Scales 
 by Staff_Contributor Travelling can be a wonderful experience. Yet, an... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -29% B-2 Spirit - 1/100 scale model $120.97 $169.95 YoYo.com -21% Apollo - 1/48 scale model $172.72 $219.95 YoYo.com -30% Toys and Models F-86F Sabre - $127.99 $181.99 Hayneedle -25% X-15 - 1/32 scale model $127.49 $169.95 YoYo.com 
Guides from our Merchants
 
 Ray Ban Wayfarer Legacy 
 The Wayfarer has been an iconic accessory gaping all... 0 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068
	</body>
</document>
