<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006983" url="http://news.foodfacts.info/2010/07/qsr-drive-thru-timer-iphone-app.html" time="2012-07-12-23:58" support="1" score="0.0011054069296049915" bingtitle="Fast Food News: QSR Drive-Thru Timer iPhone App" webtitle="Fast Food News: QSR Drive-Thru Timer iPhone App">
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>One review in the app store by a fast food restaurant owner reads: ... DT KVS and front counter timed like it was written ... McDonald&apos;s Leaving Iceland; Taco Bell Adds New ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Fast Food News 
 
 Tracking the latest news on the food, chains, industry and trends of Fast Food.
brought to you by Fast Food Facts - the fast food nutrition database. 
 
 Thursday, July 29, 2010 
 
 QSR Drive-Thru Timer iPhone App 
 There&apos;s an iPhone app aimed at those in the QSR (Quick Service Restaurants) industry who need to keep tabs on or track the efficiency of their (or their competitions) drive-thru performance. It&apos;s called the Fast Food Timer .

It could also be fun for those app-happy fast foodies out there with nothing better to do with their iPhone or iPod Touch while sitting in the drive-thru.

App creator, Neal Layton , describes his app:
 Fast Food Timer was developed for the QSR Industry. This app is for all the Business Consultants, Owners, Supervisors, managers, A-crew and Secret Shoppers (or anyone else!) that wants to Observe, Analyze and Improve the speed of service at any QSR location. This app can be adapted to or for many locations. One review in the app store by a fast food restaurant owner reads:
 While preparing for an inspection I looked at the app store for a timer and found this one, wow! DT KVS and front counter timed like it was written by corp for their consultants. It deliveres on everything it promises. Here&apos;s a screenshot:

 Posted by Ken at 11:39 AM Labels: technology 
2 comments:
 Neal said... 
Still looking for good ideas to add to this app to Make it more useful. Here are a few promo codes for people to try the app.

AR4KXJY4JHLP
K7ELM9W36N3A
ANYRAXN79KY6
AJKRKWW3RWJH
H96KNEREH9L4
RJME4A49T6YM
K79NN4JY766H
XHTPWPKPAEJY
9FRRT7LK9PMT
MXMJEXYNE44L
 9/01/2010 11:50 AM Anonymous
said... 
Seems an Android equivalent has popped up (link)
 1/22/2011 4:08 AM 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) Fast Food Facts Nutrition Data Search 

 FastFoodNews on Twitter 
Followers
 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (3) 
 ►  February (2) 
 Why Is a Big Mac Cheaper Than a Salad? Cannibalistic Chicken McBites TV Ad 
 

 ►  January (1) 
 Burger King Begins Delivery Experiment 
 
 

 ►  2011 (7) 
 ►  December (1) 
 New&quot;Spicy Ketchup&quot;coming to Whataburger 
 

 ►  November (1) 
 Our McRib Photo Featured on Fox News 
 

 ►  February (3) 
 McDonald&apos;s Angus Chipotle BBQ Bacon Hardee&apos;s New Breakfast Platter, 860 calories for $... El Pollo Loco Introduces Fish Tacos 
 

 ►  January (2) 
 Taco Bell Responds to&quot;Ground Beef&quot;Claims Lawsuit Disputes Taco Bell&apos;s&quot;Ground Beef&quot;Claims 
 
 

 ▼  2010 (22) 
 ►  August (6) 
 Jim Gaffigan Talks Fast Food on Letterman Taco Bell Intros New Cantina Tacos Jack&apos;s New Breakfast Pita Pocket Whataburger Celebrates 60 Years Today Tip for Volcano Burrito Lovers on a Budget (Taco B... Laredo Wendy&apos;s Accepting Pesos 
 

 ▼  July (10) 
 Jamba Juice Making Cheeseburger Smoothies!?!? QSR Drive-Thru Timer iPhone App Fast Food Drive Thru Fun; Video from Funny or Die Blizzard vs. Blizberry: DQ Sues Yogubliz El Pollo Loco&apos;s Queso Crunch Burrito is Back In-N-Out Animal Style Recipe from AHT Carl&apos;s/Hardee&apos;s Testing Foot-Long Hamburger Free Smoothie Samples at McDonald&apos;s *Cancelled* Chipotle Wants Your Junk E-Mail Has the King infiltrated McDonald&apos;s 
 

 ►  March (2) 
 Health Care Law Includes Menu Reform Chipotle Supports Movie About Kids&amp;Food 
 

 ►  February (4) 
 Wendy&apos;s Bacon&amp;Blue Burger Fast Food Solutions for Lent Fast Food Study: Most Trusted Nutritional Claims Anatomy of McDonald&apos;s Mac Snack Wrap 
 
 

 ►  2009 (96) 
 ►  December (1) 
 New Salads from Carl&apos;s Jr. 
 

 ►  October (5) 
 Fast Food Halloween Treats Chipotle&apos;s Kid&apos;s Menu McDonald&apos;s Leaving Iceland Taco Bell Adds New Color... Black Wendy&apos;s NEW Bacon Deluxe 
 

 ►  September (3) 
 Subway To Pass McDonald&apos;s Restaurant Number KFC Expands Value Menu McDonald&apos;s Using Foreign Beef in US Angus Burgers 
 

 ►  August (11) 
 Free Chick-fil-a for Fans on Labor Day Chipotle iPhone App Now Available Breakfast at Chipotle? What is Dublin Dr. Pepper? McDonald&apos;s Japan: The Mega-Egg Esquire: Famous Chefs Fast Food Favs The Onion: Taco Bell Goes Green [Video] KFC Mystery Meat Photos Jack&apos;s Chorizo Sausage Breakfast Burrito 
 

 ►  July (15) 

 ►  June (15) 

 ►  May (22) 

 ►  April (8) 

 ►  March (8) 

 ►  February (4) 

 ►  January (4) 
 

 ►  2008 (167) 
 ►  December (9) 

 ►  November (16) 

 ►  October (39) 

 ►  September (54) 

 ►  August (20) 

 ►  July (22) 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (4) 

 ►  April (1) 
 

 ►  2007 (78) 
 ►  December (4) 

 ►  November (5) 

 ►  October (24) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ►  May (2) 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (6) 

 ►  February (13) 

 ►  January (5) 
 

 ►  2006 (222) 
 ►  December (9) 

 ►  November (7) 

 ►  October (20) 

 ►  September (23) 

 ►  August (39) 

 ►  July (34) 

 ►  June (27) 

 ►  April (9) 

 ►  March (18) 

 ►  February (24) 

 ►  January (12) 
 

 ►  2005 (189) 
 ►  December (25) 

 ►  November (6) 

 ►  October (9) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ►  August (13) 

 ►  July (15) 

 ►  June (30) 

 ►  May (50) 

 ►  April (25) 
 
 
Labels
 McDonald&apos;s Wendy&apos;s Burger King burger KFC advertising Taco Bell trans fat breakfast nutritional data video Hardee&apos;s Jack in the Box Chick-fil-a Subway coffee free Arby&apos;s Sonic Drive-In chicken french fries shake Carl&apos;s Jr. gross Chipotle Popeye&apos;s industry Dunkin&apos; Donuts White Castle dessert drink funny t-shirt Panera charity drive-thru El Pollo Loco Starbucks pizza regulation Boston Market Krystal Long John Silver&apos;s Pizza Hut Quizno&apos;s kids technology Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s AandW Del Taco HFCS In-N-Out environment ice cream salad Jimmy John&apos;s Papa John&apos;s Steak-n-shake Taco Bueno Taco Del Mar game   Fast Food Facts and Fast Food News are
 ©1999-2009 , Ken Kuhl , All Rights Reserved.
 Terms of Use ¦ Advertising info ¦ Privacy policy 
All trademarks/servicemarks referenced on this site are properties of their respective owners.
Fast Food Facts is not affiliated with any restaurant.
	</body>
</document>
