<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006999" url="http://www.frommers.com/destinations/kauai/11_inddin.html" time="2012-07-12-23:59" support="1" score="0.000913874475402424" bingtitle="Restaurant Listings in Kauai at Frommer&apos;s" webtitle="Restaurant Listings in Kauai at Frommer&apos;s">
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>Complete listing of restaurants in Kauai. ... Cultural Immersion Food &amp; Drink Outdoor &amp; Adventure Road Trip Theme Park Winter Sport</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt; Destinations &gt; North America &gt; USA &gt; Hawaii &gt; Kauai &gt;Restaurants 
 
 
 Home Destinations ▼ 
 Asia Australia&amp;S. Pacific Caribbean&amp;Atlantic Central&amp;S. America Europe M. East&amp;Africa N. America New York City Paris Las Vegas Washington, D.C. Los Angeles Rome Hong Kong San Francisco London Miami 
 Trip Recommender: Discover New Destinations 100 Family Trips: Places the Kids Will Love All Destinations»   
 
 Hotels ▼ 
 New York City Paris Las Vegas Washington, D.C. Los Angeles Rome Hong Kong San Francisco London Miami Hotel Slideshows: Great Rooms&amp;Views All Hotels»   
 
 Trip Ideas ▼ 
 Arts&amp;Culture Beach&amp;Water Sports Cruise Cultural Immersion Food&amp;Drink Outdoor&amp;Adventure Road Trip Theme Park Winter Sport Disabled Family Gay&amp;Lesbian Honeymoon Senior Single Student Women 
 Cruise Inspiration: Top Picks for 2012 Food and Drink: Discover Great Tastes Honeymoon Slideshows: Great Romantic Getaways All Trip Ideas»   
 
 Deals&amp;News ▼ 
 Airfare Cruise Hotels Packages Podcast Blogs Pauline Frommer See All Slideshows: Ideas for Escapes All Deals&amp;News»   
 
 Tips&amp;Tools ▼ 
 Calendar of Events Money&amp;Currency Health&amp;Travel Insurance Interactive Maps Entry Requirements&amp;Customs Packing Tips All Tips&amp;Tools»   
 
 Community ▼ 
 Forums Photos Members Blogs  - Arthur Frommer&apos;s Blog  - Cruise Blog  - Behind the Guides Ask a Question: Connect with Travelers Win $1,000: Enter our Photo Contest All Community»   
 
 Store ▼ 
 Complete Guides Day by Day Guides Pauline Frommer&apos;s Spend Less Frommer&apos;s ShortCuts Unofficial Guides 500 Places Free&amp;Dirt Cheap With Kids Guides With Your Family Guides Frommer&apos;s 24 Great Walks Frommer&apos;s Great Drives In... Mobile Apps New: Frommer&apos;s Guides for iPad&amp;iPhone Audio: City Guides by Tourism Radio All Series»   
 
 100 Family Trips 

 
 
 Kauai Introduction Planning a Trip Kauai Hotels Kauai Restaurants List All Overview Best Dining Bets Family Friendly Restaurants Vegetarian Kauai Attractions Kauai Nightlife Kauai Shopping In Depth Organized Tours Active Pursuits Suggested Itineraries Kauai Events Kauai Maps Kauai Forum Kauai Photos Index 

 Most Recent Kauai Forum Posts Most Recommended Articles Most Commented Articles
	</body>
</document>
