<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006866" url="http://www.foodserve.com/Faq.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:51" support="1" score="0.0017895836569208439" bingtitle="POS Software - Food Service Cafeteria Software Restaurant Menu ..." webtitle="POS Software - Food Service Cafeteria Software Restaurant Menu Software,Point of Sale Software">
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>The local POS station sends only the items purchased, POS station, cashier and payment information to the server along with a ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME POS ONLINE PAYMENTS BIOMETRICS FOODCO FORMS ABOUT FSS CONTACT 
 US 
 
 
 
 
 Overview Products Tech.Assistance Video Who&apos;s Talking What&apos;s News Contact Us FAQ 
 
 
   
 
 
 
FSS®POSitive ID System III&quot;Simple, reliable and affordable&quot;
 How &apos;shrink-wrap&apos; cafeteria
 software, centralized database, TCP-IP technology, off the shelf hardware, and Biometric
 options seamlessly combine to &quot;feed more kids&quot; 
                      School Lunch Cafeteria Software
 
Frequently Asked Questions:  

What is the benefit a real time central database for school lunch software? 

A central database, contains all of your students, their census information and
 transaction history. One database for the entire school. When a student eats lunch
 at any school, the data is updated real time on the central server. When lunch is
 over, reports can be run from any connected computer in the district.

The advantage is that moving large amounts of data (batch processing), is minimized.
 The more often you move data the more likely it is to get lost or corrupt. Most
 POS cafeteria software requires moving 200 or 20,000 transactions at one time via
 a batch upload/download. It is not only cumbersome, it is dangerous. A connection
 drops in the middle of the transfer process, and it might just ruin your day or
 worse, cost you a Saturday off when you have to come in and straighten it out.

Our central database is updated with each transaction (sale or payment) as it happens.
 There is no midnight update and because the central database is updated real time,
 there is nothing to lose.

  How do the POS machines communicate to the server?
 
Wide area networks allow for data to move between unconnected buildings/computers
 using TCP/IP. True Internet based programs (surfing, Ebay, e-mail) termed Thin Client
 applications, are unavailable if the web-server is down.

FSS POSitive ID System III is engineered for use across a Wide Area Network with
 a minimal demand on bandwidth. The local POS station sends only the items purchased,
 POS station, cashier and payment information to the server along with a student
 ID number, thus the amount of network traffic is minimized.

  So what happens when the server is down?
 
Great question. We install a copy of the database locally on each POS terminal.
 We know one thing for sure---that even if the electricity goes off (never mind the
 fact that you can&apos;t get your e-mail) lunch is still expected to be served. If the
 server goes down in the middle of lunch, or even if it never woke up this morning,
 your point of sale is still up and running. The individual POS terminal has all
 the information it needs to get your cashiers, and the students, through lunch until
 the server is on-line. The data is written to the local POS until the server comes
 back on line. We call this &quot;Smart Terminal Technology&quot;. Furthermore, with all of
 the data being kept on the local machine in case of an emergency, we can access
 things like student pictures, special needs, etc. right from the local POS terminal
 so that they don&apos;t have to be transmitted across the network at each transaction.

  You didn&apos;t address the electricity going down.
 
Caught me. As we use standard PC hardware, a good battery backup is a sound investment
 to handle power spikes or outages. These start at $100-$150 and you pay more for
 more capacity (bigger batteries) that can last up to two hours. Hopefully if there
 is a long term power outage everybody gets to go home.

  Shrink-wrap software?
 
Our goal is to make this software so simple and bulletproof you can install it,
 set it up and run it with an absolute minimum of support. The only reason to maintain
 expensive support contracts is if the product requires extensive support. That costs
 both time and money ........yours and ours.

 Read more on shrink-wrap software

  What type of database do you use?
 
We chose to use Microsoft SQL Server 2005 for our server database and Microsoft
 SQL Server 2005 Express for the local database at the POS machine. This database
 allows fast record searching and posting and also gives us the ability to scale
 from small installations to very large ones. Microsoft SQL Server is number 1 when it comes to databases;
 Microsoft ships more units than Oracle and IBM combined. 

  What is the difference between a proprietary and non proprietary system?
 
Proprietary systems require you to purchase hardware from a specific manufacturer.
 Many point of sale companies even have proprietary operating systems that force
 you to buy the computer, screens and peripherals at an inflated cost directly from
 them. A nonproprietary system allows you to purchase PC based hardware and peripherals
 from any supplier that offers a competitive advantage. PC hardware to run our software
 starts at under $500 (monitor based-mouse driven) to $2000 for a fast-food, all-in-one,
 small footprint touch screen PC.

  Does your system use any other input device other than biometrics for
 identification?
 Any number pad or scanner (bar code or magnetic) can be used to identify
 a student for FSS POSitive ID System III. These identification devices can be used
 interchangeably so that an elementary school may use a card while a high school
 uses a combination of biometric scanners and number pads.

  Isn&apos;t biometrics overkill for a lunch line?
 
That depends. Using Biometrics, a student may be identified to his/her lunch account
 with no other instrument than their finger. A PIN number takes one second per digit,
 so a simple four digit number takes four seconds to enter. Biometric identification
 will occur in less than two seconds.

Anyone who has experienced ID cards knows that over 50% of the cards will need to
 be reissued. The student will lose it, destroy it, and often forget it. The blank
 card is an expense, but that is insignificant compared to the soft time (labor)
 it takes to complete the reissue process. A good blank card machine costs $5000-$10,000.
 Read More on Biometric Identification 

  What about the ACLU and big brother issues concerning biometrics?
 
Choice is the secret to privacy. Every student/parent is given a choice: Biometric
 registration, (finger scan) or remember your student ID number. When offered this
 choice, less than 1% opt to remember the ID number. Both of the biometric identification
 methods we use offer encrypted databases and store only the result of registration,
 not actual images. As the process is opt-in, the individual is only recognized at
 predetermined locations (i.e. ABC High School Point of Sale, ABC Football field,
 ABC Student Entry Door #1). It is impossible to use the biometric data for any other
 purpose. As for the acceptance of biometrics as a means of identification, polls
 now show that over 80% of Americans now favor some sort of national ID card.

 The Biometric Process Defined
 (PDF) 

  What is your policy on hardware?
 
Hardware specifications are detailed on the POS page and we will support FSS POSitive ID System III software whether
 we supply the hardware or you purchase from another source. If you are looking for
 quality the fast food, spill proof low profile units, CobraPOS terminals are state-of-the
 art and competitively priced. The CobraPOS features a 15&quot; touchscreen LCD screen,
 Celeron 2.0Ghz or 2.4Ghz Pentium IV and 256 MB RAM (can be upgraded to any amount
 of RAM). Options include wireless keyboard, customer display, internal Bar Code/Magnetic
 Card reader. Warranty is standard one year and service is overnight replacement.

  What about server/network requirements?
 
Good question. Your IT department knows the LAN/WAN capacity within your district
 and absolutely must be consulted before you consider any system. Many large districts
 across the USA are at a quandary today as the distributed database applications
 they have purchased for point of sale flat out &quot;don&apos;t work.&quot; Data loss, service
 interruption and system down time are all proportional to the number of simultaneous
 users/lines in operation.

As lunch is served at the same time school is in session consider the following.
 At lunch 125 cashiers conduct 25,000 transactions, there are 6 computer labs, 3
 Internet classes, student attendance systems, faculty e-mail, VOIP phones and a
 host of other applications simultaneously running across the LAN/WAN competing for
 both server time and bandwidth. The best answer to network-bandwith-server issues
 is a detailed analysis by both your IT department and our Network Technicians. If
 there is any chance it won&apos;t work when the system is stressed you are better off
 knowing up front. Failure to do so is buying &quot;a pig in a poke&quot;. It is absolutely
 imperative to get your IT department involved and follow their lead. They must ultimately
 be the first line of support for any system.

  Why is your support so much less than the competition?
 
Two key features of the system design allow for this policy. First is the platform.
 Our software by nature is simple to use, operate and maintain. FSS POSitive ID
 System III, utilizes a central database and most of the maintenance in existing
 systems revolves around moving data, both student information and student transactions,
 in batch dumps. We eliminate this headache.

In addition, we expect the IT department in your district to be the first line of
 support for the food service department. No one knows your network better than the
 people who work with it day in and day out. No one will be able to respond to an
 on site need faster than someone who is already there. We respect the expertise
 already on staff and because your/our point of sale system uses the same infrastructure
 as the rest of the district, their support is paramount to the success of any project.
 Without the direction of your IT department we don&apos;t even care to be involved.

  How are training and installation handled?
 
The installation of the point of sale system will be coordinated with your IT department.
 Once the specifications for the server and bandwidth are addressed our preference
 is to install every station and turn the entire district on. Will it be chaotic?
 Absolutely. But how much nicer will it be after the week of chaos, when all reporting
 is done out of one database, one system for student accountability, one policy and
 procedure for administrative support and one cohesive staff committed to the project
 at hand. If you are up for the challenge it sure beats six to sixty weeks of chaos--turning
 the system on one school at a time. One suggestion here. If at all possible, something
 new should not be initiated when something else new is going on simultaneously.
 This brings to mind all of added pressure of making day one the first day of a new
 school year. One out of every five kids won&apos;t even know where the cafeteria is the
 first day of school let alone being ready to make his/her contribution to a successful
 roll out.

Our preference is support your support staff in both the training and installation
 of a system. When we agree to come on site, install, train and assist with turn
 on--we stay until you are comfortable.

  What will insure a successful installation?
 
Our philosophy is the one-third times three principle. One third, our software and
 staff at Food Service Solutions, Inc., one third, your staff, including trainers,
 cashiers and IT department. That&apos;s only two-thirds, right? The other third is the
 kids, the parents, the teachers and the administrators of the district. This is
 often overlooked but if it weren&apos;t for the kids, we wouldn&apos;t need a point of sale.
 If we offer debit accounting and only the free and reduced students participate,
 what have we accomplished. If 80% of the kids continue to use cash, what have we
 done to affect lunch line speed? If the teachers refuse to use the system, what
 message does it send to the student body? If the administration does not back up
 policies on arrear accounts, recognize the dilemma our cashiers are in when 50%
 of students are without ID cards or consider how critical real time student census
 data is to the success of a system then the odds for a thoroughly satisfied client
 significantly diminish. It is our goal to meet and exceed your expectations, but
 these expectations must be conveyed to every participant in the process. 
 Join the
 Food Service Solutions Mailing List * Email * First Name Last Name Company State * = Required Field 
 
 
 Find out about our Industry leading
 biometric technology 
 
Quality Back Office Software
 FOODCO  

FOODCO™back office software for Institutional Food Service

 Overview Inventory Purchasing Recipes Receiving Menu Plan Menu Forecast Event Results Graphs Reporting The more you look... the better FOODCO looks 
      
 
   About Us | Products | Contact Us | News | Support 
 POS Software | Restaurant Inventory Software | Point of Sale Software 
Copy right Food Service Solutions2009
	</body>
</document>
