<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006204" url="http://rarelyknown.org/2010/11/22/fast-food-resteraunts-around-the-world-pics/" time="2012-07-12-22:53" support="3" score="0.011541699564541666" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurants Around the World (Pics) | Rarely Known" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurants Around the World (Pics) | Rarely Known">
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>California Burrito Co is a fast food restaurant chain selling ... There are now 4 stores in Buenos Aires, 1 store in ... Leave a Reply Cancel reply</description>
	<body>
		Rarely Known Facts, Curiosities, Enigmas. Skip to content 
 Home About The Book 
 ← Unbelievable Future Appliances: Fridge, Stove, Table, and More. Fainting Goats! → 
Fast Food Restaurants Around the World (Pics)
 Posted on November 22, 2010 by admin 
 The Netherlands–FEBO 

 

 

 FEBO is a chain of Dutch walk-up fast food restaurants of the automatiek type. Founded in 1941 in Amsterdam, FEBO is most notable for this automatiek format: a counter is available for purchasing French fries, beverages, and hamburgers. Other FEBO snacks can be bought from the automats. The primary automat-vended items are krokets, frikandellen, hamburgers,“cheese soufflés”and such.

 

A kroket, a typical food from FEBO.

 

FEBO from the street. 




 Argentina–California Burrito Co.
 

 

 Califor nia Burri t o Co is a fast food restaurant chain selling gourmet burritos. It was started by Jordan Metzner and Sam Nadler in 2006 in Buenos Aires [1] . There are now 4 stores in Buenos Aires, 1 store in Medellin, Colombia and 1 in Cordoba, Argentina.

 

 

 Australia—Oporto 

 

 Oporto is an Australian-based fast-food franchise with a Portuguese-theme. Oporto specialises in Portuguese style chicken (properly known as Galinha à Africana ), burgers, chips and spicy chilli sauce. Oporto has more than 100‘eat in’or‘take-away’restaurants in Australia, New Zealand, China and the United Kingdom, although a large majority of these are located in New South Wales.

Here’s one of their commercials:

 

 Brazil–Bob’s 

 

 Bob’s is the first Brazilian fast food chain, founded in 1952 by the American Brazilian tennis champion Robert Falkenburg, Wimbledon tourney winner in 1948. The first store was open in the borough of Copacabana in Rio de Janeiro. Falkenburg (also known as“Bob”) was the first person to introduce the fast-food concept in Brazil. [ citation needed ] The first store in Rio, introduced for the first time in the country Hot Dogs, Hamburgers, milkshakes and sundaes. In 1972, however, Falkenburg sold the franchise to the Brazilian Fast Food Corporation (BFFC).

 

Video taken at Bob’s (interesting):

 

 Costa Rica–Rostipollos 

 
 

 RostiPollos is a restaurant franchise founded in Costa Rica by Nicaraguan businessman Mauricio Mendieta. The franchise specializes in roast chicken dishes, with sides such as salads and fries in a more Central American style. (The name“RostiPollos”roughly translates as“roasty chicken.”) Entrees reflect traditional Central American cuisine. The first restaurant was opened in the wealthy Escazú district of San José, Costa Rica in 1983 by the husband-and-wife team of Mauricio Mendieta Herdocia and Ivania Espinosa [1] . As Mauricio Mendieta is Nicaraguan, the restaurant claims to be the first Nicaraguan restaurant to have franchises.

 

( Photo source )

And here’s a really cool commercial from them:

 

 People’s Republic of China–Mr. Lee 

 

 Mr. Lee (Simplified Chinese: 李先生; Hanyu Pinyin: Lǐ Xiān Sheng) is a popular fast-food chain in mainland China, specializing in beef noodle soup and other Chinese-style fast food. The chain was formerly called California Beef Noodle King U.S.A. (simplified Chinese: 美国加州牛肉面大王; pinyin: Měiguó Jiāzhōu niúròumiàn dà wáng ). The first franchise was opened in Beijing in 1988 by a Californian Chinese-American, Li Beiqi (Chinese: 李北祺; pinyin: Lǐ Běiqí ), also known as“Mr. Lee.”Li’s face can be seen as part of the company logo, in a style similar to KFC’s Colonel Sanders logo. Today, there are several hundred franchises are present in many major north-eastern Chinese cities. Notable locations include Shanghai, Nanjing, Tianjin, Harbin, Changchun, Qingdao and Shenyang. [1] Mr. Lee competes with foreign franchises such as KFC and McDonald’s with lower prices and a greater appeal towards Chinese tastes.

 

 Finland–Hesburger 

 

 Hesburger (commonly known in Finland as hese ) is a fast-food chain based in Turku, Finland. Today, it is the largest Finnish hamburger restaurant chain, with a larger presence in the Finnish market than U.S.-based McDonald’s. With only 12 outlets in 1992, Hesburger expanded to over 200 restaurants in 60 towns across Finland over the following decade, absorbing rival chain Carrols in 2002. Hesburger has also expanded to international markets, opening outlets in the Baltic states and Germany. [1] There was a Hesburger in Syria for a short period, but it was closed as unprofitable. In the spring of 2006, Hesburger had 204 restaurants in Finland, 25 in Latvia, 23 in Estonia, 17 in Lithuania, four in Germany and two in Russia. Hesburger continues with attempts to penetrate the Middle East markets, via contracts with local companies.

 

Also watch this hilarious commercial:

 

 Ireland–Abrakebabra 

 
 

 Abrakebabra is a franchise chain of Irish fast food restaurants owned by Abrakebabra Investments and was established in 1982. When the first Abrakebabra restaurant was opened it attracted a young market because of its late opening hours, good music and its new food concepts such as kebabs and taco fries. In recent years Abrakebabra have begun to open at earlier times and in new locations like shopping centres, catering to a wider market. It has over 55 successful franchisees bringing in an annual turnover of over €30,000,000. It is owned in partnership with entrepreneur Graeme Beere and promoter Denis Desmond.

 

I guess Colin Ferrell is a fan.

 Japan–Yoshinoya 

 

 Yoshinoya was established in Japan in 1899, is the largest chain of beef bowl (or gyūdon ) restaurants and one of the leading Japanese fast food chains. Its motto is“Tasty, low-priced, and quick”. [1] It has its headquarters in the Da Vinci Shinjuku Building (ダヴィンチ新宿ビル, Davinchi Shinjuku Biru ? ) in Shinjuku, Tokyo. In its restaurants in Japan, tables are often counters, and in that case they take orders over those counters. Chopsticks are ready to provide. Orders might include standard-serving ( nami , or namimori , 並盛), large-serving ( ōmori , 大盛), or extra-large-serving ( tokumori , 特盛) beef bowls, pork bowls ( butadon , 豚丼), raw eggs (to stir and pour on top, sometimes mixed with soy sauce), miso soup, and pickles (called oshinkō [お新香] in its menu, kind of asazuke ). They also serve red ginger ( beni shōga ), spice, and Japanese tea ( ocha , お茶) free of charge. Some menus including raw eggs and miso soup can be taken out. [5] Some customers make special requests such as“ tsuyu-daku ”(extra sauce/gravy), less commonly“ negi-daku ”(extra onions), and vice versa,“ tsuyu-nuki ”(without sauce/gravy), or“ negi-nuki ”(without onions), all of which need no extra charge.Its beef bowl is sometimes called“ Yoshi-gyū ”by its enthusiasts in Japan as a contraction meaning Yoshinoya’s gyūdon , which they also use for calling the restaurant itself.The kanji of“ yoshi ”in the name Yoshinoya is slightly different from“吉”and has a part of“土”instead of“士”, which is not included in standard Japanese computer fonts.

 

 

( photo source )

 Nigeria–Mr. Biggs 

 

 Mr. Bigg’s is Nigeria’s first chain of fast food restaurants. Owned by conglomerate United African Company of Nigeria PLC, there are currently around 170 locations in Nigeria, including the country’s first drive-through restaurant, with another four locations in Ghana. Mr. Bigg’s specialty is the meat pie. A common lunch might also include scotch eggs, a sugared donut, chicken, and a soft drink. While western fare such as hamburgers is served, Nigerian delicacies such as jollof rice and moin moin are more popular. Birthday cakes are also a popular product, and Mr. Bigg’s bakery offers cakes and pastries

 
 
Looks yummy, that’s heritage beef and plaintains.

So which one’s your favorite?
 This entry was posted in Food , Places , Weird and tagged Brazil Bob&apos;s , California Burrito Co , fast food netherlands , FEBO , food all over the world , foods from all over the world , Mr. Biggs , weird food , world fast food . Bookmark the permalink . ← Unbelievable Future Appliances: Fridge, Stove, Table, and More. Fainting Goats! → 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published.

 Name 

 Email 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 
Categories

 Aliens Animals Art Bizarre Food Going Viral Google Earth History Internet New World Order Occult People Photos Places Religion Subculture Series Technology Uncategorized Video Weird 
 
Recent Posts

 Self-Described 22 Yr. Old“Vampire”Bites Into 69 Yr. Old Man in Florida Creepy NWO Federal Logo–Now Defunct Prophecy of the Popes–Each Pope Predicted for Hundreds of Years Tarim Mummies–Evidence of Europeans in Asia before historical record? Subculture Series–“Straight Edge” 
 
Google Ad
 
Recent Comments

 Lexii on 16 Most Bizarre&amp;Fascinating Google Earth Images Valeriya Rabacheva on 7 Inspiring People Over 100 Years Old Andy on Foods You’ve Never Heard Of Peter Mwariri on The Mystery of Coral Castle news on Overtoun Bridge: The Bridge Where Dogs Commit Suicide 
 
Tags
 aliens amazing amazing places ancient aliens ancient cities animals architecture bizarre bizarre news bizarre places China coolest library fascinating feral children food google earth google maps history interesting stuff japan jesus christ library mysteries new world order occult odd paganism places religion robots strange strange animals strange google earth strange news strange places strange stuff strange things ufos weird weird animals weird facts weird food weird news weird places weird stuff © 2010 Rarely Known. All Rights Reserved. All original content may not be reproduced, re-published on other blogs or websites, print, electronic, or storage bases without a direct acknowledgment of its original publication, i.e., Rarely Known, and its author/s. All work that is not original will be cited and referenced. Nothing may be used without written permission from the author of this blog and website. 
Check It Out:
 
 
 
Check out these articles
 
 Rarely Known Proudly powered by WordPress.
	</body>
</document>
