<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006122" url="http://www.macscouter.com/Cooking/Backpacking_GourmetBackpacker.asp" time="2012-07-12-22:48" support="3" score="0.0027669422556510313" bingtitle="MacScouter: Cooking for Scouts and Scouters" webtitle="MacScouter: Cooking for Scouts and Scouters">
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>1/4 cup parmesan cheese 2 tsp. cornstarch 1/2 cup ... Remember to pack out can and other trash. Mexican ... Several packages of taco sauce from a fast-food restaurant or dried ...</description>
	<body>
		Advancement Ask Andy Awards Baloo&apos;s Bugle Camps Clipart Cubmasters E-mail Lists Forums Jamborees International MacScouter Merit Badges NetCommish Scouts-L Scout Leader Scoutmasters USscouts.org USSSP Blog Venturing 
 
 
 
 
 

 Custom Search 
 

    USSSP/usscouts.org Home 
   USSSP/MacScouter.com Home 

      MacScouter Cooking Home 
 The Dutch Oven Cookbook The Geezer Cookbook The Philmont Country Cookbook A Taste of Troop 928 Cookbook Cooking Hints Camping Food Chili Recipes Miscellaneous Camping and Outdoors Recipes Foil Cooking Recipes The Box Oven Cookbook Young Backpackers Food Hints and Recipes Gourmet Backpacker Menus More Backpacking Recipes Cubs in the Kitchen 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Gourmet  Backpacker Menus 

 By Claude  Freaner, Lake Ridge, VA 

 These recipes were put together  as a result of wanting to eat well during 8 day hikes in the High Sierras  of California, generally between Mt. Whitney and Yosemite Valley (not  all in 8 days!!!). These recipes are what we actually took on various  hikes, but are primarily geared toward adults or older youths (people  who like green stuff and strange tastes). 
 Menu 

 
 Italian 
 Fettuccine With White  Clam Sauce
Minestrone Soup
Green Vegetable
Punch
Cake

 
 Mexican Fiesta 
 Vegetable Soup
Refried Beans
Tortillas
Spanish Rice
Sweet Corn Cake
Punch 
 
 Oriental 
 Won Ton Soup
Beef Chop Suey
Steamed Rice
Punch
Almond Cookies 
 New England Dinner 
 Potato Soup
Corned Beef and Cabbage
New Potatoes
Carrots
Cherry Pie 
 All  American 
 Onion Soup
Steak
Home Fries
Green Vegetable
Apple Pie

 


 Recipes 


 Italian 
 Fettuccine With White Clam  Sauce
Minestrone Soup
Green Vegetable
Punch
Cake

This menu is good for either a weekend outing or as a special meal on a  long trek. Serves two.

Ingredients:

6 oz. can of Minced Clams
9 oz. pkg. Contadina Fresh Fettuccine or 6 oz. dried pasta
1/4 cup parmesan cheese
2 tsp. cornstarch
1/2 cup powdered milk
2 Tblsp. Margarine
1 pkg. Knorr Minestrone Soup
Fresh Broccoli or Freeze-Dried Green Beans
Crystal-Lite Drink Mix
Mrs. Whites Muffin Mix

Fix soup according to package directions. Put broccoli into 1 inch water,  cover and boil for 5 minutes, set aside. For long-term treks, fix the green  beans according to package directions. Put pasta in large pot of boiling  water, simmer for about 5 minutes, cover and set aside. Mix cornstarch,  milk, and 1/4 cup water in pot and heat, stirring constantly, until thick.  Add butter, clams and juice from can, plus small amount of additional water  if sauce is too thick; stir until hot. Serve pasta with sauce poured on  top. Sprinkle parmesan cheese on top of pasta sauce and broccoli. Put muffin  mix into Silverstone frying pan, add water, stir, cover with another upside-down  frying pan and put on low heat for 10 minutes. Hold both pans together,  flip, and cook other side for 10 minutes. Check for doneness by inserting  a fork into cake; if done, the fork comes out clean; if not, cook a little  longer. Remember to pack out can and other trash.

 
 
 
 Mexican Fiesta 
 Vegetable Soup
Refried Beans
Tortillas
Spanish Rice
Sweet Corn Cake
Punch

This meal is good for a weekend and is especially good on a long trek. Serves  two.

Ingredients:

1 pkg. Knorr Vegetable Soup
Freeze-dried Refried Beans
Corn Tortillas
1 pkg. Lipton Spanish Rice Mix
1/2 can Marie Calendar&apos;s Corn Bread Mix
1/4 cup sugar
Crystal-Lite Drink Mix
1/4 lb. cheddar cheese
Several packages of taco sauce from a fast-food restaurant or dried red  pepper flakes
Dried onion flakes or several green onions
Optional: For a weekend hike, bring along some frozen hamburger, crumble  and fry for burritos or tacos. On a long-term trek, if you can catch some  fish, add cooked fish to make fish tacos.

Fix soup according to package directions; add &quot;some&quot; red pepper flakes to  spice up the soup and give it a Mexican flavor. Fix some freeze-dried refried  beans according to package directions (get these at Smart and Final). Heat  tortillas one at a time in the bottom of a frying pan over high heat. Cut  up the cheese into very small chunks so it looks grated. On a long-term  trek, add the onion flakes and some more red pepper flakes to the beans,  put some beans and cheese into a tortilla and eat. On a weekend, cut up  the green onions; put beans, cheese, and onions into tortilla, add taco  sauce, and eat. For sweet corn cake, make the corn bread according to directions,  adding the sugar before baking. Pour the batter into a Silverstone frying  pan, cover with another upside-down frying pan, and put over low heat for  10 minutes. Hold both pans together, flip, and cook other side for 10 minutes.  Check for doneness by inserting a fork into cake; if done, the fork comes  out clean; if not, cook a little longer.

 
 
 
 Oriental 
 Won Ton Soup
Beef Chop Suey
Steamed Rice
Punch
Almond Cookies

This menu is for a weekend outing. Serves two.

Ingredients:

Won Ton Cup-A-Soup Mix
8 oz. steak, frozen, or 8 oz. hamburger meat, frozen
2 cloves garlic (or 1 tsp. garlic powder)
2 oz. olive or peanut oil or 2 Tblsp. margarine
1 pkg. chop suey vegetable mix (fresh produce section of grocery store)
1/2 tsp. red pepper flakes
1 cup regular long-grain rice
1 beef bouillon cube
Crystal-Lite Drink Mix
Several packages of soy sauce from Chinese take-out restaurant
Almond cookies

Cut steak up into small pieces at home and freeze. Fix soup according to  package directions. Put 2 cups water and 1 cup rice into pot, heat to a  boil, reduce heat and simmer for 10 minutes covered. Remove from heat and  set aside. Heat oil or butter in Silverstone frying pan, add meat and sautéuntil done. Add package of chop suey mix and cook for about 4 or 5 minutes.  Add red pepper flakes according to how much you prefer Szechwan style. Serve  with the rice. Season with soy sauce as desired.

 
 
 
 New England Dinner 
 Potato Soup
Corned Beef and Cabbage
New Potatoes
Carrots
Cherry Pie

This menu is for a weekend backpack trip. Serves two.

Ingredients:
1 Cup Instant Mashed Potato Mix
2 Chicken Bouillon Cubes
Onion flakes or several green onions
1/2 cup dried milk
1 Can corned beef
1/2 head green cabbage
2 medium red potatoes
2 medium carrots
4 Tblsp margarine
2 individual cherry pies (bread and sweet roll section at Von&apos;s)

Heat 4 cups water to boil. Add bouillon and dried milk, reduce heat to simmer.  Add in instant mashed potatoes slowly, stirring constantly. Add onion flakes  or finely chopped green onion and simmer over low heat for 3 or 4 minutes.  In large pot, put quartered potatoes, cut up peeled carrots, and cabbage  cut into 4 pieces, along with about 1 inch water. Heat to boiling, reduce  heat and simmer until potatoes and carrots are done (about 30 minutes).  After vegetables are done, cut corned beef into chunks, put in pot on top  of vegetables and heat another 5 minutes. Make sure pot doesn&apos;t run out  of water. Serve, putting margarine on top of potatoes.

 
 
 
 All American 
 Onion Soup
Steak
Home Fries
Green Vegetable
Apple Pie

This menu is great for a weekend backpack trip. Serves two.

Ingredients:

1 pkg. Lipton French Onion Soup Mix
16 ox Sirloin steak, frozen
2 medium potatoes
1 small yellow onion
4 oz. olive oil
Frozen Julienne Green Beans
2 Individual Apple Pies (bread and sweet roll section at Von&apos;s)

Fix onion soup according to package directions. Quarter potatoes and onion,  then cut into thin slices. Heat half of oil in Silverstone frying pan and  add potatoes and onion, sautéfor about 20 minutes, or until done.  Cover and set aside. In a small pot, put 1/2 cup water and the green beans.  Heat to boiling and simmer for 5 minutes. Cover and set aside. Heat rest  of oil in Silverstone frying pan, add steak, sautéuntil done enough.  Options: Take along a small plastic container of A1 Sauce, Worcestershire  Sauce, or whatever else you like. You can also add a little cut up bell  pepper to the home fries. 
 --Thanks to : Claude Freaner
Lake Ridge, VA
 
 

 
 
 
 ©1994-2011 - MacScouter | Site Map | Disclaimer | Project Team | Web Stats | Contact Us | Privacy Policy | USSSP is Proud to be Hosted by Latisys.com . 
 

 The MacScouter Scouting Rersources Online website is provided by R. Gary Hendra, Tindeuchen Chapter adviser OA and ASM Troop 92, Milipitas, CA; President, U.S. Scouting Service Project. E-mail the MacScouter 

 
Materials found at The MacScouter website may 
be reproduced and used locally by Scouting volunteers for training purposes 
consistent with the programs of the Boy Scouts of America (BSA) [ Links 
to BSA Sites ], the World Organization of the Scout Movement (WOSM) or other 
Scouting and Guiding Organizations. No material found here may be used or 
reproduced for electronic redistribution or for commercial or other non-Scouting 
purposes without the express permission of the U. S. Scouting Service Project, 
Inc. (USSSP) or other copyright holders. USSSP is not affiliated with BSA or 
WOSM and does not speak on behalf of BSA or WOSM. Opinions expressed on these 
web pages are those of the web authors. You can support this website in two ways: Visit Our Trading Post at www.ScoutingBooks.com or make a donation by clicking the button below. 
 (U.S. Scouting Service Project Donation) 

 (Ruth Lyons Memorial Donations)
	</body>
</document>
