<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006783" url="http://www.kathysfastfoodtoys.com/" time="2012-07-12-23:46" support="54" score="0.25174641370834516" bingtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - Your #1 source for fast food toys!" webtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - Your #1 source for fast food toys!">
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="40"/>
	<description>The Internet&apos;s #1 source for fast food toys ... but will be provided as soon as possible once we receive ... Restaurants other than McDonald&apos;s Catalogs: This page ...</description>
	<body>
		Menu

TOYS
FOR SALE

 


TV, MOVIE AND CHARACTER TOYS
 A to J K to R S to Z 


FAST FOOD CHAINS
AND STORES
 A &amp; W Arby&apos;s Big Boy Blockbuster Braum&apos;s Burger King Carls Jr. Chick Fil A Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s Pizza Hardee&apos;s Hungry Jack&apos;s IHOP Jack In The Box KFC K Mart Little Caesar&apos;s Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s 1 McDonald&apos;s 2 Pancho&apos;s Pizza Hut 7 Eleven Showbiz Pizza Place Sonic Subway Taco Bell Target Walmart Wendy&apos;s Whataburger White Castle Wienerschnitzel 


OUR PERSONAL COLLECTION
 Our Collection 1 Our Collection 2 Our Collection 3 
 
 


Need Help?
 Search our website 
 

 WELCOME! 


So many of you ask if we are still collecting or if we buy toys. Up until 2010, we did, but because of ongoing illness in the family that takes most of our time and energy, we are no longer collecting or buying. However, we do still have many, many toys for sale, especially on the &quot;Our Collection&quot; pages. At this time, we are not selling outside the USA. Perhaps we will be able to again in the future.


If you are interested in making a purchase from this site, just email us at katriggs@tx.rr.com , mention the page(s) and item(s) you are interested in, and please include your zip code so we can let you know the shipping cost when we reply. For payment we accept PayPal, money orders, personal checks or cash. Prices are not included here on the website, but will be provided as soon as possible once we receive your e-mail. We mail very quickly by USPS--usually within 24 hours or less of receiving payment--and every package is shipped with a delivery confirmation number.


Once something is marked as &quot;Sold&quot; we will no longer have that item available. We DO NOT manufacture toys. We do not represent, nor are we associated with, any of the corporations mentioned on this website. All logos and names are trademarks of these corporations. We aren&apos;t perfect and would never claim to be, so you may find mistakes on the site. Please let us know if you come across misidenitified toys, pictures/descriptions that don&apos;t match, typos, etc., and we will correct. Unless otherwise stated, toys on this website are not suitable for children 3 years of age or younger.


 Menu Information 


 TOYS FOR SALE - In the menu on the left, you will find everything we have for sale. This includes:
 TV, Movie&amp;Character Toys : These pages include many PVC figures and other miniature toys. The majority of items on these pages aren&apos;t fast food toys, although some are.
 Fast Food Chains and Stores : From A&amp;W to Wienerschnitzel--all the sets and individual toys that we have for sale.
 Our Personal Collection : These three pages are our Personal Collection and we are now selling many of the toys on these pages. Page 1 includes McDonald&apos;s toy sets; page 2 includes toy sets from fast food establishments other than McDonald&apos;s; and page 3 includes collections and sets that aren&apos;t fast food toys but instead are advertising, cereal, retail, etc.


 REFERENCE ONLY - In the menu on the right, you will find:
 McDonald&apos;s Catalogs : These pages include pictures and names of McDonald&apos;s toy sets from the year 2001 through the year 2010.
 Restaurants other than McDonald&apos;s Catalogs : This page includes toys from restaurants other than McDonald&apos;s for the year 2010.
 Restaurants : These links will take you to the official websites for several fast food establishments. Visit them to see many of the current toys available with their children&apos;s meals and other fun things!
 Books : Click on this link to see many different fast food collectibles books available. We recently purchased a few extra books and we have made note of the books we have available for sale now on this page.


 Other Stuff 


 PAYPAL -
For those of you who would like to use Paypal but have not yet signed up or don&apos;t know how to, click this link for some helpful information: Setting Up Your PayPal Account and Profile. 


 
Menu

REFERENCE ONLY

 


McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 

 


RESTAURANTS OTHER THAN McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 

 


RESTAURANTS
 A &amp; W Arby&apos;s Big Boy Braum&apos;s Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. Chick-Fil-A Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s Pizza Hardee&apos;s IHOP In-N-Out Jack In The Box KFC Little Caesars Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Pancho&apos;s Pizza Hut Popeye&apos;s Showbiz Pizza Place Sonic Subway Taco Bell Wendy&apos;s Whataburger White Castle Wienerschintzel 
 


BOOKS


 

 

 ©2010 kathysfastfoodtoys.com - All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
