<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006195" url="http://www.possystem.ca/" time="2012-07-12-22:52" support="11" score="0.02170744025514446" bingtitle="POS System - POS System - Retail POS, Restaurant POS, Hospitality ..." webtitle="POS System - POS Systems - Retail POS, Restaurant POS, Hospitality POS">
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... Store, cigar shop, convenience store, gas station, fast food restaurant, quick service restaurant, table ... Epson&apos;s TM-U220 retail impact POS systems receipt printers are ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Retail POS Hospitality POS Clients Support Contact Us 
 
 


 
 Tweet Home 
POS System
 
What Is Point Of Sale, Retail POS, Hospitality POS and Restaurant POS Systems?
 
 
 
 

 Point of sale or point of service ( POS or PoS ) can mean a retail shop, a POS checkout counter in a shop, or the POS location where a transaction occurs. More specifically, the POS System ( point of sale system ) often refers to the POS systems hardware and retail POS software used for checkouts -- the equivalent of an electronic cash register but with easy to use feature.  Point of sale systems for Retail POS are used in supermarkets , clothing Store, liquor Store, cigar shop, convenience store, gas station, fast food restaurant, quick service restaurant , table service restaurant, Japanese restaurant, Chinese restaurant, bar and pub, night club hotels , stadiums , and casinos, as well as almost any type of retail point of sale establishment. Hospitality POS and Restaurant POS systems can provide fast checkout on dine-in, take out and delivery order. Kitchen preparation ticket can be also print out at the restaurant POS systems.
   
Microsoft Dynamics for retail POS systems in Calgary
 
 
 
 

For Calgary retailers POS systems designed specifically for independent, single-store retailers, Microsoft Dynamics POS Systems (Microsoft Dynamics Point of sale or Dynamics POS Systems) streamlines inventory management and reporting, automates transaction processing start-to-finish, and makes it easy to track customer information and maintain detailed customer histories. We also carry Restaurant POS Systems and hospitality POS Systems. Point of Sale systems also includes Microsoft Office Accounting Professional 2007, delivering a true solutions suite that connects POS Systems and financial management processes. Free consulting in Calgary , Alberta.
 
 »Read more: Microsoft Dynamics for retail POS systems in Calgary 
   
New Citizen CT-S310 for Retail POS, Restaurant POS, Hospitality POS Systems
 
 
 
The Citizen CT-S310 POS retail POS Systems, restaurant POS Systems, hospitality POS systems printer

The Citizen CT-S310 POS Systems printer for retail pos systems, restaurant pos systems and hospitality POS systems printer has it all: 150 mm/sec high-speed printing, the smallest footprint in its class and a dual-interface standard (USB + serial, parallel, or Ethernet) on all models. All this, plus it can be positioned horizontally, vertically, or even wall mounted for extra versatility. Best of all, it comes with the features you have come to know and trust from one of the most respected names in  retail and hospitality POS systems printers: drop-in paper loading, a long-life paper cutter, barcode printing, and the industry’s best three year warranty in Calgary. It can be easily install with most retail and hospitality POS systems. Technical support for available in Calgary , Alberta, Canada.
   
Epson POS Systems Receipt Printer Family for retail POS systems and Restaurant hospitality pos systems
 
 
 
 Retail POS and hospitality POS systems printing solutions. 

 
 Epson is one of the leading suppliers of advanced POS systems technology solutions and services for a wide range of industries including retail, banking, hospitality and supermarkets. As a leading provider of POS Systems solutions, Epson customers include the largest banks, retailers and supermarkets in their industries and Epson provides globalized products and support services for some of the largest multinational companies. 

 
 
 

 Epson TM-T88V POS system thermal printer is the latest addition to Epson&apos;s industry-leading TM-T88 POS system printer series. The POS SYSTEM utilize TM-T88V delivers more speed and more reliability than ever before. It offers 50% faster printing of text and graphics at POS SYSTEM than the TM-T88IV, 35% more reliability, new ease-of-use features and dual interfaces. In addition, the TM-T88V was the first POS SYSTEM thermal printer to be ENERGY STAR qualified* and is the most energy efficient in its class
 

 
 
 

 Epson TM-T88IV POS system thermal receipt printer delivers two-color capability and 25% faster printing than the TMT88III. It is widely used on retail POS systems and hospitality pos systems . Free technical support and installation in Calgary. 

 
 
 

 Epson TM-T88III POS system thermal receipt printer designed to meet the high speed POS System requirements of coupon and clean receipt printing, Epson&apos;s T88III raises the bar on performance with a print speed of 5.9 inches per second. The Epson TM-T88III employs a POS paper loading system that makes POS paper replacement fast and easy. It also features thoughtful design elements that make head cleaning and other POS System maintenance tasks a breeze. It is widely used on retail POS systems and hospitality pos systems . 

 
 Epson T20 POS system thermal printer is the latest addition to Epson&apos;s line of energy-efficient POS system printers. Based on advanced POS printing technology, Epson T20 was designed specifically to meet the needs of low volume retailers with basic POS printing functionality, high reliability and ease-of-use features.

 
 

 
 
 

 Epson&apos;s TM-U220 retail impact POS systems receipt printers are the enhanced, more powerful successors to the best-selling POS system TM-U200 family. Free technical support and installation in Calgary. 

 Epson&apos;s TM-U220 restaurant hospitality POS impact receipt printers are the enhanced, more powerful successors to the best-selling TM-U200 POS systems printer family. Free technical support and installation in Calgary. 

 
 
 

 Epson&apos;s TM-U230 hospitality POS systems impact receipt printer is high-quality impact printer is ruggedized to provide reliable performance in restaurant and kitchen environments. Free technical support and installation in Calgary. 

 
 
 

 The Epson TM-T90 POS Systems label printer is an ideal solution for retailers who want two-color thermal POS receipt printing at the highest speed available. Free technical support and installation in Calgary. 
   
POS System in Calgary, Alberta - POS-X Releases the next generation XPC500 All-In-One retail POS systems
 
 Sunday, 24 August 2008 10:26 |
 Last Updated (Thursday, 22 January 2009 00:03) |
 Written by Ray C 
XPC500 contain High-end Intel® chipset components have been paired with the industry leading touch retail point of sale hardware technology found in the POS-X XTS4000 Touch POS Monitor to create the XPC500. A retail POS system designed to meet the demands of the harshest environments, while remaining cost-effective. Free installation available in Calgary, Alberta, Canada. 
Customer Service

 1-403-648-2749 (Calgary&amp;Areas) 1-780-701-7362 (Edmonton&amp;Areas) 1-403-388-1499 (Lethbridge&amp;Areas) 1-604-636-1887 (Vancouver&amp;Areas) 1-905-695-9067 (Toronto&amp;Areas) 1-877-628-8385 (Toll Free Hotline) POS System Information Request POS System Technical Support POS System Demonstration 
 
POS System Solutions

 Retail POS Systems Hospitality POS Systems Debit&amp;Credit Card Terminals POS Merchant Account Complete POS System Rental Plan Online e-Store Solutions Inventory Management Barcode Labeling Solutions 
 
POS System Concepts

 Supermarket POS / Grocery POS Liquor Store POS / Cigar Shop POS Convenience Store POS System Restaurant POS / Table Service Restaurant POS / Take Out&amp;Delivery Restaurant POS / Bar and Night Club Restaurant POS / Pizza Store POS Restaurant POS / Coffee Shop POS Restaurant POS / Juice Bar POS Restaurant POS / Multi Language Fast Food / Quick Service POS Beauty POS / Spa and Salon POS Citaq Opoz Series Hardware 
 
POS System Hardware
 
POS Video Surveillance

 Axis Surveillance Network Camera Toshiba POS Security Surveillance 
 
POS System Resources

 POS System Home POS Support and Downloads POS Technical Documents POS Systems News 
 
POS consumable supplies

 POS Paper Roll and Ribbon POS System Access Card POS Label Supplies 
 Feed Entries 
Product Highlight

 
 
 


 Hospitality / Restaurant POS systems [Gallery] package includes restaurant touch screen POS system terminal, thermal receipt printer, remote kitchen preparation ticket printer, restaurant POS system kitchen printing network, Automatic cash drawer. Free installation, technical support and training in Calgary areas. 

 
 

 

Purchase, lease to own and regular leasing options available. Please contact our POS system customer service at 1-877-628-8385 for more details on the restaurant pos systems .

 
   We provide custom programming on multi-language restaurant menus in touch screen POS systems. Please contact our POS systems menu designer for more details.   
 
Manufacturer Link

 Manufacturer Partner 
 Search 
Copyright 2010 © PosSystem.ca - Retail, Hospitality and Restaurant POS Systems Solution in Calgary and Edmonton, Alberta.
	</body>
</document>
