<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006313" url="http://www.allstaractivities.com/general/car_games_for_travel.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:00" support="4" score="0.005833240241915987" bingtitle="Games to keep kids amused in the car during travel" webtitle="Games to keep kids amused in the car during travel">
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>Next Car is Mine Pick a number from 1 to 10. ... different phrase using the letters in order ... Fast Food Restaurant: Subway or train sign: Sign with ...</description>
	<body>
		Sports and activity information for 
 the ALL STAR in your house 
 
 
 
 
 Home 
 Hobbies 
 Sports 
 Activities 
 Music 
 Reading 
 Movie 
 Photo Gallery 
 Links 
 Equipment Store 

 
 Visit All Star Activities Equipment Store 
  
 
 
 Web Search 
 
 
 
 ● Summer 
 Fun 
● 4th 
 of July Fun 
● Gift 
 Basket Ideas 
 ● Halloween Fun 
 ● H a l l o w e e n 
 G H O S T I N G 
 ● Arasapha 
 Haunted Hayride and Bates Motel 
 ● Halloween 
 Safety Tips for Pets 
 Fall 
 Fun 
● Thanksgiving 
 Fun 
 ● Tips 
 for Carving a Turkey 
● Thanksgiving 
 Crafts and Decorating Tips 
● T hanksgiving 
 Dinner Checklist 
 ● Chanukah 
 (Hanukkah) Fun 
 ● Hanukkah 
 Coupon Book 
 ● Christmas 
 Fun 
 ● Christmas 
 Games 
 ● Holiday 
 Crafts 
● Priceless 
 Presents 
● Christmas 
 Books, Movies 
● Kid&apos;s 
 Xmas Party Recipes 
● Holiday 
 Songs 
 ● Selecting 
 a Christmas Tree 
 ● Christmas 
 Links 
 ● Twelve 
 Days of Christmas Ghosting Game 
 ● Creating 
 Holiday Traditions 
 ● New 
 Year&apos;s Eve Tips 
 ● Super 
 Bowl Party Ideas 
 ● Valentine Fun 
 ● Valentine 
 Gift Basket Ideas 
 ● Valentine&apos;s 
 Day Coupon Book 
 ● Winter Fun Ideas 
 ● P r e s i d e n t &apos;s D a y A c t i v i t i e s 
 ● St. Patrick&apos;s Day Fun 
 ● Easter 
 Games 
 ● Easter 
 Recipes 
 ● Easter 
 Scavenger Hunt 
 ● Fun&amp;Creative Easter Basket Ideas 
 ● Mother&apos;s Day Gifts Kids Can Make 
 ● Mother&apos;s 
 Day Coupon Book 
 ● Teacher Gift Ideas 
 ● Ideas 
 for Teacher Appreciation Luncheon 
● Graduation 
 Party Tips 
 ● Post 
 Prom Party Tips 
 ● Kindergarten 
 Graduation Ideas 
● Junior 
 and Senior Prom Tips 
 ● Father&apos;s Day Gifts Kids Can Make 
 ● Father&apos;s 
 Day Coupon Book 
 ● Presents 
 for Grandparents 

 ● Sport Hall of
 Fame 
 ● Music Hall of Fame 
 ● Amusement Parks 
 ● Family Vacations 
 ● Family 
 Day 
 Trips 
 ● Parent Weekends
 ● Family Weekends 
 ● Family 
 Mystery Adventures 
 ● Family Camping 
 ● Caribbean 
 Vacations: Money Saving Tips 
 ● Haunted 
 Hotel Stories 
 ● Must 
 See Halloween Destinations 
 ● USA 
 Trip Ideas 
 ● Landmarks 
 Kids Must See 
 ● Trip 
 Ideas: Ancient Natural Wonders 
 ● Famous 
 Zoos 
 ● Pros/Cons: 
 All-Inclusive vs. Traditional Hotels 
 ● All-Inclusive 
 Resort Tips 
 ● Tropical 
 Islands -- Things to Do 
 ● Passport Tips 
 ● Packing Checklist 
 ● Items 
 Needed When Traveling with Kids 
 ● Easy 
 Travel Tips 
 ● Sunglass 
 Tips 
 ● Sunscreen 
 Tips 
 ● Vacation 
 Memory Page 
 ● Vacation 
 Word Search 
 
 ● Kids Corner 
 ● Teach 
 Kids About Strangers 
 ● Addition 
 Helper Worksheets 
 ● Kids 
 Craft: Boredom Bottle 
 ● 100 
 Boredom Tips 
 ● Fun 
 Thing for Sisters To Do 
 ● Kids 
 Craft: Pen Pal Kit 
 ● Kids 
 Craft: Snow Ruler 
 ● Kids Car Games 
 ● Kids and Pets 
 ● Kids&amp;Allowance 
 ● Kids 
 Organization and Responsibility 
 ● Kids 
 Crafty 
 Concoctions 
 ● Kids 
 Craft: Miniature Treasure Hunt 
 ● Kids 
 Craft: Miniature Garden 
 ● Kids 
 Websites 
 ●Kids 
 Craft- How to make an Olympic Torch 
 ● Scavenger 
 Hunt Ideas 
 ● Smoothies 
 for Kids 
 ● Summer Camps 
 ● Service 
 Project Ideas 
 ● Sick 
 Day Survival 
 ● Sports 
 Team Tailgating 
 ● Sports/Activities 
 Clipart 
 ● Sports/Activity 
 Guide by Age 
 ● Sports 
 Team Roster 
 ● Tips 
 to Making Your Fundraiser Successful 
 ● Ideas 
 for a Carnival Fundraiser 
 ● Easy 
 Way to Organize Volunteer Schedules and Donation Lists 
 ● Kid&apos;s 
 Winter Party Ideas 
 ● Party 
 Planning Tips 
 ● Kid&apos;s 
 Cooking Party 
 ● Sleepover Ideas 
 ● Kid&apos;s 
 Beach Party Ideas 
 ● Kid&apos;s 
 Craft - Beach Cover-up 
 ● Creating 
 Birthday Party Traditions 
 

 ● Drugs and Kids 
 ● High 
 School Community Service Idea 
 ● College 
 Care Package Ideas 
 ● Keep 
 Safe on Campus 
 ● Parent 
 Campus Safety Questions 
 ● Saving for College 
 ● Student/Parent 
 College Planning Timeline 
 ● Ways 
 to Find Out About Colleges 
 ● List 
 of Things To Bring To College 
 ● Types 
 of Financial Aid for College 
 ● Moving with Kids 
 ● Goodbye 
 Box 
 ● Goodbye 
 Poem/Craft 
 ● Child Care Tips 
 ● Child Obesity 
 ● Sibling Separation 
 ● Learn Study 
 Skills 
 ● Tips on Test Anxiety 
 ● Tips for Kindergarten Parents 
 ● School 
 Supply List 
 ● Tips 
 for shopping for school supplies 
 ● Job Description of a 
 Parent 
 ● Real 
 Mother&apos;s Poem 

 ● Company Mission 
 ● Submit a Picture 
 ● Contact Us 
 ● Link to Us 
 ● What&apos;s New 
 ● Press Release 

 
 
 
 All Star 
 Activities 
 Car Games 
 for Travel 
  
 

 A lthough 
 everyone loves to take vacations traveling a long distance in a car with 
 children can be difficult. Simple car games are a great way to to 
 pass time away and keep children amused during a long trip. I have 
 compiled a list of car games that I have played over the years with my 
 children and they have been a great success when we travel. Give it a 
 try and have a great trip! 

 

 Great Craft -- M agnetic 
 Car Tray : Learn how to make a tray of magnetic games 
 and drawing supplies that will keep your kids amused when you are 
 heading out on a long road trip. Car games for travel are important to 
 keep your children happy on the road.  Click here for 
 details:  Car 
 Tray 
  

 

 Alphabetical Trip    

 This is a fun 
 and easy car game that let&apos;s the kids use their imagination. 

 One person 
 starts with the letter&quot;A&quot;and says,&quot;I&apos;m going on a trip, and I&apos;m going 
 to bring ____&quot;and names something that begins with the letter&quot;A.&quot;The 
 next person repeats what the first person said, and adds something that 
 starts with a&quot;B.&quot;The next repeats what they said, but adds a&quot;C&quot;item, 
 and so on until someone can&apos;t remember the whole list. For small 
 children, don&apos;t repeat and just let them add a new item that is the next 
 letter of the alphabet. 

 

 Instant Messaging, Car Style 

 This car game 
 will help make the travel time go by a little quicker and the kids will 
 enjoy playing it.

 Pack along a 
 large drawing tablet and thick, black markers. Have kids make signs to 
 send messages to other cars, such as&quot;If you like Texans, wave!&quot;or&quot;Your brake light is out! &quot; 

   

 Count to win  

 Pick a theme it can be anything. Some 
 examples are Tractor Trailers, Pick-up Trucks, SUVs, White Vans, 
 Volkswagens, Billboards, Stop Signs etc Set a timer for 30 minutes. Start to count all the items that you find on your side of the road. The 
 person with the most when the timer goes off is the winner. Sounds 
 like a fun car game right? 

 

  I Spy   

 Look 
 around and pick an object you can see inside or outside of the car. Then 
 give others a clue such as,&quot;I spy with my little eye... something 
 blue. Continue to give more clues until they guess the object. 
 Every kid loves to play I Spy, so why not use it on your trip as a car 
 game to keep them amused? 

   

 

 TV 
 or DVD Player  

   A 
 great investment for long trips is a built in TV or better yet a 
 portable DVD player. The portable player is better because your child 
 can also take it on trips when you are flying. This way they can watch 
 movies at the airport during layovers or use it at resorts if you are 
 out of the room and they need to be kept amused. Just remember to bring 
 a few good movies. Not a car game but a necessity when you are 
 going on a long trip with kids. 

   

 Guess Who? 

 Think of a friend or relative, write 
 their name on a piece of paper, and then give a hint to help the rest of 
 the family figure out who the mystery person may be. For example,&quot;It 
 is a female&quot;. Each person then gets a turn to ask a question to help 
 figure out who it is. The first person may ask Does she wear 
 glasses? You answer the question and they take a guess. If they are 
 not correct it goes to the next person who has a chance ask a question 
 but if they are correct they get to select the next mystery person. Car games for travel are a great way to help the time go by quickly 
 because the kids are absorbed in the game and forget to ask the famous 
 question&quot;Are we there yet&quot;. This is a great car game since it is 
 about someone that they know!! 

   

 Name That Song 

 Each person in the car gets a turn at 
 selecting a word and then everyone else has to see if they can come up 
 with a song that uses the word. The key here is that they have to sing 
 the song! For example: Someone gives the word cheeseburger What 
 song has cheeseburger in it well someone in the car begins to sing Jimmy 
 Buffets Cheeseburger in Paradise. You can take it a step further and 
 then ask who the artist is who sang the song.  

   

 Next Car is Mine 

   Pick 
 a number from 1 to 10. Count off the number of cars that pass you based 
 on your number. When you reach your number check to see what your car 
 happens to be. Everyone takes a turn and then you vote to decide on who 
 is the winner. The winner can be the person with the nicest car or the 
 worst car or the biggest car or the smallest car. You decide be 
 creative. 

   

 Hand Held 
 Electronic Game 

 If you child has a hand held video 
 game be sure to take it along. You may consider purchasing a new game 
 for it prior to the trip and giving it to your child on the day of 
 departure. This will keep them interested and amused so be sure to 
 take it on your trip. 

 

 Music and Headsets 

 Individual musical electronics with 
 headsets is a wonderful thing to take on a trip. Kids, especially 
 pre-teens and teenag ers, 
 can listen to their music forever thus ticking away at travel time. 

   

 License Plate 
 Letters 

   Search 
 for an outof-town license plate and call out the letters on it. Everyone takes a turn coming up with a different phrase using the 
 letters in order as they appear on the license plate. For example if the 
 letters were WIG the phrase could be Watermelon is good. When you 
 can&apos;t think of any more phrases then find another license plate and 
 start again. 

 Car 
 Scavenger Hunt 

 Kids love scavenger hunts! So 
 why not add it to your travel car game list and play it while driving in the car?  
 CLICK HERE FOR &lt;&lt;printable format&gt;&gt;   
 
 City 
 Scavenger Hunt Country 
 Scavenger Hunt Suburbs Scavenger Hunt Bus Cow Mini Van Person on a 
 cell phone Brown Horse School Taxi Cab Picket Fence Gas Station Statue or Art 
 work Silo Fast Food Restaurant Subway or 
 train sign Sign with 
 Farm or Ranch Name Car Dealer Ladies Retail 
 Store Tractor Playground Book Store Pond or Lake Church Museum Dirt Road Red Light Billboard Country Store Bike Hotel Mail Box Dog Restaurant Railroad 
 Tracks Child Playing Theatre Stop Sign Movie Theatre Men at work 
 sign/ construction sign Church Post Office Skyscraper Pick-up Truck Super Market
	</body>
</document>
