<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006913" url="http://nushiesnatural.com/2011/08/09/fast-food-consumption-drives-childhood-obesity-family-education-on-healthy-food-is-essential-to-healthy-lifestyle/" time="2012-07-12-23:54" support="8" score="0.016301575950759945" bingtitle="Fast Food Consumption Drives Childhood Obesity: Family Education ..." webtitle="Fast Food Consumption Drives Childhood Obesity: Family Education on Healthy Food is Essential to Healthy Lifestyle.Thinking Food">
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>... for their children at a San Diego fast-food restaurant. ... asked to retain and present their receipts ... were any modifications to their order. For every purchased item, the ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Thinking Food 
By Nushie&apos;s Natural&quot;Ice Cream without the guilt!&quot;
 
 Home About Recipes Videos Vitamins&amp; Minerals 
 
Fast Food Consumption Drives Childhood Obesity: Family Education on Healthy Food is Essential to Healthy Lifestyle.
 August 9, 2011 tags: chef nush , childhood obesity , GI Foods , Glycaemic Index , health , Healthy diet , Healthy eating , Healthy foods , Low GI , no refined sugar , non dairy , nush galbally , Nushie&apos;s Natural , nushies natural ice creamery , nutrition , Obesity , organic , Organic Food , organics , wholefoods 
The following article appearing in Science News 2nd August 2011 summarises the problem the US is facing with childhood obesity and Australia is not far behind. Approximately 1.5 million Australians under the age of 18 are overweight or obese. This is a startling 20% to 25% of that sub group of the Australian population. If this trend is not reversed soon the cost to Australian taxpayers in health expenses will be massive.

“ What’s in a Kids Meal? Not Happy News 
ScienceDaily (Aug. 2, 2011) — High-calorie, high-sodium choices were on the menu when parents purchased lunch for their children at a San Diego fast-food restaurant. Why? Because both children and adults liked the food and the convenience.

However, the study of data compiled by researchers in the Department of Pediatrics at the University of California, San Diego, appearing this week in the new journal, Childhood Obesity, showed that convenience resulted in lunchtime meals that accounted for between 36 and 51 percent of a child’s daily caloric needs. In addition, 35 to 39 percent of calories came from fat and the meals provided more than 50 percent of the recommended total daily sodium intake for most children- and as high as 100 percent of sodium levels recommended for pre-schoolers.
“We found that families perceived fast-food restaurants as easy and cheap, and many were using fast food as a reward for their children,” said Kerri N. Boutelle, PhD, Behavioral Director of the Weight and Wellness Clinic at the University of California, San Diego and Rady Children’s Hospital-San Diego, who has studied childhood obesity, its causes and treatment for over 15 years.
 
“Considering the high prevalence of fast-food consumptions by adults as well as kids, it’s important to recognize the impact of fast food and its impact on the current obesity epidemic in the U.S.”
 
The UC San Diego researchers surveyed 544 families with children entering a fast-food chain restaurant located inside Rady Children’s Hospital in San Diego, California at lunch time over a six-week period. Families were asked to retain and present their receipts from food purchases and complete a brief survey. Families were provided a $2 incentive to participate.
Families were asked to clarify their purchases: for whom each item was purchased, if items were shared, sizes of individual items (small, medium, large), whether soft drinks were regular or diet, what items were included in any combination meals purchased, and if there were any modifications to their order. For every purchased item, the surveyors asked for age and gender of the person eating it.
 
“The number of meals and snacks eaten away from home is believed to contribute to excess calories consumed by children, and this number has increased dramatically in the past 30 years,” said Boutelle. “On a typical day, a remarkable 30 percent of youth report consuming fast food.”
 
The purpose of the study was to evaluate the nutritional content and quality of food, as well as the reasons reported for dining at a fast-food restaurant. Perhaps unsurprisingly, the top reasons for going to this restaurant were “the children like the food” and it was “convenient.” Just over half the families reported the choice as “a reward for visiting the hospital” (about the same number as replied “hungry with no other options”).
But adults also overwhelmingly reported that they liked the food. The toys included with the children’s meals did not appear to be a top reason (49 percent said it didn’t enter into their decision “at all”).
The nutritional content of the food choices supported other published data on fast-food and dietary intake on children. The highest percentage of daily caloric needs represented by these meals (51 percent) was in the age 2 to 5 years. Menu items most frequently purchased for preschoolers were French fries, soda, chicken nuggets, cheeseburgers and hamburgers. Meals for older children years were similar, with the addition of hot apple pies (ages 6 to 11) and chocolate chip cookies (ages 12 to 18).
Of note, soda was purchased much more often than milk or juice when a drink was purchased. The researchers also observed that while healthier options such as apple dippers or fruit parfaits were available, families did not seem to choose them over more typical fast foods.
Strengths of this study were that purchase receipts were an objective measure of meal choices, and a large number of families — both economically and ethnically diverse — was polled. However, limitations included the lack of data on what was actually consumed, and that the study may have been influenced by the restaurant’s location inside a children’s hospital, limiting the choice of restaurants if not the food choices themselves.
 
“Bottom line, we need to educate families on making health decisions when in a fast-food restaurant,” said Boutelle, acknowledging that any intervention to decrease fast-food consumption will need to take into account that people of all ages simply like fast food.”
 
The education is in fact simple and the food choices are not only simple but tasty. Good food is not about wearing a sackcloth! It is simply about smart informed choices. Simple choices such as low GI (Glycemic Index) foods. Less refined sugar, no trans fats. At Nushie’s Natural we believe healthy food is not only good for you but tasty as well. Try our low GI ice creamery. No transfats and no refined sugars. It is also organic, dairy and gluten free and tastes fabulous.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. from→ Uncategorized ←Busting Food Myths: Sustainable Food is Not just a Greenies Issue Flaxseed Shown To Protect Against Harmful Effects Of Radiation And Is Crucial For The Development Of The Brain And Nervous System.→ No comments yet 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Nushie’s Natural
 
Recent Posts

 Omega-3 Lowers Inflammation in Overweight Older Adults More Good News on Health Benefits of Coconut Milk Dark Chocolate Could Prevent Heart Problems in High-Risk People Fast Food Diet Increases Risk of Depression by More than Fifty Percent Omega-3 Fatty Acids Found to Help Reduce the Spread of Cancer 
 
Categories

 Uncategorized 
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 March 2011 February 2011 
 
 Follow Us On Twitter 

 2 New Blogs on nushiesnatural.com &apos;More Health Benefits of Coconut Milk&apos;&amp;&apos;Omega-3 Lowers Inflammation in Overweight Older Adults&apos; 2 weeks ago Latest Blog on nushiesnatural.com &apos;Dark Chocolate Could Prevent Heart Problems in High-Risk People&apos; 3 weeks ago New Blog on nushiesnatural.com Fast Food Diet Increases Risk of Depression by More than Fifty Percent 2 months ago Latest Blog - Omega-3 Fatty Acids Found to Help Reduce the Spread of Cancer nushiesnatural.com 2 months ago 
 
 
 Mad Scientist likes
 
 
 Nushie&apos;s Natural 
 Create your Like Badge 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .

Theme: Vigilance by The Theme Foundry .
 Follow 
 Follow“Thinking Food” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
