<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006209" url="http://www.medicinenet.com/script/main/art.asp?articlekey=76861&amp;page=2" time="2012-07-12-22:53" support="9" score="0.0184067245862577" bingtitle="Sodium: Easy Ways to Cut Back on Salt - Disease Prevention and ..." webtitle="Sodium: Easy Ways to Cut Back on Salt - Disease Prevention and Wellness Information to Improve Your Health on MedicineNet.com">
			<query id="000635" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000010" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>Cut Back on Condiments. Always dress your sandwiches and ... the dressing offered at the Jack in the Box fast-food restaurant: ... Drugstore Tooth Whiteners: Top Picks; Assess Your ...</description>
	<body>
		About Us | Newsletter July 12, 2012 
 Follow us on: 
 
 Home Slideshow
Pictures Image
Collection Quizzes Diseases
 &amp; Conditions Symptom
Checker Health
 &amp; Living Medications MedTerms
Dictionary Pet
Health 
 
 Slideshow Pictures 

 All Slideshows Newest Slideshows Pet Health Slideshows 
 
Featured Slideshow
 
Sexual Health

Surprising Health Benefits of Sex

View Slideshow  » 
 
 Image Collection (categories) 

 Allergic Skin Disorders Bacterial Skin Diseases Bites and Infestations Diseases of Pigment Fungal Skin Disease Medical Anatomy and Illustrations Noncancerous, Precancerous&amp;Cancerous Tumors Oral Health Conditions Papules, Scales, Plaques and Eruptions Scalp, Hair and Nails Sexually Transmitted Diseases (STDs) Vascular, Lymphatic and Systemic Conditions Viral Skin Disease Additional Skin Conditions 
 
Featured Image
 
Picture of Psoriasis

A reddish, scaly rash often located over the surfaces of the elbows, knees, scalp, and around or in the ears, navel, genitals or buttocks...

View Image Gallery  » 
 
 See All Quizzes (100) 

 Happiness - Test your emotional IQ Superfoods - Are you eating enough? Fat and Fats - What do you know about fat? Skin Pictures - Can you identify these conditions? Chronic Fatigue Syndrome –What do you know about CFS? 
 
Featured Quiz
 
Take the Sex&amp;Love Quiz!

The brain. The body. The bedroom. What do you know?

View Quiz  » 
 
 Topic Centers 

 Conditions A-Z Procedures A-Z Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Arthritis Asthma Blood Pressure Cancer Cholesterol Chronic Pain Cold&amp;Flu Depression 
 
 

 Diabetes Digestion Eyesight Health&amp;Living Healthy Kids Hearing&amp;Ear Heart HIV/AIDS Infectious Disease Lung Conditions Menopause Men&apos;s Health 
 
 

 Mental Health Migraine Neurology Oral Health Pregnancy Senior Health Sexual Health Skin Sleep Thyroid Travel Health Women&apos;s Health 
 
 Health&amp;Living 

 Diet&amp;Weight Management Exercise&amp;Fitness Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes Prevention&amp;Wellness 
 
Featured Topic
 
Weight Loss

The No-Diet Approach

Learn More » 
 
 Medications 

 Supplements and Vitamins 
 
 home &gt; health&amp;living center &gt; prevention&amp;wellness a-z list &gt; sodium: easy ways to cut back on salt article
 
 
 smaller medium larger 
 
 Previous 1 2 
 
 
Sodium: Easy Ways to Cut Back on Salt (cont.)
 


 5 Steps to Less Salt 

 1. Pass Up Processed Foods 

The Food Standards Agency of the United Kingdom estimates that 75% of salt intake comes from processed food. Some food companies are developing products with less sodium, so keep an eye out for sodium listed on food labels. Only small amounts of sodium occur naturally in foods, eating mostly natural, whole foods will help keep levels of sodium down.

 2. Cut Back on Condiments 

Always dress your sandwiches and burgers yourself. This way, you can not only control the amounts of condiments used, you can choose those that are lower in calories, fat, and sodium, such as:

 Balsamic vinegar. 2 teaspoons has 14 calories, 0 grams fat, and 2 milligrams sodium Mustard. 1 teaspoon has 10 calories, 0 grams fat, and 100 milligrams sodium Pickle relish. 1 tablespoon has 21 calories, 0 grams fat, and 109 milligrams sodium Horseradish. 2 teaspoons has 4 calories, 0 grams fat, and 10 milligrams sodium Low-sodium light mayonnaise. 17 calories, 1.3 grams fat, and 27 milligrams sodium (the numbers may vary depending on brand). Lemon juice (from 1/2 lemon). 8 calories, 0 grams fat, and 1 milligram sodium

Feel free to load on all the lettuce, tomato, and onion your heart desires. Each adds 5 calories or less per serving, and is mostly sodium-free.

 3. Beware of Dressings and Sauces 

If you think a little bit of dressing or sauce won&apos;t add that much sodium to your meal, think again. Take a gander at some of the dressing offered at the Jack in the Box fast-food restaurant:

 Creamy Southwest Dressing (71-gram serving): 1,060 milligrams sodium
 Bacon Ranch Dressing (71-gram serving): 810 milligrams sodium
 Asian Sesame Dressing (71-gram serving): 780 milligrams sodium


 4. Opt for Alternatives 

Purchase a battery-operated pepper grinder and your favorite flavor of salt-free herb and spice blend (like Mrs. Dash). Then keep them front and center on your kitchen table to help you break the habit of salting your food.

 5. Forgo Fast Food 

Eating at fast-food chains may be fast and cheap, but you pay the price in calories, fat, and sodium. Many fast-food items are big on sodium. The following items, at a few top chains, topped the sodium scale:

 Jack in the Box 

 Bacon Ultimate Cheeseburger: 2,040 milligrams sodium Chipotle Chicken Ciabatta with Grilled Chicken: 1,850 milligrams Bruschetta Chicken Ciabatta Sandwich: 1,810 milligrams Ciabatta Breakfast Sandwich: 1,770 milligrams Ultimate Breakfast Sandwich: 1,700 milligrams Bacon &apos;n&apos; Cheese Ciabatta Burger: 1,670 milligrams Chipotle Chicken Ciabatta with Spicy Crispy Chicken: 1,650 milligrams Sausage, Egg,&amp;Cheese Biscuit: 1,430 milligrams

 Wendy&apos;s 

 Homestyle Chicken Strips (3) with dipping sauce: 1,690-1,890 milligrams sodium, depending on sauce Frescata Club Sandwich: 1,610 milligrams Frescata Italiana Sandwich: 1,530 milligrams Roasted Turkey&amp;Swiss Frescata Sandwich: 1,520 milligrams Big Bacon Classic Sandwich: 1,510 milligrams

 McDonald&apos;s 

 Deluxe Breakfast: 1,920 milligrams sodium Premium Crispy Chicken Club Sandwich: 1,830 milligrams Premium Crispy Chicken Ranch BLT Sandwich: 1,750 milligrams Premium Grilled Chicken Club Sandwich: 1,690 milligrams Big Breakfast: 1,470 milligrams Sausage, Egg,&amp;Cheese McGriddle: 1,300 milligrams

Published October 2006.
 
SOURCES: &quot;Healthy Lifestyle Could Significantly Reduce High Blood Pressure,&quot; American Stroke Association Journal Report , Jan. 24, 2006. American Heart Association scientific statement. Loria C.M. Journal of Nutrition 2001; vol 131: pp 536S-551S. Bihorac, A. American Journal of Hypertension , August 2000; vol 13: pp 864-872. Reusser, M.E. Journal of Nutrition , April 2006; vol 136: pp 1099-1102. Thierry-Palmer M. Journal of Nutrition , January 2003; vol 133: pp 187-190. Falkner, B. Hypertension , 1990; vol 15: pp 36-43. Weinberger, MH. Hypertension , 1986; vol 8 (Suppl II): II: pp 127-34. Hillel W. Cohen, DrPH. American Journal of Medicine , March 2006; vol 119 : pp 275.e7-275.e14. American Heart Association web site. Food Standards Agency web site. Jack in the Box web site. McDonald&apos;s web site. Wendy&apos;s web site. Food Processor nutritional analysis software, ESHA Research. WebMD Feature: &quot;Beware of the Salt Shockers.&quot; Myrtle Thierry-Palmer, PhD, professor of biochemistry, Morehouse School of Medicine, Atlanta.

©2006 WebMD Inc. All rights reserved.
 
 
 Previous 1 2 
 
 Privacy Policy 
Weight Loss Wisdom

Get tips, recipes and inspiration.
 Health&amp;Living Center 
 Diet&amp;Weight Management Exercise&amp;Fitness Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes Prevention&amp;Wellness 
 Alternative Medicine (CAM) Beauty&amp;Body Image Disease Prevention Emotional Wellness Healthy Habits Healthy Relationships Sexual Health Stress Management Travel Health Prevention&amp;Wellness RSS BMI Calculator from WebMD 

 
WebMD Food&amp;
Fitness Planner

Diet and exercise just
got a lot easier.
Introducing the new
way to meet your healthy living goals.
 
Latest Prevention&amp;Wellness News
 
 Health Tip: Help Prevent Drowning Simple Steps Can Shield Children From Dog Bites 3-D Movies: Thrills and Ills It&apos;s Not So Much the Heat, It&apos;s the Lack of Power Greater L.A. Heating Up, Climate Experts Predict Want More News? Sign Up for MedicineNet Newsletters! Health News Feed 
 Use Pill Finder Find it Now 
Pill Identifier on RxList

 quick,
easy,
pill identification 

Find a Local Pharmacy

 including
24 hour
pharmacies 
 Adult Skin Problems Recognize These Skin Conditions? View Slideshow 
From WebMD
 
Nutrition and Healthy Eating Resources

 Spouse Sabotaging Your Diet? Healthy Eating Habits for Teens Healthy Recipe Finder: Heartburn Edition 

Featured Centers

 Dupuytren&apos;s Contracture: What You Need to Know Eating Out? Cut Calories, Heartburn What&apos;s Lurking in Your Mouth? 

Health Solutions From Our Sponsors 

 Treating Depression Joint Pain Help Center Understand Fibro 
 
Health Categories:

 Slideshow Pictures Diseases&amp;Conditions Symptoms&amp;Signs Procedures&amp;Tests Medications Image Collection Quizzes MedTerms Dictionary Pet Health 
 
Popular Health Centers:

 Allergies Arthritis Blood Pressure Cancer Chronic Pain Cold&amp;Flu Diabetes Digestion Health&amp;Living Healthy Kids 

 Hearing&amp;Ear Heart Infectious Disease Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Pregnancy Sexual Health Skin Women&apos;s Health More... 
 
MedicineNet.com:

 Privacy Policy Newsletters Contact Us Site Map WebMD Corporate WebMD Medscape Medscape Reference eMedicineHealth RxList BootsWebMD 
 
Follow Us On:

 Facebook Twitter Google+ RSS 
 Ad Choices ©1996-2012 MedicineNet, Inc. All rights reserved. Terms of Use. 
MedicineNet does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. See additional information .
	</body>
</document>
