<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006724" url="http://www.debtconsolidationcare.com/collection-agencies/alliedinterstateinc-dealings.html" time="2012-07-12-23:43" support="2" score="0.0008803453147121817" bingtitle="Dealing with Allied Interstate Inc - Debt Consolidation Forums" webtitle="Dealing with Allied Interstate Inc - Debt Consolidation Forums">
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000591" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>Credit Card Payment; Debt Reduction; APR ... the number on the back of your card, put in your account number ... that desperate you could go to a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Internet&apos;s first get-out-of-debt community
441,573 members Toll Free 800-DEBT-913 Chat Live Sign In | Join Community 
 
 
 Credit Counselling Debt Settlement Debt Collectors Foreclosure Credit Monitoring Bankruptcy 
 
 
 Welcome How to choose Forums Wiki Videos 
 
 Counseling - Ask questions Get professional help DIY credit counseling Credit counseling forums Resources on counseling 
 
 Ask a settlement question Get professional help DIY debt settlement Debt settlement forums Best companies 
 
 Ask a question - Collectors Get professional help DIY - Debt collection Collection agency forums Resources on debt collectors 
 
 Foreclosure - Ask a question Get professional help DIY foreclosure Avoid foreclosure forums Resources on foreclosure 
 
 Ask credit question Get professional help DIY credit monitoring Credit monitoring forums Credit monitoring resources 
 
 Ask a question on bankruptcy Get professional help DIY Bankruptcy Bankruptcy forums Bankruptcy resources 
 
 Debt Consolidation Forums Collection agencies and creditors 
Dealing with Allied Interstate Inc
 
 Go to Page... 
 
   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
 
 Anonymous 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 51,360 


 Sub:
# 1 Dealing with Allied Interstate Inc 
Replied on 
07-25-2009, 01:45 PM 
 As mentioned in the thread regarding Capital One...I received a letter from Allied Interstate saying my account from Capital One was turned over for collection.

Today I called Capital One and they have no records of turning my account over for collection. We even talked that while I am a month behind, they don&apos;t turn over accounts until after 6 months behind on payments.

Capital One had me read the letter from Allied Interstate and they were as confused as I. On the letter from AI it has their address, phone numbers, work hours etc. They even reflect that on Saturdays they close at noon, yet they keep trying to call me. I have been advised to stay away from them. Do I answer their call and tell them to buzz off?

How do I handle them since this is obviously a scam?
 
 
 
 
 
 SOAPLADY 
 
 
 
Posts: 13,784 
Credits: 124,819 


 Send message to SOAPLADY Sub:
# 2 
Replied on 
07-25-2009, 01:48 PM 
 It may not be a scam. You might have been talking to a CSR at Cap One that was misreading the file. Allied from what i understand does some early outs for Cap One...i.e...early defaults.

Call and ask them. Make them validate it.
 
 
 
 
 
 Anonymous 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 51,360 


 Sub:
# 3 
Replied on 
07-25-2009, 01:52 PM 
 You make a potentially good point, but the CSR made several points that there is nothing in our account records making mention of referring to a collection agency. We talked about this several different times.
 
 
 
 
 
 Anonymous 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 0 
[ Check ]

 Sub:
# 4 Allied Interstate 
Replied on 
07-26-2009, 03:49 PM 
 Hi
I actually work for the collections department with allied interstate...we are base dout of canada

allied interstate handles two departments for capital one triage which is accounts 1-120 days past due and liquidate cash wich is 120 to 180 days

i work for liquidate cash..we have this problem all the time..we do represent capital one and my liquidate cash department is the only one cap one has but because we are known to capital one as liquidate cash if you say allied interstate they wont know what your talking about

we have to use allied interstate as our company name because we are third party even though we work for cap one..we can even transfer to thier customer service department and hardhsip etc...

its frustrating because we are just doing our job and we work on the cap one system..i can only do as much as the system lets me do... our office is not a scam

if you called cap one and said my account is in liquidate cash they would know what your talking about

if you have anymore questions about allied interstate and thier workings ask me
 
 
 
 
 
 Anonymous 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 51,360 


 Sub:
# 5 
Replied on 
07-26-2009, 04:44 PM 
 I think you&apos;re full of it.

Sorry to be rude, but considering I have now called Cap One twice and there is absolutely no records on my file of being transfered to a collection or cash liquidation...i smell trouble.

Besides I noticed on the bill I got from them their hours closed on Sat at noon, yet my phone was still ringing as of 6 pm yesterday.
 
 
 
 
 
 SOAPLADY 
 
 
 
Posts: 13,784 
Credits: 124,819 


 Send message to SOAPLADY Sub:
# 6 
Replied on 
07-26-2009, 05:06 PM 
 Sorry ...it is the same thing I spoke about...it aint a scam nor is he full of it. This is the way it works.

Yes agencies have official hours. However often collectors work other hours as well. Our agency posted official hours Monday thru Saturday...and yet we frequently worked sunday.
 
 
 
 
 
 Anonymous 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 0 
[ Check ]

 Sub:
# 7 
Replied on 
07-31-2009, 06:38 AM 
 hi all again...we get this all the time..the customer service people have no idea about collections because they usually only deal with people who are usually trying to get and account or are up to date with thier bills..i like to tell people on the phone if you called the number on the back of your card, put in your account number, and now you&apos;ve been routed to allied interstate we must be for real...we also work on the capital one system....
you give me your account number i can tell you all your personal information from your social to your last purchase and everyday we get 40000 accounts in our collection department loaded from capital one...

i think the biggest problems is people are more upset with themselves letting them get into collections... we are late stage 4-6 months

the way it works is up until 4months your are still directly with capital one and they will lower your apr, do long term payment plans waive fees etc etc to get people back on track..when people still cant or wont do that they get sent to the third party..aliied interstate.. theyve had a chance for four months then they wonder why their minimum payment on thier 3000 isnt 45 dollars anymore..yet we still offer them fees and settlements etc etc.

i understand some people go through serious situations medical, divorce, nat disaster..and we do have a hardship department...capone does not consider unemployment a hardship unfortunately...and if your really that desperate you could go to a fast food restaurant..but some people just dont want to pay...well sorry but thats not your money its cap ones money...

you have 6 months to make some effort towards your bill adn then your screwed..you account gets charged off and although we say you&quot;may get an R9&quot;at the least its and R8 but most often its and R9 and the people in recoveries are not nice they want the full balance and your credit is screwed for the next 7-10 years

a lot of people also think that because they are in collections there is no point but i have taken 5,6,7,even 1000 dollars off peoples balances so call i and we are able to work with you
 
 
 
 
 
 betdalval 
 Posts: n/a 
Credits: 51,360 


 Sub:
# 8 
Replied on 
10-09-2010, 05:08 PM 
 How about when you are totally current and never late with a bill and you get a letter from Allied Interstate saying you are in collection? Capital One says your not. Sounds like a huge scam to me.
 
 
 
 
 
 SOAPLADY 
 
 
 
Posts: 13,784 
Credits: 124,819 


 Send message to SOAPLADY Sub:
# 9 
Replied on 
10-09-2010, 08:47 PM 
 Nope....no scam. Payment might have been missed or misposted. Read the rest of the thread and what the AI collector said.
	</body>
</document>
