<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006014" url="http://www.magicyellow.com/category/Chinese_Food/Carle_Place_NY.html" time="2012-07-12-22:41" support="3" score="0.02102413446284251" bingtitle="Carle Place Chinese Food | Asian Food in Carle Place, NY" webtitle="Carle Place Chinese Food | Asian Food in Carle Place, NY">
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>We are a Chinese Food fast food restaurant in offering ... or if you&apos;d like to pick up an order or ... We are a Chinese Food fast food restaurant in Carle Place offering ...</description>
	<body>
		Add Your Business  |  Write a Review  |  Link to this page  |  Business Center 
 
 
 
 
 What? (e.g. Property Management or Public Notaries) 
 
 Where? (e.g. Nanticoke, PA or 18634) 
 
 
 
 

   
 Carle Place Chinese Food search results Premier Listings 

 
   
 Popular Chinese Food Terms 
Chinese food is very versatile. You can enjoy take out or delivery at home, or sit down for a buffet, family-style or dim sum meal. Recipes may be wok-fried, stewed, pot-roasted, smoked, steamed or braised. These terms are common to Chinese menus. Asian fusion – Asian fusion restaurants often cater to a more gourmet, metropolitan crowd and integrates Thai, Vietnamese, Japanese, Indian and Chinese elements. They may also serve Asian-infused Western recipes such as edamame bruschetta. Dim sum – Servers at dim sum restaurants will present carts of small plates, which you choose a la carte. You may recognize traditional fare such as teriyaki pot stickers, pork dumplings, fried wonton soup and egg rolls, and you’ll also encounter more exotic choices like lotus wraps and savory turnip cakes. Many take out and delivery restaurants feature dim sum. Hoisin sauce – Hoisin sauce has a spicy, piquant taste with heavy notes of soy and garlic. It may be used in Chinese barbecue, General Tsao&apos;s Chicken, and in beef dishes. Hunan cuisine – Hunan cuisine is chock-full of nutritional vegetables and fresh chili peppers. “Sweet and sour” and “hot and sour” combinations are frequent menu options. MSG – Monosodium glutamate, or MSG, has been used to intensify flavors in Chinese food since the 1950s. While this ingredient has been stigmatized because it gives some people migraines and other unpleasant symptoms, it can be used in place of fat and salt to enhance flavor. Oyster sauce – Oyster sauce is a thick brown condiment made with oysters, sugar and salt. It can top rice and noodle dishes or serve as the base for recipes. Szechuan cuisine – Szechuan dishes are heavy in garlic, chili bean paste, ginger, sesame and the signature Szechuan peppercorn. Kung Pao chicken is a popular Szechuan dish. 
   
 Panda Express 
 Providing Chinese Food for pickup or dine-in. We are a Chinese Food fast food restaurant in Carle Place offering chinese chicken, asian vegetables,&amp;chinese noodles. (2) Reviews Write a review   User Review: &quot;The above ppl commented about eating at a panda express in chewelah....We do not have one here. They must be refering to...&quot; - Lori (WA) 
   
 Sort By Default Highest Rated Most Rated Limit By City No Yes Distance Default 5 miles 10 miles 15 miles 20 miles 
 
 Christine&apos;s Chinese Cuisine 
 351 Old Country Rd Unit C, Carle Place, NY 11514 Write a review (516) 333-8288 
 
 Lee&apos;s Chinese Food 
 351 Old Country Rd Unit C, Carle Place, NY 11514 Write a review (516) 997-7337 
 
 Panda Chinese Food 
 639 Jericho Tpke, Syosset, NY 11791
8.0MI from Carle Place (1) Review Write a review (516) 921-5555   User Review: &quot;This is a good thing to have when u need things&quot; - Morgan (NY) 
 
 Jade Palace Chinese Restaurant 
 128 Mill Rd, Valley Stream, NY 11581
9.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 791-3424 
 
 Wah Sanj Kitchen 
 159 Dubois Ave, Valley Stream, NY 11581
9.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 823-9523 
 
 New Golden Chopsticks Chinese Restaurant 
 561 Atlantic Ave, Oceanside, NY 11572
9.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 536-2678 
 
 Great China Kitchen 
 2777 Brower Ave, Oceanside, NY 11572
9.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 766-1780 
 
 Great Wall Kitchen 
 47 Boundary Ave Ste 4, Farmingdale, NY 11735
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 293-8889 
 
 Yan&apos;s Kin Wah Chinese Restaurant 
 693 Main St, Farmingdale, NY 11735
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 249-2927 
 
 Maxim&apos;s Chinese Rest 
 559 Fulton St, Farmingdale, NY 11735
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 249-7815 
 
 Chin&apos;s Kitchen 
 4135 Merrick Rd, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 541-4460 
 
 Chun Mei Restaurant 
 4640 Merrick Rd, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 798-0893 
 
 White Cloud Chinese Kitchen 
 1 Park Ln Ste E, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 541-8197 
 
 Wok N Roll 
 909 Carmans Rd, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 797-8899 
 
 New Chen&apos;s Chinese Kitchen 
 1084 Broadway, Woodmere, NY 11598
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 374-6622 
 
 New Da Hang Restaurant Inc 
 626 Broadway, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 798-0284 
 
 Golden Garden Chinese Restrnt 
 5505 Merrick Rd, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 797-3377 
 
 Hunan New Jade Chinese Restaur 
 1495 Hicksville Rd, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 579-2828 
 
 Ed Youngs Chinese Restaurant 
 107 Fulton, Farmingdale, NY 11735
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 420-9763 
 
 Twisted Wok 
 179 Jerusalem Ave, Massapequa, NY 11758
10.0MI from Carle Place Write a review (516) 799-7600 
 



 Chinese cuisine has been popular in this country for nearly a century. And for good reason! Chinese food is delicious and often nutritional. It tastes wonderful, whether you&apos;re eating it in a restaurant, or as a take out or delivery option, and it&apos;s usually good for you too!

Most people have a Chinese - or Asian - recipe that they prefer more than any other. Some people, for instance, love traditional dishes, like dim sum. Or wonton soup. Or spicy egg rolls. Other people prefer to eat wok fried meats and vegetables. Chicken, pork, and beef all taste great when fried in a wok. Still other people prefer to eat simple rice dishes with teriyaki or soy sauce added to them for extra flavor. And some people - especially indecisive types - love Chinese restaurants for their plentiful buffets.

Many people also love Chinese food because many restaurants offer extensive menu options. Some restaurants even add take out and delivery options to their menus.

There are many reasons to love Chinese food. It&apos;s tasty, nutritious, and convenient. It&apos;s also often less intimidating to Western diners than Japanese and Thai cuisine, and that makes it great for slightly less adventurous eaters. Chinese food is versatile and inexpensive, and everyone ought to enjoy at least one Chinese recipe.

So, if you&apos;d like to eat at a Chinese restaurant, or if you&apos;d like to pick up an order or have an order delivered to your house, consider contacting your local Chinese restaurant today. Odds are, you&apos;ll be glad you did! 

 Showing Listings 1 - 20 of 199 
     
 
 
   
 
 Related Categories 
 
 Bagels 
 Banquet Rooms 
 Bar Supplies Fixtures&amp;Equipment 
 Barbecue Food&amp;Catering 
 Bistro 
 Buffet Restaurants 
 Cafes 
 Cafeterias 
 Cake Decorating Equipment&amp;Supplies 
 Candy&amp;Confectionery Retail 
 Caribbean Food 
 Cheese Wholesale 
 Chocolate&amp;Cocoa 
 Family Style Restaurants 
 Flavoring Extracts 
 Food Brokers 
 French Food&amp;Restaurants 
 Frozen Foods Wholesale 
 German Food 
 Greek Food 
 Hamburger&amp;Hot Dog Stands 
 Ice Cream Parlors 
 Italian Restaurants 
 Peanut Products 
 Pretzels Retail 
 Restaurant Equipment&amp;Supplies Retail 
 Restaurants Asian 
 Restaurants Food Delivery 
 Soul Food 
 
   
 New York Cities 
 
 Albertson 
 Amagansett 
 Amityville 
 Aquebogue 
 Atlantic Beach 
 Babylon 
 Baldwin 
 Bay Shore 
 Bayport 
 Bayville 
 Bellmore 
 Bellport 
 Bethpage 
 Blue Point 
 Bohemia 
 Brentwood 
 Bridgehampton 
 Brightwaters 
 Brookhaven 
 Calverton 
 Cedarhurst 
 Center Moriches 
 Centereach 
 Centerport 
 Central Islip 
 Cold Spring Harbor 
 Commack 
 Copiague 
 Coram 
 Cutchogue 
 Deer Park 
 East Hampton 
 East Islip 
 East Marion 
 East Meadow 
 East Moriches 
 East Northport 
 East Norwich 
 East Quogue 
 East Rockaway 
 East Setauket 
 Eastport 
 Elmont 
 Farmingdale 
 Farmingville 
 Floral Park 
 Franklin Square 
 Freeport 
 Garden City 
 Glen Cove 
 Glen Head 
 Glen Oaks 
 Glenwood Landing 
 Great Neck 
 Great River 
 Greenlawn 
 Greenport 
 Greenvale 
 Hampton Bays 
 Hauppauge 
 Hempstead 
 Hewlett 
 Holbrook 
 Holtsville 
 Huntington 
 Huntington Station 
 Inwood 
 Island Park 
 Islandia 
 Islip 
 Islip Terrace 
 Jamesport 
 Jericho 
 Kings Park 
 Lake Grove 
 Laurel 
 Lawrence 
 Levittown 
 Lindenhurst 
 Locust Valley 
 Long Beach 
 Long Island City 
 Lynbrook 
 Malverne 
 Manhasset 
 Manorville 
 Massapequa 
 Massapequa Park 
 Mastic 
 Mastic Beach 
 Mattituck 
 Medford 
 Melville 
 Merrick 
 Middle Island 
 Mill Neck 
 Miller Place 
 Mineola 
 Montauk 
 Moriches 
 Mount Sinai 
 Nesconset 
 New Hyde Park 
 New Suffolk 
 North Babylon 
 Northport 
 Oakdale 
 Ocean Beach 
 Oceanside 
 Old Westbury 
 Orient 
 Oyster Bay 
 Patchogue 
 Peconic 
 Point Lookout 
 Port Jefferson 
 Port Jefferson Station 
 Port Washington 
 Quogue 
 Remsenburg 
 Ridge 
 Riverhead 
 Rockville Centre 
 Rocky Point 
 Ronkonkoma 
 Roosevelt 
 Roslyn 
 Roslyn Heights 
 Sag Harbor 
 Sagaponack 
 Saint James 
 Sayville 
 Sea Cliff 
 Seaford 
 Selden 
 Shelter Island 
 Shelter Island Heights 
 Shirley 
 Shoreham 
 Smithtown 
 Sound Beach 
 South Jamesport 
 Southampton 
 Southold 
 Speonk 
 Stony Brook 
 Syosset 
 Uniondale 
 Upton 
 Valley Stream 
 Wading River 
 Wainscott 
 Wantagh 
 Water Mill 
 West Babylon 
 West Hempstead 
 West Islip 
 West Sayville 
 Westbury 
 Westhampton 
 Westhampton Beach 
 Williston Park 
 Woodbury 
 Woodmere 
 Wyandanch 
 Yaphank 
 
   
 New York Cities 
 
 Albany 
 Buffalo 
 Long Island 
 New York City 
 Rochester 
 Syracuse 
 New York Statewide
	</body>
</document>
