<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006289" url="http://www.cardratings.com/visa-mastercard-plan-new-merchant-bank-service-fees.html" time="2012-07-12-22:58" support="3" score="0.0031776439508241928" bingtitle="Visa, MasterCard Merchant Processing Fees to Increase April 1" webtitle="Visa, MasterCard Merchant Processing Fees to Increase April 1">
			<query id="001052" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>Payment networks would charge banks a ... in half, gas station owners and fast food restaurant ... Credit card rules have changed, making it more challenging for college ...</description>
	<body>
		En Español Google + Facebook Twitter RSS Feed 
 Home Compare Credit Cards Credit Scores Credit Card News CardRatings Blog Forum 

 Home » Credit Card News »Visa, Mastercard Plan New Merchant Bank Service Fees For April 1 
Visa, MasterCard plan new merchant bank service fees for April 1
 
March 2, 2012
By: Joe Taylor Jr.
 
Unintended consequences from the Dodd-Frank Act could raise prices at retail stores after April 1. That&apos;s the deadline Visa and MasterCard set for new rates they charge merchant banks that process credit card transactions on behalf of retail stores, service providers and other businesses. According to a Dow Jones Newswires report, the payment platform providers announced new fixed processing fees to banks. These fees would circumvent interchange fee caps set by the Durbin Amendment to the financial reform laws of 2010.

How much are the new fees?

Payment networks would charge banks a fixed annual fee ranging from $2 to $85 for each location where its merchant customers process debit and credit cards. Under rules set by the Durbin Amendment, banks can charge merchants no more than 24 cents in processing fees for each transaction involving a debit card. While the cap dropped the average transaction fee almost in half, gas station owners and fast food restaurant operators claim that they now bear an unfair burden compared to retailers with larger sales.

 Let CardRatings.com help you find the best balance transfer offer for you. 


Before the passage of the Dodd-Frank Act, merchants with small average sales could qualify for deeply discounted interchange fees. However, representatives from merchant banks contacted by Dow Jones admitted that most payment processors eliminated discounts, matching the maximum rates allowed by law.

Though retail industry lobbyists claim that stores and restaurants could lower their prices if payment processors reduced their rates, banking officials have countered that interchange fees help cover the costs of cash back rebate cards , rewards points, and other promotional incentives.

Visa explains why

Despite the increase in rates for many speciality merchants, Visa and MasterCard still face a significant revenue drop as new limits take effect and as more consumers switch to debit cards from credit cards. Visa spokesman Paul Cohen told Dow Jones that the new fees, aimed directly at banks instead of retailers, would help his company recoup some of that lost revenue.

Cohen also explained that lowering Visa&apos;s per-transaction processing fee would help Visa retain its role as a preferred payment processing network after merchants gain the ability to choose networks on April 1. Industry analysts speculate that banks will find ways for the new payment network fees to trickle down to merchants. In turn, retailers will likely adjust their own prices to keep pace with payment processing costs.


 
Share this article with:

 Delicious    Digg    Tipd    Facebook    Twitter    StumbleUpon    
 0 Responses to &quot;Visa, MasterCard plan new merchant bank service fees for April 1&quot; 
No Comments


 Leave a Comment Name (required) E-mail (required; won&apos;t be published) Website Your comment     
   Related Articles: 
 American Express in trouble over late fees United Arab Emirates caps credit card interest at 18 percent 
 How to find the best Cash Back credit card? Top articles from Joe Taylor Jr. 
 Why it pays to be a credit card deadbeat Credit cards of the future: 4 exciting trends 5 credit cards you won&apos;t find anywhere else Capital One launches 2 percent cash back credit card for small business New Citi/AA airline credit card offers &quot;chip and PIN&quot; plus elite perks 
 
Top Cards by Category
 Cash Back Credit Card Discover ® Open Road Card 
0% intro APR on purchases and balance transfers for 15 months, then the variable standard purchase APR of 10.99% - 20.99%.* Earn 2% cashback automatically at gas stations and restaurants. Great rewards with no annual fee, no rewards redemption fee, and no additional card fee.
 Airline Miles / Rewards Points Credit Card Gold Delta SkyMiles ® Credit Card from American Express - $0 Intro Annual Fee for the First Year 
Earn 30,000 bonus miles toward Award Travel when you spend $500 on the Card in the first three months from account opening. Receive double miles on Delta purchases.
 Credit Card Deals Gold Delta SkyMiles ® Credit Card from American Express - $0 Intro Annual Fee for the First Year 
Earn 30,000 bonus miles toward Award Travel when you spend $500 on the Card in the first three months from account opening. Receive double miles on Delta purchases.
 Balance Transfer Credit Card Discover ® More ® Card 
Earn up to 5% cash back* in categories that change throughout the year and enjoy a 0% introductory rate for 15 months on Balance Transfers and 15 months on Purchases.
 Low Introductory Rate Credit Card Discover ® More ® Card 
Earn up to 5% cash back* in categories that change throughout the year and enjoy a 0% introductory rate for 15 months on Balance Transfers and 15 months on Purchases.
 Low Interest Rate Credit Card Discover ® More Card - 18 Month Promotional Balance Transfer 
Enjoy a 0% introductory rate for 18 months on Balance Transfers and 6 months on Purchases. Earn up to 5% cash back in categories that change throughout the year.
 Student Credit Card Discover ® Student Clear Card 
0% intro APR on purchases for 9 months, then the variable standard purchase APR of 12.99% - 18.99%*. 5% Cashback Bonus in categories that change throughout the year like gas, restaurants, department stores and more. Limitations apply*. No annual fee.
 Gas Rebate Credit Card Discover ® Open Road Card 
0% intro APR on purchases and balance transfers for 15 months, then the variable standard purchase APR of 10.99% - 20.99%.* Earn 2% cashback automatically at gas stations and restaurants. Great rewards with no annual fee, no rewards redemption fee, and no additional card fee.
 Explore Card Offers 
 Best Card Offers Low interest Low intoductory Rate Balance Transfer Cash Back Gas Cards 
 Life changes. So should your cards. Best credit cards for new college grads Credit card rules have changed, making it more challenging for college
students to get their own credit cards before graduation. CardRatings.com
presents five offers that can help recent college gradua... Read More Six best credit cards for Mom (or Mr. Mom) The best credit card reward programs could be worth up to $4,500 per child.... Read More See grandkids, or the Grand Prix! Best credit cards for retirees No matter what you&apos;re planning for your retirement years, there&apos;s a credit
card to fit your new lifestyle.... Read More 6 best credit cards for your small business Credit card issuers are courting small business entrepreneurs again with
special cash back rebates and other money-saving perks.... Read More 2011 Editor&apos;s Choice Awards, Part 1 This year&apos;s best credit card offers include innovative travel rewards cards
and cash back reward programs.... Read More 2011 Editor&apos;s Choice Awards, Part 2 Credit cards that help establish, restore and extend credit captured the
attention of our panelists this year.... Read More 
Featured
 
 
 If Olypmic athletes were credit cards... 
 
 5 outrageous credit card purchases 
 
 Should you use peer-to-peer lending to pay off your credit cards? 
 
 Attack of the clones: why you&apos;re at risk for a credit card scam 
 

 Featured Articles Archive 
 
Archive
 
 Credit card offers match stock market trends, posting fewest direct mail campaigns in two years Discover Card website earns top honors, as CFO considers issuing private label credit cards MasterCard customers spend $600 more per month with PayPass contactless credit cards Rewards credit card holders will drive to summer vacations, if they can&apos;t fly for free Sovereign Bank taps LevelUp for mobile wallet promotion
	</body>
</document>
