<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006009" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/do-restaurants-pay-royalties-when-they-sing-happy-birthday" time="2012-07-12-22:41" support="1" score="0.000824707340788272" bingtitle="Do restaurants pay royalties when they sing Happy Birthday? | ChaCha" webtitle="Do restaurants pay royalties when they sing Happy Birthday? | ChaCha">
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>Ridiculous Receipts. Viewed 3,878 times ... What happens if you cant pay for your bill at a ... What is the highest paying fast food restaurant in Missouri?</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Do restaurants pay royalties when they sing Happy Birthday? 

In: Lifestyle › Dining Out 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Singing Happy Birthday in a restaurant technically requires a license and royalties, but offenses are rarely prosecuted. ChaCha! 
 Answered

 by Rosalie A. - 623 days ago at 9:35pm on Oct 27 2010 
Related Questions for Dining Out 

 
 What is the average hourly pay for a full time fast food restaurant employee? 

The average hourly wage for a fast food worker ...

in Careers&amp;Employment | 19 hr 4 min ago via Android app 
 
 What fast food restaurants and grocery stores pay weekly pay checks? 

Most grocery stores pay biweekly; fast food is ...

in Careers&amp;Employment | 23 hr 24 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 How much does working at a fast food restaurant pay per month? 

Most jobs are part time and have few educationa...

in Careers&amp;Employment | 1 day ago via web 
 
 What happens to people that eat at a restaurant but don&apos;t have the money to pay for it? 

It would depend on the managerially decision pr...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 How do you pay in a restaurant? 

You can pay with a credit,debit card or cash. M...

in Dining Out | 3 days ago via sms text 
 
 When you&apos;re paying at a restaurant if the tab added gratuity do you still have to give tip? 

No, if gratuity is already on the bill, you don...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Can you pay with debit at restaurants? 

Many debit cards also carry the Visa or MasterC...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 5 days ago via Android app 
 
 What would happen if you ate at a restaurant and couldn&apos;t pay for your meal? 

When you enter a restaurant you are in contract...

in Dining Out | 5 days ago via Android app 
 
 What happens when you eat at a restaurant but don&apos;t have enough money to pay for the meal? 

If someone goes up to the cashier and realizes ...

in Dining Out | 5 days ago via web 
 
 Can I make more money for a job that pays hourly or for a server at a restaurant? 

This all depends on the hourly rate they&apos;re pay...

in Careers&amp;Employment | 8 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is it called when you run out of a restaurant without paying the bill? 

Stiffed, stiffing, or stiffs is a slang term us...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 8 days ago via Android app 
 
 Which fast food restaurants can you pay with EBT? 

Some fast food restaurants that you can pay wit...

in Dining Out | 9 days ago via web 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Galleries for Dining Out 

 
 
 
 10 Worst Brunch Foods for Your Diet 
 Viewed 833 times 
 
 
 
 5 Alternatives to Traditional Gym Equipment 
 Viewed 371 times 
 
 
 
 6 Unhealthy Fast-Food Kids Meals 
 Viewed 672 times 
 
 
 
 13 First Date Fashion Mistakes Men Make 
 Viewed 3689 times 
 
 
 
 How to Overcome Bad Eating Habits 
 Viewed 777 times 
 
 
 
 10 First Date Fashion Mistakes Women Make 
 Viewed 3717 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Quizzes for Dining Out 

 
 
 
 What&apos;s Your Food Weakness? 
 
 
 
 Which Foods Are Higher in Calories? 
 Viewed 23093 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know the Facts About Secondhand Smoke? 
 
 
 
 Are You Eating Proper Food Portions? 
 Viewed 3113 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Your Calorie Counts? 
 Viewed 9074 times 
 
 
 
 How Should You Celebrate Mother&apos;s Day? 
 Viewed 8740 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Dining Out 

 Wendys» Dominos Pizza» Applebees» Hooters» Red Robin» Papa Johns» Arbys» Bob Evans» Cracker Barrel» Drive Thru» 
 
Top Trends in Lifestyle 

 Puppies» Makeup» Restaurant» Kittens» Fishing» Fast Food» liquor» McDonalds» Pizza» Coke» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Ford» Hurt» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Lifestyle › Dining Out 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
