<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006964" url="http://up.opencarry.org/forums/showthread.php?71591-Open-Carry-List-for-St-Louis-County/page3" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="1" score="0.0020949273694349613" bingtitle="Open Carry List for St. Louis County - Page 3" webtitle="Open Carry List for St. Louis County - Page 3">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>I live in unincorporated St. Louis County and I ... But at a fast food restaurant or small mom and pop store. ... is always just on the other side of the counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 

       
 What&apos;s New? Forum 
 New Posts FAQ Calendar Community 
 Albums Member List 
 Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 Today&apos;s Posts View Site Leaders 
 
 Blogs 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum Stories From The States Missouri Open Carry List for St. Louis County 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. Please review the Forum Rules frequently as we are constantly trying to improve the forum for our members and visitors. 
 Page 3 of 4 First 1 2 3 4 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 51 to 75 of 93 
Thread: Open Carry List for St. Louis County 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 01-23-2011,  06:00 PM #51 kylemoul 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location st louis Posts 415 if open carry is not allowed in your city, are you still allowed to OC on your private property? Reply With Quote 01-24-2011,  08:04 AM #52 lancej3540 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location Arnold, mo Posts 11 Originally Posted by kylemoul if open carry is not allowed in your city, are you still allowed to OC on your private property? you can open carry or conceal carry on your own property
anyway you wish to carry on your own property make sure about the laws where you like just in case you happen to step off.. Reply With Quote 01-24-2011,  02:15 PM #53 kylemoul 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location st louis Posts 415 ok cool. that what i thought.
does anyone know the statue for that offhand?

i sit on the front porch at my bros in ferguson right off of elizabeth. pretty busy road. i can only imagine one of the crazy joggers or dog walkers will call the cops cause i have a sidearm. Reply With Quote 01-24-2011,  03:06 PM #54 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by kylemoul ok cool. that what i thought.
does anyone know the statue for that offhand?

i sit on the front porch at my bros in Ferguson right off of Elizabeth. pretty busy road. i can only imagine one of the crazy joggers or dog walkers will call the cops cause i have a sidearm. Ferguson has no Open Carry specific restriction laws. You can OC on any ones property that you can legally be on with a firearm. You may want to look at the list that this thread is started off of.

Doc Reply With Quote 02-04-2011,  02:25 PM #55 kylemoul 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location st louis Posts 415 well, i cant go to lemay/oakville/mehlville and look at the laws. im in lemay every friday after work but its too late. and i would probably be late for bowling.

anyone live in those cities? Reply With Quote 02-06-2011,  12:12 AM #56 goldengoose14 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2011 Location St. Louis CO. Posts 2 Hey sohigh! Thanks for all the great info its much apprechiated! I was wondering if you knew anything about shooting an air rifle/pellet gun on your own private property? I live in unincorporated St. Louis County and I have a proper steel pellet trap that I target shoot with. Is this legal? Thanks in advance. Reply With Quote 02-06-2011,  09:15 AM #57 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by goldengoose14 Hey sohigh! Thanks for all the great info its much apprechiated! I was wondering if you knew anything about shooting an air rifle/pellet gun on your own private property? I live in unincorporated St. Louis County and I have a proper steel pellet trap that I target shoot with. Is this legal? Thanks in advance. The law that applies to unincorporated areas of St Louis County is this.

716.135 Regulation of BB and Pellet Guns.--

1. It shall be unlawful for any person under sixteen (16) years of age openly to carry any BB gun or pellet gun on or in any public street, road, highway or park unless accompanied by a person eighteen (18) years of age or older.
2. It shall be unlawful for any person under sixteen (16) years of age and openly carrying a BB gun or pellet gun to willfully enter or go upon the premises or property of another, or to discharge any BB gun or pellet gun while on the premises or property of another, without having first obtained the written permission from the owner or other person in charge of such premises or property and having said written permission on his person; except, however, this section shall not apply to a person carrying or discharging a BB gun or pellet gun while in the immediate presence and with the consent of the owner or person in charge of the premises or property.
3. It shall be unlawful for any person to discharge a BB gun or pellet gun in such a manner so as to injure, wound or damage the person or property, real or personal, of another; or in such direction that any projectile expelled strikes, hits, enters or goes through any vehicle, dwelling, residence, or other building; or from or across any street, sidewalk, road, highway, or any park except on a target or practice range. Reply With Quote 02-06-2011,  12:00 PM #58 goldengoose14 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2011 Location St. Louis CO. Posts 2 thank you very much! Reply With Quote 02-08-2011,  06:39 PM #59 kylemoul 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location st louis Posts 415 am i seeing things, or is there absolutely no ordinance about weapons offenses at municode for the city of ferguson? Reply With Quote 02-08-2011,  06:41 PM #60 kylemoul 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location st louis Posts 415 nevermind found it Reply With Quote 05-03-2011,  07:48 PM #61 cash50 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2010 Location St. Louis Posts 349 Bump for our newest member.

Maplewood, if not already added, is OC Illegal now. Reply With Quote 05-07-2011,  11:41 AM #62 usmcbess 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Labadie, Missouri, USA Posts 191 
City of Chesterfield
 I just got off the phone with a city of Chesterfield police officer. For what it is worth this officer told me that open carry had been discussed at a recent&quot;roll call&quot;and that open carry was legal on public property in the city limits. Reply With Quote 05-07-2011,  08:04 PM #63 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 Originally Posted by usmcbess I just got off the phone with a city of Chesterfield police officer. For what it is worth this officer told me that open carry had been discussed at a recent&quot;roll call&quot;and that open carry was legal on public property in the city limits. Interesting..... I wonder if they would send you a letter stating that? Sure would like to see it!
Did he give any indication as to what happens if you are on private property? I&apos;m in the valley several days a week! Would sure make my days. Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-07-2011,  11:22 PM #64 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by sohighlyunlikely List updated to reflect change in Maplewood from legal OC to illegal.

Doc Reply With Quote 05-08-2011,  05:50 AM #65 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 DOC, what do you make of the previous post where&quot;OC is legal on public property&quot;from The City of Chesterfield? Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-08-2011,  10:18 AM #66 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by mspgunner DOC, what do you make of the previous post where&quot;OC is legal on public property&quot;from The City of Chesterfield? As there is no laws that would apply to open carry on public property(other than park laws and government building restrictions). I have always said that open carry is legal in Chesterfield, Wildwood and Unincorporated St Louis County. I myself have open carried numerous times in unincorporated St Louis County. On private property I am always sure that the manager on duty is either in eyes view or addressed and is aware of my presence.
I have done some open carry in Chesterfield as well. You may be aware of me being denied my open carry rights at Adventure Shooting Sports in Chesterfield.

 http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MEbXNd5M3-s 

Doc Reply With Quote 05-08-2011,  10:24 AM #67 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 So if I for instance go to Sam&apos;s Club in the valley, go in with OC and ask for permission to OC in the store am I legal if seeking permsission? Grant you, I&apos;m not that brave about it, just wondering/ Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-08-2011,  01:32 PM #68 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by mspgunner So if I for instance go to Sam&apos;s Club in the valley, go in with OC and ask for permission to OC in the store am I legal if seeking permission? Grant you, I&apos;m not that brave about it, just wondering/ Yes, But here is were it gets complicated. As is my understanding of the law in Chesterfield. Once you have interacted with the person to whom has charge over the property you must be in his presence or be given written permission to be on that property if not in the presence of a person to whom has charge over that property. In this modern world were written permission is rarely given by anyone to do anything your shopping trip to any big box store would be near impossible to adhere to the law. But at a fast food restaurant or small mom and pop store. A manager is always just on the other side of the counter, problem solved.

Here is a question I am interested in knowing. Is this law like trespass? Were as it is the responsibility of the Property owner(or his ward) to press charges if this law is broke. Or can a LEO write this ticket(as it is a misdemeanor) on his own.

Doc Reply With Quote 05-08-2011,  03:53 PM #69 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 Originally Posted by sohighlyunlikely Yes, But here is were it gets complicated. As is my understanding of the law in Chesterfield. Once you have interacted with the person to whom has charge over the property you must be in his presence or be given written permission to be on that property if not in the presence of a person to whom has charge over that property. In this modern world were written permission is rarely given by anyone to do anything your shopping trip to any big box store would be near impossible to adhere to the law. But at a fast food restaurant or small mom and pop store. A manager is always just on the other side of the counter, problem solved.

Here is a question I am interested in knowing. Is this law like trespass? Were as it is the responsibility of the Property owner(or his ward) to press charges if this law is broke. Or can a LEO write this ticket(as it is a misdemeanor) on his own.

Doc Good points, good questions. I don&apos;t think I&apos;d go to the Chesterfield police to find out. I&apos;ll just continue to CCW my evil firearm in the valley for now! Don&apos;t ask, don&apos;t tell will keep legal expenses down for now. Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  12:31 PM #70 usmcbess 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Labadie, Missouri, USA Posts 191 Originally Posted by mspgunner Interesting..... I wonder if they would send you a letter stating that? Sure would like to see it!
Did he give any indication as to what happens if you are on private property? I&apos;m in the valley several days a week! Would sure make my days. Like most other places in STL County you must obtain written permission to OC on private property. Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  01:30 PM #71 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by usmcbess Like most other places in STL County you must obtain written permission to OC on private property. I do not agree with your statement . This is only law in Wildwood, Chesterfield and the unincorporated parts of St. Louis county.

Doc Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  02:09 PM #72 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 Originally Posted by usmcbess Like most other places in STL County you must obtain written permission to OC on private property. And getting written permission is tougher than pulling teeth! Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  10:01 PM #73 xdmcompact 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2011 Location St Louis City Posts 222 I could swear I read that Kirkwood did not allow OC? OC is legal in Kirkwood? Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  10:21 PM #74 mspgunner 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Feb 2009 Location Wildwood, Missouri, USA Posts 1,030 Originally Posted by xdmcompact I could swear I read that Kirkwood did not allow OC? OC is legal in Kirkwood? Kirkwood is&quot;legal&quot;on the list I have, always check the local laws first. Subscribe to the newsletter for Missouri Open Carry http://itsarightmooc.com register and download today!
If you pull it, you use it. If you pull it and you don&apos;t use it, you&apos;ve done some thing wrong and you might not get another chance. Think about it before you pack it! Reply With Quote 05-10-2011,  11:27 PM #75 sohighlyunlikely 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message View Blog Entries Visit Homepage 
 Regular Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Overland, Missouri, USA Posts 724 Originally Posted by xdmcompact I could swear I read that Kirkwood did not allow OC? OC is legal in Kirkwood? Kirkwood Starbucks

Doc

 Reply With Quote 
 Page 3 of 4 First 1 2 3 4 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Quick Navigation Missouri Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Rules of Engagement 
 Forum Rules Frequently Asked Questions Announcements The Law Library OpenCarry.Org In The News 
 Open Carry Brigade 
 Hot Topics News&amp;Political Alerts Selecting a Handgun Holsters and Accessories Why Open Carry Open Carry Questions True Tales of Self Defense GMU Students For Concealed Carry General Discussion The Social Lounge 
 Stories From The States 
 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
 US Territories 
 Guam Northern Mariana Islands Puerto Rico US Virgin Islands 
 International Gun Rights 
 Great Britain Canada 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts   
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On [VIDEO] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 

 -- Default Style -- Default Mobile Style 
 Contact Us OpenCarry.org Archive Top 
 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 04:57 PM . Powered by vBulletin® Version 4.2.0
Copyright©2012 vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
