<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007780" url="http://www.tccd.edu/Wafeeq_Sabir.html" time="2012-07-13-00:44" support="1" score="0.0006735656125197563" bingtitle="Tarrant County College - Wafeeq Sabir" webtitle="Tarrant County College - Wafeeq Sabir">
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>TCC Adjunct Professor Wafeeq Sabir was a fast-food restaurant ... Bill Holt; Razan Saleh; Rebecca Balcarcel; Brian Boerner ... An author and researcher on social change, Sabir ...</description>
	<body>
		Future Students Current&amp;Former Students Alumni 
 Business&amp;Community Faculty&amp;Staff Foundation&amp;Scholarships 
 
 Español LIBRARIES Financial Aid A-Z Index Calendar MyTCC 
 
 
   Getting Started Plan for Success Apply for Admission Financial Aid&amp;Scholarships Placement Testing Academic Advisement Academic Enrichment Program (AEP) Costs&amp;Payments Register for Classes Student ID&amp;Parking Bookstores&amp;Textbooks TCC Brochure About TCC Strategic Plan, TCC Vision 2015 Accreditation Administration Board of Trustees Chancellor College History Community Reports Education Initiatives Information Center Statistics Office of Institutional Research, Planning and Effectiveness (IRPE) Legal Notices Mission Statement Recent News Open Records Requests Police Department Public Relations and Marketing Publications Quick Facts Admissions Apply for Admission Meningitis Vaccinations - MCV4 Residency Submit a Transcript Evaluation of Transfer Coursework Admission Status and Notices Registration and Withdrawal Registrar Offices Courses and Programs Program Offerings Mandatory Attendance Policy Academic Enrichment Program (AEP) Credit vs. Noncredit Degrees and Certificates Basics / Core Curriculum Fields of Study Honors Program Weekend College Course Descriptions Class Schedules Catalog Service Learning Study Abroad Transitional Programs Student Services Academic Advisement Bookstores and Textbooks Career and Employment Costs and Payments Disability Support Financial Aid Graduation Health and Fitness Labs and Tutoring Student Activities Student Records Student Conduct and Appeals Student IDs and Parking Permits Testing Transportation, Housing, Childcare and Food Veterans and Military Continuing Education Registration Campus Office Locations&amp;Hours African American Professionals Conference (AAPC) Career Programs Children and Youth Continuing Professional Education Corporate Services Developmentally Challenged Students Economic Development English as a Second Language (ESL) Personal Enrichment and Leisure Senior Citizens Tarrant SBDC Test Preparation Workforce Services Campuses and Centers Northeast Campus Northwest Campus South Campus Southeast Campus Trinity River Campus Trinity River East Campus May Owen Center / District Offices Distance Learning Corporate Services Training Centers Criminal Justice Training Center Fire Service Training Center Haltom City Northeast Center Learning Opportunities Centers Tarrant SBDC   
 Laura Rusnok Glenn Lewis Brad Gorrondona Onika Taylor Brian Mathis Susan Bryan Wafeeq Sabir 

 Jennifer Huie Donnell McKenzie Bill Holt Razan Saleh Rebecca Balcarcel Brian Boerner Buck Kelsey Lakisha Morgan Richard Weinhold Robert Smith Tommy Walker Donlita Cloud Andy Wambsganss Shelly Williams Harold Willis Kimberly Blackmon Teresa Nelson Hung Vu Steve Elms Kay Hancock Chase Webster Christi Crews Darrell Whitsell Johnny Phipps Traci Adame Lauren Lee Jeremy Spann Horace A. Davis Chris Carcerano Maricela Pineda Northeast Campus&apos; Jazz Lab Band Woody Kageler Nick Smith Lauren Mathers The Collegian Angela Peragine Andre McEwing Esmeralda Duran Aaron Gomez Angel Garcia Kevin Burch Respiratory Care Students Tiashanta Latham Terry Kranz Christene Moss 
 Home  &gt;Wafeeq Sabir Print / Share 
 Print Page Send to a Friend Facebook MySpace StumbleUpon 
       
Wafeeq Sabir

 TCC Adjunct Professor Wafeeq Sabir was a fast-food restaurant manager in Houston when one harrowing incident changed his life. He was confronted by an armed gunman, and suddenly a prophecy frequently made about the business was fulfilled.

&quot;When you get robbed, and you will,&quot; said Sabir, who teaches sociology at Southeast Campus. &quot;That&apos;s what everyone told me. It&apos;s not a matter of &apos;if&apos; but when.&quot;

Contemplating his future, Sabir responded to a Fort Worth Police Department recruiting ad and knew he had to give law enforcement a try. His assignment to Fort Worth&apos;s acclaimed gang unit placed him front and center of escalating gang problems in the city&apos;s middle and high schools.

An author and researcher on social change, Sabir lectured parents, teachers and community leaders about the destruction brought on by street criminals. And, he used his skills as a rapper to reach students from Fort Worth to Europe.

&quot;Society will never totally eradicate gangs, but the public is becoming more aware,&quot; said Sabir, who holds a doctorate from Minneapolis-based Capella University. Schools, he said, must become safe zones, and education can transform at-risk students.

&quot;I like the interaction with the students,&quot; he said. &quot;I just want to take whatever blessings God showers down,&quot; said Sabir, nearing his 25th year as a police officer. &quot;I still have this desire to reach back into the community -- not just have these degrees and step on these platforms. I really feel I need to make an impact.&quot;

 By Debra Dennis 
   
 Employment Help&amp;FAQs Emergency Information Directory CampusCruiser-WebAdvisor Legal Notices 
   
Tarrant County College District 1500 Houston Street Fort Worth, Texas 76102
Information Center: 817-515-8223 Hearing / Speech Impaired (TTY) 
 Online Institutional Resumes (per Sec. 51A.002, Texas Education Code)
 Report A Problem 

 An Achieving the Dream Institution 
 Copyright©Tarrant County College District. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
