<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007500" url="http://www.problogs.com/Post3766.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:28" support="2" score="0.00548982539469868" bingtitle="Food Allergies &amp; Fast Food Restaurants! A review on McDonalds by ..." webtitle="Food Allergies&amp;Fast Food Restaurants! A review on McDonalds by Belinda Long">
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="65"/>
	<description>I am very careful to inform whomever is taking my order that my child has food ... How to tell if a man loves you ABRAHAM, SARAH, HAGAR and sons ISHMAEL and ISAAC</description>
	<body>
		Home Log In Sign Up FAQ&apos;s Contact ProBlogs About ProBlogs 

   
 Become a ProBlogger! Be a part of the professional blogging community at ProBlogs.com!

 Signup Now! | Log In   


 Featured Bloggers Creative (54,965) 
 Robert Melaccio, sr (28,936) 
 CatherineYen (20,979) 
 Mike Fak (18,246) 
 Danny Davids (13,494) 
 Alf Gordon (13,356) 
 Rob Trahan (12,495) 
 beanerywriters (11,675) 
 CarolynCHolland (9,534) 
 BJChips (5,633) 

   
 Home » Categories » Health » Health News »Food Allergies&amp;Fast Food Restaurants! A review on McDonalds 
 
Food Allergies&amp;Fast Food Restaurants! A review on McDonalds
 
By Belinda Long (267) 

 Posted Wednesday, January 09, 2008
 View All Blog Posts submitted by Belinda Long 

    Mcdonalds. It has become the Toys R Us of Fast food for children. But is it safe for children with food allergies? The answer is no.      Unfortunately, despite the recent elevation of food allergies in kids, it seems fast food companies have forgotten about the food allergic community. McDonalds is on the top of the list of fast food places that fail to recognize food allergies.      I have a 5 year old allergic to dairy. Naturally I went right to McDonalds website to see what products they made did not contain dairy. We have settled on getting a hamburger happy meal with an apple juice juicebox and apple dippers with no caramel dip. I am very careful to inform whomever is taking my order that my child has food allergies and stating plainly that he cannot have anything else. However, on several different occasions, at several different McDonalds, I have experienced flawed service.      On one occasion, I got home with McDonalds only to find that they had put fries in his bag. When I contacted McDonalds, a very brave employee actually grumped out the comment &quot;What do you want me to do about it?&quot; On another saidoccasion, at a different McDonalds, the lady taking my order informed me that she was out of Apple Dippers. When I requested that they substitute the Apple Dippers for an apple pie (also dairy free), due to my sons allergy to dairy, the clerk retorted that she had never heard anything about dairy being in thier french fries and refused to substitute.      I realize that if you don&apos;t know someone with food allergies, you probably won&apos;t know much about them. Alternatively, I believe that if you work in the food industry, you should make it your business to know about them. Even employess of fast food restaurants should either know, or have a reference they can refer too.     

 This Blog Post has been read 266 times.
Posted to ProBlogs.com on Wednesday, January 09, 2008
 View other posts by Belinda Long 

 Comments on this blog post: 
 Molasses from Seattle WA: (86 days 16 hours ago.) 
Didn&apos;t realize McDonalds fries contained a dairy derivative. I checked the McDonald&apos;s website and verified that it does. My 21-month old has dairy and peanut allergies. We only give him fries when at McDonald&apos;s thinking this would be the only food without dairy. He hasn&apos;t had a reaction so far and he loves his fries. I do agree that most of the staff aren&apos;t well-informed about food allergies. I inquired once if McNuggets contained egg or dairy and was confidently told &quot;NO!&quot;. I ordered it but didn&apos;t feed it to my son as I just had a gut feeling about it. We&apos;ll try the Hamburger Happy Meal next time. Thanks.

 DV from Houston, TX: (76 days 6 hours ago.) 
I too have had problems with Mc Donalds. My son is allergic to peanuts and tree nuts so even though I check restaurant websites, I always make sure to ask if the food I order is in fact nut free. The last time I went to Mc Dondald&apos;s and asked the manager what type of oil was used to fry their fries and she said she did not know. I explained my son&apos;s allergies and then another employee approached us and said, &quot;Oh yeah. We use peanut oil.&quot; We left with my son asking for his fries and when I emailed Mc Donald&apos;s I was told they did not know why I was told that. Is it too much to ask for their employees to be informed and show a little care and consideration for people with food allergies? It is really upsetting. Suffice it to say that it has been months since that last time I set foot into a Mc Donald&apos;s. My son is only two and I don&apos;t want him to get used to food and then have the restaurant change ingredients and him not being able to have it anymore. If only others knew the difficulty of living with a food allergy.
 
Leave a Public Comment or Question:
 

 
 Bad Habits Promote Good Health 
 Possible Link Between Cell Phone Usage and Male Infertility 
 Social Anxiety - The Top 5 Pets That Can Help You 
 Choking Game Poses Serious Health Threats to Unsuspecting Teens 
 Getting Off Meds Has Consequences? How About Getting On Them? 
 Cardiovascular Suicide and The Church Of Biological Mysticism 
 Lunacy Abounds At The CDC - The Flu Shot Lottery 
   
 Most Recent Related Posts Just what is it you who have can’t seem to grasp or don’t want to? 

 Home Improvement: The Bathroom Reformation 

 Rightful Discrimination: Why DNA Databasing by Government is Wrong 

 The Heart Sutra - a greatest sutra in buddhism 

 The Media’s White Wash Of The Winter Solider Conference 

 Online Auctions: Love Them or Loath Them? 

 Passion versus 2nd Ambition 

 New Migration of Immigrants in Northern Virginia. 

 Home alone - fending off robbers or working? 

 Building a PC for Dummies...Dummy 

   


 Most Popular Related Posts How to tell if a girl likes you 

 A Tragic Screen Goddess--the forever Romy Schneider 

 A Tribute to Audrey Hepburn 

 How to tell if a man loves you 

 ABRAHAM, SARAH, HAGAR and sons ISHMAEL and ISAAC 

 Life is too short to wake up with regrets 

 A Genteel Grace of A Leading Movie Star-Deborah Kerr , Died at 86 (1921-2007) 

 25 Things you should NOT do on a First Date! 

 Doctors Urge&quot;Don&apos;t Stop Taking Anti-depressants&quot; 

 The Art of Chinese Brush Pen and Ink Stone 

   
 

 Home | FAQ&apos;s | Categories | Blogging Guidelines | Recent Referrals | Terms of Use | Privacy | About ProBlogs | Contact ProBlogs Copyright 2008 ProBlogs.com - All rights reserved. 
 Not Logged In
	</body>
</document>
