<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007592" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g32530-d830461-Reviews-Tomikawa_Sushi_Bar_Restaurant-Irvine_California.html" time="2012-07-13-00:33" support="2" score="0.008509220808208219" bingtitle="Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant, Irvine - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant - 11 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>This is the typical step up from fast food restaurant. ... spilled all my water on me, and they made my food ... every little need including taking your order ...</description>
	<body>
		Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant, Irvine
 
 Home Irvine 
 Irvine Tourism Irvine Hotels Irvine Vacation Rentals Flights to Irvine Irvine Restaurants Things to Do in Irvine Irvine Travel Forum Irvine Photos Irvine Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; California (CA) &gt; Orange County &gt; Irvine &gt; Irvine Restaurants &gt; Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant 
 
 All 347 Irvine Restaurants» 
Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant
 14191 Jeffrey Rd , Irvine , CA 92620-3404 949-786-9888 Menu Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #110 of 347 restaurants in Irvine 11 Reviews Cuisines: Japanese Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
11 reviews from our community
 36% Recommend 
 Excellent 2 Very good 2 Average 4 Poor 1 Terrible 2 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 11 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any Expat-in-Schweiz Switzerland Senior Contributor 32 reviews Reviews in 23 cities 17 helpful votes “Average to good Japanese cuisine” Reviewed March 25, 2012 
This is the typical step up from fast food restaurant. Please don&apos;t expect perfect service. You do get satisfactory service for this type of restaurant.
I am not an expert on Japanese food and I don&apos;t eat sashimi so I can&apos;t help in that area. I go to Tomikawa often for a quick bite and it is usually for their... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Javanut4673 Millbrae, California Senior Reviewer 10 reviews Reviews in 6 cities 3 helpful votes “Had fun to open the holiday season with friends...” Reviewed January 18, 2012 
I went with 5 other friends around 5:30pm for the Happy Hour Specials. The atmosphere was nothing to write home about EXCEPT to say that the acoustics allowed for private conversations to be heard without shouting or worrying about disturbing the next table - which is unique today. The food - we ordered 27 different kinds of sushi with two... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Shuttrrbug Sugar Land, Texas Senior Contributor 37 reviews Reviews in 21 cities 16 helpful votes “Excellent Japenese cruisine!” Reviewed December 31, 2011 
Family finally persauded me to try Japenese and Tomikawa did not disappoint. Excellent cruisine. This was my first meal to totally consume with chop sticks. So fun. Try the steak and chicken tempura combination for lunch. Sushi and many of the rolls were very good. We will return and hope to see you there.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by Shuttrrbug for Irvine 65oski Irvine, California Senior Contributor 43 reviews Reviews in 22 cities 30 helpful votes “Good neighborhood place” Reviewed December 23, 2011 
We go to Tomikawa about once a quarter and were there on a Sunday evening. Not crowded and no wait for a table but most tables were full. They&apos;ve added an appetizer of edamame fried in butter and garlic that&apos;s the best $3.50 you&apos;ll spend; really good way to start a meal. Service is good and food is the usual... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 2 more reviews by 65oski for Irvine Obok15 Valdez, Alaska Contributor 20 reviews Reviews in 11 cities 24 helpful votes “Disgusting, Dreadful Place” Reviewed July 29, 2011 
This terrible place is a restaurant that nobody should go to. The food tastes very bad, and it is very expensive. The service is horrible. All the staff just ignored me. Also, the waiters and waitresses are so clumsy that they spilled all my water on me, and they made my food drop on the floor. Also, they did not... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 9 more reviews by Obok15 for Irvine Fatbird1 Santa Ana, California Top Contributor 218 reviews Reviews in 44 cities 130 helpful votes “Boy, were we disappointed--this place has changed for the WORST” Reviewed February 13, 2011 
We ate here about a year ago and enjoyed it, but when we went in February 2011, we were really disappointed. Has the place changed hands? The tempura tasted heavy, greasy, and uncooked. My teriaki chicken came cold, and although I was served tea, there was never any refill. The whole experience was not what we had before and I... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by Fatbird1 for Irvine OCer Dana Point, California Reviewer 4 reviews Reviews in 3 cities “Great Japanese and Sushi” Reviewed January 10, 2011 
I had read some bad reviews about this restaurant. Fortunately I ignored them and decided to go for dinner with my fiance. Everything was very good. The service was excellent and the prices were extremely reasonable for such high quality food. They have a very extensive sushi menu as well as many cooked Japanese dishes. An A+
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook 1 helpful vote “Inexpensive and good.” Reviewed November 16, 2008 
Inexpensive and good.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook “I LOVE Ultimate Salmon here~” Reviewed June 29, 2008 
I LOVE Ultimate Salmon here~
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? NuShrike SoCal 1 review “mockery of a restaurant!” Reviewed May 15, 2008 
poor service and food: Forget getting refills for water. Treat it as a place where you have to grab the servers for every little need including taking your order, asking for the check, and boxing the food yourself to take home.
Only thing of merit is the large non-traditional selection of rolls.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? 1-10 of 11 reviews « 1 2 » 
Travelers who viewed Tomikawa Sushi Bar Restaurant also viewed
 Tuscany Mediterranee Grill 32 Reviews Irvine, Orange County
	</body>
</document>
