<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007529" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g48261-d842038-Reviews-The_Original_Honey_s-Niagara_Falls_New_York.html" time="2012-07-13-00:30" support="6" score="0.006593691091668652" bingtitle="The Original Honey&apos;s, Niagara Falls - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor" webtitle="The Original Honeys Reviews - 28 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>Our table was sticky so I wiped it was a napkin and ... grime, including door handles, floor, tables, condiment ... Get the best picks for where to eat, sleep, and play.</description>
	<body>
		The Original Honey&apos;s, Niagara Falls
 
 Home Niagara Falls 
 Niagara Falls Tourism Niagara Falls Hotels Niagara Falls Vacation Rentals Flights to Niagara Falls Niagara Falls Restaurants Things to Do in Niagara Falls Niagara Falls Travel Forum Niagara Falls Photos Niagara Falls Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; New York (NY) &gt; Niagara Falls &gt; Niagara Falls Restaurants &gt; The Original Honey&apos;s 
 
 All 220 Niagara Falls Restaurants» 
The Original Honey&apos;s
 2002 Military Rd , Niagara Falls , NY 14304 (716) 297-7900 Ranked #110 of 220 restaurants in Niagara Falls 28 Reviews Cuisines: Fast Food 3 visitor photos Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
28 reviews from our community
 33% Recommend 
 Excellent 3 Very good 6 Average 1 Poor 6 Terrible 12 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 28 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any JohnNDonna The Villages, FL Senior Contributor 23 reviews Reviews in 17 cities 15 helpful votes “What a disappointment” Reviewed July 10, 2012 NEW 
Honey&apos;s in the past served good food at a reasonable price. That is history. The new location at Niagara Falls Blvd and I-190 is convenient. The shrimp dinner was good, the fries were the way you would want them. The cole slaw was marginal. The medium wings were so hot that we couldn&apos;t finish the order and we have been... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Concetta16 Niagara Falls, New York, United States Senior Reviewer 7 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “dissapointing” Reviewed June 27, 2012 
i was so upset with the service and food. our waitress only came to our table to take our order and give us our order. no drink refills,no how was was your meal. we had to search for her to get the bill. did not take the not eaten cold,burnt food back or take it off our order. it was... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by Concetta16 for Niagara Falls GFamilyfromATL Roswell, Georgia 1 review “Served Rancid Wings!” Reviewed June 25, 2012 
We usually love going to Honey&apos;s and make it one of the places we visit when we&apos;re up in Niagara Falls visiting family. The pizza&apos;s good (my extremely picky daughter loves it) and I enjoyed their cream of mushroom soup with brie but on this visit my husband was served rancid, rotten chicken wings. The first few were fine but... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? whywouldntwe Lewiston, New York Reviewer 5 reviews Reviews in 5 cities 2 helpful votes “Bad Food thats overpriced” Reviewed June 24, 2012 
If you want subpar pizza thats overpriced then this is the place for you! My undercooked, ketchup sauce with skimpy cheese pizza cost $17.50 for a&apos;Honey&apos;s Tray&apos;. Well it&apos;s tough to find bad pizza in Niagara Falls as even the average pizza shop slices are better than most other pizza in the US. Not Honeys!! In Niagara Falls you... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Darren S Hamilton, Canada 1 review 1 helpful vote “crap” Reviewed June 10, 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
we went there tonite. talk about skimpy on the cheese for the nachos and pizza. the wings were over cooked and no flavor the beer was warmer then the food.save your money they were better when they were at the outlet mall.i will not be going back.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? dragon749 Contributor 13 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 8 helpful votes “Not what it used to be” Reviewed June 9, 2012 via mobile 1 person found this review helpful 
First off, they have moved to a new location.. Its right around the corner.
I was thinking about this meal all day, ever since I made plans to meet with an old friend. Good thing we had lots of catching up to do.. It took 1 hr 15min for our pizza to arrive. Food was good other wise, service leads... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Jane P Toronto, Canada Senior Contributor 32 reviews Reviews in 10 cities 13 helpful votes “Diner fare” Reviewed May 21, 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
My husband and I eat at Honey&apos;s every time we go to the nearby outlet mall. The new location isn&apos;t as convenient as the the former - right on the mall parking lot - but was easy to find. The new location is much larger, but somehow lacks the sticky charm of the old place. There are more restrooms -... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? grahamd62 Canada Contributor 11 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 4 helpful votes “WALKED OUT !” Reviewed May 17, 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
I went to the new location on a Friday night..Never again ..hostess was more concerned about chatting to staff members,instead of seating us...music was very loud and annoying.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? stilltugboat Hamilton, Canada Contributor 13 reviews Reviews in 3 cities 7 helpful votes “New and Improved” Reviewed May 14, 2012 
It had been a few years since we visited Honey&apos;s. We had had two bad experiences in a row there and decided to give it a rest. The recently moved to Niagara Falls Blvd. The decor is cleaner. The old location had way to much stuff on the walls. My wife and I shared an order of Nachos and an... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 4 more reviews by stilltugboat for Niagara Falls TheJawsman New York Senior Contributor 23 reviews Reviews in 10 cities 8 helpful votes “Just as good as the original.” Reviewed May 13, 2012 
I&apos;m actually surprised at all of the negative reviews this place has gotten. I am reviewing this place as it stands on it&apos;s new location on Niagara Falls Blvd. where the old Timberlodge Steak House used to be.
This place has certainly improved from when I last went to a Honey&apos;s restaurant on Pine Ave. many many years back.
All... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by TheJawsman for Niagara Falls 1-10 of 28 reviews « 1 2 3 » 
Been to The Original Honey&apos;s? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage The Original Honey&apos;s, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (220) | Hotels (49) | Things to Do (43) The Original Honey&apos;s 2002 Military Rd Niagara Falls, NY 14304 Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Free Niagara Falls Guide
 Get the best picks for where to eat, sleep, and play.   Get it now 
Popular Niagara Falls restaurants

 Donatello&apos;s Restaurant Zaika Indian Cuisine Caffe Lola Villella&apos;s Ristorante Wine on Third Kobans LA Hacienda Restaurant Buzzy&apos;s New York Style Pizza la Cascata Viola&apos;s Submarine House De Dee&apos;s Dairy Leon&apos;s Italian Bistro&amp;Pizza Red Coach Inn - Restaurant Portage Bakery Hard Rock Cafe Bob Evans Restaurant Starbucks Peppertree Restaurant La Galera Mom&apos;s Coffee Shop&amp;Restaurant 
 
Hotels around Niagara Falls

 BEST WESTERN PLUS Cairn Croft Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 262 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Budget Host Inn 2.5 out of 5, 35 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Days Inn Near The Falls 4.0 out of 5, 97 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Econo Lodge at the Falls North 3.5 out of 5, 97 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Rodeway Inn&amp;Suites 3.0 out of 5, 25 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Comfort Inn Clifton Hill - Niagara Falls Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 382 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Harbour House Hotel 4.5 out of 5, 426 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 The Barton Hill Hotel&amp;Spa 3.5 out of 5, 262 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Acacia Bed&amp;Breakfast 4.5 out of 5, 9 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 Motel 6 Niagara Falls 3.5 out of 5, 40 reviews Last reviewed Jul 5, 2012 Red Carpet Inn Grand Island 2.0 out of 5, 9 reviews Last reviewed Jul 5, 2012 BEST WESTERN Summit Inn 3.5 out of 5, 87 reviews Last reviewed Jul 4, 2012 Rodeway Inn Niagara Falls 3.5 out of 5, 48 reviews Last reviewed Jun 11, 2012 Caravan Motel 2.5 out of 5, 16 reviews Last reviewed May 30, 2012 E-Lodge Near the Falls 4.0 out of 5, 11 reviews Last reviewed May 28, 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Peacock Alley in New York City 4.0 out of 5, 68 reviews Crab Trap Restaurant in Somers Point 4.5 out of 5, 115 reviews Cheese Importers in Longmont 5.0 out of 5, 22 reviews Stayner&apos;s Wharf Pub&amp;Grill in Halifax 4.0 out of 5, 52 reviews Redneck&apos;s Southern Pit BBQ in Kingman 4.5 out of 5, 91 reviews Texas Roadhouse in Watertown 4.5 out of 5, 71 reviews 
 Hotels 
 l Approdo Rapallo 4.5 out of 5, 138 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Renaissance Okinawa Resort in Onna-son 4.0 out of 5, 283 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Kale 4.0 out of 5, 8 reviews Last reviewed Oct 13, 2011 Moda Hotel in Vancouver 4.0 out of 5, 281 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor®features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, vacation packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Some photos provided by VFM Leonardo. * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
