<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007114" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/f/2/124/Chicago/Fast-Food-Places" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="5" score="0.016334716199055632" bingtitle="Chicago Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Chicago Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="21"/>
	<description>The place was plastered with photos of dogs on the front counter, on the walls, even ... Steak burrito - I have loved Chipotle ever since I first tried their food ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Chicago » Fast Food 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Green Bay Indianapolis Los Angeles Louisville Milwaukee New York St. Louis More... 
 
 Add Restaurant Chicago Fast Food Places 
 
Prices

 $$ Moderately priced (48) $ Cheap eats (2224) 
 
Neighborhoods

 
 Center 

 Loop (105) West Loop (30) 
 Show all 
 North 

 Aurora (52) Downers Grove (32) Elgin (30) Lake View (39) Lincoln Park (29) Logan Square (33) Niles (32) Schaumburg (48) Waukegan (28) 
 Show all 
 South 

 Bolingbrook (27) Gage Park&amp;Chicago Lawn (31) Joliet (45) Orland Park (30) 
 Show all 
 West 

 Naperville (51) 
 Show all 
 
Cuisines

 American (2786) Asian (554) Bakery (823) Barbecue (369) Breakfast&amp;Brunch (607) Burgers (1538) Chinese (1187) Coffee (1143) Desserts&amp;Ice Cream (763) Diner (425) Fast Food Hot Dogs&amp;Sausages (513) Italian (1308) Mexican (1638) Pizza (2075) Pub Food (1025) Sandwiches&amp;Subs (2315) Seafood (580) Steakhouse (376) Tacos (475) 
 Show all 
Features

 BYOB (5) Cash Only (9) Delivery (77) Food Truck (4) Free Wi-Fi (34) Gluten-Free Frie... (3) Happy Hour (4) Kid Friendly (716) Late Night (123) Live Music (2) Outdoor Dining (18) Private Parties (3) Sports Bar (5) Vegan Friendly (19) 
 Remove: Fast Food Sort: Best
| Alphabetical | Recently added Featured restaurants 
 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Downers Grove - Sandwiches/Subs, Fast Food Dairy Queen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Niles - Fast Food Dairy Queen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Crete - Fast Food 
 
 1 Portillo&apos;s Hot Dogs... 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ River North - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 100 W Ontario St 2 Gene&amp;Jude&apos;s Red Hot Stand 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ River Grove - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 2720 River Rd 3 Superdawg Drive-in 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Jefferson Park/Norwood Park - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 6363 N Milwaukee Ave 4 Paradise Pup 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Des Plaines - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1724 S River Rd 5 Johnnie&apos;s Beef 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Elmwood Park - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 7500 W North Ave 6 Pita Inn 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Skokie - Fast Food, Middle Eastern 3910 Dempster St 7 Buffalo Joe&apos;s 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Evanston - American, Barbecue, Fast Food 812 Clark St 8 Portillo&apos;s 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Arlington Hts - American, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 806 W. Dundee Rd. 9 The Wiener&apos;s Circle 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lincoln Park - American, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 2622 N Clark St 10 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Oak Park - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1115 Lake St. 11 Hienie&apos;s 96% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ South Chicago - Fast Food, Pizza 10359 S Torrence Ave 12 Chipotle Mexican Grill 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Orland Park - Fast Food, Tacos, Tex-Mex 15240 S La Grange Rd 13 Wow Bao 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Magnificent Mile - Asian, Chinese, Fast Food 835 N Michigan Ave 14 Pita Inn 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Wheeling - Fast Food, Middle Eastern 122 S Elmhurst Rd 15 Paul&apos;s Pizza&amp;Hot Dogs 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Westchester - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages, Pizza 3044 Wolf Rd 16 Chipotle Mexican Grill 96% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Deerfield - Fast Food, Mexican 675 Deerfield Rd 17 Meatheads Burgers&amp;Fries 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Naperville - Burgers, Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 2555 W 75th St 18 Clark Street Dog 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lake View - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 3040 N Clark St 19 Chicago Pita Kitchen 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East Side - Fast Food, Greek, Mediterranean 13227 s. Brainard ave. 20 Left Bank 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lake Forest - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 659 N Bank Ln 21 Noodles&amp;Company... 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Naperville - Asian, Fast Food, Noodle Shop 207 S Washington St 22 Gigio&apos;s Pizzeria 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Evanston - Fast Food, Pizza, Sandwiches/Subs 1001 Davis St 23 Mickey&apos;s Gyros&amp;Ribs 96% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Oak Park - Fast Food 525 N Harlem Ave 24 UNCLE Remus Restaurant 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Broadview - Barbecue, Fast Food, Seafood 1801 W Roosevelt Rd 25 Harold&apos;s Chicken Shack #62... 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ South Loop - American, Fast Food, Seafood 636 S Wabash Ave 26 Poochie&apos;s 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Skokie - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 3832 Dempster St 27 Chipotle Mexican Grill 85% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Naperville - Fast Food, Mexican 22 E Chicago Ave 28 Scooby&apos;s Hot Dogs 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ West Chicago - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 28W771 North Ave 29 Johnny&apos;s Beef&amp;Gyros 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Joliet - Burgers, Fast Food, Mediterranean 3567 W Jefferson St 30 Herm&apos;s Hot Dog Palace 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Skokie - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 3406 Dempster St 31 The Chunky Chicken 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Shorewood - American, Fast Food, Seafood 1522 Rt. 59 32 Sonic Drive-in 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Aurora - Burgers, Fast Food 2974 Kirk Rd 33 The Patio Restaurant 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Bridgeview - American, Barbecue, Fast Food 9100 S Harlem Ave 34 Five Guys Burgers and Fries 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Naperville - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 22 E Chicago Ave 35 Tortas Frontera by Rick... 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Airport: Chicago O&apos;Hare - Fast Food, Mexican, Sandwiches/Subs Terminal 5, Chicago O&apos;Hare Airport 36 Budacki&apos;s Drive-in 95% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lincoln Square - Burgers, Fast Food 4739 N Damen Ave 37 Mr. Beef 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ River North - American, Fast Food, Italian 666 N Orleans St 38 Jimmy&apos;s Red Hots 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Humboldt Park/Garfield Park - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 4000 W Grand Ave 39 Hot Spot Hot Dogs 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Carol Stream - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1030 Fountain View Drive 40 Shore&apos;s Xpress 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Douglas - Barbecue, Fast Food, Southern/Soul 3851 South Michigan 41 Chicago&apos;s Dog House 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lincoln Park - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 816 W. Fullerton 42 Fat Johnnie&apos;s Famous Red... 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Gage Park/Chicago Lawn - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 7242 S Western Ave 43 Chipotle Mexican Grill 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Elmhurst - Fast Food, Tacos, Tex-Mex 139 N. York Road 44 Downtown Dogs 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Gold Coast - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 804 N Rush St 45 Harold&apos;s Chicken Shack 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Chatham/Avalon Park - Fast Food 100 W 87th St 46 Skyway Dog House 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ South Chicago - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 9480 S Ewing Ave 47 Chipotle Mexican Grill 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Wheaton - Fast Food, Mexican 811 Butterfield Rd Ste 101 48 Chicken Hut 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lake View - Fast Food 3200 N Broadway St 49 Nicky&apos;s Gyros 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lockport - Fast Food, Greek, Hot Dogs/Sausages 903 E 9th St 50 Turkey Time! 97% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Chatham/Avalon Park - Barbecue, Fast Food, Organic 8301 S Stony Island Ave 
 « Previous Page
1 Next » 
Critic reviews

Fast Food

 May 24, 2012 Tortas Frontera by Rick Bayless By Time Out Chicago The XOCO-like options (a warm roasted-garlic torta is piled with three types of mushrooms, black beans, arugula and... Full review July 23, 2011 Top Pita Inn By Zagat Offering &apos;healthy&apos; fare &apos;as delicious as it is cheap&apos;, this trio of... Full review July 23, 2011 Top Pita Inn By Zagat Offering &apos;healthy&apos; fare &apos;as delicious as it is cheap&apos;, this trio of... Full review 
 
Blogger reviews

Fast Food

 July 5, 2012 Portillo&apos;s Hot Dogs (Chicago) By BiteMe dre in Chicago: We saw this place across from the 2-story McDonald&apos;s. We knew it sold hot dogs, but what we didn&apos;t know that it was a large food court! We thought it was a restaurant from... Full review June 4, 2012 Portillo&apos;s Hot Dogs (Chicago) By dee Cuisine &quot;Where can we get a good Chicago dog?&quot;is what we often asked Chicagoans during our recent trip to Chicago. The response by most: Portillo&apos;s Hot Dogs . And if someone asked us the same... Full review May 31, 2012 Portillo&apos;s Hot Dogs (Chicago) By Would I Buy It Again? If you look through our blog archives , you can see that we’ve made several visits to Portillo’s throughout the years (have even gotten food by mail) and in each review, we’ve reviewed... Full review 
 
Diner reviews

Fast Food

 July 7, 2012 Nicky&apos;s Gyros by elipt5 ( 1 review ) Awful dining experience. I was visiting from out of town and had a taste for a good gyro. Instead I got a very average tasting dish, high prices, poor customer service and almost overcharged (even more so than their regular prices). For starters, they tried to charge me for a bottle of water that I brought in. When I explained that I did not take it from the freezer but brought it in myself, I was looked at as if they didn’t believe me and thought I was lying. Next, in my opinion, the prices are really high and the portions are small. I ordered cheese fries and got a few drops of cheese on them. The customer service was bad and I think one of the people working was probably the owner. Lastly, the place was extremely hot – they made it very uncomfortable to stay there and enjoy a meal. Oh and I almost forgot, they require that you spend a minimum of $10 in order to use your credit card. July 5, 2012 Wow Bao Mobile review by Mademoiselle ( 1 review ) The order was not processed correctly and then we had to wait 20 minutes to get an extra quinoa bowl.. The other things got cold in the meantime. July 4, 2012 The Chunky Chicken Mobile review by AnnaR ( 5 reviews ) Went under :( 
 
Restaurant tweets

Fast Food

 about 1 hour ago Wow Bao The BAO-Mobile just pulled up to 600 W Chicago!!! #BunsOnTheRun cc: @VerveyChiChi @GrouponChicago More tweets by BaoMouth about 2 hours ago Noodles&amp;Company (Naperville, S Washington) Help us celebrate our 300th restaurant opening in Waterloo, IA! Register to be part of our history! t.co/eki5vBlD Code: Noodles300 More tweets by noodlescompany about 13 hours ago Superdawg Drive-in RT @_TheMayor: Stopped @Superdawg on way to @winatrivers. So basically I already won. ($ spent @superdawg is way better than $ lost @ slots) More tweets by Superdawg 
 
 Add Restaurant Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
