<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007588" url="http://www.mymysteryparty.com/totuschuindo.html" time="2012-07-13-00:33" support="1" score="0.0015537293922031146" bingtitle="THANKSGIVING SCAVENGER HUNT GAME - Murder Mystery Party Games" webtitle="THANKSGIVING SCAVENGER HUNT GAMEMurder Mystery Party Game">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>EXAMPLE ONE: Go to any fast food restaurant and purchase some ... EXAMPLE THREE: Go to any cosmetic counter and draw ... Team selection squares : A game rule summary for 5 teams</description>
	<body>
		home contact us view cart privacy policy about us 


 
 Investigate the Site Home &gt; Games by Season &gt; Thanksgiving &gt;Totally Turkey Scavenger Hunt - Instant Download Item# THANKSCAV $19.95 
 Description 
 Are you and at least 7 of your family members and friends ready for a fun Thanksgiving Scavenger Hunt adventure?

This Thanksgiving scavenger hunt party is an entertaining challenge that allows you and your guests to compete in an ultimate race against time. The scavenger hunt party will be a huge success as long as you and your guests relax, strategize and take some hilarious proof pictures to provide lifelong memories. 
 In summary, the guests will draw for scavenger hunt teams and navigate their way in their own cars about the town to complete a list of Thanksgiving-related tasks. The team who makes it back to home base (the host&apos;s party location) with the most successfully completed tasks verified by &apos;picture proofs&apos;...wins!



 This is the instant download version of the game - no waiting! However, if you want to play along with the rest of your guests and have the professionals at My Mystery Party put your kit together - Click here for the Party Ready Pack version of the game! 

There are 5 copies for 5 teams of the 30 TASKS in this game. If you have more than 5 teams - just simply make more copies of the game sheets!

 Some examples of the Thanksgiving-related tasks are as follows: 

EXAMPLE ONE: 
Go to any fast food restaurant and purchase some French fries (or find someone about to throw some away that they are finished with) and spell out &apos;We Are Thankful&apos; with the French fries. The picture proof is of the Thanksgiving message with at least one team member&apos;s face looking very proud. *Do this on a clean surface in case you want to eat them afterwards and not waste them!

EXAMPLE TWO: 
Make a copy of one team member&apos;s hand - with their fingers spread open wide. Make the hand photocopy into a beautiful turkey by using pens, markers, etc. Give this Thanksgiving creation to anyone not on your team. The picture proof is of the team member handing the hand-turkey drawing to someone.

EXAMPLE THREE: 
Go to any cosmetic counter and draw a turkey on one team member&apos;s cheek. Take a picture proof of it and in order for this task to count as successful, the team member should still have the turkey on their cheek during judging.

Now picture that! Hilarious, right! You&apos;ll have those great picture proofs of the scavenger hunt that you and your friends/family/co-workers can enjoy for a lifetime!

 SCAVENGER HUNT GAME MATERIALS INCLUDE THE FOLLOWING: 
 Complete game instructions for the host!  Team instructions - game play - final judging!    Team selection squares A game rule summary for 5 teams The scavenger hunt task list (30 tasks) for 5 teams Optional &apos;not cooperating with the Captain&apos; sheets for 5 teams The scavenger hunt judging score sheet 


 Life is one party at a time - so why not make this one your next? 
 
Accessories
 
 
 How to Host a Scavenger Hunt Party 
 
 Free, printable invitation 
 
 Alternative Version: Free, printable invitation 
 
 Contact us via email at: support@mymysteryparty.com (24/7) or by phone at 1-800-714-3951 (M-F, 10-3PM Central). Dallas, Texas USA

 
 Adult Mystery Party Games Teen Mystery Party Games Kid&apos;s Mystery Party Games Need More Characters? Party Ready Packs Games by Season Scavenger Hunt Games Party Props Game Extras Need Help Choosing a Game? FAQ Testimonials Gift Certificates Costume and Party Supplies Halloween Games Bridal Games The Author 
 home | contact us | view cart | privacy policy | about us Copyright 2007-2012 My Mystery Party All Rights Reserved.
The best site for Halloween Murder Mystery Parties and Games.
Contact us at 1-800-714-3951 (M-F, 10-3 PM Central) or via email: partyadvisor@mymysteryparty.com
	</body>
</document>
