<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007877" url="http://blog.cleveland.com/metro/2010/03/cleveland_police_officer_aric.html" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="1" score="0.0010595953353881682" bingtitle="On-the-mend Cleveland police officer Aric Pruitt, Max&apos;s Deli and ..." webtitle="On-the-mend Cleveland police officer Aric Pruitt, Max&apos;s Deli and ACORN: Whatever happened to ...? | 						cleveland.com">
			<query id="000698" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>... Frank Jackson&apos;s push to bring a fast-food restaurant ... cruiser, hitting a median, another car and then a pole near Randall Park ... can order elaborately prepared trays of ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Register for free Sign in to cleveland.com Username   Password Remember me I forgot my username or password» Don&apos;t have an account?
 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:

 

 AIM    Google    OpenID 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Business Sports Entertainment Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 
 Home &gt; Metro - cleveland.com &gt; Breaking News 
On-the-mend Cleveland police officer Aric Pruitt, Max&apos;s Deli and ACORN: Whatever happened to ...?

Published: Sunday, March 28, 2010, 4:33 PM   Updated: Monday, March 29, 2010, 9:18 AM 
 By Plain Dealer staff The Plain Dealer 
 Follow 10 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print 
 Chuck Crow / The Plain Dealer Cleveland police officer Aric Pruitt is back doing what he loves: working out. Pruitt was involved in a near fatal car crash in August 2007 during a police chase. Pruitt, who was unable to walk, talk or eat and breathe on his own after the accident, is currently working at the Cleveland Police Department&apos;s gym at the Justice Center and living on his own. &quot; Whatever happened to . . .?&quot; is a weekly series updating some of the most newsworthy and interesting local stories covered in The Plain Dealer. Have a suggestion on a story we should update? Send it to John C. Kuehner at jkuehner@plaind.com, or call 216-999-5325. 

 

 Today, we answer these questions: 

 Whatever Happened to . . . 

 . . . Aric Pruitt, the Cleveland police officer who survived a near fatal car crash? 

 . . . Max&apos;s Deli, which was slated to reopen at Westgate in Rocky River? 

 . . . Cleveland Mayor Frank Jackson&apos;s push to bring a fast-food restaurant chain and gas station on city property near Hopkins International Airport? 




 
 Whatever happened to Aric Pruitt, the Cleveland police officer who survived a near fatal car crash nearly two years ago?

 Aric Pruitt is doing well according to mom, Beverly Humphreys.

In 2007, Pruitt was on duty when a car was going the wrong way down Miles Avenue. Pruitt swerved out of the way and then pursued the vehicle. During the chase, Pruitt loss control of the cruiser, hitting a median, another car and then a pole near Randall Park Mall.

Doctors didn&apos;t expect Pruitt to survive. His jaw, neck and leg were broken, along with bones in his face. Pruitt also suffered a brain injury.

Today, doctors are amazed by his recovery. 

Pruitt hasn&apos;t returned to the patrol car, but he has returned to work . Since the middle of 2009, Pruitt has been working at the Justice Center gym as a trainer, helping people with their workouts and keeping the facility clean. He also helps to train new recruits in the police academy. Pruitt says it&apos;s good to be working with his colleagues again.

&quot;I love it.&quot; Pruitt said. &quot;Officers in all police departments, not just Cleveland, are my brothers and sisters. I feel like I&apos;m back at home. It&apos;s fantastic.&quot;

Pruitt is not at Jarhedz, the 24-hour gym he once owned. The family had to let it go because it became too difficult to take care of Aric and run his business.

As glad as Pruitt is to be working out again, he is unhappy about being unable to bench press 425 pounds, which he could before the accident. He can only bench press 350 now.

 &quot; He&apos;s crying about it,&quot; Humphreys laughs.

Pruitt has his own apartment now, but family is always close by to assist and oversee his affairs.

&quot;It&apos;s pretty good to be back on my own,&quot; Pruitt said. &quot;But it&apos;s because of the good Lord that ma and pa have helped me to get me back to where I am.&quot;

 -- Tonya Sams 
 


 Whatever happened to Max&apos;s Deli, which was slated to reopen at Westgate in Rocky River? 

Max&apos;s Deli owner Michele Anter-Kotoch is still looking for a new location. 

She said that much of last year was spent being a caretaker for her ailing father; she suffered the loss of two family members in 2009.

She has still been running the Max&apos;s Deli carry-out catering business and Web site ( www.maxsdeli.com , on which you can order cakes and other desserts too, though not individual servings), but her personal responsibilities slowed down her search for a new deli site.

&quot;We do want to open up again, but the looking process has been tough,&quot; she says. While the economic slowdown would seem to have created more vacant space, Anter-Kotoch says, &quot;It seems a lot of landlords don&apos;t understand the economic conditions and haven&apos;t adapted to the current market.&quot;

She&apos;s not seeing the deals she thought she would in a recessionary climate, she adds.

But, she adds, &quot;I&apos;m a foodie, and I still think there&apos;s a need for Max&apos;s Deli, which is a California-style deli.&quot; She&apos;s looking for space all over the western suburbs, including in Lakewood, Rocky River and Westlake.

&quot;I still get calls from people coming back to town, wanting to eat at Max&apos;s Deli, and asking me where it is,&quot; Anter-Kotoch says. Max&apos;s Deli was a 25-year fixture on Detroit in Rocky River before closing in June 2007.

In the meantime, you can order cakes, including the favorite triple-chocolate torte; a dozen cupcakes and other full-sized desserts on the Web site. For parties, people can order elaborately prepared trays of food, though Max&apos;s is not a full-service caterer, Anter-Kotoch explains.

The former site of Max&apos;s Deli, 19337 Detroit Road in Rocky River, is now Sweet Melissa&apos;s Confections and Eatery, which is owned and operated by some former Max&apos;s staffers.

 -- Evelyn Theiss 


 




  Whatever happened to the investigation of ACORN, the community group suspected of fraudulent voter registration practices in Cuyahoga County before the November 2008 presidential election?

 It&apos;s now on hold.

The criminal investigation in Cuyahoga County -- one of a handful of highly publicized inquires across the country into ACORN&apos;s voter registration activities -- resulted in one successful prosecution.

Darnell Nash, 25, of Garfield Heights, was sentenced last August in Cuyahoga County Common Pleas Court to six months in jail after pleading guilty to three counts of false registration. Using fake names and addresses, Nash registered to vote nine times though ACORN between May and September of 2008, according to Cuyahoga County Prosecutor Bill Mason&apos;s office.

 ACORN, as an organization, was not charged with any crimes. 

&quot;We reviewed the activities of ACORN in the Cleveland area and found no criminal culpability,&quot; Mason&apos;s spokesman said in an e-mail. &quot;Any new evidence will be reviewed.&quot;

New evidence against ACORN, however, could be scarce.

The national organization is in the midst of shutting down its offices across the country. The agency never seemed to recover from the negative attention it received for suspicious voter registration practices in Ohio and other states before the 2008 presidential election.

Ohio Republicans accused ACORN of trying to rig the presidential election by using fake names to register voters, and registering other voters multiple times. But the GOP failed in court to force Ohio Secretary of State Jennifer Brunner to investigate by cross-checking hundreds of thousands of new registrations.

ACORN said the fraud was limited to a handful of independent workers, whom it fired. Brunner directed county boards of elections to check their own records. And Cuyahoga County elections officials said after their review that it was highly unlikely anyone could vote more than once. The elections board subpoenaed people who registered multiple times to a hearing in October 2008 that attracted national medial attention. Information from the hearing was sent to the county prosecutor and county sheriff.

After the election, ACORN faced more problems.

 Funding sources were cut off after ACORN staffers were caught on hidden camera last year advising a man and woman on how to buy property for houses of prostitution. 

Now, the organization is on the verge of bankruptcy, The New York Times reported this month.

According to a March 22 statement on ACORN&apos;s Web site, all field offices will be closed by April 1. Messages could not be left at a phone number for the Cleveland ACORN office, and phone lines for other Ohio offices of ACORN have been disconnected .

-- Joe Guillen 


 Related topics: 2008 election , acorn , aric pruitt , cuyahoga county , max&apos;s deli , police officer injured in chase , voter fraud , westgate mall 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Metro - cleveland.com
 Previous story
 Court Watch: Killers, armed robbers, child porn collectors, drunken drivers due in court this week Next story
 Fallen Marine Robert Gilbert II awarded Bronze Star at funeral Copyright 2012 cleveland.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 10 
Comments Feed 
 View: 
 
 Oldest first | Newest first haluap March 28, 2010 at 5:00PM Follow 

The radical group ACORN is going under, bankrupted. That is pure bull...
As seen elsewhere the group will surface with another name with the backing of our beloved president and all of his cronies called the democratic party. Spread the wealth by making all citizens accountable to the government for ALL of the lifes needs. Instead of 25% being on assistance, it will be 75%.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new stlydnfan March 28, 2010 at 5:14PM Follow 

Way to go haluap. You nailed it. It is groups like ACORN that will bring our great country to it&apos;s knees. So few taking care of so many. I keep hearing we are at a tipping point. We are so past a tipping point it is scary! Obama really has found his stride in building the dependency nation. So much government takeover and assistance in just 16 months. Never before have we seen such a cancer spread like this across our society. And all these liberals and progressives blowing their own horns about Obama. Sure, just the next generation of freeloaders bowing to the hand that feeds them. Disgusting, diry . lazy, uneducated people.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new Keswick March 28, 2010 at 5:30PM Follow 

Looks like our great Secretary of State was wrong. She certainly showed political favoritism. Vote her out next election. Show her the voters run the show not her.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new booey420 March 28, 2010 at 5:46PM Follow 

What ever happened to the story about the fast food and gas station near the airport story?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new monkie March 29, 2010 at 10:17AM Follow 

i was just wondering the same thing?!?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new lkwoodcon March 28, 2010 at 7:05PM Follow 

April 1st ehh ..... ahh the irony .../lol

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new centsible March 28, 2010 at 9:36PM Follow 

Keep up the good work, keep it strong Aric... We are all still praying for you dude... The &apos;06 crew at the &quot;Batters Eye&quot;...

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new theshocker10 March 28, 2010 at 10:16PM Follow 

I used to go to Max&apos;s 2 times a week. I find it hard to believe with all the vacant buildings they cannot find a place to put Max&apos;s is she looking for someone to give her property for free? I have to say I missed it for a long time but now my world goes on without Max&apos;s it could not possibly be the same. Sweet Melissa&apos;s is a great place I would say even better than Max&apos;s.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new peedeezee March 29, 2010 at 11:21AM Follow 

Bad reporting on ACORN. ACORN is structured in such a way that they will continue to do the work they&apos;ve always been doing...just under a different name. Their evil will persist for as long as there are uneducated people living in the inner city waiting to be taken advantage of...all for the sake of building the base for the Liberal Democrat Party.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new tlange April 01, 2010 at 10:18AM Follow 

Aric Pruit is such a nice guy - always happy and wearing a smile! Bless him and his family! Tricia/storage.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new 
 
Post a comment
 (You may use HTML tags for style) 
 

You must accept the terms of service before you can post a comment.
 
Post a comment
 
Sign in to cleveland.com
 Username Password 
  Remember me? I forgot my username or password» 
Don&apos;t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 
 AIM Google OpenID 
 
More Metro - cleveland.com

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Metro - cleveland.com stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 184 President Barack Obama pulls away from Mitt Romney in latest Quinnipiac University poll 54 Bobcats&apos; pre-draft trade ramps up speculation: NBA Draft rumors and links 52 Ohio State&apos;s Jared Sullinger doesn&apos;t deserve this pre-draft free fall: Doug Lesmerises commentary 14 President Barack Obama will return to Ohio next week on heels of expected health care decision (updated) 11 Romney willing to tackle tough issues, Obama planning bus tour, more: Presidential Race Roundup 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most Metro - cleveland.com comments in the last 7 days 0 jillie23 
 

Users We Love
 &quot;LongSufferingBrownsFan&quot; recognized as a featured cleveland.com user 
Learn more about &quot;LongSufferingBrownsFan&quot;, cleveland.com&apos;s latest featured user. More Users We Love 
Connect with cleveland.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Map | Advertise | Contact us Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Interact | Living | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Classifieds | Shopping | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Blogs Forums Travel Music 
 
 Post a Job Post a free classified ad Sell your car Sell/Rent your Home Apartments&amp;Rentals Claim your Business
    Listing for Free 
 
 Friday! Magazine High School Sports Arts Taste Going Out Guides Style 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Subscribe to Email Newsletters cleveland.com Twitter feed cleveland.com on Facebook cleveland.com mobile site 
 Special home delivery offers! The Plain Dealer 
 Sun News Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 Cleveland Live LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of Cleveland Live LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
