<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007257" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Name_a_reason_someone_might_prefer_eating_at_a_fast_food_resturant" time="2012-07-13-00:13" support="1" score="0.009542898115111071" bingtitle="Name a reason someone might prefer eating at a fast food resturant" webtitle="Name a reason someone might prefer eating at a fast food resturantName a reason someone might prefer eating at a fast food resturant">
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="121"/>
	<description>Name a reason someine might prefer eating at a fast food restaurant? People think it&apos;s quick, cheap, ready-to-go meal. They simply walk in, pay, and lunch is done.</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Technology &gt; Inventions &gt; Name a reason someone might prefer eating at a fast food resturant? 
Name a reason someone might prefer eating at a fast food resturant?
 In: Inventions , Food&amp;Cooking [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: 1. reason is maybe you dont have food at your house 2. you dont have to cook and 3.resteraunts rule!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

Good food
Fast service
Convenient 

 First answer by Rachelle177 . Last edit by Phydrick . Contributor trust : 0 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 1 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these Inventions questions?
 
 When was the first computer built and what was it called? Answer it! Who invented the timpani and when? Answer it! What did we benefit from Albert Einstein? Answer it! Who invented and patented the phonograph? Answer it! Who invented octal and when and how? Answer it! 
 
Related ads:
 

 
Shopping for Inventions deals?

Find Coupons and Promo Codes on Coupons by Answers.com

 Ann Taylor Coupons Adagio Teas Coupons Angel Food Ministries Coupons Adobe - DE Coupons 
 FIND MORE COUPONS AND PROMO CODES Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 Does NH3 have resonance structure? In: Waves Vibrations and Oscillations Answer it! What is the value of a sterling silver stamp holder necklace? In: Gold and Precious Metals Answer it! How many glasses of wine do you have to have to get pulled over? In: Wine and Champagne Answer it! What is the nautical miles from key west to Grand Cayman? In: Sea Miles Answer it! » more 
Featured guides
 
 How To Grill With Cedar Planks 101 Diabetic Recipe Ideas How To Rent A Bucket Truck Best Wireless Internet Providers Email Marketing 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
