<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007564" url="http://networkingstar.com/tips-2/selling-great-expectations/" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.000811936936528629" bingtitle="Selling Great Expectations | Networking Star - A Place for ..." webtitle="Selling Great Expectations | Networking Star - A Place for Entrepreneurs to Connect, Share, and Learn">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>Order Status; Contact Us ... exactly what to expect and then make that expectation sound like the greatest thing in the world. No one goes to a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		About Ask Networking Star Categories Contact Us FAQ Giveaways 
 Vemma Promo 
 Registration Terms and Conditions 
 
 Jeffery Boyle Login MarketPlace Networking Star Season 2–Join Us Privacy Policy Products Register Reviews Star Voice Application Star Voices Suggest a Company Take the Survey Terms and Conditions Update Company Info User Stories WishList Member 
 
 
 
&quot;Passionate About Entrepreneurs&quot; 
 Home Entrepreneurs 
 Reviews 
 MLM 
 Rankings&amp;Reviews 
 Star Mentors 
 Jeffery Boyle Heather Eastman Jen Howard 
 Training 
 Business Fitness 
 Blog Companies MarketPlace 
 Products Shopping Cart Order Status 
 Episodes 
 Home Entrepreneurs     Reviews MLM     Rankings&amp;Reviews Star Mentors     Jeffery Boyle     Heather Eastman     Jen Howard Training     Business     Fitness Blog Companies MarketPlace     Products     Shopping Cart     Order Status Episodes 
 » Networking Star–You CAN Do More » Self-Reliance is Key to Success » ViSalus: Bravo Growth Award » XANGO RECEIVES DIRECT SELLING ASSOCIATION 2012 ETHOS AWARD » The Future of Income Protection is Direct Selling » Simply Said is Award Finalist » Ernst&amp;Young announces DePaul Industries’President&amp;CEO Dave Shaffer is the Entrepreneur Of The Year® 2012 Award winner in the Pacific Northwest Region » 6 Entrepreneurs Who Turned Service Into A Career » The search for“Entrepreneur of the Year” » Uni Core Holdings Announces the Opening of Two Additional Direct Sales Stores by Prosperous Agriculture 
 You Are Here: Home » Tips » Selling Great Expectations Posted by: Networking Star Posted date: September 01, 2011 In: Tips | comment : 0 Selling Great Expectations 
Post Rating:
 


 I hear it from people all the time. You can hear the frustration and the sadness in their voice. Business owners constantly complain that they bend over backwards for their clients, yet it is never good enough. Why? Is it the business owners fault? Or, do clients just have unrealistic expectations?

The real issue is that business owners set themselves up for failure by giving the client unrealistic expectations during the sales process. Most businesses misunderstand the sales process. They are so focused on the sale that they fail to realize that this process will set the foundation and the expectation for the whole relationship. There are a few different ways that businesses set themselves up for failure during the sales process. However, they all come down to one thing. They fail to set proper expectations and to take control as the leader of the relationship. As a business owner or leader try to keep in mind that no one can work very well while bending over backwards. That means if you are having to bend over backwards, you will not be able to produce your best work.

You will never be able to live up to your clients expectations if you let them set the expectations. Use the sales process to tell the client what they should expect. This may seem counterintuitive because we have been taught to believe that providing great customer service is providing the client whatever they want.  The problem is that this is not realistic. Ultimately customers want the world for free and if you don’t set clear expectations they won’t be happy until they get the world (for free).

Many frustrated business owners feel like their clients don’t respect the fact that the moon was pulled down and handed to them.  What the business owners don’t realize is that without setting clear expectations the customer is expecting the whole universe.

The funny thing is that clients and customers really will be happy with much less than even the moon as long as we are honest and upfront about what we can and will provide. For example don’t just tell clients that you will build them the best widget ever. If you stay that vague they will expect a Robot that transforms into a spaceship and runs on oxygen. In other words being vague lets them image whatever they want and that imaginative (and impossible) image of excellence becomes their reality. However, if you set the expectation upfront that you will provide the best widget ever that does a, b, and c, and then go out and create an awesome a, b, and c widget your client will get exactly what they expected and will be thrilled.

The best way to insure happy clients and customers is not to sell them whatever makes them happy, but instead to tell them that what you provide is exactly what they are looking for. Some of the most successful companies in the world have people happily line up for mediocre products. How? They tell customers exactly what to expect and then make that expectation sound like the greatest thing in the world. No one goes to a fast-food restaurant expecting a fine dining experience, yet 9 out of 10 ten customers walk away happy because they got exactly what they expected. Yet, you go to a fine dining restaurant and their percentage of unhappy customers skyrockets. The difference is that the fine dining establishment promised the best quality available, but left quality up to interpretation, whereas, the fast-food restaurant simply promises fast food, and they hit the mark almost every time.

I am not suggesting that every business join the fast food model, but the fact of the matter is that we can’t expect our customers to be happy if we don’t tell them what happy is.
 Tweet ‹ Previous Next › 
About The Author
 
 Networking Star 




 Number of Entries :
827 
Related posts
 
 
 The New Animated Gif 
 
 Video Tip: The Series 
 
 Five Keys in Having an“Economy Proof”Career 
 
 Lighting A Headshot 
 
 
Leave a Comment

You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
Latest Networking Star Episode
 Subscribers Followers 1569 Fans Subscribe 
 Popular Recent Comments Tags 
 
 
 XanGo 
 June 15, 2012 
 Avon Products, Inc. 
 May 15, 2012 
 Morinda Bioactives 
 April 15, 2012 
 Arbonne International 
 March 15, 2012 
 Isagenix International 
 February 15, 2012 
 
 
 SBA Administrator Mills to Tour Local Small Business-Manufacturer 
 July 12, 2012 
 ThriveHive Closes $1.5M in Seed Funding to Transform Local Small Business Marketing 
 July 12, 2012 
 Valpak Signs Seven New Franchise Agreements 
 July 12, 2012 
 John Hancock’s Advanced Markets Unit Offers Producers New Online Tools To Meet Needs of High Net Worth Clients, Small Business Owners 
 July 11, 2012 
 Michigan Pre-Seed Capital Fund Invests $600,000 in Three Start-Ups 
 July 11, 2012 
 
 
 Mary Pougnet:
Heshie and Werner are two of my favorite people! I&apos;m thrilled both to ... 
 
 dmrizzi:
Park Lane Jewelry is high quality, high fashion jewelry. It is made w ... 
 
 Toon Boom Animation:
Hey Thanks for posting the info about our Flip Boom apps. If you like ... 
 
 Toon Boom Animation:
Hey Thanks for posting the info about our Flip Boom Doodle. If you lik ... 
 
 kakusanUSA:
Hi, Cathy I am Eddie Takahashi who have been contacting for Lacy at N ... 
 
 Books business business-owners CA Commitment to Business Growth corporate DC direct-sales economy entrepreneurial entrepreneur leadership entrepreneurs entrepreneurship events financial FL franchise funding GA health Insurance Corner intelligent entrepreneur jobs marketing mlm mobile technology money network-marketing networking networking star NY online opportunity sales small-business social networks solutions success taxes tech technology TX UT women your-business 
Facebook
 
Twitter
 ©2011 Networking Star. Networking Star is SM of Boyle Network   
 Networking Star–You CAN Do More   
 
 Networking Star–A Body In Motion   
 
 NetworkingStar.tv–2011 MLM Startup Conference   
 
 twitter facebook youtube feedburner Vimeo
	</body>
</document>
