<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007649" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/46702774/F-B-Service" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="7" score="0.021306687527807813" bingtitle="F&amp;B Service - Scribd" webtitle="FB Service">
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000073" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000092" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000093" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>Tray service. In the tray service the food and ... The service of food and beverages in a fast food restaurant is at ... public bar, and the other is the service or dispense ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 You are seeing our new document Reader view. Click here to revert. Feel free to leave us feedback on this feature here . × Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Short Notes on Basics of F&amp;B Service Aboyer Aboyer aids the communication between the kitchen and restaurant. He receives the food order from the service staff and announces the order to the kitchen. Aboyer is responsible for hot plate section of the pantry. A la carte Menu A la carte menu is a type of menu, where the food items are priced individually. Literary meaning of a la carte is ³from the card´ American service It is a type of table service. In American menu the food is pre-plated and portioned at the kitchen. This type of service is relatively less formal and seen in coffee shops. ABC ABC stands for Ashtray, Budvase and Cruet. ABC is kept at the centre of the table while laying the cover. Back of the House Back of the house is the ancillary area of the restaurant, where all the supporting service is carried out. Some of the back of the house sections are pantry, dishwashing, hot plate, still room etc. Bain Marie Bain Marie is equipment that holds the Food hot. The equipment contains cylindrical drum, which is heated with water. Bain Marie is usually used in Hot Plate section of the pantry. Barker Barker is another term for Aboyer. Barker is the person who communicates between service and kitchen and help to pick up the food in time. Usually the order taken by the waiter is hander over to the Barker. Bone China It is a white translucent ceramic material made from kaolin, china clay and bone ash. It is used in restaurant to serve various dishes. Briefing   Briefing is done prior to the opening of the restaurant. In the briefing the senior most staff gives instructions to the junior staff with regard to availability of dishes, special items of the day, and also some training. Buffets Buffet is a type of assisted service, where food and beverage is displayed at counters. Waiter assists at the counters to take the food from the counters or the guest help themselves. Bus Boy Bus boy is a person who helps the waiter. The main responsibility of a bus boy is to bring the food from the kitchen and also do the clearance of plates from the table. Carousel Carousel is a circular counter that revolves to display the food items. The carousel is fitted in such a way that the one side is always inside the kitchen and other side is in the service area. As the carousel revolves the counter is filled up from the kitchen and guests selects the food as it revolves. Carte du jour Carte du jour means ³card of the day´. It is used to highlight the special dishes of the day. carte du jour is actually an supporting menu to the main menu. Chafing dish It is a hollowware used to keep the food warm usually in buffet service. Chafing dish has a water container, which is the base, food container and place for fuel. Using the fuel the water is heated up and in turn the food is heated up with the hot water. Cover Cover is the space on the table allotted for table-wares to the guest to consume his/her meal. The size of the cover is 24 inch * 18 inch. Cutlery Cutlery is the term denotes all the cutting implements such as knives. Cutlery can be made of EPNS or stainless steel. Demi-tasse Demi-t asse means ha lf cup. I t is used to serve coffee except br eakfa st. Size of demi -tasse is 75 ml. Dummy waiter/ Demi waiter   Dummy waiter is another term for side board. it is a restaurant furniture and used to keep all the serving equipments for a meal session. E levenses Elevenses is a meal served at 11 o¶ clock. It includes the food items as biscuits, cake etc. and usually offered to children. Gueridon trolley It is a mobile trolley from which the gueridon service is done. Hostess Hostess is a member of restaurant brigade. Duty of hostess includes taking restaurant reservation and receiving them at t he door. Indian breakfast It is a type of breakfast, which includes Indian dishes such as dosha, idly, chapathi etc. served with chutney and vegetable curries. There are two types of Indian breakfasts viz. North Indian and South I ndian. Lounge service It is a type of specialized service. Lounge service is done at the lounge of a hotel. Items such as morning tea, after noon tea, and alcoholic beverages are ser ved in the lounge. Maitre d¶hotel Maitre d¶hotel is the Supervisor of the a F&amp;B outlet. He looks after the day to day operations of a food service outlet. Menu Menu is a list of food and/or beverage than can be served to a guest at a price. It helps guests to select what they would like to eat and/ or drink. It is a document that controls and directs an outlet¶s operation and is considered the pri me selling instrument Mise-en-scene It means prepare the environment of the outlet before service. Mise-en-scene includes preparing the restaurant welcoming, create ambience with regard to cleanliness, furniture setting and temperature. Mise-en-place Mise-en-place means ³putting in place´ and the term denotes to the preparation of a work place for ultimate smooth service. To ensure that the restaurant is ready for service the waiter makes sure that this station has been efficiently pr epared for service. page 1 of 11 of 00 
More From This User
 22 p. Bell Boy Functions khalkho_k74 1056 Reads 3 p. French khalkho_k74 84 Reads 11 p. F&amp;B Service khalkho_k74 478 Reads 
Related
 7 p. Table Service nickjano 1495 Reads 48 p. TYPES OF SERVICE khushi1422 7592 Reads 48 p. TYPES OF FOOD&amp;BEVERAGE SERVICE OPERATIONS khushi1422 7592 Reads 48 p. 1st Sem Notes khushi1422 7592 Reads 10 p. bleeh 엘크릿 133 Reads 45 p. Local knowledge Shakila Dahanayake 3061 Reads 45 p. Food and Beverage Manager Shakila Dahanayake 3061 Reads 45 p. F&amp;B Notes Shakila Dahanayake 3061 Reads 88 p. Motels rleorobert 4640 Reads 88 p. Commercial Catering rleorobert 4640 Reads 88 p. Unit- I (1) rleorobert 4640 Reads 286 p. FOOD AND BEVERAGE SERVICE jammy_u 842 Reads 179 p. 63711540 Bsc Beverage Juner Lim 58 Reads 179 p. Food and Beverage margauxe 80 Reads 179 p. 2bsc Beverage ponebike 68 Reads 179 p. null engradedotcom 44 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Ruby Ann David 119 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Bharat Uniyal 52 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Sanjay Jamwal 63 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Juner Lim 53 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage mtutabia 46 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Shelly Ann Labbay 65 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Saurabh Dass 60 Reads 179 p. Bsc Beverage Marga Ripoll 65 Reads 179 p. Food n Beverage HRassignment 107 Reads 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
F&amp;B Service
 Download or Print This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
