<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007566" url="http://www.nojazzfest.com/chat/showthread.php?t=9898" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.000377959642421188" bingtitle="RIP William Hemmerling... a great artist,.. a better man... - New ..." webtitle="RIP William Hemmerling... a great artist,.. a better man... - New Orleans JazzHeritage Festival">
			<query id="001472" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>RIP William Hemmerling... a great artist,.. a better ... anywho,.. come the end of one day at fest,.. we ... owned a credit card, never even ate at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		New Orleans Jazz&amp;Heritage Festival &gt; Main Category &gt; Jazz Fest Forum RIP William Hemmerling... a great artist,.. a better man... 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register FAQ Members List Calendar Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 

   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
  # 1   06-17-2009 
 PaulC Senior Member   Join Date: Nov 2006 Location: sunshine state,.. but enjoy clouds... Posts: 3,026 
 RIP William Hemmerling... a great artist,.. a better man... check out the video in the link.... i know that cafe du monde is a religion to some,.. but bill took it to a whole different level....

 http://www.wwltv.com/topstories/stor....879a706a.html 
 
 PaulC View Public Profile Find all posts by PaulC 
 
  # 2   06-17-2009 
 Moon Senior Member   Join Date: Oct 2006 Location: Atlanta, Ga. Posts: 1,992 
 I wonder how long it will take the for the prices to skyrocket? 
 
 Moon View Public Profile Find all posts by Moon 
 
  # 3   06-17-2009 
 PaulC Senior Member   Join Date: Nov 2006 Location: sunshine state,.. but enjoy clouds... Posts: 3,026 
 posted this on another thread,.. thought i would bring it on over here....

--------------------------------------

the world has lost a very genuine, nice man,.. and one very cool artist....

rip mr. hemmerling....




back in 03,.. think it was 03 (i think i recall it as the year the new mastersounds played the front porch of the white house across from liuzza&apos;s ??),.. some friends of ours were enamored w/ an art piece that mr. hemmerling had for sale,.. as were so many people that year... his stuff sold quick,.. and it was priced to sell that year.... we had already hit our art limit when he hit his booth,.. went well beyond it actually,.. so we sadly failed to buy a piece of his....

anywho,.. come the end of one day at fest,.. we saw our good friend walkin&apos; towards the exist w/ that piece of hemmerling&apos;s,.. one that we had both considered purchasin&apos;.... he told me that his wife,.. who so very much wanted that piece,..was unaware that he had purchased it for her...,..

as we were scheduled to meet up w/ them at liuzza&apos;s that evenin&apos;,.. i asked him if i could walk up holdin&apos; the piece... he instantly agreed,.. and like a dummy i carried it the whole way.... as we got closer to the meet up my far better half and i slowed down some to allow him to get there a few minutes before us... those were the days of the dollar beer store so all was well......

so here we come wanderin&apos; down the street,.. we meet up at the corner across from luizza&apos;s by the white house,.. get our hugs in,.. and all the while his wife is eyein&apos; the piece w/ the most astonished look... i give her a big hug and tell her,..&quot;check out what we bought&quot;.... her jaw dropped so low,.. and her husband played it perfectly.... i was goin&apos; to play it out a bit longer but she was gettin&apos; near tears,.. so we let her in on the joke...

she near pissed herself she was so happy....

i will never forget how thrilled people were enjoyin the work that mr. hemmerling had in his booth....
---------------------------------

and i will never forget how inexpensive his work was the 1st year he had a booth at fest.... stood there like a dummy for at least half an hour wantin&apos; so many pieces i couldn&apos;t decide on one... as mentioned,.. we had extended ourselves that year,.. but man,.. still can&apos;t believe i didn&apos;t buy a piece of his that year... the followin&apos; year i couldn&apos;t buy because i was so mad at myself for not buyin&apos; when they were so much lower the year before...

it was so obvious that his work was destined to go much higher,.. and still somehow we didn&apos;t buy,.. even though we both loved his work... some times you jus&apos; can&apos;t fix stupid... at least i had his poster framed far better than any other we own.... Last edited by PaulC : 06-17-2009 at 01:10 PM .
 Reason: referred to a good friend as a good fiend... had to fix that... 
 
 PaulC View Public Profile Find all posts by PaulC 
 
  # 4   06-17-2009 
 Blitzzzzz Senior Member   Join Date: Oct 2006 Location: Ann Arbor Michigan Posts: 2,372 
 A sad day to be sure, though I&apos;m not quite as big a fan as some.
I thought his pieces were a bit on the pricey side, especially when compared with Bruce Brice and Richard Thomas, but I guess that&apos;s what makes horse racing! 
 
 Blitzzzzz View Public Profile Visit Blitzzzzz&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by Blitzzzzz 
 
  # 5   06-17-2009 
 swag Moderator   Join Date: Oct 2006 Location: Dallas, TX, USA Posts: 8,580 
 Chris Rose column on Hemmerling:

 Louisiana folk artist Bill Hemmerling dies at home in Ponchatoula
by Chris Rose, Columnist, The Times-Picayune 

In 2002, Bill Hemmerling, a retired window dresser for Sears&amp;Roebuck, was living the life of a reclusive pauper in a back-a-town shack in the sticks of Tangipahoa Parish.

As recalled by Carol Siekkinen, who would soon become his closest friend and agent, Hemmerling walked into the Louisiana Furniture and Art Gallery in Ponchatoula one day out of desperation and announced:&quot;You know, I did the decorations at Sears and I think you need more color on your walls.&quot;

Show us what you&apos;ve got, the gallery proprietors said, and Hemmerling went on to produce a series of rudimentary yet captivating portraits of rural African American rituals and religion, using discarded house paint on pieces of wood he found during his walks around town.

It was the beginning of a brief, prolific and meteoric art career that saw Hemmerling&apos;s work travel a course from a small town gallery to a fixture at Jazz Fest to Art Expo New York to hanging alongside paintings by Salvador Dali and Fernando Botero just two weeks ago in an exposition in the Dominican Republic.

Hemmerling died Tuesday morning in Ponchatoula after a long bout with colon cancer. He was 66 and left no immediate family behind.

Producing paintings at a rate of one a day, sometimes faster, he left behind a massive body of work and a legion of fans and collectors who could be called nothing less than devout.

&quot;It&apos;s almost like a fairy tale story; where he came from and where he got to,&quot;Siekkinen said Tuesday.&quot;The spirituality that people got from his paintings and got from him had the power to change lives.&quot;

Indeed, dozens of comments attesting to this point flowed onto Hemmerling&apos;s website from well-wishers around the world in his final weeks.&quot;How fortunate I have been to sit and talk with you and listen as you talk to others,&quot;wrote Connie Burns.&quot;Something about your words, thoughts, art and the words on your paintings is so soothing, so nurturing and mindful of the pace we should all follow in life.&quot;

And what a life. It was as curious as his artwork.

Born in Chicago, he relocated to his mother&apos;s hometown of Ponchatoula as a young man and began life as a journeyman decorator for Sears, traveling from store to store across Louisiana and Mississippi. Though the job required an artistic temperament, Hemmerling had never painted a picture until after he retired and went looking for a way to make a living.

Naive and innocent are the terms most friends and collectors hung on his work, but it fit his lifestyle as well. For instance, it turns out Hemmerling wasn&apos;t really broke when he walked into the Ponchatoula gallery in 2002. The fact was, he had a retirement account built up from three decades at Sears but his ignorance of how to use a PIN number and a touch-tone phone left the account unaccessed for years, Siekkinen said.

&quot;He had never used a computer, never owned a credit card, never even ate at a fast food restaurant until recently,&quot;she said.&quot;It&apos;s hard to imagine that he worked at Sears all those years and still managed to stay so sheltered from the world. Anyone who knew him would say he was very childlike - possessing the innocence of a child.&quot;

Such an innocent&apos;s view of the world is also what informed his painting style and made for its appeal. Landscapes and colors are flat, people are faceless, clothing is antiquated and actions are simple. Over and over he painted a young black woman he called&quot;Sweet Olive,&quot;who would become his signature subject in the way that the Blue Dog defines fellow Louisiana artist George Rodrigue. But there was no rivalry between the two Southern folk art titans. Rodrigue, in fact, was a huge fan of Hemmerling.

&quot;Hemmerling is a pure artist,&quot;Rodrigue raved in 2005, upon the debut of Hemmerling&apos;s official Jazz Fest poster that year, featuring jazz pioneer Buddy Bolden.&quot;He paints from his heart, from his soul, he really paints what he feels....He has no boundaries. I think he&apos;s a free spirit. He&apos;s real sincere about himself. And the paintings are honest and straightforward. It&apos;s beautiful art.&quot;

Through it all, Hemmerling remained quiet, simple, centered. Even as his paintings soared in value - they began at $75 in 2002 and currently reach up to $20,000 now - he continued to use recycled house paint and found objects as his predominant media. His few acknowledgements of fortune were a beloved Cadillac and a move out of his old shack in Pontchatoula into a warehouse/studio complex next to the Louisiana Furniture&amp;Art Gallery.

As for his fascination with Southern African American culture - Hemmerling was white - it appears to have blossomed from a life in the country, simply watching the people around him.

&quot;He just painted what he saw in life,&quot;Siekinnen said.&quot;He painted what was in his heart. He thought African American women were beautiful. And he thought his paintings were a way to bridge the gap between the races.&quot;

Whatever they were, they sold furiously. Business at the gallery in Ponchatoula was always brisk and Hemmerling opened a second gallery in New Orleans last year, on Magazine Street, but he rarely made it across the lake to visit. It&apos;s impossible to tell where his career would have gone from there had the cancer not taken him down hard in recent months.

His final show was last month at the Palacio de Bellas Artes in Santo Domingo in the Dominican Republic. High rollers from the international art world swarmed the premises buying works by renown greats. Unable to attend, Hemmerling savored the dispatches.

&quot;It wasn&apos;t until his last weeks that he felt he made it,&quot;Siekkinen said.&quot;He hung with the Big Guys in Santo Domingo. He hung with Dali and Botero. They were men of great fame. This was something special for a man who never considered himself an&quot;artist&quot;but, simply, a painter.&quot;

A visitation for Hemmerling will be held Thursday from 5 to 9 p.m. at his gallery at 3932 Magazine St. A funeral Mass will be held Friday morning at 10, at Our Lady of Guadeloupe Church, 411 Rampart St. A jazz funeral procession will follow, from the church to Cafe du Monde, where, many years ago, Hemmerling - formerly a lapsed Catholic - often claimed to have undergone a spiritual awakening while drinking coffee next to a man he said looked like Jesus. __________________
sig test 
 
 swag View Public Profile Visit swag&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by swag 
 
  # 6   06-17-2009 
 swag Moderator   Join Date: Oct 2006 Location: Dallas, TX, USA Posts: 8,580 
 Artist website:
 http://www.hemmerlingart.com/original-art/ __________________
sig test 
 
 swag View Public Profile Visit swag&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by swag 
 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 

 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts vB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Main Category   Jazz Fest Forum   Everything You Ever Wanted to Know about Jazz Fest   Jazz Fest Moments   General Music Discussion 
 


 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 05:32 PM . 
 
 Contact Us - New Orleans Jazz&amp;Heritage Festival presented by Shell. - Archive - Top 

 (c) New Orleans Jazz&amp;Heritage Festival&amp;Foundation
	</body>
</document>
