<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007769" url="http://www.steadyhealth.com/Happy_people_can_make_you_happy_t198277.html" time="2012-07-13-00:43" support="4" score="0.004294495853426308" bingtitle="Happy people can make you happy · Small Talk discussions ..." webtitle="Happy people can make you happy · Small Talk discussions | General center | SteadyHealth.com">
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>My wife and me were in a local fast food restaurant we went to ... ordered with the meal hopped off the server&apos;s tray ... They make servers pay for broken glasses, dishes ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in or Register Now 
 Info Center Articles Discussions Videos Games&amp;Apps 
 
 All Discussions Articles Videos 
 
   Well Being 
 Nutrition&amp;Dieting Weight Loss Healthy Living Physical activities 
 Workout&amp;Exercises Office Exercises 
 Beauty Care 
 Plastic, Cosmetic and Reconstructive Surgery 
 
 Health Conditions 
 Cardiovascular Disorders and Diseases Ear, Nose, Throat, and Dental problems Gastrointestinal Disorders Urinary Tract Issues Respiratory tract disorders and diseases Musculoskeletal Issues Lymphatic&amp;Endocrine system Nervous System Disorders and Diseases Eye Disorders and Diseases Autoimmune diseases Cancer Injures, Fractures and Burns Skin&amp;Hair problems Allergies 
 Family&apos;s Health 
 Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health Children&amp;Teens Health Pregnancy 
 Pregnancy Exercises 
 Sexual Health 
 Therapies&amp;Treatments 
 Alternative medicine&amp;healing therapies Drugs&amp;Medications 
 Prescription&amp;Over-The-Counter Drugs 
 
 Emotional&amp;Mental Health 
 Addiction&amp;Recovery Mental Disorders Emotional and Stress Management 
 
 
 SteadyHealth Community Home Discussions General Small Talk 
 
Happy people can make you happy
 1 
person has this question
 Me too! Reply Start new topic Subscribe to this topic 
Would you tip your waitress more money just because she&apos;s smiling?

 Yes 
 63% [ 7 ] 
 No 
 9% [ 1 ] 
 I do not leave tips at all. 
 27% [ 3 ] 
 

 Total Votes : 11 
 View Profile pseudonim 
 Posts: 303 Joined: Dec 25, 2004 
 
Awards

 Most Helpful Member for January, 2006 
 
 pseudonim over year ago 
 According to the story Your smile goes farther than you think being happy affected even those people you didn&apos;t know.

 

I wonder if happiness could be contiguous? Reply Log in to leave feedback   54     56 Add to favorites Report abuse s 
 See these topics also: 
 View Profile sheclosedher... 
 Posts: 2 Joined: Oct 5, 2009 
 
 sheclosedhereyes over year ago 
 smiling goes a long way! Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile healthnfitne... 
 Posts: 6333 Joined: May 9, 2009 
 
 healthnfitnessguy over year ago 
 I make it a policy to smile every day and it definitely does help. I found out that it helps release endorphins so I would say it&apos;s worth the time. What do other people think?
_________________
 
 Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse Certificate Info 
First Aid Certificate passed on 2011-08-28 21:27:56

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 10 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 View Profile kingfreze 
 Posts: 973 Joined: Jul 19, 2009 
 
Certificates

 First Aid Certificate since Aug 28, 2011 
 
 kingfreze over year ago 
 Going back to the OP, I&apos;m a part of the &apos;tight git&apos; brigade and never tip 

Yeh its got to be good to smile and even have a good old belly laugh every now and again. You may not think it but just forcing a smile does do a lot to cheer you up if your down. 
_________________
 I&apos;m just sharing my experiences. You should always see a doctor. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile healthnfitne... 
 Posts: 6333 Joined: May 9, 2009 
 
 healthnfitnessguy over year ago 
 kingfreze wrote: 
 
Going back to the OP, I&apos;m a part of the &apos;tight git&apos; brigade and never tip :P

Yeh its got to be good to smile and even have a good old belly laugh every now and again. You may not think it but just forcing a smile does do a lot to cheer you up if your down. :lol: :D :) :P
 

Hey that&apos;s all well and good, but be sure that you don&apos;t do that in the States, mister! People here work solely for tips (I made $2 an hour--all that goes to taxes) so you really should remember that if you visit. ;)
_________________
 
 Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse Certificate Info 
First Aid Certificate passed on 2011-08-28 21:27:56

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 10 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 View Profile kingfreze 
 Posts: 973 Joined: Jul 19, 2009 
 
Certificates

 First Aid Certificate since Aug 28, 2011 
 
 kingfreze over year ago 
 Thats awful healthguy. If that was the case I&apos;d probably feel so bad I&apos;d be rather generous.

Over here its been known for employers to take the tips and subtract that from the waitress&apos; wages to avoid having to pay them the minimum wage. Pretty much signalled the end of me ever leaving tips.
_________________
 I&apos;m just sharing my experiences. You should always see a doctor. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile bluedog 
 Posts: 2343 Joined: Jun 1, 2009 
 
 bluedog over year ago 
 kingfreze wrote: 
 
Thats awful healthguy. If that was the case I&apos;d probably feel so bad I&apos;d be rather generous.

Over here its been known for employers to take the tips and subtract that from the waitress&apos; wages to avoid having to pay them the minimum wage. Pretty much signalled the end of me ever leaving tips.
 

That is really sad to hear that employers do that too though, because it means that waiters don&apos;t feel like they did a good job. I waited tables for a few years and bad tips usually left me feeling like I wasn&apos;t good enough. But then again that&apos;s why I don&apos;t wait tables now. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile TayaTaya 
 Posts: 155 Joined: May 2, 2009 
 
 TayaTaya over year ago 
 I never tip in restaurants and bars ... I am European though ) 

I always tip my hairstylist - about 20% ( I have long hair , so I cut my ends once in a while approx 4 times a year) my husband says I am way too generous.. I read somewhere that women mostly tip hairstylist. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse Certificate Info 
First Aid Certificate passed on 2011-08-28 21:27:56

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 10 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 View Profile kingfreze 
 Posts: 973 Joined: Jul 19, 2009 
 
Certificates

 First Aid Certificate since Aug 28, 2011 
 
 kingfreze over year ago 
 Nope, never tip my barber either. They charge enough as it is without me adding any more on 
_________________
 I&apos;m just sharing my experiences. You should always see a doctor. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse Certificate Info 
Basic Pregnancy Knowledge Certificate passed on 2011-12-20 23:55:02

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 10 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 Certificate Info 
First Aid Certificate passed on 2012-02-27 11:52:42

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 10 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 Certificate Info 
Sexual Health: Truth or Myth passed on 2012-03-01 01:12:37

See detailed info for this Certificate 

To get this certificate you must to pass an exam.

Before you be able to start exam you need to have this conditions:

 5 days from registration 3 posts 3 bonus posts 

You are able to start exam 
 View Profile taz1890 
 Posts: 987 Joined: Nov 17, 2008 
 
Certificates

 Basic Pregnancy Knowledge Certificate since Dec 20, 2011 First Aid Certificate since Feb 27, 2012 Sexual Health: Truth or Myth since Mar 1, 2012 
 
 taz1890 over year ago 
 I actually teach a class occasionally about customer service. The best thing about a smile...it&apos;s universal. It needs no translation! Smiles lower anxiety ...let people take their guard down...
_________________
 ~ Taz 

Feel free to message me if there is something you&apos;re more comfortable discussing privately - just click the avatar picture next to my name then click &apos;send message&apos;! Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile njoynlife 
 Posts: 2853 Joined: Jul 27, 2009 
 
Awards

 Most Helpful Member for September, 2011 
 
 njoynlife over year ago 
 I always try to be cheerful when dealing with service people. It&apos;s worth a million to see them smile. Particularly if I&apos;m behind some bast**d who just gave them a real ration of s**t.

My wife and me were in a local fast food restaurant we went to often one time when the 16 oz. glass of milk I ordered with the meal hopped off the server&apos;s tray into my wife&apos;s lap. The poor girl was mortified. We began laughing because it just seemed really funny and we tried to calm her but she was still pretty upset. They gave us the meal for free but I left a tip that was more than the price of the meal in case they made her pay for the free meal. Many restaurants are pretty cheap that way. They make servers pay for broken glasses, dishes etc. and for the bill on a customer who skips without paying.

My years of attending bar at the local watering hole gave me some insights too. Insurance salesmen are the cheapest of the bunch. They sit at a table with a community tab. Then when it&apos;s time to pay they argue over who owes what for 15 minutes and they each leave exactly the portion they think they owe. They leave it on the table and get up and leave. It&apos;s usually short a drink or two and never includes the tax. Of course there is nothing left over for a tip.

The ladies bowling league is fun to watch while they take a similar amount of time to figure out who owes what, but they usually leave the correct amount but not much of tip.

At the bar, the ones who stiff the bar tender are usually driving a Cadillac or some other luxury liner. Also people who drive VWs almost never leave a tip, except for the&quot;Hippies&quot;with a VW bus.

I sat next to the judge who was sitting on a murder trial at the court house, one night. I didn&apos;t know who he was at the time and he was so obnoxious that I left after one drink. I left the money for my drink on the bar along with a tip as the bartender was out back at the time and I didn&apos;t want to wait for him to get back. The next night the bar tender hit me with&quot;you stiffed me last night&quot;. I told him what happened and he knew right away I wasn&apos;t lying. He was familiar with the judge and he told me the judge took it. He has to watch him real close because he steals tips off the bar whenever he gets the chance.

I always leave a good tip because I&apos;ve seen how they get treated by many customers, and the IRS.
Most wait staff get paid far less than minimum wage because the IRS allows it. To add insult to injury some years ago the IRS went on a campaign to maximize their tax collections. They made the employers add the value of a meal to the assumed wages because they assumed the waiter/ess got to eat a free meal while working. They also had a formula to figure the tips that had to be added to the pay for tax computation.

During that same persecution campaign they mandated that all types of employee benefits for all employees be added to wages for tax computation. My racing partner was the parts manager at a garage where he took the parts delivery truck home until the IRS said they had to add the use of the truck to his wages. That edict basically did away with the traditional vehicle use by all people at garages, including salesmen. At the TV shop where I was working many of us took a vehicle home because there was no place to park them at the store&apos;s location. The owner basically said F.U. to that IRS edict and we continued to take them home.

To show how F&apos;ing cheap the IRS was, I was a director at the drag strip at that time. We generally figured it was our job as corporate directors to be present at some of the races to see how things were going. We usually helped out around the place where ever it appeared needed. For larger events we hired many extra people to man the gates. If an inexperienced ticket seller was getting grief from someone who thought he should be getting free admission or something, they usually appreciated having someone in back of them with the authority to settle the dispute. We also watched things like lines at concession stands to see what was holding them up if they were getting too long so we could discuss those things at the next board meeting.

The IRS decreed that the company was to keep a record of which directors came to a race and add the value of the ticket to the money we got paid for being directors --- so they could tax it. The work around for that one came from a disk jockey at the radio station where we did a lot of advertising. We gave them free tickets to use as promotions for every race. The directors tickets were subtracted from those. Since they were free to begin with, there WAS no value.
_________________
 
 
 Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile commando12 
 Posts: 9 Joined: Apr 29, 2010 
 
 commando12 over year ago 
 smile is contagious ..someone has said an apple a day keeps the doctor away..someone added to it ..a smile a day keeps the apple away.. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse View Profile aliCOOPER 
 Posts: 43 Joined: Apr 8, 2010 
 
 aliCOOPER over year ago 
 smile has unforseen benefits to physical and mental health . this is also clinically proven to help you fight illness. Reply Log in to leave feedback   0     0 Link to this post Report abuse Reply Start new topic Subscribe to this topic 
Related content 

 Similar Discussions Related Articles Recommended Facts Recommended Videos 
 
 Your smile goes farther than you think My BF quit smoking pot and lost his sex drive finding it hard to cope after an abortion can you get pregnant if you use a condom and the guys doesn&apos; Study shows that older people are happier than young people total vs parcial knee replacement 
 
Featured

 The Gift of a Happy Parent 

Oct 26, 2011

&quot;My earliest
memories of my father are of seeing him work at his desk and realizing that he
was happy. I did not know it then, but that was one of the most precious gifts
a father can give his...
 
 Why Is Facebook Making You Unhappy? Smile When You Eat Your Veggies – For Your Kid&apos;s Sake 
 
 Global breast cancer crisis Happiness takes work: 5 choices to create happiness Easy relaxation techniques for busy people Health benefits of happiness Ringworm - Important precautions! 
 
 Advertisement 
Find health and lifestyle advices&amp;Get answers!

Share real-life experiences with more than 200,000 community members!
 Join SteadyHealth! 
or Log in if you’re already registered!
 
Poll 
 
Which form of birth control do you and your partner use?
 Male condom
 Female condom
 Spermicide
 Diaphragm (cervical cap)
 Contraceptive implant (implanon)
 Combined pill/mini pill
 IUD
 Vasectomy
 Contraceptive injection
 Withdrawal
 None
 
 
 
Permissions

 You can post new topics in this forum You can reply to topics in this forum You cannot edit posts in this forum You cannot delete posts in this forum You cannot vote in polls in this forum 
 Advertisement 
 
Explore real people&apos;s
knowlegde on
 SteadyHealth.com 
Searching for:
   
Wait, You can get More!

Get more similar topics directly in your email inbox!

Type in your email address or register with SteadyHealth in order to receive more similar discussions and articles!
 Your email address: or Sign me up! You can also subscribe to current topic. 
 SteadyHealth Community Home Discussions General Small Talk 
 
Steady Health .com

Disscusion boards licensed
and powered by SteadyHealth.com v4.8.0
 Development supported by LifeForm Inc. 

All Rights Reserved by SteadyHealth.com 
 ©2004 - 2012 

 This site complies with the HONcode standard for trustworthy health information: verify here .

 
Information provided on this site is intended for informational and educational purposes only. It is not meant to substitute for medical advice provided by your physician or other medical professional. If you have or suspect that you have a medical problem, promptly contact your physician or health care provider. Only your physician can provide relevant diagnosis, prescribe medications and/or put you on adequate therapies.
 
Polices&amp;terms

 Privacy Policy Registration terms Global Terms of Use Copyright policy Advertising policy 
 
Site information:

 About us Contact us Advertise with us 


Useful links


 Find a Doctor in your area Find drug information Find specific medical term Read lifestyle articles Read Frequently Asked Questions 
 
Go Social with SteadyHealth.com:

 Please visit SteadyHealth YouTube Channel 
 
 SteadyHealth.com:: Medical Questions&amp;Online Health Community H-Desk.com:: PC Security Matters - PC Tech Community RealCool.biz:: The Most Comprehesive Business Community 

 RunningForums:: The Need To Speed RealPoor.com:: MMORPG Gaming&amp;Trading Center XTourist.com:: Traveling Without Moving
	</body>
</document>
