<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007674" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/t/26/2/Orlando/Vegan-Friendly-restaurants" time="2012-07-13-00:38" support="1" score="0.0021318562213810547" bingtitle="Orlando Vegan Friendly Restaurants | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Orlando Vegan Friendly Restaurants | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="41"/>
	<description>... place however upon finding a hair in my food and ... The former fast food restaurant building has been transformed ... store day at @parkavecds bring your receipt in ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Orlando » Vegan Friendly 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Charleston Jacksonville Los Angeles Miami New York Tampa Bay More... 
 
 Add Restaurant Orlando Vegan Friendly Restaurants 
 
Prices

 $$$$ Fine dining (10) $$$ Higher priced (28) $$ Moderately priced (49) $ Cheap eats (141) 
 
Neighborhoods

 
 Metro Area 

 Altamonte Springs (9) Disney&amp;Lake Buena Vista (12) Kissimmee (6) Lake Mary (11) Longwood (6) Mount Dora (9) Sanford (8) Winter Garden&amp;Ocoee (5) Winter Park (21) 
 Show all 
 Orlando 

 Avalon Park&amp;Waterford Lakes (7) Colonial (10) Downtown (13) I-Drive&amp;Universal (10) Restaurant Row (6) South (11) UCF Area (9) 
 Show all 
 
Cuisines

 American (74) Asian (12) Breakfast&amp;Brunch (23) Burgers (11) Coffee (19) Desserts&amp;Ice Cream (14) Indian (15) Italian (16) Mediterranean (20) Mexican (13) Organic (18) Pizza (15) Sandwiches&amp;Subs (29) Seafood (18) Smoothies (13) Steakhouse (12) Sushi (17) Tacos (17) Tex-Mex (11) Vegetarian (34) 
 Show all 
Features

 BYOB (25) Cash Only (58) Delivery (439) Food Truck (129) Free Wi-Fi (630) Gluten-Free Frie... (249) Happy Hour (544) Kid Friendly (2060) Late Night (914) Live Music (272) Outdoor Dining (953) Private Parties (210) Romantic (293) Sports Bar (205) Vegan Friendly Waterfront (58) 
 
Reservations

 Orlando restaurants that take reservations online through Urbanspoon 
 Where All of Orlando Metro Area DeLand Disney/Lake Buena Vista Longwood Orlando Downtown Ivanhoe Village North When Today Tomorrow Sat Jul 14 Sun Jul 15 Mon Jul 16 Tue Jul 17 Wed Jul 18 Anytime 8:00am 9:00am 10:00am 11:00am 12:00pm 1:00pm 2:00pm 3:00pm 4:00pm 5:00pm 6:00pm 7:00pm 8:00pm 9:00pm 10:00pm 11:00pm Remove: Vegan Friendly Sort: Best
| Alphabetical | Recently added Featured restaurants 
 QQ to Go Chinese Food&amp;... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Davenport - Chinese, Japanese, Sushi Seasons 52 Fresh Grill 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Altamonte Springs - Modern American, Wine Bar International Food Club... 100% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ I-Drive/Universal - International, Mediterranean, Middle Eastern 
 
 1 Lazy Moon Pizza 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ UCF Area - Pizza, Soups, Salads 12269 University Boulevard 2 Black Bean Deli 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Winter Park - Cuban, Latin American, Sandwiches/Subs 325 South Orlando Avenue 3 California Grill 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$$ Disney/Lake Buena Vista - California, Sushi, Modern American 4600 North World Drive 4 Ethos Vegan Kitchen 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Ivanhoe Village - American, Breakfast/Brunch, Vegetarian 1235 North Orange Avenue 5 Mediterranean Blue 95% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Downtown South - Greek, Mediterranean, Vegetarian 435 East Michigan Street 6 Seasons 52 Fresh Grill 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Altamonte Springs - Modern American, Wine Bar 463 East Altamonte Drive 7 Azteca D&apos;Oro 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ South - Mexican, Tacos 12403 South Orange Blossom Trail 8 Johnnie&apos;s Hideaway 81% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$$ Disney/Lake Buena Vista - American, Seafood 12551 South Apopka Vineland Road 9 Sushi Pop 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Oviedo - Japanese, Seafood, Sushi 310 West Mitchell Hammock Road 10 Sea Thai Restaurant 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Colonial - Thai 3812 East Colonial Drive 11 Five Guys Burgers and Fries 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kissimmee - American, Burgers, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1310 W Osceola Pky 12 Orchid Thai Cuisine 85% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Winter Park - Thai 305 N Park Ave 13 Keke&apos;s Breakfast Café 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Millenia - American, Breakfast/Brunch 4192 Conroy Rd 14 Chef&apos;s Table at the... 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Winter Garden/Ocoee - American, Modern American 99 W Plant St 15 Jade Bistro Asian Cuisine&amp;... 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ College Park - Asian, Sushi 2425 Edgewater Dr 16 Taverna Opa 79% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ I-Drive/Universal - Greek, Mediterranean, Middle Eastern 9101 International Drive 17 Dandelion Communitea Café 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Mills 50 - American, Tea, Vegetarian 618 North Thornton Avenue 18 Keke&apos;s Breakfast Café 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Winter Park - American, Breakfast/Brunch 345 West Fairbanks Avenue 19 First Watch 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ UCF Area - American, Breakfast/Brunch, Coffee 3402 Technological Avenue 20 Apps Pizza&amp;Subs 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Saint Cloud - Italian, Pizza 2615 13th St 21 El Patron Mexican Restaurant... 79% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Disney/Lake Buena Vista - Mexican, Tacos 12167 South Apopka Vineland Road Make a reservation 22 Wrap Planet 98% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Winter Park - Sandwiches/Subs, Smoothies, Tacos 127 W Fairbanks Ave 23 Hummus House 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ UCF Area - Greek, Mediterranean, Vegetarian 11565 University Blvd 24 Mediterranean Deli 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ North - Greek, Mediterranean, Sandwiches/Subs 981 W Fairbanks Ave 25 Pine 22 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Downtown - American, Burgers, Organic 22 East Pine Street 26 Lạc Việt Bistro 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Colonial - Vietnamese, Noodle Shop 2021 East Colonial Drive 27 Bikkuri Sushi Noodle and... 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Colonial - Japanese, Sushi, Noodle Shop 1915 East Colonial Drive 28 The Goblin Market Restaurant 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$$ Mount Dora - American, Seafood, Steakhouse 330 Dora Drawdy Way 29 FishBones 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Lake Mary - Seafood, Steakhouse, Sushi 7005 County Road 46A 30 Drunken Monkey Coffee Bar 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Colonial - Coffee, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 444 N Bumby Ave 31 Stardust Video&amp;Coffee 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Audubon Park Garden District - American, Coffee, Sandwiches/Subs, Vegetarian 1842 East Winter Park Road 32 Red Bamboo Thai Restaurant 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ I-Drive/Universal - Asian, Thai 6803 S Kirkman Rd 33 Bikes, Beans&amp;Bordeaux 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Audubon Park Garden District - Coffee, Sandwiches/Subs, Wine Bar 3022 Corrine Dr 34 Anatolia Orlando 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Restaurant Row - Mediterranean, Seafood, Turkish 7600 Doctor Phillips Boulevard 35 Oh Que Bueno Restaurant 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ East - Colombian 1125 South Semoran Boulevard 36 Woodlands 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ South - Chinese, Indian, Vegetarian 6040 South Orange Blossom Trail 37 Mix Frozen Yogurt 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East - Smoothies, Frozen Yogurt 11772 E Colonial Dr 38 That Deli 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Lake Mary - Sandwiches/Subs, Soups, Salads 3801 West Lake Mary Boulevard 39 Thai Thani 85% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Celebration - Thai 600 Market St 40 Azteca D&apos;Oro 82% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Winter Haven - Mexican, Tacos 313 Cypress Gardens Blvd 41 Wok&amp;Roll Chinese... 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ DeLand - Chinese 1580 N Woodland Blvd 42 Moghul Indian Cuisine 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Winter Park - Indian 401 North Semoran Boulevard 43 Garden Café 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Downtown - Asian, Chinese, Vegetarian 810 W Colonial Dr 44 Kumo Japanese Restaurant 95% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Davenport - Japanese, Sushi 207 Ambersweet Way 45 Kabob N Curry 80% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Disney/Lake Buena Vista - Indian, Vegetarian, Buffet 12185 South Apopka Vineland Road 46 Chilangos 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Winter Springs - Mexican, Tacos, Vegetarian 162 East State Road 434 47 Spooky&apos;s Black Cat Café and... 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Colonial - American, Sandwiches/Subs, Tapas 207 North Primrose Drive 48 Hibachi Express 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Casselberry - Japanese, Sushi, Teriyaki 3950 S Us-17-92 #1072 49 Cheeburger Cheeburger 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Avalon Park / Waterford Lakes - American, Burgers 509 N Alafaya Trl 50 Viet Thai Café 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ South - Asian, Thai, Vietnamese 1925 Sand Lake Road 
 « Previous Page
1 Next » 
Critic reviews

Vegan Friendly

 June 2, 2012 Black Bean Deli By Orlando Magazine Think of Black Bean Deli as a food truck without wheels, a remarkably small place with a kitchen, ordering counter... Full review May 20, 2012 The Goblin Market Restaurant By Orlando Sentinel Pork belly is a menu darling these days. As the name implies, the boneless cut comes from the under portion of the... Full review March 31, 2012 Seasons 52 Fresh Grill By Orlando Magazine The wood grill does its job on caramelized sea scallops ($20.95), a half-dozen smoky and sweet scallops served with... Full review 
 
Blogger reviews

Vegan Friendly

 June 12, 2012 FishBones By Central Florida&apos;s Good Eats So, overall, our experience was somewhat uneven, not what I&apos;d expect for a restaurant like this, given the high prices. I&apos;m not sure I&apos;d really go back again. I&apos;ve had better food and... Full review June 7, 2012 Woodlands By Delights and Delectables ...It is a vegetarian Indian restaurant. It was awesome... Full review June 3, 2012 Thai Thani By FoodieCuisine.com One important thing I learned on previous lunches it to order the Pepper Plate .  The pepper plate comes with various peppers, including Thai peppers, and is a must-have if you like spicy... Full review 
 
Diner reviews

Vegan Friendly

 July 11, 2012 Johnnie&apos;s Hideaway Superb eats in tourist central by Steve Lansin ( 5 reviews ) Fantastic homemade pickles&amp;terrific food! July 11, 2012 Lazy Moon Pizza i love lazy moon! by Bianca ( 4 reviews ) every time i crave pizza, this is my number one spot! the pizza, about $4 a slice, is HUGE and delicious. its thin crust and they offer many, fresh, delicious toppings, as well as excellent beer choices. they also have specials during the week. its a laid back environment and they play cool, indie music. the staff is always really nice and the fact that its down the street is awesome. July 10, 2012 Keke&apos;s Breakfast Café Mobile review by Jim Bellow ( 3 reviews ) Absolutely the best service&amp;food. Great atmosphere. It&apos;s a breakfast&amp;lunch restaurant. Usually closes at 2:30. 
 
Restaurant tweets

Vegan Friendly

 about 2 hours ago Dandelion Communitea Café Oh you are all gonna love this - today we have VEGAN CREAMY BROCCOLI SOUP for you! Pair it up with a salad or... t.co/eCohKXql More tweets by dandelioncafe about 5 hours ago Taverna Opa We&apos;ve launched Curbside Pick-Up! E-mail your order in today! t.co/dwiTTFjs More tweets by TavernaOpaOrl about 13 hours ago That Deli Special Sandwiches

The Hen House: Chicken Sausage, Red Onion, Cheddar Cheese and Tarragon Mayo in a Toasted... t.co/Vtte9s4b More tweets by thatdeli 
 
 Add Restaurant Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
