<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007534" url="http://www.menifee247.com/2008/05/countryside-market-place-tenant-update.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:30" support="11" score="0.005474863302431202" bingtitle="Countryside Market Place - Tenant Update ~ Menifee 24/7" webtitle="Countryside Market Place - Tenant Update ~ Menifee 24/7">
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001105" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000979" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001230" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001294" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000352" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="49"/>
	<description>I also hope shoppers not only stay conscious of putting trash in trash receptacles ... wash and 22 parking spaces; Parcel 4 includes a 1,700 square foot fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Home Advertise About Us Contact Us Write For Us Submit News Links Subscribe 
 
 Home Deals Parks Real Estate Events People Restaurants Arts Columns 
 
 Countryside Market Place - Tenant Update 
 by Steve Johnson @ 5/07/2008 04:14:00 PM 
 
 
 Several readers have e-mailed me asking for an update on the list of tenants going into Countryside Marketplace.

First, I want to point out that I actually published a list of tenants about a year ago, here...

 http://www.menifee247.com/2007/06/countryside-marketplace-presentation.htm 

For the record, here&apos;s the list again... Retailers... 

Target
Lowes
Kohls
Best Buy
Linens and Things
Sport Chalet (corrected from Sportmart)
Old Navy
Tilly&apos;s
Lane Bryant
PETCO
Staples
Beverages and More
Payless Shoes
Jewelry Store (yet to be named)

 Food and Drink... 

B.J.&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Brewery
Chipotle or Baja Fresh (not decided yet)
Starbucks
Jamba Juice
Panda Express (or other fast food Chinese)
Japanese Restaurant (yet to be named)
Corner Bakery or Panera Bread (not decided yet)
Red Robin
Chick Fila
TGI Fridays
In-N-Out Burger
Round Table Pizza

 Other Businesses... 

Wells Fargo Bank
Wachovia Bank
Washington Mutual Bank Last week, I contacted Donahue Schriber, the company that owns Countryside Marketplace, and asked them if they can clear up some of the unknowns, as denoted in the parentheses above. Their answer is that they don&apos;t have any answers. They&apos;re still trying to pursue tenants.

They did say that they&apos;re no longer pursuing Corner Bakery or Panera Bread, although they&apos;d welcome either one of those.

As for Linen and Things having filed for bankruptcy a week or two ago, Donahue Schriber doesn&apos;t have any information on this either. It&apos;s up to the bankruptcy court to sort all that out and decide what happens.

So the only update that we have thus far, is that a bread shop won&apos;t be there. 
 Labels: Countryside-Marketplace 
263
Comments:
 «Oldest   ‹Older  1–200 of 263  Newer›   Newest» Holly said... 
It is not going to be done soon enough. Tired of eating at Carnitas.
 May 07, 2008 5:01 PM Anonymous
said... 
So if Target is moving to the new location, what is replacing their old spot? Does anyone know?
 May 07, 2008 8:35 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;ve heard two *rumors* on the old target being replaced by Michael&apos;s or the owner of Trevi&apos;s building a bowling alley there. Both are unconfirmed.
 May 08, 2008 9:14 AM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;ve heard that it will be 24hr fitness. I&apos;m hoping, I&apos;ve got a membership.
 May 08, 2008 10:39 AM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;d like to see Kevin Jewelers and Baja Fresh come in.
 May 08, 2008 10:41 AM Anonymous
said... 
A 24hr fitness would be great!! I love the RANDOM store requests.... Kevins Jeweler&apos;s?
 May 08, 2008 11:15 AM Anonymous
said... 
Target has found a buyer for it&apos;s old building and the building will be sectioned off into more retail stores by the new owner. The fitness club is going in on the northwest corner of Newport and Haun Roads presumably west of the gas station and north of Newport.
 May 08, 2008 1:20 PM Anonymous
said... 
A bowling alley would be great. Then we would need a nice movie theater. An aquatic center would be icing on the cake.
 May 08, 2008 2:59 PM Anonymous
said... 
The Aquatic Center is going in at the corner of Newport and Haun Roads on the south side of Newport and west of Haun...basically across the street from the Countryside Marketplace.
 May 08, 2008 8:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Wow! An aquatic center? What size will it be? When will that open? That would be great! Maybe MESA Aquatics could start having practices up here. I know that with the coming summer heat that getting some time in a pool would be great for the kids of Menifee.
 May 09, 2008 6:40 PM Scott Mann said... 
Click on The Californian link below for an article in 2006 about the &apos;Menifee Regional Aquatics Center&apos;. The original vision was for a targeted completion in Summer &apos;08. I believe that timeline has slipped slightly. I&apos;ll work to get an update for you unless someone else knows the answer and can post the current information on the aquatics center. Its definitely happening!
 May 10, 2008 7:14 AM Anonymous
said... 
I would like to know when their are having a jobfair so we all can aply.
 May 12, 2008 3:57 PM Anonymous
said... 
anyone know when/how i can apply for a associate position at the new target store?
 May 13, 2008 4:29 PM Scott Mann - Candidate for Menifee City Council said... 
The new Super Target and jobs...!

I spoke with the Regional HR folks for Target and they are not yet staffing the new Super Target in Menifee. They stated that there would be future advertising in the community announcing when they would be seeking applications to coincide with the store&apos;s opening. They went on to say that even the associates at the current store would have to &apos;re-apply&apos; for positions at the new Super Target.

In closing, they said that no applications were being taken at this time. I&apos;ve linked the Target Careers webpage to this comment. Just &apos;click&apos; on my name.
 May 13, 2008 5:46 PM Anonymous
said... 
I heard the fitness center was LA Fitness.?? When I spoke to associate at LA Fitness...they stated that Menifee is on their list to open a new location. Any idea which fitness club is going in the Marketplace center.
 May 14, 2008 3:33 PM Anonymous
said... 
Ive heard BOTH gyms - LA Fitness and 24 Hour are coming to menifee area. Does anyone know if there building a LA Fitness across from Albertson on Scott/Antelope? It has the round shape of their building with that tall tower thing (I know a Walgreens is in there too)
 May 14, 2008 10:01 PM Noah
said... 
Does anyone know what is planned for the lot on the northwest corner of Antelope Road and Newort Road (across from the Ralph&apos;s / Target Shopping Center)? I read an article on the internet that some stores, some restaurants and possibly a sports center may be going in there. I can&apos;t remember the Web Site I was on.
 May 15, 2008 6:38 PM Anonymous
said... 
I want Rubio&apos;s Fish and Henry&apos;s Market and 99 cents store and Dave&amp;Buster at Countryside Marketplace in Menifee.
 May 17, 2008 1:03 AM Anonymous
said... 
no 99 cent store, please. Lets keep it a little more upscale. Dont get me wrong - I like the store - somewhere else
 May 18, 2008 10:30 PM Baby said... 
Does anyone know if with all this building if they are going to put in a Lucilles BBQ Rest. anywhere??
A nice place to have some dinner and listen to music would be nice.
 May 20, 2008 8:26 AM Anonymous
said... 
No Rubios unfortunately..they don&apos;t have any interest since a Chipotle&apos;s is slated to go there.
 May 21, 2008 6:35 PM Anonymous
said... 
99 cent store? Please tell me you&apos;re not serious. That&apos;s sad
 May 22, 2008 11:18 AM Anonymous
said... 
I never knew poeple actually thought &quot;Hey I&apos;d love to have a 99 cent store&quot; But hey to each its own.
 May 22, 2008 1:51 PM Anonymous
said... 
Lucilles is going in on the new addition of the Mall in Temecula along with PF Changs.
Please no 99cent store. We dont need that here. Lets keep Menifee upscale to a point.
I hope that no one splits up the old target into multiple shops. We need something nice there. Trevi would be great!!!
 May 26, 2008 8:53 PM Anonymous
said... 
OMG give me a break! No Hometown Buffet, no 99 cents because its not upscale enough?? People there is nothing wrong with those places. Other cities have them so why can&apos;t we?? Are we that SNOTTY??
 May 27, 2008 7:12 AM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t think we&apos;re &quot;SNOTTY&quot; just trying to spruce this place up a bit! Some of us have $$ to spend and we&apos;d like quality places to spend it! Even a HomeGoods or Kirklands would be nice. Maybe an upscale children&apos;s boutique. I&apos;m just tried of seeing a Jack in the Box in EVERY center!
 May 27, 2008 8:57 PM Anonymous
said... 
Its not about being SNOTTY. Its about wanting quality places that have quality people. No matter how you look at things - some things come with certain stigma&apos;s. Its reality. Hometown Buffet and 99 cent stores have a lower stigma and one of lesser value. So - if we have a choice - why would you CHOOSE it??? Choose more upper class places to portray more upper class area
 May 27, 2008 10:45 PM Lee
said... 
Wow! Upscale place bring in upscale people??? If you didn&apos;t know, we don&apos;t exactly live in La Jolla or Beverly Hills. Let&apos;s just appreciate that shops are coming. Unlike some people who seem to worry so much about bringing in upscale stores and restaurants, I personally am thrilled at whatever comes. Tired of driving down to Temecula and Murrieta every time I want to shop. Man, just being able to walk to some stores is fantastic. Whether it&apos;s Trader Joe&apos;s or 99 Cent store, I would shop at both. I just want choices and that&apos;s what we are going to get. Maybe we could get a little of everything, at 48 square miles of potential city land, we have the space for it. I am happy at what we are getting and for whatever comes. Let&apos;s stop all the &quot;no Hometown Buffet! No 99 Cent store!&quot; The more stores that come to the area the better. I do wish though that we could have a movie theatre or an entertainment place for our families and for the youth to have a place to have fun. Relax and look forward to OUR stores...
 May 27, 2008 11:31 PM Anonymous
said... 
the old target is going to be a 24 hr fitness and i hope its a chiptole not a baja fresh mmm. please no more jack in the boxes
 May 28, 2008 10:01 AM Anonymous
said... 
Looking at a previous diagram of the marketplace, it looks like the Lowe&apos;s building isn&apos;t up yet??? Don&apos;t know if the planning changed. I see where Best Buy will be, and I think I know where Super Target will be, but where is the Lowe&apos;s building? Maybe what I think is Super Target is really Lowe&apos;s. In the diagram, it shows Lowe&apos;s, Super Target, then Kohl&apos;s basically side by side, but when I see the building site, it doesn&apos;t look that way.
 May 30, 2008 4:09 PM Anonymous
said... 
To the last anonymous poster, you are correct that the Lowes building is not up yet. They have been in the process of laying the foundation for Lowes. It is the southern-most pad closest to the 215, just as the diagram shows.
 May 30, 2008 8:30 PM Anonymous
said... 
Sounfd like a nice assortment thus far. I agree, lets stay away from the Big Lots and 99-Cents stores. No, not because I&apos;m too good, but because of the nasty appearance of the sidewalks around them, shoddy carts everywhere, which detracts from an appearance and encourages more litter. I also hope shoppers not only stay conscious of putting trash in trash receptacles (which should already be their habits), BUT that they will complain loud and clear when they see storefronts becoming unsightly. When the Walgreens opened up at McCall and I-215, on my first visit I complained to the store manager about the litter strewn around the store and walkways. Yes, he thanked me and cleaned it up. Taking pride in my community is just part of being a good citizen. BTW, we all love the western motiff the center seems to be taking ! It will behoove the occupants to expound on that. Sure do love our country out here and love to get out and ride from Menifee to Sun City to Quail Valley and Romoland - they&apos;re ALL unique! I&apos;m a professional shopper....If I see a shopper toss litter or ram carts into cars....expect me to speak up !
 June 01, 2008 11:28 AM Anonymous
said... 
I talked to a checker at Linens N Things in Temecula and asked her if all Linens N Things were going to go out of business and she said no. But they will not be opening a store in Menifee as originally planned.
 June 01, 2008 7:56 PM Anonymous
said... 
Any plans for a movie theatre? That would be fantastic!
 June 03, 2008 10:07 PM Anonymous
said... 
We should have Big Lots and 99 Cent store where the old Target store is at. Plus I want McDonalds on this side of the freeway (Menifee Lakes).
 June 04, 2008 12:17 AM Anonymous
said... 
Big Lots&amp;a 99 cents store would only further depreciate menifee lakes home values... How is it you people don&apos;t see that? Don&apos;t get me wrong, I&apos;d shop there if I had to but I&apos;d rather drive to these stores than to have them in my back yard.
 June 04, 2008 4:38 AM Anonymous
said... 
We need a movie theatre and a place to go enjoy on a night out with friends and family. Like a Dave&amp;Busters. Something!. A lucky stirke bowling alley would be great. As few mentioned before we need to keep Menifee retailers as much upscale and clean as possible. Lets make it a mini &quot;Irvine&quot; to be Menifee Hills. We sure could use a Costco and Costco gas station.. NO WALMART!!!. Rather have 99cnt store then walmart
 June 04, 2008 11:01 AM Anonymous
said... 
Big Lots and 99 cent store??....You have to be joking! Please...c&apos;mon. Do you really want those kinds of stores around here?
 June 04, 2008 11:17 AM Treasure
said... 
I would love to see a costco or a nice craft store!
 June 04, 2008 11:55 AM Anonymous
said... 
To Anonymous, who commented on: May 27, 2008 10:45 PM,
I&apos;m tired of hearing &quot;bring in high end stores or restaurants no Wal-mart, 99 cents, Hometown Buffet, or Big Lots.&quot; In case you haven&apos;t notice, there are families living here that can&apos;t afford to shop at high end stores (upscale children&apos;s boutique??). Yes some of us can afford it but there are other families that live in our community that can not. Does that mean that if a Hometown Buffet or 99 cents store gets put in that you guys are going to look at customers differently?? That they are lower than you?? All I am saying is don&apos;t critized. Just be HAPPY that we finally get a shopping center&amp;be HAPPY with the stores&amp;restuarants come with it.
 June 04, 2008 3:48 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;m with you Treasure, Costco and/or a nice craft store. Preferrably JoAnns since they have fabric too!!!
 June 04, 2008 4:02 PM Anonymous
said... 
Is there a projected occupancy date yet??


Also, anyone know anything about the Stater Bros. center that&apos;s scheduled for the corner of Menifee and McCall? The &quot;now leasing&quot; signs have been up for 2 years now and they haven&apos;t done squat. Same with the Albertsons slated for Menifee and Hwy 74.
 June 04, 2008 4:31 PM Anonymous
said... 
No one is judging people who shop at 99 cent stores etc. I shop there, but if I had my CHOICE - I would prefer stores with a little more upper class scale. Im not saying they are bad - but we have one in driving distance on Madison - so lets get things that we would shop at frequently, are a bit more classy, and would make our daily shopping easier. At this point, the closer I have to drive - the better my wallet is with gas prices!
 June 04, 2008 5:21 PM Anonymous
said... 
To Anonymous who posted at June 04,2008
....i&apos;m tired of hearing &quot;bring on the white trash stores&quot;..like 99 cent, Big Lots, Walmart, Hometown Buffet. So it goes both ways. Whats wrong with being happy with Target? They are not expensive at all. Why the need for trashy stores to only bring this city down?... i just don&apos;t get it.
 June 04, 2008 7:15 PM Anonymous
said... 
In the first place I never said that Target was expensive so I don&apos;t know why you brought it up. Everyone needs to stop whining about &quot;oh not that store but this store&quot;. All I said was that there are people in OUR community that can not afford to shop at &quot;upscale&quot; stores. You have to think about them too. What we&apos;re just going to ignore them? So once again I say be happy with what we get, I know I am!
 June 04, 2008 9:18 PM Lee
said... 
I totally agree with the last comment. Tired of hearing about all of the &quot;no Hometown, no 99 cent store&quot; comments. I am also happy to get whatever comes. We are now a city of 48 square miles, that&apos;s larger then Temecula. We will have room for everything. Please don&apos;t think that Countryside will be the only place to shop. I am sure now that we are a city that other store will come, we surely have to place for them.
 June 04, 2008 10:20 PM Anonymous
said... 
I would like to know about that Stater Bros&amp;Albertson&apos;s off Menifee Rd as well, I heard before that Stater&apos;s was having problems getting other businesses on board. Would definitely be a great addition to all of us at Heritage Lake.

As far as 99 cents, Big Lots, Hometown Buffet,etc. they are great, affordable alternatives for those on a budget- I grew up going to them, but understand the fact they&apos;re not for everyone. Maybe they&quot;d be better suited for the half abandoned center on Bradley&amp;McCall..... The new City of Menifee should have more than enough space.
 June 04, 2008 11:09 PM 4comments said... 
This question has probably been asked before, but does anyone have an expected date the Countryside Martket Place will open?
 June 05, 2008 4:31 PM Anonymous
said... 
The first phase will be open by October this year.
 June 06, 2008 1:29 PM Anonymous
said... 
i heard its opening in oct. :)
 June 06, 2008 2:00 PM Katie D
said... 
We need more clothing stores. I look like a rag doll! My children only wear Target stuff which I hate buying now. We need a children&apos;s clothing store. We also need a Trader Joe&apos;s, a Souplantation, Olive Garden?, Marie Calenders, a better Cingular store, and a DSW Shoe Store would be awesome!!
 June 06, 2008 2:54 PM anonymous said... 
Oh yes, a JoAnns or Michaels, how about the Olive Garden or Black Angus. A bowling alley is a must for ALL to enjoy. We really need things to keep Menifee&apos;s kids in town and not on the road going somewhere else. I love Menifee and it is deserving of some quality amenities. Let&apos;s ALL try to keep our new city clean.
 June 06, 2008 5:46 PM Anonymous
said... 
clothing stores would be great! I know there is a Lane Bryant going in but what about the woman that don&apos;t shop at that store. A Nordstroms Rack would be great.
 June 06, 2008 7:13 PM Anonymous
said... 
We had a bowling alley. It closed down several years ago because of the thugs that hung out there. It was drug dealer heaven there. I much rather see a movie theater than another bowling alley.
 June 06, 2008 10:42 PM Anonymous
said... 
HOMETOWN BUFFET and 99ct store lovers. I love them too BUT our property values are most important. statistically homes with those stores in the immediate area depreciate. for those that can&apos;t afford to shop elsewhere but own homes in menifee, wouldn&apos;t you rather drive the 10 minutes so that you can make some money off of your home once the values start raising? the distance off of murrieta hot springs is nominal in comparison to establishing a more UPSCALE Menifee. It would benefit ALL of the homeowners to improve MENIFEE, nicer streets, more landscaping, better stores, a nice place to look at AND to live in. DRIVE to the cheaper stores (they aren&apos;t THAT far) AND establish a better upscale community in Menifee. It&apos;s not like we have to drive an hour to get to the 99ct store. they will probably open hometown walmart biglots or like places up the 215 where the new Home Depot is-by the way it is only 5 miles??? REMEMBER, improve your community and improve your values and improve your employment opportunities AND PAY. what kind of jobs, environment and money do those lower end stores bring to our area? NICE MENIFEE = MORE VALUE = MORE MONEY. fortunately the stores that we want to avoid are within 5 to 12 miles of us anyway so we have the BEST of both worlds. MAKE GOOD DECISIONS MENIFEE!
 June 07, 2008 10:26 AM Anonymous
said... 
To the previous poster - AMEN!
 June 07, 2008 3:19 PM Anonymous
said... 
The Menifee Marketplace will need security and law enforcement presence because teenagers will surely gather. Nothing against kids, but there will be problems where they gather. A very similar shopping center in Corona (The Crossings) had major problems related to juveniles (vandalism, fights, etc.) and business suffered. This shopping center requires constant monitoring by police officers now assigned to that center (like many malls/shopping centers) because juveniles still gather. You can go there in the afternoon/evening and watch carloads of teenagers be dropped off by parents. Police enforce the 10:00 PM city curfew, so you can watch the same parents lining up to pick up the kids at 9:55 PM. I personally stopped going to that shopping center on the weekends because I did not want to walk through a crowd of 200 teenagers in front of the movie theater. Go to The Crossings between 8 and 10 PM and stand near the fountain and see if you want the Menifee Marketplace to look like that. Some cities have 8 PM curfews for anyone under 18 years old in a designated shopping center. Menifee should consider this.
 June 07, 2008 5:11 PM Anonymous
said... 
I agree with the person who basically said...more upscale stores = nicer community = higher home values = happier homeowners!!!!! A 99 cents store would make our area unattractive...I agree with the others who have said they would rather drive to another area to shop there.
 June 07, 2008 7:33 PM Anonymous
said... 
I appreciate the &quot;need to make Menifee more upscale and enhance property values&quot;(not a direct quote)but as gas soars over 5 bucks a gallon I would love to see drivers in Menifee start paying attention to their driving habits. The way most of us drive in town and around our schools all we are going to be able to afford in the near future is the 99 cent store! Slow down and maybe you will be able to pay cash for those dinners, the clothes, and the home decor. Upscale but casual would make a great Menifee.
 June 07, 2008 8:18 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank GOD! Finally some people that agree with me about upscale shopping. It&apos;s about time...
 June 07, 2008 9:03 PM Anonymous
said... 
no walmart no 99 no hometown
 June 09, 2008 8:41 AM The Gus&amp;amp;Bryce Show
said... 
For the comment on 24 hr fitness potentially moving into the old target building, the 24 hr fitness website does not make mention to a new club in Menifee (http://www.24comingsoon.com/) which is a bummer because I too have a membership and would enjoy not driving to Murrieta for workouts.
 June 09, 2008 1:19 PM Anonymous
said... 
I still am trying to figure out what is being built across from Albertson&apos;s on Scott and Antelope. Besides a Walgreens. The building with the large round structure entrance - looks like a LA Fitness front - but then again - starbucks look like that too. Anyone know?
 June 10, 2008 8:51 AM Anonymous
said... 
Antelope Square

Stores So Far:

Walgreens
AM/PM
Jack in the Box
Submarina
Fantastic Sams
Dry Cleaner
Modern Nails
Dental
Figaro&apos;s Pizza


21 spots still available and 1 anchor spot
 June 10, 2008 2:43 PM Anonymous
said... 
here is a link for the Antelope Square brochure and it lists where the businesses are located...
http://www.davcondev.com/uploads/antelope_square/AntelopeSquareFlyer.pdf
 June 10, 2008 3:01 PM Anonymous
said... 
After living in the North park area for 16 years and 30 years in San Marcos. Now Menifee it would be nice to get popular and desired shops. I for one would love to see a Nordstroms rack or a T.J Max,Marshalls how about the Cheesecake Factory, Oscars,Daphnes,Calif Pizza,Sprouts or a real good authentic Mexican restaurant or a good Steak house. A nice sports Bar. A bakery that offers out side sitting area where you can hang out and eat Deserts and drink coffee,tea,desired beverages. Panera would be nice especially in the Fall and Winter when it gets pretty chilly, they have delicious soups with home made bread bowls.
 June 10, 2008 9:45 PM Anonymous
said... 
The Coffee Bean and Tea Leaf would be a great coffee shop addition.
 June 11, 2008 4:05 PM Menifee Constituant
said... 
Our homes have decreased enough with all of the foreclosures in the area. PLEASE no 99 cents or Big Lots stores!!! Have you ever been inside Ross Dress for Less store in that center? You can&apos;t push your cart down the isles because patrons throw everything on the floor. And...does this mean that whoever owns the shopping center will clean the sidewalks and empty the trash sometime soon?
 June 11, 2008 8:09 PM Anonymous
said... 
We really need a Trader Joes, Fresh and Easy or health food store with eatery attached.
A Movie theatre and good dining restaurants with a place for live bands would be Wonderful.
 June 12, 2008 10:28 AM Anonymous
said... 
Fresh&amp;Easy will be in the new Countryside Market place
 June 13, 2008 10:21 PM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t see Fresh and Easy on the list. Is there a new updated list somewhere? If so, where can we find it?
 June 14, 2008 5:35 AM Anonymous
said... 
What the heck is Fresh&amp;Easy?
 June 14, 2008 10:22 AM Anonymous
said... 
While I heard a fresh&amp;easy would be there - on the Fresh&amp;easy Website - it says Coming soon on Newport&amp;Menifee. Would that be by The Lakes? A Fresh&amp;easy is a new store that basically is like a local farmers market. They sell fresh produce and is kinf of like a trader Joes or Sprouts. You can check it out at freshandeasy.com and click on the map to see the menifee store.
 June 14, 2008 1:43 PM Gayle Reed
said... 
There have been a lot of posts here about what people would like to see in the new Countryside Marketplace. I, for one, would like developers to consider another idea for development here in Menifee--a Restaurant Row, something like the one they&apos;ve had in San Marcos for YEARS. A good developer could create an entertainment center with numerous restaurants of all varieties and a movie theater as well. NOT something like the Promenade, where parking for restaurants is a nightmare, but a place for eating/theater only, where shopping will not be the focus. And while I&apos;m wishing for a Restaurant Row, I&apos;ll put in my bid for The Elephant Bar:)
 June 20, 2008 10:20 PM Anonymous
said... 
I agree with the comments of the &quot;menifee Consultant&quot; posted 6/11/08 8:09 pm. We walked into Ross once and it was enough. No 99 cent stores, or big lots or anything else that would invite &quot;the wrong&quot; crowd. If that makes us snooty, oh well. Yeah and we&apos;re not in Beverly Hills or in La Jolla, but I don&apos;t want to hang my head when I say I live in Menifee either. I want people to want to come here. Give me a break..what do you think about when you say Moreno Valley aka Mo. Val. (I&apos;ve even hear &quot;Murder Valley&quot;, or Perris, or Hemet? Do you really want that here?
 June 21, 2008 8:31 AM Anonymous
said... 
How can we petition Donohue for a Panera Bread or Great Western Bread - both chains in midwest with absolutely wonderful breads and ambience in their shops? We could really upgrade our mall with either of these !
RE: TREVIS - If this is the same company already in Lake Elsinore; the Lake Elsinore City Council and Police Dept are already inundated with complaints of unauthorized loud music, building-permit violations, etc. With the owner (trevis) consistently violating ordnances, do we really want to cope with them in Menifee??
 June 22, 2008 10:11 AM Anonymous
said... 
Trevis is also the one who bought or leased the old K-Mart Store in Lake Elsinore and made it into a bowling alley; and now is trying to expand it into a night club; AND has been less than a stellar business owner in the Lake Elsinore community. Be careful what you ask for....
 June 22, 2008 10:35 AM Anonymous
said... 
Developers were meeting at the corner of Menifee Road and Newport Road last Friday. When asked what was going in there, they stated it was going to be a new location for Fresh&amp;Easy.
 June 22, 2008 10:39 AM Anonymous
said... 
WHY does it seem that the Menifee Lakes&apos; folks always speak as though the new shopping areas and EVERYTHING else that&apos;s going on centers around them?? Let&apos;s keep in mind Menifee Lakes is just PART of our new city; what about the rest of the community? OMG..build those cheapie stores around Sun City, Quail, or Romo...just bring the elite ones near Menifee Lakes. Is that why we wanted the name to be just &quot;Menifee&quot; (so Menifee Lakes could think of it as only theirs) instead of &quot;Menifee Valley&quot; to include all the areas?

FOR THE ONE ALWAYS directing his demeaning sermons to &quot;YOU PEOPLE&quot;; give me a break...do you live your pompous existence setting yourself on a pedestal to exclude all of us &quot;you people&quot; ?? Have you ever considered &apos;NO MAN IS AN ISLAND&apos; and we need each other? Happy Sunday...no more &apos;you-people&apos; sermons!
 June 22, 2008 10:53 AM chattycathy said... 
I am just curious if anyone has an update as to the completion date of the Marketplace? They are definitely making some progress. I think it was originally scheduled to open (at least part of it) Oct.&apos;08. Is that still the plan? BTW I live on the Menifee/Sun City border and I don&apos;t want crappy stores there either. You know, no matter which city in the &quot;menifee valley&quot; you live in, we all have a common goal. I think that we all want to live in a safe, friendly community that we can live happily with our families...no matter what city you are in.
 June 22, 2008 2:10 PM Anonymous
said... 
I saw in the paper today (in the jobs section) an ad that said Kohls in Menifee is hiring for full time positions. Part time positions will come a little later according to their website. I wonder when everyone else will be hiring - I imagine it will be very soon if not already!
 June 22, 2008 5:30 PM Anonymous
said... 
This is a great website. We just bought a home in Menifee and are totally lost - this site has really helped.
 June 24, 2008 12:38 PM Anonymous
said... 
This is a great website. We just bought a home in Menifee and are totally lost - this site has really helped.
 June 24, 2008 12:39 PM Anonymous
said... 
Adding to the post of 9 June RE Panera Breads: The fall is really nice to stop in for a pastry (or bread bowl) and sit by the fire with their flavored coffees ! They always have a round fireplace with tables and chairs surrounding it...Give us some of these places to enjoy ! Maybe the developers need to restructure their marketing dept to more aggressively go after some of these shops...like Nordstrom&apos;s Rack, TJ Maxx, Sax Off Fifth, etc. No, I&apos;m not snooty, let&apos;s embrace some of the better stores!
 June 26, 2008 11:30 AM Anonymous
said... 
I think it would be great to see Sprouts or wholefoods come into the area.
 June 26, 2008 2:42 PM Anonymous
said... 
TJ MAXX???
 June 26, 2008 11:24 PM Anonymous
said... 
LOL at TJ Maxx and Sax off Fifth. People complain about the Ross store&amp;TJ Maxx is the same thing. As for as Nordstorms&amp;Sax I don&apos;t think they will make money out here just yet. They would have to build a mall for that to happen.
 June 27, 2008 7:08 AM Anonymous
said... 
Called 24hr Fitness Corporate. They&apos;ve pulled out of Menifee. Fitness 19 is planning on opening up near Bradley/Newport.
 June 27, 2008 3:23 PM Anonymous
said... 
What ever stores do come in; My concern is teenagers hanging out causing trouble. Have teenagers? Keep an eye on them and pay attention to who they hang out with!!! As far as 99c stores or lower class shops; perhaps some of you can afford to spend money on gas to shop at these stores elswhere. How about those that cannot afford to drive the extra mile? Those people really do need inexpensive stores (close to home) to shop at. In case you haven&apos;t noticed those people are already living in Menifee!! Supposedly; Murrieta is more upscale than Menifee and they have those inexpensive shops in their city. I think what it takes is being a good citizen and staying involved in keeping the place clean, even if it takes calling the store&apos;s headquarters to make comments or complaints.
VERY GLAD TO SEE NOW SHOPS COMING IN!!!
 June 27, 2008 4:38 PM Anonymous
said... 
What ever stores do come in; My concern is teenagers hanging out causing trouble. Have teenagers? Keep an eye on them and pay attention to who they hang out with!!! As far as 99c stores or lower class shops; perhaps some of you can afford to spend money on gas to shop at these stores elswhere. How about those that cannot afford to drive the extra mile? Those people really do need inexpensive stores (close to home) to shop at. In case you haven&apos;t noticed those people are already living in Menifee!! Supposedly; Murrieta is more upscale than Menifee and they have those inexpensive shops in their city. I think what it takes is being a good citizen and staying involved in keeping the place clean, even if it takes calling the store&apos;s headquarters to make comments or complaints.
VERY GLAD TO SEE NOW SHOPS COMING IN!!!
 June 27, 2008 4:39 PM Anonymous
said... 
give me a break. If you don&apos;t like teenagers then maybe you should move to SUN CITY. Or go roll your trailer somewhere else!
 June 27, 2008 6:08 PM Anonymous
said... 
It was just a word of advice. Take it however you like. Have teenagers, I know what I&apos;m talking about. Best of Luck To Youl.
 June 27, 2008 7:38 PM Anonymous
said... 
We all know whats being said is right about teens; yes we love kids, but all one has to do is observe the skateboard activity in the Target Center (Antelope) or spend some evening at the Promenade Mall with teens gathering. This certainly does NOT mean bad kids, just kids with nowhere else to gather. NOR does it mean a bad neighborhood ! Kids are kids wherever they are.
 June 27, 2008 8:17 PM Anonymous
said... 
Called LA Fitness corp today. Yes, the new fitness center is an LA Fitness, going-in next to Lowes. Take a look at the building; the sign is up! LA FITNESS. And for heaven&apos;s sake, please, please stop asking for business&apos; likeTthe 99 Cents Store, or Hometown Buffet. People, the trailer parks are almost gone from Menifee! Let&apos;s move on...
 June 27, 2008 11:02 PM Anonymous
said... 
thank you! another person with some common sense. NO TRASHY STORES PLEASE!!!!
 June 28, 2008 11:12 AM Anonymous
said... 
They could Build A 99 cent store or Big Lots and a Home Town Buffet
over on the Sun City Side Or by Winco.
 June 28, 2008 2:24 PM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t see anyone interested in BJ&apos;s restaurant? what do you people think about it?
 June 28, 2008 8:53 PM Anonymous
said... 
One of my big concern is the Walmart supercenter that they are building on the corner of scotts, on the other side of the nursery. I just so don&apos;t like Walmart! Also I have to agree with everyone who do not want low end stores. Our property value already dropped almost 50%, let&apos;s not make it stay that low or drop even more. Upscale shopping centers along with a clean city and nice landscapes will slowly raise it. Let&apos;s make this city one that people want to move here not for the cheap houses or cheap shopping area but for the quality and the attractiveness. Just because we want nice upscale shopping area doesn&apos;t make us snotty. We just don&apos;t want to be Perris. As for not having the luxury of wasting gas driving to murrieta for the 99 cent store or temecual for hometown buffet. Well, the money you save on gas driving there, I&apos;m sure you can put that in the tabs when eating at the nicer new restuarants and stuff at Target is not that much more expensive. Or if you seriously love 99 cents store then make it a habit to stock up when you do get the luxury of driving 10 miles to shop there, unless you just LOVE going there everyday. If so then gosh, I&apos;m sure there are tons of house for sale near the stores, should put that into your agenda. no offense.
 June 28, 2008 11:23 PM Anonymous
said... 
As for BJ&apos;s, I am very excited to see that restaurant come here! They are still planning on coming, right? I love the one in Temecula. It will be nice to not have to drive very far to eat there!!
 June 29, 2008 5:41 AM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;ve stopped shopping at the Ross store. People allow their children to run in and out of the clothing racks; hence, clothing all over the floor. Perris has a Big Lots, and I don&apos;t want a 99 cent either. I&apos;m just happy to see a Chick Fil A, and an In&amp;Out Burger. I&apos;d also like a Trader Joe&apos;s--it&apos;s too much hassle to find a parking place in Temecula. A ham store/restaurant like the one in Murrieta is a great place for homemade soups and sandwiches. Bowling Alley&apos;s always attract drug dealers, etc., but a movie theater where seniors could go during the day, and teens and families in the evening, should do well.
 June 29, 2008 2:43 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;m very glad Chick Fil A is coming. We head down to Murrieta for Family Night many Tuesdays (the crew knows us there now). I am happy we&apos;ll have an indoor playland for my young kids that is close besides Carl&apos;s Jr on Scott. There are not many places to take young children to play inside during the summer.

I&apos;m really mad at 24hr not putting up a gym here. One reason we bought a membership to the one in Murrieta was they said it was coming to Menifee this year. The one in Menifee was suppose to have a pool like the Temecula one does (which is too far to drive with traffic....)

This is the first I&apos;ve heard of the WM or Aquatics center. I&apos;d like the Aquatics center but the Hemet Supercenter is close enough for me. I would prefer it not to be closer. I&apos;m sure I&apos;ll shop there once it&apos;s up but if I could choose I wouldn&apos;t move it to Menifee.
 June 30, 2008 2:26 AM Anonymous
said... 
Agree with the poster about the Ross Store and kids pulling stuff all over. BUT have you heard how MANY times the manager comes over the PA requesting kids be kept under control while shopping. Its the parents who are to blame on this one, not the store. Remember these SAME parents will be shoppping at the new stores too. Anyone with a quick-fix for messy stores due to kids running rampant? maybe asking them to leave a couple of times will cure them.
 June 30, 2008 12:26 PM Anonymous
said... 
How about a Honeybaked Ham store ? NOW THAT&apos;s TALKING ! And befoer Thanksgiving and Christmas would help. I&apos;m not snotty..or SNOOTY...but give us upscale stores to spend our dollars!
 June 30, 2008 12:28 PM Anonymous
said... 
Since were clamoring for &quot;our&quot; stores, how &apos;bout putting in a Gordon Biersch. I like BJ&apos;s but, they can&apos;t hold a candle to Gordon&apos;s.
 June 30, 2008 3:18 PM Anonymous
said... 
Well I wonder if Starbucks is out now that they plan on closing some stores&amp;have said for now no more new ones. While we&apos;re fighting for new places why not a Bob&apos;s Big Boy? I want something simple not to high price. Temecula is opening one up by the old Ritchie&apos;s Diner. Heck I would be happy with Ritchie Diner too.
 July 01, 2008 6:50 PM Jennifer
said... 
TRADER JOES please!!!

Restaurants! But not the same old thing that we can drive 10 - 15 miles to get.
Give us something NEW and EXCITING. Make us the destination place. Give others a reason to come here as we go there for certain restaurants and such. Duplication in every town is BORING.

Give us what MV, Temecula, and Murrieta don&apos;t already have: Cheesecake Factory, PF Chengs, Peppino&apos;s (OC Italian) or Romano&apos;s (from the canyon crest center in Riverside), Javier&apos;s or Fresca&apos;s (Mexican), Sports Bar. A good old Baskin Robbins would be nice too.

Thrilled for the new nice TARGET over the clearance target that has been here.
 July 01, 2008 8:11 PM Anonymous
said... 
Yes a Trader Joe&apos;s would be nice!

I like the idea of a restaurant/entertainment place.... good restaurants (not repeats from surrounding towns) and a MOVIE theater (like Harkins with the child care center inside!).
 July 01, 2008 8:14 PM Anonymous
said... 
COSTCO would be convenient.

Bob&apos;s Big Boy... yummy but might turn into a oldies hangout like cocco&apos;s.

Whatever it turns out to be... just bring it quick! The waiting is killing me.
 July 01, 2008 8:19 PM Anonymous
said... 
&quot;Bob&apos;s Big Boy... yummy but might turn into a oldies hangout like cocco&apos;s&quot;....ummm so where do you expect them to hang out? They live here too.
 July 01, 2008 11:19 PM Anonymous
said... 
An LA FITNESS in menifee? does anyone know the lastest on this topic?
 July 02, 2008 10:36 AM Anonymous
said... 
How about a Yardhouse Restaurant? And why not a comedy club next to a new movie theater? I&apos;d love to see a Nordstroms Rack, as well. BTW, I totally agree that 24Hour Fitness sucks for not moving into Menifee. I have spoken to sooo many people that are as disappointed about this as I am.
 July 02, 2008 12:29 PM chattycathy said... 
There seems to be a lot of us that want a Trader Joe&apos;s in Menifee! If you go to their website you can suggest a new location. Let&apos;s get everyone that we know to flood them with emails about bringing a store to Menifee!!! It can&apos;t hurt...right?? Copy the link below, fill it out and send it. Let&apos;s see what happens.

http://www.traderjoes.com/location_requests_form.aspx
 July 02, 2008 7:59 PM chattycathy said... 
Sorry I don&apos;t think that the link I posted copied correctly. Here&apos;s the Trader Joe&apos;s link again

www.traderjoes.com/location_requests_form.aspx
 July 02, 2008 8:02 PM Anonymous
said... 
I reside in the community right across Newport from the Countryside Marketplace and I&apos;m excited at being &apos;self-contained&apos; as a community. Not so much about the traffic coming in, but that&apos;s progress. I actually heard that Joann&apos;s is moving in to the old Target space, and in all honesty, I love Hometown and would welcome one here, but I also don&apos;t mind driving a few miles. My wife works for Albertson&apos;s so the Walmart thing is kinda touchy. And someone commented on some places going in the shopping center in Sun City where the post office is; I think that&apos;s a great idea, that whole area could use a pick-me-up. All-in-all, bring it on, and open up my darned street so I don&apos;t have to detour.
 July 04, 2008 3:52 PM Anonymous
said... 
Do you think the rumor about JoAnns is true? I would LOVE that!! I hope it is true.
 July 04, 2008 5:18 PM Anonymous
said... 
&quot;Bowling Alley&apos;s always attract drug dealers&quot;... Apparently you should know, since you must be high. Cal Oaks is one of the busiest centers in CA and is not a problem child for Murrieta.
The Trevi center concept, without the Trevi&apos;s questionable business ethics, would be a welcome source of entertainment for me.
 July 04, 2008 6:38 PM Lee
said... 
Something totally absurd that I just heard, SuperTarget is also opening up in The Orchard shopping center just two exits south of the Countryside Marketplace&apos;s SuperTarget. It right off the 215. This is totally crazy. Why in the world would they do this? One will surely fail. They are too close together. This is what I am totally worried about, too many same stores, no choices. How many Jack-in-the-boxes, how many Walgreens, Del Tacos do we need? Come on, this is ridiculous!!! Two SuperTargets about five miles from each other. Target is crazy, and so is Murrieta. I feel that Menifee&apos;s SuperTarget will do better since it will be supported by better stores. The one at Murrieta will be supported by Dixieline and Marshall&apos;s. This will probably take some business away from our store however.
 July 05, 2008 8:57 AM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t look forward to seeing more &quot;shopping carts abandoned&quot; around the community. A couple of times we reported Ralph&apos;s carts tossed aside on Newport Road and Ralph&apos;s couldn&apos;t be concerned enough to send someone for them. I&apos;m assuming that eventually, Valley Wide finally picked them up. I&apos;m afraid we&apos;re in a run for our money in trying to see the areas between the stores and close neighborhoods kept clean. Increased walkers doing the shopping will lead to more trash and wrappers tossed aside in the area. Am I being overly-concerned and paranoid or does this bother others too?
 July 05, 2008 9:13 AM Anonymous
said... 
So are we getting a super walmart or not... I still have no answer
 July 05, 2008 10:44 AM Anonymous
said... 
PLEASE! NO WALMART!!!!!! it&apos;s trashy!
 July 05, 2008 12:06 PM Anonymous
said... 
Tired of ignorant people always trashing stores. GET OUT OF MENIFEE if you don&apos;t like stores coming in. I welcome all stores that might help our economy. Every major city seems to have a Wal-Mart and they are doing just fine. They could be better kept, but are not trashy. Get a life!
 July 05, 2008 1:41 PM Menifee&apos;r
said... 
If you haven&apos;t seen it already, check out the Christensen Ranch website:

https://www.brensoncommunities.com/index.php?cmd=findhome.community&amp;community;=2#shop

I like all the stores except Walmart. Some of the shopping center info on this website could be a bunch of B.S. to sell some homes.

Where are the police and fire stations going to be located?
 July 06, 2008 12:10 AM Anonymous
said... 
I have seen a sign saying that BevMo is coming. What is BevMo? Any clues?
 July 06, 2008 10:17 AM Anonymous
said... 
there is nothing ignorant about not wanting a WALMART! I have a life thank you...i just hate to see trashy stores being built. Yes, i said it again...&quot;TRASHY&quot;. It&apos;s the truth. I&apos;m sorry.
 July 06, 2008 11:33 AM Anonymous
said... 
BevMo is &quot;Beverages and More&quot;.
 July 06, 2008 1:26 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;m sorry I said ignorant, I meant childish. If you think it&apos;s trashy, then I wish you a happy move. I hear it&apos;s coming. I hear Wal-Mart generates 1-2 million dollars in tax revenue for the cities that have them. If that&apos;s trashy, I&apos;ll be a garbage man. I bet you have shopped at Wal-Mart anyway. What a hypocrit! Be happy with whatever we get. It&apos;s better than nothing. Do you think that your desires matter anyway. To the rest that are reading my post, I&apos;m sorry. I&apos;m just tired of people calling stores trashy and think that their wants are more important than others.
 July 06, 2008 4:37 PM Anonymous
said... 
i&apos;m sorry, but i would rather have nothing than have a Walmart. it&apos;s just an opinion. Calm down...you make me laugh.
 July 06, 2008 6:02 PM Anonymous
said... 
So then all the Wal-mart haters can go shop at the new Target. I for one love the idea of having both. There are some items at Wal-mart way cheaper than Target. Just remember Wal-mart will also bring in tax money in for OUR NEW CITY. I don&apos;t shop at Trader Joe&apos;s but I&apos;m not going around saying &quot;Don&apos;t build it&quot;. I wasn&apos;t impress with that store. The same goes with Normstrom&apos;s rack, looked like a Ross, Marshalls, and TJ Max. So Wal-mart some of us Menifee residents WELCOME YOU!
 July 07, 2008 7:19 AM Anonymous
said... 
you can go online and do a search and come up with the actual land survey report for the Walmart. If built as planned - it will be on the corned or Haun and Scott Rd. The Christiansen Ranch website might be a little bloated to attract buyers - but overall - its somewhat accurate. I did see the Walmart Lot drawing online and it only showed spaces available for other stores - it did not list Barnes&amp;Noble like the CR website did. I will try and find the link to the site
 July 07, 2008 1:03 PM Lee
said... 
The last two commenters are great! They are what this site needs - people with insite and information, not just trashing stores. I thank you two for your information.
 July 07, 2008 2:44 PM Anonymous
said... 
Menifee residents...think diversity and opportunity for growth. Look around you. How many foreclosed homes do you see? We need this it couldn&apos;t come at a better time maybe it will boost our ego!
 July 07, 2008 4:06 PM Anonymous
said... 
I agree that Menifee needs more options fr the entire community but I also know that for the business to be successful they will depend on the community to sustain them financially. We see everyone asking for upscale stores but if we have forgotten were not living in La Jolla where the demographics are very different from Menifee. People moving here from OC and SanDiego are escaping the high prices not wanting the same. So as a work in the community I am hearing too often that prices for everything are too high. So as we are all excited about the new shops I hope that we can contribute and not let the shops owners down by running them ut of business as too often is happening in every other city.
 July 07, 2008 7:06 PM Anonymous
said... 
You have a good point. The way things are right now, the cost of just about everything is sky high. How many of us could really afford to shop at high end stores on a frequent basis? Once it awhile, maybe. But until the economy gets better, a lot of us are in survival mode.
 July 07, 2008 7:18 PM Anonymous
said... 
Yes, now more people are making some sense. Let&apos;s be happy about any stores coming in. I&apos;m just a bit bothered that SuperTarget is also opening just two exits down on Clinton Keith at the The Orchard. Too close to our SuperTarget. I hope it doesn&apos;t take away any business.
 July 07, 2008 8:13 PM Anonymous
said... 
Yeah, that does not make any sense at all. Is that a for-sure thing? What are the &quot;planners&quot; thinking? And at one time I heard there is an Annas Linens coming, anyone know if that is the case? And what about JoAnns going in where the old Target is? I&apos;d love to find out for sure....
 July 07, 2008 8:57 PM Anonymous
said... 
Dave&amp;Busters, Costco and Trader Joe&apos;s would be a great addition. We definitely need a nice place to take family and friends. Date Night too. Live Music. Movie Theatre. Murder Mystery Dinner place would be fun.
 July 07, 2008 9:41 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;ve been looking for a different plot map drawing but here is on I found on the Walmart.
http://www.loopnet.com/xNet/MainSite/Listing/Profile/Profile.aspx?LID=15425164&amp;StepID;=101&amp;RecentlyViewed;=true&amp;ItemIndex;=2&amp;PgCxtDir;=Down
 July 07, 2008 10:36 PM Anonymous
said... 
ok I fund them - Here is one on the shopping center (Menifee Lakes Plaza) going in across from Ralphs
http://www.rivcoeda.org/Portals/0/eventInfo/1-Menifee%20Lakes%20Plaza.pdf
and here is the one for across from Countryside with the LA Fitness (if you look hard on the enlarged version you can see it but barely)
http://www.loopnet.com/xNet/MainSite/Listing/Profile/Profile.aspx?LID=15527437&amp;StepID;=101&amp;RecentlyViewed;=true&amp;ItemIndex;=1&amp;PgCxtDir;=Down
The walmart one is the one I posted previously.
 July 07, 2008 10:42 PM Anonymous
said... 
UGH! Sorry for 3 posts in a row - but I clicked on the flyers for them and they are better! Full info and pics.
Here are 3 - Fresh&amp;easy shopping center - (note the large child care center)
http://www.loopnet.com/Attachments/C/1/1/C114D768-E0EF-43C7-A482-620016BCDDB5.pdf

Walmart - http://www.loopnet.com/Attachments/0/D/7/0D7D71FC-0CA0-478F-8E0A-AD2C977CDFF7.pdf

LA Fitness shopping center -
http://www.loopnet.com/Attachments/D/A/7/DA7AB89E-F768-4A55-9EE7-663243B398DE.pdf

Not sure how accurate the last one is as it shows other future developements such as Lowes off McCall area, another Home Depot and Fresh&amp;easy down near Newport/Murrieta Rd and other stores in various spots. They also show Heritage Lake as Menifee Valley Ranch. Also shows a 24 hour fitness off McCall/Ethanac area

Hope this helps somewhat!
 July 07, 2008 10:52 PM Anonymous
said... 
Does anyone have any information about the proposed Menifee Valley Town Center? It looks like it borders Garboni on the north, Antelope on the west, Menifee on the east, and Scott on the south. I noticed it on page 2 from the following link:

http://www.loopnet.com/Attachments/D/A/7/DA7AB89E-F768-4A55-9EE7-663243B398DE.pdf

According to that link the Menifee Town Center will consist of 1,147 units. What is that supposed to mean? As the name suggest, more retail is on the way, right? The center looks pretty big. Could it be a mall with a movie theater?
 July 08, 2008 2:22 AM Anonymous
said... 
I was just thinking... if the city council could get the new developments to install solar panals on their roofs, I bet they&apos;d generate enough electricity to power half the city....
 July 08, 2008 4:10 AM Anonymous
said... 
Reg Bev-MO i drove down the new street to take a peek and they do have there sign up on the outside road.
 July 08, 2008 6:45 AM Anonymous
said... 
WOW-am I the only one who is tired of all the &quot;wannabees&quot;? And oh yes, the aggravating &quot;Snotty&quot; vs. &quot;Snooty&quot; descriptives?? We&apos;ve turned those two words into some kind of way to address anyone we see as a threat to our way of thinking. We sound like a bunch of babies making out their lists for Santa...&quot;I want this, this, and this; BUT don&apos;t show up with that, that, and that&apos;. Poor Santa. How many who are so deadset against WalMart have shopped Walmarts at Christmastime? Fess up - you KNOW you and your neighbors have done so. So, just let them come and I&apos;ll see you all there. Same for restaurants - give us a diversity and we can pick and choose where we will eat..AFTER they&apos;re built!
 July 08, 2008 11:28 AM Anonymous
said... 
Is anyone as dismayed as I am about the design of Countryside Market Place? With the big red barns? This center is such an eyesore! It does not fit in at all in Menifee and with the surrounding architecture. Anyone with eyes can see that. We could have gone for a nice, upscale, Palm Desert look following the existing theme of palm trees, golf course, lakes, etc. But no, instead we got the &quot;country bumpkin&quot; look - it&apos;s just so misplaced and I think it hurts Menifee&apos;s image (and our home values).
 July 08, 2008 5:26 PM Anonymous
said... 
It will look fine when its all done! Its not going to look like a barn in a field. An empty lot with weeds is an eyesore....trash in fields is an eyesore....a red barn themed shop is not.
 July 08, 2008 9:55 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank you for posting the info. Not real sure how I feel about all this shopping coming in especially right now. On the one hand, I&apos;m thrilled that the commute will be less and jobs will increase but the timing is iffy, look at furniture row off Los Alamos, talk about a ghost town. Then there&apos;s the traffic, but all in all the revenue will be good. I do agree with the posters that I&apos;d like to not have the bargain stores not because they are bad but because they are rarely managed well so they then appear trashy. exception...dollar tree. but I&apos;ll happily drive to Murrieta to go there. yes to Trader Joes and a Baskin n Robbins, sorry folks, I do not like Coldstone! ok, I&apos;ve said my peace, oh wait, please, please,please not another Starbucks. Coffee bean is so much better.
 July 10, 2008 1:07 AM Anonymous
said... 
Difference in opinions, I like the Country look of our new shopping center. It&apos;s unique and will add charm to the place. This shows how beauty is in the eyes of the beholder.
 July 10, 2008 6:47 AM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t think the barn is an eyesore. If fits well in the area. This whole area was nothing but ranches/farms before all the houses came in. Parts of the area still are. I like it, to me its unique. Who wants another shopping center that looks all Beverly Hills? I agree to about bringing in Baskin Robins, don&apos;t like Cold Stone. I wish it was still here, never did find out why they pulled out of the Shell/Del Taco store.
 July 10, 2008 7:09 AM Sun City Aztec said... 
This is my first time posting as a blogger and I look forward to reading and responding to posts concerning our community.

I really find it interesting that most of us here in menifee/Sun City are excited, and at the same time, apprehensive about the Countryside Market Place. We&apos;re excited to finally have a varity of shopping and dining options and apprehensive about the future traffic situation on Newport road, but I for one am glad to save the miles and gas that I would normally use to drive to Temecula/Murrieta or Moreno Valley.

With todays gas prices every little advantage helps. Plus after living here over 15 years, its nice to see the area flourish into a City.

Other than the Aquatic Center, which is much needed, I agree with others that having a theater here would be better than sliced bread. Lets keep our fingers crossed!
 July 10, 2008 6:10 PM Anonymous
said... 
Wallmart trash product for trashy
people.
 July 11, 2008 8:53 AM Anonymous
said... 
I wish there was a way to delete comments made by ignorant people like the last commenter. If he doesn&apos;t like certain stores, then don&apos;t shop in them, and I guess Wal-Mart is the reason why our property values have decreased. Why don&apos;t you just move out of here if you don&apos;t want certain stores coming in. Get a freakin&apos; like. You say trashy people, but you write nothing but garbage. Wow, you don&apos;t have anything constructive to write.
 July 11, 2008 11:48 AM Anonymous
said... 
Wallmart? Learn to spell if your going to make comments like that.
 July 11, 2008 11:58 AM ProudMenifeean said... 
It actually is Walmart. I know, because I shop there proudly all the time! And guess what? I am not trashy! I know a lot of high income people that shop there. They are intelligent people who like to save money. I really would love to know what you people think the BIG difference is between Walmart and Target. They both treat their employees the same. They pay the same and offer the same benefits. Quit jumping on the &quot;band wagon&quot; of whackos who think there is a difference!!
 July 11, 2008 12:23 PM Anonymous
said... 
To the person who commented on July 11, 2008 8:53 AM

My family and I are not trashy so get off your high horse!! So what if I like shopping there, there are items there cheaper than Target. Not my fault that I want to save money and you don&apos;t. Don&apos;t shop there if you&apos;re too good, but don&apos;t freaken call me or anybody else trashy for shopping there.
 July 11, 2008 10:05 PM Anonymous
said... 
I found this article on NC Times about jobs. Here you go folks!

MENIFEE: Retailers to hold interviews at Mt. San Jacinto College
By The Californian | Friday, July 11, 2008 7:28 PM PDT∞

Hiring representatives from three stores that will open soon in a new Menifee shopping center will be interviewing prospective employees at Mt. San Jacinto College starting Monday.

Monday, Lowe&apos;s will accept applications and resumes and conduct interviews from 7 a.m. to 5 p.m. in Building 3000. The building is just east of the college entrance off La Piedra Road. The company will be there for several weeks, said Karin Marriott, the college&apos;s spokeswoman.

On Aug. 7, 8 and 9, employees of Target and Kohl&apos;s will be on campus to meet prospective employees. Target representatives will be in Rooms 911, 927, 932 and 969 from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m., and Kohl&apos;s representatives will be in Rooms 601 and 603 from 8 a.m. to 9 p.m.

The college is at 28237 La Piedra Road. For information, visit the calendar section of the college&apos;s Web site, www.msjc.edu, or call (951) 639-5285.
 July 12, 2008 12:17 PM Anonymous
said... 
Just curious, will there be a petting zoo at the new Menifee Countryside Market Place?
 July 13, 2008 12:16 PM Anonymous
said... 
Just curious, will there be a petting zoo at the new Menifee Countryside Market Place?
 July 13, 2008 12:16 PM Anonymous
said... 
Can&apos;t wait until the shopping center is done, I&apos;m tired of wasting so much gas driving to Temecula, to shop,&amp;get something good to eat.&amp;I&apos;m so sick&amp;tired of Jack in the Box, Micky D&apos;s,&amp;all that same crap we have here.&amp;One more thinkg! VIVA ALL THE MEXICANS HERE!!!!!
 July 13, 2008 7:17 PM Anonymous
said... 
what the heck was that?!?!
 July 13, 2008 8:14 PM Anonymous
said... 
WTF??? Some people are just weird. I&apos;m Mexican and feel weirded out by that post. Viva random quotes!!!
 July 13, 2008 11:36 PM Anonymous
said... 
Haha...The petting zoo post was hilarious. Dude, the barn thing was a bad idea, whoever thought of that concept ought to get fired. And those of you who like it need to check the air pressure on the tires of your house.
 July 13, 2008 11:41 PM Anonymous
said... 
Ok, I moved from Murrieta to Romoland a year ago. I find it sooooo funny that I live in Heritage Lake and everyone hear is so afraid to say we live in Romoland, myself included! I have to say that I had no idea that the Menifee people were has snobby as the Murrieta people! Give me a break, upscale! You think that having a Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s would make us upscale! Are you people crazy! Upscale stores would include Nordstroms, Nieman Marcus, ect.... I don&apos;t think that a 99 cent store is going to bring down the property values, the idiots who took out the stupid home loans have already done that! So next time you people want to act like you are above and beyond a 99 cent store you might want to think about what shopping there is in Menifee and the surrounding areas and be grateful that you are getting anything!

Question...where are the upscale homes in Menifee? All I see is tract homes!!!!!!!! I am just happy that I won&apos;t have to waste more money on gas to drive to other cities to shop, so I think some people need to get off their high horses and be gratefull. Besides the fact that you are happy with a Kohls, that&apos;s not upscale!
 July 14, 2008 8:10 AM SMWIA Local 105
said... 
I think that as long as nobody has plans to build a Wal-Mart all of the other stores will be fine! Let&apos;s keep supporting our fellow union workers and not the scabs!!!! Unions are American and keep this country strong!
 July 14, 2008 8:12 AM Anonymous
said... 
HOLY COW! we all sound like a bunch of whiney babies over what sores we&apos;re getting. Maybe the FIRST thing the new developers should hand out is pacifiers. Come on folks, we all put our pants on the same way; you remind me of someone who would absolutely gasp and spread the rumor at seeing their neighbors come out of a strip joint; but go home and turn on the sex channel. Live as you prefer and let others live and shop as they prefer. Enough already with arguing back and forth on here about who has the most class...good indicator that none of us do. I fall back into Therese&apos;s thinking that gave me a good laugh: &quot;a silver plated turd is still a turd&quot;.
 July 14, 2008 8:38 AM Anonymous
said... 
HAHAHAHA......That was good. Maybe the animals at the petting zoo want a silver plated turd? Then they can wave their Mexican Flags with excitement...next to the barn. (Bought of course at the 99 cent store)
 July 14, 2008 12:11 PM Anonymous
said... 
I went to BJ&apos;s in Temecula yesterday to inquire why the Menifee location was not on their websites&apos; &apos;Coming Soon&apos; list? The manager told me things had been pushed back and they would not be opening until the end of NEXT year. He did not know why. That means when everything else opens, that space will remain vacant for an entire year? What is that about?
 July 14, 2008 3:10 PM Anonymous
said... 
Target isn&apos;t a union store so why give Wal-mart a hard time?
 July 14, 2008 6:35 PM Anonymous
said... 
Unions are American? Is that why Unions are only survived by 7% of today&apos;s commerce, of which 3% is concentrated in one city in all of the U.S. - Detroit - which holds the most volatile job stability market in the nation as well as some of the highest poverty rate. But this is American??? Give me a break.
I never understood the need to pay money to some uneducated union rep to speak on behalf of my needs. The only thing that a Union does is deprive us Americans from our freedom of speech.
 July 14, 2008 11:29 PM Anonymous
said... 
My husband is a specific construction trade union and I&apos;d say we are pretty well taken care of - we have annuity, good medical benefits, yearly raises negotiated by them, the ability to keep our benefits no matter what company he works for, and the stability to know that they keep the work coming. He can retire at a fairly young age and will receive a pretty good monthly amount. Overall our experience has been pretty good.
 July 15, 2008 8:23 AM Anonymous
said... 
Can we get back to the Marketplace? How in the world are we now talking about unions? Let&apos;s get back to the stores. Is Linen &apos;N Things coming? Has anyone heard if Costco is planning on a Menifee store? What&apos;s up with Fresh and Easy? I haven&apos;t seen anything going on about them. This is the stuff I want to hear about.
 July 15, 2008 3:50 PM Anonymous
said... 
Linens N Things is not coming now that they have had to close some stores due to bankruptcy not too long ago.
 July 15, 2008 4:29 PM Anonymous
said... 
There&apos;s absolutely no need to start bashing unions on this thread - it&apos;s completely inappropriate.

As far as the stores going in, I&apos;m just glad that we have CHOICES. The list shows a wide range of options for shopping. I do hope we get a cinema here soon.

Thank You to the person who listed the job information. My teenage daughter has been struggling to find employment for the past 3 months. Hopefully, something will open up for her soon.
 July 15, 2008 5:33 PM Anonymous
said... 
Oh my gosh, my teenage daughter has had the same struggle to find a job! I can&apos;t believe how hard it is. Now she is looking forward to maybe Jamba Juice or Tillys or Kohls or something.
 July 15, 2008 6:44 PM Anonymous
said... 
I heard we might be getting a $1.99 store since we are too upscale for a straight .99cent store.
 July 15, 2008 7:16 PM Anonymous
said... 
you have issues....if you were trying to be funny....you failed!
 July 15, 2008 9:26 PM Anonymous
said... 
I talked to someone at Old Navy. They said they&apos;re taking applications online only. Try that too.
 July 15, 2008 10:20 PM Anonymous
said... 
As someone else previously posted, a Yardhouse Restaurant and Panera Bread would be a nice addition. Yardhouse Restaurant would blow BJ&apos;s and Gordon Biersch out of the water! And Yardhouse has better food and is more family-friendly!
 July 15, 2008 11:47 PM Anonymous
said... 
How &apos;bout a Rusty&apos;s Pizza Parlor?
 July 16, 2008 11:18 AM Anonymous
said... 
I don&apos;t agrree. I thought the $1.99 store post was very clever and chuckled.
 July 16, 2008 2:57 PM Anonymous
said... 
I agree. A 1.99 store is much more upscale and in tune with barn like buildings for the biggest shopping area in Menifee.
 July 16, 2008 5:17 PM Anonymous
said... 
Yee Hawl Y&apos;awl! Now if we can just get Andy Dick to get arrested at the Pit Stop then we&apos;ll really be on the map! Yee Hawl! (as I shoot bullets into the sky)
 July 17, 2008 9:08 AM Anonymous
said... 
Much appreciation for the union supporters! Obviously you guys know that a union wage and benefits are much higher than a non-union workers! Just so people understand the comment about supporting unions, union workers are very highly paid and stores like Wal-Mart put unions out of business. Understand this, my husband is a union worker, his hourly wage is $48.01 per hour, a no-union worker gets paid $19.00 per hour. Sure he pays dues, but $53.00 per month is nothing! I think that the protect union comment was only said as an example as to why we should keep super stores like Wal-Mart out of our town. Have you people ever been to a Wal-Mart? Please tell me that you don&apos;t notice the difference in people shopping there, nothing but the poor trying to make our country non-union, which goes to show why we need unions! Non-unions employees pay crappy wages which in turn makes more poor people having to support them!
 July 17, 2008 12:09 PM Anonymous
said... 
Who cares if we have a 99 cent store, according to all of the posts you people are to &quot;UPSCALE&quot; to shop there anyways! So I&apos;m sure it won&apos;t last if we get one! The funny thing is though, 99.9% of you will end up going there because you have no other place to shop!
 July 17, 2008 12:11 PM Anonymous
said... 
From what I understand Target takes good care of their people, Wal-Mart on the other hand doesn&apos;t. Don&apos;t you remember the grocery store strike not so long ago? How would you like to shop at Wal-Mart for all of your groceries? Think about this, no more grocery stores.....
 July 17, 2008 12:16 PM Anonymous
said... 
I used to work for Target. They don&apos;t take any better care of their employees than most other retailers. Its generally a cleaner store, that&apos;s about it.
 July 17, 2008 2:18 PM Anonymous
said... 
First of all, I too used to work for Target and agree with the comment above.
Second just because I shop at Wal-mart doesn&apos;t mean I&apos;m poor. I like to shop around and get good prices which I can at Walmart on some items. It comes in handy too when Christmas is around, their prices in toys and video games are the cheapest in the area. Like other bloggers have said, &quot;if you don&apos;t like shopping there then don&apos;t go there&quot;.
 July 17, 2008 4:07 PM Anonymous
said... 
I work for Albertsons (Union) and do not get paid $48 an hour, as a matter of fact I get $10 an hour. So I&apos;m not sure what your husband does but I&apos;d hate to be the one to inform you but not all unions pay the same. And BTW, even at $10 I still have to pay union dues.
 July 17, 2008 6:34 PM Anonymous
said... 
Wal-Mart&apos;s been union free for as long as its existence not only in the US but around the world. So i guess they must be doing something right.

Anyways, back to the marketplace. Whatever we get is good for us. The barn theme = WTF???
 July 17, 2008 6:37 PM Anonymous
said... 
the barn theme is perfect for all the people that want WalMart and 99 cent store. YEEHAW...have fun shopping in trashy stores....
 July 17, 2008 6:58 PM Anonymous
said... 
PARCEL MAP NO. 35261 / PLOT PLAN NO. 22674 - EA41321 - Applicant: WAL-MART STORES INC. - Engineer/Representative: Adams Engineering - Third Supervisorial District - Antelope Valley Zoning Area - Sun City / Menifee Area Plan: Community Development - Commercial Retail (CD-CR)(0.20-0.35 FAR) - Location: Northerly of Scott Road, Easterly of Haun Road, Westerly of Interstate 215 (I-215) - 30.3 Gross Acres - Zoning: Scenic Commercial Highway (C-P-S)

REQUEST: A Schedule E subdivision of 30.3 gross acres into seven (7) parcels for commercial purposes ranging in size from 1,700 square feet to 225,000 square feet. A Plot Plan for the development of a Commercial Center as follows: Parcel 1 includes the development of a 225,000 square foot Wal-Mart Supercenter and 1,235 parking spaces; Parcel 2 inlcludes a 3,200 square foot fast food drive-thru restaurant and 22 parking spaces; Parcel 3 is comprised of a 2,200 square foot convenience store with a 16-pump fueling station, drive through car wash and 22 parking spaces; Parcel 4 includes a 1,700 square foot fast food restaurant with drive-thru and 26 parking spaces; Parcel 5 proposes a 3,200 square foot fast food drive thru restaurant and 26 parking spaces; Parcel 6 proposes a 14,000 square foot retail shopping center with 84 parking spaces and Parcel 7 proposes a 7,400 square foot retail shopping center and 119 parking spaces.

APN: 360-390-011
 July 17, 2008 7:24 PM Anonymous
said... 
So we get a ton more fast food palces? Better be something besides Jack in the Box, Carls or McD&apos;s.

Im bad - m husband is union and I shop at Walmart! LOL They simply have things there that Target doesnt. Certain brands, craft supplies etc. Whatever works - just shop! We need our economy back up.

AS for the barn theme - its not that bad ppl. Its a shopping center that looks nice - its not your house. Who cares. Its not even RED. Its maroon and muted more than bright red! You all are picky. It will be better than our tiny Target, Ralphs and Yellow Basket
 July 17, 2008 10:28 PM lolamoo said... 
I just bought a home in Quail Valley and work in Temecula. I for one am looking forward to not having to drive out agqin to Temecula on the weekends to shop.

I think too much time is being spent on what the center looks like and what shops are going in.
Is there one thing you can do about it, no. The developer spent years coming up with the plan, it was approved, and the vendors that move in are coming by their choice, not ours.

As to the property values going up or down that depends on us as a whole. Working to improve the community is our job. We need to get active in physically cleaning up our community and doinf things to demand the kind our respect we want as a community. Between Quail Valley, Romoland, Winchester, Sun City, and yes Menifee we all have areas that need improvement. Making this new city a great one to live in and represent is not going to be an easy job and each of us needs to do our part. We can start by not being petty, little people seeing only the small picture, the center; but the big one,the CITY of MENIFEE.
 July 17, 2008 10:51 PM Anonymous
said... 
&quot;Yee Hawl Y&apos;awl! Now if we can just get Andy Dick to get arrested at the Pit Stop then we&apos;ll really be on the map! Yee Hawl! (as I shoot bullets into the sky)&quot;

I love you...
 July 18, 2008 1:21 PM Anonymous
said... 
Yes, very true grocery store unions suck on pay, but construction unions on the other hand pay well! Just keep in mind how many other city across the U.S.A don&apos;t want super wal-marts in their towns and please grocery store people, would you rather work at wal-mart for min wage? I have family that is grocery store union and it is unfair, but like you said no all unions are the same! Alot of construction unions build shopping centers we use, currently the one in Menifee, schools, hospitals, amusement parks, police stations, important things. Unfortunatly stores like Wal-mart don&apos;t hire union workers, Target on the other hand does and by the way, their warehouse is union. Anyways, I for one can&apos;t wait for shopping in Menifee! Hurry up and build!!!!!!!
 July 18, 2008 2:28 PM Anonymous
said... 
My husband is a union sheet metal worker. Great pay $85-$90K a year, benefits are unbeleievable, retirement one of the best in unions! Job security, OH YA!!!! Full union supporter here!!!
 July 18, 2008 2:29 PM Mike
said... 
To all the Wal-Mart haters, good for you for supporting low wage jobs, crappy health care, uncaring employees, child labor and most of all CHINA! 85% of Wal-Mart products come from China. Wal-Mart is the 4th largest buyer of products from China in the world.

Union person, I am with you! Unions make American products!!! Unions build America, the only reason people won&apos;t join is for union dues reasons, stupid! Read your history on America before supporting stores like this, people who worry about a dollar are the reason why the economy is getting bad!
 July 18, 2008 2:39 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank You! Someone else with some common sense! Finally.
 July 18, 2008 6:20 PM chattycathy said... 
I know that we are getting off the original post&apos;s subject but I had to add my 2 cents. Reading all of this union support gave me the chills! I think it is great! My husband is a union man and I don&apos;t care what the dues are, they take VERY good care of us! I am very proud of him (and all the union brothers...and sisters!)for their hard work and dedication!
God Bless America!
 July 18, 2008 11:40 PM chattycathy said... 
Forgot to add this...
To the person who posted the Andy Dick comment; I almost fell out of my chair laughing. HILARIOUS!
 July 18, 2008 11:42 PM Lee
said... 
This was a very informative post, but it&apos;s ridiculous now. Totally into other areas. I wish that this post would deal solely with the future shopping center and not go off in other directions.
 July 19, 2008 9:08 AM «Oldest ‹Older  1–200 of 263  Newer› Newest» 
 
Post a Comment


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home 
Sponsors
 































 Countryside Market Place - Tenant Update ~ Menifee 24/7 

 
Search
 
 Loading 
Recent Comments
 ↑ Grab This Widget 
News Archive
 
 ►  2012 (444) 
 ►  July (35) 
 At Menifee&apos;s Elevate Fitness, This Man&apos;s Success S... Menifee Softball Team Seeks Support in Funding Tri... &apos;Day of Wine and Chocolate&apos;Set for Sept. 30 Ameriprise Financial: Helping You Manage Your Mone... Win a Free Massage From Massage Envy Menifee Book Warehouse Serves Menifee Readers &apos;Menifee Rides&apos;Project Builds Up Steam Menifee Albertson’s: What’s Going on With That Big... Baby Bound Ultrasound Helps You Decide When to Pay... July 11th Means Free Slurpees at 7-Eleven BJ&apos;s Grand Opening Scheduled for Aug. 17 Win a Free Cleaning With Oasis Maids Lake Menifee Women&apos;s Club Purse Auction City Officials Hear What Menifee Has to Say July&apos;s Menifee Valley Chamber Mixer Unveiling of&apos;Community&apos;Painting Highlights Ribbo... Menifee Lakes Country Club Hosts Musician Nina Mar... Scott Mann Announces Run for Mayor Menifee Student Transportation Project Needs Your ... Arts Council Menifee Theater Meeting Set Urgent Care Practice is Among Menifee Dr. Vadim Gu... Study Suggests Arrival of a Walmart in Menifee Cou... Menifee 24/7 Adoptable Pet of the Week: Tilly Menifee Planning Commission Meeting Cancelled Construction on Encanto Apartment Complex Begins N... Watch UFC 148 Silva vs Sonnen II at Pitstop Pub Two Menifee Girls Softball Teams Will Play in Stat... Menifee 24/7 Favorite 5: Recover Menifee Union School District Announces Reduced Sc... Menifee Police Recover Stolen Motorcycles, Pickup ... Happy Hour at the Menifee Beer Hunter Summer Guide for Valley-Wide Parks: July Pitstop Pub Entertainment&amp;Sports Schedule for Ju... Work of Menifee Artist, Local Children Will Be Unv... Menifee Independence Day Celebration, 2012 in Phot... 
 

 ►  June (84) 
 Menifee Offers Free Shuttle Service to Parade Brian Plus Amanda Photography, Wedded Bliss Menifee 24/7 Adoptable Pet of the Week: Cisco EMWD Announces Water Rate Increase Menifee 24/7 Favorite 5: 4th of July Edition Menifee Independence Day Parade Still Seeking Entr... July 3 City Council Meeting Cancelled 10 Day Summer Fitness Blast at Elevate Menifee Valley Chamber of Commerce Installs Board ... Menifee Valley Chamber of Commerce Coffee Mixer, W... Menifee’s Newport Beautification Project Has Final... Beer Hunter Introduces New Menu of Midweek Special... Spider-Man Eats Free at Carl&apos;s Jr. on July 4 Skate Park to Come to Menifee Watch UFC 147 Silva vs. Franklin at The Pitstop Pu... 
 

 ►  May (84) 

 ►  April (80) 

 ►  March (48) 

 ►  February (54) 

 ►  January (59) 
 

 ►  2011 (597) 
 ►  December (49) 

 ►  November (75) 

 ►  October (60) 

 ►  September (43) 

 ►  August (47) 

 ►  July (44) 

 ►  June (72) 

 ►  May (41) 

 ►  April (43) 

 ►  March (42) 

 ►  February (40) 

 ►  January (41) 
 

 ►  2010 (134) 
 ►  December (56) 

 ►  November (30) 

 ►  October (3) 

 ►  September (2) 

 ►  August (3) 

 ►  July (2) 

 ►  June (4) 

 ►  May (3) 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (8) 

 ►  February (7) 

 ►  January (13) 
 

 ►  2009 (139) 
 ►  December (8) 

 ►  November (8) 

 ►  October (1) 

 ►  September (2) 

 ►  August (3) 

 ►  July (9) 

 ►  June (23) 

 ►  May (17) 

 ►  April (15) 

 ►  March (12) 

 ►  February (23) 

 ►  January (18) 
 

 ▼  2008 (349) 
 ►  December (11) 

 ►  November (16) 

 ►  October (40) 

 ►  September (20) 

 ►  August (28) 

 ►  July (46) 

 ►  June (67) 

 ▼  May (62) 
 The countdown begins: 30 days left! There&apos;s a new Sheriff in Town! Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Tonight Beautifying Menifee Movies In The Park Tonight Good Shepherd Lutheran School - Menifee Menifee Union School District May Get Worse Menifee City Council Candidate Map Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Show #4 Proposition 98 versus Proposition 99 - Eminent Dom... Deane Foote versus Jeff Stone Pet of the Month Rental Homes in Menifee Lakes Lost Dog Bill Gould Announces City Council Picks Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Tomorrow City Council Candidate Contributions Iraq Veteran Welcomed Home Movies In The Park Postponed Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Show #3 The Californian Weighs in on Menifee Cityhood The Reason Why the Republican Party is Hurting Candidates Speak on Menifee Valley Talk Radio Dan Stephenson - Buying a City Council City Council Candidate Campaign Disclosure Tornado Hits Perris, Near I-215 Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Show #2 Goat Hill in Canyon Lake to be Clipped Iraq Veteran is being welcomed home this Saturday 3rd Annual Movies In The Park The Crude Barrel Follow the Money for City Council Candidates Measure G - Elections at Large or by District Menifee Valley Talk Radio - a Success Menifee Valley Talk Radio - Corrected Time FBI and Pipe Bombs in Menifee Student&apos;s mother killed in car crash outside Herit... Construction on Antelope and Craig near Holland Jason Roth for City Council Menifee Valley Talk Radio Sun City Nursing Home Seeks Cityhood Proponents Mail-in Ballots Require Extra Postage Vote and Hear a Concert Chester Morrison End of the Year Carnival Bill Gould Gets His Wish Romoland and Cityhood Scott Road Widening Project Which Came First: Sun City or Menifee? Scott Mann Picks up Endorsements Christensen Ranch - Construction Update Canyon Lake Gets Tough on Seatbelt Violations Quail Valley&amp;Menifee Cityhood Menifee Relay for Life - This Weekend Governor Gets Tough on Weeds Zumba Comes to Menifee Valley Will Perris Annex Sun City? Scrapbooks for Foster Children Scot Harden Inducted into Motorcycle Hall of Fame Countryside Market Place - Tenant Update Armed Forces Day Celebration at Good Shepherd Luth... Pet of the Month Menifee City Council Race - Menifee 24/7 Live Deba... 
 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (14) 

 ►  February (13) 

 ►  January (29) 
 

 ►  2007 (304) 
 ►  December (29) 

 ►  November (27) 

 ►  October (60) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ►  August (25) 

 ►  July (41) 

 ►  June (27) 

 ►  May (46) 

 ►  April (10) 

 ►  March (10) 

 ►  February (6) 

 ►  January (7) 
 

 ►  2006 (81) 
 ►  December (8) 

 ►  November (16) 

 ►  October (12) 

 ►  September (10) 

 ►  August (9) 

 ►  July (3) 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (6) 

 ►  April (2) 

 ►  March (3) 

 ►  February (5) 

 ►  January (5) 
 

 ►  2005 (65) 
 ►  December (2) 

 ►  November (7) 

 ►  October (6) 

 ►  September (4) 

 ►  August (15) 

 ►  July (15) 

 ►  June (5) 

 ►  March (2) 

 ►  February (3) 

 ►  January (6) 
 

 ►  2004 (28) 
 ►  December (13) 

 ►  November (15) 
 
 

 

   Copyright 2004-2011 Clear Digital Media, Inc. Design by New WP Themes | Bloggerized by Lasantha - Premiumbloggertemplates.com Free Host
	</body>
</document>
