<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007612" url="http://www.navigon.com/portal/za/produkte/navigationssysteme/navigon-40-easy-navi-vom-testsieger.html" time="2012-07-13-00:35" support="2" score="0.0030359588386882665" bingtitle="NAVIGON 40 Easy | NAVIGON - a Garmin company." webtitle="NAVIGON 40 Easy | NAVIGON - a Garmin company.">
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>With NAVIGON Sightseeing inspired by MERIAN, you will receive background information ... know exactly how far away the nearest filling station or your favourite fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Navigon. All the world is yours. 

 Navigation überspringen 
 
 MyNAVIGON log-in South Africa EN 
 
 Shop Products Customer services MyNAVIGON About NAVIGON 
 - Products - Navigation systems - NAVIGON 40 Easy 

Designed for beginners, equipped for experts
 Please select a product NAVIGON 70 Premium NAVIGON 40 Premium NAVIGON 40 Easy NAVIGON 20 Easy NAVIGON 6300 NAVIGON 3300 max NAVIGON 1400 iPhone 
 Overview 
 
 Overview Functions Design Maps Technical data 
 
NAVIGON 40 Easy

 NAVIGON 40 Easy: excellent navigation at an entry-level price 
Take a look at out entry-level model, and you’ll see it’s not just for those who are new to navigation! The NAVIGON 40 Easy will get you safely and stress-free through the traffic with its fantastic functions. Active Lane Assistant provides you with images of at what point you need to change lanes in traffic, ahead of when you need to turn. This is done in the form of a travelling animation that provides you with a realistic display of the actual road ahead.

 

 The NAVIGON 40 Easy as your personal tour guide 
The new NAVIGON 40 Easy not only gets you safely and stress-free to where you want to go but can also act as your personal tour guide if you want to take in some culture along the route. With NAVIGON Sightseeing inspired by MERIAN, you will receive background information such as telephone numbers, opening hours, prices, reviews and historical background for interesting tourist attractions along your route, and you will also be able to navigate there directly.
 
Active Lane Assistant

Follow the navigator! With Active Lane Assistant, you will know exactly which lane you need to be in at all times. On the right of the display, you will see a realistic, dynamic travelling animation of the road, which will show you which lane you need with an orange arrow. Active Lane Assistant also shows you in plenty of time when you need to change lanes and to which one. You’ll therefore be able to keep an overview in hectic driving conditions and can drive safely and stress-free to your destination. Keep an eye on the road ahead with NAVIGON.

 EXPERIENCE MORE 
 
NAVIGON MyBest POI

Your three favourite points of interest, always at a glance: with the NAVIGON MyBest POIs function, you can choose your three favourite points-of-interest categories and see how far away you are from these POIs at the top of the display screen. So you’ll always know exactly how far away the nearest filling station or your favourite fast food restaurant is on your route. Or the nearest cinema or hotel. You decide what is displayed based on your individual requirements!

 EXPERIENCE MORE 
 
 Map of Southern Africa NAVIGON MyRoutes Text to Speech 
 
 Download manual 
 Proceed to functions 
 Visa AmericanExpress 
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Social bookmarks:

 
 
© Fri Jul 13 00:35:03 CEST 2012
 Garmin Würzburg GmbH - All rights reserved

 NAVIGON international Site map Contact Imprint Data protection General Terms and Conditions Terms of use
	</body>
</document>
