<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007956" url="http://reason.com/blog/weekly/2009-01-04" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="1" score="0.001188825718721043" bingtitle="Week of April 11, 2012 - Hit &amp; Run : Reason Magazine" webtitle="Week of July 12, 2012 - HitRun : Reason.com">
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>... or full approval for TARP funds include the credit card ... from a late-night run to a Jack-in-the-Box fast food restaurant. ... on the drums, with Mr. James &quot;Iggy Stooge/Pop ...</description>
	<body>
		Reason.com
 
 reason.org reason.com reason.tv donate 
 previous link 
 REASON.TV VIDEO: Randy Barnett: Losing Obamacare While Preserving the… (7.12) REASON.TV VIDEO: Killing California&apos;s Costly Death Penalty (7.11) REASON.TV VIDEO: Public-Private Partnerships in Puerto Rico (7.9) REASON.TV VIDEO: How Free Markets Will Beat Climate Change: Q&amp;A with UCLA&apos;s… (7.5) REASON.TV VIDEO: James V. DeLong on Ending &quot;Big SIS&quot; (The Special Interest State… (7.3) REASON.TV VIDEO: 3 Big Takeaways From Obamacare Decision (6.30) REASON.TV VIDEO: Bikini Banners and F*cking Cops Cracking Down on Curse Words… (6.29) REASON.TV VIDEO: Is There a Silver Lining to the Supreme Court&apos;s Obamacare… (6.28) REASON.TV VIDEO: Gandhi, Mandela, and...Mailmen? Postal Workers Wage Hunger… (6.27) REASON.TV VIDEO: The Politics of Poker: Why It&apos;s Time To Legalize Online Gaming (6.27) 
 next link ✕ Loading... 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 close video 
 Subscribe 
 Print E-Reader Reason E-Mail Lists Reason Stuff Shop at Amazon Subscriber Services 
 Mobile 
 Reason on Google Currents for Droid and iOS Android App iPhone App E-Reader 
 About 
 About Contact Media Privacy Reason Foundation Submission Guidelines 
 Staff 
 Staff Contributors 
 Archives 
 Archives Print Issues Cover Gallery Hit&amp;Run Blog Brickbats 
 Topics Poll Feeds 
 Podcasts RSS 
 Events Advertise Donate 
 
Weekly Archives
 2002   | 2003   | 2004   | 2005   | 2006   | 2007   | 2008   | 2009   | 2010   | 2011   | 2012 
 Jan   4–10   11–17   18–24   25–31 Feb   1–7   8–14   15–21   22–28 Mar   1–7   8–14   15–21   22–28   29–31 Apr   1–4   5–11   12–18   19–25   26–30 May   1–2   3–9   10–16   17–23   24–30   31 Jun   1–6   7–13   14–20   21–27   28–30 Jul   1–4   5–11   12–18   19–25   26–31 Aug   1   2–8   9–15   16–22   23–29   30–31 Sep   1–5   6–12   13–19   20–26   27–30 Oct   1–3   4–10   11–17   18–24   25–31 Nov   1–7   8–14   15–21   22–28   29–30 Dec   1–5   6–12   13–19   20–26   27–31 
 
 Oakland BART Officer Who Shot Pinned, Unarmed Man Resigns 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 8:28PM | Brian Doherty 

The San Francisco Chronicle reports . This gets Johannes Mehserle off the hook for having to
actually cooperate in internal police investigations of his murder
of Oscar Grant. A great detail:
 
Alameda County District Attorney Tom Orloff said he plans to
move quickly toward a decision on possible charges. Orloff met
Wednesday with Oakland Mayor Ron Dellums&apos; chief of staff, several
elected officials and other community leaders who arrived at his
Oakland office demanding information about the probe.

&quot;These things normally take weeks rather than days, but I am
trying to expedite this and get it resolved as quickly as we can,&quot;
Orloff said.
 
Any people in public prosecutors offices out there? Does it
really take weeks to even decide to press charges in your
average case of a multiple-eyewitness and on-video shooting? Or
could it be officers are treated with kid gloves an average citizen
shooter would not be.

 Note: An earlier version of this post made the
presumption, which I now believe not to be accurate, that the
&quot;statewide fund for police officers&quot; that Mehserle&apos;s lawyer says in
the story will pay for his defense--despite no longer being an
officer--was paid for by taxpayers. While I have not been able to
verify this for sure this Friday evening, it could well be this private defense
fund . If I learn that taxpayers are indeed on the hook, I&apos;ll
update.

Earlier blogging on this, each one with embeds or links to the
news report with the citizen-shot video of the leadup to the
shooting and shooting, from Michael Moynihan and me .

 Permalink | 239 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Broken Heart, New Alfa Romeo, Funded by Belgian Taxpayers 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 6:12PM | Michael C. Moynihan 

Today&apos;s Wall Street Journal looks at the epidemic of healthy sick people in Belgium (i.e. people with
hangovers bilking the government and their employers by taking
advantage of the country&apos;s overly generous sick leave policies). In
a Hit&amp;Run post last year, I
mentioned that, according to OECD figures, Sweden is one of the
healthiest countries in Europe, yet its citizens topped the tables
in accrued sick days. Odd, that.

Back in June, I offered the
following anecdote from Sweden: &quot;An acquaintance of mine in
Stockholm was on sick leave for six months, collecting
three-quarters of his salary after his girlfriend left him,
rendering him &quot;burned out&quot;— utmattningssyndrom —and incapable of work.&quot; Well,
according to the Journal , brokenhearted Belgians are also
forcing the government to underwrite bad relationship
decisions.
 
Mr. Lombard&apos;s method found a recent subject in Fabrice
Vandervelpen, a 36-year-old manager at a frozen-vegetable packing
plant in southern Belgium. In September, he called in sick. His
girlfriend of six months had just left him, he says. A psychiatrist
diagnosed him with depression and certified him for medical
leave.

[...]

Mr. Vandervelpen says he spent his first two weeks off writing
poetry at his parents&apos; home, where he lives. His mother,
Marie-Jane, often took him shopping for new clothes, she says. He
played soccer again with his local club, FC Burdinne, and
volunteered as club treasurer. He visited a Catholic shrine in
Banneux, Belgium, where the Virgin Mary is said to have appeared in
1933.

In November, Mr. Vandervelpen bought a bright red Alfa Romeo
MiTo for $30,000. Zipping through the hills and sugar-beet fields
in his new car made him feel better, he says. He visited his
ex-girlfriend and went to parties...

If the law didn&apos;t mandate paid sick leave, he would have gone
back to work sooner, says Mr. Vandervelpen. Hesbaye Frost paid his
full salary for the first month he was off. After that, a
government-backed insurance company picked up 80% of his salary,
which the law guarantees indefinitely. &quot;The government keeps €1,000
[about $1,357] a month in taxes off me, so why shouldn&apos;t I get help
when I don&apos;t feel well?&quot; he asks. He makes €2,500 before taxes.
 
According to the Journal , a number of Belgian
government agencies &quot;were averaging 35 days of paid sick leave per
employee each year, more than twice the national rate and seven
times the U.S. average,&quot; before authorities cracked down on the
cheats. And remember, Belgian workers are already the
beneficiaries of four weeks of statutory vacation . With a less generous welfare state, perhaps
the great Plastic
Bertrand would find it necessary to start recording again. In
the meantime, we can only rewatch YouTube videos of the greatest
song to ever come out of Brussels, &quot;Ça plane pour moi.&quot;
 
 Permalink | 53 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Just How the Hell Do You Sum Up George W. Bush&apos;s Presidency? 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 4:43PM | Nick Gillespie 

 Reason Contributing Editor and San Francisco
Chronicle reporter Carolyn Lochhead tiptoes through the disaster that was the
George W. Bush presidency in a long, comprehensive summary of the
past eight years or thereabouts. Snippets:
 
Historians will suspend immediate judgment. All modern
presidents leave office sullied, yet many, like Harry Truman, Bill
Clinton and even Jimmy Carter, have had their reputations restored
with time. But from the vista of now, the nation&apos;s 43rd president
risks joining the likes of Franklin Pierce, his own distant
relative, as among the nation&apos;s worst presidents, harshly judged in
their day and never bathed in the warm afterglow of hindsight.

Bush leaves to his successor two unfinished wars, Osama bin
Laden living in an unstable Pakistan, a U.S. reputation soiled by
Abu Ghraib, Guantanamo and torture, a deep recession and what is
sure to be the first $1 trillion-plus deficit. In short, a gigantic
mess, all the bigger for the peace, prosperity and black ink he
inherited....

Bush both grew the government and gave laissez-faire a bad name,
overseeing a rash of corporate scandals in 2002 and the housing
meltdown. The financial wreckage has many fathers, but Bush, the
first MBA president, stands among them, failing to restrain the
liquidity bubble as it ballooned and asking for $700 billion to
rescue banks as it burst. The GOP is fractured and adrift....

The plan for a swift victory and quick exit [in
Iraq] turned into a bungled and bloody occupation that has
left roughly 4,800 U.S. troops dead, 33,000 Americans wounded, as
well as thousands of contractors and tens of thousands of Iraqis
dead. The wars in Iraq and Afghanistan have lasted longer than
World War II and cost 50 percent more than Vietnam: $904 billion
since 2001, according to the Center for Strategic and Budgetary
Assessments. That ultimately could rise above $2 trillion,
including decades of care for wounded veterans, estimated as high
as $65 billion alone. Bush economic chief Lawrence Lindsay was
fired for saying publicly that the Iraq war could cost $200
billion....

Conditions are worse now than when Truman left office, said
Sean Theriault, a political scientist at the University of Texas.
&quot;The objective standards by which we can evaluate the presidency
are just so bad. The economy is truly in tatters, and I don&apos;t think
any Republican or Democrat, liberal or conservative, can dispute
that. When Bill Clinton left office you could argue that Americans
were generally pleased, but people thought he wasn&apos;t a beacon of
integrity. But we can&apos;t have an argument about the success of
Bush&apos;s economic policies.&quot;
 
The whole story, well worth reading, is online here .

 Permalink | 197 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 No Search, No Service 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 3:51PM | Jacob Sullum 

A year ago, I criticized a California Supreme Court
ruling that said the state&apos;s constitution guarantees a right
to freedom of speech on other people&apos;s property. Now the court has
an opportunity to go further in the dangerously misguided
direction of treating private action as equivalent to state action
when it comes to civil liberties. This week the court heard a case brought by Daniel Sheehan, a San Francisco 49ers fan
who objected to a post-9/11 NFL policy of patting down spectators
at the entrance to stadiums before championship games. As an
anti-terrorism measure, this policy seems gratuitous and
ridiculously ineffectual, and Sheehan may be right that the
true aim is to catch people bringing their own booze to games.
If he felt strongly enough it, he could
have stopped buying 49er tickets. Instead he filed a
lawsuit accusing the team of violating his constitutional right to
privacy.

&quot;There is, of course, no constitutional right to attend a
football game,&quot; lawyers for the 49ers noted. They also pointed
out that fans consent to searches when they buy their tickets;
furthermore, Sheehan bought season tickets again even after he was
offended by the pat-downs. Based on that decision, the trial judge
concluded that Sheehan did not have &quot;a reasonable
expectation of privacy&quot; and that &quot;the pat-downs are not
sufficiently serious in their nature, scope and actual or potential
impact to constitute an egregious breach of the social norms
underlying the privacy right.&quot; The appeals court agreed. But both
accepted the notion that a private business&apos;s search policy could violate the privacy clause of California&apos;s
constitution, which lists privacy as &quot;an inalienable right.&quot;
At least one California appeals court, in a 1989 decision involving drug testing, has held that the privacy
guarantee applies to &quot;both governmental and nongovernmental
conduct.&quot;

Conceiving of civil liberties this way transforms them into
arbitrary demands that can be satisfied only by violating other
people&apos;s rights. If Sheehan has a right to attend a football game,
an applicant has a right to a job, and a protester has a right to
distribute leaflets in a shopping mall, each on his own terms, then
the team owner, employer, and mall owner lose (some of) their
freedom of association, freedom of contract, and property rights.
Constitutional rights are supposed to protect people from the
government. For right violations by individuals, the proper
recourse is the civil or criminal law. Unless Sheehan can show that
the 49ers committed a tort or a crime by searching him as a
condition of letting him into the stadium, this case does not
belong in court.

 Permalink | 68 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Jesse Walker on Winners and Losers in the Gaza Conflict 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 3:00PM 

 As the second
week of combat ends in the Gaza strip, it still isn&apos;t clear what
&quot;winning&quot; the war would entail. But as Managing Editor Jesse Walker
writes, Israel and Hamas aren&apos;t the only forces with a stake in the
conflict. Look beyond that dysfunctional duo, and you&apos;ll see some
winners and losers already emerging.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Domo Arigato 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 2:30PM | Katherine Mangu-Ward 

Robots are not quite up to Asmovian levels worldwide yet, sadly.
But we&apos;ve hit about 1 million industrial robots worldwide. Check
out the distribution
of robots about the globe , from IEEE:

 

Unsurprisingly, Japan is kicking serious metallic ass. And these
figures don&apos;t even count adorable robot dogs and creepy robot women (hello uncanny
valley !).

 

Assuming our march toward an all service economy continues
despite the downturn, we&apos;ll probably never catch up to Japan on
industrial robots, so we&apos;d better make a go of it with service
robots, America.

Via BoingBoing 

 Permalink | 45 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 The Lighter Side Of....Pyramid Schemes 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 2:28PM | Brian Doherty 

Hey, some people do profit from them! The Associated
Press via Fox
News (and not Dave
Berg ) takes a look at &quot;victims&quot; of the Madoff scheme who
actually have already pulled out way more than they put in...and
are wondering if they should apply for aid from the Securities Investors Protection Corp (not a government agency) anyway. (They are also wondering if they
might be ordered by courts later to kick their winnings back.) Read
the whole
thing .

 Permalink | 23 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 The Secret Life of the American Teenager is Boring as Hell 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 2:07PM | Nick Gillespie 

Over at the new Big
Hollywood blog, I&apos;ve got a post up (my first, in fact)
about the second-season premiere of the ABC Family show Th e
Secret Life of the American Teenager, which is about a
high school girl who gets knocked up. A snippet:
 
Apart from the vaguely titallating premise and promise of
the show&apos;s title, the thing is safe as milk. Skim milk. Soy
milk. Possibly powdered milk. The Secret Life, arguably
Hollywood&apos;s most naked bid at the jailbait market since Saved
By The Bell went into permanent summer recess sometime
before Dustin Diamond entered a long-delayed
puberty , thus exemplifies the worst tradition of
after-school special.

It&apos;s preachy beyond belief and, for all the bad stuff that&apos;s
supposed to happen to the characters, it plays out in a world that
is about as menacing and gritty as the dancing gangs in West
Side Story . Give me Rock and Roll High
School any day, the 1979 flick that ends with the blowing
up of Vince Lombardi High, as great a Sophoclean catharsis as has
been recorded in a movie featuring Clint Howard.

 The Secret Life also represents a ubiquitous Hollywood
tendency that all libertarians and even conservatives should reject
out of hand: That television and other forms need to be instructive
to youth and other idiot members of society who
apparently take their moral cues from the small and large
screens.
 
 Whole thing, including some Rob Reiner and Mark Foley bashing,
here .

 Permalink | 56 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Noncompliant Nipple Ring Sold Separately 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 1:33PM | Radley Balko 
 
 The latest from Playmobil :
 
The woman traveler stops by the security checkpoint. After
placing her luggage on the screening machine, the airport employee
checks her baggage. The traveler hands her spare change and watch
to the security guard and proceeds through the metal detector. With
no time to spare, she picks up her luggage and hurries to board her
flight!
 
 The customer reviews are priceless .  Save on shipping by
ordering it with the Playmobil Police
Checkpoint and Playmobil SWAT playsets in time for your favorite little
authoritarian&apos;s birthday!

 Permalink | 50 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 El Paso City Council Wants Debate on Drug Decriminalization 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 12:36PM | Radley Balko 

 Earlier
this week , the El Paso, Texas city council passed a resolution
with 12 steps the U.S. and Mexican governments might take to quell
the violence in Juárez, Mexico, El Paso&apos;s sister city just over the
border.  Juárez saw 1,600 homicides last year, with 20 more
already this year.

But it was the twelfth and final recommendation that brought out
El Paso Mayor John Cook&apos;s veto pen: The city council unanimously
voted to urge both governments to at least study and open debate
about the possibility of legalizing narcotics.

It&apos;s encouraging that the city council managed to pass the
resolution without a dissenting vote.  It&apos;s disappointing that
in calling for no more than study and discussion, the resolution
met only derision and dismissal from the mayor and from El Paso&apos;s
congressman, Rep. Silvestre Reyes (D-Texas).

 Permalink | 27 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Kitten Crush? Is That Like Puppy Love? 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 12:03PM | Jacob Sullum 

 New York Times legal columnist Adam Liptak notes that the Supreme Court is likely to hear the federal
government&apos;s challenge to a decision in which a federal
appeals court concluded that a 1999 law making it a felony to sell
depictions of animal cruelty violates the First Amendment. The law
was aimed primarily at &quot;crush&quot; videos, in which women use their
bare feet or spike-heeled shoes to injure and kill small animals.
As testimony quoted in the House committee report on the
legislation put it, &quot;these depictions often appeal to persons
with a very specific sexual fetish who find them sexually arousing
or otherwise exciting.&quot; Yet the law is broadly worded, prohibiting
the creation, sale, or commercial possession of audio, video, or
still photographs of &quot;animal cruelty&quot; that is illegal in the
jurisdiction where the material is created, sold, or possessed. The
defendant in the case that the solicitor general wants the Supreme
Court to consider, which is the first such case to go to
trial, was arrested for selling videos of dogfighting and
of pit bulls attacking pigs and boars.

As Liptak notes, the law covers footage even of conduct that was
legal at the time or in the place where it occurred. The
dogfighting in this case happened in Japan, where the
sport &quot;appears to be legal,&quot; and in the United States in the 1960s
and &apos;70s. Videos of bull fighting in Spain, bear baiting in
Russia, or even hunting out of season likewise could be grounds for
felony charges under the law. There is an exception for material
with &quot;serious religious, political, scientific, educational,
journalistic, historical, or artistic value,&quot; but how the
government would determine which depictions qualify is
anybody&apos;s guess. As UCLA law professor Eugene Volokh tells Liptak,
&quot;what constitutes serious value is very much in the eye of the
beholder.&quot; So it&apos;s not surprising that the U.S. Court of Appeals
for the 3rd Circuit ruled in 2007 that the law is unconstitutional.
Volokh predicts that if the Supreme Court hears the case it will
agree, by a large margin and perhaps unanimously, declining to
recognize a new category of speech that, like obscenity, threats,
&quot;fighting words,&quot; and incitement to &quot;imminent lawless
action,&quot; is completely outside the protection of the First
Amendment.

I&apos;m not a dogfighting fan, and the crush videos sound pretty
appalling. Still, it seems obvious to me that merely
distributing a record of offensive conduct, even when the
conduct itself is illegal, should be permitted. In any case,
what does it say about our political culture that Congress
felt it necessary to prohibit the sale of videos showing cruelty to
animals but has not passed a law attempting to suppress the traffic
in videos of cruelty to people?

The 3rd Circuit&apos;s ruling is here (PDF).

 Permalink | 103 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Guillemette Faure on Shopping for Fertility Markets 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 12:00PM 

 From our
February issue, Guillemette Faure reports that when it comes to
reproductive technology, Americans are more tolerant than the
French.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Smoke &apos;Em While You Can Afford &apos;Em 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 11:29AM | Brian Doherty 

Americans for Tax Reform is smokin&apos;
mad about a fresh congressional proposal to raise cigarette
taxes by 61 cents per pack--a 156 percent increase, ATR says, and a
direct blow to the working poor of the sort Obama swore he&apos;d
eschew.

The war on smoking on grounds other than cost is covered quite extensively here at Reason magazine and
Reason.com.

 Permalink | 44 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Are You Listening President Obama?: Miami Needs Waterslides! Akron Needs Decorative Fences! Salt Lake City Needs Bathrooms! 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 11:01AM | Nick Gillespie 

 CNS
reports that Barack Obama met yesterday with the mayors of nine
cities who are asking for almost $11
billion for &quot;shovel-ready&quot; projects including the
desperately needed necessities listed in the headline of this
post.

To get a sense of the meeting, read this snippet:
 
Among the mayors who met with Obama, Miami Mayor Manuel Diaz is
asking for the most federal tax dollars, a total of $3.2 billion.
His requests include $1.5 million to build the Grapeland Flowrider,
a new water park attraction, and $100,000 to build dirt-bike
trails.

Miami also wants $94 million in federal tax dollars for parking
garages at the Orange Bowl, and $20 million for work on a city park
that would include a new pool and a sports and fitness center.
 
Overall, the article notes &quot;the mayors of all 641 cities
[represented by the U.S. Conference of Mayors] are asking for
$96.6 billion in federal funds for 15,221 municipal projects.&quot; Whole
bit here .

 Reason did a quick litany of the greatest/awful-lest
hits of the Conference of Mayors&apos; wish list when it came out. It is
truly stunning , even if you believe that the federal government
should be spending $71,000 to coordinate the lights on Fort Riley
Boulevard in Manhattan, Kansas (an actual request).

Reason Foundation&apos;s Bob Poole wrote in the Wall Street Journal
that &quot; stimulus
shouldn&apos;t be an excuse for pork .&quot;

 Permalink | 103 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Trespassing Bees in California—Ronald Coase to the Rescue 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 10:37AM | Ronald Bailey 

Bees are trespassing into California mandarin orange groves,
according to the Associated Press. Here&apos;s the scoop :
 
Is it trespassing when bees do what bees do in California&apos;s
tangerine groves?

That is the question being weighed by state agriculture
officials caught between beekeepers who prize orange blossom honey
and citrus growers who blame the bees for causing otherwise
seedless mandarin oranges to develop pips.

&quot;Both sides are unwilling to give any ground, and both have
valid points,&quot; said Jerry Prieto, the former Fresno County
agricultural commissioner who has spent six months mediating the
dispute.

The fight comes amid a worldwide consumer taste shift toward
seedless grapes, watermelons and tangerines — at the same time the
nation&apos;s struggling bee colonies look for winter food.

The California Department of Food and Agriculture is scheduled
to issue draft regulations this month that will require beekeepers
to register their locations with county agricultural commissioners
by March 1 so growers can monitor hives within two miles of their
groves. If bees are too close, growers can ask beekeepers to move
and hope they comply.

&quot;But they won&apos;t have to move,&quot; said Rayne Pegg, deputy secretary
of legislation and policy for the CDFA.

Absent a method of resolving disputes, Prieto predicted: &quot;This
is going to end up in court.&quot;
 
But this situation doesn&apos;t have to end up in court or need
government regulations. After all, Nobel Economics laureate Ronald
Coase explained, absent substantial transactions costs, the initial
allocation of property rights does not impede achieving the most
economically efficient result. Why? Because parties can negotiate
their differences and figure out whose activities are more
valuable. The party whose activities earn more can pay off the
other party and proceed. (Economist Steven Levitt has a nice explanation of the &quot;Coase Theorem&quot; at his Freakonomics
blog.)

But perhaps the transactions costs are too high in this case. In
fact, Economics Nobelist James Meade used exactly this bee
situation to try to disprove the Coase&apos;s arguments, but as
economist David Friedman explained in Reason some years ago it is, in fact, a near perfect
example of Coasean bargaining:


 
Meade offered, as an example of the sort of externality problem
for which Coase&apos;s approach offered no practical solution, the
externalities associated with honey bees. Bees graze on the flowers
of various crops, so a farmer who grows crops that produce nectar
benefits the beekeepers in the area. The farmer receives none of
the benefit himself, so he has an inefficiently low incentive to
grow such crops. Since bees cannot be convinced to respect property
rights or keep contracts, there is, Meade argued, no practical way
to apply Coase&apos;s approach. We must either subsidize farmers who
grow nectar rich crops (a negative Pigouvian tax) or accept
inefficiency in the joint production of crops and honey.

It turned out that Meade was wrong. In two later articles,
supporters of Coase demonstrated that contracts between beekeepers
and farmers had been common practice in the industry since early in
this century. When the crops were producing nectar and did not need
pollenization, beekeepers paid farmers for permission to put their
hives in the farmers&apos; fields. When the crops were producing little
nectar but needed pollenization (which increases yields), farmers
paid beekeepers. Bees may not respect property rights but they are,
like people, lazy, and prefer to forage as close to the hive as
possible.

The fact that a Coasian approach solves that particular
externality problem does not imply that it will solve all such
problems. But the observation that an economist as distinguished as
Meade assumed Coase&apos;s approach was of no practical significance in
a context where it was actually standard practice suggests that the
range of problems to which the Coasian solution is relevant may be
much greater than many would at first guess.
 
So which is more valuable--seedless mandarin oranges or citrus
blossom honey? I suspect that what is happening is that the
mandarin orange growers and the beekeepers are both hoping the
courts/bureaucrats will side with them and thus avoid having to pay
whichever party the costs for the externalities they impose. That
would mean that one party would get to impose their externality on
the other party without having to pay for it, resulting in a
overall loss of economic efficiency. Sigh.

One more note: Coasean bargaining is a dandy way to
handle those nasty cross-pollenation disputes between organic
farmers and farmers who want to grow genetically enhanced
crops.  See also Reason&apos;s 1997 interview with Coase here .

 Permalink | 65 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 U.S. Unemployment Jumps to 7.2 percent 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 9:00AM | Matt Welch 

 Worse than expected.

How does that compare from miseries past? The national rate was
7.2 percent or higher between December 1974 and April 1977 (peaking
at an even 9.0), according to the aptly named Misery Index website ;
and again 7.2 percent or higher between May 1980 and August 1985,
with a late-&apos;82 peak of 10.8 percent unemployment. There was also a
brief 7.2+ period between December &apos;91 and January &apos;93, peaking at
7.8.

Are we as bad off now as we were during the Carter-Reagan
recession? If not, will we soon lap that and graduate direcly to
the 1930s? Vote in the comments.

And read Reason&apos;s prescient roundtable on &quot; The Coming
Recession &quot; from our June 2008 issue.

 Permalink | 207 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Strings Attached 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 8:57AM | Jesse Walker 

Industrial policy, Democratic-style: The goverment will spend
billions to help your company if you make yourself more green.
Industrial policy, Republican-style: The government will spend
billions to help your company if you do something about those
damn unions .
 
Provisions of General Motors&apos; and Chrysler&apos;s $17.4 billion in
federal loans automatically places them in default if union workers
go on strike.

A General Motors Corp. filing this week with the Securities and
Exchange Commission detailed the provision as part of its $13.4
billion in federal loans.

A person briefed on Chrysler LLC&apos;s $4 billion loan, who didn&apos;t
want to be identified because the company is in talks with the
United Auto Workers union about concessions, confirmed Thursday
that the Chrysler deal also has a similar provision.

The UAW isn&apos;t a party to the deal and hasn&apos;t threatened a
strike, its most potent weapon against the Detroit automakers.
 
[Hat tip: quasibill .]

 Update : Down in the comments, R.C. Dean writes :
 
I don&apos;t see that as anti-union, I see it as giving the union
even more leverage in the upcoming negotiations.
 
Under different circumstances I would agree. But right now the
UAW is as desperate for that money as the companies are -- maybe
more so, since it has more to lose in the event of a
bankruptcy.

 Permalink | 22 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Sarkozy, on our &quot;immoral system&quot; 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 8:37AM | Matt Welch 

Remember the good old days, when French President Nicolas
Sarkozy was the darling of the American Right ? So much for that :
 
Sarkozy, leading a two-day conference with former British Prime
Minister Tony Blair on the future of capitalism, said the crisis
has shown that no country can go it alone on economic policy.

&quot;In the 21st century, there it is no longer a single nation who can
say what we should do or what we should think,&quot; he said.
[...]

Sarkozy blamed financial speculators for encouraging a system
fueled on debt. He called financial capitalism based on speculation
&quot;an immoral system&quot; that has &quot;perverted the logic of
capitalism.&quot;

&quot;It&apos;s a system where wealth goes to the wealthy, where work is
devalued, where production is devalued, where entrepreneurial
spirit is devalued,&quot; he said.

But no more: &quot;In capitalism of the 21st century, there is room for
the state,&quot; he said.
 
As there was in the capitalism of the 20th century, too, but
never mind the details: Burn the
speculators !

Here&apos;s how the Irish Times&apos; Lara Marlowe summed up Sarko&apos;s noisy and interesting year:
 
The financial crisis fostered the spectacular conversion of
Sarkozy from Reaganomics - one of his campaign slogans was &quot;less
government, less taxes&quot; - to state intervention on a massive scale.
After claiming, pre-crisis, that government coffers were empty,
Sarkozy found 320 billion [Euros] to guarantee interbank loans, and
up to 40 billion [Euros] to recapitalise French banks. On December
4th, he announced a 26 billion[-Euro] economic stimulus package
that will drive France&apos;s budget deficit to 4 per cent of GDP in
2009.

The authoritarian drift in domestic policy created concern for
civil liberties. A new law will enable the state to continue to
imprison sexual offenders after they have completed prison
sentences. Former justice minister Robert Badinter called this &quot;a
dark period for our justice system&quot; and noted that &quot;a person will
be locked up not for things he has done, but for things he might
do...&quot; [...]

The number of French people taken into custody doubled from 300,000
in 2001 to 600,000 in 2007, and the police give the impression they
are out of control. In November, nine young people were arrested on
trumped up charges of &quot;terrorism&quot; in a small rural village.
Gendarmes used a sniffer dog and body searches to look for drugs in
a classroom of 13 year-olds, and a former newspaper director was
taken in handcuffs from his home, stripped and subjected to two
rectal searches because a businessman with a fraud conviction
accused his newspaper of defamation.
 
 Permalink | 20 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 TARP Ain&apos;t Nothing But Crap Mispelled. Or, Where Did the Money Go? 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 8:17AM | Nick Gillespie 

A panel charged with overseeing the Troubled Asset Relief
Program (TARP) is whacking the program&apos;s administrators like a
soggy pinata: You keep hitting the thing, but it never quite offers
up what you really want from the thing. From a report that is
invariably described as &quot;scathing&quot; comes this sort of info:
 
The report noted that the Treasury Department initially said
that it would invest funds in &quot;healthy&quot; banks, naming Citigroup
among them and providing the bank with $25 billion. But less than a
month later, Treasury gave Citi $20 billion in additional financing
&quot;apparently to avoid systemic failure.&quot; ...

Though TARP originally was conceived as a bank rescue plan, the
dozens of companies that have received preliminary or full approval
for TARP funds include the credit card company American Express and
insurance giant AIG.

The panel said that Treasury should &quot;clearly identify the types
of institutions it believes fall under the purview&quot; of the rescue
package.

&quot;The question is how the infusion of billions of dollars to an
insurance conglomerate or a credit card company advances both the
goal of financial stability and the well-being of taxpayers,
including homeowners threatened by foreclosure, people losing their
jobs and families unable to pay their credit cards,&quot; the report
said.
 
 More here .

A massive government program that was hastily created in a
couple of weeks time (tops) is doing a poor job? Or doesn&apos;t even
know what its job actually is? And can&apos;t answer questions properly
to its oversight body? Say it ain&apos;t so, Joe!

It&apos;s a good thing that there&apos;s a new sheriff in town, who is
going to fix all this profligate and obscure funding with the
&quot; wisdom and
discipline &quot; the situation calls for. Wow, we sure dodged a
bullet there, especially with an $800 billion (or whatever)
stimulus package on the launchpad.

 Reason Foundation on the
bailout(s) here .

 Permalink | 19 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 We Are Officially a Sub-Prime Nation 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 7:55AM | Matt Welch 

That is, according to the FICO-score calculators over at the Credit
Loan blog .
 
If Uncle Sam wanted to buy a house, he would get a rate of
7.836% for a 30 Year Fixed rate.
 
The main downward pressure our credit rating?
 
[T]he government owes almost four times its yearly take. Compare
that to your own debt level and you can see why this looks
insurmountable.
 
Link via Instapundit .
 
 Permalink | 18 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Friday Funnies 

 Posted on January 9, 2009, 7:00AM 

 In the latest
edition of Friday Funnies, Scott Stantis predicts the impact of
President-elect Obama&apos;s stimulus plan. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Everyone Celebrate Stimulus Thursday! 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 8:04PM | Brian Doherty 

I know, I know...in Obama&apos;s America, every day is stimulus
day ! But let us contemplate these two bits of stimulusiana on
a fine Thursday afternoon:

*Bryan Caplan seems to endorse this temporary stimulus idea: states
stop collecting sales taxes with a federal guarantee to make good
the income difference for them out of its coffers. Isn&apos;t this in
effect like a federal tax cut? Not exactly, he thinks:
 
...in a world with inflexible prices and wages, intertemporal
substitution ramps up the effect of a sales tax cut, but not an
income tax cut. What&apos;s the difference? When sales taxes are
temporarily low, people have an incentive to buy more now.
With inflexible prices, this intertemporal substitution diminishes
the surplus in the goods market. Income tax cuts, in contrast,
encourage people to work more now - exacerbating the
surplus in the labor market.
 
As a proposal in an imperfect world in which I&apos;d rather
government not take any concerted action to manipulate our behavior
but they are dead set on it, this strikes me on first couple of
thoughts as not a terrible idea. (Yes, in the long term, where are
the Feds getting this money they are rebating to the states? But
where are they getting any of the money for any of the crazy crap
they&apos;ll be doing in the next four years?)

*Also Caplan&apos;s partner at the EconLog blog, economist David
Henderson, is in Forbes explaining how the professional work of Obama&apos;s candidate for
chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, Christina Romer, seems
to indicate that attempts to obviate grim economic cycles (such as
the one we are now in) with federal fiscal stimulus measures of the
sort Obama wants to initiate, whether on the tax or spending end,
have a spotty history:
 
Tax changes intended to offset the business cycle, though,
aren&apos;t so effective. The Romers [Christina and husband David]
write, &quot;[C]ountercyclical fiscal policy is not achieving its
intended purpose.&quot; Why? &quot;[I]t is difficult for fiscal policy to
respond quickly to economic developments.&quot; The two largest
countercyclical tax changes between 1947 and 2005 were Lyndon
Johnson&apos;s 10% surcharge on income taxes ,
implemented to &quot;cool off&quot; the economy, and Gerald Ford&apos;s 1975 tax
rebate, implemented to boost the economy.

The Romers point out that the surcharge was first proposed in
January 1967 but wasn&apos;t passed until June 1968. And, although the
1975 tax rebate was passed within three months of being proposed,
they note that it was not proposed until 14 months into the 1973-75
recession. They could have noted that the recession ended in March
1975, the same month the rebate was proposed and three months
before it was passed.
Changes in government spending to offset the business cycle are
also fiscal policy, and they have the same problem. We are well
into the recession, we don&apos;t know how long it will last and we
won&apos;t get an actual &quot;stimulus&quot; bill signed before February at the
earliest. Even the pessimistic Federal
Reserve is predicting a recovery beginning in the second half of
2009 . 
I wrote
about some Romer research about the effect of tax cuts in the
February 2008 issue of Reason magazine.

 Permalink | 36 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Murder in Oakland 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 6:02PM | Michael C. Moynihan 

There is no other conclusion to draw from the video embedded
below, filmed by a San Francisco subway passenger, other than the
blindingly obvious one: Oscar Grant, the 22-year-old butcher&apos;s
apprentice shot by Bay Area Rapid Transit Police (BART) on New
Year&apos;s day, was murdered. Face down on the ground, handcuffed, and
unarmed, BART officer Johannes Mehserle unholsters his service
weapon and fires a single shot into Grant&apos;s back. The New York
Times has details .
 
The killing of Grant precipitated protests and rioting in
Oakland last night, with many using the tragedy as a pretext for
looting. The San Francisco Chronicle filed this odd story from across the Bay, advising the rioters to at least
target white people. Or something:
 
The roving mob expressed fury at police and frustration over
society&apos;s racial injustice. Yet the demonstrators were often
indiscriminate, frequently targeting the businesses and prized
possessions of people of color.
 
Wait, would targeting non-black-owned business have been more
&quot;discriminate?&quot;
 
The mob smashed the windows at Creative African Braids on 14th
Street, and a woman walked out of the shop holding a baby in her
arms.

&quot;This is our business,&quot; shouted Leemu Topka, the black owner of
the salon she four years ago. &quot;This is our shop. This is what you
call a protest?&quot; Wednesday night&apos;s vandalism victims had nothing to
do with the shooting death by a BART police officer of Oscar Grant
on New Year&apos;s Day - but that did little to sway the mob.
 
Full Chronicle story here .

 Update: In a fit of outrage, I neglected to
mention that Brian Doherty blogged the BART murder here. 

 Permalink | 296 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Zombie Corporations Love to Eat Maaaaaaarkets! 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 5:56PM | Katherine Mangu-Ward 

 Occasional Reason contributor Todd Seavey finds some rhetorical
silver lining in the bailout cloud:
 
On the bright side, rhetorically, I have to love the fact that
the term “zombies” has been used in recent months for propped-up,
government-subsidized, bailed-out firms that aren’t really
functional. Clearly, this highly pejorative term was not
focus-grouped by government spin teams. It’s simply too
accurate—and well-timed, since this is a month of the undead at the
cinema (witness the abominable and David Goyer-discrediting The
Unborn , as well as the vampire movies Let the Right One
In , Twilight , and Underworld: Rise of the
Lycans , this last being the story of an actress named Kate
Beckinsale being replaced by an eerie duplicate named Rhona Mitra —
and in the more distant future lies the apocalyptic all-out zombie armageddon film World
War Z , from the director of Quantum of Solace and
the writer of Babylon 5 and The Changeling ).

I wonder, though — to touch on a major
controversy among horror nerds — will these “zombies” be the
fast-moving kind or the slow-moving kind? I suspect they will start
out fast and get slower and slower, and stupider and stupider.
 
Seavey is celebrating a Month of Liberty (i.e. Property) on his
blog, as a way to recover from his Month of Feminism in December.
Head over and enjoy the archives.

More Reason on zombies here .

 Permalink | 46 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Police Shoot Minor League Baseball Pitcher Near Houston 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 5:50PM | Radley Balko 
 
 This
doesn&apos;t look good :
 
It was 2 a.m. on December 31 when [Robbie] Tolan and his cousin,
Anthony Cooper, were confronted in the driveway of their home by
Bellaire, Texas, police officers. Police officials say the officers
suspected the two young men were driving a stolen car.

Bellaire is a prominent, mostly white suburb in southwest
Houston.

[...]

Tolan’s relatives say the two young men had just arrived from a
late-night run to a Jack-in-the-Box fast food restaurant.

As they walked up the driveway to their home, Anthony Cooper
said an unidentified man emerged from the darkness with a
flashlight and a gun pointed at them.

“We did not know it was a police officer,” said Cooper. “He
said, ‘Stop. Stop.’ And we were like, ‘Why? Who are you?’”

The officers ordered both men to lie down on the ground. Tolan’s
parents heard the commotion and came outside. Police will only say
an “altercation” took place. Tolan’s family say it involved his
mother.

“The cop pushed her against the wall,” said Tolan’s uncle, Mike
Morris.

Relatives say Tolan started to lean up from the ground to ask
the officer what he was doing to his mother. That’s when the family
says Tolan was shot in the chest, the bullet piercing his lung and
then lodging in his liver.

But Tolan’s SUV wasn’t stolen. Both men were unarmed and
relatives say they were hardly a threat to the police officer.
 
Tolan happens to be the son of a former major league baseball
player, and is in the early stages of his own pro baseball career.
The police department initially denied racial profiling played a
role, but has now stopped talking about the case publicly, saying
only that “they’re investigating how the officers on the scene
mistakenly determined that the SUV Tolan and his cousin were
driving had been stolen.”

Even if there had been an SUV reported stolen that night that
looked like the one Tolan’s cousin was driving, you first have to
wonder why the cops wouldn’t run the plates before ordering
everyone out of the truck at gunpoint. And that’s before you start
looking at the shooting, and the confrontation with Tolan’s
mother.

If there wasn’t an SUV reported stolen that resembled
the one Tolan was in, this is going to get really, really ugly.
 
 Permalink | 35 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Matt Welch on Bailing Out Failing Newspapers 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 3:00PM 

What&apos;s black and white and red all over? Newspapers looking for
a handout, that&apos;s what! Matt Welch says that if print journalists
have anything to say about it, we shall be hearing much more about
a potential bailout of failing newspapers.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Big Corn Muscles Aside Solar, Wind and Geothermal Subsidies 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 2:25PM | Ronald Bailey 

The Environmental Working Group has just issued a report that
finds that 75 percent of all renewable fuels tax subsidies in 2007
went to environmentally damaging corn-ethanol production. In
addition, the corn ethanol industry, teetering on the edge of
collapse despite billions already wasted in subsidies on it, now
wants additional billions for a bailout. According to EWG:
 
A little noticed analysis buried in an April 2008 report from
the federal Energy Information Administration (EIA) 1 shows that the corn-based ethanol industry received $3 billion in
tax credits in 2007, more than four times the $690 million in
credits available to companies trying to expand all other forms of
renewable energy, including solar, wind and geothermal power.
 
In the EWG press release, report author and EWG Midwest Vice
President Craig Cox says:
 
&quot;With America facing an exploding federal deficit and the crisis
of climate change, it defies common sense to continue to lavish
billions of tax dollars on corn-based ethanol, a fuel that has
failed to fulfill its promises at every turn.&quot;

&quot;Corn-based ethanol production, spurred by federal subsidies and
mandates, is polluting our nation&apos;s water, eroding our soil and
plowing up precious wildlife habitat -- and worst of all is likely
contributing to global warming,&quot; Cox said. &quot;As the polluting
ethanol industry gets fat at taxpayer expense, proven clean
technologies such as solar, wind and geothermal are fighting for
support. America needs a truly renewable energy portfolio, and the
evidence is mounting that corn-based ethanol will not get us where
we need to go.&quot;
 
Of course, Reason.com has been inveighing against ethanol subsidies for years. But right on EWG! Hmmm. I wonder how
EWG knows that the renewable energy sources its wants to subsidize
won&apos;t have similar unintended consequences. Oh, never mind.

Whole EWG report here . Reason TV&apos;s video &quot;Silly
Senator, Corn is for Food,&quot; can be found here .

 Permalink | 88 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 There Are Two Kinds of Libertarians.... 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 12:59PM | Brian Doherty 

....those who think you can divide all libertarians into two
types, and those who don&apos;t.

Joining the former, and previous more or less useful
classifications such as anarchist and minarchist, paleo and cosmo,
utilitarian and natural rightsers, is the division between &quot;policy
libertarians&quot; and &quot;structural libertarians,&quot; explicated by Jacob Lyles over at &quot;Distributed Republic.&quot;

Here is the line of division, Lyles says:
 
Policy Libertarians (PLs) include the vast majority of the most
visible organizations and writers in the modern libertarian
movement: the Reason Foundation, the Cato Institute, the Ron Paul
campaign, the LP, the Constitution Party, most libertarian
economists (e.g. Milton Friedman), and single-issue organizations
like Students for a Sensible Drug Policy. PLs, as their name
suggests, focus their energies on inventing and advocating a list
of policies that governments should follow. For example, you can
find policy libertarians opposing liberal eminent domain laws,
fighting for lower taxes and deregulation, supporting cultural
tolerance, opposing invasive police searches, and advocating the
rest of the familiar libertarian manifesto.

Structural Libertarians (SLs) are much rarer in modern times
than PLs, although the opposite used to be the case. Structural
libertarians include Patri Friedman , Mencius Moldbug , David Friedman, Murray
Rothbard , all libertarian Public Choice economists, Lysander
Spooner, and the classical liberals that libertarians have adopted
as intellectual ancestors. SLs often have the same moral and policy
beliefs as PLs, but they focus their energies on the alternative
ways to structure a government and the effect that government
structure has on its incentive to adopt good policy. At their most
extreme, SLs barely sound like libertarians. Under a market-based
government system (a common SL proposal), the architects of
Singapore would likely find plenty of customers for a burbclave
that is incredibly prosperous and clean, but where communists are
sent to jail and litterbugs are viciously beaten with sticks.
 
And he&apos;s taking sides--he thinks &quot;policy libertarians&quot; are naive
and largely useless given the structural incentives of modern
democracy.

 Reason magazine contributor and
economist Bryan Caplan has some
thoughts questioning the validity of the division Lyles
sees:
 
 ...institutions themselves are a kind of policy . They
arise because previous institutions create incentives for change,
and endure because current institutions create incentives for
stability. Or as we economists like to say, &quot;Institutions are
endogenous.&quot;
 
I remain a gooey ecumenicist when it comes to libertarian
activism and agitation, who thinks that the currents of social
change are often too chaotic to usefully model, predict, or manage,
and that every attempt using whatever strategy or technique to
create policy and ideological change in the direction of fewer
decisions in the human social world being made under threat of
violence deserve to be pursued in the great division of political
labor--presuming that some libertarian activist chooses to pursue
it.

Undoubtedly, as in any market, there will be plenty of efforts
exerted that prove ex post to have been misguided, but it&apos;s hard to
know that before hand--and sometimes efforts at ideological and
political change are consumption goods anyway.

This is not to say such taxonomic divisions and side-taking in
libertarianism are useless or to be condemned--just that I think
whatever such divisions you can create, it is quite likely that
libertarians on either side are doing good things to help bring
about a more libertarian world, even if that merely means
convincing one more person that we should live in such a
world.

 Permalink | 135 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Nudged 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 12:41PM | Radley Balko 

All hail the rise of &quot;soft paternalism:&quot; 
 
The incoming administration of President-elect Barack Obama will
name Cass Sunstein, a Harvard Law School professor who pioneered
efforts to design regulation around the ways people behave, as
regulatory czar, the Wall Street Journal reported.

A report on WSJ.com said Sunstein would head the White House
Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, overseeing
&quot;regulations throughout the government, from the Environmental
Protection Agency to the Occupational Safety and Health
Administration.&quot;
 
Will Wilkinson slapped around
Sunstein&apos;s Nudge in our October 2008 issue.

 Permalink | 68 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Washington Metro Area Transit Authority Goes After Flex Your Rights 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 12:38PM | Mike Riggs 

Back in October, the Washington Metro Area Transit Authority
implemented a shady bag-check policy in order to protect metro
riders from terrorists. (&quot;Shady&quot; because the WMATA did its best to
enact the policy without getting feedback from riders, and because
the policy doubles as a way to boost drug
confiscations ). In response to the new policy, members of Flex Your Rights , a nonprofit that seeks to &quot;teach people to
understand, appreciate, and assert their constitutional rights
during police encounters,&quot; gathered en masse outside the Dupont Circle Metro station near
downtown D.C. and handed out fliers explaining that the bag checks
are voluntary, and that riders who wish to avoid them should
politely decline a search and leave the station.

According to Flex Your Rights&apos; Scott Morgan, the WMATA was irked that Flex Your
Rights used its logo on their fliers without permission , and
promised to sue the group if it didn&apos;t destroy the remaining fliers
and issue a public apology by Jan. 5. It&apos;s now Jan. 8, and Flex
Your Rights has yet to say sorry:
 
The Washington Metro Area Transit Authority (WMATA) has threatened
us with legal action due to our use of Metro&apos;s &quot;M&quot; logo on our informational flyer about refusing random searches. Metro
alleges that our use of the logo on the widely-distributed flyer
constitutes a violation of their registered servicemark and has
promised legal action if we do not destroy all remaining flyers and
issue an apology by January 5th.

The 5th has now passed, and we have no intention of complying
with Metro’s ill-conceived intimidation tactics. We’re well aware
that the 1st Amendment protects &quot;fair use&quot; of trademarked material
for the purpose of criticism. The ACLU of the National
Capital Area has agreed to represent us in the event that Metro
files a lawsuit. Our attorney Art Spitzer contacted
Metro in a letter today, urging that the legal threats against
us be promptly withdrawn to avoid an inevitable loss in court.
 
It&apos;s good to see Flex Your Rights stand up to the WMATA over the
use of the logo, but I would like to point out that fair use isn&apos;t
protected by the First Amendment.

 UPDATE : After a heated (but well-meaning) email
exchange, FYR&apos;s Scott Morgan directed me to an article
entitled &quot;The Interdependency of Fair Use and the First
Amendment,&quot; which effecively explains the connections between the
1976 Copyright Act and the First Amendment. Here&apos;s a rather
lengthy, but fascinating excerpt:
 
The first amendment balances an individual&apos;s right to free
speech against the needs of society; the copyright clause, at base,
balances an individual&apos;s right to control his or her work against
society&apos;s need for access; however, the focus within most copyright
conflicts is between one individual&apos;s economic claim in copyright
against another&apos;s economic claim to use. The result is a common
legal view of copyright as a grant of property to a creator against
a claim to property by a user. The actual policy upon which the
copyright clause is based and which supports public access, fades
from discussion altogether.

To understand the commonalities in the goals of the policies
behind the free speech grant and the copyright clause would lead to
characterization of the copyright statute as regulatory rather than
proprietory in nature, and would eliminate a claim of conflict
between the copyright clause and the constitutional intent of the
first amendment.

Other possible resolutions to this conflict reside in two
aspects of the copyright law: 1) the law restricts access to the
expression of an idea but not to the idea itself, and 2)
application of fair use. But the idea/expression dichotomy fails to
protect public access to information. Particularly with the
ubiquity of digitized information, the access that would be allowed
to ideas is limited. Digitized communication often merges the form
of expression of the idea with the idea itself, so that the idea
cannot be extracted from its protected form. The copyright law was
developed at a time when technology had not yet advanced to a level
at which it was common for ideas and expressions to become so
intermingled that public access is hindered. We can no longer rely
on the idea/expression dichotomy established by the copyright law
to ensure the advancement of learning and knowledge creation. Fair
use, then, becomes of utmost importance for protecting the public&apos;s
right to information when the idea/expression dichotomy ceases to
function as an assurance of protection for first amendment
values.

Some legal scholars argue that a first amendment exception
should be applied when the idea/ expression dichotomy fails to
support the policies that ensure public access to information; but
the first amendment exception is neither established law nor is it
often applied by adjudicators. Fair use, then, is the only
assurance of access to the information that forms the basis of free
speech.
 
See below for a short, safe-for-work video documenting Flex Your
Rights&apos; activities at the Dupont Circle Metro (shot and edited by
yours truly):
 
 Permalink | 32 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Obama: Let&apos;s Get the Spending Party Started 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 12:10PM | Nick Gillespie 

 The text of Obama&apos;s
major economic address, delivered live earlier today, has been
posted. Read it and weep here .

The short version: We&apos;re gonna spend like there&apos;s no tomorrow.
Because if the government doesn&apos;t spend enough right now,
there ain&apos;t gonna be no tomorrow.

Highlights include generic shout-outs to massive spending and
then a steaming pile of feel-good slogans such as these:
 
We will modernize more than 75% of federal buildings
and improve the energy efficiency of two million American homes,
saving consumers and taxpayers billions on our energy bills. In the
process, we will put Americans to work in new jobs that pay well
and can&apos;t be outsourced - jobs building solar panels and wind
turbines; constructing fuel-efficient cars and buildings; and
developing the new energy technologies that will lead to even more
jobs, more savings, and a cleaner, safer planet in the
bargain....

[W]e will make the immediate investments necessary to
ensure that within five years, all of America&apos;s medical records are
computerized....

We&apos;ll provide new computers, new technology, and new
training for teachers so that students in Chicago and Boston can
compete with kids in Beijing for the high-tech, high-wage jobs of
the future....

We&apos;ll put people to work repairing crumbling roads,
bridges, and schools by eliminating the backlog of well-planned,
worthy and needed infrastructure projects. But we&apos;ll also do more
to retrofit America for a global economy. That means updating the
way we get our electricity by starting to build a new smart grid
that will save us money, protect our power sources from blackout or
attack, and deliver clean, alternative forms of energy to every
corner of our nation. It means expanding broadband lines across
America, so that a small business in a rural town can connect and
compete with their counterparts anywhere in the world.
 
Wow, that&apos;s change everyone can believe in! We&apos;re
going to put people to work computerizing medical records, changing
lightbulbs, turning wind turbines, you name it. The whole thing,
featuring various exhortations to not delay (&quot;We could lose a
generation of potential and promise&quot;) in passing even more spending
bills, is here .

How did we get here? Obama calls out the
following:
 
Too many Wall Street executives made imprudent and
dangerous decisions, seeking profits with too little regard for
risk, too little regulatory scrutiny, and too little
accountability. Banks made loans without concern for whether
borrowers could repay them, and some borrowers took advantage of
cheap credit to take on debt they couldn&apos;t afford. Politicians
spent taxpayer money without wisdom or discipline, and too often
focused on scoring political points instead of the problems they
were sent here to solve. The result has been a devastating loss of
trust and confidence in our economy, our financial markets, and our
government.
 
That&apos;s all true, though it&apos;s really important to
underscore that by implicitly and explicitly guaranteeing market
losses for homeowners and investors, the government radically
alters the ways in which people behave. And sets up precisely the
next big tumble. The losses surrounding Bernie Madoff involve
mostly the fat-cat shitheads who invested with him; we&apos;re unlikely
to socialize those bad choices.

On the point of &quot;the devastating loss of trust and
confidence,&quot; I direct Hit&amp;Run readers&apos; attention once again to a
terrfying-if-true working paper titled &quot;Regulation and Distrust,&quot;
by Philippe Aghion, Yann Algan, Pierre Cahuc, and Andrei Shleifer.
The authors argue:
 
&quot;Distrust influences not just regulation itself, but
the demand for regulation. Using the World Values Survey, we show
both in a cross-section of countries, and in a sample of
individuals from around the world, that distrust fuels support for
government control over the economy. What is perhaps most
interesting about this finding...is that distrust generates demand
for regulation even when people realize that the government is
corrupt and ineffective.&quot;
 
 Read the whole thing here . And despair.

 Reason Foundation
on the bailout(s). 



 Permalink | 78 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Alexander Zaitchik on How Treacherous Border Crossing Became a Theme Park 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 12:00PM 

 From our
February issue, Alexander Zaitchik reports from Mexico&apos;s Alberto
Eco Park, where middle class Mexicans and European and American
tourists pay to experience a simulated &quot;border crossing,&quot; complete
with verbally abusive border guards, harsh physical conditions, and
horrifying screams in the dark.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 There&apos;s No Fat Left to Cut! Pass the Pork Rinds! 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 11:51AM | Matt Welch 

For those (few?) aficionados of long-form (of course!) alternative weekly
pissing contests , this j&apos;accuse by L.A. lefty Marc Cooper aimed at the newish owners of the LA
Weekly is something to behold. I know and have worked with
many of the players involved, including Cooper, so I&apos;ll stay out of
the fray, but I was struck by this bit of throat-clearing at the
top:
 
I was so turned off by what I saw happening that I visited my
Weekly office exactly three times in the last two years, mostly to
pick up accumulated checks in my mailbox. During election week in
November, I was given a layoff notice with a generous
settlement.

They had lost interest in me and I was too expensive. With very
few exceptions, I had long lost interest in them, too. It was a
miracle, in fact, that I had lasted the two years since New Times
took over the Weekly.
 
Maybe I&apos;ve just got too much management on the brain, but I
always find it striking when journalists who confess to mailing it
in then turn around and bitch about cost-cutting from the evil
owners. There&apos;s no fat left to cut! I am very expensive and
under-motivated!

Most newsroom bosses, in fact, more or less agree; here&apos;s new
editor Monty Cook of the admittedly beleaguered Baltimore
Sun saying something that would turn my ears purple if I was signing his
paychecks:
 
&quot;I told our staff a few days ago that they will never hear me
utter the phrase &apos;We must do more with less.&apos;&quot;
 
 Permalink | 33 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reason Writers Around the Ether 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 11:30AM 

Managing Editor Jesse Walker&apos;s weekly freeform radio show, Titicut Follies , will be broadcast on WCBN-FM this
afternoon from 12 to 3, eastern time. If you live in the Ann
Arbor/Ypsilanti area, you can tune in at 88.3 FM; if you live
elsewhere, you can listen online .

For more information about the show, go here .

 Permalink | 5 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 &quot;One day we&apos;ll be an absolutely smoke-free world&quot; 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 10:36AM | Matt Welch 

The city of Los Angeles is seemingly on the verge of banning smoking from the outdoor patios of restaurants on
grounds of...well who the hell knows anymore?
 
The measure&apos;s sponsor, Councilman Greig Smith, said he wrote the
legislation after noticing that California&apos;s ban on smoking inside
restaurants was driving smokers just outside the establishments&apos;
doors, exposing children and other patrons to secondhand smoke as
they entered the venue or waited for tables.
 
Note: One of the last L.A. public spaces you can still smoke in
is your local municipal golf course. Beause, after all, the city
would make less money if its customers couldn&apos;t enjoy the cigars
that are readily available at the city-owned golf course
kiosks....

I&apos;m neither smoker nor scientist nor fan of cigarette companies,
but the only place I&apos;ve ever felt the presence of second-hand smoke
outside–i.e., that place where there IS NO ROOF–is when the smoking
patio of my favorite neighborhood margarita-dispenser enveloped
itself in an airtight plastic condom for warmth. To which we had a
shockingly radical solution: Leave, and let the friendly owners
know that we wouldn&apos;t come back until the covering was gone. No
individual liberties were sacrificed in the process.

Still, as depressingly inevitable as this news is, it&apos;s
heartening to see some residents of my former neighborhood raise a
hackle or two:
 
Outside Cafe Tropical in Silver Lake on Wednesday evening,
smoker Omar Montes said he worried the City Council was going too
far.

&quot;When you get into the government telling you what to do outdoors,
I worry about that,&quot; said Montes, a 43-year-old computer systems
technician. &quot;I understand the health reasons for it.... But for me
it&apos;s about Big Brother. How far is it going to go? You can&apos;t text
[while driving], you can&apos;t talk on the phone. I mean c&apos;mon.&quot;

A smoker in the upstairs Biergarten at Silver Lake&apos;s Red Lion Inn
predicted that the council would face strong opposition from
smokers.

&quot;We have already been penalized and prosecuted as smokers in the
last five, 10 years or so,&quot; said Matthew Tolmachoff, a 38-year-old
biotech equipment salesman. &quot;If it&apos;s your choice that you want to
kill yourself smoking a cigarette, you should at least be able to
have a drink to go along with that.&quot;
 
 Reason asking &quot;How far will smoking bans go?&quot; here .

 Permalink | 21 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Green Car Mirage 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 10:30AM | Ronald Bailey 

Pete Geddes, executive director of the Foundation for Research
on Economics and the Environment (FREE), has a sharp column
explaining &quot;The Inconvenient Truth About Cars.&quot;
 
U.S. energy policy is best described as “keep it cheap.” It’s
ironic that our political class is berating the Big Three for
building the vehicles Americans bought in response. Congress is now
poised to mandate that Detroit manufacture electric and hybrid
vehicles. This approach is bound to fail, for these are cars
consumers (a) don’t want and (b) even if they did, can’t afford.
The recent plunge in the price of gas at the pump has not helped.
November sales of hybrid cars fell 50 percent. U.S. hybrid sales
are now back where they were in 2005. (Ford’s best selling product
in November was the F-150 pickup.) Only when electric and hybrid
vehicles really do provide more value to consumers than the
alternatives will they succeed.

There is a straightforward way to transition the U.S. auto fleet
to a greener future. Place a gradual tax on gasoline such that in
five years it reaches a floor of $5 per gallon. Nothing else will
work, certainly not the Rube Goldberg approach Congress has taken
since the 1970s, best exemplified by the Corporate Average Fleet
Economy (CAFÉ) standards.

In a masterstroke of special-interest politics, the UAW used
CAFÉ’s “two fleet” rule to forbid Detroit from importing smaller
cars from its foreign operations. Forced to build small cars in
domestic plants, with above market labor costs, Detroit could not
make a profit. (In 2007, Toyota made 9.37 million vehicles and GM
about the same. Toyota made a profit of about $1,874 per car, while
GM lost $4,055.) Even Japanese and European carmakers rely on
sedans with moderate fuel economy for profits. Small,
super-efficient cars remain a niche product. Here’s an inconvenient
truth: forcing Detroit to build fuel-efficient cars in UAW
factories is inconsistent with viable, sustainable
manufacturing.

Critics often portray the Detroit automakers as “greedy,
short-sighted profit seekers.” To claim Detroit is refusing to sell
cars consumers “really” want, compared with the cars they actually
purchase, is a stretch. Is there a simpler explanation? Perhaps
alternative cars are simply not ready for prime time?

The Financial Times reports on a French government
study that analyzed the options for building cleaner, more
fuel-efficient cars by 2030. After reviewing a leaked copy, the FT
notes: “It [the report] concludes...there is not much future
in...all electric-powered cars. Instead, ...the traditional
combustion engine powered by petrol, diesel, ethanol or new
biofuels...offers the most realistic prospect of developing cleaner
vehicles. ... {T}he overall cost of an all-electric car is unviable
at around double that of a conventional vehicle. Battery
technology...still...severely limits performance both in terms of
range and speed.”

The Wall Street Journal’s Holman Jenkins’ coverage of this issue
nails it: “Ford and GM in Europe successfully sell cars that are
small, but not cheap. Europeans are willing to pay top dollar for a
refined small car that gets excellent mileage, because they face
gasoline prices as high as $9. … In the U.S., except during bouts
of high gas prices or in the grip of a Prius fad, the small cars
that American consumers buy aren’t bought for high mileage, but for
low sticker prices. And the Big Three, with their high labor costs,
cannot deliver as much value in a cheap car…. {Legislators] won&apos;t
repeal CAFE because they fear the greens. They won&apos;t repeal CAFÉ’s
“two fleet” rule...because they fear the UAW. They won’t hike gas
prices because they fear voters.”
 
It should be noted that most auto industry observers believe
that Toyota has never made a profit on its Prius hybrid.
President-elect Obama has promised to put 1 million
plug-in hybrids on American roads by 2015.  How? By
bribing consumers with a $7,000 tax credit for each car. Since
there are about 250 million passenger vehicles in the U.S., that
would mean that such hybrids would total less than one half of a
percent of the cars on American roads.

Whole Geddes column here .

 Disclosure: I have had the happy experience of having FREE
pay my travel expenses several times to participate in the
organization&apos;s superb conferences. 

 Permalink | 156 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 HackWatch: Nancy Pelosi 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 10:18AM | Radley Balko 

 Nancy Pelosi in 2004 :
 
House Democrats&apos; anger at heavy-handed Republican tactics
reached a new level yesterday, with the chamber&apos;s top Democrat
asking the House speaker to embrace a &quot;Bill of Rights&quot; for the
minority, regardless which party it is.

[...]

Pelosi&apos;s document, which she vows to honor if Democrats regain
the majority, says: &quot;Too often, incivility and the heavy hand of
the majority&quot; have silenced Democrats and choked off &quot;thoughtful
debate.&quot; She called on the majority to let the minority offer
meaningful amendments and substitutes to important bills; to limit
roll-call votes to the normal 15 minutes rather than keeping them
open to round up needed votes; and to let all appointees to
House-Senate conference committees participate in meetings and
decisions.

&quot;When we are shut out, they are shutting out the great diversity
of America,&quot; Pelosi said in an interview. &quot;We want a return to
civility; we want to set a higher standard.&quot;

[...]

Democrats and several analysts say recommital votes are largely
meaningless. Hastert&apos;s leadership team portrays them as &quot;procedural
votes&quot; rather than matters of policy, and unwritten parliamentary
rules make it essentially treasonous for lawmakers to vote against
their party&apos;s leadership on procedural matters.
The inevitable party-line vote that keeps Democrats from
recommitting a Republican bill &quot;is the whole ballgame,&quot; Ornstein
said, because it prevents Democrats from having a debate and a vote
on the substance of their alternative proposals. 
 Nancy Pelosi, 2008 :
 
The spirit of bipartisan cooperation didn&apos;t survive the first
day of the 111th Congress as House Democrats pushed through a
package of rule changes Tuesday that the furious Republican
minority said trampled their traditional rights to affect
legislation.

[...]

The most contentious rule change places new restrictions on
motions to &quot;recommit&quot; a bill for new amendments to the committee
that approved it. In practice, that motion often meant a lengthy or
even permanent delay in passing the measure. Motions to recommit
would still be possible, but the new rules allow the full House to
reconsider the bill almost instantaneously.

[...]

Because of the special rules regarding budgetary legislation,
Republicans argued that the new restrictions on motions to recommit
will hobble their ability to challenge tax increases that are
included in larger, &quot;must-pass&quot; bills.

Unlike in the Senate, where the threat of a filibuster gives the
minority strong bargaining leverage, the minority party in the
House has relatively few tools to challenge the majority&apos;s will.
Mr. Dreier noted that the recommit motion had been in place for 100
years, and he rejected Democratic claims that the new rules were a
minor tweak to an obscure parliamentary proceeding.

In Congress, he said, &quot;process is substance.&quot;
 
It&apos;s a somewhat complicated procedural issue, but the bottom
line here is that while Pelosi demanded minority rights and decried
GOP procedural chicanery while her party was in the minority, she&apos;s
starting the new Congress by pushing through rules changes that
would make it much more difficult for Republicans to have any
influence on pending legislation.

Pelosi gets a 7 out of 10 on the somewhat
arbitrary Hackery Index.

HackWatch took on Sen. John Kyl (R-Ariz.) here , and former
White House Office of Legal Counsel honcho John Yoo here . If you
see an example of a pundit, politician, major blogger, or other
Beltway creature who’s done a 180 on this or another issue, please send it to us ,
with links, and “HackWatch” in the subject line.

 Permalink | 44 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reason Writers Around Town: Radley Balko on Keeping Politicians Out of Sports for ESPN 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 9:20AM 

 Over at
ESPNtheMag.com , Radley Balko argues that politicians are the
last people we should be asking to fix college football&apos;s Bowl
Championship Series—or, for that matter, whatever other problems
might be afflicting the sports world.

 Permalink | 16 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Where McGovern Bashing Gets Us 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 9:06AM | Nick Gillespie 

 Writing in The American Conservative , occasional Reason magazine contributor Daniel
McCarthy argues:
 
If Republicans and liberal hawks were correct in calling Obama a
new McGovern, they only succeeded in proving how repellent most
Americans, including many conservatives, find today&apos;s GOP. The
trouble is, instead of the country getting George McGovern—a
temperamental conservative, an anti-militarist, and a committed
decentralist—we&apos;re getting Barack Obama, who dreams of another New
Deal and picked Hillary Clinton as his chief diplomat. Somehow the
neoconservatives and liberal interventionists prevailed again.
 
 Whole story
here .

Bonus: Why pro-labor Dems hate McGovern .

 Permalink | 75 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Obama: &quot;Only government can break the vicious cycles that are crippling our economy&quot; 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 8:26AM | Nick Gillespie 

 Barack
Obama speaketh on the troubles facing the republic:
 
We cannot depend on government alone to create jobs or long-term
growth, but at this particular moment, only government can provide
the short-term boost necessary to lift us from a recession this
deep and severe. Only government can break the vicious cycles that
are crippling our economy—where a lack of spending leads to lost
jobs which leads to even less spending; where an inability to lend
and borrow stops growth and leads to even less credit.
 
 Read more from the president-elect&apos;s remarks that will be aired
later today. &quot;If nothing is done, this recession could linger for
years,&quot; he says. And yes, &quot;the cost of this plan will be
considerable.&quot;

But if people and businesses can&apos;t borrow and spend on terms
disconnected from actual market forces, then how are we going to
get into the next cycle where people and businesses borrow
and spend too much?

You know, the very era that Obama declaimed in a speech late last
year :
 
Politicians spent money they didn&apos;t have. Lenders tricked people
into buying homes they couldn&apos;t afford and some folks knew they
couldn&apos;t afford them and bought them anyway.

We&apos;ve lived through an era of easy money, in which we were
allowed and even encouraged to spend without limits; to borrow
instead of save.
 
As always, the answer to the problems caused by easy money will
be easier money. Now and forever, amen. The important thing is that
we don&apos;t just stand, we do something. I&apos;m about to enter a space
pod timed to wake up in the year 2525 ( if man is still
alive ). Tap on the container earlier when the government
actually announces the crisis is done and public-sector spending
can return to, I don&apos;t know, to the obscene levels pioneered by George W.
Bush .

As you ponder the effect of Obama&apos;s &quot;new New Deal,&quot; think about
the effects of FDR&apos;s:

 

 Permalink | 81 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 LAPD Pressured Coroner to Change Findings in Police Shooting 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 7:48AM | Radley Balko 

 From the L.A. Times: 
 
The Los Angeles Police Department waged an aggressive
behind-the-scenes campaign to convince coroner&apos;s officials to
change their finding that a SWAT officer&apos;s bullet killed a
19-month-old girl held hostage by her father three years ago,
according to records reviewed by The Times.

The intense lobbying effort, which involved one of the
department&apos;s highest-ranking officials, led to significant friction
between the LAPD and coroner&apos;s office. It also raises questions
about whether the LAPD crossed an ethical line in pushing so hard,
some medical and law enforcement experts said.
 
The department rested its case on self-serving conclusions by a
four-year ballistics investigator with no medical training,
challenging a team of experienced medical examiners in the county
coroner&apos;s office.
 
The department tried repeatedly to find a pathologist to review
the case, according to the LAPD&apos;s case log, which shows that Hudson
tried to contact at least eight outside experts. One of the
requests was made to the U.S. military&apos;s pathology institute. When
the institute refused to accept the case, Berkow formally appealed
to the Department of Defense and was turned down again, records
show.

The LAPD&apos;s search led eventually to Dr. William Oliver, a
forensic pathologist at the Georgia Bureau of Investigation. For a
$2,000 consulting fee, Oliver agreed to review the case in the
summer of 2006, according to the LAPD&apos;s internal case log of the
investigation. His conclusions, however, were not what the LAPD
wanted to hear.

&quot;There is little or no good evidence that the wound is from . .
. a handgun,&quot; he wrote.
 
I don&apos;t agree with how often and under what circumstances LAPD
deploys its SWAT team.  But it is worth noting that this
incident aside, they are extremely well-trained, and have a
near-spotless record.

That said, while there&apos;s nothing wrong with seeking an outside
opinion, there&apos;s plenty wrong with pressuring the coroner to change
his findings before seeking an outside opinion. Kudos to
the L.A. county coroner for holding his ground.

 Permalink | 14 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Links on a Thursday Morning 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 7:30AM | Jesse Walker 

* The politics
of poetry in Somalia.

* The Gaza war in Second
Life .

* A &quot;widening generational gap on the Alternative Right.&quot;

* A stimulus package for the Pentagon ?

 Permalink | 9 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Steve Chapman on the Madoff Scandal and the Empty Case for More Regulation 

 Posted on January 8, 2009, 7:00AM 

 The call for
more regulations, writes Steve Chapman, ignores some inconvenient
facts. The first is that con artists will often outfox regulators.
For example, if the SEC couldn&apos;t catch the brazen Bernard Madoff in
eight tries, what suggests we should place greater faith in the
ability of other agencies trying to monitor a vast network of
financial companies?

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Meanwhile, Joe the Plumber Is Heading off to Go Cover the Israel-Hamas War for Pajamas TV 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 6:20PM | Matt Welch 

No, really .

[Link via Wonkette ]

 Permalink | 108 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Man Demands Return of Kidney, Redefines &quot;Messy Divorce&quot; 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 5:02PM | Katherine Mangu-Ward 

A man in from Ronkonkoma, New York, gave his wife a kidney
during their marriage. Now she wants a divorce, and he wants his
kidney back (or $1.5 million in compensation) as part of his
divorce settlement. And you thought your divorce was bad.

Soon-to-be-divorcé and one-kidneyed man Richard Batista probably
won&apos;t get any compensation though, because legally speaking, our
organs have no value. They can be given as gifts, but never bought.
For opponents of organ sales, it would be a dangerous precedent
indeed to set the value of a kidney in divorce proceedings. But
it&apos;s not likely to happen.

From the article :
 
Medical ethicists agreed that the case is a nonstarter. Asked
how likely it would be for the doctor to either get his kidney back
or get money for it, Arthur Caplan at the University of
Pennsylvania&apos;s Center for Bioethics, put it as &quot;somewhere between
impossible and completely impossible.&quot;

First and foremost, said Robert Veatch, a medical ethicist at
Georgetown University&apos;s Kennedy Institute of Ethics, &quot;it&apos;s illegal
for an organ to be exchanged for anything of value.&quot; Organs in the
United States may not be bought or sold. Donating an organ is a
gift and legally &quot;when you give something, you can&apos;t get it back,&quot;
he said.
 
Obviously, actual removal and return of the kidney is not in the
cards, not least because finding a doctor willing to do that kind
of violence to the hippocratic oath would be no easy task. But it&apos;s
pretty clear that the kidney is an asset that Richard brought into
the marriage, no?

Via commenter sixstring

Extra points to the commenter who writes a relevant and
metrically correct limerick which begins, &quot;There once was a man
from Ronkonkoma...&quot;

For lots more on who owns your body parts, read Kerry Howley here and here .

 Permalink | 95 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Too Bad 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 4:35PM | Radley Balko 
 
I can’t say that I blame him, but this is disappointing :
 
Former Ohio State football player Derrick Foster is expected to
plead guilty to felony charges in connection with shooting two
Columbus police officers, 10TV reported Wednesday.

Foster is scheduled to plead guilty to the felony charges on
Friday, 10TV’s Maureen Kocot reported.

The former defensive end, who played at Ohio State
from 1998 to 1992, is expected to serve time in prison as part of
the plea.

The shootings occurred last April during a raid at a
suspected East Rich Street crack house.

Officer Tony Garrison was shot in the arm and
undercover narcotics Officer John Gillis was wounded in the leg,
10TV News reported.

Foster admitted going to the house to gamble and told
investigators he never heard officers identify themselves before
initiating the raid.
 
The house appears to have been a dice/gambling house,
not a &quot;crack house.&quot;  Last I read, no one in the house had
been charged with a drug crime, including Foster. If anyone has, I
haven&apos;t seen it reported in the local media. The raid was the third
raid of the night for that particular Columbus SWAT team.

Foster had no prior criminal record, and in fact had
an exemplary employment record as a code inspector for the city of
Columbus. He also had a legal permit for the gun he used, and has
said he thought the place was being robbed.  When several of
Foster’s friends and acquaintances wrote letters to the judge
vouching for his character, arguing that he wasn’t the kind of
person who would knowingly shoot at a police officer, the police
union initiated an
intimidation campaign against them. 

I’m actually surprised the prosecutors offered him a
plea. It may be an indication that they weren’t confident trying
him on the attempted murder charges.  Shooting at cops
generally isn’t the type of charge for which a DA will cut you a
break.

Still, if Foster was offered a decent deal, you can’t
blame him for taking it.  An attempted murder conviction
against two cops would put him away for a long time.

MORE: The Columbus Dispatch reports that one person in the
house was charged with possession of cocaine.
 
 Permalink | 24 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Bush Really Comes Out for Darwin! 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 4:34PM | Nick Gillespie 

In setting aside a gazillion nautical miles in the Pacific as a
&quot;marine national monument,&quot; outgoing George W. Bush isn&apos;t just
trying to secure an environmentally friendly legacy in the last
days of his failed presidency.

The one-time anti-evolution chief executive is giving Charles
Darwin a big, sloppy wet kiss.

From Bush&apos;s statement &quot; on
the Occasion of the Designation of the Marianas Trench Marine
National Monument, Pacific Remote Islands Marine National Monument,
and the Rose Atoll Marine National Monument &quot;:
 
Baker, Howland, and Jarvis Islands were first formed as fringing
reefs around islands formed by Cretaceous-era volcanoes
(approximately 120-75 million years ago)....

Palmyra Atoll is a classic Darwinian atoll that formed atop a
sinking Cretaceous-era volcano.
 
I realize that Bush didn&apos;t write this statement (or
probably even read it), but I would have loved to have heard him
pronounce the following sentence:
 
&quot;The waters surrounding Baker, Howland, and Jarvis Islands have
fish biomass double that of the Papahânaumokuâkea Marine National
Monument, and 16 times that of the main Hawaiian Islands, due to
the Equatorial Undercurrent that moves from west to east along the
equator, creating localized nutrient-rich upwellings in shallows
next to the islands.&quot;
 
What a difference a few years make!

Back in 2002, Bush said, &quot; On the issue of
evolution, the verdict is still out .&quot; In December 2008, he was
more accomodating, telling ABC&apos;s Nightline , &quot;I think that God created the earth, created
the world; I think the creation of the world is so mysterious it
requires something as large as an almighty and I don&apos;t think it&apos;s
incompatible with the scientific proof that there is
evolution.&quot;

In December, Reason &apos;s Ron Bailey gave reasons to worry
about the new president&apos;s science squad when it came not to
evolution but to the environment. Read about that
here .

 Permalink | 29 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Dave Weigel on Where Libertarian Politics Went Wrong in 2008 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 3:00PM 

 From our
February issue, David Weigel looks back on a thrilling and
dispiriting year in libertarian politics.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Krugman v. Gupta 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 2:21PM | Michael C. Moynihan 

 The New York Times columnist Paul Krugman is unhappy with the Obama administration for offering the job
of surgeon general to Dr. Sanjay Gupta, CNN&apos;s chief medical
correspondent and former Clinton White House policy wonk. According to The Washington Post , Gupta &quot;has also been
offered a top post in the new White House Office of Health Reform,
twin duties that could make him the most influential surgeon
general in history.&quot; That Gupta seems eminently qualified and would
be the highest-ranking Indian-American to serve in the federal
government is of no consequence. Because the TV Doc, says Krugman,
criticized (or as he writes, &quot;mugged&quot;) Michael Moore on CNN by
questioning some of the numbers in his lousy pro-Cuba film Sicko —and made two mistakes in doing so. Here is
Krugman:
 
What bothered me about the incident was that it was what Digby
would call Village behavior: Moore is an outsider, he&apos;s uncouth, so
he gets smeared as unreliable even though he actually got it right.
It&apos;s sort of a minor-league version of the way people who pointed
out in real time that Bush was misleading us into war are to this
day considered less &quot;serious&quot; than people who waited until it was
fashionable to reach that conclusion. And appointing Gupta now,
although it&apos;s a small thing, is just another example of the lack of
accountability that always seems to be the rule when you get things
wrong in a socially acceptable way.
 
There is no need to revisit whether or not Moore &quot;got it right&quot;
in his film or in his counterattacks on Gupta and CNN, but it
should be pointed out that our future surgeon general copped to two
mistakes in his criticism of Sicko . One was the result of
a transcription error ($251 was read as $25), the other was an
incorrect affiliation. Even if Krugman is broadly correct, this is
partisan hackery at its worst: Gupta—a proponent of single-payer
health care, incidentally—should be held &quot;accountable&quot; for
having criticized an incoherent film by a director with a history
of abusing source material?

Also, I recommend a quick read of Gene Epstein&apos;s Econospinning , which
convincingly demonstrates that Krugman (in his role as Times pundit) might want to consider holding himself
&quot;accountable&quot; for his slippery use of source material.

I reviewed Sicko here. 

 Permalink | 74 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 The Nightmare of Legal Immigration 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 1:50PM | Nick Gillespie 

Forget all illegal immigration for a minute. And focus on just
how screwed up the U.S.A&apos;s system for totally legal immigration is. An infuriating testimony from Splice Today&apos;s John
Lingan:
 
In July 2008, we received word that the Department of State
needed another copy of Justyna&apos;s medical forms, the very same ones
we had already filed on two separate occasions. They admitted to
losing it, yet still instructed us to complete the $300 checkup and
documentation procedure ourselves, within 90 days. When I asked our
lawyer whether an appeal could be made, he said of course, but the
process would take longer than 90 days and Justyna&apos;s entire file
would be thrown out after that deadline.

If this sounds like a farce, it is. Here is a woman who has made
the incomparable sacrifices of leaving her home country, her
family, and her friends just to bring her new family together under
one roof. The U.S. should be begging people like Justyna-who holds
a master&apos;s degree and desires only to work legally and pay the
according taxes here-to live and raise their families within our
borders, yet our government makes it humiliating and nearly
impossible for them to do so.
 
 Read the whole thing here .

I&apos;ve yet to meet an immigrant who went through proper channels
who wasn&apos;t embittered by the experience.

 Reason mag&apos;s Editor in Chief Matt Welch spills the
beans on how he&apos;s both broken and been broken by immigration laws
over the years. Read about it
here .

Reason.com has tons of stories on immigration. Read some of them
here .

And watch The Wall Street Journal &apos;s Jason Riley make a
five-minute case for letting them in already:

 

And go to Reason.tv for a longer interview with
Riley .

 Permalink | 72 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 &quot;The death of one man is a tragedy, the death of millions is a statistic.&quot; 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 1:32PM | Ronald Bailey 

That&apos;s what Soviet dictator Joseph Stalin allegedly once said to U.S. ambassador Averill Harriman. And Stalin was an expert on
the topic since his regime killed as many 43 million people. It turns out that the mustachioed murderer
may have been expressing an acute insight into human psychology.
Earlier this week, the Washington Post&apos;s always
interesting Department of Human Behavior columnist Shankar Vedantam
reported on the research of University of Oregon professor Paul
Slovic who looked at how people respond to humanitarian tragedies.
As Vedantam explains:
 
In a rational world, we should care twice as much about a
tragedy affecting 100 people as about one affecting 50. We ought to
care 80,000 times as much when a tragedy involves 4 million lives
rather than 50. But Slovic has proved in experiments that this is
not how the mind works.

When a tragedy claims many lives, we often care less than if a
tragedy claims only a few lives. When there are many victims, we
find it easier to look the other way.

Virtually by definition, the central feature of humanitarian
disasters and genocide is that there are a large number of
victims.

&quot;The first life lost is very precious, but we don&apos;t react very
much to the difference between 88 deaths and 87 deaths,&quot; Slovic
said in an interview. &quot;You don&apos;t feel worse about 88 than you do
about 87.&quot;

Slovic did one experiment shortly after the Rwandan genocide. He
asked volunteers whether they were willing to spend precious
resources getting water to a refugee camp in Zaire, now called
Congo. There were many pressing demands for the money, but Slovic
told the volunteers that the water could save 4,500 lives. Without
the volunteers&apos; awareness, however, the researcher told some people
the refugee camp had 11,000 people while telling others that the
camp had 100,000 people. The number of lives that could be saved
was the same in both cases -- 4,500 -- but Slovic found that people
were reluctant to divert resources to save lives in a large camp
rather than the same number of lives in a small camp.

In another experiment, Slovic asked people to imagine they were
disbursing money on behalf of a large foundation: They could give
$10 million to fight a disease that claimed 20,000 lives a year --
and save 10,000 of those lives. But they could also devote the $10
million to fight a disease that claimed 290,000 lives a year -- and
this investment would save 20,000 lives.

Slovic found that people preferred to spend the money saving the
10,000 lives in the first scenario rather than the 20,000 lives in
the second scenario: &quot;People were responding not to the number of
lives saved but the percentage of lives saved,&quot; he said. In the one
case, their investment could save half the victims; in the case of
the more deadly disease, it could save 7 percent of the
victims.

There are parallels between such behavior and how we perceive
physical sensations, and evolution&apos;s hand in shaping the way we
perceive physical sensations may be behind the errors we make in
judging suffering among our fellow humans. We are sharply aware of
the difference between total darkness and the light thrown off by a
five-watt bulb, but we are hard pressed to tell the lighting
difference between a 90-watt bulb and a 100-watt one.

Slovic said people probably are inappropriately -- and
unconsciously -- using a similar metric in humanitarian crises:
Failing to save only half the victims in a tragedy seems less
dreadful than failing to save 93 percent of the victims of another
tragedy. The mathematical side of our brain could tell us the
absolute number of victims saved is more important than the
percentage of survivors, but our analytical side isn&apos;t usually in
charge.

Slovic has also shown that the amount of compassion humans feel
can diminish as the number of victims increases: In an experiment
in Israel, Slovic asked volunteers whether they would help raise
$300,000 to save eight children who were dying of cancer. Those in
another group were told only about one child with cancer and asked
how much they were willing to donate to save the life of that
child. Slovic found that people were willing to give more money to
save one life than to save eight.

&quot;When we trust our feelings in these cases, we are led down the
path of turning our backs on the suffering of many people,&quot; Slovic
said. &quot;Even though we don&apos;t think of ourselves as uncaring, if we
trust our moral intuition, it is not designed by evolution to
respond accurately to these types of situations of mass
tragedy.&quot;
 
Fascinating. Whole Post article here .

 Permalink | 45 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Aiding Al Qaeda 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 12:59PM | Jesse Walker 

The Gaza war has at least one clear beneficiary, writes Marc
Lynch:
 
Ayman al-Zawahiri has finally weighed in on behalf of al-Qaeda over the Gaza crisis ,
calling it part of the West&apos;s war on Islam and calling on Muslims
everywhere to attack Western and Israeli targets. He sounds about
as happy as I can remember hearing him of late. He probably can&apos;t
believe his luck.

Israel&apos;s assault on Gaza has really created an almost
unbelievable no-lose situation for al-Qaeda. If Hamas &quot;wins&quot;, then
al-Qaeda gets to share in the benefits of the political losses
incurred by its Western and Arab enemies (Zawahiri mentions Mubarak
and the Saudis in this tape, but not the Jordanians) and can try to
take advantage of the political upheavals which could follow. If
Hamas &quot;loses&quot;, al-Qaeda still wins. It will shed no tears at seeing
one of its bitterest and most dangerous rivals take a beating at
Israel&apos;s hands or losing control of a government that they have
consistently decried as illegitimate and misguided. Either way, the
Gaza crisis guarantees that a far more radicalized Islamic world
will face the incoming Obama administration -- potentially severely
blunting the challenge which al-Qaeda clearly felt after the
election (hence Zawahiri&apos;s attempt to pre-emptively discredit Obama
by declaring the attack Obama&apos;s &quot;gift&quot; to Muslims).
 
You should read the whole post . It
goes well beyond the familiar observation that Israel&apos;s attacks
have radicalized Arab opinion, zeroing in on how they&apos;ve affected
intra-Islamist rivalries. E.g.:
 
The way this crisis is playing out shows the bankruptcy and
strategic dangers of trying to simply reduce Hamas to part of an
undifferentiated &quot;global terrorist front&quot;. The Muslim Brotherhood,
from whence Hamas evolved twenty years ago, is no friend of the
United States or Israel but is nevertheless one of al-Qaeda&apos;s fiercest rivals ....Al-Qaeda has long been desperate for a foothold in Palestine , but has been largely
kept out because Hamas has the place locked. Jihadist forums bear a
deep grudge over Hamas&apos;s crackdown on various jihadist groups which have tried to set up
shop there (Jaysh al-Islam, et al)....

Even if Hamas emerges weakened, as Israeli strategists hope, all the better (from al-Qaeda&apos;s point of view, that is). In
general, where the MB is strong (Egypt, Jordan, and Palestine for
example), AQ has had a hard time finding a point of entry despite
serious efforts to do so, while where the MB is weak (Iraq, Saudi
Arabia, Algeria, Lebanon) it has had more success. Up to now, AQ-minded
groups have had little success in penetrating Gaza, because
Hamas had it locked. Now they clearly have high hopes of finding an
entree with a radicalized, devastated population and a weakened
Hamas.
 
 Permalink | 38 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 In the Videotex Graveyard 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 12:30PM | Jesse Walker 

 In a sharp column about media history, Jack
Shafer points out that the newspaper industry did not, as some assume, come late to
the Internet. Indeed, its experiments with electronic distribution
date back to the late &apos;70s. But its approach was cautious, at times
even protectionist; like pre-cable broadcast companies, newspapers
didn&apos;t want any potentially disruptive technology to emerge unless
they could be sure they controlled it. Shafer describes the
results:
 
Newspapers deserve bragging rights for having homesteaded the
Web long before most government agencies and major corporations
knew what a URL was. Given the industry&apos;s early tenancy, deep
pockets, and history of paranoid experimentation with new
communication forms, one would expect to find plenty in the way of
innovations and spinoffs.

But that&apos;s not the case, and I think I know why: From the
beginning, newspapers sought to invent the Web in their own image
by repurposing the copy, values, and temperament found in their
ink-and-paper editions. Despite being early arrivals, despite
having spent millions on manpower and hardware, despite all the
animations, links, videos, databases, and other software tricks
found on their sites, every newspaper Web site is instantly
identifiable as a newspaper Web site. By succeeding, they failed to
invent the Web.
 
 Permalink | 18 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reid Is Backing Down As Fast As He Can 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 12:19PM | Jacob Sullum 

 The Washington Post and The Boston Globe are both reporting that the Senate&apos;s
Democratic leaders, after insisting that no one
appointed by Illinois Gov. Rod Blagojevich would be
allowed to replace Barack Obama, are getting ready to let
Roland Burris take his seat after all. Although Burris was not
seated yesterday, ostensibly because his appointment
papers did not bear the signature of Illinois
Secretary of State Jesse White, Senate Majority Leader
Harry Reid met with him today and signaled that he will
eventually be allowed to serve. The two prerequisites seem to be 1)
a ruling by the Illinois Supreme Court on whether White&apos;s signature
is necessary and, if so, whether he may legally withhold it and 2)
Burris&apos; testimony to the state legislature (which is working
on the governor&apos;s impeachment) about the circumstances of his
appointment. Burris is scheduled to testify tomorrow. &quot;Once that&apos;s
done, we will be in a different position,&quot; said Reid, who
called Burris &quot;very engaging&quot; and &quot;very nice.&quot;

White refused to sign Burris&apos; credentials because he did not
think a governor facing corruption charges should appoint Obama&apos;s
successor, especially since Blagojevich is accused of trying (or at
least hopng) to get something of value in exchange for that
appointment. But White does not seem to have any legal
grounds for withholding his signature, and he now says
it doesn&apos;t matter anyway, telling WGN Radio &quot;they could have seated him without my
signature,&quot; which he called purely &quot;ceremonial.&quot; He confidently
predicted that Burris would be seated. Unless Burris testifies
tomorrow that he bribed Blagojevich to choose him (an allegation no
one has made), it sounds like he could be seated in a matter of
days.

That&apos;s the right decision, since it&apos;s the one required by law.
But by announcing that Burris would be barred from the Senate as a
matter of principle and quickly giving in, Reid and his allies look
like the spineless, shifty hacks they are. By trying to avoid
the embarrassment of serving with a man appointed by a fellow
Democrat accused of corruption, they have only magnified their
humiliation.

On Monday I noted that Reid
was getting ready to give in. Last week I said Reid never should have tried to
keep Burris out. In a recent column , Steve Chapman concurred.

 Permalink | 60 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Some Questions for Eric Holder 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 12:12PM | Damon W. Root 

 The Legal Times reports that Sen. Arlen Specter (R-Pa.)
is gearing up for next week&apos;s confirmation hearing for Attorney
General-designate Eric Holder:
 
In a speech on the Senate floor Tuesday, Specter, R-Pa., said he
plans to focus his inquiry on three areas: the pardon of fugitive
commodities trader Marc Rich; the decision by Holder&apos;s then-boss
Attorney General Janet Reno not to appoint a special prosecutor to
look into Vice President Al Gore&apos;s 1996 fundraising activities; and
the clemency granted to a group of Puerto Rican nationalists.

&quot;All of these matters relate to judgment,&quot; Specter said. &quot;They
relate to whether Mr. Holder had the kind of resoluteness displayed
by Attorney General Griffin Bell, by Attorney General Elliot
Richardson, to say &apos;no&apos; to their superiors.&quot;

Specter also said he plans to ask Holder his views on
journalists&apos; privilege, the Bush administration&apos;s surveillance
policies and the Justice Department&apos;s evolving view of
corporations&apos; attorney-client privilege.
 
A few questions about the Second
Amendment wouldn&apos;t be a bad idea either.

 Whole thing
here. 

 Permalink | 12 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Ron Bailey Interviews Science Writer Matt Ridley 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 12:00PM 

 From our
February issue, Science Correspondent Ronald Bailey discusses the
causes of poverty and prosperity with Genome and Nature via Nurture author Matt Ridley.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 It&apos;s Getting Hard for the Porn Industry 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 11:32AM | Radley Balko 

 TMZ reports that porn moguls Joe Francis and Larry Flynt are
asking the government for a $5 billion bailout, citing a 22 percent
drop in DVD sales last year.

I&apos;d guess that has more to do with the abundance of free porn on
the Internet than the credit crunch.

In any case, I will now take this opportunity to open the
comments section to bad puns incorporating pornography and
Congressional bailouts.

 Permalink | 57 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 The Wall Street Journal Contributes to a Possible Torture &quot;Truth Commission&quot; 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 11:26AM | Brian Doherty 

 The Wall Street Journal points
out that some Congress members are also complicit in
pre-knowledge of possibly criminal torture policies of the Bush
administration:
 
Beginning in 2002, Nancy Pelosi and other key Democrats (as well
as Republicans) on the House and Senate Intelligence Committees
were thoroughly, and repeatedly, briefed on the CIA&apos;s covert
antiterror interrogation programs. They did nothing to stop such
activities, when they weren&apos;t fully sanctioning them. If they now
decide the tactics they heard about then amount to abuse, then by
their own logic they themselves are complicit. Let&apos;s review the
history the political class would prefer to forget.

According to our sources and media reports we&apos;ve corroborated,
the classified briefings began in the spring of 2002 and dealt with
the interrogation of Abu Zubaydah, a high-value al Qaeda operative
captured in Pakistan. In succeeding months and years, more than 30
Congressional sessions were specifically devoted to the
interrogation program and its methods, including waterboarding and
other aggressive techniques designed to squeeze intelligence out of
hardened detainees like Zubaydah.

The briefings were first available to the Chairmen and ranking
Members of the Intelligence Committees. From 2003 through 2006,
that gang of four included Democrats Bob Graham and John D.
Rockefeller in the Senate and Jane Harman in the House, as well as
Republicans Porter Goss, Peter Hoekstra, Richard Shelby and Pat
Roberts. Senior staffers were sometimes present. After September
2006, when President Bush publicly acknowledged the program, the
interrogation briefings were opened to the full committees.
If Congress wanted to kill this program, all it had to do was
withhold funding. And if Democrats thought it was illegal or really
found the CIA&apos;s activities so heinous, one of them could have made
a whistle-blowing floor statement under the protection of the
Constitution&apos;s speech and debate clause. They&apos;d have broken their
secrecy oaths and jeopardized national security, sure. But if they
believed that Bush policies were truly criminal, didn&apos;t they have a
moral obligation to do so? 
Lest you think the Journal has gone &quot;soft of terror,&quot;
they are of course running this article with the intention of
pulling a reductio ad absurdum on any attempts to bring government
officials complicit in such policies to justice, or at least to
some political damage, through a thorough investigation into Bush
administration interrogation policies.

However, intentionally or not, the Journal has done a
service in bringing this to, or back to, our attention. No
politicians of whatever party or whatever branch should pass
through their roles in these crimes unscathed, either by possible
legal action or the public obloquy they deserve.

 Permalink | 27 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Don&apos;t Miss Reason Podcasts; Subscribe to Our YouTube Channel 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 11:06AM | Nick Gillespie 

You want audio podcasts of Reason.com and Reason.tv
material?

Then don&apos;t delay: Go here
now for the latest episode of the Reason.tv Talk Show; for
anarchist author Crispin Sartwell&apos;s thoughts on, well, anarchy; for
Bjorn Lomborg&apos;s radical perspective on prioritizing global
problems; for former Securities and Exchange Commission member Paul
Atkins&apos; explosive views on how that agency added to financial
turmoil; and much more.

And don&apos;t forget to subscribe to Reason.tv&apos;s YouTube channel,
which is online
here .

 Permalink | 2 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Obama: Tomorrow We Scrimp, But Tonight We Spend Like There&apos;s No Tomorrow! 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 10:17AM | Nick Gillespie 

 The
ever-credulous Washington Post reports just the facts in a
science-fictional piece titled &quot; Stimulus
aside, Obama vows future budget restraint .&quot; Read some details
and decide for yourself whether the truth is out there:
 
Two weeks away from assuming the presidency, Obama vowed Tuesday
to &quot;bring a long-overdue sense of responsibility and accountability
to Washington&quot; and called the need for budget reform &quot;an absolute
necessity.&quot;...

&quot;Many will focus on the upfront cost of this
legislation,&quot; [House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.)] was
to tell a House Democratic Policy and Steering Committee forum,
according to an excerpt of her prepared remarks. &quot;While we are not
discussing small sums, focusing on the price tag alone ignores the
cost of inaction and the real payoff in terms of job creation and
increased revenues to our Treasury.&quot;

While promising to fight waste and to make tough budgetary
decisions, however, Obama warned that the nation could face
trillion-dollar deficits for years to come. Eight years ago, the
federal budget ran a surplus; the deficit on Sept. 30 was about
$455 billion. That was before the government began spending nearly
half of a $700 billion bailout fund for the financial
sector....

Obama has not detailed solutions for vexing problems such as
growing demands on Social Security and Medicare. His prescriptions
to make government accountable could easily run aground, much like
those of predecessors who vowed to tackle government waste, fraud
and abuse.
 
That&apos;s the same Obama who&apos;s pulling for a $775 billion stimulus
package. And who has been trotting the spend-now,
save-later line to sellout crowds for months now. That&apos;s the
same Nancy Pelosi, by the way, who came into power saying the Dems
would enforce fiscal discipline and then pushed a farm bill
that blew the stops out on subsidies and whatnot.

 The laffs continue here. 

The good news is that Obama is not from Texas. Both LBJ and
George W. Bush spent like not just drunken sailors but like
falling-down-drunk drunken sailors. Inflation-adjusted
discretionary spending increases during the past half-century have
averaged 1.7 percent, with LBJ and Bush hitting high notes of 6.6
percent to 14.8 percent. Who wants to bet Obama&apos;s first budget
comes closer to the high numbers than the low?

To stoke your fears of a unified government and spending (and
that was all before we became the bailout nation), go here .

 Permalink | 69 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Should We Apply the Logan&apos;s Run Principle, Updated for Inflated Life Expectancies Of Course, to Congress and the Courts? 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 7:43AM | Nick Gillespie 

 Denver Post columnist
and Reason contributor David Harsanyi goes ageist on the only native
criminal class in these United States:
 
Thirty years after Ted Kennedy griped about Ronald Reagan&apos;s
advanced age, the man serves as a 76-year-old, nine-term senator
recovering from brain-tumor surgery. Really, is there no one else
available in the state of Massachusetts who can drop his Rs and
vote dependably Maoist?

An average adult would not trust Sen. Robert Byrd (who is 91) to
pet-sit their mutt for fear that the unfortunate creature might
accidentally turn up in chili con carne. Yet, Byrd sits on the
powerful Senate Appropriations Committee, where he doles out
massive amounts of taxpayer funds for West Virginia landmarks with
&quot;Byrd&quot; in the title. Fortunately, this session Byrd has lost his
chairmanship to make way for a young whippersnapper in Hawaii&apos;s
Daniel Inouye, who is 84.

And, sure, there has been some progress in the Senate with the
ousting of Alaskan criminal Ted Stevens (85). The youth movement
continued in the House with the ejection of 82-year-old John
Dingell from his chairmanship of the House Energy and Commerce
Committee to make way for Henry Waxman, who comes in at a stylish
69.
 
Then, says Harsanyi, there&apos;s the Supreme Court:
 
Then there are Supreme Court justices, who in many ways hold
power beyond that of legislators. Certainly the position entails a
far higher level of intellectual rigor. The average age in that
institution is 69. Five justices are over 70 and another two are
over 60. Justice John Paul Stevens is 88.

In 2004, six in 10 Americans believed that there should be a
mandatory retirement age for Supreme Court justices - probably
because, like myself, they often can&apos;t get their childrens&apos; names
straight, much less remember what the Third Amendment says.
(Though, in the end, we all stand united against the quartering of
soldiers.)
 
The author of Nanny State concludes:
 
Theoretically, it would be nice to allow citizens to vote for
anyone they please, young or old. But since we already have a
minimum, constitutionally mandated age limit to serve in place, why
not a maximum age? How about at least placing it wherever the
average life expectancy falls?

Because, right now, Washington looks more like Del Boca Vista
than America.
 
 Whole
thing here . I don&apos;t agree with mandatory retirement ages, but
it is fun to make fun of jerk-off old senators.

 Reason on
definitively senile and decrepit Supreme Court Judges here .

 Reason interviews Harsanyi here .

 Permalink | 116 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Recently at Reason.tv: How Far Will Smoking Bans Go? 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 7:17AM 

On Friday, January 9, the California city of Belmont&apos;s controversial smoking ban —which snuffs out smoking &quot;in
individual units and their patio/yard areas of multi-unit,
multi-story residences (apartments, condominiums, and townhouses)
that share common floors and/or ceilings with at least one other
such unit&quot;—goes into effect. As a result, about the only place
Belmonters will be free to smoke is detached single-family
houses.

Which makes it a good time revisit Reason.tv&apos;s &quot;Just Can&apos;t Quit:
How far will smoking bans go?&quot; This eight-minute documentary was
produced by Ted Balaker and features one of the greatest
exhortations to do things for the &quot;children, children, children,&quot;
you&apos;ll ever see outside of an episode of The Simpsons (right around the 3.50 mark).


For embed code, related links, and the video &quot;Talking Butts&quot; (which
features a great cameo by John Waters), go here .

Related video:

&quot; Do You Really
Want to Live in a World Where Giant Inflatable Apes Are
Banned? &quot;

&quot; Banned: Welcome
to Nanny State Nation &quot;

 Reason mag on smoking issues .

 Permalink | 21 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Jacob Sullum on TARP, the GMAC Bailout, and the Lawlessness of the Bush Administration 

 Posted on January 7, 2009, 7:00AM 

 The GMAC
bailout, writes Jacob Sullum, highlights the lawlessness of the
Bush administration, which has ignored statutory restrictions on
the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) and treated it as a slush
fund for politically favored supplicants. Although he has strongly
criticized President Bush for flouting the law, President-elect
Obama has applauded the latest manifestation of that tendency.
Evidently Obama opposes only the &quot;unnecessary&quot; abuse of executive
power.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Thirdhand Smoke Alarm 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 6:44PM | Jacob Sullum 

A recent New York Times headline warns parents to be on the lookout for &quot;A New
Cigarette Hazard: &apos;Third-Hand Smoke.&apos;&quot; The freshly coined term,
introduced by a study reported in the journal Pediatrics ,
refers to particles and gases that linger in a room after someone
has smoked there or in the clothing and possessions of people who
have smoked (or been around smokers) elsewhere. The genius of the
study is that it tries to stir up alarm about thirdhand smoke
without bothering to show that such trace levels of toxins and
carcinogens cause any measurable harm to children (or to anyone
else). Instead the authors simply assume that thirdhand smoke is
dangerous and then do a survey to see how many people are aware of
this &quot;fact.&quot;

You can get a sense of the researchers&apos; method from the first
sentence of their abstract: &quot;There is no safe level of exposure to
tobacco smoke.&quot; As I noted when former
Surgeon General Richard Carmona said something similar in
connection with his 2006 report on secondhand smoke, this is an
article of faith, not a scientific statement, since it cannot be
proven or disproven. But if you start from the premise that there
is no safe level of exposure to tobacco smoke, it is very easy to
arrive at the conclusion that thirdhand smoke (as well as
fourthhand smoke, fifthhand smoke, and sixthhand smoke) is
dangerous. Here is another taste of the researchers&apos; approach:
 
The toxicity of low levels of tobacco smoke constituents has
been proved. According to the National Toxicology Program, these
250 poisonous gases, chemicals, and metals include hydrogen cyanide
(used in chemical weapons), carbon monoxide (found in car exhaust),
butane (used in lighter fluid), ammonia (used in household
cleaners), toluene (found in paint thinners), arsenic (used in
pesticides), lead (formerly found in paint), chromium (used to make
steel), cadmium (used to make batteries), and polonium-210 (highly
radioactive carcinogen). Eleven of these compounds are group 1
carcinogens (most carcinogenic designation).
 
Noting that many of the chemicals in cigarette smoke are toxic
or carcinogenic in high enough doses proves nothing about the
dangers posed by tiny levels of those chemicals. One searches the
article in vain for any acknowledgement of the toxicological
principle that the dose makes the poison. Talking to the Times , the lead author suggests we should instead apply
the smell test, which tells us to fear a fellow elevator rider who
has recently smoked a cigarette:
 
&quot;Your nose isn&apos;t lying,&quot; he said. &quot;The stuff is so toxic that
your brain is telling you: &apos;Get away.&apos;&quot;
 
On his tobacco policy blog, anti-smoking activist Michael Siegel notes that the Pediatrics article
&quot;cites just a single study to support its contention that low
levels of tobacco smoke exposure are associated with health harm.&quot;
That study found an association between low levels of cotinine (a
nicotine metabolite) in children&apos;s blood and their scores on
cognitive tests. Siegel, a public health professor who supports
smoking bans but believes their advocates routinely exaggerate the
hazards of secondhand smoke, details the study&apos;s weaknesses, which
make it impossible to conclude from it that thirdhand smoke causes
brain damage.

&quot;There is no convincing scientific evidence that exposures of
this magnitude produce any significant health harm,&quot; Siegel writes,
&quot;with the one possible exception being children who have asthma and
are sensitive to tobacco smoke.&quot; He worries that propaganda
campaigns focusing on thirdhand smoke may backfire, convincing
parents who now make it a point to smoke outside the house or to
smoke when their children are not around that such precautions are
more trouble than they&apos;re worth.

[Thanks to GregA for the tip.]

 Permalink | 91 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Do You Know the Importance of a Cuban Skypager? 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 6:44PM | Michael C. Moynihan 

As noted previously here at Reason , Cubans recently &quot;celebrated&quot; (or privately
lamented) the fiftieth year of Castroite totalitarianism, an
ideology that has forced millions into poverty and, for those brave
and lucky enough to escape, exile in America and Europe. But, it&apos;s
defenders argue, most of those undernourished compañeros can read (it&apos;s just that no good books are allowed!) and
they have free health care (good luck filling that
perscription!).

When Raul Castro took over from his big brother Fidel, now just
a desiccated corpse squeezed into a track suit , he convinced the
easily-conviced that his would be a more liberal, more open regime.
As the AP reported last year: &quot;First microwaves, now cell phones.
Is this the new Cuba? Raul Castro is revolutionizing his brother&apos;s
island in small but significant ways - the latest in a decree
Friday allowing ordinary Cubans to have cell phone service, a
luxury previously reserved for the select few.&quot;

 Previously ? Such luxuries were still out of reach for
the noble peasant, of course, because the average Cuban salary is
$19 a month. When the AP filed that story, it was $130 just to
activate the telephone on the state-run network. So a year later, The Washington Post looks at how cell phones have
transformed Cuba and discovers that...well, they haven&apos;t.
 
Tatiana González stood transfixed before the glass display case
watching a single cellphone spin around and around on a carousel at
the government-run store. It was a Nokia 1112, a simple, boxy gray
workhorse of mobile telecommunications technology--and González was
in love.

She coveted that phone. She confessed she had dreamed of that
phone. But she would have to wait just a little longer before she
could cradle it to her ear. How much longer? &quot;I hope a year, no
more,&quot; said González, who toils as a manager of medical records in
a hospital, earning $21.44 a month.
[...]

The United States entered and exited the Age of the Beeper in the
1980s, but Cuba has just arrived at it. All over Havana, a visitor
sees people looking at the cellphones, not speaking into
them.

When Pérez and other Cubans get a call, they rarely answer.
Instead, they look at the number, find a land-line telephone, which
is ubiquitous and dirt cheap to use, and return the call. If
they&apos;re feeling flush, they might type a message. &quot;We just type,&quot;
explained Pérez, wagging his finger. &quot;No talk.&quot;

The Cuban government has not released official tallies of cellphone
users, though a person who works in the technology field in Havana
estimated that there were no more than 250,000 users in a nation of
11.2 million.

[...]

To open a mobile phone account with the state telephone monopoly,
ETECSA, a user must go, with a cellphone in hand, to one of the few
offices in Havana, stand in line for an hour and then pay $65 to
activate the service -- a bargain compared with the $130 the
government used to charge. This money is not paid in Cuban pesos
but in the parallel currency used by foreigners, Cuban &quot;convertible
pesos,&quot; known as CUCs and pronounced &quot;kooks.&quot; These are huge sums
for Cubans, whose average monthly salary is around $20.

[...]

Standing in a two-hour line at the ETECSA shop at the Miramar
Trade Center, a young woman said the Samsung cellphone she has had
for more than a year was a gift from an aunt who lives in Spain. &quot;I
used it as an alarm clock,&quot; she explained, &quot;while I saved my money
to activate the line.&quot;

As every cellphone owner learns, the price of minutes in Cuba is
cruel. Local calls between cellphones cost 65 cents a minute.
Cellphone calls to a land line are slightly more. Calls abroad?
Ordinary Cubans interviewed for this article laughed. No one calls
abroad. Dialing the United States costs $2.70 a minute. Europe will
set a caller back $5.85.
 
Full article here. Headline reference here .

 Permalink | 49 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Ron Bailey on Whether Nazism Can Happen Here 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 6:00PM 

 In 1961,
obedience experiments conducted by Yale&apos;s Stanley Milgram famously
revealed that Americans were no better at resisting the claims of
authority than other people. So why hasn&apos;t the U.S. had its own
Gulag or Auschwitz? The answer, writes Science Correspondent Ronald
Bailey, is liberty. Our social institutions have traditionally
limited what authorities can get away with.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Now at Reason.tv: The Reason.tv Talk Show featuring Michael C. Moynihan and Nick Gillespie, with guests Sallie James and Sam MacDonald 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 3:00PM 



On December 19, Reason.tv&apos;s Nick Gillespie and Michael C.
Moynihan sat down with Australian-born Cato Institute trade policy
analyst Sallie
James and memoirist and former Reason magazine
staffer Sam
MacDonald , whose new book is The Urban
Hermit , a slacker update of sorts of Ben Franklin&apos;s
Autobiography.

Topics covered include the future of free trade under President
Obama, what it&apos;s like to grow up in Australia, the future of
libertarian politics, and whether lentils, which are a huge part of
MacDonald&apos;s memoir, are inherently awful.

Approximately 25 minutes. Go here for embed code,
related links, and past episodes of the talk show. Go here for an
audio podcast.

 Permalink | 14 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 &quot;For Middle-Class Pakistanis, a Gun Is a Must-Have Accessory&quot; 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 2:32PM | Katherine Mangu-Ward 

 Greatest headline ever.

In today&apos;s Wall Street Journal , an story about incentivizing
private solutions when public law enforcement fails:
 
After escaping kidnappers who chained him to a bed for 25 days,
Mohammad Javed Afridi pressed Pakistani law enforcement for swift
justice. The police offered him something else: temporary permits
for four automatic assault rifles.

Since Mr. Afridi&apos;s ordeal ended in mid-October, police in his
hometown of Peshawar, in northwestern Pakistan, haven&apos;t made an
arrest in his case....

So the cops allowed Mr. Afridi to arm himself against future
abductions. The 35-year-old journalist now carries an AK-47 to work
and back home to his wife and five children. Relatives rotate duty
as his bodyguards. If his car is again stopped by armed men on a
dark road, Mr. Afridi vows to shoot first.
 
In Pakistan, at least, sometimes you really do need to own four
assault weapons in self-defense—even the police think so. Suck it, Brady
Campaign Myth #8 .

 Permalink | 235 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Big Hollywood Is on the Intertubes 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 1:47PM | Nick Gillespie 

 Conservative writer Andrew Breitbart has launched a new group blog called Big Hollywood . It&apos;s kind
of an answer to the Huffington Post (which Breitbart
helped develop) and here is Breitbart&apos;s capsule description
of his new site&apos;s goals:
 
Big Hollywood&apos;s modest objective: to change the entertainment
industry. To make Hollywood something we can believe in—again. In
order to give millions of Americans hope.

Until conservatives, libertarians and Republicans—who will be
the lion&apos;s share of Big Hollywood&apos;s contributors—recognize that
(pop) culture is the big prize and that politics is secondary,
there will be no victory in this important battle.
 
 More on that here .

Currently up at the site: A cogitation by Fox News&apos; Red
Eye Host Greg Gutfeld about free markets and rock (&quot;&apos;If only
Kurt Cobain had chased the almighty dollar instead of the dragon,
he&apos;d be alive today,&apos; Steve Albini might have said, if he wasn&apos;t so
busy reading Hayek.&quot;); an explication of The Beatles&apos; &quot;Dear
Prudence&quot; by GOP Rep. Thaddeus G. McCotter (&quot;Our majority was
emaciated by electoral liposuction; our bold re-branding initiative
put speed freaks to sleep&quot;); and a well-headlined bit by The New
Republic&apos;s Jamie Kirchick (&quot;Listening To Annie Lennox&apos;s Gaza
Commentary is Like Walking on Broken Glass&quot;). All that and a
bit by orgone enthusiast Orson Bean .

While there are plenty of areas of disagreement between Reason and Breitbart—his love for the Popeye-elbowed
and out-of-wedlock-fathering baseball near-great Steve Garvey is
only the most obvious one—he is certainly right that culture is the
prize and that, as Matt Welch and I have argued in various places
(including Politics magazine ), politics is indeed a lagging
indicator of change in American society. Given that, several of
us at Reason will be participating at Big
Hollywood, so look for us to bring a libertarian perspective
to the site, one that is surely less down on the entertainment
industry&apos;s lack of patriotism and more about the absurdity of
all the combatants in the culture wars, especially idiots such as these .

Bonus Reason.tv footage: Breitbart and Gutfeld talk about not
getting jobs back at Reason magazine when they might have
still turned their lives around.



 Permalink | 70 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 RNC Hopefuls on Ron Paul 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 12:56PM | Brian Doherty 

At the Western Standard (where they are tracking Canada&apos;s
heroes of liberty), Kalim Kassam sums up the comments various seekers of the job of chairman of
the Republican National Committee made re: Ron Paul at a debate
hosted by Grover Norquist.

While Kassam frames it as if they are all smartly recognizing
the potential importance of Ron&apos;s libertarian,
anti-interventionist, anti-fiat money crew to the GOP, the quotes
he presents sound a lot more hesitant and grudging than that to
me--less &quot;these Ron Paul people are a valuable part of our
coalition and should be heeded&quot; and more &quot;we ought not utterly and
firmly bar these strange and disturbing people from crossing our
threshold, if they really, really wanna help us out.&quot;

But check out the summary quotes and video here and decide for yourself, as exciting new media
technologies allow us to do. The Wall Street Journal coverage of RNC hopefuls and Paul, which Kassam
quotes.

 Permalink | 94 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Ron Asheton, R.I.P. 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 12:10PM | Brian Doherty 

One of the great guitar-grinders of all time is gone: Ron
Asheton of the Stooges is dead at
age 60 , found in his Ann Arbor home. Asheton has more than fair
claim to space on top of that most crowded of pedestals, the one
where we stand up and honor the &quot;father(s) of punk rock.&quot;

Ron and his brother Scotty on the drums, with Mr. James &quot;Iggy
Stooge/Pop&quot; Osterberg writhing and howling up front, were not only
seminal in the draggy/thumpy/crunchy/fuzzy evocations of emotional
and sonic charged ennui and fuck-all mayhem; they were, more
important than being early to the game, still and always really,
really great at it.

The classic Stooges line-up only made two albums back in 1969
and 1970 (though 1973&apos;s Raw Power , when guitarist Asheton
was shifted to bass, is also a stone classic). The Ashetons and
Iggy reunited as the Stooges with Minuteman Mike Watt on bass this
century, and I&apos;m very glad I got to be right up front at one of
their 21st century reunion shows, watching the very un-rock n&apos; roll
looking Mr. Asheton bring his quiet, maybe even almost a little
bored looking, sense of a working man doing a precise and important
job as his fingers summoned the fuzzy violence that buoyed up the
more colorful Iggy as he danced with the spirits and drew the
crowds attention and energy and ferocity, all the qualities being
stirred and shaped by that chubby old guy over to Iggy&apos;s left whose
name they might not have known. He was Ron Asheton, and we&apos;re all
lucky to have had him.

 Permalink | 41 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reason Writers Around Town: Nick Gillespie on Joseph Priestley, The Invention of Air , and Why America Should Look to an 18th-Century Scientist for Inspiration 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 12:00PM | Nick Gillespie 

 Writing in The New York Post about a new biography of Joseph
Priestley, the 18th-century scientist credited with isolating
oxygen, creating Unitarianism, and influencing Ben Franklin and
Thomas Jefferson, Nick Gillespie argues:
 
We live in troubling times, filled with signs of a great
economic apocalypse, politicized science on topics from birth
control to climate change and religious zealots who kill innocents
rather than live peacefully with them. This is exactly the moment
to learn from Priestley, who survived riots, threats of
prosecution, and other hardships and yet never doubted that &quot;the
world was headed naturally toward an increase in liberty and
understanding.&quot; Ironically, The Invention of Air underscores that there is nothing natural about progress and
liberty, each of which must be fought for and defended every single
day by visionary individuals.
 
 Read all about
it here .

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Obama&apos;s Neocon Fans 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 11:25AM | Jesse Walker 

The neoconservative pundit Jennifer Rubin takes a look at the
pending presidency and likes
what she sees :
 
So let&apos;s get this straight: Robert Gates will be the Defense
Secretary, we&apos;re ramping up U.S. forces in Afghanistan and
providing a reasonable period of time for a hand-off in Iraq, there isn&apos;t going to be a windfall oil profits tax or income tax
hike but there is going to be a huge set of business tax
cuts -- and Rick Warren is giving the invocation at the
Inauguration. Who won in November?

I&apos;m sure there will be times during the next four years when the
Obama administration&apos;s decisions on issues (e.g. judicial
appointments) have conservatives banging their heads against the
wall, bemoaning the fact that John McCain wasn&apos;t elected. But so
far it&apos;s hard to imagine McCain would have been doing more than the
incoming Obama team seems to be proposing -- and with as much
chance of success -- to further some key center-Right policy
aims.
 
Those tax cuts might sound like good news, but they&apos;re bundled with some giant hikes in spending; they&apos;re basically a way to bribe
Republicans into voting for the &quot;stimulus&quot; package. As for the rest
-- well, it&apos;s no surprise that a Commentary writer would
find more value in keeping Robert Gates in office than in blocking
Detroit&apos;s corporate welfare package.

Meanwhile, Richard Perle and Douglas Feith seem happy with Obama&apos;s choice to run the CIA.

 Permalink | 67 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 &quot;Perhaps the whole of the General Theory was intended as a huge (400-page) joke, and Keynes was appalled to find disciples who took it all literally.&quot; 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 11:20AM | Damon W. Root 

Over at the Foundation for Economic Education&apos;s Anything
Peaceful blog, Sheldon Richman highlights libertarian
journalist Henry Hazlitt&apos;s 1959 book, The Failure of the &quot;New
Economcs&quot; , which offers a startling take on famed economist
John Maynard Keynes:
 
The more I read the more I thought: Keynes was surely joking. No
one in his position could really be that confused, contradictory,
and ignorant of economic logic. It had to be a gag on the economics
profession, an emperor-with-no-clothes experiment.

Thus I smiled when I got to Hazlitt&apos;s statement in chapter XXV,
&quot;Did Keynes Recant?&quot; (p. 398):
 
Keynes was a brilliant man. Much of what he wrote he wrote in
tongue-in-cheek, for the pleasure of paradox, to épater le
bourgois [shock the middle class], in the spirit of Wilde,
Shaw, and the Bloomsbury circle. Perhaps the whole of the General Theory was intended as a huge (400-page) joke, and
Keynes was appalled to find disciples who took it all
literally.
 If it was a joke, Keynes helped inflict much misery and oppression
on innocent people just for a laugh. I guess for the elitist
Keynes, the well-being of the masses can&apos;t be allowed to impede his
bold and daring lifestyle. It is for people like him that
secularists like me wish there was a place of fire and
brimstone.
 
 Read
the whole thing here. 

 Permalink | 67 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Where Presidents Meddle With Your Television Set 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 10:47AM | Matt Welch 

Starting last night, thanks to Le Prez Nicolas &quot; Bling Bling &quot;
Sarkozy, France&apos;s four (count &apos;em!) national public television
stations are now prohibited from broadcasting commercials between 8
p.m. and 6 a.m. Lest you think this is some kind of Hungaro-Gallic
starve-the-beast ploy to get L&apos;etat out of the TV biz, think again :
 
The government says the reforms will improve the quality of
programming on public television by freeing it from &quot;the tyranny of
ratings&quot; and it has pledged to make up for any shortfall in
advertising revenues. [...]

The reform creates a funding gap for public TV which will largely
be filled by a levy on private broadcasters and Internet providers
and by government support.

The 2009 budget includes 450 million euros to compensate for the
loss of revenue[.]
 
The usual protest strikes are scheduled, etc.

Note: French households currently pay 116 Euros a year (newly indexed to inflation ) for the privilege of owning a television
set. Also, as every French journalist is quick to tell you in
conversation, Sarko is close personal friends with the heads of
various private television honchos and other media owners, and has
been cruder than his predecessor in using that influence to quash
stories and reward allies; neither of which has ever proven
particularly difficult in France. And, as part of the same law
banning ads, the president will now have the direct ability
(instead of merely the indirect ability) to hire and fire heads of
state-owned media.

 Permalink | 131 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 No One Better Than Ezra 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 9:55AM | Matt Welch 

The good folks at The Western Standard have compiled
their Top 100 Canadians for liberty for the year 2008, starting
with this top-25 tranche . Clocking in at numero uno (that&apos;s Canadian for
&quot;Chief Moose&quot;) is Ezra Levant. Explainer:
 
The issue that dominated 2008 for the freedom movement was the
attack on freedom of speech and expression by human rights
commissions across Canada, and Ezra Levant was at the centre of
this issue as a pro-free speech newsmaker, advocate, lawyer and
blogger. Levant is pushing back against Canada&apos;s human rights
commissions with his new book &quot;Shakedown: How Our Government is
Undermining Democracy in the Name of Human Rights.&quot; Levant&apos;s
single-minded defence of free speech in 2008 makes him the Western
Standard&apos;s choice for the #1 spot on our Liberty 100 list. Levant
is the former publisher of the Western Standard.
 
Jacob Sullum on Levant here .

 Permalink | 18 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Great Firewall of China, Version 3.0: Stop the Porn and Vulgarity! 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 9:38AM | Nick Gillespie 

From the Financial Times via Drudge comes the latest rationale for
why the Chinese government must crack down on intertube
search engines:
 
China&apos;s government has accused the country&apos;s leading internet
search engines and web portals, including Google, of threatening
public morals by carrying pornographic and vulgar content.

While Beijing regularly launches web censorship campaigns, the
new crackdown is the first in which the government has targeted
heavyweight companies such as Google and Baidu, the local rival
that leads the Chinese search market. During the last campaign
about a year ago, the authorities listed only small and
little-known websites as responsible for spreading unhealthy
content.
 
 More here. 

Give the Chinese repressocrats this much credit: They must have
been reading Reason magazine all these years to realize
that &quot;vulgar&quot; culture is indeed often a motive force in dramatic
social change. As Charles Paul Freund wrote in 2002:
 
Popular, commercial forms are not thoughtful. Rather, they are
temporary, noisy, intense, ecstatic. They are sensual and
disruptive. Because they are frequently set in motion by powerless
and even despised outgroups, they appear subversive. They not only
threaten social morals, but challenge established power
relationships.

The result is that such ecstatic forms are attacked not only by
the West&apos;s left-liberal critics for their commercial origin, but by
the West&apos;s conservatives for their disruptive power. Cultural
ecstasy may have billions of participants, but it hardly has a
single friend.
 
Freund&apos;s stunning essay, &quot; In Praise of
Vulgarity: How commercial culture liberates Islam—and the
West ,&quot; is worth reading on a daily basis. It opens with a
memorable description of the liberation of Kabul, &quot;when the streets
ran with beards? As one city after another was abandoned by Taliban
soldiers, crowds of happy men lined up to get their first legal
shave in years, and barbers enjoyed the busiest days of their
lives.&quot;

Here&apos;s his masterful finish:
 
The Central Asian Republic of Kazakhstan—just a few hundred
miles north of Afghanistan—began a crackdown on dangerous
&quot;bohemian&quot; lifestyles. The authorities went after a number of
familiar outsiders—gays, religious dissidents—but even Westerners
were surprised to learn that one targeted group was &quot;Tolkienists.&quot;
It turns out that there are Kazakh Hobbit wannabes who like to
dress up in character costume and re-enact scenes from J.R.R.
Tolkien&apos;s novels. For their trouble, they were being subjected to
sustained water torture.

Hobbit re-enactors in Kazakhstan? Where do they get their
paraphernalia? Are there Kazakh Tolkienist fanzines? Have fans
started changing Tolkien&apos;s narratives to suit themselves, the way
Western Star Trek subcultures turned their own obsession
into soft-core pornography? Do re-enactors change roles from time
to time, or are any of them trapped inside a Frodo persona? Is
there no end to the identities waiting to be assumed? No end to
what invention makes flesh, before it tosses it aside and starts
again?
 
So maybe the Chinese are onto something by trying to control the
culture, especially the vulgar commercial culture, their citizens
are glomming all over. And while the attempt may cause all sorts of
trouble, it
will inevitably fail .

 Permalink | 12 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Inventor of Hawaiian Shirt Says Final Aloha 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 7:40AM | Nick Gillespie 

 Alfred Shaheen, the inventor of the &quot;aloha shirt&quot; worn by
everyone from returning World War II vets to Elvis Presley to slob
frat boys to fictional fruit-drink pitchman and
rageaholic &quot; Punchy ,&quot;
has died at the age of 86. His technically and culturally
innovative shirts didn&apos;t just throw bright colors and shimmering
fabrics out into circulation; they were one small
but noteworthy contribution to the ongoing and wonderful
globalizing and mongrelizing of post-war society and fashion.
From The Los Angeles Times obit:
 
Elvis Presley wore a Shaheen-designed red aloha shirt featured
on the album cover for the &quot;Blue Hawaii&quot; soundtrack in 1961.

Born into a family established in the textile business, Shaheen
maintained high standards by controlling the process from start to
finish at the factory he built in Honolulu.

He hired professional artists and silk-screened their designs on
silk, rayon and cotton fabrics he imported to Hawaii. Then his
seamstresses cut and pieced together garments that were sold at his
own shops and other retail outlets in Hawaii or exported to the
mainland and around the world.

&quot;He was a genius,&quot; Dale Hope, art director for the
Honolulu-based Kahala shirt maker and author of &quot;The Aloha Shirt:
Spirit of the Islands,&quot; told The Times. &quot;He knew more about the
inner workings of all of the elements of printing, the garment
business and wholesaling and retailing and distribution. He was
really a bright, sharp and smart man.&quot;...

Most of the patterns featured three to five colors that laborers
applied to silk screens by hand, saturating the fabric. Artists in
the Shaheen studio had more than 1,000 dye colors to choose from,
including innovative metallic shades, and they consulted rare
books, libraries and museum collections. Sometimes Shaheen sent the
designers on field trips to Tahiti and other exotic locales to soak
up the culture for future work.
 
 More here .

 Permalink | 28 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Is the Village Voice a Zombie Newspaper? 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 7:18AM | Nick Gillespie 

...in that it&apos;s already dead?

Over at the excellent Splice Today , alt-media icon
Russ Smith questions a recent New Yorker story by Louis
Menand about the venerable (and editorially ailing) grandpa
of downtown weeklies, the Village Voice (once owned by none other than Rupert Murdoch):
 
Menand also claims that the mainstream press, aping the
weeklies, discovered &quot;youth culture&quot; in the early 70s and hired men
and women who understood the prevailing popular culture. In fact,
it was the slow learning curve of the daily newspapers that opened
up a market for the second wave of weeklies, papers that provided
extensive events listings, affordable advertisements for small and
independent retailers, free classifieds and intelligent arts
criticism. The daily newspapers, contrary to Menand&apos;s assertion,
never did get the &quot;youth market&quot; right and in city after city
produced competing free papers that were laughable imitators of the
weeklies.
 
 Whole thing here .

Smith, who created the Baltimore and Washingtion City
Papers and the New York Press back in the
day, is down on print in general and, as a libertoid
Republican, he&apos;s down on the GOP these days too. Here he is on the
Reason.tv Talk Show yapping on all that and more:



 Permalink | 8 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Tim Cavanaugh on What the Contract with American Can Teach Today&apos;s Republicans 

 Posted on January 6, 2009, 7:00AM 

 From our
February issue, Contributing Editor Tim Cavanaugh explains what the
modern GOP could learn from rereading its two-page 1994
masterpiece.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Bob Barr Recants DOMA Very Publicly, A Couple of Months After Two Relevant Votes 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 6:26PM | Brian Doherty 

That is, the one for him for president, and the one where the
state in which his op-ed appears, California, voted to bar gay
marriage.

Libertarian Party candidate Barr was not well-loved by many
party members for writing the 1996 federal Defense of Marriage Act,
which Barr disavows in the Los Angeles Times with some of these
words. (This is not the first time he&apos;s said he regrets DOMA. But
it is the first time he did so in a piece written by him in a major
newspaper. It might have been politically smarter to write and try
to get prominent placement for this piece in late October.)
 
I&apos;ve....come to the conclusion that DOMA is not working out as
planned. In testifying before Congress against a federal marriage
amendment, and more recently while making my case to skeptical
Libertarians as to why I was worthy of their support as their
party&apos;s presidential nominee, I have concluded that DOMA is neither
meeting the principles of federalism it was supposed to, nor is its
impact limited to federal law.

In effect, DOMA&apos;s language reflects one-way federalism: It
protects only those states that don&apos;t want to accept a same-sex
marriage granted by another state. Moreover, the heterosexual
definition of marriage for purposes of federal laws -- including,
immigration, Social Security survivor rights and veteran&apos;s benefits
-- has become a de facto club used to limit, if not thwart, the
ability of a state to choose to recognize same-sex unions.

Even more so now than in 1996, I believe we need to reduce
federal power over the lives of the citizenry and over the
prerogatives of the states. It truly is time to get the federal
government out of the marriage business. In law and policy, such
decisions should be left to the people themselves.
 
 Reason magazine ran a cover feature
interview with candidate Barr in our November 2008 issue.
Reason.com did a post-election
chat with him in late November.

 Permalink | 102 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 A New Year&apos;s Police Murder in San Francisco Bay Area 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 4:24PM | Brian Doherty 

Three police officers at the Fruitvale BART station early on New
Year&apos;s Day have a young black man, Oscar Grant, pinned on the
ground, and one of them shot him in the back and murdered him.
(Grant and a group of other people were being held and questioned
regarding reports of a fight on the train. He was not armed.)

Video report from local news station KTVU here . News account from San Francisco Chronicle here (and the video seems to fully corroborate the worst
version of the story from witnesses in the written
account).

 Permalink | 114 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, $100,000 Bluefin 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 3:07PM | Katherine Mangu-Ward 

 Everyone knows sushi can be expensive, but this is something else:
 
Two sushi bar owners paid more than $100,000 for a Japanese
bluefin tuna at a Tokyo fish auction Monday, several times the
average price and the highest in nearly a decade, market officials
said. The 282-pound premium tuna caught off the northern coast of
Oma fetched $104,700, the highest since 2001.
 
You might think that the sale of this huge, delicious,
scary-looking tuna is all part of the grand Tokyo tradition going
back centuries. And it is, in a way. But a fusion of American and
Japanese tastes, techniques, natural resources, and new
refrigeration and travel technology made the tuna market what it is
today.
 
The taste for richer fish such as tuna arrived [in Japan] with
American troops after World War II, who introduced enthusiastic red
meat eating to a previously ascetic people. The most prized sushi
today is fatty tuna from the belly of the fish, or toro .
But before Americans started ordering nigiri —raw fish laid
on balls of rice—most traditional sushi chefs looked down on tuna
with the same disdain a French chef has for fat-free
mayonnaise.

Likewise, the American concept of tuna—the white, flaky stuff in
cans—had no place for the rich, red flesh of the 600-pound
creatures being caught in the cold water of the Atlantic. The huge
tuna that now spark intense bidding wars at Japan’s Tsukiji seafood
market were used primarily to make cat food.
 
An airline executive with empty cargo holds to fill got a
worldwide market in tuna going, and the rest is history.

Read the rest of the article on sushi and globalization from me,
here in &quot; The
Day of the Flying Fish .&quot;

 Permalink | 108 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Cathy Young on Russian Liberalism and the Putin/Medvedev Regime 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 3:00PM 

 A year ago,
Russian liberals harbored at least modest hopes that Dmitry
Medvedev, Vladimir Putin&apos;s handpicked presidential successor, might
prove more liberal than Putin. Today, writes Contributing Editor
Cathy Young, the winds of change in Russia are blowing again—harsh
winds that may yet turn into a storm.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 One of Those Other Up-in-the-Air Senate Seats... 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 1:43PM | Brian Doherty 

...is a little closer to resolution. But still maybe a lawsuit
away. Details from AP:
 
The state Canvassing Board was posed to certify the results of
the recount in Minnesota&apos;s grueling Senate election in Al Franken&apos;s
favor — but that doesn&apos;t mean the race is definitely over.

The board was to meet Monday and was expected to declare which
candidate received the most overall votes from nearly 3 million
ballots cast. The latest numbers showed Franken, a Democrat, with a
225-vote lead over Republican Sen. Norm Coleman.

But after the announcement, there will be a seven-day waiting
period before an election certificate is completed. If any lawsuits
are filed during that waiting period, certification is conditional
until the issue is settled in court.

Coleman, who led Franken on election night, hasn&apos;t ruled out a
lawsuit challenging the results, claiming there were irregularities
that gave Franken an unfair advantage.
 
The head of the Senate Rules Committee--which sits in mighty
judgment over contested elections to his body--thinks it&apos;s all
over, apparently:
 
New York Sen. Charles Schumer....said Sunday that Franken had
won the election.

&quot;While there are still possible legal issues that will run their
course, there is no longer any doubt who will be the next Senator
from Minnesota,&quot; Schumer said. &quot;With the Senate set to begin
meeting on Tuesday to address the important issues facing the
nation, it is crucial that Minnesota&apos;s seat not remain empty, and I
hope this process will resolve itself as soon as possible.&quot;
 
Republicans, meanwhile, unsurprisingly are being procedurally
scruplous and saying the seat should remain empty until all legal
questions are resolved.

I did not once make any &quot;Al Franken Decade&quot; jokes. At least not
in this decade.

 Permalink | 98 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 HackWatch: John Yoo Edition 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 1:26PM | Radley Balko 

 Per Jacob
Sullum&apos;s post below on the John Yoo/John Bolton piece in the New York Times , I think we have a new addition
to our
HackWatch feature .  Yoo, who under President Bush has
argued that the president has the power to unilaterally withdraw
from treaties, now wants the Senate to reassert its treaty power,
because he fears the sorts of entanglements into which
President-Elect Obama might get us enmeshed.

 Yoo gets an 9 out of 10 on the
somewhat-arbitrary Hackery Index.  The only ameliorating
factor, here, is that Yoo&apos;s hackery seems more issue-oriented than
strictly party-oriented. That is, he isn&apos;t explicitly arguing that
Republican presidents should have more power than Democratic
presidents.  Rather, he believes the president should have
plenary power to negate treaties pertaining to issues broadly
related to national security, but wants the Senate to reassert
itself on treaties related to domestic policy.  Of course, the
issues where Yoo wants plenary executive power happen to be issues
where he agrees with Republicans, and the issues where he wants
more Senate control are those issues where he doesn&apos;t trust
Obama.  But Yoo does at least have a constitutional argument
for making the distinction. It just happens to be a crappy one .

If you see an example of a pundit, politician, major blogger, or
other Beltway creature who’s done a 180 on this or another issue, please send it to us ,
with links, and “HackWatch” in the subject line.

 Permalink | 25 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Historians and the Great Depression 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 1:24PM | Damon W. Root 

David Beito, professor of history at the University of Alabama
and author of the superb From Mutual Aid to the Welfare State , has published an
open letter to the journalist Daniel Gross, taking issue with
Gross&apos; assertion that &quot;one would be very hard-pressed to find a
serious professional historian who believes that the New Deal
prolonged the Depression.&quot; Here&apos;s Beito:
 
If the quotation accurately represents your views, it is very
mistaken.

Off the top of my head, I can name &quot;several serious professional
historians&quot; who would probably argue (and argue strongly) &quot;that the
New Deal prolonged the Depression.&quot; In addition to myself, they
include Jonathan Bean of Southern Illinois University, Brad Birzer
of Hillsdale College, Brad Thompson of Clemson University, Jeffrey
Hummel at San Jose State University, Larry Schweikart of the
University of Dayton , Michael Allen of the University of
Washington at Tacoma, Ralph Raico of Buffalo State College, Burton
Folsom of Hillsdale College, David Mayer of Capital University in
Columbus, John Moser of Ashland University in Ohio, and Paul Moreno
of Hillsdale. All have doctorates in history from top-ranked
universities.
 
 Whole thing
here. Reason.tv looks at whether Obama&apos;s new New Deal
will be as bad as the old New Deal here . Amity
Shlaes discusses &quot;Franklin D. Roosevelt&apos;s baleful economic legacy,
the growth of government, and the death of classical liberalism&quot;
with Nick Gillespie here .

 Permalink | 125 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 John Yoo Worries About Presidential Presumption 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 12:13PM | Jacob Sullum 

In a New York Times op-ed piece, John Bolton and John
Yoo, former Bush administration officials not known for expressing
concern about executive branch power grabs, urge Congress to demand that the president respect
its constitutional authority...to reject international
agreements that Bolton and Yoo do not like. While evading the
Treaty Clause&apos;s requirement of approval by two-thirds of the
Senate was OK in the case of Bretton Woods, GATT, and NAFTA,
they say, it is clearly improper when dealing with climate change
agreements, the Law of the Sea Treaty, and the International
Criminal Court. Bolton and Yoo, who as a Justice Department
attorney notoriously argued that the president can do pretty much whatever he wants in the name
of national security, conclude by slyly suggesting that
Republicans in the Senate help the incoming Democratic
president &quot;strike the proper balance between the legislative
and executive branches that so many have called for in recent
years.&quot;

 Permalink | 36 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Matt Welch on Arnold Schwarzenegger&apos;s Failure 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 12:00PM 

 From our
February issue, Editor in Chief Matt Welch writes that if
California Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger is the face of &quot;moderate&quot;
Republicanism, the party is even more doomed than the 2008
elections suggest.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reid&apos;s Thin Reed Bends 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 11:34AM | Jacob Sullum 

In an interview with NBC&apos;s
David Gregory on Meet the Press yesterday, Senate Majority
Leader Harry Reid insisted &quot;there&apos;s clearly legal authority for us
to do whatever we want to&quot; when Roland Burris, Illinois Gov.
Rod Blogojevich&apos;s choice to replace Barack Obama, tries to
claim his seat. At the same time, Reid left room for a deal that
would allow Burris to serve. Here is his rationale for
resisting the appointment:
 
Blagojevich obviously is a corrupt individual. I think
that&apos;s pretty clear. And the reason that he&apos;s done what he&apos;s done
is to divert attention from the arrest that was just made of him
and the indictment which will be coming in a few days, according to
the U.S. attorney in Illinois. That&apos;s why President-elect Obama
agreed with us that Mr. Burris is tainted. Not as a result of
anything that he&apos;s done wrong. There&apos;s—I don&apos;t know a thing
wrong with Mr. Burris.
 
Article I, Section 5 of the Constitution says, &quot;Each House shall
be the Judge of the Elections, Returns and Qualifications of its
own Members.&quot; The Supreme Court has ruled that in this context
&quot;qualifications&quot; are the criteria laid out by the
Constitution itself—e.g., that a senator be at least 30 years old
and a U.S. citizen for at least nine years. In any event, Reid
concedes there&apos;s nothing wrong with Burris&apos; personal
qualifications; according to Reid, it&apos;s Burris&apos; appointment by
a governor accused of corruption that&apos;s problematic. Reid is
arguing that the Senate has a right to judge the legitimacy of
Burris&apos; appointment, just as it would have the right to judge the
legitimacy of another senator&apos;s election. Yet if Burris himself is
clean, as Gregory pointed out, &quot;there&apos;s nothing suggesting
that the appointment was at all illegal&quot; (that it was the result of
a bribe, for example).

Perhaps recognizing that his position is legally untenable, Reid
declined to say that he would press it in court and suggested that
Burris might be allowed to serve after all:
 
 Gregory: But there sounds to me like there may
be some room here to negotiate and actually seat Burris?

 Reid: Hey, listen, David, I&apos;m an old trial
lawyer. There&apos;s always room to negotiate.

 Gregory: All right, so you&apos;re not saying no
completely that he won&apos;t serve?

 Reid: That&apos;s right.
 
Last week I said the
rule of law demands that Burris be permitted to take his
seat. In his column today,
Steve Chapman, no fan of Burris or Blagojevich, fleshes out that
argument.

 Permalink | 102 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Private Benjamins 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 11:18AM | Jesse Walker 

Writing in The Wall Street Journal , George Selgin suggests a solution for Argentina&apos;s small-change shortage:
 
Why the shortage? Argentina&apos;s central bank blames it on
&quot;speculators,&quot; meaning everyone from ordinary citizens, who
stockpile coins, to Maco, the private cash-transport company (think
of Brinks) that repackages change gathered from bus companies to
resell at an 8% premium. But those explanations ring false. &quot;Black
marketeering&quot; would not exist if coins were easy to get in the
first place. After all, Argentines could just as easily hoard razor
blades or matchbooks. Yet there&apos;s no shortage of those. What&apos;s so
special about coins?

The answer is that coins are supplied by the government alone.
&quot;Put the federal government in charge of the Sahara desert,&quot; Milton
Friedman said, &quot;and in five years there&apos;d be a sand shortage.&quot; If
Argentina wants to end the coin shortage, it ought to give up its
monopoly.

Crazy? Not if history is the guide. Over two centuries ago,
Great Britain faced a coin shortage more severe than Argentina&apos;s --
so severe that it threatened to stop British industrialization in
its tracks. People struggled to get coins for everyday use. The
average worker was lucky to make 10 shillings a week, while the
smallest banknotes were for 10 times as much. So the coin shortage
even prevented factories from paying wages.

 Like Argentina&apos;s government today, the
British government wasn&apos;t able to end the shortage. Yet the
shortage did end -- thanks to private-sector action. Fed
up with the government&apos;s inaction, British firms started minting
their own coins. Within a decade a score of private mints struck
more coins than the Royal Mint had issued in half a century -- and
better ones: heavier, more beautiful, and a lot harder to fake. Yet
they were also less expensive, since private coiners sold their
products at cost plus a modest markup, like other competitive
firms, instead of charging the coins&apos; face value, as governments
like to do. Finally, when those who had accepted the private coins
for payment went back to the issuer to redeem them, issuers offered
to exchange their coins for central bank notes at no cost.

Armed with this history, it takes no great flight of fancy to
imagine Argentine firms today, including supermarket and retail
chains like Carrefour and Wal-Mart, reputable banks like HSBC Bank
Argentina, and transport companies like Metrovias, issuing their
own centavos and one peso coins.
 
Selgin wrote more about the British experience with private
coins in this article and this book .

 (Note to sticklers: Yes, I know a Benjamin is somewhat
larger than small change. For now!) 

 Permalink | 40 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Debating Obama&apos;s FCC 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 11:00AM | Jesse Walker 

From 1 to 2 this afternoon, eastern time, I&apos;ll be discussing the coming
Obama FCC on KUER, the NPR affiliate in Salt Lake City. I&apos;m told the leftist communications historian Robert McChesney will participate in the conversation as well. McChesney won&apos;t be able to make it, so the other guest will be
Craig Aaron, communications director of Free Press . We&apos;ll be on
sequentially, not simultaneously.

Salt Lake listeners can tune in at 90.1 FM. XM subscribers can
turn to Channel 133. Everyone else can listen online .

 Permalink | 9 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Random Morning Links 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 10:17AM | Radley Balko 

 Obama promises 600,000 new federal employees. Amtrak
police arrest man who says he was taking pictures for an Amtrak
photo contest. Indiana
Court of Appeals strikes down Internet sex sting convictions,
finds that in order to be guilty of attempted sex with a minor, the
victim must be an actual minor, not an undercover police officer. A
solicitation charge against the man will stand. Connecticut judge drives drunk , drifts out of lane while in a
construction zone, hits a parked police car, and unleashes barrage
of racial insults shortly after the accident. Her sentence? An
alcohol education program. The charge will be erased if she stays
clean for a year. Not particularly interesting : Former Ft. Lauderdale city
commissioner has his bike stolen. Interesting-er: While in office,
commissioner created mandatory bike registration system, on the
theory that forcing city residents to register bikes would deter
theft. Interesting-est: When reporting the theft, the former
commissioner had to admit to police that he hadn&apos;t registered his
own bike, violating his own regulation. Burglars dressed as cops invade home in DeKalb County,
Georgia. 

 Permalink | 68 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 So Where Exactly Did Madoff Get the Idea to Pay Off Early Investors With Money From Later Investors? 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 10:00AM | Nick Gillespie 

The answer, deftly rendered in cartoon form and which I can&apos;t
show due to copyright restrictions, may
surprise you . But probably not, if you read the website or
watch Reason.tv .

 Hat tip: Veronique de
Rugy .

 Permalink | 40 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Where, Where the Hell Is Bill? 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 7:13AM | Matt Welch 

Bill Richardson just loves his country too much to let an ongoing New Mexico
influence-peddling investigation muck up his confirmation as
Commerce Secretary, and so good-bye . Mildly bad news, maybe, for those of us who cling to
any capital-C
Character that comes along in an otherwise dreary sea, much
like early-&apos;80s Cleveland once embraced Super Joe
Charboneau .

More substantively, to the extent that the Department of
Commerce impacts trade policy, it would theoretically seem
unfortunate that a trade-bashing
president-elect has let go a man once self-styled as a
&quot; market
Democrat .&quot; But Richardson dropped that moniker faster than a
heroin habit when he ran for president, campaigning unpersuasively
against trade agreements, and otherwise doing what Brian Schweitzer and all the other once-ballyhooed (by fools like me )
Mountain West Democrats have done–stand athwart a party bending
leftward on economics and yelling &quot;me, too!&quot; For eulogies of the
market-friendly strain within the Democratic Party, see these
pieces by Tim
Cavanaugh and David Weigel .

The worst news of all is that the Department of Commerce still
exists. An $8.4
billion budget with 38,000 employees ? What are they building in there?
Helpfully, the department&apos;s website lets us know, right there on
the front page . At a link
entitled &quot; Commerce Department
Accomplishments &quot; you can find, um, some speeches and
fact-sheets about why trade is good? Of even less help is a little
front-page box entitled &quot;Commerce and You.&quot; There you can access a nifty little
population clock for the U.S. and the world, but also such
marginalia as the Official Time in
Your Area , Today&apos;s
Weather , and (my favorite) Grant
Opportunities .

Way back in 1987, when Republicans still talked that way,
Clarence Thomas asked in a Reason interview: &quot;Why do you need a Department of Commerce?&quot; And as late
as &apos;08, soon-to-be disappointing Libertarian Party presidential
candidate Bob Barr told us that,
&quot;The Department of Commerce, to my mind, has no legitimate
Cabinet-level function.&quot;

 Permalink | 103 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Mitch McConnell Suddenly Determines That When It Comes to Bailouts and Stimulus Packages, More Time Is Better Than Less 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 7:02AM | Nick Gillespie 

 Back
in the fall, when a Republican president and Treasury secretary
were pushing an ill-defined, low-oversight bailout of the financial
sector (and everything else but the kitchen sink, although the
fixtures at Goldman Sachs are probably getting
upgraded under TARP), Sen. Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) was all for
it, with great haste. You know, we were running out of time before
everything exploded.

Indeed, McConnell praised his big house colleagues for passing a
bill loaded with &quot;sweeteners&quot; that would get a recalcitrant House
to change its original no vote, saying &quot; I think a good vote coming
out of the Senate will certainly be helpful over on the House
side .&quot;

Now, staring down the possibility of a ready-to-sign stimulus
package costing at least $750 billion for President Barack
Obama come Jan. 20, McConnell is finally urging a wait-and-see
approach:
 
&quot;What I worry about ... is the haste with which this may be
done,&quot; McConnell said on ABC&apos;s This Week . &quot;This is an
enormous bill. Do we want to do it with essentially no hearings, no
input ... from Republican senators. I don&apos;t think that&apos;s a good
idea.&quot;
 
 More
here .

Well, good for McConnell, the top Republican in the Senate and a
staunch foe of the abridgements to constitutional speech usually
praised as &quot;campaign-finance reform.&quot; We&apos;ve been stimulatin&apos; the
economy like nobody&apos;s business for a long time now, and it&apos;s worth
calling for a cool-down period before moving into the next phase of
the 1,000 fingers Magic Touch. Can we wait for, I don&apos;t know, maybe
two or three quarters before figuring out the next massive
intervention into the U.S. economy?

However, McConnell&apos;s change in attitude seems suspiciously
unprincipled and mostly partisan. I&apos;m all for divided government
(here&apos;s hoping it delivers gridlock), but one of the problems with
unprincipled pols is that, well, they don&apos;t have principles. Which
means they will flip the moment they get enough goodies promised
them to go one way or the other. And if the experience with the
financial sector bailout is any indication, expect the second (and
third, and fourth, and so on) bills to be even worse than the awful
first draft. And expect McConnell sometime soon to be on the other
side of the vote, the one with all those shiny, happy Democrats
yapping about how they just guaranteed a car in every pot and two
chickens in every garage by funding bullshit infrastructure
programs in every ZIP code in the country.

 Permalink | 21 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 New at Reason: Steve Chapman on Why the Senate Should Seat Roland Burris 

 Posted on January 5, 2009, 7:00AM 

 One of the
axioms of American democracy is that we are a government of laws,
not of men. But as Steve Chapman writes, the Democrats in the U.S.
Senate may ignore the rule of law and indulge their own preferences
by rejecting Illinois Gov. Rod Blagojevich&apos;s lawful selection of
Roland Burris to fill the senate seat left vacant by
President-elect Barack Obama.

 Read all
about it here. 

 Permalink | Leave a comment 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 George W. Bush: An Easy Act to Follow 

 Posted on January 4, 2009, 10:31AM | Nick Gillespie 

 The
first rule of being a new coach is to always follow a loser. Ron
Hart applies that logic to Barack Obama, who is effectively taking
over the Detroit Lions after years of the Marinelli
Magic . Writes Hart about Dubya&apos;s legacy:
 
Bush has been a big-government disaster. He was the &quot;outside the
Beltway&quot; Texas governor who was going to cut spending and bring
Washington under control. Instead, he oversaw the biggest expansion
of government in modern times. And the most tragic effect of the
Bush legacy is that he has set the conservative/libertarian
ideology back 20 years. He did so by not being a conservative or a
libertarian.

Now all that is left for him is to pardon a few folks and try to
burnish his legacy. To date he has pardoned fewer felons than his
predecessors. My guess is that even criminals don&apos;t want a pardon
from W because they don&apos;t want to be too closely associated with
him.
 
And this:
 
[Obama] has an easy act to follow in George W. Bush, who
solidified his position with me as perhaps our worst president when
he ignored the will of the country and Congress in giving Detroit
all that bailout money (better known as &quot;rearranging the deck
chairs on the Titanic &quot; ). Bush, with help from Dick
Cheney, has tried to establish an imperial presidency. In doing so
he has always found the desires of Congress and the American people
to be quaint and amusing. But W feels he knows best. That
would be fine, if he had been right more often.

As a result of bad choices and the betrayal of fundamental
principles, W&apos;s approval ratings are the lowest of any modern
president. The only thing Bush is still above is the law.
 
 Whole thing here .

Read all about Bush&apos;s &quot;disaster socialism&quot; in the January issue of Reason .

 Permalink | 201 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 
 Reason Writers Around Town: Nick Gillespie on Why Joseph Priestley, &quot;The Father of Modern Chemistry,&quot; Was A Gas 

 Posted on January 4, 2009, 9:30AM 

 In The New York Post , Reason &apos;s Nick Gillespie
reviews The Invention of Air , a new biography of the man
widely credited with discovering oxygen and linking it to blood,
creating Unitarianism, and inventing soda water. Arguably the
best-known scientist of his day, Joseph Priestley was a close
scientific colleague of Ben Franklin, patronized by the
Birmingham entrepreneurs who helped create the Industrial
Revolution, and an influence on Thomas Jefferson.

Author Steven Johnson figures Priestley, who was hounded
out of England after an angry mob destroyed his laboratory in 1794,
as precisely the sort of optimistic, rational seeker we need more
of today. From the review:
 
Johnson paints Priestley not as a man of the past but precisely
the sort of figure the world needs more than ever: A searcher who
shared his discoveries openly and willingly, crossed disciplinary
boundaries with impunity and insight, who conceived of the world as
a large laboratory. As important, Priestley exemplifies &quot;the
temperament that we expect to find at the birth of
America—bountiful optimism, an untroubled sense that the world must
inevitably see the light of reason.&quot;

We live in troubling times, filled with signs of a great
economic apocalypse, politicized science on topics from birth
control to climate change and religious zealots who kill innocents
rather than live peacefully with them. This is exactly the moment
to learn from Priestley, who survived riots, threats of prosecution
and other hardships and yet never doubted that &quot;the world was
headed naturally toward an increase in liberty and understanding.&quot;
Ironically, &quot;The Invention of Air&quot; underscores that there is
nothing natural about progress and liberty, each of which must be
fought for and defended every single day by visionary
individuals.
 
 Whole review here .

 Permalink | 20 Comments 
 
Reason needs your support. Please donate today! 
 
 more sharing 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
 «Previous Week Next Week» 
Most Popular Stories

 Viewed Commented Emailed 
 
 TSA Agents at Louisville Airport Steal Deaf Man&apos;s Candy, Call Him &quot;Fucking Deafie&quot; (7.10) The Real Class Warfare is Baby Boomers Vs. Younger Americans (7.11) The Dark Side of Anti-&quot;Swiss Bank Account&quot; Politics (7.10) Man Tells Police Dispatcher His Mentally Disturbed Brother Is Carrying a Fake Gun, Police Kill Him Anyway (7.9) Houston Student Detained for 12 Hours After Warning Drivers of Speed Trap (7.10) 

 A.M. Links: Russia Sends Warships to Syria, Tax Liens Causing “Second Foreclosure Crisis,” Web’s First Photo Turning 20 (7.11) A.M. Links: Navy Sending Underwater Drones to Persian Gulf, Pyramid Destruction Buzz a Hoax, Sort of, Fifth Moon For Pluto (7.12) Romney Booed by NAACP, Russia Restricts Internet, Where Is Jesse Jackson Jr.?: P.M. Links (7.11) Mitt Romney vs. Free Stuff (7.12) The Real Class Warfare is Baby Boomers Vs. Younger Americans (7.11) 

 The Real Class Warfare is Baby Boomers Vs. Younger Americans (7.11) The Roberts Ruling on ObamaCare Signals a Turning Point (7.12) The Dark Side of Anti-&quot;Swiss Bank Account&quot; Politics (7.10) TSA Agents at Louisville Airport Steal Deaf Man&apos;s Candy, Call Him &quot;Fucking Deafie&quot; (7.10) Budget Insanity (7.11) 
 
 Reason RUPE: Public Opinion Survey 

 New Poll: Romney as Consultant-in-Chief (7.12) Health Care Law Still on Trial in the Court of Public Opinion (6.28) Right-to-Work Wisconsin? (6.18) Rasmussen: 65 Percent Say No To NYC Large-Sugary Drink Ban (6.4) Actually, Americans Do Support Government Union Reform (6.4) 
 
advertisements
 
 Reason on Facebook Reason on Twitter Reason on YouTube Reason RSS 
 
Get Reason E-mail Updates!
 First Name Last Name Email Manage your Reason e-mail list subscriptions 
Site comments/questions:



Media Inquiries and Reprint Permissions:


(310) 367-6109

Editorial&amp;Production Offices:

3415 S. Sepulveda Blvd.
Suite 400
Los Angeles, CA 90034
(310) 391-2245
 
 Home | About | Advertise | Privacy | Contact 
Copyright 2012, Reason.com
	</body>
</document>
