<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007275" url="http://www.homemadedogfoodrecipesblog.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:14" support="4" score="0.014011753152579041" bingtitle="Homemade Dog Food Recipes Blog" webtitle="Homemade Dog Food Recipes Blog">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>I guess you can think of it like eating at a fast food restaurant or eating at home. ... * Green peas, 1 cup * Carrots, 1 cup coarsely chopped * Sweet potato, ½ cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Homemade Dog Food Recipes Blog 
 Homemade Dog Food Recipes for Every Dog… 
 Home Contact us Privacy Policy 
 «Older Entries 
 Is Nutrition Related to Behavioral Problems in Dogs? 
 July 20th, 2009 | Author: admin 
There is evidence that suggests that behavioral problems in dogs are related to their nutrition. According to an article by the Examiner.com, dogs that are hyperactive, out of control or aggressive may have been fed diets that are not appropriate for them. Now, just because a dog has these symptoms doesn’t necessarily mean that it’s their dog food, but it could be.

So how do you find out? Well, obviously the first thing you could try is to change their dog food. Unfortunately, that’s not a simple process, but is doable nonetheless. If you decide to change your dog food, don’t do it cold turkey. You have to do it gradually. Mix¼of the new food with¾of the old food to start for one day. Then slowly, maybe a¼at a time change it day by day. Watch your dog for any unusual changes like getting sick, runny stool, etc. If so, either try another brand or keep the same ratio for a few days and see what happens. If not, then continue to introduce the new food slowly.

What type of ingredients do you want to stay away from? If your dog is out of control or hyperactive, then it’s a good idea to find a dog food that has a low level of wheat, corn and corn meal. If your dog is aggressive, then look for a dog food that has complete proteins present. When a dog is fed incomplete proteins they don’t digest well which can lead to undesirable behaviors.

Finding the right mix in a commercial dog food is sometimes hard. Many people therefore look for homemade dog food recipes to try their hand at making their own dog food. If you decide to go this route, make sure to consult a vet or dog nutritionist before making the change. When you make your own dog food, you can control the amount of wheat, corn, corn meal and types of proteins found in the dog food.

I hope that you’ll see some great positive behavioral changes with your new dog food soon.

To see the original article check out:
 http://www.examiner.com/x-13263-Baltimore-Dog-Training-Examiner~y2009m7d6-Homemade-dog-food-may-help-resolve-behavior-problems 
 
Technorati Tags: dog food allergy , dog food recipes , homemade dog food recipes , make dog food 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes , make dog food | Tags: dog food allergy , dog food recipes , homemade dog food recipes , make dog food | 3 Comments» 
 Is Fluoride too high in your pet food? 
 July 17th, 2009 | Author: admin 
Recently, 8 out of 10 dog foods tested by an independent laboratory were found to have between 1.6 and 2.5 times higher than recommended drinking water levels of fluoride according to a report by the Environmental Working Group (EWG). The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) set the levels we are talking about for humans. So the next question that I have is what is the recommended amount of fluoride for a dog? Unfortunately, according to the study,“Scientists have not studied the safety of high doses of fluoride for dogs”. It is also noted that these numbers are just based on the amount of fluoride in the food itself. If your water supply is fortified with fluoride, and many are, then your dog will be getting even more fluoride than what they get just from the food itself.
 
It appears that the excess fluoride is coming from bone meal, which are fillers that are used in commercial dog food. The two brands that had undetectable amounts of fluoride (which was 0.2 mg/kg) in the dog food did not contain bone meal. The eight brands that had high fluoride listed ingredients that included chicken by-product meal, poultry by-product meal and beef&amp;bone meal. What exactly is bone meal? Bone meal is essentially ground up bones of animals.
 
The effects of excess fluoride on humans are mottled teeth (dental fluorosis) and weakened bones, leading to more fractures. There is other evidence in humans that high fluoride consumption is associated with reproductive and developmental system damage, neurotoxicity, hormonal disruption, and bone cancer.
 
So what do you do? Well if you feed your dog commercial dog food, you first need to look at the ingredients. If your dog food has bone meal listed as one of the ingredients, then you have several choices. First, since there are not any studies on the effect of fluoride on dogs, you can make the decision to do nothing and continue to feed your dog your current dog food. Second, you can use the recommended levels of fluoride listed for humans set by the EPA as a guideline and therefore assume dog food with bone meal may have too much fluoride for your dog and look for dog food that contain little to no bone meal listed in its ingredients.
 
Lastly, you can decide to stop using commercial dog food all together and use this report as another reason why you should make your own dog food. Homemade dog food recipes exist for those of you that want to take this route. Most people who contemplate making their own dog food do so mainly because of unhealthy or hazardous ingredients added to the dog food, which was the case in 2007 when dog food was contaminated with melamine. However, Fluoride in proper amounts is not harmful to humans, but excess amounts are. Fluoride is not a listed ingredient in dog food and most people probably would not even think about checking the fluoride level. As many people believe, by making your own dog food, you know exactly what your pet is getting. When you buy commercial dog food, we are finding out that more and more by-products are being added that are not healthy for your dog.
 
The choice is up to you and more importantly the health of your dog.
 
If you are interested in the original article check out:

 http://www.ewg.org/pethealth/report/fluoride-in-dog-food 
 
Technorati Tags: homemade dog food recipes 
 Posted in make dog food | Tags: homemade dog food recipes | 14 Comments» 
 Homemade Dog Food Recipes: Ingredients versus Nutrition 
 July 10th, 2009 | Author: admin 
I read an interesting post here that talked about difference between ingredients and nutrition in homemade dog food recipes and I have to tell you, it was a good eye opener. I mean, I usually look at the ingredients that are listed on a commercial dog food product and/or look at the ingredients in a recipe, but I’m mainly looking for those things that are harmful or questionable. I really didn’t consider looking at it as being nutritious.

In the blog post by Garry Neale, he says,“It’s not the combination of ingredients that determines the quality of your dog’s diet and whether or not the dog’s nutritional needs are being met, it’s the blend of nutrients”. So even though what’s listed on the ingredients, it’s really the interaction of those ingredients that really determine if the meal is going to be nutritious for your pet.

In fact, he says,“The ingredients in dog food only have to do with digestibility and palatability. A given dog food can contain certain ingredients that have no nutritional value or that can’t be digested by your dog.”I guess you can think of it like eating at a fast food restaurant or eating at home. The ingredients themselves at a fast food restaurant are not harmful in themselves, but they are not necessarily nutritious for you, especially if you ate at a fast food restaurant every single day.

Nutrition is the quality of the homemade dog food recipe . Ingredients would be the quantity if you will. It’s much better to have quality over quantity and in the same way, it’s better to have nutrition over ingredients if that makes sense. That is why it is advised that you consult with your veterinarian or a dog nutritionist before you use any recipe that you find on the internet. While the recipe you found may have all“valid”ingredients (i.e., nothing harmful), the recipe itself may not be nutritious for your dog. Also, remember, what might be nutritious for one dog may not be nutritious for your dog. Nutrition also has a lot to do with the breed, age, health and activity of your dog.

So play it safe, evaluate the nutritional values of any homemade dog food recipes that you find before feeding them to your pet.
 
Technorati Tags: homemade dog food recipes 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | Tags: homemade dog food recipes | 2 Comments» 
 What concerns should you have with Homemade Dog Food? 
 July 7th, 2009 | Author: admin 
Most people who provide homemade dog food recipes on the internet are usually well meaning people, however they have one problem in general; they are not dog nutritionists. They might be just rehashing a recipe that they found that is indeed healthy and nutritious for your dog, or it might be a recipe that they made up on their own, which could be unhealthy or actually harmful to your dog. How do you know, whom do you trust?

So what should you do? I am by no means a veterinarian, nor am I a dog nutritionist, so I’m very cautious when it comes to homemade dog food recipes because I really don’t know just by looking at a recipe if it is going to be both healthy and nutritious. Therefore, you might want to get educated on the nutrition requirements for your dog. You can find a great pamphlet here:“ Your Dog’s Nutritional Needs. A Science-Based Guide for Pet Owners .”

Ok, let’s say that you didn’t want this to be a high school exercise to learn your dog’s nutritional needs. What are your options then? I would suggest first check with a local veterinarian and see if he or she has any knowledge on dog nutrition. However, unless you live in a rather big city, the probability is low that your vet will have the necessary knowledge and experience to help you with your dog’s nutritional needs with your homemade dog food recipes . Nevertheless, it’s a great starting point. The next question is if you find one that has the proper knowledge and experience, what are they going to charge you? Don’t be surprised to be charged anywhere from $100 to $250 per recipe.

If you are going to pay money with your local vet and/or if your local vet doesn’t have the experience or time to help you, another option is to check online. Balance IT is a site that has created software that allows them to create recipes that are custom for your dog. Costs start at $20 for the first recipe and drop to $12.50 for additional recipes. The other site is PetDiets.com , and they too can create custom homemade dog food recipes for your dog. The costs are $25 for the first recipe and then $12 for each recipe after that.

No matter which way you go, make sure to do your homework first so that you can provide your dog with the best nutritious and safe dog food that you can provide them.


 
 
Technorati Tags: homemade dog food recipes 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes , make dog food | Tags: homemade dog food recipes | 2 Comments» 
 Five Reasons to Make Your Own Dog Food 
 July 5th, 2009 | Author: admin 
1. As I am sure, you can remember back in 2007 when many of pets became severely ill and others died even though a mass recall of pet food was done. The problem was because of pet food that was produced in China being contaminated with melamine. This led to many owners becoming more aware of such problems. The solution is to follow homemade dog food recipes .

2. Another reason to consider homemade dog food recipes is to ensure your pet is as healthy as possible. Commercial dog foods can contain preservatives that are altered by chemical processes, which can be unhealthy for dogs. The main problem with most commercial kibble food is that they contain too much low quality protein that contains a high quantity of ammonia producing agents. Homemade dog food can be healthier than the store-bought variety when it is made correctly, but make sure to consult a veterinarian’s supervision as you go forward and make your own dog food.

3. These days most of us are interested in saving money anyway we can do so. The cost of dog food is ridiculous. If you own several pets or one with a huge appetite, it can be a strain to feed them quality foods due to the cost. When you make homemade dog food though you can be sure they get the quality nutrition that they need. For the quality, you can do so at a much lower cost. You will find it also does not take that much time for you to make enough to feed them all week long.

4. There is some evidence that when you create you make your own dog food, because it is free from preservatives and other chemicals that your dog will live longer. This is especially true if your dog has allergies or other ailments. While I couldn’t find any specific evidence to this fact, it makes sense to me that by preventing your dog from eating preservatives and other chemicals that your dog will live a longer and more enjoyable life.

5. I think that this one is such a great reason to make your own dog food and that your dog will be happier. Don’t you feel better when you’re eating healthy, and doesn’t that in turn make you feel happier? I know it does for me. I think that it translates directly to your dog too. When your dog is eating food that you made, knowing that only good quality ingredients are in the recipe, your dog is going to be healthy and therefore happier. You’ll see it on your dog’s demeanor and in their actions towards you and the rest of your family. Yes using homemade dog food recipes can definitely make your dog happier.

These are just some reasons that I believe that making your own dog food will pay huge dividends over your dog’s life when you make your own dog food.

 
Technorati Tags: homemade dog food recipes 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes , make dog food | Tags: homemade dog food recipes | 2 Comments» 
 Thinking About Making Your Own Dog Food, Here Are Great Homemade Dog Food Recipes 
 June 21st, 2009 | Author: admin 
Before I share the actual recipes for you, I wanted to go over some basic concepts for homemade dog food recipes :

An appropriately balanced dog food diet contains roughly 40% meat, 30% starch and 30% vegetables. An individual recipe doesn’t have to contain those ratios absolutely as long as your dog’s overall diet is in that ratio.

- Meat: Any general type will do. Make sure that you cook the meat. While so will argue that dogs used to eat raw meat before they were domesticated and therefore okay to serve raw, they are forgetting one thing. Meat from today’s manufacturers is more likely to contain bacteria because of the mass production versus a wild animal. So, to be on the safe side, cook the meat. Also, by the way, remove the bones, either before or after cooking so as to remove any choking hazard.

- Starch: Almost any starch will do here; rice, potatoes and pasta.

- Vegetables: Vegetables should be cooked so as to reduce being a choking hazard.

Foods to Avoid:
o Alcoholic beverages
o Coffee or Tea or other caffeine products. These can cause problems with the heart and nervous system
o Citrus oil extracts; can cause vomiting
o Grapes and raisins can cause damage to the kidneys
o Too much liver can cause vitamin A toxicity
o Macadamia nuts contain a toxin that affects the digestive and nervous system

Ok, now on to the homemade dog food recipes :

Here’s a Chicken Stew Dog Food Recipe that I think your dog will enjoy.

Ingredients:
* Whole chicken, 2½pounds
* Whole barley, 8 ounces
* Rolled Oats, 6 ounces
* Green peas, 1 cup
* Carrots, 1 cup coarsely chopped
* Sweet potato,½cup coarsely chopped
* Zucchini,½cup coarsely chopped
* Yellow squash,½cup coarsely chopped
* Green beans,½cup coarsely chopped
* Celery,½cup coarsely chopped
* Kelp powder, 1 tablespoon
* Dried Rosemary, 1 tablespoon
* Water, 16 cups (or enough to cover the ingredients)

Instructions:

Combine all ingredients in a 10-quart stainless-steel stockpot with enough water to cover. Bring to a boil, then turn down the heat as low as possible and simmer for two hours–the carrots should be quite soft at the end of the cooking time. Remove from the heat, let cool, and debone the chicken.

With an electric hand mixer, or using a food processor and working in batches, blend all the ingredients into a puree. Using seal-a-meal, zip lock bags or plastic yogurt containers, make up meal-sized portions (see below). Refrigerate what you’ll need for three days and freeze the rest.

Serving size:

Amounts will vary depending on age, activity level, health, weight and season, but here are some guidelines: The amount shown below should be split into at least 2 meals daily.

Dog’s Weight/Daily Portion

   * Up to 10 pounds–1 to 1½cups
   * 11 to 20 pounds–2 to 3 cups
   * 21 to 40 pounds–4 cups

For each additional 20 pounds, add two cups.

Thanks for Halo for sharing this recipe: The original recipe can be found at http://www.petfoodindustry.com/ViewNews.aspx?id=23278 

 
Technorati Tags: homemade dog food recipes 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | Tags: homemade dog food recipes | No Comments» 
 Proposed dog food flavorings plant files for IDEM permit–Winchester News Gazette 
 May 2nd, 2011 | Author: admin 

 Proposed dog food flavorings plant files for IDEM permit 
 Winchester News Gazette 
While a formal announcement is perhaps a month away, the process remains underway to establish a proposed dog food flavorings plant at a rural Union City, Ind., site. Naturally Recycled Proteins (NRP) Wednesday submitted … 

 

 Read the rest of this entry» 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | No Comments» 
 Dog food tested after scare–Primedia Broadcasting–Eyewitness News 
 April 30th, 2011 | Author: admin 

 Dog food tested after scare 
 Primedia Broadcasting–Eyewitness News 
The dog food brands believed to have caused the deaths of a number of pets in Gauteng, have been pulled from the shelves pending further tests. Food acidity tests were being conducted on the locally produced brands including Hi-Pro, Legends and Buddies … 

 

 Read the rest of this entry» 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | No Comments» 
 Meals on Wheels In Desperate Need of Pet Food Donations–News Channel 7 
 April 27th, 2011 | Author: admin 

 Meals on Wheels In Desperate Need of Pet Food Donations 
 News Channel 7 
Seman told News Channel 7 they have only about 20 bags of dog food left to feed more than 100 clients pets. She said if they don&apos;t get more food they may not be able to continue the program.&quot;We know there are so many pet lovers out there and would … 

 

 Read the rest of this entry» 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | No Comments» 
 How much can dogs give people?–The Republic 
 April 25th, 2011 | Author: admin 

 How much can dogs give people? 
 The Republic 
You know, the one where this-town-ain&apos;t-big-enough-for-both-of-us. He&apos;ll have a few choice growls for Blackie somewhere down the line. Meanwhile, he&apos;ll stick around the corral, eating his home-cooked dog food (with gound turkey and rice – OK? … 

 and more » 

 Read the rest of this entry» 
 Posted in homemade dog food recipes | 5 Comments» «Older Entries Categories 
 dog biscuit recipes homemade dog food recipes homemade dog treats make dog food Uncategorized 
 Pages 
 Contact us Privacy Policy 
 Tags and Animal Balance BalanceIT.com best canine clips Delaney diy dog dog&apos;s diet dogfood dog food dog food recipes dogs Dr. food free grooming health healthy home homemade homemade dog food homemade dog food recipes how ingredients IT Luvbeags made make dog food natural organic pet pets puppies puppy recall recipe recipes Sean to treats videos wellness Search for: Search Archives 
 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 
 Meta 
 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Copyright Homemade Dog Food Recipes Blog. All Rights Reserved. / Labrador Retriever / Music text 
Download from Pets Wordpress Themes
	</body>
</document>
