<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007528" url="http://blog.bluefur.com/2009/03/17/business-101-revenuegenerating-products/" time="2012-07-13-00:30" support="3" score="0.004555164829963499" bingtitle="Business 101: Non Revenue-Generating Products « BlueFur.com" webtitle="Business 101: Non Revenue-Generating ProductsBlueFur.com">
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>... these were left open for use at the condiment stand, the same place where you’d find straws and napkins. ... Can you imagine going to a fast food restaurant and being ...</description>
	<body>
		CANADA WEB HOSTING 
 Bluefur - Canada Web Hosting 
 
 BlueFur.com Hosting Services Help&amp;Support About Us Contact 
 
Business 101: Non Revenue-Generating Products
 Published on Mar 17, 2009   //    Business Topics 6 
 

Most businesses have some products in their lineup that do not directly generate any revenue. When you go to a coffee shop, for example, you are given“free”napkins, sugar, cream, stir sticks, disposable paper cups, and so on. When you go to a clothing store, you are offered a“free”shopping bag to tote your purchase back home. These are all valid expenses for their respective businesses, but they do not generate any revenue on their own.

This does not mean, necessarily, that you should try your best to abandon these products altogether. They add to the customer experience and most customers come to expect these so-called“extras”when they visit the related establishments. However, some companies are really starting to cut back on these kinds of items, because they hurt the bottom line without directly helping it.

One of the best examples that I’ve personally experienced recently was at the movie theatre. Although I don’t normally partake, I decided to buy myself some popcorn. The person behind the counter asked if I wanted butter, telling me that it would be an extra charge. Many people would then opt out of the butter, but the person behind the counter never offered the complimentary margarine substitute . The margarine does not generate income on its own, but the butter does.

Further still, I used to expect the ability to douse my bag of popcorn with a variety of flavored shakers. In the past, these were left open for use at the condiment stand, the same place where you’d find straws and napkins. A few years ago, movie theatres removed those shakers, but the flavored powder was still made available from behind the counter in small Dixie cups. They were still complimentary and you could have as many as you wanted. During my most recent visit, there were no shakers at the condiment stand nor where the Dixie cups of flavored powder made available. They were not being directly offered in any way.

After I finished my movie, I noticed a small sign (only next to one of the six available cash registers) that said you could have one complimentary pouch of flavored powder with each bag of popcorn. Additional pouches, which were remarkably small, would come at an extra charge. Not only am I paying an inordinate amount of money for the popcorn itself; you have to insult me with these small extra charges for what should already be made available for free.

Can you imagine going to a fast food restaurant and being charged for the ketchup? These added costs should be factored into the purchase price. It’s all about the customer’s perception of how you run your business.
 Share This Article: 
6 Comments to“Business 101: Non Revenue-Generating Products”

 
 Dr. Cossack 
March 17, 2009 4:43 pm
 
It’s not like those popcorn flavors are expensive to produce either…I can understand why some businesses want to keep their costs at a minimum, but it shouldn’t bring down the consumer’s experience either. That’s especially true for coffee shops: in a mid-size to large town, you can usually find two or three of those within a city block. If one is being too cheap, it’s very easy to go to the next building…
 
 sarcasmom 
March 17, 2009 6:36 pm
 
I agree with your sentiments. I do, however, work for a large retailer. I see how the rising cost of all the expected amenities is making it harder to show a profit. We may keep giving you free bags for your groceries,, but your wait in line will be longer because we can’t pay as many people to ring them up. We may all have to readjust our expectations.
 
 gadgets 
March 18, 2009 4:11 am
 
Yes, I too have come across many companies that back on such kinds of items, because they do not get benefit whatsoever.
 
 Ruby Web 
March 18, 2009 8:25 am
 
The old days of handfulls of ketchup sachets and serviettes are long gone, as the pursuit of the bottom line profit is causing most businesses to tighten their belts. Tough economic climes is causing a general belt tightening, which is filtering through everywhere…
 
 Donna 
March 18, 2009 10:46 am
 
This was a very well written article.

I totally agree with you that the little not-for-profit perks add value to the overall customer experience.

Thanks for sharing!
 
 clickktdotcom 
March 19, 2009 6:09 am
 
Great article. I feeling love your blog. Nice theme.
Thanks for sharing!
 
 
Categories

 BlueFur Customer of the Week (86) BlueFur News (6) Business Topics (225) Cartoon (97) Contest (36) DealDotCom (4) Development (248) Did You Know (35) Discussion (51) Emerging Markets (21) Events (106) Fantastico Updates (31) Gadgets (230) Geek of the Week (104) Guest Post (2) In the Sphere (229) Managed Blog Hosting (5) Marketing Tips (270) Network Issues (9) News Worthy (120) Phish Phinder (9) Polls (99) Reviews (28) Security (25) Showcase Saturday (87) Social Media (48) Top Post (4) Tutorials (8) Video (17) Web Development (2) Weekend Projects (59) WordPress (262) 
 
Archives

 December 2011  (1) October 2011  (2) September 2011  (30) August 2011  (31) July 2011  (31) June 2011  (30) May 2011  (31) April 2011  (30) March 2011  (31) February 2011  (28) January 2011  (32) December 2010  (32) November 2010  (31) October 2010  (31) September 2010  (30) August 2010  (31) July 2010  (31) June 2010  (30) May 2010  (31) April 2010  (30) March 2010  (31) February 2010  (28) January 2010  (27) December 2009  (27) November 2009  (26) October 2009  (32) September 2009  (32) August 2009  (42) July 2009  (113) June 2009  (63) May 2009  (58) April 2009  (61) March 2009  (68) February 2009  (69) January 2009  (74) December 2008  (55) November 2008  (54) October 2008  (55) September 2008  (53) August 2008  (53) July 2008  (55) June 2008  (50) May 2008  (52) April 2008  (52) March 2008  (52) February 2008  (50) January 2008  (54) December 2007  (52) November 2007  (54) October 2007  (56) September 2007  (53) August 2007  (56) July 2007  (58) June 2007  (54) May 2007  (52) April 2007  (35) March 2007  (34) February 2007  (29) January 2007  (10) December 2006  (6) November 2006  (6) October 2006  (3) September 2006  (1) August 2006  (1) July 2006  (1) June 2006  (4) May 2006  (2) April 2006  (2) March 2006  (4) February 2006  (4) 
 
 Canada Web Hosting 

Our servers are all located in premium Canadian datacenters !
 
 Web Hosting Wizard 

Answer a few simple questions and we will recommend a package that will best fit your needs .
 
 Coupons&amp;Specials 

View our current coupons and specials to help you save money.
 ©1997 - 2010 BlueFur.com. Terms of Service :: Privacy Policy 

 Web Hosting :: Managed Blog Hosting :: Dedicated Servers :: Email Hosting :: Domain Names 
 Client Login :: Who We Are :: Contact Us :: Support Knowledgebase :: Our Blog 
 Hosting in Canada : Vancouver - Calgary - Edmonton - Regina - Winnipeg - Toronto - Ottawa - Montreal - Halifax
	</body>
</document>
