<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007120" url="http://www.accidentaid.co.uk/compensation_wrist_injury.php" time="2012-07-13-00:06" support="1" score="0.0006833971466943508" bingtitle="Accidents Leading to Wrist Injury Claims - Car Accident Claim ..." webtitle="Accidents Leading to Wrist Injury Claims">
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>... slipped in a large fast food restaurant. ... In order to promote consistency and ... lasting pain and stiffness, a claimant should expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Our Service  |  Free 
 Assessment  |  Advice&amp;Guidance  |  FAQ&apos;s  |  How much could you claim? Quadriplegia Paraplegia Brain Damage Eye Injury Deafness Chest Injury Lung Disease Asbestosis Related Disease Asthma Related Injury Neck Injury Back Injury Shoulder Injury Pelvic and Hip Injury Arm Injury (Amputations) Arm Injury (Non Amputations) Elbow Injury Wrist Injury Hand Injury Finger Injury Thumb Injury Leg Injury Knee Injury |  Contact Us   
 
 
 
 First Name  Last Name  Contact Number  Best time to call  9am-12pm 12pm-3pm 3pm-6pm 6pm-9pm -- please select injury type -- whiplash injury repetitive strain injury arm or hand injury eye injury spinal chord injury leg injury other injury Contact me 
 
 
 
 NO FEE WIN OR 
 LOSE You talk directly 
 to a qualified Solicitor 

   &quot;Excellent service. Got my personal injury money within 3 months&quot; Mr. 
 Goldman, Age 42 won 3,300 following a road traffic accident 

 Latest 
 News: Porthole damage compensation on the rise. Kendal Worker Awarded£300,000 for Crushing Injury. 
 

 View all latest 
 news. 
 

   
 
 
 
 Success Stories View more&gt;&gt; Mr J. 
 B. 
 Recovered 
 6000 for his injuries when he slipped in 
 a large fast food restaurant. 
 
 More 
 information on claims: -- please select 
 an injury type -- Whiplash Injuries Repetitive 
 Strain Injuries Back Injuries Arm and Hand 
 Injuries Neck 
 Injuries Eye 
 Injuries Spinal Chord 
 Injuries Leg 
 Injuries or: -- please select 
 an accident type -- Road Traffic 
 Accident Pedestrian 
 Accident Motorcylce 
 Accident Cycling Accident Car Driver 
 Accident Passenger 
 Accident Accident at Work Slipping 
 or Tripping Accident Defective 
 Product Other Accident 
 Types 
 
 
Amount of Compensation

 In order to promote consistency and 
 assist the courts, personal injury solicitors 
 and other advisers, the Judicial Studies Board 
 publish a set of guidelines for the level of injury 
 awards for a broad range of injuries. The information, 
 which follows, has been taken from those guidelines. 
 Whilst the guidelines are very useful and provide a good 
 general indicator of the level of damages which may be 
 paid, it should be remembered that no two cases are ever 
 the same and general damage claims for injuries 
 resulting from accidents will always reflect the 
 individual circumstances of the particular in dividual 
 and the injuries he or she has suffered and claims will 
 be assessed accordingly. 

 

Accidents Leading to Wrist Injury Claims

 There is quite a large range within which compensation awards for wrist injury may be paid.  

 Of course, as with any other personal injury, the amount of compensation would depend upon the seriousness of the injury and the effect on the individual. 

 In personal injuries to the wrist where there is a complete loss of ability to use the joint, compensation awards would be expected to be in the region of 24,750 through to 31,000. 

 Where there is a large degree of disability but the accident victim still has some use of the wrist, compensation awards would be lower and within the bracket 12,750 to 20,000. 

 Where the injury to the wrist settles relatively quickly but there is a degree of permanent disability and some lasting pain and stiffness, a claimant should expect his claim to be paid between 6,500 and 12,750. Where wrist Injury heals completely with no residual disability, deformity or cosmetic effect, one should expect claims to be settled for between 4,000 and 5,000. 

To make a claim either call 
 Accident Aid on 0800 180 4780 or forward your query 
 without any obligation to Accident Aid by email and you 
 will be contacted by an accident injury lawyer who will 
 advise as to whether you may be entitled to claim 
 compensation for your injury and any other losses you 
 may have sustained.

           
 
 
 Injury Types Accident types Amounts Advice 
 
Common Injury Types
 Whiplash Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Repetitive 
 Strain Personal Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Back Personal Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Arm and Hand Personal 
 Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Neck 
 Personal Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Eye Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Spinal Chord Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Leg Injury Claims&gt;&gt; 
Accident types our experience
 Road 
 Traffic Accident Claims&gt;&gt;
 Pedestrian Accident Claims&gt;&gt;
 Motorcycle 
 Accidents Claims&gt;&gt;
 Cycling Accidents Claims&gt;&gt;
 Car Driver Accident 
 Claims&gt;&gt;
 Passengers Accidents Injuries 
 Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents 
 at Work Injuries Claims&gt;&gt;
 Slipping or Tripping 
 Accidents Injuries Claims&gt;&gt;
 Defective Products Accidents 
 Injuries Claims&gt;&gt;
 Other Types of Accidents Injuries 
 Claims&gt;&gt; 
Potential accident compensation amounts
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Claims for Quadriplegia&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Claims for Paraplegia&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Claims for Brain Damage&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Claims for Eye Injuries&gt;&gt;
 Accident Causing Injuries 
 Resulting in Claims for Deafness&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Chest Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Claims for 
 Asbestosis Related Disease Injuries&gt;&gt;
 Claims for Lung Disease&gt;&gt;
 Claims for 
 Asthma Related Injuries&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Neck Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Resulting in 
 Back Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Shoulder 
 Injuries Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Pelvic 
 and Hip Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Arm 
 Injury Claims (Amputations)&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Arm 
 Injury Claims (Non Amputations)&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to 
 Elbow Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to 
 Wrist Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Hand 
 Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to 
 Finger Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to 
 Thumb Injury Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Leg 
 Injuries Compensation Claims&gt;&gt;
 Accidents Leading to Knee 
 Injury Compensation Claims&gt;&gt; 
Advice and guidance
 Action Following Road Traffic 
 Accidents&gt;&gt;
 Action Following Slipping 
 and Tripping Accidents&gt;&gt;
 Action Following Workplace 
 Accidents&gt;&gt;
 Action Following 
 Accidents involving Defective Products&gt;&gt; 
 
 
 
Accident Aid is a trading style of Longfords Solicitors which is 
 regulated by the Solicitors Regulation Authority. Reg No. 423192                                 2011 All information contained within this website is protected by 
 copyright law
	</body>
</document>
