<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007385" url="http://www.cereplast.com/blog/" time="2012-07-13-00:21" support="2" score="0.0013127618822571388" bingtitle="Cereplast — We make bioplastics" webtitle="Cereplast — We make bioplastics">
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001060" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>Similarly, to reduce food waste, Bon Appétit ... live in areas where it&apos;s easier to find a fast-food restaurant than ... you will see the difference on your power bill. The ...</description>
	<body>
		Cereplast 

plastic, reimagined
 Search 
 Tweet 
 English Spanish Italian French German 

Language
 
 Home Products 
 Cereplast Compostables® Cereplast Sustainables® Technology Where to Buy Pellets Where to Buy Products 
 RezInnovation™ Bioplastics 
 Life Cycle Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) End of Life Glossary 
 Company 
 Our Mission History Corporate Governance Board of Directors Management Committees Jobs 
 Investors 
 Press Releases 
 Press Articles 
 Events and Presentations Corporate Governance 
 Management Board of Directors Committees Contact the Board 
 Financial Information 
 SEC Filings Annual Reports Quarterly Results Key Ratios 
 Stock Information 
 Historic Stock Lookup Investment Calculator Dividend History Analyst Coverage Ownership Profile 
 Investor FAQs Contact Us 
 News 
 Cereplast in the News Press Releases Videos Newsletters Event Calendar Webcasts&amp;Presentations 
 Blog Contact 
 You are here: Home » Blog 
 Environmental Film Hopes to Show Effects of Plastic on the Environment and Wildlife 

by Cereplast on June 28, 2012 
 
 

 Laysan Albatross killed by ingesting plastic. Flickr user Ars Electronica 

A new environmental film called Midway by photographer Chris Jordan aspires to show the effects of plastic on the environment and wildlife. The Laysan Albatross dwells in the North Pacific, more than two thousand miles from any mainland continent, and yet is being ravaged by our plastic waste . The birds are ingesting plastic from the Pacific Ocean Garbage Patch because they, like many other animals, mistake plastic for food. The ensuing environmental tragedy is the subject of Chris Jordan’s documentary which hopes to tell the story of the Laysan Albatross that live on the Midway Atoll . 
 
 Watch the Midway trailer and be prepared to be moved.

 
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 2 comments } 
 
 Wildlife Preservation: Discover Another Face of American Wildlife on the Nat Geo Channel 

by Anne Englebert on June 25, 2012 
 
 
 Discover stunning American wildlife photographs and videos on National Geographic Channel 

 

Just beyond our cities is a wild and untamed world that the Nat Geo Channel explores in a breathtaking four-part documentary. The show Untamed Americas showcases american wildlife and emphasizes the importance of wildlife preservation by revealing the natural beauties of the mountains, deserts, forests and coasts.

Making the series took over 2 years and was a big logistical challenge. The filmmakers travelled thousands of miles from Alaska to Patagonia to capture the extreme wildlife of the continent. They decided to organize the program into four themes to enable the audiences to really appreciate the variety and diversity of the different types of landscapes and to take the same journey as the team did, down to the American Cordillera.

The four-hour miniseries explores the Americas with amazing footage of stories and events: 
 

 From awakened black bears, newborn elk calves to the Rockies, discover the Mountains of Americas From male gentoo penguins to the Sea of Cortez off the Mexican Coast, the Coasts of Americas features some of the greatest spectacles on Earth Explore the deserts of Americas , where wildlife such as mustangs, lizards and Humboldt penguins have developed an array of survival strategies Take a through the forests of Americas where the animals living there endure extremes  such as floods, freezing temperatures and fires 
 
 

“I want to make people aware of it, to care about it and experience it for themselves,”says producer Karen Bass .“Let’s not kid ourselves that we understand our planet, because we don’t. It’s inspiration. It’s revelation.” Untamed Americas is an environmental program that aims to raise audience awareness about wildlife preservation and points to our environmental responsibility to preserve these species and lands from man-made threats.
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 London 2012 Summer Olympics: The Most Green Olympics Yet? 

by Anne Englebert on June 19, 2012 
 
 
 When London won the right to host the 2012 Olympics, former Prime-Minister Tony Blair promised a greener summer Olympic Games. Flickr User: Chris John Beckett 

After the brilliant green step made by Vancouver for the 2010 Winter Olympics , London is expecting to make the London 2012 Summer Olympics even greener. In 2005, the London Organising Committee of the Olympic and Paralympic Games ( LOCOG ) pledged to organize the first sustainable Summer Olympic and Paralympic Games . Yet, every Olympic Games always make the same promises to be bigger, cleaner and greener. With only a few weeks left before the opening ceremony, will the pledge of being the most green olympics yet be delivered? 

Making a short-term event such as the Summer Olympics sustainable is a quiet complex task. The Athens games are a great example of wasted facilities, all abandoned and covered with graffiti. It is the 2004 Olympic legacy that LOCOG wanted to avoid by presenting an ambitious and sustainable plan for the 2012 summer Olympics : Towards a One Planet 2012 . 

 

 Coming with the organization of the Olympics, in 2007, the British Standards Institution created a new standard: BS 8901 that has been developed “specifically for the events industry with a purpose of helping the industry to operate in a more sustainable manner. The standard defines the requirements for a sustainability event management system to ensure an enduring and balanced approach to economic activity, environmental responsibility and social progress relating to events.” The same year, the Commission for a Sustainable London 2012 was created to meet BS8901 requirements. 

 
 Sustainability is at the heart of the Games, from brown to green. Flickr User: Andy Wilkes 

 

 

 Sustainable Development has been taken into account since the beginning of the Olympics organization . In Olympics Park , rainwater has been collected in order to reduce the amount of potable water used in the buildings. The construction firms have a water reduction target of 40 percent! 

 
 

 In Olympics Park , visitors and athletes will mainly find organic and local foods . They will also be encouraged to recycle and compost their waste by sorting between different bins. 

 
 

 Venues: In order to respect the initial budget (around 11 billion), the LOCOG has limited the construction of new venues that would probably become useless at the end of the Games. When it was possible, the committee decided to use existing venues such as Wimbledon. If facilities could be reused, they were built with an effort to reduce the environmental impact of the construction process. For example, the Olympic Stadium is described as the greenest yet . It has been built using low carbon concrete , which sees a 40% reduction in the use of carbon. When no future reuse was identified, the LOCOG asked for temporary Olympics constructions that can be removed and reused at other events. Demountable, and reusable buildings replace permanent structures to meet the challenge to build memorable yet sustainable venues. 

 
 After the Games, the basketball arena will be dismantled and used for other sporting events. Flickr User; canonsnapper 

 

 Olympics Park has been built on a former polluted, deprived and neglected industrial zone of east London. 2 million tons of polluted ground have been cleaned and reused. 

 
 

 
During London 2012, around 17,700 athletes and officials will stay in 3,300 apartments in the Village. After the Games, the Olympic Village will be transformed into 2,800 homes for the underprivileged population of the area.
 
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 Rising Sea Levels May Significantly Increase Coastal Flood Risk in the U.S. by 2050 

by Anne Englebert on June 14, 2012 
 
 

 “All low elevation places in the many urban areas along the coast will become more vulnerable, like Boston, New York City, Norfolk (Va.), New Orleans, Charleston (S.C.), Miami, Washington, D.C./Alexandria (Va.),”said S. Jeffress Williams, scientist for the U.S. Geological Survey, Flickr User: lindenbaum 

It is not only small island nations that must face the effects of rising sea levels ; soon the United States will have to as well. Global warming has raised sea level about eight inches since 1880, and the rate of rise is accelerating. According to a new study from Surging Seas by Climate Centrale , rising seas are dramatically increasing coastal flood risk in the U.S. from storm surges. More than 3 million people from 544 U.S. cities may be affected by extreme coastal floods over the next few decades.

 Sea Level Rise: 
Currently, sea levels around the world are rising. The main factor contributing to the rising ocean level is global warming. The major store of water on land is found in glaciers and ice sheet, and as the atmosphere and ocean water warm due to greenhouse gas emissions , large quantities of ice are melting, contributing to sea level rise. Rising seas dramatically increase the odds of damaging floods. It will force every inhabitant living in a coastal area to confront the risks and the realities of flooding.

The impact of sea level rise on the U.S. coastline :
The c oastline of United States is highly populated—of the 25 most densely populated U.S. counties, 23 are along a coast. The impacts of sea level rise on those particular locations are likely to be severe. According to a new report from Climate Central , the rising ocean level may affect 3.7 million people in 544 U.S. cities. This study makes mid-range projections of 1 to 8 inches by 2030, and 4 to 19 inches by 2050, depending on the location across the contiguous 48 states. These increases are likely to cause enormous damages, mainly in cities located in Florida, Louisiana and New York where most people are living within three feet of high tide (the projected sea level rise by the year of 2100).

 

 In the New York City area, the researchers’ model projects that water will inundate the coast. Statistics accompanying the map explain that over 64,000 people live within 1 foot of the tide line. There is over a one in six chance that rising sea levels in combination with a storm surge and high tide will be 1 foot by 2020 at the New York Harbor (the nearest flood risk indicator site). 

 “Southeast Florida is definitely the highest density of population that’s really on low coastal land that’s really most at risk,” said lead author Ben Strauss, a scientist at Climate Central. Coastal flooding promises to cause billions of dollars of damages over the coming decades. If the rising sea level reaches four feet, it would impact millions of acres of roads, bridges, commercial buildings, agricultural lands, toxic waste, schools, hospitals and many problems that other coastal areas already face such as shoreline erosion . The situation of small island nations around the world should serve as a warning for the U.S.

During the 20th century, the global sea level rose by roughly seven inches due to warmer waters and it is not expected to slow down. For that matter, the U.S. government is working to diminish remaining dangers by preparing programs for higher oceans in coastal counties . Climate Central has also put together a list of plans and resources to help prepare the sea level rise in concerned areas. Some states have already taken actions to adapt to the impacts of climate change on coastal areas:

 Restoring natural storm surge buffers and incorporating climate change into coastal habitat restoration plans Building or repairing dikes, seawalls, and other structures that protect cities from erosion and storms Modifying building codes to enable structures to withstand higher water levels Expanding setbacks (the distance between a structure and the shoreline) and instituting other land-use arrangements to enable wetlands and beaches to migrate inland Upgrading and redesigning infrastructure such as bridges, roads, culverts and stormwater systems Evaluating drinking water supplies with respect to climate change Mapping coastal hazards and developing emergency response plans with regard to sea level rise 

 

 

 Marylandand Virginia’s Coastal Programs have developed a“Living Shorelines”initiative. The initiative promotes alternatives to armoring shorelines with hard structures such as bulkheads and stone revetments, which eliminate wetlands and beaches. Flickr User: ChesapeakeBayFoundation 

For more information on recent and future sea level rise and coastal flood risks in your area, please visit Surging Seas Maps (sea level rise analysis by Climate Central).
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 Environmental Preservation: California Beaches Are Among the Most Polluted in U.S. 

by Anne Englebert on June 13, 2012 
 
Avalon Harbor Beach on Catalina Island (Los Angeles County) has claimed the No.1 spot of the most polluted beaches in the state for the last 11 years. Flickr User: Keoni Cabral
 
On Memorial Day 2012, Coronado Beach in San Diego County was named the best beach in the United States by Dr Stephen Leatherman, director of Florida International University’s Laboratory for Coastal Research. But he is better known as “Dr.Beach” for his annual survey of beaches , ranking the top beaches in U.S. according to 50 categories. Despite Coronado Beach’s high ranking this year, you may not be able to find other California beaches in the rating this year. According to the green organization Heal the Bay , California leads the annual “Beach Bummers” list for the West Coast. So before summer holidays 2012 , here is what every beachgoer should know about beach pollution in California.

 Beach pollution is usually infrequent and mostly confined to local areas but is often a persistent problem. There are different sources of pollution at the beach , yet the primary cause comes from water and marine pollution , mainly due to nearby human activities such as malfunctions of wastewater treatment plants . The majority of beach closings in the United States are due to indications of the presence of high levels of harmful microorganisms found in untreated or partially treated sewage. Untreated storm water runoff from cities and rural areas can be another significant source of pollution. In some areas, boating waste and malfunctioning septic systems can also be significant local sources of beach water pollution .

People who swim in polluted water can be exposed to bacteria, viruses, and protozoans. These pathogens can be present at or near the site where polluted discharges enter the water. Children and people with weakened immune systems are the most likely to develop illnesses or infections after swimming in those areas. The most common illness associated with swimming in polluted water is gastroenteritis; other minor illnesses associated with swimming include ear, eye, nose, and throat infections. In highly polluted water, swimmers may occasionally be exposed to more serious diseases like dysentery, hepatitis, cholera, and typhoid fever.
 
Los Angeles County beaches still lag the state average, with only 82% of beaches getting an A or B grade during summer dry weather. Flickr User: Heal the Bay
 
In California, Los Angeles County leads the annual Beach Bummer List for the state, with seven locations ranking as the state’s 10 most polluted beaches . 

 Top 10 California Beach Bummers 
 1. Avalon Harbor Beach on Catalina Island (Los Angeles County) 
 2. Cowell Beach (Santa Cruz County) 
 3. Puerco Beach at the Marie Canyon storm drain (Los Angeles County) 
 4. Surfrider Beach (Los Angeles County) 
 5. Dan Blocker County Beach at Solstice Creek (Los Angeles County) 
 6. Cabrillo Beach harborside (Los Angeles County) 
 7. Doheny State Beach at San Juan Creek outlet (Orange County) 
 8. Poche Beach (Orange County) 
 9. Escondido State Beach (Los Angeles County) 
 10. Topanga Beach (Los Angeles County) 

For these reasons, the green organization Heal the Bay encourages all beachgoers to check the latest evolution of coastal water quality each week at www.beachreportcard.org , which provides data based on the latest samples. All county health departments are required to test beach water quality at least once a week during the summer season. Heal the Bay c ompiles the complex shoreline data, analyzes it and assigns an easy-to-understand letter grade for beachgoers . All 650 beaches in California, Oregon and Washington are analyzed each year based on levels of weekly bacterial pollution reports.
 
75% of marine pollution comes directly from the continent. FLickr User: NixBC
 
Fortunately, most of the California coastline earn excellent grades in summer dry weather and Los Angeles County is improving every year.

However, ocean water is not the only part of the beach that suffers from human activities.
Sand can also be polluted by waste such as plastic grocery bags, consumer goods, polystyrene containers and other debris. You can help restore a beach by joining a monthly beach cleanup event. It’s a great opportunity to participle in the environmental preservation of your local community.

Human activities have also more and more negative effects on marine life too. Check this post to learn more about marine biodiversity damage. 
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 The Lorax Story Can Help Teach Environmental Preservation to Children 

by Anne Englebert on June 1, 2012 
 
The LORAX is a fictional story about a man who abused the environment and what he learned. Flickr User: Miss_rogue
 

It is crucial that we protect the Earth and preserve the environment for future generations, and we also need to educate our youth about environmental preservation. Kids need to learn why and how to preserve the environment . The best way to explain the concept of sustainable development and environmental protection may be with cartoons and books such as The Lorax. Read on to learn how The Lorax story teaches green issues to children.

The Lorax is one the most popular childrens books . Written by Dr. Seuss and first published in 1972, this fable features a critically important message about environmental responsibility and sustainability. If we do not change the way we produce and consume, our world will soon end up like the one that the Lorax left behind: a grim environment without any animals or plants left.

The Lorax Story :

A young boy residing in a polluted world visits a strange creature called the Once-ler who lives in seclusion. He asks the Once-ler why the world is in such a run-down state. The Once-ler explains to the boy that he arrived in a beautiful, cheerful world containing happy, playful fauna that spent their days romping around blissfully among“ Truffula trees .”The Once-ler begins to cut down the truffula trees , thinking they will help him craft“ Thneeds ,”his invention that he thinks everyone will need. The Lorax, a small orange creature, appears from the stump of a truffula tree . He“speaks for the trees”and warns the Once-ler of the consequences of cutting down the truffula trees , but the Once-ler ignores him. Soon the once beautiful land becomes polluted and the fauna flee to find more hospitable habitats. Eventually the final Truffula tree is cut down, and without Truffulas the Once-ler cannot make any more Thneeds . This leads to the closure of Once-ler’s factory and the disappearance of the Lorax. The Once-ler lingers on in his crumbling residence, living in seclusion and remorse, while pondering over a message the Lorax left behind: a stone slab etched with the word“Unless”. The Once-ler now realizes that the Lorax means that“unless”someone cares, the situation will not improve. The book then returns to the present, ending on an ambiguous yet optimistic note where the Once-ler gives the boy the last Truffula seed and encourages him to plant it so that Truffula trees can return as well as the fauna, and so would the Lorax.
 
Sustainable development is a pattern of economic growth in which resource use aims to meet human needs while preserving the environment so that these needs can be met not only in the present, but also for generations to come. (Wikipedia) Flickr User: Alex E. Proimos
 
The Lorax Story and Sustainable Development Concept :
By using ideas found in the Lorax story , you can easily introduce and explain the tricky definition of sustainable development to your children as well as the huge environmental responsibility given to their generation.

The story contains many common components found in the environmental issues that we are currently facing around the world: lack of natural resources (no more truffula trees in the Lorax Story), air and water pollution, deforestation, critically endangered animals due to human activities (The Lorax had to send the Bar-ba-loots, the swans, and the fish in search of a better place to live while the Trufulla forest was being destroyed), destruction of ecosystem diversity ….

By cutting down the trufulla trees , the Once-ler endangered the planet and realized his mistake too late. The sustainable development focus is to balance quality of life with quality of the environment, something the Once-ler didn’t understand but something the young boy is able to introduce with the last Truffula seed. Thus, your children can identify with him and understand how essential it is to help preserve the environment before it is too late.
 
Raise environmental awareness with this popular childrens book. Flickr User: Chris 1051
 
If you want to go further, your children will love reading the eco-adventures in Carl Hiaasen’s books and become may even become keener than you on green issues !
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 How The City of Los Angeles Intends to Become One of the Greenest Cities in the US 

by Anne Englebert on May 24, 2012 
 
Despite improvements, the 2006 and 2007 annual reports of the American Lung Association ranked Los Angeles as the most polluted city in the country with short-term particle pollution and year-round particle pollution. Flickr User: Slice of Light
 
Located in Southern California, Los Angeles is often equated with air pollution, traffic congestion, urban-sprawl and coal power . Yet, since his election in 2005, mayor Antonio Villaraigosa has launched a very ambitious environmental program to turn Los Angeles into one of the greenest cities in United States. With a very strong green agenda , here is how L.A. may soon become the cleanest and greenest large city in North America.

According to the Brookings Institution, a Washington think tank, Honolulu and the Los Angeles metropolitan area have the smallest carbon footprint among American cities. L.A. is ranked 2nd, in front of Portland and San Francisco, two areas considered among the greenest cities in the U.S. Since 2005, Los Angeles has been taking steps to shrink its carbon footprint to become a model of sustainability.

 Energy 

In 2005, the majority of power Los Angeles used came from coal plants and only 3% came from renewable sources of electricity . The mayor’s office set a goal for the city to hit 20 percent “green” energy by 2010. On January 13, 2011, Mayor Villaraigosa pro­claimed at a City Hall press conference that the Los Angeles Depart­ment of Water and Power (DWP), the city-owned water and electric power utility, had generated 20% of the electricity it sold to its customers in 2010 from renewable energy sources . Thanks to a new strong renewable energy policy , in less than 10 years, the DWP was able to dramatically increase its use of renewable sources from 3% to 20% and successfully achieved its goal.
 
Since 2005, more than 64,000 street lights have been replaced with energy-efficient LEDs. Flickr user: letscommunicate
 
 Green regulations have also been a key to decrease Los Angeles’ energy demand by encouraging green initiatives such as solar panel roof installations and embracing green building practices. Los Angeles now requires all new public buildings to meet LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) standards provided by the US Green Building Council . The city of Los Angeles can now boast seven LEED certified-buildings , among them the Los Angeles Getty Center and the Los Angeles Convention Center , that reached LEED-EB Gold level status for the 4.1 million square feet built on a 54-acre property and became the largest convention center in the nation to achieve this milestone.

 Water 

Being among the most arid regions of California encouraged the city of Los Angeles to lay out a long-term plan to conserve water. The LA Department of Water is the largest consumer of electricity in the state, yet, since 1980, Los Angeles’ water consumption has remained steady despite an increase of more than 1 million people. The LADWP is aiming for“20 by 2020″: reducing residential water usage by 20 percent by 2020. This impressive record has been possible thanks to an aggressive conservation and water recycling program . By 2030, the population of Los Angeles is expected to increase by 500,000 people, pushing up water demand in the City by 15 percent. To meet the growing demand, the Mayor’s water plan – “ Securing LA’s Water Supply ” – calls for meeting half of the new water demand by 2030 through conservation and the other 50 percent by water recycling. 
 
Nationwide, buildings account for 71% of electricity consumption, 12% of potable water used and 40% of the greenhouse gas emissions that, scientists say, are heating the planet to dangerous levels. Flickr User: Prayitno
 
 Transportation and Air quality 

 Since January 2011 , you will not find a diesel bus in the Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transit Authority (Metro) fleet. Today, Metro boasts a fleet of 2,221 Compressed Natural Gas buses, plus six gasoline-electric hybrid buses and one electric bus. Compared with diesel buses , Metro’s new CNG fleet reduces cancer-causing particulate matter by more than 80 percent. Thanks to the switch from diesel to CNG, Metro avoids emitting nearly 300,000 pounds of greenhouse gas emissions per day. The green bus fleet is just one aspect of the clean air action plan .

 According to Nancy Helen Sutley , former deputy mayor for Energy and Environment in Los Angeles:  “ LA hasn’t spent a dime in 15 years on expanding freeway capacity. ” Instead, the city has focused on building carpool lanes, making the city more bike-friendly and expanding public transport.

Developing a better public transportation system also helps improve air quality . Under Mayor Villaraigosa, Los Angeles has made considerable improvements in air quality. “ With the Clean Air Action Plan, Los Angeles is leading the fight to clean air by reducing dirty emissions from the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach, which account for 20 percent of the toxic air emissions in the South Coast Air Basin .” (The Mayor’s First Term air plan .)
 
AltTransport rated LA on of the top 10 cities in the U.S. for public transportation.. Flickr User: Here in Van Nuys
 
 Waste Disposal 

Los Angeles produces 8,000 tons of garbage every day. With limited landfill space , LA needs to recycle and compost green waste. Currently, 71 percent of Los Angeles’ trash is recycled, well above the 33 percent U.S. average, making Los Angeles a leader among major cities with its recycling program .

After the implementation and expansion of the multifamily recycling program and the restaurant food waste program , recycling has increased by 60,000 tons per year since 2005, providing recycling services to more than 380,000 additional multifamily residences with blue bin recycling and 730 restaurants with food waste composting. In addition, collection and recycling of yard trimmings has increased by almost 95,000 tons in the last four years.
 
Waste and Recycling News gave Los Angeles its highest rating for recycling more waste than any other big city in the nation. Flickr User: Lord Jim
 
 Mayor Antonio Villaraigosa created a number of other green initiatives to make Los Angeles a cleaner, greener and more environmentally friendly city:

 The Mayor’s office has launched the community effort Million Trees LA , which is fully focused on planting a million tree throughout the Los Angeles Metropolitan area . In 2005 after his election, Mayor Antonio Villaraigosa challenged the City to open thirty-five park sites. In 2012 the goal was achieved and exceeded: 51 parks have been created around the City! Los Angeles is also among the 1000 American cities that agreed to sign the Kyoto Protocol in 2009 and the city met the Kyoto targets for reducing greenhouse gases four years ahead of schedule! 

Thanks to strict green regulations and an ongoing commitment, the Los Angeles landscape is quickly changing to become one of the greenest big cities in the world. There is still a long way to become a international model of urban sustainability , yet, the City has taken the right green path for a cleaner future .
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 0 comments } 
 
 Carsharing: A Green Initiative That Helps Reduce Air Pollution and Saves Money 

by Anne Englebert on May 22, 2012 
 
Carsharing is a model of car rental where people rent cars for short periods of time, often by the hour. Flickr User: Felixkramer
 
Going car-free in large cities like Los Angeles or Chicago may be quite a challenge, yet it is not impossible. Using your city’s public transportation system or other alternative means of transportation rather than your car are among the green initiatives you can take to help reduce air pollution as well as global car emissions . However, we sometimes do need to drive a car for buying groceries or going on an eco adventure weekend. But what is the point to own a car for so few occasions? Car sharing may be the green solution that will definitely release you from your car and enable you to fully enjoy an urban green lifestyle .

 Car share programs :
 Carsharing is an alternative to car rental and car ownership that offers the benefits of private cars without the costs and responsibilities of ownership. If you typically use public transit, walking or cycling to commute, carsharing can help you on special occasions, to move large items, or to help you do your grocery shopping. Thanks to car share programs, owning a car in large cities is no longer necessary.

 Carsharing also differs from conventional car rentals:

 Reservation, pickup and return is all self-service Vehicles can be rented from an hour to a day Users are paying a monthly membership and have been pre-approved to drive Membership or rates include insurance and fuel costs Car sharing stations are often located near public transportation 
 
Adopting car sharing as primary means of transportation helps save millions of gallons of gas and oil. Flickr User: Antonio Villaraigosa
 
The green benefits of car sharing :
If used on an occasional basis, a shared vehicle costs significantly less than car ownership. The combination of car sharing with public transportation systems saves you money and helps reduce congestion and air pollution. An on-demand car leaves a small environmental footprint : a long-term study published in 2010 by the Transportation Research Board found that 30 percent of households that joined car sharing programs sold a car; others delayed purchasing one. Transit use, bicycling, and walking also increased among members. According to Zipcar , the world’s largest vehicle-sharing company, every Zipcar takes at least 20 personally-owned vehicles off the road. After 11 years, 650,000 Zipcar users are sharing 9,000 cars throughout the world. Imagine how many cars have been removed from the road thanks to this green initiative !

After joining car sharing programs, Zipcar members save more than $500 vs. car ownership! Similarly, by taking cars off the road, on-demand cars directly reduce demand for parking spaces and traffic congestion at peak times. Fewer cars equals fewer emissions of greenhouse gases. 

Make your urban lifestyle greener: walk, ride a bicycle, take the bus or the train, car
share, but above all commute car-free. Car sharing saves you money, it’s greener, more affordable, and less stressful than driving and paying for a car you don’t even need anymore. Public transportations systems reduce your carbon footprint , and car sharing programs can give you the benefits of a car, without the typical cost or carbon footprint.
 Share/Bookmark 
 { 1 comment } 
 
 ←Previous Entries 
 
 
Recent Posts

 Environmental Film Hopes to Show Effects of Plastic on the Environment and Wildlife Wildlife Preservation: Discover Another Face of American Wildlife on the Nat Geo Channel London 2012 Summer Olympics: The Most Green Olympics Yet? Rising Sea Levels May Significantly Increase Coastal Flood Risk in the U.S. by 2050 Environmental Preservation: California Beaches Are Among the Most Polluted in U.S. 
 
Subscribe to the Cereplast Blog
 Subscribe 
Authors

 Anne Englebert Carl Howarth Emily White Frederic Scheer Jeff Cherness Jessica Coffey Kelvin Okamoto Laura Jane Louise Abellard Mark Barton Matthew Golleher Maxime Goualin Nicole Cardi Sheue Lin 
 Powered by Authors Widget 
Facebook
 
Tags
 Algae bioplastics Biobased Bioplastics BioPreferred Carbon Footprint Cereplast Climate change compostable Composting Corn Starch Cosmetics disposable bags eco-friendly businesses eco-friendly products eco-friendly wedding Environmental Activist environmental activists Environmental protection Environmental Responsibility Frederic Scheer Global warming Global warming research Green Holidays green initiatives Green Jobs green living tips Green Technology Legislation Make Your Mark Contest Marine Debris oil crisis oil pricing Oil Spills Plastic plastic alternatives Recycling Renewable Energy Sports Sustainable buildings sustainable eating sustainable farming waste reduction ways to save energy Wildlife Photos Wildlife Preservation 
 
 Site Map Terms of Use FAQ Privacy Policy 
 
 Cereplast on Iizuu Cereplast on Youtube Cereplast on Twitter Cereplast on Linkedin Cereplast on Facebook 
 
Cereplast, Inc. designs and manufactures proprietary biobased, compostable and sustainable bioplastics which are used as substitutes for traditional plastics in all major converting processes - such as injection molding, thermoforming, blow molding and extrusions - at a pricing structure that is competitive with traditional plastics. On the cutting-edge of biobased plastic material development, Cereplast now offers resins to meet a variety of customer demands. Cereplast, Inc. is a public company trading on the NASDAQ Capital Market under the trading symbol CERP.
 
©2012 Cereplast Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
