<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007834" url="http://blogs.laweekly.com/squidink/2011/02/venn_food_diagram_indian_food.php" time="2012-07-13-00:47" support="1" score="0.044888260986583245" bingtitle="Venn Food Diagrams: L.A.&apos;s Idea of Indian Food vs. What Indians ..." webtitle="Venn Food Diagrams: L.A.&apos;s Idea of Indian Food vs. What Indians Really Eat - Los Angeles Restaurants and Dining - Squid Ink">
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>Our continuing series of Venn Food Diagrams ... Venn Food Diagrams: L.A.&apos;s Idea of Indian Food vs. What Indians Really Eat ... Don&apos;t order a dosa (doe-suh) in a Tamilian ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home News Blog Ask a Mexican Archives Search LA Weekly Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Music Home Music Blog Henry Rollins Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Music Ads Restaurants Home Food Blog Find a Restaurant Menus Happy Hours Deals Gold Standard Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Arts Blog Theater Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Film Poll 2011 Film Festivals Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2011 2010 2009 2008 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Alternative Healing MMJ Home MMJ News Dispensary Guide MMJ Newsletter 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 Alcohol&amp;Spirits 

 Moderate Boozing May Prevent Bone Loss in Women 

By Samantha Bonar
 
 100 Favorite Dishes 

 80: Shu Mai at Elite Restaurant 

By Garrett Snyder
 
 Best Of L.A. 

 10 Best Pho Restaurants in Los Angeles 

By Tien Nguyen
 
 Food on Television 

 Q&amp;A With MSNBC&apos;s Chris Hayes: Pastrygate 

By Margy Rochlin
 
 L.A. Restaurants 

 5 Picks for DineLA&apos;s Summer Restaurant Week 

By Garrett Snyder
 
 Cookbook Review 

 The Official High Times Cannabis Cookbook + A Recipe 

By Jenn Garbee
 
 Coffee 

 3 Ways to Make Great Iced Coffee at Home 

By Tien Nguyen
 
 Sports 

 Steve Nash&apos;s Secret Diet + NBA Eating Habits 

By Garrett Snyder
 
 Beer 

 Rogue Brewing Beer From Brewmaster&apos;s Own Beard Yeast 

By Erika Bolden
 
 Alcohol&amp;Spirits 

 10 Best Liquor Stores in Los Angeles 

By Besha Rodell
 
   Venn Food Diagrams 
Venn Food Diagrams: L.A.&apos;s Idea of Indian Food vs. What Indians Really Eat
 By Krishna Narayanamurti Wed., Feb. 16 2011 at 9:00 AM Categories: Indian Cuisine , Venn Food Diagrams 
 Pin It 
 
Our continuing series of Venn Food Diagrams moves from the great American South to an even more controversy-prone collection of states... India.

 
 
 
 
 Methodology: Once again, we conducted an informal survey through e-mail, Facebook, and actually talking to people. Statisticians might scoff at our methods, and no doubt we probably missed a few things, but these diagrams are meant to be a conversation starter, not the whole conversation.

 Conclusion: Our natural curiosity about world cultures and daredevil fascination with spice draw Angelenos to Indian cuisine. With the prevalence and broad range of Indian restaurants and markets available in and around the city, our knowledge has mostly caught up with our appetites.

 Notes: Many of L.A.&apos;s &quot;wrong&quot; answers, like pakoras (fried vegetable appetizers) and naan bread, weren&apos;t really wrong. Indians do eat those things, but not nearly as much as we do (or think that they do).

A revealing item on the overlap - Angelenos and Indians alike raved about malai kofta (veggie balls in a thick, creamy sauce), a delicacy by which any credible North Indian chef should be judged.

Several factors complicate any attempt to define the food of a billion-plus Indians around the world. Credit for malai kofta&apos;s origin belongs to the Mughal Empire, providing just one example of how thousands of years of occupation by other ethnic groups have shaped and redefined the cuisine. To this day, India&apos;s diverse and ever-evolving religious practices, which can vary by the specific community of a family&apos;s lineage, play a fundamental role in dietary choices.

But perhaps the greatest obstacle to a consensus is that each of the 28 Indian states represents its own universe with a unique cooking style and in many cases a completely separate language. Dishes that appear common to multiple locations may have different names, along with noticeable changes in texture or flavor. Don&apos;t order a dosa (doe-suh) in a Tamilian restaurant. Order a dosai (doe-say). Rather than Angelenos vs. Indians, a more telling Venn diagram might be Indians vs. Themselves.

 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Squid Ink&apos;d: Sign up for our weekly food newsletter, which features top local food news and events,
plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips and a link to our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Indian cuisine , Krishna Narayanamurti , Venn food diagrams Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
buddhu, do you know what you&apos;re critiquing? the diagram is about what angelenos think is indian food, vs. what indians actually eat; since the majority of indian restos in LA serve punjabi/northern indian food, it only follows that that&apos;s what he&apos;s going to be talking about, and featuring on the left side of the diagram! i see several south indian dishes on the diagram, particularly on the right side - rasam, vadai, idli, dosa, rice, daal.
 
the orange-white-green color scheme is hirarious!
 
What a well-written, concise overview of Indian cuisine in L.A. -- no small feat, given the topic&apos;s enormously broad scope. I&apos;m assuming/hoping that you&apos;ll follow up with more specific reviews, which I very much look forward to reading!
 
And this is news? I&apos;m Mexican and most people think a Taco Bell Enchirito is Mexican. Or El Torito is Mexican. My wife is Vietnamese and most people never get past Pho when they eat VN food. 

I love all those things. I don&apos;t claim to be an expert, but I like Northern AND Southern Indian food. I&apos;ve had Indian food in other countries, but I still haven&apos;t been to India. I&apos;m not above admitting that I&apos;ve been known to eat Chicken Tikka Masala in London!

Let&apos;s face it, I wouldn&apos;t expect the average person to sit down and eat a bowl of Bun Oc (noodles with snails) or a Shredded Pork Skin Banh Mi. But I do have a few friends that have reached out and asked about &apos;taking things to the next level&apos; and I am proud to send them in the right direction.
 
Sadly, this writer&apos;s concept of Indian food is heavily weighted towards Punjabi food. Based on his name, one would assume that he would be familiar with South Indian food. He can&apos;t be blamed entirely though; even in India, a majority of the restaurants are Punjabi.
 

TotalComments: 5
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 The Last Days of Spago Eat l See l Hear @ FIDM&apos;s Grand Hope Park First Fridays on Abbot Kinney More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Jinya Ramen
 View Ad | View Site 
Buzz WIne&amp;Beer Shop
 View Ad | View Site 
UCLA Extension
 View Ad | View Site 
Blue Dog Beer Tavern
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow laweeklyfood on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Would You Pay $15,600k/Month For Erbe Matte in BH? Sherman Oaks Gets Casual American at The Garden A Handy Guide to Dining Out During dineLA Resto Week Post&amp;Beam What&apos;s Getting Hot in Heerreee? The Eater LA Newsletter 
 About Us | Work for LA Weekly | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 LA Weekly, LP. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
