<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007139" url="http://www.buckslocalnews.com/articles/2011/11/07/the_advance/news/doc4eb7da61d39e3307282840.txt" time="2012-07-13-00:07" support="1" score="0.0010037134522117715" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s scheduled to present revised traffic circulation plan ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s scheduled to present revised traffic circulation plan at Newtown Township Planning meeting - The Advance - BucksLocalNews.com">
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>The original sketch plan called for traffic to exit ... of life issues such as lighting, noise and trash. ... that the site is not the right location for a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertise with Us Contact Us Subscribe Manage Your Subscription 

 RSS Feeds Member Center Place a Classified Ad Special Sections 
 
 

Serving Bucks County, Pa., Hunterdon County, N.J.&amp;Mercer County, N.J.
 
Weather
 
 BucksLocalNews.com Advance of Bucks County Bristol Pilot New Hope Gazette Yardley News Pennington Post 
 
 Home Local News 
 Video 
 People 
 Blogs 
 Bucks News Sports 
 Video 
 Business Obituaries Opinion Health 
 Health TV Medical Guide 
 Video 
 Autos News Sports Health TV Showcase 
 

 Jobs Real Estate Cars 
 Video 
 Classifieds Marketplace 
 Directories Today&apos;s Ads Special Sections 
 
 
Search:
 
 Advanced Search for articles older than six months
 
 The Advance &gt; News 

McDonald&apos;s scheduled to present revised traffic circulation plan at Newtown Township Planning meeting

Published: Monday, November 07, 2011
 
By Petra Chesner Schlatter
 BucksLocalNews.com 



 
 

McDonald&apos;s is proposing to build a restaurant at the site of Office Place East. The historic Toll House can be seen at left.

 View and purchase photos 
 
 


NEWTOWN TOWNSHIP - McDonald’s is scheduled to present revised plans at the next Newtown Township Planning Commission meeting on Tuesday, Nov. 15.

The revised plan proposes a direct access road off of Durham Road from the restaurant, which would be built on the site of a vacant medical office building in the parking lot of the Village at Newtown East Shopping Center.

The original sketch plan called for traffic to exit and enter the site from an internal road servicing the shopping center and the neighboring Wells Fargo Bank.

Allen Fidler, the chairman of the Newtown Planning Commission, told BucksLocalNews.com that the planning commission is not expected to make a decision or recommendation at the meeting.“They are running the revised plan past the planning commission.” 

Fidler said under the original sketch plan, the shape of the property made it“difficult to make access into the shopping center. It’s just the geometry and how it is laid out.”

Rich Davis, the real estate manager for McDonald’s Philadelphia region, confirmed the restaurant chain would be submitting revised plans and added,“McDonald’s wants to be a good, socially responsible neighbor.”

But he said,“Because this is an ongoing process, it would be inappropriate to further comment or speculate until we meet with the planning commission on Nov. 15.”

Residents from the Cliveden Estates development, located across Durham Road from the proposed restaurant, have opposed having a fast food venue that close to their homes. They turned out in force earlier this year to object to the use and presented a petition to the Newtown Township Board of Supervisors against the proposal.

They raised numerous concerns over traffic, congestion, pedestrian safety and quality of life issues such as lighting, noise and trash.

Fidler said that whenever an E6-use (restaurant with a drive-through) comes up, there are issues raised about increased traffic, trash, among other concerns.“Those are issues a lot of people have raised,”he said. Continued... 


 1 2 See Full Story 
 Under the original proposal, the restaurant would have 68 seats and about 10 employees per shift. The existing parking spaces around the building would remain. In addition, since the building would be 3,900 square feet, replacing a larger building, eight to 10 spaces would be added.

The restaurant would not have a playground or large golden arches. The applicant said the proposed model would be“a more upscale”restaurant with a dining area separated from the service area.

Judith Norkin of the Cliveden Estates Homeowners Association said earlier this year that the site is not the right location for a fast-food restaurant with a drive-thru.“We will continue to oppose this plan if and when a land development plan is submitted,”Norkin said.

“Not allowing a drive-thru clearly benefits the area,”she said during earlier hearings on the project.“McDonalds said they won’t consider opening a store without a drive-thru because that’s not how McDonalds does things. But McDonalds has existing restaurants without drive-thrus that are successful, especially in historic areas.”

When the plan was previously being discussed, the homeowners association held meetings to increase awareness and to bring people into the process. They established a Facebook page,“Say No to McDonalds at Village of Newtown East,”and an email address, saynotomcd@yahoo.com.

Mike Anton, who holds the franchise for the proposed McDonalds, said earlier this year that he would“continue to work cooperatively with Newtown Township and the community on this project, respectful of all concerns.”

Anton has been“a local business owner here for more than 20 years and has lived in this community for the past four years.”He owns and operates five McDonalds restaurants in Bucks and Montgomery counties.
 1 2 See Full Story 
 
 1 2 3 See Full Story 
 
 1 2 3 4 See Full Story 
 NEWTOWN TOWNSHIP - McDonald’s is scheduled to present revised plans at the next Newtown Township Planning Commission meeting on Tuesday, Nov. 15.

The revised plan proposes a direct access road off of Durham Road from the restaurant, which would be built on the site of a vacant medical office building in the parking lot of the Village at Newtown East Shopping Center.

The original sketch plan called for traffic to exit and enter the site from an internal road servicing the shopping center and the neighboring Wells Fargo Bank.

Allen Fidler, the chairman of the Newtown Planning Commission, told BucksLocalNews.com that the planning commission is not expected to make a decision or recommendation at the meeting.“They are running the revised plan past the planning commission.”

Fidler said under the original sketch plan, the shape of the property made it“difficult to make access into the shopping center. It’s just the geometry and how it is laid out.”

Rich Davis, the real estate manager for McDonald’s Philadelphia region, confirmed the restaurant chain would be submitting revised plans and added,“McDonald’s wants to be a good, socially responsible neighbor.”

But he said,“Because this is an ongoing process, it would be inappropriate to further comment or speculate until we meet with the planning commission on Nov. 15.”

Residents from the Cliveden Estates development, located across Durham Road from the proposed restaurant, have opposed having a fast food venue that close to their homes. They turned out in force earlier this year to object to the use and presented a petition to the Newtown Township Board of Supervisors against the proposal.

They raised numerous concerns over traffic, congestion, pedestrian safety and quality of life issues such as lighting, noise and trash.

Fidler said that whenever an E6-use (restaurant with a drive-through) comes up, there are issues raised about increased traffic, trash, among other concerns.“Those are issues a lot of people have raised,”he said.

Under the original proposal, the restaurant would have 68 seats and about 10 employees per shift. The existing parking spaces around the building would remain. In addition, since the building would be 3,900 square feet, replacing a larger building, eight to 10 spaces would be added.

The restaurant would not have a playground or large golden arches. The applicant said the proposed model would be“a more upscale”restaurant with a dining area separated from the service area.

Judith Norkin of the Cliveden Estates Homeowners Association said earlier this year that the site is not the right location for a fast-food restaurant with a drive-thru.“We will continue to oppose this plan if and when a land development plan is submitted,”Norkin said.

“Not allowing a drive-thru clearly benefits the area,”she said during earlier hearings on the project.“McDonalds said they won’t consider opening a store without a drive-thru because that’s not how McDonalds does things. But McDonalds has existing restaurants without drive-thrus that are successful, especially in historic areas.”

When the plan was previously being discussed, the homeowners association held meetings to increase awareness and to bring people into the process. They established a Facebook page,“Say No to McDonalds at Village of Newtown East,”and an email address, saynotomcd@yahoo.com.

Mike Anton, who holds the franchise for the proposed McDonalds, said earlier this year that he would“continue to work cooperatively with Newtown Township and the community on this project, respectful of all concerns.”

Anton has been“a local business owner here for more than 20 years and has lived in this community for the past four years.”He owns and operates five McDonalds restaurants in Bucks and Montgomery counties.
 Return to Paging Mode 
 Reader Comments Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. comments powered by Disqus 
Philadelphia Sports By Bleacher Report 
 
 Penn State Football: Freeh Report Sheds Darker Light on Joe Paterno, Justly 
 Philadelphia Flyers: Full Report Card for Holmgren&apos;s Offseason Moves 
 Nike Removes Joe Paterno&apos;s Name from Childcare Center at World Headquarters 
 ADVERTISEMENT 

 

 Loading Health Theater Content...   
Recent Activity on Facebook

 
 
 Most Viewed Most Shared Hot Stories 
 
 Levittown&apos;s John Leck Jr. charged in connection with Philadelphia Highway Patrolman Brian Lorenzo&apos;s death (2285) NEWTOWN TOWNSHIP POLICE REPORT: Police take fraud and scam reports, farmer calls in crop damage, burglary at Durham and Windy Bush (625) Newtown Swim Club to close in 2013, 64 townhouses proposed for 17-acre property (614) NEWTOWN BOROUGH POLICE REPORT: Police make DUI arrests on Centre Avenue, State Street (306) RUN OVER CANCER: Hundreds hit the pavement in Newtown Township to trample down pancreatic cancer (274) Bristol unveils new Veterans memorial honoring the living and deceased who defended the nation in war (263) 
 
 RUGBY: Zach Padgett satisfies competitive spirit with Bucks County Sharks (SLIDESHOWS) (4) LEGION: Newtown Post 440 fires another no-no at Yardley-Morrisville (3) Levittown&apos;s John Leck Jr. charged in connection with Philadelphia Highway Patrolman Brian Lorenzo&apos;s death (2) Newtown Swim Club to close in 2013, 64 townhouses proposed for 17-acre property (2) Another finalist for Neshaminy school superintendent discusses job, labor dispute at public forum (2) Sesame Place presents St. Mary Medical Center with $25,000 gift to support expansion of pediatric emergency services (1) ON TAP IN YARDLEY: The Vault Brewing Company will bring unique brewpub experience to South Main Street (1) 
 
Your town. Your news.

Have a suggestion or story idea? See wrong or incorrect information in a story? Tell us here.
 
 Add your idea here 

 Email Address 
 
 
Latest Headlines

Bucks County News

 Bucks County is looking for public input on 2011 Comprehensive Plan 

Advance of Bucks County

 Newtown Corporation receives visitors bureau grant to produce videos marketing Newtown (VIDEO) 

Bristol Pilot

 Grundy Library’s Fall 2011 book discussion titles selected 

New Hope Gazette

 New Hope Chamber announces winners of annual Arts&amp;Crafts Festival 

Yardley News

 It’s all in the family at Wawa family reunion celebration in Yardley Borough (DATE CHANGE) 

Pennington Post

 Toll Gate Grammar School&apos;s Thanksgiving project for Trenton Area Soup Kitchen turns 25 

Bucks Local Sports

 BOYS SOCCER: Council Rock South stuns Lower Merion in District One tourney (VIDEO) 

Pennington Post Sports

 BOYS SOCCER: Graziano&apos;s three goals pace Hopewell Valley over West Windsor-Plainsboro South 

Opinion

 Remembering Steve Jobs, the king of all things Apple 
 
AP News Headlines



 View all AP National Headlines 
 
 Community Calendar 

 Submit an event 
 
 July 2012 Su M Tu W Th F S 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 
 
Legend:

No events

Events listed
 
Photo Galleries

 View more photos from Bucks Local News View All Galleries Share your Photos&amp;Video Order Photo Reprints 
 
National News Videos
 

 
 

 Penn State Squawks 

Penn State fans and alum, roar like a Nittany Lion. Let your voice be heard here on anything PSU!
 
 

 Veterans of Bucks County 

A collection of the &apos;Saluting our Veterans&apos; stories from your community newspapers.
 
 

 Bucks County Taste 

Be it farms, markets, restaurants, bars, wineries, small producers and local merchants, we write about the best food that Bucks County has to offer.
 
 

 Bucks Happening 

Restaurant reviews, a calendar of events, merchandise, seasonal guides...a website about all things that make Bucks County happening!
 
 

 Mama&apos;s Little Helper 

This reference site for parents in Pa. and N.J. features a calendar of local (and many FREE) events, coupons, giveaways, directories (classes, places to play, story times, consignment stores/sales), helpful articles&amp;a blog!
 
 

 Lunch Box Mom 

The blog for parents trying to save their sanity and their brains, Lunch Box Mom takes on one hot parenting topic a week with humor, intelligence and curiosity.
 
 More Blogs 
 
 See, Click, Fix 

 
 
Sections:
 Home Bucks News Bucks Sports Business Obituaries Health Blogs Video Jobs Cars Real Estate Classifieds Marketplace Special Sections 

 
Services:
 Advertise With Us Subscribe Manage Your Subscription Where to Buy Place a Classified Ad Contact Us Member Center 

 Public Notices RSS Feeds 

 
Bucks Local News Network:
 Advance of Bucks County Bristol Pilot New Hope Gazette Yardley News Pennington Post BucksLocalSports The Good Life 

 Bucks County Town&amp;Country Living Magazine Camps&amp;Programs AllAroundPhilly.com 
 
©Copyright BucksLocalNews.com, a Journal Register Property &amp;part of Journal Register PA -- All rights reserved | Our Publications | About Our Ads | Privacy Policy/Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
