<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007224" url="http://cooking-games.cooking-games.ws/" time="2012-07-13-00:11" support="1" score="0.0010900961949745355" bingtitle="Cooking Games - pizza, waitress and burger games for girls ..." webtitle="Cooking Games - pizza, waitress and burger games for girls - Cooking Games">
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Welcome to Belle&apos;s Burger, may I take your order? ... The customers can be very insistent in a fast food restaurant and... ... Making Ice Cream Learn to make ice cream from ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Members | Tell a Friend | Links 
 Find Games: 
 Our special friends: Food Games All Dress Up Games   |   Burger Games ·  Grill Games ·  Cooking ·  Cooking Games ·  Cake Decorating ·  Restaurant Games ·  Fast Food ·  Waitress Games ·  Pizza Games ·  Ice Cream ·  
 Game Sections 
 
 Burger Games 
 
 Grill Games 
 
 Cooking 
 
 Cooking Games 
 
 Cake Decorating 
 
 Restaurant Games 
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Waitress Games 
 
 Pizza Games 
 
 Ice Cream 
 
 Members Username: 
Password: 
 
 Lost your password? You have only couple of credit(s) left before you must log in or register . 
 New Games Popular 
 
 New Dress Up Games 
 01.   BBQ Restaurant 
 02.   Cooking Show Sushi Rolls 
 03.   Pineapple Bread 
 04.   Egg Balls 
 05.   Cranberry Smoothie 
 06.   Chocolate Blueberries Pies 
 07.   Tandoori Chicken 
 08.   Dessert Chef 
 09.   Juicy Server 
 10.   Memorize and Service 
 11.   Sandwich Making 
 12.   Hungry Giants 
 13.   Crazy Cup Cakes 
 14.   Stabilize the Food 
 15.   Stabilize the Food 
 16.   How to Make Madeleine Castles 
 17.   Scooby Stall 
 
 Popular Games 
 01.   Hot dog Bush 
 02.   Cooking food 
 03.   Sue Cooking 
 04.   Birthday cake 
 05.   Become a Bartender 
 06.   Cake Bakery Game 
 07.   Cream cake Game - Bake and dec... 
 08.   Create a Cake 
 09.   Fast cooking 
 10.   Disney Restaurant 
 11.   Disney Restaurant 
 12.   Fast Food Cashier 
 13.   Holly Hobbie Muffin Maker 
 14.   Spongebob Burger Game 
 15.   Breakfast Game 
 16.   Top That Restaurant Game 
 17.   Patty Panic Spongebob Game 
 18.   Pizza 
 Site Statistics Registered Users: 50079
 Total Games: 5877
 Views Today: 256161998
 Total Views: 256161980

There are 1094 users online:
 0 Members , 1094 Guests. Top Players 01.   AiNoKaikoroku - 5331
 02.   sephybaby - 4455
 03.   miss_fabolous97 - 4158
 04.   Sakuralinh - 3264
 05.   Mondstein - 3202
 06.   HessieNae - 3120
 07.   nicole990248 - 2914
 08.   ducky3gal - 2848
 09.   valval - 2411
 10.   alliemae - 2168
 Cool Links 
Hair Games
 01.   Hairdresser Games 
 02.   Hair Style Games 
 03.   Hair Games 911 
 04.   New Hair Games 
 05.   Hair Games 
 
Make Up Games
 01.   New Makeup Games 
 02.   Makeup Games for girls 
 03.   Makeup Games 
 04.   Girl Makeup 
 
Cooking Games
 01.   Cooking Games 911 
 03.   Best Cooking Games 
 
Fantasy Games
 01.   Fantasy Dress Up 
 02.   Dress Up Sites 
 03.   Princess Games 
 04.   Mermaid Dress Up 
 More Cool Links» 
 Welcome to Cooking Games - pizza, waitress and burger games for girls. Here you can find tons of great online flash games to play, all selected for their quality. Remember to check back often because we are always adding new games. Burger Games Games Burger Toppings 
 
 Hungry people love choices, and at the burger shop you can choose from a variety of burger toppings like cheese, tomatoes, and mushrooms. Create your ... 
 Fast food 
 
 Fast food 
 Burger Bar 
 
 Burger Bar 

 More Burger Games Games» Recently Played Games 
 Cooking food 
81.7 minutes ago
 Cooking food Game Staff of the month 
88.8 minutes ago
 Staff of the month Juice Machine 
104.3 minutes ago
 Prepare the juice as per the customer requirement from the juice machine and give it Cookies Mission 
104.3 minutes ago
 Play the cookies mission game and have fun. 
 Grill Games Games Belle&apos;s Burger 
 
 Welcome to Belle&apos;s Burger, may I take your order? Assemble the burger orders according to the customer&apos;s demands, some may want cheese to ma... 
 Busy Burger 
 
 In this game you will be able to help this girl to make hamburgers and French fries. The customers can be very insistent in a fast food restaurant and... 
 Burger Shack 
 
 Welcome to the Burger Shack, a delicious hamburger grill on the beach. Order anything from our menu including hamburgers, cheeseburgers with lettuce a... 
 More Grill Games Games» Cooking Games Butternut Squash Soup 
 
 Butternut squash soup is a delicious treat in the fall, especially when squash is in season and it goes great with apples in this delicious recipe. Le... 
 Stuffed Cabbage Recipe 
 
 Learn how to make a delicious and hearty stuffed cabbage dish. This traditional recipe is great for a cold winter night and uses boiled cabbage leaves... 
 Rabbit Stew 
 
 Learn how to make rabbit stew from scratch. Find out all the ingredients and follow the step by step instructions to making a delicious chicken stew, ... 
 More Cooking Games» Cooking Games Games Festive Turkey Stuffing 
 
 Follow the recipe to make this delicious turkey stuffing. A tradition for the American holiday Thanksgiving, this dish features a combination of bread... 
 Speedy Sushi Chef 
 
 Its time to learn how to prepare sushi, you will be going through all the instructions 1 by 1 until you complete the sushi rolls. Once you have comple... 
 Stuffed Mushrooms 
 
 Try out this delicious recipe for stuffed mushrooms, a great appetizer that will feed your guests and show off your cooking skills. Follow the instruc... 
 More Cooking Games Games» Cake Decorating Games Spooky Cake Decorating 
 
 When the monsters and ghouls come out to play on Halloween, they also enjoy a sweet treat to begin their night of haunting. Create a beautiful spooky ... 
 Halloween Wedding Cake 
 
 Ghouls and bats decorate this tiered beautiful haunted wedding cake for a special couple&apos;s wedding on Hallow&apos;s Eve. Create a fantastically d... 
 Perfect Cupcake Decorating 
 
 Design the perfect cupcake in this fun cake decorating game, choose your favorite frosting, toppings, and flavor for the dream dessert. Cupcakes are c... 
 More Cake Decorating Games» Restaurant Games Games Sushi Mania 
 
 In Japan, everyone is crazy about their sushi, and it is actually a very easy dish to prepare. Put together the rice, seaweed, and raw fish to create ... 
 Sushi Chef 
 
 In this game you will be cooking your sushi specials for your customers, when a customer comes into your restaurant you should take their order then c... 
 Juice Bar 
 
 Working at a juice bar can be tough work, your customers are in a hurry and are very picky about their fresh juice beverages. Do the job right and ser... 
 More Restaurant Games Games» Fast Food Games Big City Diner 
 
 Your new job as a waitress at this drive in diner. Suzie and her chef serve up good times, smiles and great meals at this fast paced, fun, American di... 
 Popcorn Booth 
 
 See what it&apos;s like to work at a popcorn booth and serve hasty customers on the way to watch a movie. Fill the orders quickly to earn money and ha... 
 Quick Serve 
 
 Working at a fast food counter is a test of your skill and reflexes, remember the order your customers give and place the right in front of them. But ... 
 More Fast Food Games» Waitress Games Games Fast Food Resto 
 
 Lea got a job as a waitress at the new fast food restaurant in her hometown, help her make some money and keep her customers happy with the service by... 
 Japanese Restaurant 
 
 Lee just got a job at a hot new Japanese Restaurant, help her keep her waitress job by fulfilling all the duties, she has a 5 day trial period so don&amp;... 
 Italian Restaurant 
 
 You got a summer job as a waitress in an Italian restaurant. Fulfill your duties as a waitress, seat the customers, take their orders, and deliver the... 
 More Waitress Games Games» Pizza Games Games Making a Pizza 
 
 This game is full of steak cutting, ingredient chopping, dough pounding fun. Get through each of the unique cooking challenges to win this pizza game.... 
 Deep Dish Pizza 
 
 Learn how to cook a delicious Chicago-style deep dish pizza that can be a great dinner for your whole family. Start off with the dough and bake it in ... 
 New York Pizza 
 
 Everyone knows that you can find the best slice of pizza in New York City. The thin crust New York style pizza, is something the best chef wishes to c... 
 More Pizza Games Games» Ice Cream Games Making Ice Cream 
 
 Learn to make ice cream from scratch in this fun cooking game. Beat together the eggs and milk and add your favorite flavors to create your perfect ic... 
 How To Make Banana Split 
 
 Are you ready to lean how to cook a delicious desert? The desert on the menu today is a super yummy banana split! It is your job to make these all day... 
 Ice Cream Parlor 
 
 Welcome to the town&apos;s new biggest and best ice cream parlor. You have been invited to come work at this magical place for the day, serving some o... 
 More Ice Cream Games» 
 ice cream games   |   Hot Mom Try Sons   |   Mom Boy Hot   |   Www Boy Try Mom Pic   |   Mom Boy Pic   |   Faty Games Com   |   Www Fattygame Com   |   Mom Boy   |   Tokyo Mew Mew Dress Up   |   Karevin   |   Marilyn77 Yahoo Com   |   Www Fatty Game Com   |   Hot Mom Boy   |   Hot Mom Pic   |   Hot Mom And Boy   |   Momboy   |   Hot Boy Profile   |   Fatty Game Gallery   |   Www Mom Try Boy Pics Com   |   Moms And Boy Hot   |   Chinese Cuties   |   
 Home - Submit - RSS - Copyright Disputes - Privacy Policy - Sitemap Copyright©2005-2012 Cooking Games.
	</body>
</document>
