<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007885" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/247757-Victorias-secret-reward" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="9" score="0.01710282681408556" bingtitle="Victorias secret reward - Welcome to Your Daily Freebies...Enter ..." webtitle="Victorias secret reward">
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000551" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001179" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000271" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000114" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>I placed an order using this card last night. It didn&apos;t even tell me what it was worth after I checked out! I received my receipt in my ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals Victorias secret reward 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Page 1 of 2 1 2 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 10 of 18 
Thread: Victorias secret reward 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 12-02-2008,  07:19 PM #1 raven716 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Apr 2006 Location PA Posts 2 
Victorias secret reward
 
Does anyone know if you can check what your Victorias secret reward card is worth without having to go to the store? Reply With Quote 12-02-2008,  07:34 PM #2 NWVinTexas 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2004 Location South Texas Posts 1,047 That&apos;s what I&apos;m wondering too! I thought about going online, entering it to see how much it would take off my total and then removing it to try the other two that I have so that I can redeem my biggest discount whatever that may be. If anyone has an easier way, I&apos;d love to know how! Reply With Quote 12-02-2008,  07:59 PM #3 natsmom 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2008 Posts 5 call customer service or the store Reply With Quote 12-02-2008,  09:15 PM #4 NotMyFault 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Oct 2005 Posts 213 I placed an order using this card last night. It didn&apos;t even tell me what it was worth after I checked out! I received my receipt in my email and the total was for $10 less than the invoice was so I figure it was a $10 reward. Reply With Quote 12-02-2008,  10:14 PM #5 finstotheleft 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Apr 2008 Posts 17 
Call the number on the back of the card
 A friend of mine called the number on the back of the card and they told her the value. Hers was $100. Yipee Reply With Quote 12-02-2008,  10:20 PM #6 sibyl 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Nov 2005 Location st.francis, wi Posts 682 there should be #s on the back try calling and asking how much Reply With Quote 12-03-2008,  07:12 AM #7 twinmom65 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries Visit Homepage View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Mar 2001 Location Central NJ Posts 1,713 I tried doing it online but it does not tell you until you actually place your order. Then it said $10 applied to your gift card balance to cc. Reply With Quote 12-03-2008,  09:44 AM #8 casper31973 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date May 2005 Location NY Posts 348 I have 4 cards and they are all $10 I would assume its worth $10 and if its more you will be in for a surprise....but I doubt its worth more. Reply With Quote 12-03-2008,  11:09 AM #9 kelbel 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jun 2007 Posts 100 How do you get one?
Do I need to sign up for credit card or something? Reply With Quote 12-03-2008,  11:38 AM #10 gaelicdancer84 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Apr 2008 Posts 116 any one know if you can combine?
i have 3 can u use all 3 in the same order? Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
