<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007458" url="http://www.granitebay.com/News_Archives.html" time="2012-07-13-00:25" support="11" score="0.005974231868708164" bingtitle="Granite Bay California news, events and information -- GRANITEBAY.COM" webtitle="Granite Bay California news, events and information -- GRANITEBAY.COM">
			<query id="000665" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001294" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001042" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>**NOTE**: The meeting place has changed for February ... Friday through Sunday, Dec. 11-13, collection receptacles ... Supervisors Select Uhler to ...</description>
	<body>
		News 
 Headlines More Top Stories News Archives 
 Placer County 
General Information

 Official County Website Placer County District 4 Supervisor Kirk Uhler Developing Projects 
 
Services

 Sheriff Department South Placer Fire District San Juan Water District 
 
Schools

 Eureka Union School District Roseville Joint Union High School District Placer Union High School District Loomis Union School District Granite Bay Christian Pre-School 
 About 
 Granite Bay&apos;s History Community Plan Information Granite Bay Community Association 
 Boards&amp;Agendas 
 Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council San Juan Water District South Placer Fire Department Placer County Board of Supervisors Planning Commission 
 Granite Bay Alert Community Blog Activities&amp;Events 
 Upcoming Events Youth Activates Recreation Worship 
 Advertising Library Contact Us 
   

 
 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 
 
 2012 
 4/27/12 
 May MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 **NOTE**: For the May 2, 2012 meeting there has been a ROOM CHANGE – this night ONLY – BIG GYM in back .

 2-1-1: 
Presented by: Ed Morgado (10 min.)
A presentation will be provided on the program, where they are in the process and what is needed to launch 2-1-1. 2-1-1 provides free and confidential information and referral on community, health and social services. 2-1-1 - is currently not available in Placer County.

 Amazing Facts Ministry: 
Presented by: E.J. Ivaldi, Placer County Planning Division/Dave Cook, Managing Principal, RCH Group (20 min.)
The Amazing Facts Ministry Project proposes to construct a 17-acre campus to support a new Amazing Facts Ministry facility. The proposed Project would be constructed in two phases with buildings totaling 208,020 square‐feet. The Project site is located on the south side of Sierra College Boulevard, between Nightwatch Drive and Ridge Park Drive, in the Granite Bay area (APN 046-050-006 and 046-050-008).

 **NOTE**: The Garage Condos&amp;Self Storage project has been cancelled.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 3/30/12 
 April MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 **NOTE**: A Thank You Reception for the Approved Granite Bay Community Plan will be held one hour before the MAC meeting from 6 PM – 7 PM , where cake, cookies and coffee will be offered.

 Granite Bay Dutch Brothers Coffee House: 
Presented by: Lex Coffroth, Architect, per Auburn Douglas, LLC (20 min.)
Proposal to construct a two-lane drive-thru coffee establishment (approximately 377 square feet) in Granite Bay Shopping Center located on the east side of Auburn-Folsom Road, just south of Douglas Boulevard.

 Amazing Facts Ministry: 
Presented by: E.J. Ivaldi, Placer County Planning Division/Dave Cook, Managing Principal, RCH Group (20 min.)
The Amazing Facts Ministry Project proposes to construct a 17-acre campus to support a new Amazing Facts Ministry facility. The proposed Project would be constructed in two phases with buildings totaling 208,020 square-feet. The Project site is located on the south side of Sierra College Boulevard, between Nightwatch Drive and Ridge Park Drive, in the Granite Bay area (APN 046-050-006 and 046-050-008).

 Olive Ranch Subdivision Gated Entry: 
Presented by: Roy Schaefer, Placer County Planning Division
The New Home Company is requesting a Subdivision and Conditional Use Permit Modification to allow a gated entry (8 feet high) and one pedestrian gate (6 feet high) and related pilasters (8 feet high), within the Right-of-Way of Carlisle Woods Place. The Olive Ranch Subdivision comprises approximately 15 acres, and is located at 4977 Olive Ranch Road in the Granite Bay area.

 Terracina Subdivision Gated Entry: 
Presented by: Roy Schaefer, Placer County Planning Division
The Terracina Homeowners Association is requesting a Subdivision and Conditional Use Permit Modification to allow a gated entry (8-foot – 11 inches high) with 2 pedestrian gates and related pilasters (10 feet high), within the Right-of-Way of Terracina Lane. Terracina Subdivision is a 17-lot Residential Planned Development on 83 acres, and is located on Terracina Lane at the intersection with Laird Road in the Loomis area.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 3/30/12 
 Placer County Library to Hold Community Meeting 
 
On Thursday, April 5, 2012 , the Placer County Library is planning its future and we want the development to be rooted in our community. To do that we need your help! Join us to meet your neighbors and share your insights about the communities we serve.

The meeting will be held at the Placer County Office of Education Annex - Nobili Room (365 Nevada St., Auburn, CA) from 5:30 PM -7:30 PM .

For additional information, please contact Library Director, Mary George at 530-886-4551 or mgeorge@placer.ca.gov .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 3/2/12 
 Businesses Moving In 
 
 UPDATE: Given the community&apos;s interest in the Granite Bay Walmart Neighborhood Market , Walmart has developed a fact sheet that may be of interest.

 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON 1/29/12: A Walmart grocery store is proposed at the site currently occupied by Grocery Outlet at Douglas and Sierra College Boulevard .

A new Chic-fil-A restaurant is going through County design review with plans to locate at the site previously occupied by Burger King in the Sierra Oaks Shopping Center at the corner of Douglas and Sierra College .

 Do you want to comment on this story? Read comments about this story 
 2/29/12 
 **JUST IN**: March MAC Meeting Cancelled 
 
The monthly MAC meeting scheduled for Wednesday, March 7, 2012 has been cancelled. The next meeting will be held on April 4, 2012 .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 2/14/12 
 **JUST IN**: SPFD Meeting Postponed 
 
The SPFD regular board meeting of February 15, 2012 has been postponed until February 29, 2012 .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/29/12 
 Placer County Sheriff’s Department 
 
Residents were advised by the sheriff deputy present that there had been an increase in residential burglaries. Thieves kick in the door to test if anyone is home and if there is no response, they enter and burglarize the home. Residents were reminded to set burglar alarms and avoid having the home look unoccupied. If suspicious activity is noted, call the Sheriff’s office at (530) 889-7800 .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/29/12 
 January&apos;s Supervisor’s Report 
 
Supervisor Uhler reported on the following:

 The final phase of the Auburn-Folsom widening project is moving forward.

 Placer County anticipated cuts in monies from state and allowed for this possibility when balancing the County budget.

 During a walk-through of area businesses sponsored by the Roseville and Granite Bay Chamber of Commerce, business owners
 requested relaxing sign ordinances.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/25/12 
 February MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 **NOTE**: The meeting place has changed for February meeting only . The meeting will be held at the Eureka School Library (5455 Eureka Road, Granite Bay, CA)

 Amazing Facts Ministry: 
Presented by: Dave Cook, Managing Principal, RCH Group (20 min.)
The Amazing Facts Ministry Project would include construction of a 17-acre campus to support a new Amazing Facts Ministry facility. The proposed Project would be constructed in two phases with buildings totaling 208,020 square-feet. The Project site is located on the south side of Sierra College Boulevard, between Nightwatch Drive and Ridge Park Drive, in the Granite Bay area (APN 046-050-006 and 046-050-008).

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/20/12 
 Sign Up Now For Sheriff’s Community Awareness 2012 Academy 
 
It’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Office’s popular Community Awareness Academy, which offers an inside look at the law enforcement agency.

Classes are held Monday and Wednesday evenings, beginning March 5, 2012 and ending March 28, 2012 .

To learn more about this year&apos;s Community Awareness 2012 Academy , click here .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/12/12 
 Kindergarten Registration in Granite Bay 
 
If you have an incoming Kindergarten student for the 2012-2013 school year, you may pick up a registration packet any time during regular business hours , beginning February 1st at your local school:

 Greenhills School 
 8200 Greenhills Way
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916) 791-4230

 Maidu School 
 1950 Johnson Ranch Dr.
 Roseville, CA 95661
 (916) 789-7910

 Oakhills School 
 9233 Twin Schools Road
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916) 791-5391

We will begin accepting completed packets February 1st . Included in the registration packet are the times of school tours and the Parent Welcome and Information Night . We are looking forward to your child’s great first step into school. Welcome!

For more information on Kindergarten Registration, please click here . If you have any questions please call 791-4230 .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/6/12 
 SPFD to Review Survey Results 
 
The South Placer Fire Board will hear and discuss the results of the survey mailed to approximately 5,000 residents to gather input regarding future operations of the fire department. The agenda item will be for information only. The meeting will be held at the Eureka Road Fire Station at 7:00 PM on January 18 .

 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON 12/7/11: The SPFD contracted with SCI to survey about 8,000 residents served by the SPFD concerning the financial status of the fire district. Sometime in January, the SPFD will hold a public meeting to discuss the results of the survey. Contact 791-7059 for date, time, and place.



 South Placer Fire District Webpage Read other stories about the SPFD looking for ways to raise revenue Do you want to comment on this story? 
 1/3/12 
 January MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 State Responsibility Area Fee: 
Presented by Rui Cunha, Asst. Director of Emergency Services, Placer County Community Outreach/Office of Emergency Services (15min.)
Overview of the $150 fee per habitable structure in areas east of Laird Road and north of CavittStallman Road/Twin Rocks Road.

 Amazing Facts Ministry: 
Presented by: Dave Cook, Managing Principal, RCH Group (20 min.)
The Amazing Facts Ministry Project would include construction of a 17-acre campus to support a new Amazing Facts Ministry facility. The proposed Project would be constructed in two phases with buildings totaling 208,020 square-feet. The Project site is located on the south side of Sierra College Boulevard, between Nightwatch Drive and Ridge Park Drive, in the Granite Bay area (APN 046-050006 and 046-050-008).

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 
 2011 
 12/7/11 
 Amazing Facts Ministry Update (AGAIN) 
 
The Amazing Facts Ministries&apos; project faces opposition. To read more about this, click here .

 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON 12/1/11: The Amazing Facts Ministries&apos; project will not be heard until early 2012. Future date still to be determined.

 ORIGINALLY REPORTED ON 10/3/11: The stated objective of the project is to develop the Amazing Facts house of worship facility and offices to accommodate the multifaceted ministry that supports their local and worldwide mission.

Furthermore, comments to the Draft EIR will be heard on October 13, 2011 at 10:05 in the Placer County Commission Hearing Room at 3091 County Center Drive (corner of Richardson Drive and Bell Road in Dewitt Center), Auburn. The purpose of the hearing is to receive comments on the DEIR for the project, comments related to the merits of the project will be considered at a later hearing on the entitlement for the project.

The Draft EIR is available and may be reviewed at the Granite Bay Library or on the County website, click here .


 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 12/1/11 
 December MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 Public Workshop-Preliminary Draft Granite Bay Community Plan: 
Presented by E.J. Ivaldi, Supervising Planner and Chris Schmidt, Senior Planner, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency. (One Hour)
The MAC will continue its review of the Preliminary Draft Granite Bay Community Plan. This document is the product of collaboration and participation from a Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC) subcommittee and County staff over the past two years, and the draft provides community members and the public a chance to review the vision, goals, policies and regulations related to development in Granite Bay over the next 25 to 30 years. County Staff is seeking a recommendation from the MAC to the Planning Commission and Board of Supervisors to adopt the Granite Bay Community Plan Update document.

 View Draft for Community Plan Read the Board of Supervisors Notice Do you want to comment on this story? 
 12/1/11 
 Amazing Facts Ministry (UPDATE) 
 
 IN COMING INFORMATION: The Amazing Facts Ministries&apos; project will not be heard until early 2012. Future date still to be determined.

 ORIGINALLY REPORTED ON 10/3/11: The stated objective of the project is to develop the Amazing Facts house of worship facility and offices to accommodate the multifaceted ministry that supports their local and worldwide mission.

Furthermore, comments to the Draft EIR will be heard on October 13, 2011 at 10:05 in the Placer County Commission Hearing Room at 3091 County Center Drive (corner of Richardson Drive and Bell Road in Dewitt Center), Auburn. The purpose of the hearing is to receive comments on the DEIR for the project, comments related to the merits of the project will be considered at a later hearing on the entitlement for the project.

The Draft EIR is available and may be reviewed at the Granite Bay Library or on the County website, click here .


 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 11/17/11 
 Yellow Ribbons to Hang Along Douglas During Holidays to Honor Military 
 
Yellow ribbons will adorn trees along Douglas Boulevard in Granite Bay over the holidays to honor men and women serving the U.S. military in war zones overseas.

The ribbons also will pay tribute to American soldiers who lost their lives serving their country, and are part of a nationwide campaign to thank all men and women who serve in the U.S. military and to welcome them when they return home.

About 150 ribbons will be hung in trees in the Douglas median from Cavitt Stallman Road to Auburn Folsom Road. They will go up Sunday and remain through New Year’s Day.

To learn more about the tribute, click here .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 11/2/11 
 Eureka Union School District New Superintendent Search Survey 
 
The Board of Trustees is beginning the process of searching for a new superintendent and has asked the firm, Hazard, Young, Attea&amp;Associates to help the Board with the process.

As one of the initial steps in the process, the Board is seeking your input on the desired characteristics and skills that you would like to see in the next superintendent. Please share your thoughts by responding to the apppropriate surveys linked below.

As you respond, please remember that all characteristics listed are desirable, but we are interested in knowing your perceptions about which characteristics are &quot;most important&quot; for the Eureka Union School District.

To access the Survey:
 1. Identify the group to which you belong and click on the link below
 2. Follow the directions on the survey
 3. Respond by Friday, November 11, 2011 
 Click here to take the survey.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 10/26/11 
 November MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 **NOTE:** This meeting will be held at the &quot;BIG GYM&quot; at the Eureka Union School District office located at 5455 Eureka Road, Granite Bay. 

 AB885 Update, Statewide Sewage Policy: 
Presented by Jill Pahl, Environmental Health Director, HHS (15 min.)
Assembly Bill (AB) 885 was approved by the California State Legislature and signed into law in September 2000. It directed the State Water Resources Control Board to promulgate a statewide wastewater regulation by the year 2004. A revised draft of the regulation, waiver, and DEIR were released November 7, 2008. Since then they have been in the process of updating the policy.

 Public Workshop-Preliminary Draft Granite Bay Community Plan: 
Presented by E.J. Ivaldi, Supervising Planner and Chris Schmidt, Senior Planner, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency. (One Hour)
An overview of the Preliminary Draft Granite Bay Community Plan will be presented. This document is the product of collaboration and participation from a Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC) subcommittee and County staff over the past two years, and the draft provides community members and the public a chance to review the vision, goals, policies and regulations related to development in Granite Bay over the next 25 to 30 years. County Staff will be on hand to answer questions from the MAC and public.

 View Draft for Community Plan Read the Board of Supervisors Notice Do you want to comment on this story? 
 10/25/11 
 Granite Bay Community Plan: Draft to be Released for Public Comments 
 
The updated Granite Bay Community Plan will be brought back to the Board for adoptions. Soon, the county will release the draft community plan for public comment. On November 2, 2011 , people will have a chance to comment on the draft plan at the regular meeting of the Granite Bay MAC . Other opportunities for public input are on the horizon. Both the Granite Bay MAC and Planning Commission will formally review the draft plan and send their recommendations to the Board of Supervisors before action is taken.

The draft Granite Bay Community Plan may be reviewed at the Granite Bay Public Library , 6475 Douglas Boulevard, or click here to see it online.



 Read other stories about the Granite Bay Community Plan Learn more about the Community Plan View Draft for Community Plan Read the Board of Supervisors Notice Do you want to comment on this story? 
 10/3/11 
 Supervisor Uhler’s Report 
 
The final County budget for 2012 will be adopted by September 30. Assessed valuation of property is down another 3% which is a reduction of 12% since 2008. The County budget has been reduced by 17% over the last several years with a cut of 4.9% for next fiscal year. County employees are on a two tier system now and are contributing more to benefits.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 10/3/11 
 San Juan Water District Update 
 
General Manager, Shauna Lorance, discussed SJWD’s current water issues, state water objectives and current and past water legislation. Water issues are a hot topic in the legislature and from the presentation, it is apparent that southern California doesn’t think northern California can manage water. Bills pending and passed by the legislators strive to regulate water conservation to such an extent that lifestyles in this non desert area served by a large water shed would be drastically changed.

Please contact SJWD at 791-0115 and ask to be placed on their email list in order to stay aware of water issues and be able to take appropriate action when SJWD needs support on water issues vital to this area.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 10/3/11 
 Overview of Placer Mosquito&amp;Vector Control District Services 
 
According to the presenter, out of 1,500 mosquito samples, 37 have tested positive for West Nile Virus. To date West Nile Virus cases have been detected in nine dead birds, four sentinel chickens, and three humans, with most of these occurring on the western border of the county.

Mosquito numbers are generally lower this year due to a combination of milder than usual temperatures and the district’s aggressive larval mosquito control program. Residents can take steps to protect themselves by draining standing water; using an effective insect repellent, wearing long sleeves and pants when outdoors, and keeping door and window screens in good condition.

For further information call (888) 768-2343 or click here .

 Do you want to comment on this story? Read comments about this story 
 9/28/11 
 September MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 Granite Bay Garage Condos&amp;Self-Storage Facility: 
Presented by Roy Schaefer, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency (30 Min.)
Proposal for a 74,900 square foot garage condominium development and 73,975 square foot self-storage facility on approximately 8.7 acres located on the north side of Douglas Boulevard (7135&amp;7175 Douglas Boulevard), approximately 0.17 miles east of the intersection of Auburn Folsom Road and Douglas Boulevard.

 Amazing Facts Ministry: 
Presented by E.J. Ivaldi, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency. (45 Min.)
Proposal for a 17-acre campus to support a new Amazing Facts Ministry facility. The “House of Worship” facility would be constructed on a portion of a 74.2 acre site located on the south side of Sierra College Boulevard between Nightwatch Drive and Ridge Park Drive. The project would be constructed in two phases with buildings totaling 208,020 square feet. Phase I of the proposed Project would include a 106,800-square-foot multi-use building consisting of an auditorium/gymnasium, ministry offices, Sabbath school classrooms, a fireside chapel, an audio/visual production suite, and kitchen facilities. Phase I would also include a separate ±11,220 square-foot resource center building. Phase II would consist of a ±90,000 square-foot multi-use building which will replace the Phase I multi-use building’s function as the main sanctuary for this ministry and serve as the permanent worship facility with seating for 2,000 people. Approximately 625 on-site parking spaces would be provided as part of Phase I and an additional 275 parking spaces as part of Phase II for a total of approximately 900 spaces. The Draft EIR public review period ends October 17, 2011.

 Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council’s Design Elements and Landscape Goals for Granite Bay’s “Central District” – Name Change: 
Consider changing the name of the “Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council’s Design Elements and Landscape Goals for Granite Bay’s “Central District”. The term “Central District” is proposed to be changed to the “Douglas Corridor”. The Granite Bay MAC originally approved these design guidelines in February 2008. These design guidelines are provided to developers, builders, and private citizens at the Community Development Resource Agency upon submittal of building plans for projects within this defined area of Granite Bay.


 9/16/11 
 Search&amp;Rescue Fundraising Confusion 
 
 Placer County Sheriff’s Search and Rescue is conducting its annual fund raising efforts with the assistance of a telemarketing company. However, another group has been calling Placer County residents, asking for donations for Search and Rescue, but this group has no connection to the sheriff’s entity.

Please click here , to learn more.


 9/13/11 
 Vote For Friday Night&apos;s GBHS Football Game 
 
The voting for this weeks KCRA High Scool Playbook game of the week ends Wednesday, September 14th at 7 PM , so vote fast and this Friday&apos;s game between Granite Bay and Vacaville could be the Game of the Week, which will be announced during KCRA 3 Reports at 11 PM .

To vote and learn more, please click here .


 9/2/11 
 **September&apos;s MAC Meeting Canceled** 
 
The monthly meeting of MAC, scheduled for Wednesday, September 7, 2011 , has been canceled.


 8/30/11 
 Sign Up For Sheriff’s Community Awareness Academy 
 
It’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Office’s popular Community Awareness Academy, which offers an inside look at the law enforcement agency.

Attendees are asked to attend all eight classes, each of which covers a different topic. Classes are held Tuesday and Thursday evenings, beginning Oct. 4 and ending Oct. 27. Participants will hear from members of the department’s special units and take “field trips” to the Placer County Jail and morgue, 911 dispatch center, as well as the air operations hangar.

 Click here for more information.

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 8/17/11 
 Grant Targets Underage Drinking and Alcohol Sales 
 
The Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Office recently received a grant from the State of California Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control for 2011-2012. The grant, totaling nearly $40,000, will be used to combat underage drinking and alcohol sales to minors in the county. The grant will also assist the Sheriff&apos;s Office in providing awareness and training in alcohol-related crimes and their impact for school staff, parents, students and the community.

To learn more about this, please click here .

 Do you want to comment on this story? 
 8/1/11 
 Granite Bay Community Plan: Refresher&amp;Update 
 
The update of the GBCP began in August, 2008, when the Board of Supervisors directed Planning staff to begin review of the document originally adopted in 1989. The Plan’s primary purpose is to direct future land use and development in a manner that preserves the character and identity of the community.

A series of public meetings began in 2009 and ultimately through community input, it was determined that there was overwhelming support to not change the Land Use Element of the Plan. In August, 2010, the Board of Supervisors voted to update only the Goals and Policies section of the Plan with no changes to the Land Use Element.

A volunteer MAC sub-committee began working with Placer County staff in December, 2010, to update the Goals and Policies of the Plan. A draft document will be released to the subcommittee for review in early August. The draft document will probably be available to the public in early September after which a special MAC meeting will be held in mid-September to hear comments.

If everything proceeds on schedule, the proposed GBCP will be scheduled for a public workshop before the Planning Commission on October, 13, followed by a Public Hearing on November 10 for action by the Planning Commission. At the conclusion of this procedure there will be a Public Hearing before the Board of Supervisors to take action on the updated Granite Bay Community Plan. This is tentatively scheduled for December.


 8/1/11 
 Auburn-Folsom Widening Project – Update 
 
Many have wondered about the status of this project which seems to have stalled. According to Placer County Public Works, even though the project got off to a good start wet weather significantly impacted available working days. At this point, the contractor has until the end of September to finish the project.

At the end of July, the contractor will shift traffic in order to install an underground drainage system along the east side of the road to drain excess ground water from the road surface. The extra work is in response to the unanticipated ground water and roadway saturation issue that was found this past winter and hadn’t presented itself previously. The extra work is estimated to take two weeks.


 8/1/11 
 2010 Census/Redistricting 
 
The 2010 Census will affect the current Supervisorial Boundaries based on population. The updated proposals can be viewed here .


 8/1/11 
 Improvement Project for Treelake Park and Playground 
 
County Parks Division discussed plans for updating the playground at Treelake Park that does not comply with current safety standards or meet requirements of the Americans with Disabilities Act.

The cost for the rehabilitation is estimated at $150,000. MAC recommended the Board of Supervisors approve the request for $108,000 from Granite Bay’s Landscape and Lighting District reserves and redirect $42,000 from currently budgeted reserve funds for the upgrades to the playground at Treelake Park.


 8/1/11 
 Adopt Dry Creek Greenway Regional Vision and Certify the Final EIR 
 
This project received $250,000 grant funding several years ago and is ready to move forward. The proposed Dry Creek Greenway will provide a continuous and coordinated loop system of preserved lands and habitat, with a connection corridor of walking, equestrian and bicycle trails, from the Sacramento border to Dry Creek’s sources, and to the Folsom Lake State Recreation area.

MAC passed a motion recommending that the Planning Commission and Board of Supervisors adopt the Dry Creek Greenway Regional Vision and Certify the Final EIR. For more information about the project, click here .


 7/29/11 
 Sheriff’s Search and Rescue Fundraising Begins 
 
The Placer County Sheriff Office’s Search and Rescue teams are beginning their annual telemarketing fundraising drive throughout the county. For more information, please click here .


 7/28/11 
 August MAC Meeting Summary 
 
 Overview of Placer Mosquito&amp;Vector Control District Services and Vector-borne Disease Update: 
Presented by Ada Barros Heiser, MPH, Public Information Officer, Placer Mosquito&amp;Vector Control District (20 min.)
An overview of the district’s services, future plans and projects will be presented. Updated information on the West Nile Virus will be provided.

 San Juan Water District Update: 
Presented by Shauna Lorance, General Manager, San Juan Water District (25 min.)
Discussions and overview of San Juan Water District (SJWD), current water issues, state water objectives and current and past water legislation.


 6/29/11 
 **July&apos;s MAC Meeting Canceled** 
 
The monthly meeting of MAC, scheduled for Wednesday, July 6, 2011 , has been canceled.


 6/1/11 
 Supervisor Uhler Monthly Report 
 
 &gt;&gt; Placer County has a budget shortfall of $1 million. Some of the actions taken to balance the budget include suspending step increases for management and confidential employees to save about $129,000, and suspending step increases for non-management employees to save over $1 million. As a result, only 17 of the 2,500 employees will be laid off. However, unknown impacts from State budget actions could amount to a $38 million hit to Placer County’s budget.

 &gt;&gt; County is in process of contracting out services for Douglas Corridor maintenance.

 &gt;&gt; Two weeks of dry weather are needed to complete paving the current road widening project on Auburn-Folsom Road and then it will take 2 or 3 weeks to finish the overlay.


 6/1/11 
 San Juan Water District May Meeting Overview 
 
At its May 9 meeting, the San Juan Water Board voted to give an 8% raise to district employees and have the employees contribute 8% into the EMC (employee member contributions) instead of the district continuing to pay this benefit. The Board considers this move a “wash” and took the action because the public has been asking for transparency in employee pay.

For more information about this, click here .


 6/1/11 
 April&apos;s MAC Meeting Overview 
 
At April&apos;s MAC Meeting a Recreational Storage Facility , a Mixed Use Project and the Regina Caeli Project at Rocklin and Barton Road were all discussed. For more information on these items, click here .


 5/26/11 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: June 
 
 MAC Committee Reports 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee. For more information, click here .

 The Collections at Granite Bay
(previously Seymour Ranch) 
Presented by E. J. Ivaldi, Supervising Planner, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency (20 min.)
Proposal by the New Home Company for a Subdivision Modification and Variance to allow vehicle entry gates and related monument walls. The project site is located on the east side of Cavitt Stallman Road, at its intersection with Great Oak Circle.
 Action requested: Recommendation to approve Subdivision Modification and Variance to allow vehicle entry gates and related monument walls.

 Adopt Dry Creek Greenway Regional Vision and Certify the Final EIR 
Presented by Christopher Schmidt, Senior Planner, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency (20 min.)
The proposed Dry Creek Greenway will provide a continuous and coordinated system of preserved lands and habitat, with a connecting corridor of walking, equestrian, and bicycle trails, from the Sacramento border to Dry Creek’s sources, and to the Folsom Lake State Recreation Area. Greenway Plan and EIR can be found here .
 Action requested: Recommendation to Planning Commission and Board of Supervisors to Adopt the Dry Creek Greenway Regional Vision and Certify the Final EIR.

 Improvement Project for Treelake Park and Playground 
Presented by John Ramirez, Placer County Parks Administrator, Department of Facility Services (20 min.)
The County Parks Division is requesting funding to remove and replace the old playground at Treelake Park that does not comply with current safety standards or meet requirements of the Americans with Disabilities Act. The cost estimate for the project is $150,000.
 Action requested: Recommend the County Board of Supervisors approve the request of the County Parks Division for $108,000 from Granite Bay’s Landscape and Lighting District reserves, and redirect $42,000 from currently budgeted reserve funds, for a new playground at Treelake Park, 5255 Parkford Circle.

 2010 Census/Redistricting 
Presented by: Loren Clark, Asst. Agency Director, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency (45 min.)
Discussion of 2010 Census and how it effects District Supervisorial Boundaries.


 4/28/11 
 **May’s MAC Meeting Canceled** 
 
The monthly meeting of MAC, scheduled for Wednesday, May 4, 2011 , has been canceled.


 4/11/11 
 Placer County Zoning Administrator to Hold Public Hearing on Bayside Church Request 
 
The Placer County Zoning Administrator will be conducting a public hearing on Thursday, April 21, 2011 at 9:30 AM in the Planning Commission Hearing Room (3091 County Center Drive, Auburn, CA 95603) , to consider a request from Bayside Church, for a Minor Use Permit; this permit would allow for special events to take place at the church throughout the year.


 4/5/11 
 South Placer Fire District Looking For Ways to Raise Revenue 
 
At its regular meeting on March 16 , the SPFD Board voted 3-1 (one absent) to hire SCI Consulting Group to conduct an initial assessment to create an ongoing new revenue source to fund its operational and facility needs. The most likely new revenue source is a new benefit assessment or parcel tax, and the company specializes in opinion research specifically tailored to address the unique aspects of a mailed weighted ballot benefit assessment.

Benefit assessment districts circumvent Prop 218 which says a parcel tax must be approved by 2/3 vote. By doing a mailed weighted ballot benefit assessment 50% plus 1 of the RETURNED BALLOTS will pass a special tax, and similar agencies have turned to this post 218 method to raise taxes for fire protection and emergency services where districts are finding it difficult to fund salaries, benefits, and pensions. (The mosquito abatement assessment special tax was passed in Placer County this way and the amount appears on property tax bills.)

Phase I will cost the SPFD $24,000 and is an analysis of the District including parcels by type and location, property ownership, property attributes, fire and emergency service needs and other factors that may influence the proposed new funding measure. After the preliminary fire assessment methodology and ballot measure strategic plans are reviewed, a survey is mailed to affected property owners. Proposed fire assessments and weighted ballot “votes” for each property owner will be integrated into the survey and opinion research. The findings will be analyzed and strategic recommendations for an assessment ballot to garner property owner approval for a new benefit assessment tax will be developed for review by the District.

At this point, the Board has the opportunity to decide whether the survey results favor proceeding with an assessment mailed ballot measure or a parcel tax, what rate to propose and when to conduct the mailed ballot proceeding. If, after analyzing the results of the returned surveys, the District elects to proceed with Phase II, there will be an additional cost of about $70,000.

 NOTE: This assessment is considered a benefit to the property and revenue raised cannot be used to fund the ambulance service which accounts for 75% to 80% of the calls. In 2010-11, revenue from this source amounted to $943,318. In 1981, residents voted for an annual special assessment of $70 which has provided additional revenue every year and which accounted for $662,494 this budget year. This income, plus property taxes, fees, rentals, interest, etc., provided revenue of $7,352,158 for 2010-11.

The Director who voted against hiring a company to survey residents to determine how they would vote noted the fire district is doing a good job. However, he felt the economic situation in the country has changed and a better, more efficient job could be done to reduce costs. He did not feel raising taxes for revenue was the way to go. The Granite Bay Community Association will update members as this matter goes forth.



 South Placer Fire District Webpage Read March&apos;s Granite Bay Alert 
 4/5/11 
 Compromise Reached: Enclave At Granite Bay Update 
 
After many years of controversial hearings before MAC, the Planning Commission, and the Board of Supervisors, the community, neighbors, and the proponent have reached a compromise on a general plan for the Enclave at Granite Bay.

Proposed on the north side of Elmhurst Drive at the intersection of Swan Lake Drive in Treelake just east of Oakhills and Ridgeview Elementary Schools, this housing development’s general plan has been amended to allow 12 home sites where 6 were allowed under the current zoning. Approximately 46% of the site will be open space and access will be from Pastor Drive rather than from Elmhurst and Swan Lake Drive. Proponent originally sought a rezone and general plan amendment for 43 homes targeted at residents 55 years of age and older.


 3/31/11 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: April 
 
 MAC Committee Reports 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee. For more information, click here .

 Douglas Boulevard and Sierra College Boulevard Pedestrian Facilities 
Presented by Jeff Apps, Project Manager; Department of Public Works (15 min.)
The proposed project will complete approximately 0.50 miles of pedestrian facilities along the Sierra College Boulevard including five (5) foot wide sidewalk, ADA ramps and driveway entrances. The project proposes to fill in the few remaining gaps along Douglas Boulevard with five (5) foot wide sidewalks, ADA ramps and driveway entrances.

 Recreational Storage Facility Project 
Presented by Tony Cardoso – Capital Pacific Company; (15 min.)
This project is to build a boat/RV storage area on the undeveloped portions of parcels 047-0150-012 01510-042 (referred to as the East Portion). These properties are located on Douglas Boulevard. Currently these areas are vacant undeveloped land with commercial and some residential properties adjoining the project boundary. This project would propose the grading, paving, landscaping, fencing, concrete work and stripping of the undeveloped portions in order to place 97 – 10’x30’ boat storage stalls and 8 – 12’x45’ RV storage stalls on the West Portion of the project and 83 – 10’x30’ boat storage stalls on the East Portion of the project.

 Mixed Use Project 
Presented by Tony Cardoso – Capital Pacific Company; (15 min.)
This proposed project is located on approximately 19.9 acres at the south east corner of Auburn Folsom and Fuller, consisting of 68 single family lots, 23,000 square feet of retail on the corner of Auburn Folsom&amp;Fuller and 6,000 square feet of office on the south end of the project. The APN #: 047-150-045-000 and 050-190-001-000.


 3/31/11 
 Join the Historical Advisory Board 
 
Applications are being accepted for the Historical Advisory Board . For an application, please click here .


 3/9/11 
 Vehicle Burglaries on the Rise in Granite Bay 
 
The Placer County Sheriff’s Office is urging residents of Granite Bay to be extra vigilant about locking their vehicles and not leaving their belongings in their cars in light of a rash of recent vehicle burglaries. Click here for more information.


 2/24/11 
 Three Positions Now Open 
 
Applications are being accepted for Granite Bay MAC Secretary , Library Advisory Board and the Placer County Older Adult Advisory Commission . To apply for a position, click here .


 2/24/11 
 ** Attention **: Changes For March MAC Meeting 
 
There have been some one-time scheduling changes made for the March MAC meeting as well as the monthly MAC Sub-Committee Meeting
held on Wednesday, March 2, 2011 .

The MAC Sub-Committee Meeting on the Community Plan, which is held before the MAC meeting will not be held at the Eureka School District Office . The meeting has been relocated, and will now take place at the Granite Bay Branch Library located at 6475 Douglas Blvd at 5:00 PM .

The MAC meeting, which is normally held at 7:00 PM is now scheduled to begin at 6:50 PM back at the Eureka Union School District office located at 5455 Eureka Road .


 2/24/11 
 Kindergarten Registration Now Underway in Eureka Union School District 
 
If you have an incoming Kindergarten student for the 2011-2012 school year, you may pick up a registration packet at any of the K-3 schools:

 Greenhills School 
 8200 Greenhills Way
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916)-791-4230

 Maidu School 
 1950 Johnson Ranch Dr.
 Roseville, CA 95661
 (916)-789-7910

 Oakhills School 
 9233 Twin Schools Road
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916)-791-5391

Included in the registration packet are the times of School Tours , the Parent Welcome Meetings and Information Nights .


 2/24/11 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: March 
 
 MAC Committee Reports 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee. For more information, click here .

 Enclave at Granite Bay 
Presented by E.J. Ivaldi, Planning Services Division of the Community Development/Resource Agency; Applicant: Camille Courtney, Rancho Cortina Properties (5 min.)
The proposed project is a 12-lot planned residential development on 12.07 acres, with approximately 46% of the site dedicated to open space including natural wetland areas. The project is located on the North Side of Elmhurst Drive, at the intersection of Swan Lake Drive, in the Granite Bay area.

 Douglas Boulevard Self Storage&amp;Granite Bay Garage Condos 
Presented by Al Johnson – Al Johnson Consulting; Applicant: Al Johnson, Al Johnson Consulting (10 min.)
This project consists of two phases – 73,975 sq. ft. of Self Storage Units on the western parcel (APN: 047-060-016) and 74,902 sq. ft. of Garage Condos on the eastern parcel (APN: 047-060-033). The Self Storage portion includes a two-story office with a sales/rental area and a residence for the manager. The Garage Condos include a two-story club house with restrooms, lounge area, meeting rooms, and kitchen space for condo owners. The Garage Condos would also include a self service vehicle wash area. The project is located on the north side of Douglas Boulevard, approximately 0.08 miles east of its intersection with Auburn-Folsom Road.

To learn more about the Douglas Boulevard Self Storage&amp;Granite Bay Garage Condos , please click here .


 2/1/11 
 UPDATED: MAC Agenda Item Summary: February 
 
 MAC Committee Reports 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee. For more information, click here .

 ** Applicant for the item below has requested a continuance to the March 2 MAC meeting . 

 Douglas Boulevard Self Storage&amp;Granite Bay Garage Condos 
Presented by Al Johnson – Al Johnson Consulting (10 min.)
This project consists of two phases – 73,975 sq. ft. of Self Storage Units on the western parcel (APN: 047-060-016) and 74,902 sq. ft. of Garage Condos on the eastern parcel (APN: 047-060-033). The Self Storage portion includes a two-story office with a sales/rental area and a residence for the manager. The Garage Condos include a two-story club house with restrooms, lounge area, meeting rooms, and kitchen space for condo owners. The Garage Condos would also include a self service vehicle wash area. The project is located on the north side of Douglas Boulevard, approximately 0.08 miles east of its intersection with Auburn-Folsom Road.

To learn more about the Douglas Boulevard Self Storage&amp;Granite Bay Garage Condos , please click here .

 Overview of Placer County Air Pollution Control District Burn Rules and Responsibilities 
Presented by Ann Hobbs, Air Quality Specialist, Placer County Air Pollution Control District (15 min.)
The Placer County Air Pollution Control District staff will present information on the amending of the District’s Burn Rules, along with an overview of the District’s responsibilities. There have been no regulatory changes in burn rules; the newly organized guidelines simplify and consolidate rules and bring them into compliance with State regulations; the document also makes the information more user friendly.


 1/29/11 
 Kindergarten Registration in Granite Bay 
 
If you have an incoming Kindergarten student for the 2011-2012 school year, you may pick up a registration packet any time during regular business hours , beginning February 1st at your local school:

 Greenhills School 
 8200 Greenhills Way
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916)-791-4230

 Maidu School 
 1950 Johnson Ranch Dr.
 Roseville, CA 95661
 (916)-789-7910

 Oakhills School 
 9233 Twin Schools Road
 Granite Bay, CA 95746
 (916)-791-5391

For more information on Kindergarten, please click here to access the California Department of Education’s FAQ website.
 1/28/11 
 Opening For MAC Secretary 
 
The Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council has a vacancy for a secretary. To learn more, click here . Applications are now being accepted; click here to apply.


 
 2010 
 12/31/10 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: January 
 
 MAC Committee Reports 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee

 The Enclave at Granite Bay (Revised) 
Proposal to subdivide a 12.07 acre site into a 13-lot Planned Residential Development consistent with the Board of Supervisor’s approval (December 14, 2010) of a General Plan Amendment and Rezone. The revised vesting tentative subdivision map reduces the number of proposed lots from 26 to 13. Lot sizes would range in area between 15,000 square feet and 25,718 square feet. Approximately 42% of the site would be set aside as open space with active and passive recreation areas, including a pedestrian pathway connecting to Twin Oaks School. The project site is located on the north side of Elmhurst Drive, at the intersection of Swan Lake Drive in the Granite Bay area.


 12/14/10 
 Host Families Needed 
 
Please consider opening your home to an Educational Homestay Program international student for 3 ½ weeks this coming summer! This is an amazing opportunity for your family and surrounding communities to participate in an international exchange promoting language learning and building cross cultural relationships that will last a lifetime.

This next summer our students will be coming from France , Spain and Italy . The are arriving on July 7th and will be departing on Aug 2, 2011 . The students are supervised by EF staff from 8:00am-5:30pm Monday-Friday. For more information, please contact the local Program leader: Nicole McClintock at (916) 768-5829 or nicolemcclintock@yahoo.com .


 12/9/10 
 Grants Advisory Board for Youth (GABY) Now Offering HOPE Grant 
 
The Placer County Community Foundation is now accepting applications for the 2011 HOPE grant. The deadline for applications is January 7, 2011 . Click here for more information.


 12/2/10 
 Project Blue Light To Honor Fallen Officers 
 
The Placer County Sheriff’s Office is encouraging residents and businesses throughout Placer County to display blue lights during the month of December in honor of Project Blue Light.

For additional information on Project Blue Light, please click here , or call Community Services Officer Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 .


 11/27/10 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: December 
 
 MAC Committee Reports: 
Granite Bay Community Plan policy review committee.


 11/27/10 
 News10 Coats for Kids Winter Coat Drive 
 
Just clean out those closets and donate new or gently used coats to News10&apos;s Coats For Kids! Coats of all sizes are accepted. There are many ways you can help out from donating a coat, to taking donations yourself, holding an event where you collect coats, making a monetary donation, and volunteering your time.

Rogers Jewelry Company, Century 21 M&amp;M;and Associates and Swansons Cleaners will be collecting coats at all of their locations. So, donate now through December 3rd .

Locally, you can donate at the:
 Swansons Cleaners in Granite Bay at 6941 Douglas Boulevard
 Rogers Jewelry Company in Roseville at 9217 Sierra College Blvd.
 Tri Counties Bank in Granite Bay at 4100 Douglas Blvd.

 Click here to see more donation locations.


 11/27/10 
 Enclave at Granite Bay: Outcome of Meeting 
 
At the November 23rd meeting both the Granite Bay MAC and the Placer County Planning Commission recommended denial of the applicant’s request for a Rezone and General Plan Amendment; and, after input from the audience and discussion by the Supervisors, a motion was made and passed directing planning staff to return to the December 14 Board of Supervisors Meeting at 10:40 a.m. with findings for a General Plan Amendment and Rezone in order for the Board to consider the request to extend the zoning on the east side to the Pastor property.


 11/9/10 
 The Tyreke Evans Charity Poker Tournament 
 
It’s time for the 6th Annual Charity Poker Tournament supporting the American Diabetes Association. This year Tyreke Evans of the Sacramento Kings is joining Dr. Scott Warren to find a cure for diabetes, and he’s inviting local celebrities to join him. In addition to a fun night of poker, food, and drinks the celebrities will also be available for signings and pictures.

Please click here , and find out how to join this night of fun with the local celebrities.


 11/3/10 
 MAC Openings/Appointments 
 
Supervisor Uhler noted there are currently two openings on the MAC . Because all MAC members are required to resign and reapply in January, he has opted to make no appointments at this time but will instead consider applications submitted and fill all seven positions in January for a two year term. Contact Linda Brown at 800-488-4308 for information .


 11/3/10 
 Community Plan: Granite Bay MAC Sub-committee/Working Group Now Forming 
 
The Sub-committee, which consists of two MAC members (a Chair and Vice-Chair) and is open to any and all community members/property owners who are interested in providing input to staff on the policy items, will begin meeting in December. Ultimately, the intent of the sub-committee is to provide MAC with input on all recommendations by July 2011.

Planning staff will help coordinate and facilitate the meetings, which will be held at the Eureka Union School District Office at 6:00 p.m., one-hour prior to the regularly scheduled monthly MAC meetings. Additional sub-committee meetings may be convened as needed/required.

The Sub-committee’s Chair and Vice-Chair will provide monthly updates to the general MAC.


 11/3/10 
 Rancho Del Oro: Outcome of October 5th Meeting 
 
Despite the fact that correspondence and oral input overwhelmingly opposed applicant’s request, in the end, the Board of Supervisors approved the Rancho Del Oro project 3-1 .

At the October 5th meeting , applicant made a request for a Rezone. This Rezone would remove the Planned Development designation on the parcel, allowing for an additional 26 lots to be obtained.

While one concession was made to the residents, the 6 foot high wall along 3,000 feet of rural Olive Ranch Road be a 3 foot open design on top of a 3 foot solid base, with pedestrian access through the gated project from sunrise to sunset, for the most part, Chairperson, Supervisor Uhler ignored his constituents and the Granite Bay Community Plan and was perceived as acting as an advocate for the proponent.


 12/3/10 
 Enclave at Granite Bay: Outcome of Meeting 
 
At the November 23rd meeting both the Granite Bay MAC and the Placer County Planning Commission recommended denial of the applicant’s request for a Rezone and General Plan Amendment; and, after input from the audience and discussion by the Supervisors, a motion was made and passed directing planning staff to return to the December 14 Board of Supervisors Meeting at 10:40 a.m. with findings for a General Plan Amendment and Rezone in order for the Board to consider the request to extend the zoning on the east side to the Pastor property.


 11/3/10 
 Volunteer Planting Events: Creek Week 
 
As part of Creek Week, the Granite Bay Miners Ravine Nature Reserve Restoration project will occur on Saturday, November 13 from 9:00 a.m. to Noon at 7530 Auburn Folsom Road . Dry Creek Conservancy and Chad Aakre of Restoration Resources will lead volunteers. For more information and to RSVP please contact 773-6575 or Dry Creek Conservancy at dcc@surewest.net .


 11/3/10 
 South Placer Fire Department: October Report 
 
Fire Marshal Richardson reported that September was a busy month, especially for medial calls. He also noted that the fire personnel will wear pink T-shirts for the month of October in recognition of Breast Cancer Awareness Month. As of October 6, the SPFD has sold 500 of the shirts for $15 each to benefit the Susan B. Komen, Sacramento fund.


 11/3/10 
 California Highway Patrol: October Report 
 
A representative from CHP noted that Douglas Boulevard and Auburn-Folsom continue to be the areas of traffic accidents, 5 with injuries.


 10/29/10 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: November 
 
 Granite Bay Community Plan Update: 
County staff will provide an overview of the work plan for the Granite Bay Community Plan Update (Policy Document only) and also provide details of the Granite Bay MAC Sub-committee meeting that is scheduled to meet for the first time on December 1, 2010.


 10/27/10 
 “Howl-O-Ween” Event Benefits Placer County&apos;s K-9s! 
 
The public is invited to a family “Howl-O-Ween” event this Sunday, Oct. 31 , which will benefit Placer County law enforcement dogs. From 11 a.m. until 3 p.m. , meet the dogs and their handlers at Starbucks, 1228 Galleria Blvd., Roseville, across the street from the Galleria Mall . There will be K-9 demonstrations and there will be treats for dogs that come in costume. Raffle tickets will be for sale to win a brand new Trek mountain bike, generously donated by Bob’s Cycle Center. Raffle proceeds directly benefit local law enforcement dogs through the Foothills K-9 Association.

For more information, go to foothillsk9.org .

 **Raffle tickets are also available at Starbucks, Galleria Blvd., Bob’s Cycle Center, 378 N. Sunrise Blvd., Roseville, and at the Animal Nutrition Center, 1805 Cirby Way, Roseville. 


 10/4/10 
 CHP to Up Patrol of Auburn-Folsom Road 
 
Due to a number of accidents, with injuries, on Auburn-Folsom Road, CHP reports that they will increase patrol in that area.


 10/4/10 
 SPFD Supports Breast Cancer Awareness 
 
During the month of October the SPFD will trade in their blue firefighting shirts for pink ones to help raise funds for Breast Cancer Awareness . The shirts will be available at the Fire Prevention Fair , where profits from shirt sales will be donated to Susan G. Komen, Sacramento . For more information, please visit heroeswearpink.com .


 10/4/10 
 Fire Prevention Fair 
 
On Saturday, October 16 , the public is invited to join the South Placer Fire Department at Quarry Ponds eastern parking lot as they host the Fire Prevention Fair .


 10/4/10 
 Sherriff’s Department Report: September 
 
On the whole the Sheriff’s Department reports that unlawful activity is down, but there were some incidences of theft in unlocked vehicles; in addition, there were also a couple burglaries, which occurred when thieves gained access through unlocked sliding class doors.


 10/3/10 
 MAC Agenda Item Summary: October 
 
 Granite Bay Community Plan Policy Update Sub-Committee 
The MAC will be asked to review a proposal from the MAC Administrator and Planning Department regarding the creation of a MAC sub-committee to focus on, discuss and create potential policy changes to the Granite Bay Community Plan.


 9/25/10 
 Rancho Del Oro: Upcoming Meeting 
 
On Tuesday, October 5 , the Placer County Board of Supervisors will hold a public hearing to discuss the final EIR for the Rancho Del Oro project. The meeting will take place at 10:30 AM in the Board of Supervisors&apos; Hearing Room (175 Fulweiler Avenue, Auburn, CA 95603 .


 9/1/10 
 Sheriff’s Community Awareness Academy: Fall 2010 
 
It’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Office’s popular Community Awareness Academy , which offers an inside look at the law enforcement agency.

Classes will be held in the Community Room at the Placer County Sheriff headquarters in the Auburn Justice Center . The center is located at 2929 Richardson Drive in north Auburn’s Dewitt Center . Classes are scheduled from 6 p.m. to 9 p.m. 

To learn more about the academy, click here . Or, to reserve a spot, call Community Services Officer Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 or e-mail her at lharriso@placer.ca.gov .


 8/23/10 
 **UPDATE: Planning Department Makes Recommendation On Community Plan 
 
At the Board of Supervisors budget hearings on August 19 , Planning Director Michael Johnson gave an overview of the Planning Department’s budget for the next fiscal year and stated that they will proceed with Option 4 to complete the Granite Bay Community Plan update. That option is to keep the Land Use Element of the Plan as already adopted and only update the Policy portion of the Plan.

This is the Option that the Granite Bay Community Association supported at the April meeting of the Supervisors when staff reviewed five possible scenarios for moving forward with the GBCP update. It makes sense both logically and economically as some policies need updating and there wasn’t a push from the community to change the land use portion of the Plan.


 8/2/10 
 Planning Commission Vote on Rancho Del Oro Estates 
 
After much discussion at the July 22nd meeting, the Planning Commissioners voted on matters concerning the Rancho Del Oro Estates. Both sides plan to appeal the decisions.

The commissioners voted as follows:

1. Certify the R and adopt the Statement of Overriding Considerations (impacts to biological resources could not be mitigated) – Passed 4-2.

2. Approve the Vesting Tentative Map – Passed 4-2.

3. Deny the Variance for entry gates – Passed 5-1

4. Retain Agriculture overlay and direct that CC&amp;Rs;for this project cannot eliminate this condition – Passed 5-1

5. Recommended approval to the Board of Supervisors of the applicant’s request for a rezone with the above amendments – Passed 4-2
 8/2/10 
 UPDATE: Proposed State Regulations for Septic Systems 
 
The review of the new regulations proposed for the septic systems was suspended. The suspension comes in reaction to the opposition posed by Placer County and many other counties throughout the state.

Water Resources is studying a three tiered approach to develop required regulations. Additional information can be found here or jphal@placer.ca.gov .
 8/2/10 
 MAC Meetings Coming To Web 
 
At July’s MAC meeting the audience was informed that MAC meetings are now being recorded and the video is uploaded to the web; live-streaming video will be available in the near future.
 8/2/10 
 Budget Update 
 
Supervisor Uhler reported that the Board of Supervisors has adopted a preliminary balanced budget for the 2010-11 fiscal year, which involves reducing expenditures by 11% and laying off 12 people from a workforce of 2,400.
 8/2/10 
 Budget Effect on Granite Bay Community Plan 
 
Due to the preliminary balanced budget announced by Supervisor Uhler, it is projected that only one staff person will be budgeted for this task. However, the actual effect will be determined in August or September.
 8/2/10 
 Green Loan Program 
 
The popular County program which established a fund making it easier for residents to install energy conservation projects in their homes and make the financing of these projects part of their property tax bills has been suspended due to strict new underwriting requirements.
 8/2/10 
 CPR Classes 
 
Residents are invited to sign up for CPR classes offered at the fire station located on 6900 Eureka Road . Classes are limited to 20 spots , so call (916) 791-7059 for the dates of classes.
 7/29/10 
 The 27th Annual National Night Out 
 
On both Monday and Tuesday , August 2nd and 3rd , the Placer County Sheriff’s Office is hosting the 27th Annual National Night Out ; an event designed to heighten crime and drug prevention awareness and generate support for, and participation in, Neighborhood Watch. To learn more about the National Night Out activates, please click here .


 7/6/10 
 Quarry Ponds Sign Variance Appeal 
 
The Board of Supervisors will hold a public hearing on Tuesday, July 13, 2010 regarding the appeal. The meeting, located at 175 Fulweiler Avenue in Auburn , will start at 11 AM .


 7/6/10 
 Speed Limits Changes 
 
As a result of surveys on area road speeds, the Board of Supervisors approved increasing the speed limit on East Roseville Parkway to 40 miles per hour ; meanwhile, due to road constraints, the speed limit for Olive Ranch Road and Berg Street will remain at 35 miles per hour .


 7/6/10 
 Sheriff’s Report 
 
In the month of May, there were 25 residential burglaries in the community. In one case, a perpetrator, who was arrested for about eight burglaries, had been recently paroled.


 7/6/10 
 Supervisor’s Report 
 
Supervisor Uhler gave MAC an update on the County budget; he noted that the $23 million gap in the budget had been closed with the use of reserves and belt tightening.


 6/23/10 
 Free Fun: Sheriff’s Special Teams Featured at Opening Night of the Placer County Fair 
 
On Thursday night, several Placer County Sheriff’s special teams will be featured during the opening night of the Placer County Fair at the fairgrounds in Roseville. Teams will include the Placer County Sheriff’s Special Enforcement Team , Air Operations Unit featuring Falcon 30 , and the Canine Unit will provide the evening’s exciting finale. The program also includes the Sacramento Sheriff’s Posse , Touch&amp;Go Dog Agility , and a presentation by the Placer County Schutzhund Club .


 6/7/10 
 Sign Up For Sheriff’s Horse Camp 
 
It’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Department’s 18th Annual Ride With Pride , a one-day camp that pairs grade-school children with deputies and their horse partners. For more information, including dates and times, please click here .


 5/18/10 
 Placer County Sheriff’s Council Hosting Health&amp;Safety Expo 
 
This Saturday, the Placer County Sheriff’s Council is hosting its first-ever Health and Safety Expo to benefit the Placer County Sheriff’s Department. Please click here , to learn more.


 5/13/10 
 Public/Private Partnership Provides Customers Free Plants, Products and Other Discounts in May 
 
The San Juan Water District and Sierra Nursery partner during Water Awareness Month. To learn more about this, please click here .


 4/22/10 
 **NEXT STEP IN THE GRANITE BAY COMMUNITY PLAN UPDATE PROCESS 
 
All community members who have followed this issue for the past 18 or so months should try to attend this meeting. Even though it is not a Public Hearing and not usually open for Public Comment, the understanding is that Public Comment will be allowed.

&quot;The Placer County Planning Department will be providing the Board of Supervisors with an update on the Granite Bay Community Plan Review at their next regular meeting on Tuesday, April 27, 2010 . The meeting will take place at the Placer County Administrative Offices (Domes) at 175 Fulweiler Avenue in Auburn .&quot;

The full staff report and hearing agenda for the meeting is available on the website http://www.placer.ca.gov/Bos/Agenda.aspx . Click on Upcoming Meeting Agenda for 4-27-10 . Scroll down to Item 8 – Community Development Resources Agency Planning/Update to review the staff report that will be presented. On pages 129 and 130 of the report, staff presents 5 options for consideration and the possible fiscal impacts of each for the Board to consider when giving direction to staff on how to proceed.

This item will probably be heard shortly after the 9:00 starting time of the meeting.


 3/11/10 
 Sheriff&apos;s Report 
 
Deputy Clark reported there had been some smash and grab incidents in parking lots around Auburn-Folsom and Douglas. He also noted that magazine solicitors should be able to show a license for their sales activity.


 3/11/10 
 UPDATE: Chipper Program 
 
 **Updated from December 7, 2009: The popular Chipper Program has been reactivated and at least through the summer there will be no charge. For more information about the chipping services, please call (530) 889-0111 extension 3 .

About two months ago, the Chipper Program was suspended because the grant money that was used to run the program ran out. The very popular program is reorganizing and plans to resume operating sometime after the first of the year. However, residents using the service will be charged $70 per hour with a 30 minute minimum of $35.

Please visit click here for more information.


 2/23/10 
 Information on Community Plan Update 
 
In an effort to keep residents informed about the process and recent developments surrounding the Update of Granite Bay&apos;s Community Plan , here are some links that may be useful.
 &gt;&gt;For background information on the Community Plan, Minutes for the special February 11th meeting, etc, please click here .
&gt;&gt; To see specifics on the Requested Land Use Changes , please click here .
&gt;&gt; Then, to view the actual location of the parcels of land mentioned on the Requested Land Use Changes page, take the APN numbers of each request, and this map will provide the information. 


 2/23/10 
 UPDATED: February MAC Agenda Item Summary 
 
 Continued from the January 6, 2010 meeting - Zoning Text Amendment (PZTA T20090403)–Fowl and Poultry. 

Fowl and Poultry. The MAC is being asked to provide input on the proposed revisions to the Fowl and Poultry section of the Zoning Ordinance to allow for the keeping of up to three chicken hens in the Residential Single-Family (RS) zone district. The proposed wording is as follows“: In the Residential Single-Family (RS) zone district, the keeping of no more than three (3) chicken hens is permitted, subject to the approval of an Administrative Review Permit. The keeping of roosters, guinea hens, peacock hens, or other exotic hens, is prohibited. Chicken hens shall be confined to the subject property and shall not be allowed off-site. Residential Single-Family uses located in the Tahoe Basin, the Squaw Valley Land Use Plan area, as well as other adopted specific plans, are subject to this provision.

 Continued from the January 6, 2010 meeting - Zoning Text Amendment (ZTA 20080448 Emergency Shelters, Transitional and Supportive Housing) 

The MAC is being asked to provide input on revisions to the Placer County Zoning Ordinance to bring the Ordinance into compliance with State housing law for emergency shelters, transitional, and supportive housing. The proposed amendments will establish definitions for Emergency Shelters, Transitional Housing, and Supportive Housing as well as identify appropriate zoning designations where these uses will be allowed. (On Oct 8, 2009 the Planning Commission unanimously approved a motion to continue the proposed amendments to allow for additional input from interested parties as well as the MACs). Staff to discuss with interested parties concerns brought up at hearing including expanding proposed uses into additional zoning designations. In addition, staff was directed to change proposed temporary residential shelter designation into emergency shelter in order to be consistent with State’s terminology. Presenter, Jennifer Dzakowic, Senior Planner, Placer Co. Planning Dept.


 2/12/10 
 San Juan Water District&apos;s “Blue Thumb” Gardener Contest 
 
San Juan is seeking customers who have created water efficient landscapes to star in a new water efficiency advertising campaign for the Sacramento region. Nomination forms are due February 22, 2010.

If you know a resident who has created a beautiful, water efficient landscape, please visit www.sjwd.org/bluethumb to nominate them.


 
 2009 
 12/14/09 
 Rancho Del Oro Estates 
 
OPlacer County has just released a Draft Environmental Impact Report for the Rancho Del Oro Estates project. The review period for this project will be from December 8, 2009 through January 21, 2010. 

During this time, a public hearing will be held to receive comments on this project’s Draft EIR. The public hearing is scheduled on Thursday, January 14, 2010 at 10:05 AM in the Placer County Planning Commission Hearing Room , located at 3091 County Center Drive ( corner of Richardson Drive and Bell Road in the Dewitt Center ), Auburn .

Comments regarding the Daft EIR must be submitted to Maywan Krach , Environmental Coordination Services , at the Placer County Development 
 Resource Agency ( 3091 County Center Drive, Suite 190, Auburn, CA 95603 ), 
 by e-mail at cdraecs@placer.ca.gov or by fax at (530) 745-3003 . All comments must be received by January 21, 2010 at 5:00 PM .

Copies of the Draft EIR are available at the Granite Bay Public Library, and can also be seen here .


 12/10/09 
 Toy Drive to Benefit Children in Need 
 
The Placer County Sheriff’s Department has teamed with the Sacramento County Sheriff’s Department and KNCI Radio to host a toy drive for children in need. This Friday through Sunday, Dec. 11-13, collection receptacles will be set up inside Roseville’s Westfield Galleria Mall from 8 a.m. until 9 p.m. , inside the mall at the entrance to Nordstrom . Personnel from both sheriffs’departments will be staffing the doors.

This event will assist in providing underprivileged children with gifts this holiday season in Placer and Sacramento counties. KNCI will broadcast live each day of the event.

For more information, contact Community Services Officer Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 .


 11/17/09 
 Workshop Update 
 
 **UPDATE: Supervisor Uhler and the planning department have extended the deadline for summiting the survey given out at the Granite Bay Community Plan Workshop on October 28th . The new deadline is November 30, 2009 . In addition to extending the deadline, they have made the survey available on the web; click here .

Completed surveys can be dropped off at the Granite Bay Library located on 6475 Douglas Boulevard Granite Bay. Or, they can also be mailed to:
 
 Planning Department
Attn: EJ Ivaldi
3091 County Center Drive, Suite 140
 Auburn, CA 95603 
 
 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON NOVEMBER 6th: At the Granite Bay Community Plan Workshop on October 28th , county distributed a community survey of about 40 pages for residents to complete and submit by November 15, 2009 . The packet is divided into four sections: 
 &gt;&gt; Goals and Policies &gt;&gt; Proposed Policy Changes &gt;&gt; Suggested Criteria for Evaluating Land Use Requests &gt;&gt; Property Owner Land Use Change Requests 
 

If you were unable to attend the meeting and wish to complete a survey, contact the Placer County Planning Department at 800-488-4308 , extension 3000 for information.

At the November 4th MAC meeting, many residents felt the time line to respond was too short and asked to have the deadline to complete the survey extended. Supervisor Uhler said his office would look into the matter.


 10/20/09 
 Granite Bay Community Plan Review Workshop Announcement 
 
Placer County Planning Department staff will provide an overview of a community workshop scheduled for the evening of October 28th at the Lutheran Church of the Resurrection. This workshop’s primary purpose will be to solicit community input on requested changes to the community plan received from property owners.


 10/7/09 
 Otow Orchard Open House 
 
As a thank you to their customers for their patronage over the years, on Saturday, November 14, 2009 , the Otow Orchard on 6232 
 Eureka Road is holding an open house from 1 to 3 PM . Hosted 
 by the Placer Land Trust , visitors will enjoy: refreshments, (featuring
 Placer County produce), a demonstration of the ancient art of drying persimmons 
 (hoshigaki), a tour and information about the historical family farm.


 10/7/09 
 Community Plan: Hearing Mailing List 
 
As the updating of the Granite Bay Community Plan continues to be discussed, those interested in taking part in it, or simply staying informed, can be added to the mailing list to receive notices on upcoming hearings by contacting the Planning Department at (800) 488-4308, Extension 3000 .


 10/1/09 
 The 5th Annual JDRF Texas Hold&apos;Em Charity Tournament 
 
 On Friday, November 13, 2009 , take part in the 5th Annual Texas Hold &apos;Em Charity Tournament which will benefit the American Diabetes Association! Held at the Roseville Health and Wellness Center at 1650 Lead Hill Blvd , check in is at 5:30 PM with the game starting at 6:30 PM . With a tournament fee of $150, ($100 to charity and $50 to prize money) , have fun and support a great cause. The tournament is limited to the first 81 players ; so to reserve your spot, send the $100 charitable donation by November 1st to:
 
 Warren Chiropractic
1650 Lead Hill Blvd #600
Roseville, CA 95661 
 
For more information about this event, please call Scott Warren at (916) 947-4325. 


 9/16/09 
 Community Awareness Academy 
 
t’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Department’s popular Community Awareness Academy . The 
 academy offers a glimpse inside the law enforcement 
 agency. Participants are asked to attend all seven classes; each class covers a different topic. The classes which will be held in the Community Room at the Placer County Sheriff Department’s headquarters in the Auburn Justice Center (located at 2929 Richardson Drive in north Auburn’s Dewitt 
 Center) will take place  Tuesdays and Thursdays evenings, beginning October 6th and ending October 27th from 6 PM to 9 PM . To reserve a spot, call Community Services Officer Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 or e-mail her at lharriso@placer.ca.gov . For more information, click here .


 9/1/09 
 McClintock Holding Town Hall Meeting 
 
Tonight, Tuesday, September 1, 2009 , congressman Tom McClintock will hold a town hall meeting for Granite Bay residents to discuss health care reform. The meeting will be held in the gym at Granite Bay High School ( 1 Grizzly Way ) at 6:00 PM . For more information on other town hall meetings hosted by Tom McClintock, click here .


 8/29/09 
 Fire Safety Day 
 
On Saturday, October 3, 2009 the South Placer Fire District will hold a Fire Safety Day from 10 AM to 2 PM in the east parking lot of Quarry Pounds on Douglas Blvd .


 8/29/09 
 Batting Cage at Feist Park 
 
At its August meeting, MAC supported Lakeside Little League’s request of the County Parks Division to modify the park’s batting cage, giving it a steel roof and replacing the woven netting with chain link. 


 8/17/09 
 Update on Enclave Project 
 
On Thursday, August 13th , The Planning Commission voted 3-2 (two commissioners were absent) to support Placer County staff and deny a general plan amendment and rezone for the Enclave at Granite Bay project. The hearing went on for 2-1/2 hours before a standing room crowd only. The applicant requested the rezone in order to construct 27 age restricted homes (55 and older) on property zoned for 6 lots. Applicant has 10 days to file an appeal to the decision of the Planning Commission to the Board of Supervisors.

MAC had denied support of the project 7-0 and there was significant opposition from residents around the proposed project and Granite Bay as a whole.


 8/17/09 
 Lakeside&apos;s Dream Run Comes To An End 
 
After last night’s game against Chula Vista, Lakeside&apos;s All Star season has come to an end. Despite putting up a good fight, Lakeside lost to Park View . The Western Region championship game was much closer than the final score of score 11-4 indicates. Lakeside gave Park View the most challenging game of tournament; and in the process, made their community very proud.



 8/15/09 
 Lakeside Majors All Stars Reach the Championship Game 
 
After last night’s close game against Arizona, where Lakeside won 9 to 8, they now play the Park View from Chula Vista , Southern California winners. The televised game is set for tomorrow, Sunday, August 16, 2009 at 5:00PM on ESPN2 .


 8/14/09 
 Meeting To Be Held Over Deer Issue 
 
On Wednesday, August 27, 2009 there will be a meeting to discuss the proposed deer hunt. The meeting is at 7:00 PM at the Planning Commission Hearing Room, 3091 Center Dr, Auburn .


 8/14/09 
 Lakeside All Stars Make News in San Bernardino 
 
 **UPDATE: Lakeside Majors All Stars continue winning at the Little League Western Regional in San Bernardino ; 
 defeating both Utah on Monday with a final score of 10 to 0 
 and Hawaii on Wednesday 5 to 3. Next up for the 
 Lakeside Majors All Stars are the semi-finals where they 
 face Arizona , tonight at 7:30 p.m. .

 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON AUGUST 9th: The local Lakeside Majors All Stars are off to a strong start at the Little League Western Regional in San Bernardino ; defeating Nevada by a score of 7 to 1 on Friday and then Arizona on Saturday with a final score of 4 to 1. With these two wins behind them, the Lakeside Majors All Stars face Utah on Monday, August 10, 2009 . For a complete list of games and times, please click here .


 8/14/09 
 Students At Granite Bay High School Have H1N1 Virus; School To Remain Open 
 
 **UPDATE: According to the Granite Bay View , the number of confirmed H1N1 cases currently stands at 8. In addition, about 39 other students were home on Thursday with flu-like symptoms; officials caution that 
 they were not confirmed cases of the virus.

 ORIGINALLY POSTED ON AUGUST 11th: With the new school year just beginning, The Roseville Joint High School District has confirmed that four students at Granite Bay High School have contracted the H1N1 virus or swine flu. Of those four students, three of them were students that had gone to band camp at the school, which was held before the school year began. One of those students is now feeling better and is back at school. Meanwhile, the fourth student, not associated with the band, was sent home and was confirmed to have the virus on Monday. In addition to these four students, according to Principal Michael McGuire, seven other students with flu-like symptoms have been kept at home; however, those students have not been confirmed to have the virus.

The school is sending out a message to all of its parents to let them know about the cases. In addition, the District said it is following Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and Placer County health guidelines, which state that any school staff or student who show up with a fever, cough or sore throat are sent home and asked to not to return until 24 hours after the symptoms are gone. School district officials have gone on to meet with all of the school nurses, who were told, if students come to their offices with symptoms, they should be sent home.


 7/31/09 
 26th Annual National Night Out 
 
The Placer County Sheriff’s Department is taking to the streets for the 26th annual National Night Out . Monday and Tuesday, August 3 and 4 . 
 Convoys of emergency vehicles will be making their way from 
 neighborhood to neighborhood to celebrate the annual event 
 that brings neighbors and their public safety partners 
 together. National Night Out is designed to heighten crime 
 and drug prevention awareness and generate support for, and 
 participation in, Neighborhood Watch. Click here to see more details about this event. Also, for questions on future National Night Out events, call CSO Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 .


 7/12/09 
 UPDATE: Placer County Planning Commission To Hold Public Hearing 
 
On Thursday, July 9, 2009 , the Planning Commission held a 
 meeting to discuss the Enclave at Granite Bay project. After hearing a presentation by the applicant&apos;s 
 representative, the Planning Commission decided to 
 return the project back to the planning staff and have 
 re-scheduled the meeting to hear all of the issues and 
 conditions on the project. That meeting is scheduled for Thursday, August 13, 2009 at 10:05 a.m. in the 
 Planning Commission&apos;s Hearing Room - 3091 County 
 Center Drive, Auburn, CA. 


 6/29/09 
 Landscaping Project 
 
The County is hoping for bids on the Douglas Boulevard landscaping 
 project this summer. Construction would then begin after Labor 
 Day and continue through the winter.


 6/29/09 
 Update: Auburn Folsom Widening Project 
 
As discussed at last month&apos;s MAC meeting, the middle phase of the Auburn Folsom Widening Project, located from Lou Place to Ann Place (just south of Eureka Road) will be put out for bids this summer. The project is expected to take about two construction seasons to complete.


 6/29/09 
 Fish And Game Contacted Over Deer Problem 
 
Supervisor Uhler has contacted Fish and Game after a number of dear and 
 vehicle strikes in the area. The agency, concerned with 
 possible over population of deer, is considering issuing about 20 
 permits for a controlled bow and arrow hunt to thin the deer 
 population. No guns would be involved.


 6/29/09 
 Douglas Fire Station Sold 
 
The South Placer Fire District&apos;s Board of Directors has sold the 
 residentially zoned Douglas Fire Station property on Douglas 
 Boulevard to a Jewish Community Center for $616,000.


 6/28/09 
 Placer County Planning Commission To Hold Public Hearing 
 
On Thursday, July 9, 2009 , the Placer County Planning 
 Commission will hold a pubic hearing at 10:30 am in the 
 Planning Commission Hearing Room (3091 County Center Drive, Auburn, 
 CA 95603).  Click here to learn more about what will be discussed.


 6/2/09 
 MAC Makes Decision About Enclave At Granite Bay 
 
After listening to a detailed presentation, consisting of input from the project designer, an arborist and traffic engineer, MAC voted unanimously to recommend that the proposed Enclave subdivision in Granite Bay be denied.


 5/6/09 
 Sign Up For Sheriff’s Horse Camp 
 
It’s time to sign up for the Placer County Sheriff Department’s 17th annual Ride With Pride . Children ages seven to 12 are invited to participate in this one-day camp that pairs them with deputies and their horse partners. Participants may choose to attend Ride With Pride on one of four days: June 22-25, 2009 at the Gold Country Fairgrounds in Auburn . Classes will be held from 9 a.m. to 2:30 p.m. each day and a free lunch is provided as part of this free event. For more information or to register, call Community Services Officer Lynn Harrison at (916) 652-2419 .


 5/1/09 
 Auburn Folsom Road Construction 
 
After being on winter suspension, the work on Auburn-Folsom Road, from Lou Place to the Sacramento County line, will resume. The contractor will complete the median landscaping, place open graded asphalt and stripe the road. This work will be done with lane closures and is expected to take about six week to finish.


 5/1/09 
 South Placer Fire District 
 
The South Placer Fire District Board of Directors appointed Madelaine Kiliany to fill the spot vacated by Jeff Moss, who resigned to accept the position of Planning Commissioner for this area.


 5/1/09 
 Placer County Volunteer Opportunities 
 
The Placer County Sheriff’s Department is hosting an evening to showcase opportunities to 
 volunteer within county government and government support entities. On Tuesday, May 12, 2009 , an informational evening will be held at the Auburn Justice Center, 2929 Richardson Drive, Auburn, in the community room from 6-8 p.m. Among the agencies participating are the Sheriff’s Department, the District Attorney’s Office, the Museum Department, the Placer County Law Enforcement Chaplaincy, Child Advocates of Placer County and more. For more information on this event, please click here .


 4/23/09 
 Foothills K9 Association Fundraiser 
 
The Animal Nutrition Center in Roseville have begun a fundraising effort to replace the aging protective ballistic vests for the 15 law enforcement canines working in four different agencies within Placer County. The fundraiser involves tickets for dog food for a year for 12 winners, a two-night stay at the Resort at Squaw Creek, cedar dog houses, dog beds, several dinners for four at local restaurants and much more. The tickets are for sale up until the day of the event. On Sunday, May 3, 2009 , from 11 a.m. to 3 p.m. , the drawings will be held at Animal Nutrition Center at 1805 Cirby Way, Suite 10, in Roseville . For more information about this event, click here . 


 4/2/09 
 Bids&amp;Bites 
 
On Saturday, May 16, 2009 take part in Bids&amp;Bites . From 6 to 10 PM at the Lutheran Church Event Center , (6365 Douglas Blvd), the charity event, presented by Granite Bay Service Clubs , will be a casual evening of food, art, auctions and fun. Tickets are $35.00 per person ; for more information, please click here .


 3/28/09 
 Sheriff&apos;s Report 
 
An officer reported that 
 there have been a number of home burglaries and thefts from 
 vehicles. The officer suggested that some of the rise in crime is 
 driven by the poor economy and residents are urged to lock cars and homes to deter criminals.


 3/28/09 
 Supervisor&apos;s Report 
 
At February&apos;s meeting, Supervisor Uhler 
 updated the MAC on the progress of a number of road projects in the 
 southern part of Placer County; in addition, he discussed: a 
 replacement helicopter for the Sheriff&apos;s Department, and a Ritz 
 Carlton Hotel to be built at North Star. 


 3/3/09 
 Granite Bay Community Plan Update 
 
After being postponed twice the special community meeting to discuss the Granite Bay Plan, and the process for updating it, was finally held on February 11th . The County estimated that approximately 400-450 residents packed the Lutheran Church of the Resurrection, where Planning Director Michael Johnson, gave a short presentation. During which he noted that comments regarding the update must be received by June 30, 2009 . At that time, staff will review them and then prepare an EIR; a process is estimated to take about two years to complete.

Following Mr. Johnson’s presentation, about 30 residents gave input to the staff; the majority of those people questioned the necessity of updating the Plan, which seems to be working fine as is. For more information about the Plan and the update process as well as forms, please check out the hotline: (530) 745-3098 or click here .


 2/27/09 
 San Juan Water District Water News 
 
The San Juan Water District is reaching out to community organizations to provide important news about the drought, Folsom Lake water supply conditions and conservation tips. To learn more please click here .


 2/27/09 
 Roseville Arts &quot;Art in the Garden&quot; Tour 
 
Tickets for the Roseville Arts’9th annual fundraiser, &quot;Art in the Garden&quot; go on sale Sunday, March 1st . The spring home, garden tour and art sale slated for Saturday, May 2, 2009 , from 10:00am to 4:00 pm , will benefit Roseville Arts’Blue Line Gallery which supports art-related activities for
 children and adults in the community. For more information about this event, please click here . 


 2/20/09 
 Sheriff Offers Free Victim Notification Program 
 
In a new press release the Placer County Sheriff introduces a new notification program for victims of crime. To learn more about the program, please click here .


 2/12/09 
 Amazing Facts Ministries News 
 
New information about the Amazing Facts Ministries has just been posted, so check out our Development page.


 2/3/09 
 Metal Thefts 
 
Many residents have been frustrated by the theft of brass letters (from sub-division entrances) as well as catalytic converters, etc. The recently passed AB 844 bill addresses metal theft, requiring the recycler to hold payment for 3 days; in addition, the seller must present a photo ID, thumbprint and a photograph of the materials offered for sale.


 2/3/09 
 Public Safety 
 
The Sheriff’s Service Center located in the shopping center at the southwest corner of Douglas and Sierra College has closed. Lynn Harrison will be the Community Services Officer in charge of Neighborhood Watch for this area. She can be contacted at (916) 652-2419 .


 2/3/09 
 New Septic System Requirements 
 
At last month’s MAC meeting the Placer County Environmental Health Director, Jill Pahl discussed California regulations and the statewide conditional wastewater discharge waiver proposed for all existing and new septic systems. These new regulations will establish minimum requirements for permitting, monitoring and operation of Onsite Wastewater Treatment System (OWTS) as required by AB 885 passed in 2000. The proposed regulations are now part of a draft document due to go before the Water Resources Control Board on February 9th . Placer County Environmental Health will submit Placer County Comments to Water Resources on February 8th. The Public comment period ends February 9th , with July 1, 2010 being the implementation date. For addition information contact Jill Pahl at 800-488-4308 or jpahl@placer.ca.gov .

Send Comments by February 9th to: State Water Resources Control Board Division of Water Quality
Attn: Todd Thompson, P.E.
1001 I Street, 15th Floor, P.O. Box 2231 Sacramento, CA 95812 


 2/3/09 
 ***IMPORTANT REMINDER: Special Community Meeting 
 
After being rescheduled twice over the past two months, the Special Community 
 Meeting to discuss the Granite Bay Community Plan will take place on February 11th at 7:00 PM and will be held at the Lutheran Church of the Resurrection on 6365 Douglas Blvd (Right next door to the Granite Bay Library) .


 1/11/09 
 Dinner&amp;Auction to Benefit the Granite Bay High School Baseball Program 
 
The Granite Bay 
 High School Baseball Boosters Association is holding their annual dinner and auction on Saturday, 
 January 31, 2009 at the Granite Bay Golf Club . The dinner/auction is the major 
 fundraiser for the baseball program and in the past has provided 
 monies for necessary field upgrades, dugouts, equipment, uniforms, 
 training, and the like. There is still more to do to support our 
 student athletes, and district budgets need to be supplemented. The 
 Baseball Boosters welcome all supporters to attend this enjoyable 
 evening of dining, silent and live auctions, and dancing at the 
 lovely Granite Bay Golf Club. The auction has historically included 
 many exciting items for all tastes and budgets: from wine&amp;gift 
 baskets, tickets to sporting events, to one of a kind artwork and 
 exciting vacation packages! This year includes a raffle for an HP 
 Laptop Computer as well. For information regarding tickets or to make a donation to 
 the auction effort, please call Leigh Mastrantonio at 916-791-5076 .


 1/1/09 
 IMPORTANT: Special Community Meeting Date Changed (Again) 
 
The Special Community Meeting to discuss the Granite Bay Community Plan has once again been changed. At this time, the meeting is now scheduled to take place on February 11 (not January 14) at 7:00 and will be held at the Lutheran Church on Douglas Blvd .


 
 2008 
 12/9/08 
 IMPORTANT: Special Community Meeting Date Changed 
 
At the request of the community&apos;s residents the Special Community Meeting to discuss the Granite Bay Community Plan has been changed from December 17 to January 14 . The time and place of the meeting are unknown at this time.


 12/9/08 
 December MAC Meeting Moved 
 
MAC&apos;s December 3 meeting was held in the Eureka Elementary School GYM at 5477 Eureka Road Granite Bay, CA 95746 .

 12/9/08 
 Placer County Routing Information 
 
A representative of the Placer County Sheriff’s Department discussed how 911 calls made from cell phones are routed in the unincorporated County areas explaining the specific areas where these calls will still go to CHP and where they will go directly to Placer County’s dispatch.


 12/9/08 
 Auburn-Folsom Widening Update 
 
Work 
 on the widening of Auburn-Folsom Road, which will make Auburn-Folsom Road a 4-lane road from the Placer 
 County line to Lou Place , is proceeding as scheduled and for all intents and purposes was completed in November. However, depending on the weather, the final noise attenuating asphalt layer might be delayed until spring because it 
 has to be done in warmer weather. At this time, there are no plans for future phases of the widening project; but, 
 if funding is available, the project may continue in 2010 .


 12/9/08 
 Barton Road Bridge Replacement Update 
 
Westcon Construction began working on the bridge replacement project (over Miners Ravine on Barton Road) in May. While the project was scheduled to be completed in mid-November, due in part to the complexity of constructing the bridge, it somewhat behind schedule; but on budget. If the work extends beyond the contract completion date, Westcon Construction faces a penalty of $1,000 for each day beyond that date.


 10/27/08 
 Give&amp;Take: A Holiday Charity Fundraiser For The Tommy Apostolos Fund 
 
On Tuesday, December 2, 2008 at 6:00 PM , join in on a fun-filled evening of games, including: Texas Hold &apos;em, Blackjack, Checkers, Guitar Hero, Coed Table Shuffleboard, Coed Bowling, Darts, Cribbage, Air Hockey, Backgammon, Bunco and Chess. All the proceeds from this event will go to the Tommy Apostolos Fund . In addition to helping this charity, there will also be a canned food drive.

Taking place at Strikes Entertainment Center in Rocklin , space for 
 each game is limited and spots are first-come, first-serve. To learn more about the event and for registration 
 details, please click here . If you have any questions, you can email Jim Crosthwaite at jim_crosthwaite@yahoo.com or Ron Roberts at r.roberts@surewest.net .


 10/14/08 
 Granite Bay Helps in KidsCan Food Drive 
 
Between now and Friday, November 7, 2008 KidsCan continues the tradition of helping to feed hungry families in our community. To do your part, donate any canned and non-perishable food items at any participating school, food bank or other donation locations. Locally, donations are being collected at: Cavitt Junior High School: 7200 Fuller Drive
 Eureka Union Elementary School: 5477 Eureka Road
 Granite Bay Schoolhouse: 8265 Sierra College Blvd. Suite 322
 Granite Bay High School: #1 Grizzly Way
 Greenhills Elementary School: 8200 Greenhills Way
 Oakhills School: 9233 Twin Schools Rd.
 Ridgeview Elementary School: 9177 Twin Schools Rd. 
To learn more about these locations and who to contact, or to see a 
 complete list of donation locations—(including locations 
 in Roseville, Lincoln and Loomis)—please click here . 


 9/25/08 
 FYI: MAC Updating Community Plan 
 
On Wednesday, October 1, 2008 , 
 as the last item (Item C) of this month&apos;s agenda, an 
 update to the Granite Bay Community Plan will be discussed.

To learn more about this item and how 
 it will affect you, please look below at the MAC Item 
 Summary .


 9/25/08 
 10/1/08: MAC Agenda Item Summary 
 
 Placer County Emergency Call Routing Information 

A representative of the Placer County Sheriff’s Department will discuss the new routing of 911 calls made from cell phones in the unincorporated Placer County areas. The Sheriff’s representative will discuss the specific areas within the County where these calls will still go to CHP and where they will go directly to Placer County’s dispatch.

 Granite Bay Road Project Update 

Sherri Berexa from Placer County Public Works department will give the community an update on both the Auburn-Folsom Road widening project as well as the Barton Road bridge project.

 Granite Bay Community Plan Update 

The County of Placer will be initiating an update to the Granite Bay Community Plan adopted in 1989. The purpose of the update will be to insure that community&apos;s goals, policies and programs are up to date and consistent with the County General Plan. The update will also consider changes in land use.

At this time County staff is developing a work program which will include a six-month opportunity for a property owner to changes in their zoning and land use designation. It is anticipated that this opportunity would begin in January 2009. County staff will provide guidelines for property owners who wish to consider changes.

Once all requests have been submitted and considered, the work program will entail the development of a new policy document, zoning map, land use diagram and an environmental impact report. This process is expected to take at least 2 years.


 9/19/08 
 Placer County District Attorney’s 6th Annual Elder Conference: “Strategies for Successful Aging” 
 
On Saturday, October 25, 2008 from 8:00 AM to 3:30 PM join the Placer County 
 District Attorney’s office and the local non-profit referral agency, Seniors First , to learn about 
 the types of abuse being perpetrated right here in Placer County, and what seniors can do to protect themselves! 
 The conference will take place at William Jessup University located at 333 Sunset Blvd. , Rocklin, 
 CA . (There is no fee for this event and a complimentary continental breakfast will be provided. Lunch 
 will be available for purchase.) 

Following the conference, guests will be encouraged to stay and attend the resource fair. The 
 fair will include over 50 vendors who provide valuable services throughout Placer County to seniors and dependant 
 adults. You will also want to gear up for winter by getting your flu shot! Flu shots are free to Medicare 
 recipients with a card and will be available to others for a nominal fee. Seating is limited, so guests will need 
 to R.S.V.P. to Marty at Seniors First , (530) 889-9500 ext. 215 or by email Marty@seniorsfirst.org , no 
 later than October 15, 2008 .
For more information about this, please click here .

 9/8/08 
 Placer County Health and Human Services Department: Rapid HIV Testing Now Available 
 
The Placer County Health and Human Services Department wants to inform the public that rapid HIV testing, for the virus that causes AIDS, is now available in Placer County. The results of the test are ready in 20 minutes. For more information about this service, please click here . 


 9/5/08 
 FYI: New Schedules for Placer County’s Libraries 
 
Beginning Saturday, September 13, 2008, the hours of the Granite Bay, Rocklin and Auburn libraries will change. The new schedule will reduce the libraries’ hours by a net total of nine hours. The Granite Bay library&apos;s new schedule is as follows: CLOSE on Mondays and Sundays 
 OPEN from 11 AM to 7 PM on Tuesdays through Thursdays
OPEN from 10 AM to 6 PM on Fridays
OPEN from 10 AM to 5 PM on Saturdays 
To see the new hours for the branch libraries in Rocklin and Auburn , please click here . The 
 schedule will be reviewed periodically to determine its impact on 
 public services. Also, service hours will remain the same at all 
 other branch libraries and the Bookmobile.

 9/3/08 
 The 4th Annual JDRF Texas Hold&apos;Em Charity Tournament 
 
Have some fun and win some special prizes at the 4th Annual JDRF Texas Hold&apos;Em Charity Tournament on Friday, September 19, 2008 at the Roseville Health and Wellness Center at 1650 Lead Hill Blvd. With a tournament fee of $150, this night of fun will also help to raise money for the Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation, which strives to find a cure for diabetes. Please reserve your spot today by sending the $100 charitable donation for JDRF to: Warren Chiropractic 
 1650 Lead Hill Blvd #600 
 Roseville, CA 95661 
(The additional $50 of the tournament fee will be placed 
 in a prize pool, which will be given to anyone that is able 
 to knock out the three time defending champion). For 
 more information about this event, which includes dinner at 5:00 PM , please call Scott Warren at (916) 947-4325 .


 9/1/08 
 September MAC Agenda Item Summary 
 
 he Enclave at Granite Bay 

Located north of Elmhurst Drive and south of Pastor Drive, it is proposed that the 12.1 acres of land (zoned for approximately six homes) would have 29 single-family residential lots (senior housing), ranging in size from 2,200 to 2,600 square feet. In addition, approximately 49% of the land would be dedicated to open space including natural wetland areas, pedestrian pathways, bocce ball courts and a community barbecue area.

 New Email Alert Program 

The Placer County District Four website has a new feature that allows residents and business owners to sign up for email alerts about important information regarding the Granite Bay area. This system is currently in testing and needs as many people to register for it as possible to help best define what types of notices and information residents and business owners would like to receive. Suggestions for this will also be solicited at the MAC meeting. Residents and business owners will be able to sign-up at the MAC meeting or can go to http://www.placer.ca.gov/bos/District4/EmailSignUp_2.aspx 

  Village Center Monument Signs 

The project applicant is seeking the MAC’s input on the location and designs of monument signs for the retail and office projects at Southeast and Southwest corners of East Roseville Parkway and Village Center Drive.

 Granite Bay Garage Club Condos 

Sundance Properties proposes to build a custom garage condominium facility (storage buildings) on approximately 4.5 acres located at 7135 Douglas Blvd. There will be approximately 100 units, ranging in size from 800 to 1400 square feet. In addition to the units, they propose building a 2500+/- square foot clubhouse that would include a kitchen for heating prepared foods, bathrooms with showers, a lounge area with large screen TV, and an office. There would also be a wash bay for RV’s, boats and cars.

 


 8/15/08 
 FYI: Paving Work Delayed 
 
The paving work on Douglas Boulevard between Sierra College Boulevard and Seeno Avenue in Granite Bay has been slightly delayed. While the project 
 was originally supposed to be completed Saturday morning , 
 it is now is scheduled to be finished by Monday night . On Friday night, as originally scheduled, Douglas will be 
 open for eastbound traffic, while westbound lanes are being 
 repaved; the westbound traffic will be detoured southward on 
 Barton Road and west on Eureka Road to Sierra College 
 Boulevard. The detour is scheduled to remain in effect from 7 p.m. Friday to 6 a.m. Saturday. The paving work on 
 the eastbound lanes will be done Monday night. Lane closures 
 will be in effect, but no detours are anticipated.


 8/2/08 
 Ron Bakken&apos;s Memorial Bench 
 
A memorial bench, a tribute to Ron Bakken and his many years of community service, has been installed in the Granite Bay Community Park. Ron was a member of GBCA and webmaster of GraniteBay.com for many years; in addition, he served on many committees in Granite Bay and Placer County. When he passed back in January, his many friends and family thought this would be a fitting tribute, which is now located near the baseball diamond at the east end of the park.


 8/2/08 
 “Vacation Check” 
 
Offered by the Placer County Sheriff’s Department and its volunteers, “Vacation Check” is a service where volunteers will check on your property, while you are away. If you are interested in this service, contact the Sheriff’s sub-station at 791-5159 .


 8/1/08 
 FYI: MAC Meeting Canceled 
 
The August 6th (Wednesday) meeting of the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council 
 has been canceled . They will instead met at the MAC&apos;s next regularly scheduled meeting on Wednesday, September 3, 2008 .


 7/16/08 
 FYI: Special Meeting 
 
The San Juan Water District Board of Directors is holding a special meeting on Wednesday, July 23, 2008 at 8:30 AM . To find out 
 more about the agenda of this meeting, please click here .


 6/2/08 
 Fire Safety Reminders 
 
During May’s MAC Public Safety Meeting the fire marshal reminded residents to evaluate their properties and make 
 sure they are fire safe by maintaining 100 feet of defensible space around the home; in addition to 
 this, the importance of properly storing and/or disposing of oily rags according to the directions on the product containers 
 was also stressed.


 6/2/08 
 Helping Placer County Agriculture 
 
At May’s MAC meeting, Placer County’s Agriculture Marketing Director suggested that residents buy fresh fruits, vegetables, nuts, eggs, honey, etc at the Granite Bay Farmers’ Market . In purchasing locally grown food, the family farm is preserved and fresh, nutritious products are provided to the consumer. The Granite Bay Farmers’ Market, held at the corner of Douglas Boulevard and Auburn-Folsom Road , takes place on Thursdays from 9 AM to 1 PM .


 5/23/08 
 Eureka Union School District Makes A Final Decision 
 
Eureka Union School District Board of Trustees took action on several
 items brought up by the Long Range Planning Task Force . At this meeting on May 13th , it was decided, that among other things, grade level reconfigurations 
 and school closures will take place. Beginning in 2009-2010 school year, the Board 
 decided to convert Greenhills , Maidu and Oakhills to Kindergarten-5th grade schools and Cavitt and Olympus to 6th through 8th grade schools. 
 This move means the closure and leasing of facilities at Eureka and Excelsior Schools . For more information about this, click here . 


 5/3/08 
 New Park Opening 
 
The public is invited to the Grand Opening of the Franklin School Community Park at 70540 Franklin School Road (off Laird) on Thursday, May 8th at 1:30 PM . 
 The park is a joint development project between Placer County, the Loomis Union School 
 District and community volunteers; it is part of the park district for Granite Bay. The 
 4.5 acres of land was provided by the school district and the construction was overseen by 
 the Placer County Department of Facility Services. The park’s features include: a synthetic 
 turf baseball diamond/soccer field, a concrete trail and extensive landscaping; plans are 
 also underway to add a group picnic pavilion.


 4/14/08 
 Friends of the Granite Bay Library Fashion Show 
 
The Friends of the Granite Bay Library will sponsor a fashion show and luncheon on Thursday, May 1st at the Granite Bay Golf Club Conservatory . The theme 
 is “We Request the Pleasure of Your Company” and will feature bridal, trousseau and summer 
 wear. There will be local vendors with unique gifts, a silent auction and raffle prizes. Doors 
 open at 10:30 and lunch will be served at 11:45 . Tickets are $60 with all 
 proceeds to benefit the library. More information is available at the Granite Bay Library.


 3/29/08 
 Granite Bay Union School District To Make A Final Decision 
 
Taking place 
 on Wednesday, April 2nd, 6:30 PM in the Granite Bay High School Theater , the forum 
 will discuss declining enrollment in the school district, 
 examine possible solutions and take public input. A 36 member
 Long Range Task Force consisting of parents, teachers and administrators
 have been given the task of brainstorming possible solutions to this problem. 
 Some of these possible solutions include: closing schools, reconfiguring schools 
 to K-5 and 6-8, establishing a district run charter school, etc. The task force’s final recommendations will be presented to the board at its April 15th meeting; action will then be taken at the board’s May 13th meeting.


 3/29/08 
 Open House For Station 19 
 
The South Placer Fire District invites the public to the Grand Opening and Dedication Ceremony 
 of Station 19 at 5300 Olive Ranch Road on Friday, April 11th at 3:00 PM .


 3/17/08 
 FYI: San Juan Water District Will Hold Special Meeting 
 
On Wednesday, March 19th , the San Juan Water District will hold a special meeting at 9 AM .


 2/27/08 
 March MAC Meeting Cancelled 
 
The MAC&apos;s upcoming meeting on Wednesday, March 5, 2008 has been cancelled . The next meeting will be, the regularly scheduled meeting, on Wednesday, 
April 2, 2008 .


 2/14/08 
 Volunteer Work Day 
 
Bring your rakes and shovels and join the fun on Saturday, March 29, 2008 during a Volunteer Work Day at Franklin School Community Park . Beginning at 8 AM , lunch will be provided. FYI: If it rains, Saturday, April 5th , is the alternative date for this event.


 2/12/08 
 Public Meetings To Be Held on the Preliminary Plan for Folsom Lake State Recreation Area 
 
The California State Parks&amp;U.S. Bureau of Reclamation will preview the 
 Preliminary Plan as well as the Draft Environmental Impact Report and Draft 
 Environmental Impact Statement for the Folsom Lake State Recreation Area (SRA) 
 and Folsom Powerhouse State Historic Park. This preview will take place 
 over a 45-day period, ending on March 24, 2008. Click here for more information and to see a copy of The Plan. The public can also learn and share their thoughts about 
 The Plan
 during
 two meetings:
 March 5, 2008 –7-9pm at Cavitt 
 Junior High School (gymnasium), 7200 Fuller Drive, Granite 
 Bay, CA 95746
 
March 11, 2008 –7-9pm at Folsom Middle School 
 (auditorium), 350 Blue Ravine Road, Folsom, CA 95630

If you have any questions, contact Jim Micheaels at jmichel@parks.ca.gov .


 2/7/08 
 Updates on MAC&apos;s New Website 
 
The MAC website, introduced late last year, has just been updated 
 and now includes the latest agendas and other information for 2008. This information can be found at: http://www.placer.ca.gov/bos/District4/2008GraniteBayMAC.aspx .
 The 2007 information can still be found at: granitebaymac.com .


 2/6/08 
 Measure F Passes 
 
On Tuesday, February 5th , voters said &quot;Yes&quot; to measure F. The yes vote allows the fire district to allocate funds it already collects, keeping them from significantly reducing services and seeking other tax or fee increases.


 1/19/08 
 Granite Bay Recreation Association Under Development 
 
In conjunction with Placer County Parks and the Granite Bay MAC Parks Committee, FirstStep Sports Marketing is in the process of developing the Granite Bay Recreation Association, which will be dedicated to providing Recreation 
 Opportunities for both youth and adults in the Granite Bay area. For more information visit our Youth Activities section and scroll down to&quot;FirstStep, Placer County Parks and the Granite Bay MAC Parks Committee Developing the Granite Bay Recreation Association&quot;.


 1/13/08 
 GBCA Loses A Great Supporter 
 
Sadly, on Friday, January 4, 2008 , Ron Bakken passed 
 away in his sleep and the Granite Bay Community Association 
 lost a great supporter. Very active in the Granite Bay 
 community, Ron served several times on the Granite Bay MAC, 
 South Placer Fire Protection District sub-committees, an 
 alternate to Placer County LAFCO and most recently he was 
 involved in planning the Granite Bay Community Park and 
 landscaping corridor along Douglas Blvd. In 2003, Ron was 
 honored by Placer County, for his dedicated volunteer 
 service to Granite Bay; receiving a community service 
 commemorative coin, presented by Supervisor Ted Gaines.

We will miss Ron&apos;s 
 logical, constructive input at the many committees and 
 meetings, which many of us served on with him. In addition, 
 as the original webmaster of GraniteBay.com (from 2003 
 through early 2007), his valued assistance, advice and 
 continuous contributions will also be greatly missed.


 1/7/08 
 Concept Home in Granite Bay Ready For Public Tours 
 
Located in Granite Bay, come see the beautiful KCRA 3 2007 Concept Home. 
 Now complete, tours of this 4.5 million dollar, 7,875 square foot luxury 
 home are set to begin, starting Thursday, January 10th , with ticket proceeds 
 going to Easter Seals . For more information, go to KCRA 3 .


 1/7/08 
 Blood Drive At The Roseville Galleria 
 
BloodSource along with the Westfield Galleria at Roseville and KCRA 3 have
 joined forces as hosts of the KCRA 3 for Life Blood Drive . Take part in the two-day event on Saturday, January 12 and Sunday, 
 January 13 from 12PM to 6PM in Center Court near JCPenney . 
 There are no appointments necessary and child care will be available. For 
 more information, please call: 916.376.6017 .


 1/4/08 
 Dinner&amp;Auction to Benefit the Granite Bay High School Baseball Program 
 
The Granite Bay High School Baseball Boosters Association is holding their annual dinner and auction on Saturday, February 2, 2008 at the Granite Bay Golf Club . The dinner/auction is the major fundraiser for the 
 baseball program.


 
 2007 
 11/28/07 
 CHiPS For Kids Toy Drive 
 
 Now through 
 Friday, December 21st join KCRA 3 and the California Highway Patrol 
 in the 10th Annual CHiPS for Kids Toy Drive. The toys will be given to 
 hospitalized and disadvantaged children just in time for the holidays. 
 To participate bring a new, unwrapped toy to any participating school, 
 to any CHP location, the Elk Grove Automall, or to any other donation location. 
 Local drop off sites include, Ridgeview Elementary School at 9177 Twin Schools 
 Road, (916) 791-3477 . For a complete list of drop-off points and more information 
 about the 10th Annual CHiPS for Kids Toy Drive go to kcra.com .


 11/17/07 
 SEWER-INFRASTRUCTURE FINANCING PLAN: MAC Looking for Someone to Serve on Ad Hoc Group 
 
The Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council is looking for a community member to serve on an ad hoc committee that will help develop a strategic plan for financing sewer infrastructure 
improvements. No deadline has been set for receiving applications, but the seven-member MAC likely will appoint someone to 
fill the committee position at its Dec. 5th meeting. Applications should be submitted to Brian Jagger, Field Representative 
to 4th District Supervisor Kirk Uhler, at the Placer County Board of Supervisors’offices in Auburn. The mailing address is 175 Fulweiler Ave., Auburn, CA 95603 . Applications also can be faxed to 916-787-8959 . For more information, please clck here .

 11/14/07 
 Granite Bay Helps in Coats For Kids Drive 
 
Taking place now through
 Friday, December 21st , help News10, Swansons Cleaners, Gottschalks, and the Salvation 
 Army reach this year’s goal of collecting 30,000 coats for the 17th Annual Coats For Kids Drive. 
 To do your part, you can donate new or gently used coats of all sizes, make a monetary donation or 
 volunteer your time. Local drop-off sites include: Swansons Cleaners: 8711 Sierra College Blvd #5
 Granite Bay High School :#1 Grizzly Way
 Curves :8753 Auburn-Folsom Rd. For a complete list of drop-off sites and more information about the 17th Annual 
 Coats For Kids Drive go to News10.net .


 10/4/07 
 MAC Suggests Compromise on Sign Proposal 
 
The MAC rejected a proposal for a 10ft high architecturally designed monument sign at 7095 Douglas Blvd. Instead, the MAC recommended approval of the design but limited the height to a maximum of 8ft to maintain consistency within the community.


 10/4/07 
 MAC Reaches Decision on Granite Bay Retail&amp;Carwash 
 
By a 6-1 vote, MAC recommended approval of a proposal to amend the Community Plan and change the zoning on a parcel on the South side of Douglas Boulevard, across from Bushnell&apos;s Nursery, to permit a carwash and retail center. The Project includes construction of three retail buildings and an automatic carwash on approximately two acres.


 10/4/07 
 Pedestrian Path to be Constructed on Auburn Folsom Road 
 
The Dept of Public Works will construct a decomposed granite pedestrian path on Auburn Folsom Road between Douglas Blvd and Joe Rodgers Road. The path will be on both sides of the road and meander around trees and other existing features. Construction will begin on the west side of the road soon and is expected to be completed by November. Construction on the east side will occur in the spring.


 8/22/07 
 The 3rd Annual JDRF Texas Hold&apos;Em Charity Tournament to be Held Soon 
 
On Friday, 
 September 21, 2007 at 5:00 PM the 3rd Annual JDRF Texas 
 Hold&apos;Em Charity Tournament will take place at the Roseville Health 
 and Wellness Center at 1650 Lead Hill Blvd. With a tournament fee 
 of $150, this night of fun will also help to raise money for the 
 Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation, which strives to find a cure 
 for diabetes. The no limit tournament will be limited to the first 
 eighty players, so reserve your spot by September 14th , by 
 sending the $100 charitable donation for JDRF to: Warren Chiropractic
1650 Lead Hill Blvd #600
Roseville, CA 95661 (The additional $50 of the tournament fee will 
 be placed in a prize pool.)  For more information about this event, 
 please call Scott Warren at ( 916) 947-4325 .


 8/6/07 
 &quot;24th Annual National Night Out&quot; 
 
From 6 PM to 10 PM on Tuesday, August 7th neighborhoods throughout Placer County are invited to spend the evening outside with neighbors as well as members of the sheriff&apos;s department during the &quot;24th Annual National Night Out&quot; crime and drug prevention event. For more information on this event, please contact Dena Evangelista-Taylor, PC Sheriff&apos;s Department at (916) 791-5159 .


 7/19/07 
 Granite Bay Ranks In Money&apos;s Top 100 Places To Live 
 
According to Money magazine’s annual list of the Top 100 Places to Live, Granite Bay ranks #74. The ranking is based on data compiled from a variety of different categories, including: median family income, home prices, students’ test scores, commute time, crime statistics and divorce rate. Granite Bay’s location, bordering Folsom Lake , being two hours from San Francisco and 90 minutes away from Lake Tahoe doesn’t hurt either. To see a complete list of the Top 100 Places to Live for 2007, go to http://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/bplive/2007/ .


 6/21/07 
 Feist Park Tennis Courts Completed 
 
On Friday, June 15th , a grand opening ceremony welcomed the addition of six brand-new tennis courts to Granite Bay&apos;s Ronald L. 
 Feist Park . Located at 9180 Twin Schools Road between the high school and Oakhills and Ridgeview elementary schools, the 
 park’s courts will now be available to the tennis programs at Granite Bay High School as well as to the general public.


 6/16/07 
 San Juan Water District Announces Annual Student Science Fair Project and Poster Contest Winners 
 
Both contests, which were held in concurrence with Water Awareness Month, focused on water issues, and helped educate students about how various conditions and elements affect water resources. The science fair, held at Cavitt Junior High School, gave students the opportunity to work with a partner, which resulted in more sophisticated and complex projects. Of those projects, the winners are: First Place: Kevin Ranger, Will Hubbard
Second Place: Katie Zingheim, Shannon Wagner
Third Place: Micaela Saqui, Emma Slattery
Runners-up: Dana Crouch, Allyssa Anthony, Kirsten O’Guinn, Katelin Giglia The Water Awareness Poster Contest is a joint effort of the San Juan, Fair Oaks and Citrus Heights water districts and the Orange Vale Water Company and had 212 posters submitted. This year students were asked to visually express their thoughts and ideas about how to have fun conserving water. While each agency selected three winning posters to be featured in a 2008 water awareness calendar, this year’s top winners for San Juan Water District are: First Place: Molly Graves from Mrs. Yeo’s fourth grade
 class at Eureka Elementary School
Second Place: Shahana Abbasi from Mrs. Ferraro’s sixth 
 grade class at Eureka Elementary School
Third Place: Megan Dunlop from Mr. Martin’s fifth grade 
 class at Ridgeview Elementary School 


 6/11/07 
 Fire Destroys Summer Sanders’Childhood Home 
 
Saturday evening, while the two-time Olympic gold-medalist and her father were attending events at the Summer Sanders Aquatic Complex, a two-alarm fire destroyed her childhood home. The home, located on Granite Bay&apos;s Carolinda Drive, is said to be a complete loss; luckily however, no one was injured. The cause of the fire is still unknown.


 6/7/07 
 Concerns over Plans for Folsom Lake 
 
In a Position Paper, which can be found at http://www.freewebs.com/granitebaysos/POSITION%20PAPER.pdf , the Granite Bay/Mooney Ridge homeowners, facility users and environmental stakeholders of the adversely impacted Folsom Lake area convey their concerns regarding certain west shore elements of the Folsom Dam Safety and Folsom Damage Reduction project. As the document states, the group is specifically concerned about &quot;the borrow (mining, dredging and blasting) of materials from the wildlife habitat and recreational corridors north of Beal’s Point, adjacent to the populated Mooney Ridge area, the development and use of staging areas and construction of in-reservoir roads and haul routes in the same areas and viewshed, destruction/modification of the recently constructed security features at the north end of Dike 4, and the construction of a concrete floodwall on Dike 4 in lieu of raising Dike 4 with stabilized soil material similar to that currently employed in Dike 4. In their conclusion the group states: &quot;It is our desire that the Partner Agencies agree to remove the supplemental borrow site, staging and haul road contingency affecting the in-reservoir area below Mooney Ridge, in the same way the Folsom Point sites were deleted, and commit, in writing, to the acquisition of commercially quarried materials for any supplemental necessitated use. We also wish the Agencies to specifically delineate the plans for and necessity of destruction of the recently constructed bollard safety features at the north end of Dike 4 as well as the planned replacement safety feature.&quot; They also ask that others join them, by signing their petition. To learn more, go to: http://www.freewebs.com/granitebaysos/ 


 6/1/07 
 San Juan Water District to Conduct Water Supply Testing 
 
This summer the San Juan Water District along with the other agencies in the San Juan Family of Water Agencies will conduct several tests on their water systems, evaluating how well prepared they are for a water shortage or emergency. See the news release for more information. Please feel free to contact Shauna Lorance with any questions regarding the water supply testing.


 5/22/07 
 Park Grand Opening 
 
The Grand Opening Ceremony for the new tennis courts at Ronald L. Feist Park has been set for Friday, June 15, 2007 at the courts at 10:00 AM. 


 5/21/07 
 EU-SEPAC’s Electronics Recycling Fundraising Event 
 
On Saturday, June 9th from 8:00 a.m. – 2:00 p.m. at Oakhills School , the Eureka Union Special Education Parent Advisory Committee is holding its first organized fundraising event to benefit all special needs students in the District. All used/obsolete electronics can be recycled, including: televisions, computer monitors, laptop computers, computer towers, cell phones, batteries, calculators, copy machines (small desk top only), cameras, radios, stereo systems and recorders. For more details see the flyer .


 5/17/07 
 New Fire District Director Appointed 
 
The Directors of the South Placer Fire District have appointed Granite Bay resident Craig Powell to the Board of Directors. Powell will serve the remainder of the term of Ron Feist after Feist resigned when he moved from the District. .


 5/3/07 
 Supervisors Authorize Bids for Road Improvements 
 
Supervisors approved the plans and specifications for construction of the South Phase of Auburn Folsom Road Widening, allowing the Department of Public Works to advertise for bids. The estimated construction cost is $8,300,000. Additionally, they approved the plans and specifications for the replacement of Barton Road Bridge at Miners Ravine, allowing the Department of Public Works to advertise for bids, pending right-of-way certification. The estimated construction cost is $1,800,000.


 4/30/07 
 South Placer Fire Station Ground Breaking Ceremony 
 
This Tuesday, May 1, 2007 , the public is invited to the ground breaking ceremony of South Placer&apos;s new fire station. Located at 5300 Olive Ranch RD. , the ceremony will begin at 10:00 AM . 
For more information, please call, (916) 791-7059 .


 4/30/07 
 County Proposes Sewer Fee Increase 
 
The Dept. of Facility Services is 
proposing a 9% fee increase for Sewer Maintenance District 2 which serves most of Granite Bay. 
The increase will raise the fee from 44.15 per month to 48.12 per month to cover increased costs. 
The increase would be effective July 1, 2007 and would be maintained at that level for two years. 
The Board of Supervisors will meet to hear the proposal on 22nd of May .


 4/30/07 
 Granite Bay MAC Secretary Vacancy 
 
Information will be presented at 
the meeting regarding the process for applying for this position. Address inquiries to Brian Jagger , Field Representative , at 800-4888-4308, Ext. 4010 .


 4/12/07 
 MAC Takes No Action on Controversial Project 
 
Action on a proposed subdivision at
the corner of Douglas Blvd and Pardee Ct. (east of Bank of America) consisting of 35 townhouses 
and a new retail building was tabled after it became clear that the MAC was not ready to support 
the project in its current form. The MAC and residents alike expressed concern about the projects 
layout of the commercial building, inadequate parking, excessive density and traffic impacts. The 
proponent asked for some time to reassess the project and to bring the project back to the MAC next 
month.


 4/12/07 
 MAC Recommends Approval of Two Projects 
 
The MAC, on Wednesday evening recommended 
approval of a new fire station to be located at 5300 Olive Ranch Rd. at Olive Ranch Ct. Additionally, 
they recommended approval of a 4 unit residential project at the northwest corner of Barton Rd. and East 
Roseville Parkway. The project will help preserve the 300 foot setback on Douglas Blvd. by transferring the 
density from a parcel on Douglas to the project site and converting the Douglas Blvd. site to open space.


 4/9/07 
 Friends of Granite Bay Library Tea 
 
 The Friends will host this popular 
annual fundraiser on May 3rd at the Granite Bay Golf Club . Starting at 10:30 a.m. , the theme
this year is &quot;purses&quot;. There will be a fashion show and vendors. The cost is $60 per person . 
For more information contact Madelaine Kiliany at 791-1217 .


 4/9/07 
 Barton Road Bridge Replacement 
 
The project over Minor&apos;s Ravine 
will go to bid in April with construction to start in May or June. Tree removal in the 
right of way has already begun.


 3/22/07 
 Fire District Director Resigns 
 
The South Placer Fire District Board has accepted the resignation of Director Ron Feist and declared a vacancy on the Board of Directors. Applicants interested in being appointed to the position should submit a letter of interest before 5:00 p.m. on April 30, 2007 to: Debbie Frick C/O Board of Director Applicant, South Placer Fire District, 6900 Eureka Road, Granite Bay, 
CA 95746 . Applicants must live within the boundaries of the South Placer Fire District. For more information regarding the position, phone (916) 791-7059 .


 3/21/07 
 Meetings to be Held on Folsom Dam and Reservoir 
 
Interested 
 community members are invited to attend two meetings, April 4th and 5th . Sponsored by the Bureau of Reclamation , the U.S. Army 
 Corps of Engineers (USACE) along with the Sacramento Area Flood Control Agency , and the California Department of Water 
 Resources/Reclamation Board , these informational meetings which will call particular attention to local interests, serve to both
 increase the community’s awareness about the construction projects (flood control, dam safety as well as others) that are planned or 
 underway at Folsom Dam over the next 10-15 years, and allow the community to voice their thoughts and suggestions about these projects.

The meetings will 
 be held at the following locations to focus on construction activities planned for the‘Folsom side’or the‘Granite Bay side’of the reservoir: Wednesday, April 4, 2007 
6:30-9:00 p.m.
Folsom Rotary Clubhouse
7150 Baldwin Dam Road, Folsom, CA Thursday, April 5, 2007 
6:30-9:00 p.m.
Cavitt Junior High School
7200 Fuller Drive, Granite Bay, CA 
For more information visit the Bureau of Reclamation&apos;s Homepage .


 3/21/07 
 Eureka Schools Foundation Presents: Spring Home Tour 
 
With the proceeds going towards the Eureka Union School District and its students, this April, the Granite Bay Home Tour showcases five beautiful Granite Bay homes as well as an outdoor garden café and home boutique/marketplace. For more information about this event and to purchase tickets, visit: www.tourgranitebayhomes.com .


 2/25/07 
 New Web Site for Fourth Supervisorial District 
 
County Supervisor Uhler has launched a new website ( www.placer.ca.gov/Home/bos/District4.aspx ) that
 is intended to help the public stay up to date on Placer County&apos;s 4th District
 news. It will provide agendas and minutes of the Granite Bay MAC
 meetings, and will provide a means to contact the supervisor
 to ask questions or to share an opinion on 4th District issues.


 2/23/07 
 Fire District Approves Capital Facilities Plan 
 
The 2007 Capital Facilities Plan has been approved by the Directors of the South Placer Fire District . The $5.1 million plan outlines 4 major projects: 1. Building a new station on Olive Ranch Rd. to replace the old station on Douglas Blvd. ($1,750,000)
2. Up-grading traffic signals at key intersections in the community with preemption devices. ($20,000)
3. Providing permanent administrative office space with training classrooms and meeting rooms ($3,085,273)
4. Assist Placer County with the costs of communications infrastructure improvements. ($258,971) 


 2/22/07 
 Contract
 for New Fire Station Awarded 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District Board of Directors awarded a contract for
 $2.3 million to D. G. Grande Inc. of Shingle Springs to construct a
 new fire station at the corner of Olive Ranch Rd. and Olive Grove
 Dr. Ground breaking is expected by the 1st of Apr. for the new
 station that will replace the old existing station on Douglas Blvd.


 1/6/07 
 Placer County Conservation Plan
 Being Debated 
 
The 
 Lincoln Club of Placer County is announcing the debut of its Debate Series. Its premier debate will feature the foremost local 
 experts on the Placer County Conservation Plan (PCCP) on Thursday, January 18, at the Granite Bay Golf Club. Continental breakfast 
 begins at 7:00 a.m. and the Debate begins promptly at 7:30 a.m. Cost is $15.00 per person. Guest Speakers in support of the plan are 
 Robert Weygandt, Placer County Supervisor and other experts. Mrs. Brigit S. Barnes, Esq., Brigit S. Barnes&amp;Associates, Inc. and other 
 experts will oppose the plan. Dennis C. Revell will be the moderator. For more information contact Dennis C. Revell, Revell Communications, 
 (916) 443-3816, DCR@RevellComnmnuications.com. ....more 


 1/4/07 
 Granite Bay Recreation Association Under Development 
 
Six
 new tennis courts are due to be completed at Feist Park by spring. The
 courts will be available for use by the community, and will provide
 a home for the High School tennis teams and for the PE program. You
 can be a part of this great addition to the park by donating
 now.  .....more 


 1/4/07 
 Approval Recommended for New Subdivision 
 
The MAC unanimously recommended approval of a proposed subdivision, &quot;Micherra Place&quot;, comprising 20 single family one story homes at 
 the southwest corner of Auburn-Folsom Rd. and Eureka Rd. just east of the fire station. Homes are planned to be from 1400 to 2000 sq. 
 ft. on lots ranging in size from about 4500 to 6500 sq. ft.


 
 2006 
 12/22/06 
 Hearing
 Scheduled for Folsom Dam Environmental Report 
 
public hearing is scheduled for Wednesday, Jan 10, 2007 from 7 to 9
 pm at the Folsom Community Center to review the Environmental
 Reports for the flood damage reduction features of the proposed
 project to modify and raise Folsom Dam. The public will have an
 opportunity to ask questions, review displays and provide written/or
 oral comments on the Draft EIS/EIR. For further information contact
 Becky Victorine at 916-557-5162 .


 12/19/06 
 Supervisors
 Select Uhler to Represent the 4th District 
 
Placer
 County Supervisors appointed Kirk Uhler to fill the seat left vacant
 when Ted Gaines was elected to the State Assembly. He will
 serve as the representative of the 4th District of Placer County for
 the remaining two years of Gaines&apos; term. Uhler was selected
 unanimously on the third ballot from a field of 5 applicants.   Kirk
 previously represented the 4 th District on the Board of
 Supervisors from 1993-96.

 12/1/06 
 Fifth
 Annual Home Tour Scheduled 
 
Junior Achievement is presenting its fifth annual home tour in Granite Bay and Loomis from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m. Dec. 9 . The tour includes seven homes in Clos du Lac, Los Lagos, Folsom Lake Estates and Douglas Ranch, plus the Flower Farm Inn bed-and-breakfast in Loomis. Wine tasting, refreshments and gifts will be available. Tickets are $25 in advance and $35 on tour day . Visit www.jasac.org to purchase tickets online until noon Dec. 8. Tickets will be
 available the day of the tour at 6957 Eureka Road, Granite Bay.


 11/30/06 
 County Plans to Widen I-80 at Roseville 
 
County
 officials have announced plans to widen Interstate 80 from the
 County line to highway 65. The $210 million project will be done in
 stages. Work on the first phase from the County line to Douglas Blvd
 will begin in the spring.


 11/29/06 
 Seat Open for 4th District Supervisor 
 
Placer
 County is seeking applicants to replace Ted Gaines as the Supervisor
 for the 4th District. Gaines was elected to the State Assembly Nov 7
 and will leave his supervisorial position Dec 1. The Board of
 Supervisors plans to fill the vacated position Dec 19. Applications
 may be obtained by calling 530-889-4010 and will be accepted at the
 Boards office until 5 pm Dec 8.


 11/28/06 
 Sidewalks
 and Landscaping for Douglas Blvd Approved 
 
Placer
 County Facility Services officials have announced a Federal grant of
 nearly $1 million will provide Placer County with the resources
 needed to complete sidewalks and landscape on the north side of
 Douglas Blvd. from Auburn Folsom Rd. to Sierra College Blvd. When
 Douglas was widened to 4 lanes several years ago, money was not
 available for sidewalks and landscape on several areas along the
 north side of the road.


 11/16/06 
 Fire
 Board Boosts Ambulance Rate 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District Board of Directors has increased the
 basic rate for being transported in a SPFD ambulance from $580 to
 $1014. The ambulance service is supposed to be funded by user fees
 rather being subsidized by the property tax. With the projected
 annual cost of operating the ambulance service approaching $1
 million, the increase was needed to help reduce the projected need
 for $390,000 in taxpayer subsidy. 


 10/31/06 
 Sheriff&apos;s
 Department Offers Sex Offender Alerts 
 
The
 Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Department has a new Web site that provides
 residents information on where registered sex offenders live. By
 clicking &quot;Offender
 Watch&quot; , people can see where
 sex offenders live within a one-mile radius of the address entered.
 The site offers residents the option of signing up for an e-mail
 alert when registered sex offenders move into their neighborhood.


 10/20/06 
 Fire District Mulls Ambulance Rate Increase 
 
The Board of Directors
 of the South Placer Fire District directed staff to review the cost
 of providing ambulance service in the District and recommend an
 appropriate fee adjustment. Initial analysis presented to the Board
 indicated the district&apos;s fees for ambulance service are far below
 fees in adjacent communities. As a result, South Placer taxpayers
 subsidized the ambulance service by over $220,000 in 2005. The
 cost of operating the ambulances is not intended to be funded by
 property taxes, but rather to be paid for by fees charged to the
 service user. 


 9/21/06 
 Fire
 District Approves 9.4 Million Budget 
 
The South Placer Fire District Board of Directors approved a 9.375 million budget at last nights Board meeting. Total revenue is projected to rise by 9% while spending is projected to increase by 9.2%. Additionally, over $2 million is budgeted for facility expenditures, including the remodel of the Eureka Road Station and construction of a new station on Olive Ranch Rd.


 9/21/06 
 Fire
 District Board Appoints Interim Director 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District Board of Directors appointed Granite Bay
 resident Kathryn Matthews to fill the seat vacated by the
 resignation of Dave Giblin. Matthews will serve the remaining
 2 years of Giblin&apos;s term.


 9/11/06 
 Ralston
 Fire Creates Health Hazard 
 
The
 Ralston Fire burning in the Tahoe National Forest continues to
 create very smoky conditions in the valley and the foothills,
 prompting officials to continue a health advisory through 9/13.
 People (especially children and elderly) are urged to avoid physical
 exertion during the smoky conditions. Weather experts are
 predicting very cool and windy conditions beginning Thursday that
 will clear the smoke from the valley.


 9/2/06 
 Water
 District Proposes Rate Hikes 
 
The
 San Juan Water District Board will conduct a public hearing and consider action on
 a proposed rate increase for 2007 on October 11 at 7 p.m. at the district’s office, 9935 Auburn -Folsom Road.
 For an average residential water user the new rate would result in an increase of $6.50 per month in 2007, and another similar increase in 2008. During following years, smaller rate increases would apply.
 For more information, call 791-0115.


 8/17/06 
 Local
 Teen Credited for Life Saving Effort 
 
Fire
 Marshall, Lawrence Bettencourt
 presented the South Placer Fire Districts&quot;Community
 Citizens Safety Award&quot;to Jo-Jo Campisi at the Board
 meeting 8/16/06. The award was to recognize the effort
 extended by the Granite Bay teen in saving the life of her
 neighbor during a family outing at Lake Tahoe in July. Jo-Jo said she swam to
 the man and grabbed onto the sleeve of the T-shirt he was wearing while she called to the shore for help. 


 8/14/06 
 Fire
 District Board Election Averted 
 
Filing
 for election for two seats on the South Placer Fire District Board
 of Directors closed Friday 8/11. Incumbent
 Ron Feist and appointed incumbent Mike DeLaurentis were the only
 persons that filed for the two positions. As a result of only two
 candidates filing for two seats, there will not be a need for an
 election and the two that filed will be seated on the Board. 


 8/12/06 
 Man
 Arrested in Boat Parts Thefts 
 
Placer County Sheriff&apos;s detectives have arrested a 21 year old Loomis man on suspicion of stealing parts from dozens of boats in the Loomis and Granite Bay area over the last couple years. Reportedly, the suspect may have been responsible for $15,000 in stolen property that he was selling on the internet.


 8/3/06 
 MAC
 Supports Three Proposals Wednesday Night 
 
Even
 though there was not a quorum, the MAC listened and provided comment
 on three development proposals Wednesday evening. There was general consensus
 from the three MAC members present and the public alike to support: 
1. The proposal for a 12 lot, planned development sub-division with 4
 acres of open space on the north side of Olive
 Ranch Rd. about 3/4 mile east of Cavitt Stallman across from Cobble
 Ct. The developer had revised his project, in response to prior MAC
 and public comments, to eliminate any requirement for a Community
 Plan amendment or variance.

2. The proposal to transfer 3 units of residential density from the south
 side of Douglas Blvd, about 1/4 mile west of Barton Rd., to the northwest corner of Roseville Parkway
 and Barton Rd. The transfer would further implement the Community
 Plan goal of preserving the south side of Douglas Blvd. in its
 natural state by creating another open space lot on the south side
 of Douglas.

3. The proposal for a full service car wash behind Walgreen&apos;s on Douglas Blvd. The project had been revised, in response to previous MAC comments, to eliminate the oil change facilities and add significant landscaping.
 


 7/28/06 
 Vacancy on Fire District Board of Directors 
 
The South Placer Fire District has a vacancy on the Board of Directors. Interested applicants should submit a letter of interest before 5:00 p.m. September 1, 2006 to: Debbie Frick C/O Board of Director Applicant, South Placer Fire District, 6900 Eureka Road, Granite Bay, CA 95746.

Applicants must live within the boundaries of the South Placer Fire District. For more information regarding the position phone (916) 791-7059.


 7/13/06 
 Granite
 Bay Blue Print Sub Committee Established 
 
The
 MAC, after reviewing SACOG&apos;s Blueprint and in response to public
 input, has created a sub-committee to look at what our community
 should look like in 50 years. The Committee originally scheduled its
 first meeting at the Eureka School District Office 2 Aug, at 5 pm.
 However, that meeting has been changed to 6 Sep at 5 pm. Residents interested in participating are welcome to attend.


 7/13/06 
 MAC
 Rejects Two Proposals 
 
Plans
 for developing four office buildings on two parcels at the north
 west corner of Douglas Blvd. and Berg St. were rebuffed by the MAC
 and the public alike at last nights meeting. There were concerns
 about the need to change the Community Plan to accommodate spot
 zoning for the benefit of the developer while creating significant
 impacts on the community.

Additionally,
 a proposal for a monument sign at the corner of Auburn Folsom and
 Douglas to advertise a proposed new bank at the site of the present
 SAFE Credit Union was also rejected. Comments included the fact that
 granting the sign would be a special privilege to one business while
 others have been denied additional signs.


 6/28/06 
 Signal
 at Auburn-Folsom and Fuller Being Installed 
 
Placer
 County has started installing a new traffic signal at the
 intersection of Auburn Folsom Rd and Fuller Dr. at a cost to the
 taxpayers of $245,000. The signal is expected to become operational
 about 17 July. This is the first phase of the improvements planned
 for Auburn Folsom Rd. in the next few years. Acquisition of right of
 way for the rest of the improvements is continuing and the County
 hopes to start construction of phase 2 in the summer of 2007.


 6/24/06 
 Home
 Invasion Suspects Arrested 
 
The two men
 suspected of forcing their way into a home on Swan Lake Drive in Granite Bay on May
 23 were arrested in Sacramento&apos;s Oak Park neighborhood by Placer County Sheriff&apos;s
 investigators Thursday night. 


 6/22/06 
 Future
 of Ambulance Service Threatened 
 
South
 Placer Fire District’s directors and community members alike
 expressed concern, at their meeting last night, over a multi-county
 Emergency Medical Services Agency attempting to force the district
 into signing a contract to help fund the agency whose purpose is to
 overview the quality of emergency medical services in a 5 county
 area. The possibility may exist, pending resolution of some legal
 issues, for the&quot;Agency&quot;to replace the present high
 quality emergency medical services provided by the Fire District
 with a private ambulance service if the District declines to sign
 the contract.

Residents voiced the opinion that our Fire District has been providing the best emergency medical services available since the 1950’s without overview by an outside agency. Why would we now want to pay anyone significant amounts of our tax dollars to police the service we have?


 6/22/06 
 Granite Bay (MAC)
 Meeting Date Changed 
 
The
 Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council has rescheduled their next
 meeting from July 5th to Wed.,
 July 12, 7:00 p.m. at the Eureka School District Office.


 6/15/06 
 Supervisor&apos;s
 Administrative Aide Resigns 
 
In a letter to the Community, Melanie Eustice, Administrative Aide to Supervisor Ted Gaines, announced that she has accepted a position in Southern California so she may be closer to her family. With Supervisor Gaines moving on to the State Assembly, she saw a window of opportunity to make a transition in her career. Her last day will be Friday, June 23.

Our best wishes go with her, she has served this community exceptionally well. Thank you Melanie!


 6/9/06 
 Law
 Enforcement Seeks Your Help 
 
Police are appealing for the public&apos;s help in identifying suspects who have been linked to at least four home-invasion robberies last month in Sacramento and Placer counties.
 Police think the same suspects were involved in crimes in Folsom, Elk Grove, Granite Bay and Citrus Heights.
 If you have any information regarding these suspects please contact
 the Placer County Sheriff&apos;s office.


 6/8/06 
 Community
 Miffed by Proliferation of Illegal Signs 
 
Real
 estate signs and large temporary signs and banners at businesses and
 churches along Douglas Blvd. were the center of the community&apos;s
 concern as the representative of the County Code Enforcement Dept.
 explained the process of dealing with illegal signs at last nights
 MAC meeting. The MAC asked the County to make a sweep of the
 community quarterly to rid the community of the illegal signs. You
 can help by reporting illegal signs to the County Code Enforcement
 office at 800-488-4308 ext. 3050.


 6/8/06 
 MAC
 Supports Addition of Wiki-Wiki Juice&amp;Coffee Bar 
 
The
 addition of a small drive thru juice&amp;coffee bar within the Granite Bay
 Village Shopping Center was recommended for approval by the MAC
 at last nights meeting. Questions were raised over the probability
 of the improvement becoming another fast food restaurant but the
 proponent assured the community the building would not have a
 commercial kitchen and the size of the building (1500 sq.ft.) would
 not support a typical fast food restaurant.


 6/8/06 
 Sewer
 Fee Proposal Receives Cool Reception 
 
A
 proposed 9% sewer fee increase for SMD#2 was not received warmly by
 the community or several members of the MAC. The Sewer District is
 proposing to increase the rates from $40 per month to $44.15 per
 month, with the suggestion that rates will continue to increase in
 future years due to increasing cost to maintain the system and
 process the waste. By contrast, Roseville City residents pay only
 $20 per month while So. Placer MUD residents pay $48 per month.


 6/5/06 
 Wednesday
 Night MAC Meeting Agenda 
 
 June 7, 7:00 pm Eureka School District Office, 5455 Eureka Rd 

-Sewer Fee Increase for Sewer Maintenance District Number 2.
-Wiki Wiki Juice&amp;Coffee – within the Granite Bay Shopping Center
-Olive Ranch Subdivision – 12 single-family units on Olive Ranch Rd.
-Overview of sign ordinance
-Overview of zoning and allowed uses at Auburn Folsom and Eureka


 6/1/06 
 Farmers
 Market is Back 
 
The Granite Bay Certified Farmers’ Market
 is again operating on Thursdays from 9 a.m. to 1 p.m. at Granite Bay Village Shopping Center, located at the southeast corner of Auburn-Folsom Road and Douglas Boulevard. The market features farm-fresh fruits and vegetables, organic free-range eggs, local wines, hardy locally grown nursery stock, artisan baked goods,
 grass fed meats, East Indian foods and kettle corn.


 5/31/06 
 Recall
 Effort Launched Against Sierra College Trustees 
 
Several
 former county supervisors and mayors in Placer County are among the
 group that has launched a recall effort against Sierra College trustees Jerry Simmons and Aaron
 Klein. The pair are accused of wasting taxpayers money, damaging the institution&apos;s reputation and demoralized its employees.

Former county Supervisor Rex Bloomfield, one of 10 people who signed the recall petition, said the trustees are &quot;a malignant cancer that must be removed to preserve the health of Sierra College.&quot; Klein and Simmons called the effort a political trick designed to hurt Simmons&apos; effort to unseat a fellow Republican, incumbent Placer County Supervisor Robert Weygandt.


 5/26/06 
 Alert
 From the County Assessor 
 
In recent days, home owners have been receiving advertisements from Property Tax Assessor Records Corp. offering, for a fee, to provide property owners with a completed homeowner&apos;s exemption claim form to file with the Assessor.

Assessor Bruce Dear would like to alert the public to the fact that this private company is not affiliated with the Assessor in any way, nor is there any requirement that their services be used in order to file a Homeowners&apos; Exemption claim. The Assessor&apos;s Office does not charge for filing the Homeowner&apos;s Exemption claim form. Any property owner may file a claim directly with the Assessor at no charge and without using the service offered by this business.


 5/25/06 
 Gunmen Invade Home in Treelake Area 
 
TTwo men wearing masks and sunglasses used a gun to force their way into a home on Swan Lake Dr. Wednesday afternoon. Two boys in the home were tied up while the robbers ransacked the home and stole cash and computer equipment.

One of the suspects was described as heavy-set, 180 to 200 pounds. He wore dark hair pulled back into a bushy ponytail. The second man was described as 18 to 21 years old, 140 to 155 pounds. He had light-colored hair in a short military-style cut. He may go by the name of Josh. Anyone with information is asked to contact Sgt. Dennis Walsh at (530) 889-7852.


 5/7/06 
 CDF
 Warns Homeowners About Fire Season 
 
Fire season is on the horizon and homeowners in Placer County are getting an important message about clearing the area around their homes or facing the consequences. Authorities from the California Department of Forestry and Fire Protection indicate there is a lot of vegetation that is beginning to dry out.

A new law passed in 2005 requires homeowners to have at least 100 feet of defensible space around their homes with the 30 feet closest to the house consisting of a heavily watered greenbelt such as grass. In the remaining 70 feet, everything should be spaced out and all the trees should be trimmed up so that the grass on the ground can&apos;t send flame to the tops of the trees.

 5/7/06 
 Granite
 Bay Celebrates Opening of it&apos;s Newest Park 
 
It
 all began with the donation of 18 acres of land at the corner
 of Ellington Dr. and Twin Schools Rd., from Bob Coker and the Coker Ewing
 Co. to the Eureka Union School District. That was
 followed by donations of over a million dollars in cash,
 services and materials from the community. Saturday, seven
 years ahead of the original schedule, the new Placer County
 park named in honor of Dr. Ronald Feist was officially
 dedicated.

The park, features baseball, soccer, and football fields, a tot lot and a picnic pavilion. Six tennis courts a basketball court and barbeques will be added this summer.


 5/5/06 
 Business Networking Group Formed 
 
A
 new professional business networking group has formed in Granite
 Bay. &quot;LeTip&quot;is a professional organization of men and women dedicated to the highest standards of competence and
 service. It&apos;s primary purpose is to give and receive qualified business tips or leads.
 The organization meets every Thursday from 11:31 am until 1:01 pm at Mark&amp;Monica&apos;s and is actively recruiting new members. For more
 information see LeTip.com 


 5/4/06 
 Residents Complain About Signs in the Community 
 
During
 public comment at the MAC meeting Wednesday night, several residents
 and MAC members alike blasted the County for not controlling the
 proliferation of real estate and other illegal signs being displayed
 in increasing numbers throughout the community. As a result, the MAC
 has asked the County to have a Code Enforcement representative
 attend the next MAC meeting to discuss the issue.


 5/4/06 
 MAC Recommends Approval of Two Projects 
 
The
 MAC recommended approval of two new residential projects Wednesday
 evening. One project, located on a 17.5 acre parcel just east of the
 fire station on Douglas Blvd., proposes 7 single family lots and
 about 8 acre of open space including preservation of the 300 ft.
 open space corridor on the south side of Douglas. The other project
 also proposes 7 lots on the north side of Old Auburn Rd, west of
 Sierra College Blvd. 

Another
 development proposal was presented that would create 20 small lots
 at the corner of Auburn Folsom Rd. and Eureka Rd. just east of the
 fire station on Eureka. The project is designed to provide homes
 from 1400 to 2000 sq. ft.. Comments from the MAC and the public
 alike were very supportive of the concept. No action was taken on
 the proposal.


 4/26/06 
 Granite
 Bay Resident Helps Subdue United Passenger 
 
Jeffrey Powers,
 of Granite Bay and fellow passenger Sidney Pinney, on United flight
 735 from Chicago to Sacramento, subdued a man who had swung at a flight
 attendant and grabbed and yanked on the exit door handle. Powers put
 the man in a headlock, and Pinney grabbed his arms. The 36 year old
 man, from Diamond Springs in El Dorado County, was taken down by the
 two men and subsequently turned over to secret service agents on the
 flight that was diverted to Denver.


 4/18/06 
 Community Effort Needed to Reduced
 West Nile Virus 
 
With warm weather on the horizon, its time for residents to make routine inspections of their property for standing water where mosquitoes might breed. As temperatures rise, mosquitoes can develop in seven to ten days. Residents can play a huge role in reducing their risk of West Nile virus by simply removing standing water. The Placer Mosquito Abatement District recommends the inspection of the following for standing water: ▪ clogged rain gutters ▪ wheelbarrows ▪ boats ▪ flower pots
▪ buckets ▪ bird baths ▪ animal watering troughs ▪ pools/spas
▪ recycling bins ▪ or any container that might hold water. 


 4/13/06 
 CHP
 Launches Neighborhood Traffic Watch 
 
A
 program called Neighborhood Traffic Watch was launched by the CHP in the
 Treelake Village neighborhood of Granite Bay Thursday. The program, provides residents a means of reporting reckless driving in their neighborhood
 by calling the CHP office, or by logging onto www.lesleyscrusade.org . 

The
 program will enable officers to go directly to the home of the owner of a reported vehicle and talk to them.
 Officials said that by using the Web site, parents and others can check to see if
 their vehicle has been reported as being driven recklessly.


 4/3/06 
 Placer County
 Officials Caution Residents 
 
The National Weather Service has issued an Urban and Small stream flood advisory for Placer County
 and officials are cautioning residents living near flood prone creeks and streams
 to be very cautious and monitor weather reports and news. While there have not been any reports of flooding in
 the County, as a precaution, county officials set up several location where Placer County residents can get and fill sand bags.
 In Granite Bay, sandbags are available at the South Placer Fire
 Station, 6900 Eureka Road.


 4/3/06 
 Water District Receives Award for Water Efficiency 
 
San Juan Water District
 has been recognized by the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation for its innovative water-saving efforts. The district received the 2005 Regional Director’s Award, an honor bestowed on just one water provider in
 California, Nevada, and parts of Oregon, Utah and Arizona. 

The award recognizes San Juan’s many efforts to increase water efficiency, including various services for customers such as leak detection, landscape water audits, water meter-reading assistance, and distribution of low-flow shower heads, toilet tummies and kitchen and bathroom faucet aerators.


 3/30/06 
 MAC Plans to Review Two Projects 
 
The
 MAC is scheduled to review the details for two development proposals
 at their 7 pm, 5 April meeting at Eureka School. The first item is a
 12 lot sub-division proposed at 4977 Olive Ranch Rd., and the second
 item is a proposal to build a car wash and two retail buildings at
 the location across Douglas Blvd. from Bushnell&apos;s Nursery.


 3/20/06 
 Doolittle Admits
 Helping Co-Conspirators 
 
The &quot;San Diego Union Tribune&quot; reports that a week before former Rep. Randy Cunningham was sentenced to prison, he told the court that Rep. John Doolitle who represents Granite Bay and a number of other lawmakers, helped arrange federal funding for the defense contractors who bribed him. As a member of two key committees in the House, Doolittle, is positioned to help contractors gain funding through congressional earmarks. None of the lawmakers Cunningham mentioned have been accused of criminal wrong doing. But each has admitted assisting Mitchell Wade or Brent Wilkes, co-conspirators in the Cunningham case, at a time when the two were giving them tens of thousands of dollars in political contributions.


 3/8/06 
 FBI Investigating
 Suspicious Letter to Doolittle 
 
Hazmat crews from South Placer and Roseville Fire Departments responded to Rep. John Doolittle&apos;s Granite Bay
 office Wednesday afternoon when an employee in
 the office opened a letter, got some kind of substance on her hand
 and felt a tingling sensation. Fire crews evacuated the complex
 and the FBI and hazardous material crews are investigating
 the suspicious letter. 


 3/2/06 
 MAC
 Recommends Approval of New Bank 
 
The
 MAC recommended approval of a proposed new bank building, to be
 located on the east side of Sierra College Blvd, south of Douglas at
 the signalized entry to Granite Bay Business Park. The project will
 consist of a single story building housing a 3700 SF bank facility
 and a 2650 SF tenant, and it will include a drive thru window as
 well as associated site work. The MAC also recommended that a
 reasonable right of way for a left turn lane be dedicated on Sierra
 College Blvd. at that location.


 2/8/06 
 Warm
 Weather Restricting Permissive Burn Days 
 
The Placer County Air Pollution Control District reminds residents that residential burning is only allowed on permissive-burn days. Burn days are determined by the Air Resources Board and are based on meteorological conditions and forecasts. Burn days are declared when weather conditions readily disperse smoke. High-pressure systems that cause warmer weather act like a lid to hold smoke rather than allowing it to disperse. Burning on such days can cause smoke nuisances.

To find out whether burning is permitted on a particular day, residents may call 800-998-2876 . Burn-day information is updated by 8:00 a.m. daily.
 
 .


 2/6/06 
 Transportation Planning Workshops
 in Placer County  
 
Placer County&apos;s Transportation Planning Agency will hold several interactive workshops to provide you an opportunity to express what you feel is important in a transportation strategy and recommend where funds should be directed in Placer County regarding boulevards, bikeways, regional transit, streetcars, etc. Wed, Feb 8, 6-9pm, Rocklin Sunset Center, 2650 Sunset Blvd, Rocklin
Tue, Feb 21, 6-9pm, Maidu Center, 1550 Maidu Dr., Roseville
Tue, Feb 28, 6-9pm, Placer Transportation Planning Agency, 299 Nevada St. Auburn 


 2/2/06 
 MAC Opposes Appeal for
 a Reader Board Sign at Center 
 
The
 MAC voted unanimously to oppose a proposal from the owners of the
 Granite Bay Shopping Center to install a LED, changeable copy,
 animated, reader board sign at the center on Auburn Folsom Rd.
 Residents also voiced strong and unanimous disapproval of the
 proposal and expressed concern that this type of sign was not
 consistent with the Community Plan and not compatible with the rural
 nature of the Center.


 2/2/06 
 Developers Present MAC
 Two New Residential Projects 
 
The
 MAC received information on two new residential project proposals
 last evening. A project proposed at the north east corner of Old
 Auburn Rd. and Sierra College Blvd. would provide eight, one acre
 lots that are planned to be held as future home sites for the
 Dunmore family. A second proposal on Old Auburn Rd. west of
 Sierra College Blvd. would provide 7 single family one acre lots. No
 action was taken on either proposal.


 1/29/06 
 Neighborhood
 Traffic Sub Committee to Meet 
 
The
 MAC Neighborhood Traffic Management Sub Committee will hold their
 first meeting in the portable offices at the Fire Station on
 Eureka Rd. (at Folsom Auburn Rd.), on Wednesday 2/8/06 at 7pm. The public is welcome,
 especially those who have traffic management issues (speeding, stop sign running, etc) in their
 neighborhood. 


 1/24/06 
 “Slow
 Down- Don’t End Up Like This” 
 
The
 Newcastle California Highway Patrol unveiled a new enforcement
 tactic this morning at the curve on Barton Road north of
 Douglas Blvd. near Christina Court and Teague Lane. This area
 has been plagued with vehicles entering the well marked curve
 at speeds much higher than the posted advisory limit of 15 MPH
 and running off the roadway. With the assistance of County
 Roads Dept., and Roseville Towing, the CHP deployed a
 temporary visual display in an attempt to make people “think
 twice” before entering this stretch of roadway at an
 inappropriate speed.


 1/13/06 
 Scouts
 Hold&quot;Christmas In January&quot; 
 
Granite Bay&apos;s Boy Scout Troop 121 will hold their 3rd annual Eagle Scout Memorial Community Collection Drive and Blood Drive, on Sunday Jan. 29th from 10 AM to 2 PM at Cavitt Jr. High School at 7200 Fuller Dr.


 1/12/06 
 Granite
 Bay Resident Presented Community Safety Award 
 
Chief
 Corado of the South Placer Fire District presented Granite Bay
 resident Matt Ellinwood their&quot;Citizens Community Safety
 Award&quot;at their Dec. 15th meeting. Matt, an off duty
 paramedic for the Sac Metro Fire District, was being
 recognized for his unselfish actions when he assisted South Placer Fire crews at
 an emergency medical incident on Parkford Circle on October 26, 2005.


 1/6/06 
 County
 Needs Storm Damage Information Quickly 
 
Placer
 County Office of Emergency Services is asking property owners who
 suffered storm related damage from the series of storms over the New
 Years weekend to report their damages to the County. The information
 is needed by 10 Jan to meet Federal and State deadlines. If a
 Federal emergency is declared, property owners who sustained damages
 may be eligible for financial assistance through FEMA. Individual property owners should contact Emergency Services at
 530-889-4016.


 1/1/06 
 Lakeland&quot;Eyesore&quot;in Trouble 
 
The&quot;Sacramento Bee&quot;reports a home builder who angered his neighbors because
 the reconstruction project on his own home has lasted five years is about to lose his house.
 At least two lenders are foreclosing on the two-story home on Conquistador Court at the entrance of&quot;Lakeland&quot;because the owner is almost $32,000 behind on his payments.
 Several neighbors had contacted The Bee and the MAC last year to call attention to the house, which they described as &quot;an eyesore.&quot; 


 
 2005 
 12/31/05 
 Sand
 Bags Available 
 
Placer County crews and residents are facing a series of challenges resulting from the storms that have pounded the area. County crews have delivered sand and sand bags to the South Placer Fire Protection District, 6900 Eureka Road, Granite Bay; for Placer County residents if needed.

Streams are high and often overflowing the roads. Residents who live near streams should stay alert as waters may continue to rise. A number of roads have been closed. Motorists should avoid moving water. It&apos;s particularly important to keep children out of the storm water.


 12/30/05 
 First MAC of the New
 Year to Hear 2 Items 
 
Developers will present a revised design proposal for a 17.5-acre development located on the south side of Douglas Blvd, just east of Woodgrove Way. Additionally, A representative from the County will provide an overview on the current permitting process required for cell towers. The meeting is scheduled for 7:00 PM Wednesday, January 4, at the Eureka Union School District Office.

 12/22/05 
 Fire Directors
 Refuse to Support Sales Tax Proposal 
 
The
 League of Placer County Taxpayers has proposed a 1/8 cent sales tax
 increase to help the fire protection funding problem in the
 County. The proposal contends the increase would raise over
 $6 million to be distributed primarily to the rural fire districts. The directors and the public alike showed little support for
 the idea as it was seen to be lacking in detail and would be collecting
 a vast majority of the tax from the urban areas to subsidize the rural
 areas. 


 12/22/05 
 Fire District
 Approves Capital Facility Plan 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District Board of Directors approved a $3.8
 million Capital Facilities Plan for 2006. The new plan
 proposes a new station on Olive Ranch Rd. to replace the old station
 on Douglas Blvd.. It also proposes to develop additional
 administrative and training space, and it calls for the District to
 assist Placer County with the cost of major communication system
 improvements. Since the need for these new facilities and service is
 primarily the result of growth, a new mitigation fee schedule was
 also adopted. It call for a 4.3% fee hike for new construction.


 12/22/05 
 Fire District Board Selects New Officers 
 
The South Placer Fire District Board of Directors elected new officers for 2006 last evening. The Board elected Dave Giblin to be the President and Jeff Moss to be the Vice President. The new officers will assume their new post at the January 18 meeting.


 12/16/05 
 Sheriff&apos;s
 Report Cites a Number of Vehicle Burglaries 
 
The November Crime Summary from the Placer County Sheriff&apos;s office identifies a number of vehicle burglaries in the Granite Bay area. Please remember and remind neighbors and friends that valuables need to be removed from vehicles, or at the very least kept out of sight. This is especially important during the holidays.


 12/8/05 
 MAC
 Recommends Shopping Center Expansion 
 
The MAC recommended approval of a proposal to expand the Sierra Oaks Plaza shopping center at the corner of Douglas Blvd. and Sierra College Blvd. The proposal will add 12,575 square feet to the backside of the existing building located at the southeast corner of the center for a Ross Department Store.


 12/8/05 
 Traffic Calming
 Measures Considered for Macargo Rd. 
 
In response to concerns offered by the community regarding traffic hazards on Macargo Rd., the MAC recommended adoption of the Dept. of Public Works suggestion to provide a stop signs on Macargo at Johnson Lane. This latest recommendation is in addition to speed limit signs and the clearing of vegetation from the shoulders that has already been completed.


 12/8/05 
 Traffic
 Safety Committee to be Formed 
 
MAC approved the formation of a temporary committee to discuss traffic safety issues within the community.
 The Committee will be co-chaired by the chairmen of the existing
 Transportation and Safety Committees. Meeting times and dates to be
 announced.


 12/3/05 
 Post Office Extends Holiday Hours 
 
The
 Granite Bay Station of the US Post Office at 8771 Auburn Folsom Rd.
 has announced extended hours for the holidays. Beginning 12/10 and
 through 12/22, the Post office will be open from 8:30 am to 7 pm
 Monday thru Friday, and from 8:30 am to 5 pm on Saturday. The office
 will be closed on Sundays. 


 12/3/05 
 Bureau
 to Hold Meetings on Folsom Dam Improvements 
 
The US Bureau of Reclamation will hold two public meetings to discuss improvements to Folsom Dam. Earlier plans called for raising the dam and enlarging its outlets. But the revelation that it would cost millions of dollars more than anticipated has shifted discussion toward a proposal to build a second spillway on the dam&apos;s southern flank. The first meeting is scheduled for 4 to 6 p.m., Monday, Dec. 12, at the Granite Bay Activity Center, at the Douglas Boulevard entrance to the Folsom Lake State Recreation Area, in Granite Bay. The second is set for 5:30 to 8 p.m. Wednesday, Dec. 14, at the Folsom Community Center, 52 Natoma St., in Folsom.


 12/1/05 
 Dec. 7 MAC Parks Committee Meeting Cancelled 
 
Next meeting will be scheduled for Jan 4 06 at the Eureka School District office.


 12/1/05 
 New
 Public Works Director Appointed 
 
Ken Grehm, who currently serves as Assistant Public Works Director, has been named to succeed Tim Hackworth as Public Works Director when he retires at the end of the year. The Board of Supervisors confirmed the appointment Tuesday. Grehm joined Placer County Public Works in 2002. Previously he served as Supervising Engineer at the City of Sacramento, where he worked since the late 1980&apos;s. Ken is known in the Granite Bay area for his work with the community on the improvements planned for Auburn Folsom Rd.


 11/30/05 
 December 7, MAC to hear 3 Action Items 
 
A. The MAC will take action on a proposal to add 12,575 square feet onto the backside of the existing building located at the southeast corner of the Sierra Oaks Plaza shopping center at the corner of Douglas Blvd. and Sierra College Blvd. for a Ross Department Store.

B. The Department of Public Works will present information on specific concerns and/or solution concepts offered by the community and potential &quot;traffic calming&quot; measures being considered for Macargo Rd.

C. MAC will consider formation of temporary committee to discuss traffic safety issues within the community.


 11/29/05 
 Thieves
 Steal Christmas Decorations 
 
Three
 young men (19-25 yrs.) dressed in black and driving a small black
 Dodge or Toyota truck stole approximately $400 worth of Christmas
 decorations from a home on Willow Gate Ct. The incident occurred
 Friday 11/25 just after midnight. The home owner caught them in the
 act but they got away. Please everyone be extra alert, be on the look
 out, and report anything suspicious to the Sheriff. Hopefully someone can spot these perpetrators if they return. 


 11/9/05 
 County&apos;s Chief of Staff to the Board Promoted 
 
John Marin, who has served as Chief of Staff to the Board of Supervisors office for more than 17 years, has been promoted to interim Director of the Community Development/Resource Agency. Board members ratified the appointment Nov. 8. 2005. In his new position Marin will be responsible for handling environmental review of projects and for coordinating review of the largest, most complex development proposals facing the county. CD/RA includes the planning and building departments, and staff from land development sections from public works.


 11/5/05 
 November MAC Safety Committee Report 
 
The MAC Safety Committee meets on the first Wednesday each month at 6 PM at the Eureka School District Office. The public is welcome. 
 CHP Report: &gt; Crashes on Auburn-Folsom Rd. down 14 from last year but crashes on Douglas Blvd. were up 13 from last year.
&gt; Officers from several jurisdictions will be holding a Zero Tolerance Day on Auburn Folsom Rd. later this month.
&gt; CHP will be conducting a DUI Task Force effort on I-80 from Madison Ave. to Colfax.
&gt; CHP officers will be collecting toys at the Roseville Galleria on Thanksgiving weekend.
 
 Sheriff&apos;s Dept. Report: &gt; October Crime Summary lists only 4 crimes in Granite Bay. 2 Burglaries (1 vehicle- 1 residence), 1 vehicle vandalism, and 1 Grand theft from a construction site. Residents are reminded to keep valuable items out of site in their vehicles.
&gt; Sheriff&apos;s Dept. is collecting new or gently used stuffed toy animals for distribution to kids in local hospitals. Donations may be dropped off at the Sheriff&apos;s Service Center on Douglas Blvd. (Behind Granite Community Bank) or at the Cattlemen&apos;s Restaurant on Taylor Rd. in Roseville. 

 So. Placer Fire District Report: &gt; The Fire district responded to 157 calls for service in October.
&gt; The burn ban was lifted after the rain in the last week of October.
&gt; Permits for burning are required year round, and may be obtained from any fire station.
&gt; The grass fire season closed without a major fire in the community.
&gt; The colder weather brings with it the beginning of the wood-burning season. Residents are reminded to have their chimneys/flues inspected and cleaned or repaired as needed. A good plan to keep the stovepipe clean is allowing the stove to free burn for 30 minutes before reducing the airflow. Residents are also reminded to NEVER dispose of ashes in their plastic trash bins unless the ashes have been thoroughly soaked with water first. Each year several fires are caused by the improper disposal of ashes. 

 Granite
 Bay High School Report: &gt; Athletic events will bring traffic and parking to the area surrounding this weekend. If the football team wins, then they will go to post-season which will bring at least one more home game the following weekend.
&gt; The school is looking into reports of students smoking at the bus stop in front of the school. They believe that these incidents are due to students from other schools who use the bus stop as a transfer point. 

 Public Comment: &gt; A resident voiced a concern over excessive speed and noise in the 6000 block of Auburn Folsom Rd. CHP officer Kelly Baraga took note and will target the area during the Zero Tolerance Day.
&gt; Another resident brought up the subject of illegal street racing on Douglas Blvd., on Friday and Saturday nights. Officer Baraga will look into a joint effort with the Roseville Police Dept. CHP has joined with RPD on Zero Tolerance Days and other efforts, and will look forward to reciprocity in this area. 
 
 


 11/4/05 
 A
 Busy Night at the November 2 MAC Meeting 
 
&gt; A contingent of neighbors of the property located on the south side of Douglas Blvd. across from the library expressed concern about tree cutting, filling and grading on the parcel and wanted to know what the owner proposed to construct on the site. They asked for help in investigating the matter before it progressed any further. County staff present at the meeting advised they would look into the matter and as of 2:00 p.m. November 3 a cease and desist order was issued to the property owner.

&gt; A representative of Elliot Homes reported that the company had purchased the Rolling Greens Golf Course on Eureka Road and proposes to construct 10 homes on the 23 acre parcel in accordance with our Community Plan and the existing zoning. The golf course will remain available for play through 2006.

&gt; The MAC reviewed a proposal to add 12,575 square feet onto the backside of the existing vacant 18,825 square foot building located at the southeast corner of the Sierra Oaks Plaza shopping center at 4130 Douglas Boulevard. The addition is proposed for a Ross Department Store.

&gt; A proposal was presented to develop two vacant commercial properties consisting of 9.5 acres as a residential planned development of 50-60 duet homes ranging from 1300 to 2100 square feet in one and two story buildings. The parcels are located on the north side of Douglas Boulevard east of Longs on Auburn-Folsom Road. Residents expressed concerns about run off and tree removal, but MAC and the audience generally felt the concept was a good fit for the property.

&gt; A proposal for 101 Town Homes ranging from 1200 to 1750 square feet on 8.5 acres on the parcel located at the northwest corner of Old Auburn Road and Sierra College Blvd. was presented. The property is currently zoned 2.3 units per acre. The project would not comply with our Community Plan and would not be compatible with any of the surrounding low density residential neighborhoods. It was not generally supported by the MAC or the residents in the audience.

&gt; A proposal for a single story building housing a 3700 square foot bank facility and 2650 square feet for tenant occupancy was presented. The site is about .2 miles south of Douglas on the east side of Sierra College Blvd. at the signalized entry to Granite Bay Business Park and is an infill project. The applicant proposes to design the building in a manner similar to what is already developed.


 10/31/05 
 MAC Agenda Update 
 
The Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Committee agenda has changed. One action item has been removed and one Information item has been added.


 10/28/05 
 MAC Has Full Agenda, Meeting to Start Early on Wed. Nov. 2 
 
The
 Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Committee has a full agenda for the
 Wednesday Nov. 2 meeting.  The meeting will start at 6:30
 p.m., one half hour earlier than usual.  Agenda items
 include a digital monument sign on Auburn-Folsom near Douglas, three
 developments involving more than 110 homes, and an expansion
 of the Sierra Oaks Plaza shopping center (Ralphs). The agenda
 also includes a Workshop on the function of Placer County MACs.  


 10/21/05 
 Fire District
 Accepting Applications for Two Positions 
 
The South Placer Fire
 District is accepting applications for a Division Chief/EMS Officer and
 for a Division Chief/Training Officer. Salary range for both positions
 is $5,351 to $6,504 per month plus excellent benefits. Persons
 interested should contact the South Placer Fire District, 6900 Eureka Road, Granite Bay, CA 95746 or 916-791-7059 for required district application. Applications accepted until no later than 5:00 p.m. on December 16, 2005.


 10/14/05 
 County
 Transportation Planning Agency Launches Web  
 
The Placer County Transportation Planning Agency has launched a new Web site aimed at commuters to help address their concerns. The site includes information regarding transit projects, news about upcoming events, a frequently asked-question page and a forum for commuters to e-mail their frustrations, concerns and suggestions. The Web site is a way for people to express their frustrations regarding transit issues and participate in solutions.


 10/9/05 
 I
 80 Off Ramp to Douglas Blvd. to Close 
 
The eastbound Interstate 80 off ramp to eastbound Douglas Blvd. will be closed for construction for 10 days beginning at midnight Monday. Traffic on Sunrise Ave. in the construction area will be reduced to one lane in each direction for the next two weeks.


 10/6/05 
 MAC Recommends Re-Phasing Auburn-Folsom Rd. Work 
 
The
 MAC recommended the County abandon the present phasing plan
 for the Auburn-Folsom Road Widening Project that would have
 started construction near Douglas Blvd. to approximately 1500
 feet&apos; south of Eureka Rd. Instead, they recommended installing
 a signal at Fuller Dr., continuing efforts to acquire right of
 way, and to begin design of what had initially been phase 2,
 from the County line on the south to Oak Leaf Way.

The
 MAC and the public alike rejected the idea of paying $1.6
 million more than the County was offering for a narrow strip
 of right of way just south of Fuller Dr. Ironically, the owner
 of those parcels was cited by the County in June 2004 for
 removal of 75 trees and significant disturbance to the Linda
 Creek corridor that is yet to be resolved.


 9/30/05 
 County
 Announces Flu Shot Clinics 
 
The Placer County Department of Health and Human Services has announced its schedule of flu shot clinics in our area for the upcoming influenza season. The County will provide vaccinations to seniors and those who are at high risk, have chronic health issues, or who may spread influenza to those at risk. For most other residents, flu shots are typically available through their regular primary care doctors. Oct. 19: Veterans Memorial Hall, 110 Park Dr., Roseville, 8:30 - Noon.
 Nov 9: Rocklin Sunset Center, 2650 Sunset Blvd., Rocklin, 8:30 a.m. – Noon.
 Nov 16: Veteran’s Memorial Hall, 110 Park Dr., Roseville, 8:30 a.m. – Noon. 


 9/30/05 
 MAC to Take Action on Two Issues Wednesday Night 
 
A. Placer County&apos;s Department of Public Works will seek support for the re-phasing of the Auburn-Folsom Road Widening Project. The Project is now phased to begin construction at Douglas Blvd. to approximately 1500&apos; south of Eureka Rd, but the County is now proposing to start at the County Line to approximately 1500&apos; north of Oak Hill Drive.

B. A developer will seek support for a project, called Beaver Creek, consisting of seven single-family home sites on 17.5 acres. The project is located on the south side of Douglas Blvd. approximately 1000 feet east of the Fire Station at Douglas and Woodgrove Way.


 9/23/05 
 Fire District Adopts $6.3 Million Operating Budget 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District has adopted a $6.3 million operating
 budget for the 05-06 fiscal year. That figure represents a 10%
 increase over the 04-05 fiscal year spending. Salaries and benefits
 will increase nearly 11% while service and operation costs are
 projected to hold steady. Salaries alone increased over a quarter
 million dollars. Additionally, the District has budgeted for a
 nearly $2.7 million cash reserve at year end.


 9/22/05 
 Local
 Resident Recognized for Dousing Fire 
 
Chief
 Corado of the South Placer Fire District presented Larry
 Houghtby a plaque last night in recognition of his actions to
 report and suppress a fire at his neighbors home on Oak Leaf
 Way in July. After seeing smoke, he investigated and found the
 deck and the exterior wall on fire. As his wife called 911,
 Larry was able to extinguish the fire with a garden hose
 before firefighters arrived. 


 9/19/05 
 New Planning Director Named 
 
Michael
 J. Johnson, a resident of Rocklin, who currently serves as the City
 of Folsom&apos;s Community Development Director, has been named Placer
 County Planning Director to replace Fred Yeager who retired in
 August. Johnson has been with Folsom since 1997. He also served in
 Fremont and Merced. and has been a planner for the San Luis Obispo
 County Land Conservancy. Supervisors confirmed his appointment last
 week and he will start Oct. 12.


 9/14/05 
 Granite Bay Press Tribune Editor Leaving 
 
Jamie
 Trump, the editor of the Granite Bay Press-Tribune for the past
 three years has announced that she will be leaving the paper on the
 16th of Sept. The paper has not yet identified a replacement, but in the meantime Sherri Shaulis will be coordinating Granite Bay news.
 Press releases, meeting agendas, columns, etc. may be sent to Sherri at sherris@goldcountrymedia.com . Thank you Jamie for your excellent coverage of Granite Bay issues,
 we will miss you and we wish you the best for your future.


 9/13/05 
 Dinner,
 Night Out!  
 
Stoneridge Elementary School is having a community fundraising event at The Habit Burger Grill (4060 Douglas Blvd. at Sierra College Boulevard) in Granite Bay. Date: Thursday, Sept 29th, Time: From 3pm - 9pm. Invite all of your friends and family to dine out at The Habit Burger Grill on the 29th of Sept. 20% of the proceeds will go to the school&apos;s fundraiser for their 6th Grade Science Camp. Take out is available.


 9/12/05 
 Sacramento
 Metropolitan Orchestra Benefit Performance 
 
The Sacramento Metropolitan Orchestra, will perform at the Adventure Christian Church in Rocklin on Sunday, September 25, 2005, at 7:30 pm to benefit Hurricane Katrina Flood Victims. Featured guest artists will be the New Orleans Jazz Band, Banu Gibson and the New Orleans Hot Jazz. Guest vocalists performing with the orchestra are Danielle Nice,&amp;Malcolm MacKensie. Proceeds from the concert will be donated to the American Red Cross and to the Hurricane Katrina Relief Fund of the American Federation of Musicians.  Tickets can be ordered by phone at 800-225-2277 or 916-766-2277.


 9/8/05 
 Help Wanted, Tree
 Planting Scheduled for Feist Park 
 
Volunteers are needed Saturday and Sunday September 24th and 25th to help plant over 150 trees at the new Feist Park at the corner of Elmhurst and Twin Schools Rd. If you can help for a few hours at sometime during those days, bring your shovel, rake and gloves with you to the park. Planting will begin at 8 AM each day and continue until at least 4 PM. It would be a good idea to mark your tools in case they get lost.


 9/8/05 
 MAC
 Reviews Two Development Concepts 
 
-- Adventist Ministries presented MAC a site concept for a 75-acre parcel on the east side of Sierra College Blvd. on top of the hill. The proposal consists of a 2,000 seat sanctuary, administrative and resource center, small bible school and on-campus housing for 100 students. Neighboring residents expressed concern over the Fire Districts request for a 26 ft. wide access road to the project from Cavitt-Stallman Rd.

-- A conceptual proposal for the parcels located on the south side of Douglas Blvd. between the Bank of America and the existing residential area to the east would provide up to 46 owner occupied half-plex units and a 7000 sq. ft. retail building. The proposal would remove the existing old retail center where Granito&apos;s restaurant and the Barber Shop are located, but would enable relocation of existing businesses to the new building. The concept received generally favorable response from the MAC and residents alike. Some concern about the proposed density was expressed.


 8/31/05 
 20 Human Cases of West Nile Virus in Placer County 
 
Placer County health officials announced today that the total number of human West Nile virus cases has increased to 20, as the disease continues to spread in the western area of the county.

Ground
 spraying in selected areas of Roseville to combat mosquitoes which
 can carry the virus, delayed for two days due to winds, is expected
 to begin Thursday night. The
 spraying will take place between 1 a.m. and 4 a.m. on Thursday,
 Friday and Saturday, weather permitting.

 8/31/05 
 County
 Library Offers New Online Service 
 
A new service offered by the Placer County Library system permits patrons to read stories and view photographs from more than 2,000 magazines and newspapers online from the comfort of their homes, schools or offices. The new service is available through the county&apos;s library web site to anyone who has a valid Placer County library card. Library cards can be obtained by applying at any branch of the Placer County Library.


 8/26/05 
 Ground Spraying Scheduled for Placer County 
 
In its efforts to reduce the mosquito population and the spread of West Nile virus, the Placer Mosquito Abatement District will be conducting ground spraying by truck in south Roseville on Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday, August 30 through September 1. Weather permitting, the spraying will occur between 1 a.m. and 4 a.m.

Due to concerns about exposure to the mosquito-borne West Nile virus, Performing Arts of Roseville (PAR) is canceling its Sunday, August 28 concert in Roseville’s Royer Park.


 8/25/05 
 County Names New Chief Executive Officer 
 
The Placer County Board of Supervisors has named Tom Miller to succeed County Executive Officer Jan Christofferson following her retirement in late October. Miller has worked for the County for 6 years and currently serves as the director of the County&apos;s Community Development/Resource Agency. He has extensive public works and planning experience. He has a B.A. in Environmental Studies and additional graduate work in Applied Economics.


 8/16/05 
 Another Human Infected by the West Nile Virus 
 
Another human case of West Nile Virus has been discovered in Placer County. Officials from the Mosquito Abatement District and the county Health and Human Services Department announced the additional case brings to four the 2005 county total of human cases.

The new case is a female, 42-year old South County resident in the 95678 Zip code area of Roseville. The previous three Placer County cases are also from the same Zip code.


 8/10/05 
 West Nile Virus Discovered in Three Humans 
 
Three human cases of West Nile virus have been discovered in Placer County. In addition to the three human cases there have been 43 dead birds (5 in Granite Bay), two horses, two dead squirrels and eight mosquito pools that have tested positive for the virus.

As part of their eradication efforts, the Mosquito Abatement District is treating storm drains for mosquitoes in South Placer County, and will also be holding two mosquito fish giveaways. There is currently no aerial spraying planned for residential areas in Placer County to kill mosquitoes.


 8/405 
 Planning Director Receives Proclamation at MAC 
 
Supervisor Gaines presented retiring Planning Director Fred Yeager a proclamation honoring him for his 32 years of service to the County. In addition Yeager received a plaque from the Granite Bay Community Association thanking him for his efforts in drafting and supporting the Granite Bay Community Plan.


 8/4/05 
 MAC Recommends Rezone 
 
The
 MAC recommended approval of a proposal from Dave Bushnell to rezone
 the property where his nursery is located on the north side of
 Douglas Blvd, from single family residential to farm zoning. The
 zoning change would resolve some long standing non conformance
 issues and allow for the addition of several greenhouses . Residents
 and MAC members also indicated support for a side walk along Douglas
 Blvd as part of the improvements proposed.  

On another issue, the MAC was generally receptive to conceptual plans for townhouses on the east side of Padre Ct. at Douglas Blvd. and Padre Ct. The project as presented would provide a transition between commercial and single family residential and would have a total of 6 buildings with 2 units in each building targeted for individual ownership rather than rental units.


 8/3/05 
 County
 CEO to Retire 
 
Jan
 Christofferson, the Chief Executive Officer for Placer County since
 June 2001 has announced she will retire effective 28 October 2005.
 She indicates she wants to spend more time with her family and pursue
 part time career options working with her father.


 7/21/05 
 Mike Holmes to Run for 4th District Congressional Seat 
 
Mike
 Holmes, a 65 year old moderate republican has announced he will
 challenge John Doolittle in the 2006 primary election for the
 Republican nomination for the 4th congressional district seat.
 Holmes is the vice Mayor of Auburn and a retired Navy Captain. He
 describes himself as a fiscal conservative with moderate social
 views.


 7/18/05 
 Ground
 is Broken for South Placer Justice Center 
 
Placer
 County broke ground Tuesday on the new South Placer Justice
 Center in North Roseville, The first phase of the project
 will include a courthouse with nine courtrooms, a holding
 facility for inmates and space for court administration. The
 project will bring many public protection services closer to
 the South Placer area. At
 the same time, a privately owned office building is being
 constructed. The
 County will lease space there for the District Attorney&apos;s
 Office, and Probation Dept.


 7/18/05 
 Granite Bay Man Arrested for Stabbing Death 
 
A 23-year-old Granite Bay man, Caleb John Madsen, was arrested Thursday night at his family&apos;s home on Bella Vista Dr. in connection with the stabbing death of his friend Christopher Worth. Worth was found dead Sunday afternoon in a field near Madsen&apos;s home. According to the Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Department, Worth was killed at Madsen&apos;s house and his body was transported in his own truck to the nearby field.


 7/16/05 
 More
 West Nile Virus Discovered in Placer County 
 
The Placer Mosquito Abatement District announced two mosquito pools from West Placer County have tested positive for West Nile virus. One was from west of Roseville; the other was west of Lincoln. &quot;This confirms that we have mosquitoes flying now that could transmit the virus,&quot; said Jamesina Scott, Ph. D. Residents can help prevent mosquitoes in their own yards by eliminating standing water sources where mosquitoes breed.


 7/9/05 
 Water
 District Approves Rate Hike 
 
San Juan Water District Board of Directors has approved a 3% water rate increase to take effect in September. The increase is consistent with the CPI used to measure inflation. Questions regarding the new rate should be directed to the District&apos;s customer service staff at 791-0115.


 7/8/05 
 Five Buddies Head to the Marines Together 
 
Five
 proud young Granite Bay men (Ryan Adair, Nick Davison, Nick Reineke,
 Jose Sachez and Dave Volk) are joining the US Marines as part of the
 Marines&quot;Buddy Program&quot;. The 18 year olds are best buddies
 and will be headed to Marine boot camp at Camp Pendleton together on
 July 18. They say 9/11 prompted their decision. Semper
 Fi Marines.


 7/7/05 
 MAC Endorses Change to Permit Parking Ordinance 
 
At its 6 July meeting the MAC accepted a change to the Permit Parking Ordinance that would prohibit parking for a distance on the south side of Eureka Rd. The MAC heard from the Public Works Staff that up to 70 new parking places should be available prior to the beginning of school by restriping Wellington Way and using the new parking lot at the new church site on East Roseville Parkway. A proposal to eliminate permit parking on Elmhurst Dr. was rejected.


 7/6/05 
 MAC Transportation Subcommittee to Meet 
 
The Granite Bay MAC Transportation Subcommittee will host a public meeting July 13 at 7:00 PM at Eureka School District Office to hear specific concerns and/or solution concepts from residents regarding Macargo Road and to discuss potential “traffic calming” measures for the road. Additionally, the committee will review a request for a stop sign on Cavitt-Stallman South Road at the intersection with Woodthrush Way. The public is invited to attend and to share your concerns and suggestions.


 7/5/05 
 Supervisors Reappoint MAC Members 
 
The County Board of Supervisors approved reappointment of Steve Nash, Walt Pekarsky, David Kaiser and Virg Anderson to the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council, for 2 year terms, as requested by Supervisor Gaines. 


 7/5/05 
 MAC to Review Permit Parking Ordinance 
 
MAC will meet at 7:00 pm 6 July at Eureka School District Office to review and discuss possible changes to the permit parking program currently implemented in the area adjacent to the Granite Bay High School. Additionally, public input will be requested for aesthetics, such as bridge rail type and concrete finish, for the design for Barton Rd bridge replacement at Miner’s Ravine, and County staff will provide an update on the Auburn Folsom Rd.


 6/28/05 
 Board Approves Community Plan Amendment 
 
The
 County Board of Supervisors today approved the revised Circulation
 Element of the Granite Bay Community Plan. The amendment sets forth
 numerous new goals, policies and implementation programs that will
 provide a transportation system that serves the future needs of the
 Community. The Plan accommodates new development projects,
 pedestrian, equestrian and cyclist needs, while it retains and
 enhances the rural and scenic qualities of the area.


 6/28/05 
 Park
 Ownership Transfer to Placer County Approved 
 
The Placer County Board of Supervisors has approved the transfer of Feist Park, located at Elmhurst and Twin Schools Rd, from the Eureka School District to Placer County. Use agreements with the various youth sports leagues and the Eureka School District were also approved. The actual transfer will occur in July. A joint use agreement between the County and the Granite Bay High School regarding the planned tennis courts is pending.

County Parks Staff reported the county also approved spending up to $500,000 of future park dedication fees now to complete the soccer fields, walkways, etc. with the plan to hydroseed the fields in October.


 6/16/05 
 Fire Districts to Discuss Future 
 
The
 Loomis Fire District and the South Placer Fire District have
 appointed a ad-hoc committee to discuss the future of fire
 protection in the Loomis Fire District. At issue is how fire
 protection could be provided if the Loomis District fails due to its
 serious shortfall of operating revenue.


 6/14/05 
 Supervisors
 Approve&quot;The Grove&quot;Project 
 
&quot;The Grove&quot; (a 32 lot residential project at the southwest corner of Olive Ranch Rd. and Berg St.) received unanimous approval from the Board of Supervisors. The project had been approved by the MAC and the Planning Commission, but had been appealed by a neighbor who opposed the project.


 6/11/05 
 Date
 Set for Community Plan Hearing 
 
The Board of Supervisors will hold a public hearing 24 June at 1:45 pm to consider approval of an amendment to the Circulation Element of the Granite Bay Community Plan. The hearing will be in the Board Hearing Room in Auburn. No changes to the Community Plan land use designations are being considered. Interested persons are encouraged to attend the hearing or submit written comments prior to the hearing.


 6/5/05 
 Granite
 Bay Youth Sets State Meet Record 
 
Scott Roth, a junior at Granite Bay High School won his second consecutive pole vault title at the CIF State Track and Field Championship meet at Hughes Stadium on Saturday. With a vault of 17 feet 1 inch Scott erased the previous record of 17 feet that had stood since 1978. Congratulations Scott we are all proud of you.


 6/3/05 
 County
 Budgets Funds for Feist Park 
 
The 2006 Placer County Budget includes $500K from present and future park mitigation fees for construction at Feist Park at the corner of Elmhurst Dr. and Twin Schools Rd.. The money along with the construction of the tennis courts by the Granite Bay High School should be enough to complete the third and final phase of the park&apos;s construction by the end of the year.


 6/3/05 
 Supervisors
 Fill Vacant MAC Seat 
 
The
 Placer County Board of Supervisors approved the appointment of Craig
 Powell, a resident of Douglas Ranch sub-division, to the Granite Bay
 Municipal Advisory Council Seat #2 as requested by Supervisor
 Gaines.


 6/1/05 
 Folsom
 Dam Road Limited Opening Approved 
 
Federal
 Officials on Tuesday, approved the opening of the Folsom Dam Road
 during commute hours. However, the lack of funding to implement a $6
 million security plan could delay its opening at least until 2006.
 Folsom officials estimate over 7200 vehicles daily will be able to
 use the road during commute hours. The traffic impact on
 Granite Bay as a result of the opening was not immediately known.


 5/25/05 
 Supervisors
 Reschedule Project Appeal Hearing 
 
The hearing for &quot;The Grove&quot; (a 32 lot residential project at the southwest corner of Olive Ranch Rd. and Berg St.) that had been scheduled for 24 May has been continued to 14 June at 1:30 pm in the Board of Supervisors chambers in Auburn. The project was approved by the MAC and the Planning Commission, but has been appealed by a neighbor who opposes the project.


 5/19/05 
 Fire
 District Changes Meeting Time 
 
At the request of community members, the South Placer Fire District Directors voted to change the meeting time of their regularly scheduled Board meeting from 7:30 pm to 7:00 pm on the 3rd Wednesday of the each month. The new schedule will be effective in June.


 4/26/05 
 Burn Hours Extended for the Month of May 
 
The Placer County Air Pollution Control District and the South Placer Fire Protection District have agreed to implement the extended burn hours for the month of May that were recommended by the community’s Municipal Advisory Council. For the month of May if it is a burn day between the 1st and 15th, the burn hours are 8 am to 7 pm. This change affects residents who live in the 95661 and 95746 zip codes.


 4/23/05 
 Public Invited to Open House for New Folsom Bridge 
 
The
 US Army Corps of Engineers and the City of Folsom will host an Open
 House Wednesday 27 April from 4 pm to 6 pm and from 7 pm to 9 pm at
 the Folsom Community Center, 52 Natoma St. in Folsom to provide the
 public an update on the Folsom Bridge Project. For more information
 contact the Corps at 916-557-5100.


 4/22/05 
 Juvenile Justice/Delinquency Prevention Commission 
 
Judge Colleen Nichols, of the Juvenile Court and Chairman of the Placer County Juvenile Justice/Delinquency Prevention Commission, announces applications are being accepted for membership on the County’s Commission. There are adult and juvenile vacancies on the Commission. Any resident of Placer County interested in applying for membership on the Commission can call (530) 889-7900 or write for a membership application for the Commission, c/o Placer County Probation Department Attention: JJ/DP, 11564 C Avenue, Auburn, CA 95603.


 4/22/05 
 New Facility Services Director Appointed 
 
The Board of Supervisors has ratified the appointment of Jim Durfee to be the County&apos;s new Facility Services Director. Durfee currently serves as Assistant Director of Facility Services. He also serves as Assistant Executive Director of both the Western Placer and the Placer-Nevada Waste Management Authorities.


 4/22/05 
 Fire Board
 Approves Long Term Facility Upgrade Plan 
 
A
 plan outlining the estimated cost and anticipated schedule for major
 upgrades or replacement of the Fire District&apos;s facilities as they
 wear or become unfit for the type of service needed over the years
 was approved by the Board of Directors at their April 20 meeting.
 The Plan initially will cost 3.75% of the Districts annual budget
 ($250,000 in the 05/06 fiscal year). As a result of
 implementing this plan, the District&apos;s Fundamental Budget Principles
 had to change as well. Staffing will become 77.5% of the budget, a
 reduction of 2.5%, while the other elements of the budget changed
 only slightly or not at all.


 4/10/05 
 Interstate 80 Exit Ramp to Close for 12 Days 
 
Caltrans will close the eastbound exit ramp from Interstate 80 to eastbound Douglas Boulevard beginning at 6 a.m., Monday April 11. The ramp will remain closed until 11:59 p.m., Friday April 22. The ramp closure will allow crews to work on the tunnel connecting northbound Sunrise Boulevard to the freeway, and to realign the I-80/Douglas Boulevard ramp to a new configuration.


 4/7/05 
 MAC Supports Minor Change to Burn Policy 
 
After hearing pleas from residents that don&apos;t want any backyard burning permitted and residents that don&apos;t want any restrictions on burning, the MAC agreed that the compromise established nearly two years ago was not broken and needed only a very small adjustment. The only change the MAC recommended to the Fire District and the Air Pollution Control District was to extend the burn hours for the month of May to 7 pm.


 4/6/05 
 LAFCo
 Appoints New Executive Officer 
 
The Placer Local Agency Formation Commission,
 which oversees the changes in boundaries for cities and special districts within Placer
 County, has announced the appointment of Kristina Berry as the new Executive Officer. Ms. Berry is currently the Senior Analyst for the Monterey County
 LAFCo and will be assuming her new position on May 2 following the
 resignation of Scott Finley who will be returning to the County
 Council&apos;s office. 


 4/5/05 
 Two Promotions in the Fire District 
 
The South Placer Fire District has announced two promotions within its staff. Fire Marshall Lawrence Bettencourt has been selected for promotion to the rank of Battalion Chief, and Karl Fowler has been selected for promotion to the rank of Captain. Both promotions will become effective 16 April 05. Congratulations to both.


 4/2/05 
 County Creates New Development-Resource Agency 
 
In
 an effort to make the land use review process more efficient, the
 Placer County Board of Supervisors, on Tuesday, created a new agency
 that will oversee both the Planning and the Building Departments.
 The Board appointed Tom Miller, present director of Facility
 Services, as the head of the new agency.


 3/30/05 
 Fire
 District Board Selects New Board Member 
 
The Directors of the South Placer Fire District interviewed eight candidates 29 Mar. to fill the seat vacated by the resignation of John de Graaff in Feb. Mike DeLaurentis, a Granite Bay resident and a former candidate for the directors position was selected to serve the remainder of de Graaf&apos;s 4 year term. Mike is due to be sworn in on Friday at 5:00 PM.


 3/22/05 
 County&apos;s
 Planning Director to Retire 
 
Fred Yeager, Placer County&apos;s Planning Director since 1989 has indicated he will retire in August. He has 33 years of service with the County.  Fred was instrumental in the design of our Granite Bay Community Plan and has been responsible for implementing the policies of the Plan by guiding development within the community towards our community goals.

 3/22/05 
 Two New Fire Engines Arrive 
 
Two new type one fire engines have been delivered to the Fire District. The Board recognized a team of employees (Derek Carey, Brian Midtlying, Mike Rufenacht, Steve Adcock, Jim Stephens, Ray Jennings, and Russ Moorhouse) who were instrumental in designing and acquiring the new engines. The new engines cost the District $380,000 each.


 3/17/05 
 Fire
 District Proposes Long Term Facility Upgrade Plan 
 
Chief
 Corado presented the Board with a conceptual plan outlining the
 estimated cost and an anticipated schedule of major upgrades or
 replacement of the Fire District&apos;s facilities as they wear or become unfit for
 the type of service needed over the years. Until very recently, the
 District has not been saving money for the rehabilitation of their
 maturing facilities. The initial estimate for the average annual
 cost of the program over the next 30 years is over $500,000 per
 year.


 3/11/05 
 Planning Commission Approves New Development 
 
The
 County Planning Commission approved a new sub-division (The Grove at
 Granite Bay) on 32 acres at the south-west corner of Berg St. and
 Olive Ranch Rd. on Thursday, 10 Mar. The new sub-division provides
 32 custom residential lots (average lot size is 22,000 sq. ft.) with
 approximately 11 acres of open space to preserve and protect a large
 wetland area and the stream environment zones. Berg St. is planned
 to be improved to correct vertical alignment issues but will retain
 the aesthetics of a country road.


 3/3/05 
 MAC
 Approves Barton Bridge Design 
 
The
 Municipal Advisory Council approve a conceptual plan for the replacement of the bridge on
 Barton Rd. at it&apos;s 2 March meeting. Work on the new bridge which
 will widen the channel at the bridge and raise the level of the
 bridge by 3 feet is planned for 2006. Additionally, the MAC approved
 a recommendation to the County to develop and implement a graffiti
 ordinance to enable the removal of graffiti as soon as possible.


 3/3/05 
 Granite Bay MAC Needs a Secretary 
 
The Placer County Board of Supervisors is looking to fill the Secretary position for the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC). The MAC meets one evening per month. The position entails mailing out the agendas, taking minutes and other related duties. The applicant must provide for their transportation and reside in Granite Bay. The position pays $100 per meeting and is considered voluntary. The MAC is a great way to get involved in the community. For more information, contact Melanie Eustice, Placer County Board of Supervisors, (916) 787-8950.


 2/23/05 
 Supervisors
 Appoint New MAC Member 
 
The County Board of Supervisors appointed Steve Nash to the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council Tuesday. Nash has served on the MAC&apos;s parks subcommittee for several years and will replace Mike Casey who became ineligible when he moved out of the community.


 2/16/05 
 Notice
 --- Fire District
 Board Member Resigns 
 
After
 serving two years of the four year term he was elected to, South Placer Fire District Director
 John de Graaff has submitted his resignation to the Board.  He
 indicated a significant difference in philosophy with the other
 board members as the reason for his resignation.

The seat vacated by de Graaff has been officially declared vacant and residents of the Fire District interested in being appointed to serve on the Board for the remainder of his term should submit a letter of interest to the Fire District Office at 6900 Eureka Road in Granite Bay no later than 5:00 pm, March 18, 2005. Candidate interviews will be scheduled during the week of March 28, 2005. Questions can be directed to Chief Tony Corado at (916) 791-7059.


 2/16/05 
 Directors Approve Apprentice Firefighter Program 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District Board of Directors approved a new program
 that will provided a two year apprentice firefighter program
 designed to provide career development within the fire service. The
 new program will replace the current reserve firefighters who will
 be offered the new positions if qualified.


 2/12/05 
 MAC Residential Burn Sub-Committee to Meet 
 
The MAC Residential Burn Sub-Committee will meet Thursday, Feb 17 at 7:00 p.m. in the Granite Bay Library Conference Room at 6475 Douglas Blvd. (Note the change in venue)


 1/28/05 
 Notice of Public Hearing 
 
The
 Placer County Planning Commission will consider approval of an amendment
 to the Circulation Element of the Granite Bay Community Plan on
 Thursday 10 Feb. at 10:10 am. The hearing will be held in the
 Planning Commission Hearing Room, 2000 Richardson Dr. in the Dewitt
 Center in Auburn. For more information contact the Planning Dept. at
 800-488-4308 ext. 3000.


 1/21/05 
 Granite
 Bay&apos;s Supervisor Takes the Chair at SACOG 
 
Placer
 County&apos;s 4th District Supervisor, Ted Gaines, will serve as the
 chairman of the six county transportation
 planning agency
 for the next year. Gaines was sworn in as the chairman of the
 Board of Directors of the Sacramento Area Council of Governments
 Thursday after serving as the vice chair for the past
 year.   


 1/6/05 
 Residents Oppose Changing the Community Plan 
 
A large number of residents addressed the MAC, opposing amending the Community Plan. Past MAC member George Christi pointed out the value and integrity of the existing plan and the awards that it has received. Most residents were opposed to a proposal presented last month by a developer for a 43 unit age restricted development on a 12-acre parcel, next to Oakhills and Ridgeview Schools. The proposal would increase the permitted density on the parcel by about 700 percent.


 1/6/05 
 MAC
 Safety Committee Recommends Graffiti Ordinance 
 
Citing
 the fact that the County does not have an ordinance to deal with
 graffiti, such as was at the corner of Joe Rodgers and Douglas last
 year, the
 MAC Safety Sub-Committee presented information for a recommendation
 for the County to develop and adopt an ordinance to deal with
 graffiti when it occurs. The recommendation will be an action
 item on next months MAC agenda.


 1/3/05 
 MAC Parks Sub-Committee Meeting Cancelled 
 
The MAC Parks Sub-Committee meeting originally scheduled for Wednesday 5 Jan has been cancelled. The next meeting is scheduled for Wednesday 2 Feb at 5:00 p.m. in the Eureka School District Office.


 
 2004 
 12/23/04 
 Scouts
 to Collect Christmas Trees 
 
Boy
 Scout Troop 121 is offering curb side pick up of your Christmas tree
 on Saturday Jan 8, in the area south of Cavitt-Stallman Rd., for a
 tax deductible donation of $10 per tree. Or you may take your tree
 to Cavitt Jr. High parking lot Jan 8 or 9 from 9 to 4 for a donation
 of $5. For special requests or more information call 730-0588


 12/20/04 
 MAC
 Residential Burn Sub-Committee to Meet 
 
The MAC Residential Burn Sub-Committee will meet Thursday, Jan 20 at 7:00 p.m. in the portable building at Fire Station #1, 6900 Eureka Rd.

 12/17/04 
 State
 Lists Sex Offenders in Granite Bay 
 
The
 California Department of Justice&apos;s web site, lists 5 registered sex
 offenders living in Granite Bay. The site displays the last
 registered address reported by the persons required to register in
 California as sex offenders. ..... www.meganslaw.ca.gov 


 12/14/04 
 Supervisors
 Approve Permit Parking 
 
The County Board of Supervisors approved an ordinance implementing a &quot;Permit Parking&quot; program on specific streets in the Tree Lake area that are within about 10 minutes walking time from the Granite Bay High School. Parking Permits will be required to be displayed in any vehicle parking on the affected streets from 7 to 10 A.M. and from 1 to 3 P.M. on days when school is in session. The program is projected to become effective 14 Jan 05.


 12/14/04 
 Granite Bay Marshland to be Preserved 
 
Placer County Supervisors approved a &quot;Resolution of Intent&quot; to preserve, in perpetuity, the emergent marshland located across Douglas Blvd. from the Lutheran Church.


 12/2/04 
 MAC
 Recommends Approval of 32 lot Development 
 
Despite emotional concerns of neighbors, the MAC recommended approval of a 32 lot development on 31.8 acres at the southwest corner of Olive Ranch Rd. and Berg St.  County staff indicated they were supporting the proposal because it was in compliance with the Community Plan. The MAC also recommended consideration of traffic calming measures on neighboring streets to discourage through traffic and help control speed.

Information items presented to the MAC included a proposal for a 43 unit adult, age restricted community located on a 12-acre parcel, next to Oakhills and Ridgeview Schools. The proposal received support from realtors and friends of the developer, but neighbors and community members expressed concern about non compliance with the community plan and the proposed 700% increase in density.

A proposal for a Car Wash and Auto Lube to be located on property behind the existing Walgreen store on Douglas Blvd. received generally positive comments


 11/29/04 
 MAC
 Parks Committee Meeting is Canceled 
 
The MAC Parks Committee meeting originally scheduled for Dec. 1 has been cancelled. The next meeting of the committee will be 5 Jan 05.


 11/22/04 
 MAC to Take Action on Berg St. Development 
 
The Granite Bay MAC is scheduled to take action on a 32 lot planned residential community proposed on 31.8 acres located at the southwest corner of Olive Ranch Rd. and Berg St. Information items on the agenda include a proposal for an active adult, age restricted community located on a 12-acre parcel, next to Oakhills and Ridgeview Schools, and a proposal for a Car Wash and Auto Lube located on undeveloped property behind the existing Walgreen store on Douglas Blvd.


 11/11/04 
 Fire District Hires a New Fire Marshall 
 
Fire Chief Tony Corado has announced that the South Placer Fire District has selected Capt. Lawrence Bettencourt to be the new Fire Marshal for the District. Capt. Bettencourt is presently a Station Captain at Station 3 and will assume his new duties 13 Nov. 


 11/10/04 
 Ron Feist Park
 Donations Mount 
 
Donations for the Ron Feist Park continue to mount and construction on three ball fields continues weather permitting. Cash donations received to date total over $220,000, and local contractors and businesses have contributed nearly $120,000 in time materials and equipment for the park. In addition nearly $175,000 in time, material and equipment have been pledged for restrooms, snack bar, parking lots and a picnic pavilion. The High School District has pledged to build tennis courts valued at $300,000. This is all good news, but there is a long way to go to finish the north side of the park and a funding source for the south side soccer fields hasn&apos;t even been identified.


 11/4/04 
 MAC Struggles With Parking and Traffic Issues 
 
Permit Parking in the area around the Granite Bay High School was the focus of considerable debate as the MAC struggled to reach a decision on the issue. In the end, the MAC encouraged the high school, the County and the East Roseville Bible Church to finalize an agreement, to permit parking for over 100 cars on the church&apos;s property next to the fire station near the school. Additionally, they recommended the County proceed with establishing permit parking basically as was recommended by the transportation sub-committee.

On a second issue, the MAC failed to take an action on a 32 lot sub division on Berg St. indicating there were too many unanswered questions relating to traffic issues and requested the developer and County staff return in December with further information.


 11/3/04 
 Citizens
 Reject Firefighters Slate of Candidates 
 
In yesterdays election, voters in the South Placer Fire District appear to have rejected the Firefighter Union&apos;s effort to elect candidates, that were more sympathetic to their cause, to the Districts Board of Directors. With all but an unknown number of absentee and provisional ballots counted, Dave Giblin, Gary Grenfell, and Jeff Moss, are the top 3 vote getters.


 11/3/04 
 Other Local Election
 Results 
 
In the San Juan Water District Ken Miller and Pam Tobin are the top two vote getters.
In the Roseville High School District, R. Jan Pinney, Garry Genzlinger, and Paige Stauss are the top three vote getters.
Roseville High School District&apos;s Measure J passed with 59% approving the measure
Mike Lee won re-election to the Placer County Water Agency


 10/28/04 
 Parking
 Issues and New Development at
 November MAC  
 
Permit Parking in the area around the Granite Bay High School as well as a 32 lot subdivision on Berg St. will be the action items.

A proposed 17 lot subdivision located south of the existing Eden Roc subdivision and a project at the north/east corner of Sierra College Blvd. and Eureka Rd. consisting of a wine country style quaint village including a 60 room hotel will be presented as information items.


 10/22/04 
 Placer Republicans Endorse Fire District Candidates 
 
The Placer County Republican Party has announced it&apos;s endorsement of Jeff Moss, David Giblin and Anita Wright for election to the South Placer Fire District Board of Directors.


 10/18/04 
 Congressman Endorses Fire District Candidates 
 
Congressman John Doolittle announced today that he is endorsing Jeff Moss, David Giblin and Gregary Grenfell for election to the South Placer Fire District Board of Directors.


 10/15/04 
 Sub-Committee Recommends Permit Parking 
 
The MAC Transportation Committee will recommend the MAC request the County implement Permit Parking in an area within about 10 minutes walking time from the Granite Bay High School. The area includes a portion of the Tree Lake area and Eureka Rd. Parking Permits would be required to be displayed in any vehicle parking on the affected streets Monday through Friday, from 7 to 9 A.M. and from 1 to 3 P.M., from 15 August through 15 June. The issue will be discussed at the November 3 MAC meeting.


 10/8/04 
 MAC Transportation Sub-Committee Meeting 
 
The MAC Transportation Sub-Committee will meet Wednesday October 13 at 6:30 p.m. in the Eureka School Library at 5477 Eureka Rd. The purpose of the meeting is to develop a recommendation, for the MAC to consider, regarding mitigation of parking impacts from high school students in the Tree Lake area.


 10/7/04 
 MAC Hears Plethora of Issues 
 
MAC sifted through 6 major issues in a 3 1/2 hour long session last evening, ultimately providing comments and direction on some issues and recommendations of approval for others. 1. MAC recommended approval of a concept presented by the Community Association and County staff to preserve the emergent marshland across from the Lutheran Church on Douglas Blvd. in perpetuity.
2. After input from the High School, the County and residents of Tree Lake, the student parking issue near the school was referred to the MAC Transportation Committee to develop a recommendation.
3. The lighting plan for the Quarry Pond commercial center south of Douglas Blvd. near Berg St. was recommended for approval.
4. Comments to County staff concerning the design of the proposed replacement bridge on Barton Road included excessive width, length and height.
5. Positive feedback was provided for the conceptual plan of a proposed church on 75 acres at the top of the hill on Sierra College Blvd.
6. MAC expressed concern that the size of the parcel south of Douglas Blvd. across from Bushnell Nursery would not accommodate a proposed car wash and small retail center. 


 10/5/04 
 Dr. Ron Feist Endorses Fire District Candidates 
 
Dr.
 Ron Feist, recently retired Eureka Union School District Superintendent and
 a current board member of the South Placer Fire District, announced
 today that he is endorsing Jeff Moss, David Giblin and Gregary Grenfell for
 election to the South Placer Fire District Board of Directors.


 9/29/04 
 Ted
 Gaines Expresses Concern For Our Fire District 
 
In a letter endorsing Jeff Moss, David Giblin and Gregary Grenfell for election to the South Placer Fire District Board of Directors, Placer County Supervisor Ted Gaines, expressed concern about the future of our fire protection and ambulance service in South Placer County. His letter indicates a special interest group has their sights set on our Fire District because they see an opportunity for both a labor union takeover of the Board and potentially the consolidation of the South Placer Fire District with the Sacramento Metro Fire District.


 9/29/04 
 Learn More About Water Meters 
 
San Juan Water District, General Manager Shauna Lorance will discuss meters and metered rates at a public workshop on Thursday, October 14 at 6 p.m. The workshop will take place in the district’s board room at 9935 Auburn-Folsom Road. For more information, please call (916) 791-0115.


 9/23/04 
 Sacramento Bee Endorses Fire Candidates 
 
Citing potential conflict of interest with the slate of three candidates that are employed by Sac Metro Fire, the Bee has endorsed Jeff Moss, David Giblin and Gregary Grenfell for the South Placer Fire District. Indicating that they believe these candidates we be independent, and that they will watch out for employees, for taxpayers and for the safety of the public.


 9/15/04 
 Identity Theft Seminar Tuesday September 28 
 
The
 On
 Tuesday Sept 28 the Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Office will present an
 Identity Theft Seminar from 7:00-9:00 pm in the Ridgeview Elementary
 School multi-purpose room (9177 Twin School Road, Granite
 Bay). The seminar will help you protect yourself against the
 fastest growing crime in America. The presentation will
 address issues such as safeguarding your identity, avoiding becoming
 a victim, how criminals obtain information, and what to do if you
 become a victim. Detectives Jim Hudson and Alfredo Guitron,
 identity theft experts, will present the seminar. Call
 791-5884 for reservations (refer to Identity Theft Seminar).


 9/2/04 
 MAC Approves Quarry Pond Project 
 
On Wednesday 9/2 the MAC approved a redesign of the Quarry Pond shopping complex proposed south of Douglas at Berg Street. The Council withheld approval of the lighting plan until more information is available. The near standing room only audience also heard information on Lyme Disease and the West Nile Virus from County Medical staff. More information on both is available (..... Lyme ,
 ... West
 Nile ). Other information items were heard as listed in the agenda item
 below.


 8/27/04 
 West Nile Virus Found in Granite Bay 
 
Placer County officials indicate a dead bird, (an American Kestrel) found in Granite Bay 11 August has tested positive for the West Nile Virus. County officials say the most important thing residents should do, is to protect themselves from being bitten by mosquitoes. .....more 


 8/26/04 
 September 1 MAC has a Full Agenda 
 
Issues
 to be presented to the MAC include:
- a presentation on Lyme Disease&amp;West Nile Virus
- a proposal to preserve a marshland in the heart of Granite Bay
- the history of Placer County Agriculture and PlacerGrown.
- a proposed 32 lot residential project at the corner of Olive Ranch Rd and Berg St.
- a proposed church on 75 acres located on Sierra College Blvd.
- the proposed development of 4 one-story commercial buildings to replace the existing boat storage on Douglas Blvd. at Berg St.


 8/5/04 
 Hardware Store Set to Open 
 
Several years ago, we had 3 hardware stores at the same time, then 2, then 1 then none for the past few years. Now, Granite Bay Ace Hardware is set to open its new store in the Granite Bay Village Shopping Center on Auburn Folsom Rd. The new store will open its doors August 17 and will celebrate its grand opening the weekend of August 27. Store hours will be 7 am to 8 pm weekdays, 7 am to 7 pm Saturdays and 8 am to 6 pm Sundays.


 7/28/04 
 August MAC Meeting is
 Canceled 
 
The regularly scheduled meeting of the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC) for Wednesday, August 4, 2004 has been CANCELED. The next regularly scheduled meeting of the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council will be Wednesday, September 1, 2004.

 (NOTE) The Parks sub-committee will hold its regular meeting at 5 pm.


 7/27/04 
 Workshop
 Scheduled for Barton Rd. Bridge Replacement 
 
Placer County Public Works Dept. will hold a public workshop Thursday, August 5th, from 4 to 7:30 pm at the Eureka School Library to discuss the design and construction process of a new bridge to replace the old bridge on Barton Rd. where it crosses Miners Ravine. For further information you may contact Sherri Berexa at 530-889-7546.


 7/27/04 
 Lot
 Splits to Create Eight Lots 
 
The
 Placer County Parcel Review Committee will review requests from
 property owners to split 2 parcels totaling 40 acres into 8 lots all
 greater than 2.3 acres. The parcels are located south of the
 existing Boat Storage facility on Douglas Blvd about 500 feet west
 of Barton Rd. The hearing will be July 28th at 9:30 am in the
 Planning Commission Hearing Room in Auburn.


 7/24/04 
 Granite Bay&apos;s
 Community Park Grand Opening 
 
After 16 years of waiting, planning, and frustration, Granite Bay has a Community Park. Placer County Parks Div. with Supervisor Ted Gaines acting as master of ceremonies celebrated the Grand Opening of the new park located at the southeast corner of Douglas Blvd. and Barton Rd. by unveiling a wall of honor dedicated to those who were instrumental in creating the park. The park has 2 ball fields, 2 soccer fields, 2 tot lots, and a picnic area with BBQs.


 7/9/04 
 MAC Accepts Site Design, Rejects Building Design 
 
Plans for a new retail center &quot;Quarry Pond&quot; to replace the existing boat storage facility on the south side of Douglas Blvd. at Berg St. were reviewed by the MAC Wednesday. The MAC and the public generally agreed the site layout was very nice, but all seemed to reject the proposed building design as being too urban, or too industrial like. The consensus seemed to urge a building design that will provide a much more village or rural residential look, with some timbers and hip rooflines.


 7/9/04 
 Another Wireless Antenna is Proposed 
 
AT&amp;T;Wireless is proposing a 70 foot tall antenna disguised as a tree at the fire station on Auburn-Folsom Rd. to improve service in that area. The MAC and the public alike were very concerned about the appearance of the site, and urged the applicant to include significant landscaping to shield the equipment from view.


 7/9/04 
 High School Accused of Inadequate Parking Policy 
 
Repeated complaints from residents, about student behavior and student parking on the streets around the Granite Bay High School, led the MAC to initiate a letter to the School District Trustees urging the District to take an aggressive pro-active approach to solving the problem. The MAC accused the High School School District of failing to adequately address the issue and encouraged them to seek a solution to the problem internally by mitigating the issue on campus.

 6/28/04 
 ALL
 FIREWORKS ARE ILLEGAL IN GRANITE BAY 
 
A
 reminder, that all fireworks are illegal in unincorporated Placer
 County including Granite Bay. No fireworks of any kind are permitted
 including those labeled safe and sane, no sparklers, nothing. Citations
 will be issued to violators and it will be hazardous to your wealth.


 6/23/04 
 Help
 Wanted at the Fire District 
 
The South Placer Fire District is looking to fill its vacant Fire Marshals position. The District is accepting applications for the position until 5:00 p.m. August 27, 2004. The selection process is tentatively scheduled for the week of September 20, 2004. If you would like additional information or the full four page announcement, please call Debra Frick (916) 791-7059 or go to www.southplacerfire.org .


 6/22/04 
 Board Approves Auburn Folsom Widening Plan 
 
The
 Board of Supervisors approved the staff recommendations to widen
 Auburn Folsom Rd to four lanes. The project will be completed in
 phases as financing is available. The first phase will include a new
 signal at Fuller Dr., the construction of 4 lanes south of Douglas
 Blvd. to about 1500 ft south of Eureka Rd. and the acquisition
 of right of way for the whole project. The second and third
 phases will not be constructed until financing from other than local
 funds become available. The new signal at Fuller will be installed
 in 2005 and the remainder of phase one is targeted to be complete in
 2006.


 6/18/04 
 Another Bond Measure Planned by High School District 
 
This
 summer’s Roseville Joint Union High School District&apos;s construction
 projects will not fully address the needs of the rapidly growing
 student population according to the District&apos;s Superintendent. He indicates two new schools are needed to accommodate future
 students and for this reason the Board of Trustees plans to place
 yet another Bond Measure on the Nov. 2004 ballot, to fund
 construction of new schools and pay for the continued renovation of
 existing facilities and technology. .....more 


 6/18/04 
 Family Living History Day 
 
Do you wonder what it was like to live in Placer County a century ago? You can step back in time and experience the daily lifestyle of the 1800s on Sunday 27 June from 2 to 5 pm. at the Bernhard Museum, 291 Auburn-Folsom Rd, in Auburn. Follow in the steps of the pioneers. Bake biscuits on a wood burning stove. Do laundry the old fashioned way.

Family Living History Day is an ideal way for children to learn and have fun with their parents, or grandparents. Family Living History Day is free, but space is limited, please call ahead to make reservations (530) 889-6500. Come in costume, if you wish!


 6/17/04 
 Fire District to Establish a Strategic Planning Team 
 
The South Placer Fire District is in the process of developing a Strategic Plan for the operations of the District. The membership of the Strategic Planning Team will include various employees of the district from all classifications and two (2) community members. If you are interested in participating, please submit a letter explaining your interest in participating in our strategic planning process to Jim Wenzel, Assistant Fire Chief, South Placer Fire District, 6900 Eureka Road, Granite Bay , CA 95746


 6/17/04 
 Fire District Presents Preliminary Budget 
 
The South Placer Fire District Board adopted a $6.5 million preliminary budget for the 04-05 fiscal year, representing a very slight 0.3% reduction from last years budget. The reduction is due to significant cuts in Capital and Mitigation expenditures, but operational expenditures, including salaries and benefits, are proposed to increase by over 5%.

The Board also authorized the collection of a Special Tax of $70 per parcel (that will yield $640,000) even though the District had nearly $1 million in the prior year fund balance. Comments from the public urging the Board to return the excess revenue to the taxpayers went without action.


 6/10/04 
 CDF Suspends Residential and Campfire Burn Permits 
 
As of Monday June 7, 2004 the California Department of Forestry and Fire Protection (CDF) is on fire season status. Fire season means that burn permits are suspended and campfire permits may be suspended in certain locations due to the high fire danger. Anyone considering burning debris or lighting a campfire should check with local fire authorities first.


 6/10/04 
 Supervisors to Hear Auburn Folsom Rd. Project 
 
A public hearing will be held Tuesday, June 22, at 1:30 pm in the Board Chambers in Auburn to consider the Auburn Folsom Rd. widening project. Staff will seek approval of the EIR, Project Description, the funding and phasing plan, and will seek permission to go to bid for a signal at Fuller Dr. and Auburn Folsom Rd. Interested persons are invited to attend the hearing or submit their comments in writing to the Clerk of the Board prior to the hearing date.


 6/3/04 
 MAC Supports Phased Road Improvement 
 
The MAC unanimously recommended approval of the County&apos;s latest recommendation for the phasing of Auburn Folsom Rd. improvements. Due to the absence of regional funding and the unwillingness of the community to mortgage the entire community traffic mitigation fund to finance the $21.4 million project. The latest proposal outlines a 3 phase project. The first phase, at a cost of about $7.2 million, focuses on acquiring all the right of way, installing a signal at Fuller Drive and extending 4 traffic lanes with landscaping to about 1500 ft south of Eureka Rd. Construction of the improvements at Fuller Dr. could begin in the spring of 2005. The second and third phases of the planned improvements would be implemented only as financial resources from other than local sources become available.


 6/2/04 
 Environmental Disaster on Linda Creek 
 
Describing it as an environmental disaster, Placer County officials have stopped the owner of the property at the southwest corner of Fuller Dr. and Auburn Folsom Rd. from cutting trees and grading in and around Linda Creek without permits. The owner likely will be cited for his actions that blocked Linda Creek and destroyed a riparian area about 800 feet long. The area of disturbance is reported to be at least 5 acres. State and Federal authorities have also been notified.


 5/27/04 
 Commission Approves Shopping Center Modifications 
 
The Planning Commission approved the addition of three 3 new buildings, totaling about 8000 sq. ft., with landscaping at the south end of the Granite Bay Village Shopping Center near Fuller Dr. The proposal plans to move the Fuller Dr. entrance to the Center a little east to enable diagonal parking directly in front of the post office. A landscaped center median in front of the post office will have postal drop boxes. This modification along with the improvements being made on the rest of the center including a new hardware store, are aimed at rejuvenating the center.


 5/23/04 
 School District Renames Park In Honor of Ron Feist 
 
Community leaders, school officials, teachers, friends, and family honored Dr. Ron Feist at his retirement dinner 22 May. The evening of presentations and testimonials was topped off with a standing ovation when Dan Clift of the Eureka School Board presented Ron with an artist rendering of the park formerly known as Twin Schools Park and declared that it would henceforth be known as the Ronald L. Feist Park. Dr Feist is credited for accepting the donated parcel, that is presently under construction at the corner of Elmhurst Dr. and Twin Schools Rd. for the school district and the community and for leading the way in the design and construction of the park.


 5/20/04 
 Fire District Not Interested in Contracting with Roseville 
 
Citing the high quality of existing service, especially the medical service, and the absence of a community mandate to make any changes to the service being provided, the senior members of the Fire Board (Feist, Giblin, and Grenfell) rejected a proposal to look at contracting fire services to Roseville&apos;s Fire Dept. The issue, presented by the two board members presently employed by the same Sacramento based Fire Dept. that unsuccessfully attempted to take over the Dry Creek Fire Dept., was supported by the local firefighters union members but was vehemently opposed by community members in the audience.  Citizens and a board member alike, criticized the two board members for their behind the back contact with the Roseville Dept. without the consent of the entire board and questioned what their apparent hidden agenda might be.


 5/11/04 
 Water District to Celebrate 150 Years of Service 
 
San Juan Water District will celebrate 150 years of service on Saturday, May 22, from 10 a.m. to 1 p.m. at the District Office, 9935 Auburn-Folsom Rd. Bring the family to enjoy the free event that will feature the &quot;Ghost of Mark Twain&quot;, the grand opening of the newly renovated water efficient landscape garden, giveaways, displays and refreshments.


 5/6/04 
 MAC Recommends Approval of Four Projects 
 
At it&apos;s meeting 5 May the MAC recommended approval of the four projects presented for action.

 Granite Bay Village Shopping Center/South - Recommended approval of three 3 new buildings at the south end of the center near Fuller, with a stipulation that the applicant return for a review of the buildings design and landscaping.
 Seymour Ranch - Recommended approval of a 17-lot subdivision located on Cavitt Stallman South north of Douglas Blvd. as presented.
 Creekside Church - Recommended approval of construction of the church facility east of Sierra College Blvd. south of Old Auburn Rd. as presented.
 Dunmore Offices – Recommended approval of plans for 3 office buildings located at 8781 Sierra College Blvd. with a stipulation that light poles be no more than 16 ft with 250 watt lights and that landscaping be installed on the east and northern boundaries.

Additionally, proponents of a Kindergarten and Preschool on Old Auburn Rd. were asked to return after they have a pre-development meeting with County Planning staff.

Although it was not a formal action, the community and the MAC were in agreement that there should not be a signal light installed at Berg St. and Douglas Blvd. when the project to replace the old buildings at the boat storage facility is constructed. Community comments favored construction of median dividers on Douglas Blvd. that would prevent left turns from Berg St. or from the commercial property onto Douglas.


 4/28/04 
 Sheriff&apos;s Dept. Hosts 2nd Karen Johnson Memorial Run 
 
The
 Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Department is hosting its second annual
 Karen Johnson Memorial D.A.R.E. Run at the Sierra College track in
 Rocklin on Saturday, May 15, 2004 beginning at 8 a.m. The fundraising event, called the
 D.A.R.E. Fun Run in its first three years, was renamed in honor of
 Deputy Johnson who died in 2003. She was a D.A.R.E. officer and an
 avid runner who organized the Fun Run each year. Runners may request
 a registration form by calling (916) 791-5884 or click here to register online.


 4/22/04 
 Fire Board Members Suggest Contracting Fire Services 
 
n what some citizens described as yet another example of micro management of the District by two of the Fire Districts Board members (both are also members of a Sacramento fire fighters union), the directors have suggested exploring the concept of contracting fire services at the South Placer District to the City of Roseville. The board members, without approval of the entire board, met with officials of Roseville&apos;s Fire Dept. to explore options. Their action has put a hold on filling several vacant staff positions that were previously authorized.

Citizens have expressed concern that the micro management by the board and the failure to fill the positions has placed the Chief in an untenable position that could affect the quality of emergency service being provided in the District. The subject will be on the 19 May agenda.


 4/22/04 
 Local Coffee House Closes 
 
Higley&apos;s Coffee House, a fixture in the old Whispering Pines Steakhouse building on Auburn Folsom Rd. for the past several years has closed it&apos;s doors for the last time. The facility will now be used as a meeting place for youth and adult events of The Rock of Granite Bay congregation.


 4/21/04 
 Superior Court is Seeking Grand Jury Applicants 
 
Placer County Superior Court is soliciting applications from county
 residents to serve on the 2004-2005 County Grand Jury. The deadline
 for applications is 5 pm Friday May 21. Applications are available
 by contacting the Executive Officer at 530-889-7404 or on line at www.placercourts.org .


 4/21/04 
 Supervisors Approve New Justice Center 
 
County Supervisors have approved construction of a new South Placer Justice Center. The center will be located on Industrial Blvd. between Roseville and Lincoln. The first phase will cost $49 million and will include a courthouse. Other facilities to supports the courts will be added over a 20 year plan as finances become available.


 4/21/04 
 GB
 Press Tribune Will Donate to Parks Again 
 
The
 Granite Bay Edition of the Press Tribune will once again donate $14
 from each new subscription toward construction of the new Twin
 Schools Park. This offer is now valid for both new and renewal
 subscriptions. The paper has already donated nearly $2000 to the
 park.  .....subscribe 


 4/9/04 
 MAC Transportation Committee to Meet 
 
The MAC Transportation Committee will meet 13 Apr. at 5:00 pm in the south portable building at the Fire Station on Eureka Rd. The committee will be considering new options and alternatives for financing and implementing the Auburn Folsom Rd. widening project.


 4/7/04 
 Water District to Sponsor Drip Irrigation Class 
 
The San Juan Water District will hold a free drip irrigation class designed to teach the basics of installing, operating and maintaining a drip irrigation system. The class will be instructed by UC Master Gardeners, Saturday, April 17, from 9 a.m. to noon at the San Juan Water District offices, 9935 Auburn-Folsom Road.


 4/5/04 
 Open House For Dam Road Environmental Impact Analysis 
 
The Bureau of Reclamation will hold two open houses to receive public comments on the environmental impact analysis to be prepared on the impacts of closing Folsom Dam Road.  Alternatives to be studied in the EIS include: the proposed permanent restriction of public access; ending the indefinite road closure at a yet to be determined time; reopening the road on a partial basis, and a no action alternative that would reopen the road to the level of access in place before the February 2003 closure. Public open houses are scheduled for Sacramento and Folsom to obtain comments on alternatives and the significant issues and impacts related to the proposed action.


 3/29/04 
 April MAC to Review Proposed New Subdivision 
 
The
 Advisory Council is scheduled to review a proposal to create a new subdivision
 called&quot;Terracina&quot;at its 7 April meeting. The
 project is proposed to consist of 17 residential lots and 4 common
 lots and is located on the east side of Laird Rd. about 1/2
 mile north of Cavitt Stallman Rd.


 3/25/04 
 Water District Selects New Assistant Manager 
 
The
 San Juan Water District has selected Keith Durkin as their new
 assistant general manager. Durkin, a professional
 engineer and vice president of Kennedy Jenks Consultants, Inc.
 assumed his new duties March 22. He has more than 20
 years experience in engineering planning and design, project
 and program management, in addition to corporate
 management. His duties will include overseeing
 management of the district’s capital improvement projects,
 and he will help manage the district’s transition to metered
 rates next year.


 3/24/04 
 24th Annual Easter Egg Hunt April 3rd. 
 
Granite Bay&apos;s 24th Annual Easter Egg Hunt will take place Saturday, April 3 at Cavitt Jr. High School. There will be a pancake breakfast at 7 am followed by fingerprinting, arts and crafts, fire truck display, music, Easter basket raffle, balloon twisting and of course the Easter Bunny will be there. The Hunt will start promptly at 10:00 am.


 3/20/04 
 Checkpoint Finds Designated Drivers, No Arrests 
 
The first CHP sobriety checkpoint of the year was setup on Douglas Blvd. between Joe Rodgers Rd. and Barton Rd. on St. Patrick&apos;s Day evening. Officers screened over 600 cars between 8 pm and midnight. Eleven sobriety tests were administered but no arrests were made. Only a few citations for various driving infractions were issued.


 3/18/04 
 Fund Raiser to Honor Ron Feist Will Benefit Park 
 
A fund raising event called &quot;Raising the Roof for Ron&quot; is hoping to raise $70,000 for the Twin Schools Park by selling 4, 6, and 12 inch tiles for $100, $250, or $1000 to honor Dr. Ron Feist&apos;s efforts in helping to shape our community. The tiles will be engraved with special messages or the donors name and used in the construction of the park. Checks should be made payable to Eureka School District/Twin Schools Park and may be mailed to E.U.S.D. Raise the Roof, 5455 Eureka Rd., Granite Bay, CA 95746.


 3/10/04 
 Board Review of Auburn-Folsom Widening Postponed 
 
The Board of Supervisors will not consider the Auburn Folsom Road widening project March 23, as originally planned. At the request of Supervisor Gaines, consideration of the project is being delayed to allow more time to explore additional funding from regional bodies. Traffic studies have determined that 63% of the future growth in traffic on the road will be attributed to commuter traffic from out side the community. Yet the primary funding source proposed for the project is from the Granite Bay Traffic Mitigation Fee Program, which is supported by new development fees. Construction of the Auburn Folsom Road project may exhaust this fund, making it difficult to fund other future local road projects in the Granite Bay area.


 3/10/04 
 San Juan Water Board Selects Interim Director 
 
The San Juan Water District Board of Directors has selected an interim director to fill a seat left vacant when board member Lyle Hoag retired in December. Dave Peterson of Granite Bay, who has 20 years experience in water resources, was selected from a group of six candidates to serve the remainder of Hoag’s term, which expires in November 2006. Peterson joins Dorothy Kilgore and Joe Alessandri, the newly elected president and vice president of the board, and directors Ted Costa and Kenneth Miller.


 3/5/04 
 Bayside Church to Hold First Services in New Home 
 
After 7 years in the planning, a couple years of legal wrangling and nearly 2 years in the construction process, workmen at the new Bayside Church at the corner of Cavitt-Stallman Rd. and Sierra College Blvd. continue to apply the finishing touches in preparation for the first services in the new facility Sunday 7 March. Their Grand Opening is scheduled for the weekend of March 20 and 21.


 3/4/04 
 MAC Rejects Approval of Road Widening Plan Again 
 
The Granite Bay MAC rejected County staff&apos;s proposal for widening Auburn-Folsom Rd. for the second time Wednesday evening. MAC members and the public alike cited significant disagreement with the staff&apos;s funding plan, that would leave the community with no funds in the traffic mitigation account for the next 20 years. MAC members and the Community suggested that since 70% of the projected traffic would be commuters passing through our community, the adjacent communities should help fund the improvements. The MAC voted 4 to 1 to not recommend approval of the plan.


 3/2/04 
 Public Workshop Scheduled for New Folsom Dam Bridge 
 
The
 US Army Corp of Engineers will host a workshop at Eureka School
 Multi-Purpose Room Wednesday 10 Mar. from 4:30 to 7:30 pm to take comments from
 the public relating to subjects the environmental studies need to
 address prior to construction of a new bridge at the dam. If
 you have a concern about impacts from the bridge proposed below the
 dam, you should attend the workshop and let the Corps know your
 concerns.


 2/25/04 
 Ground Broken for Twin Schools Park 
 
Ground Breaking ceremonies were held at the park site 25 Feb. to officially tip off construction of the park. Supervisor Ted Gaines addressed the gathering citing numerous community groups and individuals for their efforts to bring this park site to fruition. Not least of all Dr. Ron Feist who along with the School District Board had the vision to accept the property for a park site when it was offered.


 2/25/04 
 MAC to Hear Latest on Auburn-Folsom Widening 
 
The 7 pm 3 March MAC meeting will hear the latest information about the widening of Auburn-Folsom Rd. and will receive a brief introduction to Digital Path Network, a high-speed wireless Internet service provider. Additionally, Bank of America will present a proposal for a stand alone sign for Bank of America.


 2/19/04 
 Press Tribune to Help Fund Twin Schools Park 
 
The Granite Bay Edition of the Press Tribune will once again donate $14 from each new subscription toward construction of the new Twin Schools Park. The promotion will run for the rest of the year. They also hope to do a mailing to non-subscribers in mid March wherein they will donate the entire $34 for those who respond during a two week window. The paper has already donated nearly $2000 to the park.


 1/28/04 
 You are Invited to the Twin Schools Park Ground Breaking 
 
A ground breaking ceremony will be held for the new Twin Schools Park on February 25 at 4:30 p.m. The festivities are open to the public. The park is on Twin Schools Road, between Oakhills Elementary School and Granite Bay High School.


 1/28/04 
 MAC&apos;s February Meeting is Cancelled 
 
The regularly scheduled meeting of the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC) for Wednesday, February 4, 2004 has been CANCELED. The next regularly scheduled meeting of the MAC will occur on Wednesday, March 3, 2004.


 1/27/04 
 Meet the Candidates Running for Placer County Superior Court 
 
Candidates for Judge of the Placer County Superior Court will present their views and respond to questions at a forum sponsored by Placer County Grand Jurors Association on Monday, February 9, 1:00 PM., in the Rocklin Library community room at 5460 5th St., Rocklin.  Colleen Nichols, and Frank Rowley are running for Judge in Office I. Jeffrey Penney and Kevin Burdick are the candidates for Office 2. The public is invited to attend the forum.

 1/24/04 
 You are Invited to the Placer County Blueprint Workshop 
 
What will life be like for your children and grandchildren? Where will they live and play? How long will it take them to get to work? If these questions concern you, then come to the Placer County Blueprint workshop and put your fingerprint on the new blueprint of our county. The workshop will give you the opportunity to view and discuss maps depicting potential changes in our region over the next 50 years, make changes to suit you, and learn how those changes will affect air quality, traffic congestion, housing and the economy. The workshop will be Saturday, January 31, 8:30 am to noon at the Maidu Community Center, 1550 Maidu Drive, Roseville.  Please RSVP either online at www.sacregionblueprint.org 


 1/20/04 
 High School District Considers Another Bond Measure 
 
Indicating that developers are paying only approximately fifty percent of the cost for constructing new facilities necessitated as a result of the addition of new homes, and citing continued rapid growth in the west Roseville area and overcrowded classrooms, the Superintendent indicates the District may seek another bond measure on the November ballot. Depending upon the outcome of the March election, the Board will confirm if a district wide local school bond measure will be pursued, and how much funding should be requested later this spring.


 1/15/04 
 Secretary Needed for the Granite Bay MAC 
 
The Board of Supervisors is looking to fill the Secretary position for the Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council (MAC). The MAC meets one evening per month, normally the first Wednesday. The position entails mailing out the agendas, taking minutes and other related duties. The applicant must provide their own transportation and reside in Granite Bay. The position pays $100 per meeting and is considered voluntary. The MAC is a great way to get involved in the community. For more information, please contact Melanie Eustice, Placer County Board of Supervisors, (916) 787-8950.


 1/14/04 
 Seniors Commission Presents Issues to the Candidates 
 
The Placer County Commission on Ageing held a forum presenting Pam Tobin, a candidate for the 4th District County Supervisors seat, with four major issues for seniors. The issues discussed included Transportation for seniors, Senior Housing, Home Services for seniors and seniors access to information.  Supervisor Ted Gaines was unfortunately unable to be present due to a conflict in his schedule.


 1/13/04 
 Park Task Force Working to Reduce Park Costs 
 
The Twin Schools Park Task Force headed by Phil Johnson is working to develop a Community Volunteer Partnership with the County, School District, local contractors, developers, business organizations, families, service and athletic organizations. The goal of the partnership is to reduce the cost of constructing the Twin Schools Park from the estimated $2.3 million to less than $1 million through volunteered labor and materials.


 1/11/04 
 Rotary to Sponsor Crab Feed to Benefit Parks 
 
Granite Bay Rotary is having a crab feed Saturday January 31 at the Placer Fair Grounds in Roseville. The social hour will begin at 6:30 pm and dinner is at 7:30 pm. There will be dancing and a raffle with lots of prizes. Tickets are only $35.00 each. For details call Mike Baker at 791-4241 or Mike Wilson at 791-3596. Proceeds will go toward purchasing equipment and facilities for parks in Granite Bay.


 1/9/04 
 Items Recommended for Approval by MAC 
 
At it&apos;s Jan 7 meeting the MAC, recommended approval of Measure E, which is a $394 million bond measure for Sierra College on the March 2004 ballot. If approved by voters, the bond will cost homeowners $19 for every $100,000 of assessed value annually.

Additionally, the MAC recommended approval of a request for a stop sign on Barton Road at East Roseville Parkway.

Plans for modification of the south end of Granite Bay Village Shopping Center (the area near the Post Office) that includes three new buildings and landscape modifications received very positive comments from the Council and from the public.


 1/1/04 
 Burn Barrels and Burning Paper and Cardboard Prohibited 
 
Beginning January 1, 2004, the use of a burn barrel and the burning of paper and cardboard will be prohibited in Placer County by a new state law aimed at protecting community health. The California Air Resources Board approved a statewide measure to reduce emissions of dioxins and other toxics from outdoor residential waste burning. While Placer County regulations have prohibited trash burning since 1974, that ban now extends to the use of a burn barrel for any burning and makes burning paper or cardboard illegal.


 
 2003 
 12/18/03 
 Fire District Approves Ordinance Regulating Open Burning 
 
The Directors of the South Placer Fire District approved an Open Burning Ordinance Wednesday night. The Ordinance imposes a requirement for a permit year round for open burning and provides specific guidance for the burning of yard waste. It is applicable to all areas within the Fire District boundaries encompassed by the 95661 and 95746 Zip codes and will become effective 1 February 2004. The Directors further directed the boundaries of the Ordinance be broadened in the future to include all of the Fire District.


 12/10/03 
 Eureka Union School District Superintendent to Retire 
 
Dr. Ron Feist, Superintendent of the Eureka Union School District for the last 22 years, officially presented his retirement plans to the School District&apos;s Board of Trustees at their meeting 9 Dec. He plans to retire at the end of June after a 38 year career in education.  Bob Schultz, the current Assistant Superintendent of Curriculum and Instruction for the District has been named to succeed Dr. Feist.

 12/4/03 
 MAC Recommends Approval of Three Proposals 
 
The MAC recommended approval of a proposed commercial office building on Douglas Blvd. between Barton and Joe Rodgers Rd.. They also supported the Fire District&apos;s request to adjust the boundaries of the recently established burn policies to include all of the 95746 Zip code area along with the unincorporated area of the 95661 zip code area and further supported broadening the boundaries to include all of the Fire District in the future. Additionally, the MAC recommended approval of a pilot program for fire hazard abatement in the community.


 12/4/03 
 Two From Granite Bay Receive &quot;Placer County Hero&quot; Award 
 
The Board of Supervisors awarded Kathie Marynik and Sam Malhotra &quot;Placer County Hero&quot; commemorative coins. Kathie was honored for volunteering 2,300 hours at the Placer County Sheriff&apos;s Department&apos;s substation in Granite Bay and for her volunteer efforts as the Web master for Granite Bay High School&apos;s Web site. Sam is the owner of Lakeside Beverages in Granite Bay and was honored for his work with the poor. For 13 years he has sponsored wine tasting events, which have raised more than $48,000 for various charities in the community. Our congratulations go to both.


 12/4/03 
 MAC Member Covington Resigns 
 
Saskia Covington has submitted her resignation from the MAC leaving a vacancy to be filled. Supervisor Gaines indicated applications are being accepted to fill the position. Applications should be submitted to the Clerk of the Board, 175 Fulweiler Ave, Auburn, CA 95603.


 12/2/03 
 Supervisors Approve New Noise Ordinance 
 
Placer County Supervisors approved a noise ordinance Tuesday that proponents say is needed to control noise from motor bikes, gunfire and loud neighborhood parties. The ordinance prohibits sounds 5db above the ambient noise level, or sounds that exceed the hourly average of 55db daytime and 45db nighttime when measured at the receptors property line. The ordinance is targeted to become effective in March.


 11/24/03 
 Two Candidates Pull Papers for District 4 Supervisor 
 
TTo date, Ted Gaines and Pamela Tobin are the only two persons that have pulled papers from the Placer County Elections Department to file to run for Placer County Supervisor of the 4th District. Persons interested in filing must file their papers with the Elections Dept. by 5 Dec. No one has filed papers as of 24 Nov.


 11/23/03 
 Supervisors Approve Green Waste Program 
 
The concept of weekly curbside collection of green waste at no additional cost to the customer has been approved by the Board of Supervisors for &quot;toter customers&quot; of the Auburn Placer Disposal Service. Customers with toters, living in sub-divisions with parcels smaller than 2 acres will be receiving a new green toter. Toter customers on larger parcels may also receive the service if the specific parcel fits the route parameters. If parcels do not qualify for the pickup service, and for customers that do not have toter service, coupons for free dumping of two yards of green waste at the land fill site two times per year will be provided. The details of the program are now being negotiated with APDS and the program is targeted to be phased in by summer.


 11/5/03 
 CHP to Launch Senior 
 Volunteer Program 
 
The Auburn/Newcastle office of the CHP is starting a Senior Volunteer Program. The program will be open to qualified seniors at least 50 years old. Persons interested in participating in this program should contact Officer Joe Edwards or Sgt. Bertola at 663-3344.


 11/5/03 
 Fire Chief Announces Plan for Year Round Burn Permits 
 
Chief Corado indicated that all existing residential burn permits in the Granite Bay area will expire 31 Dec 03. Additionally, he indicated burn barrels would no longer be permitted and that a valid residential burn permit will be required in Granite Bay year round beginning Jan. 1 04.


 10/29/03 
 Draft Noise Ordinance Available for Review 
 
In July, the Board of Supervisors appointed a task force of community representatives to make recommendations on what a noise ordinance should look like. The task force met several times and a draft ordinance is now available for review on the County web site. It is anticipated the Board of Supervisors will review the ordinance at their 2 December meeting. Comments should be submitted by email to noise@placer.ca.gov or by mail to: The Board of Supervisors, 175 Fulweiler Ave. Auburn,
 CA 95603.


 10/25/03 
 A Workday at the Community Park 
 
Volunteers planted more than 1500 shrubs and trees at the new Community Park last weekend and saved $15,000 in construction costs. Workdays were scheduled for both Sat. and Sun. at the park site at Douglas Blvd. and Barton Rd. Over 100 volunteers showed up each day, including groups from churches, scouts, and youth athletic leagues.


 10/12/03 
 Fire District Salaries and Benefits Increase 19% 
 
The
 South Placer Fire District, the wealthiest District in Placer
 County, continues it&apos;s own pattern of tax and spend. At its
 Board meeting Sept. 17 the Board passed a $6.6 million budget for
 2003-2004. The budget proposes a 19% increase in spending for
 salaries and benefits, nearly 11% for fixed assets and only 1.5% for
 service and operations. 


 10/2/03 
 MAC Recommends Approval of New Traffic Circulation Plan 
 
At it&apos;s Wednesday night meeting, the MAC recommended approval of the County&apos;s proposed new Circulation Element for the Granite Bay Community Plan, requesting several changes recommended by the MAC Transportation sub-committee be included in the plan. The Plan will now go to the Planning Commission and subsequently to the Board of Supervisors for approval.


 9/4/03 
 MAC Does Not Recommend Approval of Road Widening 
 
Placer County Public Works presented MAC with the proposal for the design of their Auburn-Folsom Rd. widening project Wednesday evening. The highlight of the proposal was the fact that the total cost of the project is proposed to be paid for by Granite Bay funds. No State, Federal or Regional funds are planned to be used even though 70% of the traffic will be from regional sources. The County indicated plans to borrow between $9 and $14 million from other sources but to be repaid with interest from Granite Bay&apos;s future traffic mitigation funds. It was suggested that if that happens, no other road improvement projects could ever be funded by the mitigation funds. The MAC basically supported the recommendations made earlier by their Transportation Committee when they voted to deny a recommendation for approval unless the funding issue could be resolved.


 
 
 News Placer County Supervisor Uhler Granite Bay&apos;s History Community Plan Information Granite Bay Community Association Granite Bay Municipal Advisory Council San Juan Water District South Placer Fire Department Placer County Board of Supervisors Planning Commission Granite Bay Alert Community Blog Upcoming Events Youth Activates Recreation Worship 

 Advertising Library Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
