<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007686" url="http://www.bsu.edu/news/article/0,1370,548--,00.html" time="2012-07-13-00:39" support="1" score="0.0007517962701714765" bingtitle="Researcher: Older men want young mates, women seek men with power" webtitle="Researcher: Older men want young mates, women seek men with power">
			<query id="000386" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>For after-hours calls, dial the number below and ... the president&apos;s office and put him in a fast food restaurant ... less attractive if he worked as a garbage ...</description>
	<body>
		Alumnus Magazine Ball State Sports Communications Center Radio and TV Student Newspaper About University Marketing and Communications Ball State Facts Photo Services Public Records Request Search Archives by Keyword Search Archives by Date   University Marketing and Communications 
AC Building, Room 224
Ball State University
Muncie, IN 47306

Office Hours
8 a.m. - 5 p.m. Eastern time, Monday-Friday
For after-hours calls, dial the number below and you will be directed to an on-call staff person.
Phone: (765) 285-1560
Fax: (765) 285-5442
 umc@bsu.edu 


 Email a Friend    Print    Larger    Smaller Researcher: Older men want young mates, women seek men with power (9/1/1998) By Marc Ransford 
Communications Manager

MUNCIE, Ind. -- After President Clinton recently
 admitted to an inappropriate relationship with a former intern, the public is left
 wondering what they saw in each other.

The explanation is the 52-year-old Clinton and
 the 25-year-old Monica Lewinsky were doing what comes naturally, says Michael Wiederman, a
 Ball State University psychological science professor and relationship researcher.

&quot;There is something in our genetic makeup
 that makes men and women different when it comes to seeking mates or sexual
 partners,&quot; he said. &quot;We agree on what tastes sweet and sour. My young daughter
 knows that at age 2. But, when it comes to potential mates, we have totally different
 opinions.&quot;

Wiederman said Lewinsky falls into the category
 of what men are looking for in a one-time sexual partner.

&quot;A recent survey found that most men said
 the perfect partner for anonymous sex would be an attractive female about 19 to 25,&quot;
 he said. &quot;Many men with money, power and prestige seek out women in this age
 range.&quot;

When it comes to women&apos;s idea of a perfect mate,
 several studies point out that females would select a male who is famous, rich or
 powerful, Wiederman said.

&quot;Take Clinton out of the president&apos;s office
 and put him in a fast food restaurant and I don&apos;t think Monica would give him a second
 look,&quot; he said. &quot;Someone once said that power is an aphrodisiac.&quot;

In an informal classroom study, Wiederman said
 most females agreed that men would find model Cindy Crawford attractive even if she worked
 as a waitress or retail clerk. However, women found a movie star like Mel Gibson less
 attractive if he worked as a garbage collector or factory worker rather than an actor.

&quot;In another study, a male was pictured in an
 expensive business suit, a fast-food uniform and a simple t-shirt,&quot; he said.
 &quot;Women found the man in the business suit the most attractive. When he was wearing
 the suit, he was seen as doing well. When he was in the fast food uniform, he was seen as
 not doing well.&quot;

If women disagree with his assessment of male and
 female likes and dislikes, Wiederman points out the relationships between rock and roll
 stars and models.

&quot;When you put some of these rock singers on
 stage, you have all sorts of attractive women trying to meet them,&quot; he said.
 &quot;But, if you put these guys with their long hair and tattoos outside the local
 convenience store, most women wouldn&apos;t even consider talking to them.&quot;

 ( NOTE TO EDITORS: For more
 information, contact Wiederman by E-mail at mwiederm@bsu.edu or by phone at 765-285-2386.) 
 

 
 Copyright©2012 Ball State University   2000 W. University 
 Ave. Muncie, IN 47306
800-382-8540 and 765-289-1241
 Legal Information    |    Employment    |    TTY Numbers 
&quot;Education Redefined&quot; is a registered trademark of Ball State University.
	</body>
</document>
