<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007907" url="http://forum.volition.com/topic.asp?TOPIC_ID=830&amp;whichpage=2" time="2012-07-13-00:53" support="8" score="0.013235540638334542" bingtitle="List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while ..." webtitle="List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while mystery shopping?">
			<query id="000760" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000069" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>I was at a fast food restaurant that had one of those indoor ... would stop in. $4 got me in the door and a tray of ... I put a quarter in the slot and am promtply ...</description>
	<body>
		Username: 
 Password: 
 Save Password Register Forgot Password / Username? 
 
 
 Home | Search | Chat | FAQ | Posting Rules 
 
 

 

   All Forums 
   Mystery Shopping, Merchandising&amp;Demo 
   Mystery Shopping 
  List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while mystery shopping?   Reply to Topic 
   Printer Friendly 
 

 Previous Page | Next Page 
 

 
 
 Author  Topic  Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 of 50 
 MandyMershon 
 Valued Contributor 
 


 Kyle , TX 
 USA 
 187 Posts 
 
 Posted - 06/09/2003 : 08:08:03 AM     Oh no Jules! Was that the FF shop we were discussing the other day? Are you ok now? How terrible! Certainly not work the shop fee on that one.

Mine was this weekend. The hotel shop I was doing was reimbursement only and it was a national chain so I thought it would be ok as a small weekend getaway with my husband for our anniversiary. The reservation phone call and checking in a the front dest was smooth but did not follow the outlined protocal. That is what we are supposed to report about so I wasn&apos;t too worried until we stepped off the elevator. We had asked for a nonsmoking room and ours may have been but the rest of the floor wasn&apos;t and it smelled TERRIBLE. My husband commented that he had been in bars that did not smell as smoky as this and he used to be a smoker so it is hard to offend him! On top of that, the vending maching and ice maker area was empty and blocked off. Obviously there had been a leak of some kind and there was peeling wall paper and mildew on the floor and wall, adding to the icky smell. Then we went into our room. Yes, there was a non-smoking sign on the door but we found numerous cigarette burns and the room smelled terrible. I had not been a non-smoking room for very long. Maybe while we were checking in, they stuck that sign on the door really quick. The bed sagged in the middle and you could feel the bed springs when you sat on it. There was hair in the tub. It was terrible and this was supposed to be a fun night away from the baby with my hubby! I started entering the report on my laptop and I started crying. I didn&apos;t want to stay here. So after about 20 minutes in the room we decided the reimbursement only was just not worth it. We went back down to the front desk and told the clerk our room was unacceptable and we wanted our money back. She gave it to us with no problem and asked why we were leaving. We told her about the smell and the bed and she laughed but by that time we were laughing too because we were so glad to be getting out of there. I feel awful about escaping and possibly leaving the scheduler in the lurch (she was very nice about it by the way) but I have offered to write up the long report anyway so the hotel can know what is going on. It is pretty bad when the mystery shopper refuses to stay there for free!
	</body>
</document>
