<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007498" url="http://www.sporcle.com/games/gwukelic/Presidents_by_Name_Length/results" time="2012-07-13-00:28" support="1" score="0.016161023558699077" bingtitle="U.S. presidents in order of the number of letters in their last ..." webtitle="U.S. presidents in order of the number of letters in their last names (least to most) Quiz Results | Online Games&amp;Trivia by Sporcle">
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="40"/>
	<description>... you will find the least and most remembered U.S. presidents in order of the number ... Fast Food Restaurant by Burger</description>
	<body>
		mentally stimulating diversions 
 
 
 
 Random Quiz Random Just For Fun 
 Home Games Create User Created 
 
 Go 
 
 Most Popular Newest By Rating By Length By Favorites By Difficulty By Tags 
 
 Geography Entertainment Science History Literature Sports Language Just For Fun Religion Movies Television Music Gaming Miscellaneous Holiday 
 
 Here you will find the least and most remembered U.S. presidents in order of the number of letters in their last names (least to most), as well 
 as how your score stacks up against everyone else who took this quiz.

Think you can do 
 better this time?
 Play Again . Popular Just For Fun games today Visual Typing Challenge 23663 Clickable 1-100 Mines 18802 Missing Word: 2007 Movies 9996 Word Ladder: Deer Season 7645 1-100 1982 Missing Word: 2010 Movie Titles 1521 Shape-ology 1193 And more...   
 
 This U.S. Presidents by Last Name Length Quiz has been taken 62,348 times (3 today). 
 Starting Letter U.S. President % Guessed Right B (H. W.) Bush 97.1% B (W.) Bush 96.4% A Adams 93.4% T Taft 91.5% F Ford 90.4% A (Q.) Adams 90.3% P Polk 85.8% O Obama 85.6% N Nixon 84.8% W Washington 84.4% R (T.) Roosevelt 79.7% R (F.) Roosevelt 79.7% G Grant 79.3% E Eisenhower 77.4% J (A.) Johnson 77% J Jackson 76.8% L Lincoln 75.8% J (L.) Johnson 75.4% C Carter 74.5% K Kennedy 73.4% R Reagan 73.1% M Monroe 72.1% 
 
 Starting Letter U.S. President % Guessed Right H Hoover 71.1% J Jefferson 69.2% M Madison 68.2% W Wilson 67.3% C Clinton 66.8% C Coolidge 60.5% V Van Buren 60.5% T Tyler 60.3% T Truman 60.3% H (B.) Harrison 59.7% H Harrison 58.9% G Garfield 56.1% H Hayes 56.1% P Pierce 56.1% T Taylor 55.2% A Arthur 52.6% B Buchanan 52.2% C Cleveland 48.6% F Fillmore 47.5% H Harding 46.8% M McKinley 44% 
 
 How do you compare to other U.S. Presidents by Last Name Length quiz takers? 


 
 Number % Answered 43 (all) 12.7% 38-42 20.6% 33-37 17.7% 28-32 15.1% 23-27 11.5% 18-22 7.5% 13-17 4.9% 8-12 5% 3-7 3.7% 1-2 1.3% 
 
 
 
 You might also like these games: Common US Presidents&apos; First Names     U.S. Presidents in Reverse     US Presidents in Alphabetical Order 
 Loading...
 There are 35 comments for this game.
 (Warning: comments may contain spoilers) 
U.S. Presidents by Last Name Length Quiz
 
 
 by gwukelic 
 

 Created Feb 21, 2011 in Just For Fun Featured Mar 16, 2011 Game Plays 62,348 
 
 Report a Mistake 
 
 
Tags

 Numbers Quizzes Letter Quizzes US Presidents Quizzes least last order starting length amount Presidents 
 Remember, Sporcle is now...
 
Friend Scores and Standings
 Loading friend results.... 
Top Games Today in Just For Fun

 Visual Typing Challenge 23,796 Clickable 1-100 Mines 18,941 Missing Word: 2007 Movies 10,047 Word Ladder: Deer Season 7,701 
 
Top Games with Similar Tags

 MLB Teams by Name Length 731 U.S. Presidents in Reverse 93 Common US Presidents&apos; First Na... 67 Least Common Presidential Name... 22 
 
Top User Games in Just For Fun

 Who Wants to be a Millionaire?... 1,052 Blitz: Red, White, OR Blue 549 True Colors 335 &lt;( ● ) &gt; Insomniac&apos;s word l... 273 
 
 
 Archived comments: show them 
 gwukelic : Feb 22nd, 2011 at 02:23 GMT   6 points This is a sequel to my U.S. state quiz. I hope you like this one, and if you really enjoy it, here&apos;s the link to the other one. http://www.sporcle.com/games/gwukelic/big_words_hurt_my_brain 
 Comment below threshold: show it 
 siciliana099 : Feb 23rd, 2011 at 01:14 GMT   -18 points not good 
 
 micah : Mar 9th, 2011 at 05:47 GMT   8 points You know what I hate? When I miss Lincoln because, when I&apos;m at the end and running through all the presidents in my mind, Lincoln is so obvious that I figure surely I couldn&apos;t have forgotten him. That&apos;s what. 
 
 MikeN : Mar 9th, 2011 at 18:17 GMT   -2 points THe first letter makes it too easy. Just have them be entered in alphabetical order within each length. 
 
 iamthesecretbox : Mar 11th, 2011 at 22:28 GMT   4 points looks like you ran out of room in the title lol 
 Game published: Mar 16th, 2011 at 04:03 GMT 
 gwukelic : Mar 16th, 2011 at 04:08 GMT   31 points Many thanks to Sporcle for publishing my quiz! I hope you all enjoy it. :) 
 
 punniker : Mar 16th, 2011 at 04:50 GMT   52 points there will soon be a day when all of the ways to name the presidents of the USA have been submitted. 
 
 Sulli : Mar 16th, 2011 at 04:51 GMT   3 points i cant believe i missed 6 
 
 glueyourfingers : Mar 16th, 2011 at 05:13 GMT   26 points Loved this more than I thought I would. I&apos;d love to see the format carried over to US states, countries of Africa, etc. 
 
 fcogcommish : Mar 16th, 2011 at 05:35 GMT   6 points Love the President&apos;s quizzes. Always challenging. I never remember Hayes. Why is that? How can I always remember Arthur and Fillmore and forget Rutherford? 
 Comment below threshold: show it 
 BamaRainbow : Mar 16th, 2011 at 05:47 GMT   -15 points My only complaint was that I spent a good 30 seconds on the first &quot;J-7&quot; because it wouldn&apos;t take my (correct) answer. Where there are &quot;ties&quot; on possible answers, some sort of &quot;tiebreaker&quot; needs to be indicated in the instructions. All we&apos;re told is to enter last names. (An indication for alphabetical order where multiple choices are possible would help.) 
 
 gwukelic : Mar 16th, 2011 at 06:05 GMT   11 points @BamaRainbow: I do mention that in the game notes, but I understand that most people don&apos;t read that. @All: As a reminder, all names are LAST NAMES and in the event of a tie (the same amount of letters), enter the last names in order alphabetically. 
 
 gwukelic : Mar 16th, 2011 at 06:08 GMT   7 points One more thing. If you enjoyed this quiz, I have an original quiz similar to this, but involving the US States. I will mostly make more quizzes like this if this quiz does well. Anyway, I encourage you to try my first one. Here&apos;s the link: http://www.sporcle.com/games/gwukelic/big_words_hurt_my_brain 
 
 sooners : Mar 16th, 2011 at 06:37 GMT   1 point I always forget Obama, I&apos;m not sure how to fit him into that president&apos;s song from elementary school :( 
 
 TessSGS : Mar 16th, 2011 at 07:27 GMT   12 points Missed 2, McKinley and Cleveland, not bad for a Brit. 
 
 pirate6711 : Mar 16th, 2011 at 11:31 GMT   3 points Good quiz and a good amount of time to complete. It presents a good and realistic challenge. 
 
 Hullabaloo : Mar 16th, 2011 at 11:42 GMT   -1 points My knowledge of US presidents is a bit rusty to say the least. Got 29 though, so I can&apos;t complain too much. Nice quiz, cheif. 
 
 Retracto : Mar 16th, 2011 at 12:22 GMT   7 points Gah! Missed Clinton, of all people. My poor head gets stuck in a historical mode. 
 
 olegauchos : Mar 16th, 2011 at 16:17 GMT   5 points First in war, first in peace, first in number of letters 
 
 monstro : Mar 16th, 2011 at 16:31 GMT   2 points Got all but McKinley, then it seemed a bit odd to see that he was the most-missed. Come on, brain, there&apos;s a mountain named after him! 
 
 WyattsTorch : Mar 16th, 2011 at 16:48 GMT   1 point I missed Gore. Oh wait... 
 
 jojofiss : Mar 16th, 2011 at 17:17 GMT   3 points &quot;And they made it their sign, because, Van Buren, our 8th President, was the man they most admired.&quot; 
 
 lynnline : Mar 16th, 2011 at 18:19 GMT   1 point Could not think of the &quot;V&quot; president for the life of me! Surprised I got tripped up as much as I did. Good quiz! 
 
 Nordeck52 : Mar 16th, 2011 at 18:22 GMT   1 point Can&apos;t believe I missed Clinton. I guess I was also in &quot;history mode&quot; or something like that. x.x 
 
 44magnum : Mar 16th, 2011 at 18:24 GMT   1 point It took a few tries but I finally got them all. Missed different ones each time. This was a good quiz. Congrats on getting it published. 
 
 yankeespurs101 : Mar 16th, 2011 at 18:26 GMT   5 points Its probably easier if you go through all the presidents in your head and fill it in that way instead of guessing 
 
 abard124 : Mar 16th, 2011 at 22:30 GMT   7 points Damn good thing Arnold Schwarzenegger isn&apos;t eligible to be president... 
 
 mustango : Mar 16th, 2011 at 23:42 GMT   3 points For P-6 I so got hung up on President Palmer. 
 
 EpicWinFTW : Mar 17th, 2011 at 02:13 GMT   3 points ...Truman *in Jerry Seinfeld&apos;s voice* 
 
 Supersonicfan3 : Mar 17th, 2011 at 03:39 GMT   2 points brilliant jojofuss, just brilliant! 
 
 Girma : Mar 23rd, 2011 at 23:05 GMT   2 points I would like to thank the Animaniacs&apos; &quot;President song&quot; for this success. 
 
 bballcenter7 : Apr 15th, 2011 at 13:46 GMT   2 points 41/43. The two I missed? Reagan and Lincoln X_X 
 
 ewanmcfadyen : Jun 1st, 2011 at 03:57 GMT   2 points For the long &quot;G&quot; I nearly tried Gerald Ford 
 
 Mizzie : Jun 13th, 2011 at 00:26 GMT   2 points I was racking my brains for the first two &apos;B&apos;s...the only B I could think of was Buchanan. My brain, for some reason, thought &quot;butter&quot; was an answer...WTF, self. 
 
 psylockecable : Apr 9th, 2012 at 16:03 GMT   0 points Filmore has one L. 
 2007-12©Sporcle, Inc. - About  | Advertise  | Feedback  | Blog  | FAQ  | Embed  | News  | Terms  | Jobs  | Privacy   Part of USA Today Sports Media Group Go to the Sporcle.com Mobile Site→
	</body>
</document>
