<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007550" url="http://www.penangfoodgalore.blogspot.com/2008/07/taiwanese-food-at-taiwan-fast-food.html" time="2012-07-13-00:31" support="52" score="0.21088827703262644" bingtitle="Penang Food Galore: Taiwanese Food at Taiwan Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="Penang Food Galore: Taiwanese Food at Taiwan Fast Food Restaurant (Pulau Tikus)">
			<query id="001514" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001254" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="65"/>
	<description>Additional, each set comes in a tray consisting of a drink, soup, rice ... Taiwanese Food at Taiwan Fast Food Restaurant (Pul... Homemade Chicken Teriyaki ...</description>
	<body>
		Penang Food Galore 
 
 
 
Sunday, July 20, 2008
 
Taiwanese Food at Taiwan Fast Food Restaurant (Pulau Tikus)
 As my job entails me to travel frequently regionally, I have travelled to Taiwan many times before. For whatever reason after all these years, I still don&apos;t enjoy Taiwanese food very much. I have to admit there are places in Taiwan that serve extremely good food but they are usually high end restaurants and beyond the reach of the masses. In general, I just can&apos;t find any connection with Taiwanese food. My general perception is that they are blend and uninteresting. However, I am willing to make an exception to this rule. My wife and I love this Taiwanese restaurant located on the 1st floor of Midlands shopping complex. It&apos;s run by a Taiwanese expatriate who has now made Penang her home. We always get so much satisfaction from the food she dishes out partly because they have been localised to our taste buds. For directions, just watch for this sign that says Taiwanese Fast Food. Take the staircase which leads you to the 1st floor. While it&apos;s quite hidden, the restaurant has survived since its inception in the early part of the millennium through the support of many regular patrons...including your truly. :) 
 
 As you enter the restaurant, you will quickly notice that the interior design of the restaurant is simple, comfortable and inviting. While the restaurant itself is relatively small, the effect of the lighting makes you perceive otherwise. Groovy. 
 


While this restaurant serves both ala cartes and set orders, I would recommend that you opt for the latter. They are reasonably priced and range from RM 10-20 per set. Additional, each set comes in a tray consisting of a drink, soup, rice, vegetables, dessert and the main dish of your selection. The main dish consists of a wide selection to choose from ranging from pork chop, pig&apos;s tongue, shabu shabu to a variety of noodles. Wicked! 
 Here&apos;s a selection of drinks to choose from for your set menu. There&apos;s the bubble tea which I really enjoy. They come with the soft, chewy tapioca balls. As a matter of fact, they are even better than those I had in Taiwan. Other beverages to choose from are the green tea with tapioca balls, special fruit juice, ice mocha and a number of tea and coffee selections.

 
 
Grilled chicken set. My wife and I love this. The chicken is grilled with sweet sauce and tasted like char siu bak except that this one is a lot tender. 
 

Chicken chop set. This set order is an all time favorite at this restaurant. It comes in a generous portion too which is why its popular. 
 
 Another dish that is popular with the patrons is the meat floss with rice set. 
The owner is always exploring new recipes to include in her menu. She recently added the chicken with special spices to her menu. 

 
 Entrails in spicy soup. This dish is an acquired taste but the soup is nice though. Pork chop set. 
For side dish, I recommend the Taiwanese milk toast. They come in thick soft slices dabbled in milk. There&apos;s even a green tea toast as an option. 
 
 
 
This is just some of the many noodles this restaurant serves - beef ball noodles.
 
 


For directions to the restaurant, the address is as follows:
 488-D, 01-02, Midlands Center (Shopping Mall) Burma Road, 10350 Penang Tel:04-2295922 Just note that they are close on every Wednesdays. For the regular patrons, please note that they have just opened a new outlet at the basement of Gurney Plaza just beside Seoul Garden. See you there! Posted by Andrew at 10:10 AM Labels: restaurant 
7 comments:
 J2Kfm said... 
oh something new?
never realized there are good eateries in Midlands, other than the cheap buffet lunch at Berjaya hotel.
The only Taiwanese restaurant I&apos;ve tried in Pg is Kocha, on Jln Burma I think.
 July 22, 2008 8:51 PM Fortesfidelis said... 
They have now opened a new outlet at Gurney Plaza just beside Seoul Garden. It&apos;s a lot convenient for those who like to shop there. I like this restaurant simply because it&apos;s so much cheaper than Kocha and the food is always so satisfying.
 July 23, 2008 8:18 AM gill gill said... 
yea i agree with you, fortesfidelis. This outlet are nicer and cheaper then Kocha. anyway, thankx for sharing they had been opened another outlet in gurney....coz i never reliase it...
 July 24, 2008 1:37 AM Fortesfidelis said... 
Gill gill - The outlet at Gurney Plaza has got very nice ambience too. However, it is also pack most of the time as compared to the one at Midlands.We prefer the outlet at Midlands simply because we are use to going there.
 July 24, 2008 7:43 AM Leslie said... 
G’day, I’m Leslie from Penang.cc (Penang Community Centre). I enjoy reading your articles and would like to request permission to feature the article on Taiwan Fast Food 台灣風味情 in our website (for more info visit http://www.mrain.com/pgcc/content/view/185/49/). In addition, we will like to extent invitation for your participation in our Bloggers’Appreciation Programme (find out more at http://www.mrain.com/pgcc/content/view/158/69/). Join us to participate in our invited reviews for travel destinations, dinnings, product&amp;services etc., at the same time receive exclusive deals&amp;prizes for your readers. Kindly email me at leslie.loh@penang.cc for more information. TQ
 June 17, 2010 3:37 AM chin aun said... 
mmm
 April 8, 2011 6:27 PM Siok Mei Koh said... 
There&apos;s another good and authentic Taiwanese restaurant in Chai Leng Park, Prai. Little Taipei Village is located opposite Chai Leng Park wet market, next to Guilin Chinese medical hall. Run by a Taiwanese lady who has chosen Penang as her home. Try her hot pot (I love it), char chiang noodle, beef noodle, dumpling, intestines, honey drumstick rice and the best of all its mango and red bean ice. This place serves the best mango ice. Restaurant closed on Tuesday. I have been her loyal customer since 2 years ago and still looking forward to dine there.
 October 22, 2011 12:14 PM 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
 
About Me
 Andrew View my complete profile 
Other Sites I Maintain
 
 Personalised Label Ladies Corner 
 
Subscribe to my feed
 
My Photo Album
 www. flick r .com 
 This is a Flickr badge showing public photos and videos from fortesfidelis . Make your own badge here . 
Recent Foodies
 Grab this Widget by Wowzio 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2009 (1) 
 ►  January (1) 
 Sunday Street Market At Upper Penang Road 
 
 

 ▼  2008 (73) 
 ►  December (1) 
 Improvised Green Chicken Curry (Recipes) 
 

 ►  November (3) 
 JL Steamboat Restaurant (Georgetown) Soon Lai Seafood Restaurant (Greenlane) Yaw&apos;s Roast and Grill Western Food At Gerbang Midl... 
 

 ►  October (4) 
 Breakfast At Eng Loh Coffee Shop (Georgetown) Goreng Pisang At Free School Road (Greenlane) Vegetarian Lunch At Nine Emperor Gods Festival (Ge... Chu Char at De Lai Sang Ding Seafood Restaurant (G... 
 

 ►  September (10) 
 Penang Floggers Gathering At Edelweiss (Georgetown... Ice Kachang At Kek Seng Coffee Shop (Georgetown) Homemade Butter Cake (Recipe) Dim Sum At De Tai Tong (Georgetown) High Tea At E&amp;O Hotel (Georgetown) Classic Kopitiam Food At Old Town (E-Gate) Homemade Apple Crumble Recipe Hong Kong Cuisine At Kim Gary (Gurney Drive) Homemade Crab Stick Maki (Recipe) Chu Char At Batu Lanchang Market (Greenlane) 
 

 ►  August (19) 
 Losing Manhood Over Soya Bean Drink At Soya King Chinese Restaurant At Red Rock Hotel (Georgetown) Hainanese Lor Mee At Harbin Cafe (Pulau Tikus) All Time Classic Chicken Pies From Penang Hill (Ai... Everyone&apos;s A Winner At McDonald&apos;s Imagine If You Have This For Dinner Wonderful Set Lunch At Manila Place (Georgetown) Homemade Carrot Muffins - Recipe Soya Bean Puddings At Prangin Mall (Georgetown) Desserts At Sugar Dynasty (Georgetown) Double Good Restaurant (Bayan Lepas) Japanese Fried Rice (Recipe) Chinese Food At Fuho Restaurant (Bayan Lepas) Dim Sum At Fun Tea Garden (Georgetown) Japanese Food At Tao Cuisine Japanese Restaurant (... New Domino&apos;s Pizza Outlet (Greenlane) Home Catering Service (Greenlane) Economy Rice at Mandarin Cafe (Greenlane) Medicated Tea Shop Along Kimberley Street (Georget... 
 

 ▼  July (15) 
 Chicken Chop With Mushroom Sauce (Recipe) Malay Food at Restaurant Minah (Gelugor) Japanese Groceries From Meijiya Mini-Market (Pulau... Indian Breakfast at Arati Vilas (Tanjung Bungah) Homemade Katsu Kare and Chicken Karaage (Recipe) Taiwanese Food at Taiwan Fast Food Restaurant (Pul... Homemade Chicken Teriyaki (Recipe) Hawker Food at Hong Kong Tea Garden Cafe (Georgeto... Penang Pasembur Along Persiaran Gurney (Gurney Dri... Japanese Food at Tsuruya (Bayan Lepas) Western Food at Esplanade (Georgetown) Yummy durians from Lorong Susu (Georgetown) Potato and Lettuce Salad (Recipe) Tu Kar Chor (Pig&apos;s Trotter Vineger) at Teik Seng C... Lazy Man&apos;s Pizza (Recipe) 
 

 ►  June (19) 

 ►  May (2) 
 
 
My Blog List
 
 What2See : The Best of Penang Food! Ramadan Buffet Dinner with Gearbox Soup @Eastin Hotel Penang 19 hours ago San&apos;s Blessed Moments Just Caffe, Penang 20 hours ago My Love•My Food Home Cooked Fried Noodle 自家炒麵 1 day ago Makan King and Queen White and Brown Shimeiji Stir-Fry 香炒真姬菇 4 days ago Lingzie&apos;s Tummy Treats Morganfield’s @ Gurney Paragon, Penang 2 weeks ago Yummy Station Chez Weng @ Precinct 10, Tanjung Tokong, Penang 2 months ago Rainbows Fine Dining @ Suffolk House.... 7 months ago Cariso Delicacies Corner No energy to update both. Go straight to www.cariso.net 10 months ago CRIZ BON APPETITE WINE DINNER AT FERRINGHI GRILL 1 year ago Food and Dine by PenangTuaPui Making of Sparkling Apple Juice | Huat Koay’s Little Corner 1 year ago The Gastronomic Diary I miss my food! 1 year ago Gourmet Garden Blog Migration 2 years ago Havenly Allie Migration of Havenly Allie 3 years ago 
 
Foodies Who Dropped By
 ↑ Want this widget? 

 
Site Meter
	</body>
</document>
