<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007157" url="http://www.ajcn.org/content/91/3/771.full" time="2012-07-13-00:08" support="1" score="0.000584378730298263" bingtitle="Interactive effects of reward sensitivity and residential fast ..." webtitle="Interactive effects of reward sensitivity and residential fast-food restaurant exposure on fast-food consumption">
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>Fast-food restaurant exposure was operationalized as the number of fast-food ... are reported in Table 2 (model 1). The association between fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition
 
 Skip to main page content 

 HOME CURRENT ISSUE EMAIL ALERTS ARCHIVES SUBSCRIPTIONS SEARCH FOR ARTICLES 

 CUSTOM PUBLICATION FAQ 
 Search AJCN Submit Advanced Search 
 
 
 
 
 © 2010 American Society for Nutrition 

Interactive effects of reward sensitivity and residential fast-food restaurant exposure on fast-food consumption 1 , 2 , 3 
 
 Catherine Paquet , Mark Daniel , Bärbel Knäuper , Lise Gauvin , Yan Kestens , and Laurette Dubé 

 1 From the School of Health Sciences University of South Australia Adelaide Australia (CPMD); the Department of Medicine St
 Vincent&apos;s Hospital The University of Melbourne Melbourne Australia (MD); the Psychology Department McGill University Montreal
 Canada (BK); the Département de Medecine Sociale et Préventive Université de Montréal Montreal Canada; Centre de Recherche
 du Centre Hospitalier de l&apos;Université de Montréal Montreal Canada (LGYK); the Direction de Santé Publique de Montréal Montreal
 Canada (YK);the Faculty of Management McGill University Montreal Canada (LD). 

 
 ↵ 2 Data collection was provided in equal parts through the Canada Research Chairs program and the Canada Foundation for Innovation
 (grant 201252; MD), Canadian Institutes of Health Research (grant 200203 MOP 57805; to LG), and Fonds de la Recherche en Santé
 du Québec (team grant 8394; to LD). CP was supported by a postdoctoral fellowship from the Fonds de la Recherche en Santé
 du Québec; MD was supported by a Canada Research Chair for Biopsychosocial Pathways in Population Health, awarded by the Canadian
 Institutes of Health Research; and YK was supported by a postdoctoral fellowship from the Heart and Stroke Foundation of Canada.
 LG holds a Canadian Institutes for Health Research/Centre de Recherche en Prevention de l&apos;Obésité Chair in Applied Public
 Health Chair on Neighbourhoods, Lifestyle, and Healthy Body Weight. LD holds the James McGill Chair in Consumer and Lifestyle
 Psychology and Marketing. MD holds a Research Chair for Social Epidemiology at the University of South Australia.
 
 ↵ 3 Address correspondence to C Paquet, School of Health Sciences, University of South Australia, City East Campus, GPO Box 2471,
 Adelaide, South Australia 5001, Australia. E-mail: catherine.paquet{at}unisa.edu.au .
 
 Next Section 
Abstract

 Background: Local fast-food environments have been increasingly linked to obesity and related outcomes. Individuals who are more sensitive
 to reward-related cues might be more responsive to such environments.

 Objective: This study aimed to assess the moderating role of sensitivity to reward on the relation between residential fast-food restaurant
 exposure and fast-food consumption.

 Design: Four hundred fifteen individuals (49.6% men; mean age: 34.7 y) were sampled from 7 Montreal census tracts stratified by socioeconomic
 status and French/English language. The frequency of fast-food restaurant visits in the previous week was self-reported. Sensitivity
 to reward was self-reported by using the Behavioral Activation System (BAS) scale. Fast-food restaurant exposure within 500
 m of the participants&apos; residence was determined by using a Geographic Information System. Main and interactive effects of
 the BAS and fast-food restaurant exposure on fast-food consumption were tested with logistic regression models that accounted
 for clustering of observations and participants&apos; age, sex, education, and household income.

 Results: Regression results showed a significant interaction between BAS and fast-food restaurant exposure ( P &lt;0.001). Analysis of BAS tertiles indicated that the association between neighborhood fast-food restaurant exposure and
 consumption was positive for the highest tertile (odds ratio: 1.49; 95% CI: 1.20, 1.84; P &lt;0.001) but null for the intermediate (odds ratio: 1.03; 95% CI: 0.80, 1.34; P = 0.81) and lowest (odds ratio: 0.84; 95% CI: 0.51, 1.37; P = 0.49) tertiles.

 Conclusion: Reward-sensitive individuals may be more responsive to unhealthful cues in their immediate environment.
 Previous Section Next Section 
INTRODUCTION

Cues associated with palatable food are strong drivers of food consumption, even beyond homeostatic needs ( 1 ). The preponderance of such cues in our modern environment is considered to be a major contributor to the current obesity
 epidemic. However, not all individuals exposed to obesogenic environments will necessarily become obese. Various factors might
 influence individual responsiveness to environmental food cues. The need to identify such differences for explaining variations
 in individual resistance and susceptibility to weight gain ( 2 ) and obesity ( 3 ) is increasingly recognized. In addition, understanding for whom or under what circumstances the food environment is more
 likely to lead to overconsumption might assist the development and implementation of tailored environmental interventions
 to fight obesity.

Recent advances in neuroscience could help in identifying individual characteristics that capture a propensity to respond
 to palatable food cues. Palatable foods such as those high in sugar and fat are highly reinforcing. The reinforcing effect
 of food is tied to reward brain pathways ( 4 , 5 ), mediated in part by the dopaminergic systems ( 6 , 7 ). Cues associated with palatable foods are known to activate such systems ( 4 , 5 , 8 ) and, in turn, to promote food intake ( 7 ). Important individual differences have been reported in these neural responses to food cues ( 9 ), thus highlighting potential individual variations in sensitivity to the reward properties of food.

Individual differences in responsiveness to incentive-related environmental cues are supported by studies measuring trait
 reward sensitivity using, for example, the Behavioral Activation System (BAS) scale. Measures of BAS have been shown to covary
 with differences in neural responses to food cues ( 9 ) and reflect a tendency for individuals to experience positive affect in response to incentives or appetitive stimuli and
 to engage in approach behaviors to attain these stimuli. Reward sensitivity has been positively associated with caloric consumption
 ( 10 , 11 ), preference for sweet/fat food ( 10 ), obesity, and dysfunctional eating ( 12 , 13 ). It was also found to discriminate individual responses when exposed to either rewarding (ie, varied) or monotonous food
 in a laboratory setting ( 14 ), which suggests that, in this study, reward sensitivity moderated responses to the manipulated food environment.

On the basis of this previous research, it was proposed that individual differences in reward sensitivity should be evaluated
 to understand variations in the influence of palatable food cues on health behaviors and related outcomes in the current obesogenic
 environment. The main effect of the accessibility or availability of fast-food restaurants (as measures of exposure to palatable
 but unhealthful food cues) on diet quality and obesity-related outcomes has been the object of many studies. Such studies
 have provided mixed support for a significant association. For instance, some studies have shown that a lower access to fast-food
 restaurants is associated with healthier diets and lower rates of obesity ( 15 – 17 ), whereas others ( 18 – 22 ) failed to support such relations. Limited research has addressed individual factors that could explain variations in the
 association between obesogenic environmental cues, such as cues potentially triggering intake of high-sugar and/or high-fat
 foods, and health outcomes. In particular, there is a need for population-based studies that evaluate the moderating role
 of psychological factors, such as reward sensitivity. This study sought to assess in a representative sample of urban-dwelling
 residents the moderating role of sensitivity to reward measured with the BAS scale on the association between residential
 exposure to fast-food restaurants, which are known to present extensive cues for high-fat, high-sugar foods ( 23 ), and fast-food consumption.
 Previous Section Next Section 
SUBJECTS AND METHODS
 
Context

This study derives from the Montreal Neighborhood Survey of Lifestyle and Health, which was designed to collect behavioral,
 psychosocial, and biological markers of health status and to integrate these into a Geographic Information System ( 24 ). The study used a stratified cluster sampling, where Montreal Island census tracts ( n = 521) were stratified into tertiles of socioeconomic status (SES) based on census income and education data ( 25 ). Using 2001 Canada Census data, for each SES tertile, one dominantly French-speaking and one dominantly English-speaking
 census tract were randomly selected to represent both official Canadian languages. The resulting 6 census tracts were subsequently
 complemented with an additional medium-SES French tract to augment sample size.

Recruiters delivered informational material to noncommercial addresses within each census tract. Recruiters visited addresses
 48–72 h after the delivery of material to inquire about willingness to participate in the study. Contact could not be established
 with residents of ≈40% of addresses. Of those reached and eligible, ≈15% agreed to participate. Inclusion criteria were as
 follows: aged between 18 and 55 y, no diagnosis of cardiovascular or metabolic disease, and ability to read French or English.
 A total of 415 individuals participated in the study. For the present study, complete data were obtained for 404 participants
 (7 individuals were excluded because of missing BAS measures and 4 because of missing age values).
 
Data collection

Participants completed a questionnaire on health behaviors and psychosocial factors relevant to cardiovascular health by telephone,
 Internet, or hard copy mailers. Data were collected from March 2006 to April 2007. The participants&apos; addresses were geocoded
 and integrated into a Geographic Information System ( 24 ) containing, among other databases, census data ( 25 ) and a comprehensive inventory of businesses and services ( 26 ) located within the Montreal Census Metropolitan Area (CMA) in 2005. The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical
 standards stated in the Canadian Tri-Council Policy Statement and were approved by the ethics committee of the Centre de Recherche
 du Centre Hospitalier de l&apos;Université de Montréal.
 
Measures

Fast-food consumption was measured by using a 4-point scale, where individuals reported the number of times they had visited
 a fast-food restaurant in their neighborhood in the previous 7 d (0, 1–2, 3–4, or ≥5 times). Neighborhood was not a priori
 defined to allow participants to use their own definition of neighborhood. Given the high percentage of participants who had
 not been to a fast-food restaurant in that period (71%), responses were dichotomized in terms of one or more visits or no
 visits.

Reward sensitivity was measured by using the BAS component (thirteen 5-point items) of the Behavioral Inhibition System/BAS
 scales developed by Carver and White ( 27 ), a well-established measure that taps individual differences in the BAS ( 27 ). Items on the BAS scale pertain to persistence at pursuing goals, seeking new and pleasing stimuli, and anticipation of
 rewarding event. The scale includes items such as “When I see an opportunity for something I like, I get excited right away,”
 “When I want something, I usually go ‘all-out’ to get it,” and “I will often do things for no reason other than that they
 might be fun.” The convergence and discriminant validity as well as the internal consistency of the scale have been demonstrated
 ( 27 , 28 ). Items were summed to obtain an overall BAS score (scale: 0–65) for which the predictive ability in the domain of food was
 previously shown ( 10 ). Internal consistency among items was determined for the present study and was found adequate (Cronbach&apos;s α = 0.81).

Fast-food restaurant exposure was operationalized as the number of fast-food restaurants located within 500 m of the participants&apos;
 residence. Restaurants were extracted by using Standard Industry Classification codes from a commercial database ( 26 ) containing a comprehensive inventory of businesses and services located within the Montreal CMA in 2005. All businesses
 and services were geocoded by using GeoPinPoint software (version 6.4; DMTI Spatial Inc, Markham, Canada) either at the address
 (82%) or the 6-digit postal code (18%) level. Six-digit Canadian postal codes pertain to one side of one street section. A
 validation study of this commercial database in the Montreal CMA showed that it was valid in terms of the likelihood that
 a listed establishment was present in the field (positive predictive value = 0.90) and that a food establishment present in
 the field was correctly listed in the database (sensitivity = 0.84) ( 29 ). Restaurants were coded as fast-food or non–fast-food by a rater with extensive knowledge of the Montreal restaurant industry.
 Fast-food restaurants were defined as any chain or nonchain restaurant offering rapidly prepared and served, primarily high-caloric
 food, for home or out-of-home consumption and were coded based on restaurant names only ( 30 ). Intrarater reliability was 90.2% when fast-food restaurants were recoded again, 3 mo later. Interrater reliability for
 classifications of fast-food restaurants by the same coder was also high (κ = 0.73) when previously assessed for the 2003
 version of the database ( 30 ).

Covariates included the participants&apos; age, sex, education, and household income. In a secondary analysis, we also accounted
 for area-level SES, given its reported inverse relation with the density of fast-food outlets ( 30 – 36 ). The participants self-reported their date of birth, educational attainment (9 categories), and household income (9 categories).
 Educational attainment was operationalized as being a university graduate or not and household income as low [&lt;20,000 Canadian
 dollars (CAD)], medium (CAD 20,000-50,000), or high (more than CAD 50,000). We also accounted for the socioeconomic background
 within the participants&apos; immediate residential environment by considering the proportion of households spending ≥20% on food,
 shelter, and clothing than the average of households of similar size, region, and resident density ( 25 ). This variable was obtained at the census tract level by using 2001 census data and defined for a buffer zone of 500-m radii
 centered on the participant&apos;s residence by using the weighted average of values from any adjacent census tracts, with weights
 being defined by the proportion of the area of the buffer represented by each census tract.
 
Statistical analysis

Logistic regression analyses were conducted to test the main and interactive effects of BAS and fast-food restaurant exposure
 on fast-food consumption, with adjustment for age, sex, individual-level education and income, and residential SES (secondary
 analysis). Generalized estimating equations estimators were used to account for the clustering of observations within census
 tracts. All analyses were conducted by using SAS version 9.1.3 (SAS Institute, Cary, NC). Continuous predictors were standardized.
 Statistical significance was set at α = 0.05.
 Previous Section Next Section 
RESULTS

Characteristics of the sample analyzed appear in Table 1 . Two-sided exact binomial probability tests comparing characteristics of participants with Canada Census data (2001) for
 each selected census tract showed a greater proportion of participants holding a bachelor&apos;s degree than the general population
 of Montreal. In 3 census tracts, greater proportions of married and households with income greater than CAD 100,000 participants
 were found. One hundred eighteen participants had visited a fast-food restaurant in their neighborhood in the previous week.
 Results from the generalized estimating equations logistic regression analysis are reported in Table 2 (model 1). The association between fast-food restaurant exposure and fast-food consumption was not statistically significant,
 whereas the BAS was positively associated with fast-food consumption. The BAS interacted significantly with fast-food restaurant
 exposure, with the positive association between fast-food restaurant exposure and fast-food consumption being stronger among
 persons with higher BAS scores. None of the covariates were statistically significant in relation to fast-food consumption.
 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 TABLE 1 
Descriptive information for participants in the Montreal Neighborhood Survey of Lifestyle and Health: 2006–2007 ( n = 404)
 View this table: 
 In this window In a new window 
 TABLE 2 
Logistic regression results for the associations between fast-food consumption, Behavioral Activation System (BAS) scale,
 and fast-food restaurant exposure (main and interactive effects) accounting for covariates among participants in the Montreal
 Neighborhood Survey of Lifestyle and Health ( n = 404)
 
To explore the nature of the interaction between BAS and fast-food restaurant exposure, we estimated the association between
 fast-food restaurant exposure and fast-food consumption for different levels of BAS. To do so, the sample was divided into
 tertiles of BAS. Compared with individuals in the first 2 tertiles, individuals in the highest BAS tertile were younger [aged
 33.0 (high BAS) compared with 35.6 (low-intermediate BAS) y; P = 0.01] and were less likely to be male [40.0% (high BAS) compared with 53.8% (low-intermediate BAS); P = 0.02] and to have a university degree [39.1% (high BAS) compared with 50.6% (low-intermediate BAS); P = 0.04] and a high income [&gt;$50,000; 22.6% (high BAS) compared with 35.2% (low-intermediate BAS); P = 0.02]. Results from analyses performed for each BAS tertile are illustrated in Figure 1 , where the predicted log odds of having consumed fast-food in the past 7 d is plotted for different values of fast-food restaurant
 exposure (mean and 1 SD above and 1 SD below the mean) for all 3 tertiles of BAS. As illustrated, the association between
 neighborhood fast-food restaurant exposure and consumption was positive for the highest tertile (odds ratio: 1.49; 95% CI:
 1.20, 1.84; P &lt;0.001), but null for the intermediate (odds ratio: 1.03; 95% CI: 0.80, 1.34; P = 0.81) and lowest (odds ratio: 0.84; 95% CI: 0.51, 1.37; P = 0.49) tertiles. For high-BAS individuals, an increase of 1 SD in fast-food restaurants was associated with a 49% greater
 likelihood of having visited a fast-food restaurant in the previous week.
 View larger version: 
 In this window In a new window 

 Download as PowerPoint Slide 
 FIGURE 1 
Predicted log odds ratios (ORs) of having visited a local fast-food restaurant at low (1 SD below the mean), intermediate
 (mean), and high (1 SD above the mean) levels of fast-food restaurant exposure for tertiles of the Behavioral Activation System
 (BAS) scale from logistic regression analyses with values estimated for average-aged, middle-income men with a university
 education.
 
A secondary analysis was conducted on the basis of evidence that fast-food restaurants are more commonly found in deprived
 neighborhoods than in affluent neighborhoods ( 31 , 33 , 35 , 36 ). Hence, our results might not be specific to fast-food restaurant exposure, but rather to the socioeconomic characteristics
 of the participants&apos; immediate environment. To rule out this alternate explanation, we repeated the logistic regression analysis
 testing the main and interactive effects of BAS and fast-food restaurant exposure in association with fast-food consumption
 while accounting for the proportion of individuals under a low-income cutoff within 500 m of the participants&apos; residence ( Table 2 , model 2). The main effect of BAS and its interaction with fast-food restaurant exposure remained statistically significant.
 The proportion of low-income individuals living in proximity to participants was not statistically significantly associated
 with fast-food consumption.
 Previous Section Next Section 
DISCUSSION

The results of the present study indicate that the association between exposure to fast-food restaurants and fast-food consumption
 varies with an individual&apos;s predisposition to engage in rewarding behaviors. This study provides initial evidence for the
 moderating influence of reward sensitivity in a natural setting with a population-based sample. The results echo laboratory
 findings showing that a palatability manipulation was found to be effective only in participants who were highly sensitive
 to reward ( 14 ). The present study extends previous laboratory work by showing that such associations hold in a real-world setting.

Significant research efforts are underway to evaluate the importance of the food environment in shaping dietary behaviors
 that contribute to current obesity rates. The available evidence is mixed. Hence, there is a need for more refined hypotheses
 to evaluate under what circumstances or for whom environmental factors may influence energy balance-related behaviors ( 37 – 39 ) and obesity-related outcomes ( 40 ). Despite the recognition that individual factors are likely to play a role in moderating environmental influences on health
 and health behaviors, studies explicitly focusing on this issue have been scarce. Research investigating individual-level
 moderators of the association between the fast-food environment and health behaviors and outcomes have focused mainly on individual
 or area-level sociodemographic factors such as age, sex, education, income, and ethnicity ( 15 , 18 , 19 , 21 , 22 ). In these studies, none of these sociodemographic factors were found to statistically moderate the association between exposure
 to fast-food restaurant and behavioral/obesity outcomes.

Moving beyond sociodemographic moderating factors, the present study assessed and provides evidence for the moderating influence
 of psychological factors on the relation between the food environment and health-related behavior. Future studies are needed
 to explore the moderating role of other psychological constructs. Of particular relevance in the current obesogenic context
 is the ability of individuals to execute control over their impulses. Beyond the homeostatic regulation of eating, 2 brain
 systems appear to be important in the regulation of eating behavior. The present study examined one of these systems, namely
 the striatal-dopaminergic reward brain system, which underlies responsiveness to incentive-related environmental cues. The
 second system represents the cognitive processes involving the prefrontal cortex, which can inhibit cue-induced responses
 when these have negative consequences ( 41 , 42 ). Future research is needed to assess whether or not individual differences in inhibitory processes could also explain which
 individuals are more likely to respond to the current obesogenic food environment. Studies could also evaluate the moderating
 role of food-specific reward sensitivity as assessed by the newly developed power of food scale ( 43 ), which was developed specifically to represent individual differences in the psychological effect of living in food-abundant
 environments.

By identifying individual factors contributing to susceptibility to environmental influences, this study is relevant to 1 ) determining priorities for implementing environmental interventions by prioritizing groups of individuals who would be most
 likely to benefit from such interventions, and 2 ) developing broadly-based public health mass media campaigns addressing both factors predisposing (eg, sensitivity to reward)
 and reinforcing (eg, fast-food exposure) unhealthful diets as well as their combined influence. Identification of individuals
 at risk could be achieved by using simple assessment tools such as the BAS or the aforementioned power of food scale. Susceptible
 individuals could also be identified by determining potential correlates of reward sensitivity. In our sample, high-BAS individuals
 tended to come from poorer socioeconomic backgrounds. If this observation is generalizable, it implies that individuals of
 low socioeconomic backgrounds are potentially more sensitive to fast-food cues, although the direction of this association
 remains to be determined. These individuals are also more likely to live in deprived neighborhoods, which could potentially
 compound their risk of overconsuming fast-food given accumulating evidence that the density of fast-food outlets is greater
 in relatively more deprived neighborhoods ( 31 , 33 , 35 , 36 ).

Understanding which individuals are more susceptible to environmental food cues might also help tailor individual interventions
 addressing such vulnerabilities as either a complement or an alternative to environmental interventions. A recent study showed
 that the effectiveness of strategies to cope with food cravings depends on the psychological sensitivity to the food environment
 ( 44 ). Specifically, acceptance-based strategies, which entails recognizing and accepting (as opposed to controlling) one&apos;s thoughts
 and feelings about food, were found to be particularly effective in individuals who were considered more susceptible to the
 influence of food environment. Similar strategies could potentially be developed to help susceptible individuals coping with
 their tendency to respond to environmental food cues.

Limitations of this study include its cross-sectional design, which precludes inference regarding the direction of relations.
 In addition, fast-food consumption was based on a proxy measure using visits to a local fast-food restaurant in the previous
 week. Future studies could provide a more direct measure of eating habits as provided by food diaries and food-frequency questionnaires.
 Many studies investigating the health correlates of local fast-food environments have used a relative measure of exposure,
 such as the number of facilities per capita ( 45 ) or the proportions of restaurants that serve primarily fast-food ( 15 ). In the present study, we opted for a more direct measure of exposure. Results from post hoc analyses using a relative measure
 of fast-food restaurant exposure (proportion of restaurants that are fast-food) did not largely differ from the ones presented
 above. In addition, the study context limits the generalizability of the results. Our investigation was limited to 7 census
 tracts on the Island of Montreal, selected to be representative of the Montreal population in terms of spectrum of socioeconomic
 level and language. These census tracts may not have been representative of the fast-food environment of the entire Island.
 The low response rate could also have influenced the generalizability of the results. The sample, however, did not largely
 differ from the base population, except in terms of education, which has already been associated with higher response rates
 ( 46 ). Future studies are required to assess whether or not the moderating role of reward sensitivity extends to biological markers
 of cardiometabolic risk, which have also been associated with the fast-food environment.

In conclusion, reward-sensitive individuals may be more responsive to unhealthful cues in their immediate environment than
 are individuals less sensitive to reward signals. Understanding these moderating factors can provide valuable insights into
 environmental influences on health-related outcomes in vulnerable populations ( 39 ) and also help direct resources to those most likely to benefit through tailored interventions based on such observations
 ( 47 ). Future research is needed to develop health promotion and public health strategies recognizing and addressing the sensitivity
 to environmental food reward cues for certain individuals residing in unhealthful food environments.
 Previous Section Next Section 
Acknowledgments

We thank Karine Léger, geomatics specialist, for assistance in geocoding the participants&apos; and businesses&apos; addresses and extraction
 of area-level variables.

The authors&apos; responsibilities were as follows—LD, MD, and BK: contributed to the conception and design of the larger research
 program under which this report falls; CP, MD, and LD: formulated the study hypothesis for this study; MD and LG: supervised
 the survey data collection; YK: contributed to the acquisition of geospatial data; CP: prepared the data, conducted statistical
 analyses, and wrote the paper; and CP and MD: interpreted the data. All authors critically revised the article for important
 intellectual content and approved the final version. None of the authors declared a conflict of interest.
 
 Received September 11, 2009. Accepted December 23, 2009. 
 Previous Section 
REFERENCES

 1. ↵ 
 Cohen DA , Farley TA 
 . Eating as an automatic behavior . Prev Chronic Dis 2008 ; 5 : A23 (abstr) . Medline 2. ↵ 
 Blundell JE , Stubbs RJ , Golding C , et al 
 . Resistance and susceptibility to weight gain: individual variability in response to a high-fat diet . Physiol Behav 2005 ; 86 : 614 – 22 . CrossRef Medline 3. ↵ 
 Davis CA , Levitan RD , Reid C , et al 
 . Dopamine for “wanting” and opioids for “liking”: a comparison of obese adults with and without binge eating . Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009 ; 17 : 1220 – 5 . Medline 4. ↵ 
 Wang GJ , Volkow ND , Telang F , et al 
 . Exposure to appetitive food stimuli markedly activates the human brain . Neuroimage 2004 ; 21 : 1790 – 7 . CrossRef Medline 5. ↵ 
 Killgore WDS , Young AD , Femia LA , Bogorodzki P , Rogowska J , Yurgelun-Todd DA 
 . Cortical and limbic activation during viewing of high-versus low-calorie foods . Neuroimage 2003 ; 19 : 1381 – 94 . CrossRef Medline 6. ↵ 
 Epstein LH , Leddy JJ 
 . Food reinforcement . Appetite 2006 ; 46 : 22 – 5 . CrossRef Medline 7. ↵ 
 Wise RA 
 . Role of brain dopamine in food reward and reinforcement . Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 2006 ; 361 : 1149 – 58 . Abstract / FREE Full Text 8. ↵ 
 Rothemund Y , Preuschhof C , Bohner G , et al 
 . Differential activation of the dorsal striatum by high-calorie visual food stimuli in obese individuals . Neuroimage 2007 ; 37 : 410 – 21 . CrossRef Medline 9. ↵ 
 Beaver JD , Lawrence AD , van Ditzhuijzen J , Davis MH , Woods A , Calder AJ 
 . Individual differences in reward drive predict neural responses to images of food . J Neurosci 2006 ; 26 : 5160 – 6 . Abstract / FREE Full Text 10. ↵ 
 Davis C , Patte K , Levitan R , Reid C , Tweed S , Curtis C 
 . From motivation to behaviour: a model of reward sensitivity, overeating, and food preferences in the risk profile for obesity . Appetite 2007 ; 48 : 12 – 9 . CrossRef Medline 11. ↵ 
 Guerrieri R , Nederkoorn C , Stankiewicz K , et al 
 . The influence of trait and induced state impulsivity on food intake in normal-weight healthy women . Appetite 2007 ; 49 : 66 – 73 . CrossRef Medline 12. ↵ 
 Nederkoorn C , Braet C , Van Eijs Y , Tanghe A , Jansen A 
 . Why obese children cannot resist food: the role of impulsivity . Eat Behav 2006 ; 7 : 315 – 22 . CrossRef Medline 13. ↵ 
 Loxton NJ , Dawe S 
 . Alcohol abuse and dysfunctional eating in adolescent girls: the influence of individual differences in sensitivity to reward
 and punishment . Int J Eat Disord 2001 ; 29 : 455 – 62 . CrossRef Medline 14. ↵ 
 Guerrieri R , Nederkoorn C , Jansen A 
 . The interaction between impulsivity and a varied food environment: its influence on food intake and overweight . Int J Obes 2008 ; 32 : 708 – 14 . CrossRef 15. ↵ 
 Mehta NK , Chang VW 
 . Weight status and restaurant availability. A multilevel analysis . Am J Prev Med 2008 ; 34 : 127 – 33 . CrossRef Medline 16. 
 Maddock J 
 . The relationship between obesity and the prevalence of fast food restaurants: state-level analysis . Am J Health Promot 2004 ; 19 : 137 – 43 . CrossRef Medline 17. ↵ 
 Li F , Harmer PA , Cardinal BJ , et al 
 . Built environment, adiposity, and physical activity in adults aged 50-75 . Am J Prev Med 2008 ; 35 : 38 – 46 . CrossRef Medline 18. ↵ 
 Pearce J , Hiscock R , Blakely T , Witten K 
 . A national study of the association between neighbourhood access to fast-food outlets and the diet and weight of local residents . Health Place 2009 ; 15 : 193 – 7 . CrossRef Medline 19. ↵ 
 Jeffery RW , Baxter J , McGuire M , Linde J 
 . Are fast food restaurants an environmental risk factor for obesity . Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2006 ; 3 : 35 . CrossRef 20. 
 Simmons D , McKenzie A , Eaton S , et al 
 . Choice and availability of takeaway and restaurant food is not related to the prevalence of adult obesity in rural communities
 in Australia . Int J Obes 2005 ; 29 : 703 – 10 . CrossRef Medline 21. ↵ 
 Morland K , Wing S , Roux AD 
 . The contextual effect of the local food environment on residents&apos; diets: the Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities Study . Am J Public Health 2002 ; 92 : 1761 – 8 . Medline 22. ↵ 
 Burdette HL , Whitaker RC 
 . Neighborhood playgrounds, fast food restaurants, and crime: relationships to overweight in low-income preschool children . Prev Med 2004 ; 38 : 57 – 63 . CrossRef Medline 23. ↵ 
 Prentice AM , Jebb SA 
 . Fast foods, energy density and obesity: a possible mechanistic link . Obes Rev 2003 ; 4 : 187 – 94 . CrossRef Medline 24. ↵ 
 Daniel M , Kestens Y 
 . MEGAPHONE: Montreal epidemiological and geographic analysis of population health outcomes and neighbourhood effects . Montreal, Canada : Centre de Recherche du Centre Hospitalier de l&apos;Université de Montréal , 2007 . 25. ↵ Statistics Canada . 2001 Census Data . Ottawa, Canada : Statistics Canada , 2001 . 26. ↵ Tamec Inc. Zipcom database . Montreal, Canada : Tamec Inc , 2003 . 27. ↵ 
 Carver CS , White TL 
 . Behavioral inhibition, behavioral activation, and affective responses to impending reward and punishment: the BIS/BAS scales . J Pers Soc Psychol 1994 ; 67 : 319 – 33 . CrossRef 28. ↵ 
 Jorm AF , Christensen H , Henderson AS , Jacomb PA , Korten AE , Rodgers B 
 . Using the BIS/BAS scales to measure behavioural inhibition and behavioural activation: factor structure, validity and norms
 in a large community sample . Pers Individ Dif 1998 ; 26 : 49 – 58 . CrossRef 29. ↵ 
 Paquet C , Daniel M , Kestens Y , Léger K , Gauvin L 
 . Field validation of listings of food stores and commercial physical activity establishments from secondary data . Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2008 ; 5 : 58 . CrossRef Medline 30. ↵ 
 Daniel M , Kestens Y , Paquet C 
 . Demographic and urban form correlates of healthful and unhealthful food availability in Montréal, Canada: implications for
 the obesity epidemic . Can J Public Health 2009 ; 100 : 189 – 93 . Medline 31. ↵ 
 Hemphill E , Raine K , Spence JC , Smoyer-Tomic KE 
 . Exploring obesogenic food environments in Edmonton, Canada: the association between socioeconomic factors and fast-food outlet
 access . Am J Health Promot 2008 ; 22 : 426 – 32 . Medline 32. 
 Smoyer-Tomic KE , Spence JC , Raine KD , et al 
 . The association between neighborhood socioeconomic status and exposure to supermarkets and fast food outlets . Health Place 2008 ; 14 : 740 – 54 . CrossRef Medline 33. ↵ 
 Cummins SCJ , McKay L , MacIntyre S 
 . McDonald&apos;s restaurants and neighborhood deprivation in Scotland and England . Am J Prev Med 2005 ; 29 : 308 – 10 . CrossRef Medline 34. 
 Macdonald L , Cummins S , Macintyre S 
 . Neighbourhood fast food environment and area deprivation-substitution or concentration? Appetite 2007 ; 49 : 251 – 4 . CrossRef Medline 35. ↵ 
 Reidpath DD , Burns C , Garrard J , Mahoney M , Townsend M 
 . An ecological study of the relationship between social and environmental determinants of obesity . Health Place 2002 ; 8 : 141 – 5 . CrossRef Medline 36. ↵ 
 Pearce J , Blakely T , Witten K , Bartie P 
 . Neighborhood deprivation and access to fast-food retailing a national study . Am J Prev Med 2007 ; 32 : 375 – 82 . CrossRef Medline 37. ↵ 
 Kremers SPJ , de Bruijn GJ , Visscher TLS , van Mechelen W , de Vries NK , Brug J 
 . Environmental influences on energy balance-related behaviors: a dual-process view . Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2006 ; 3 : 9 . CrossRef Medline 38. 
 Ball K , Timperio AF , Crawford DA 
 . Understanding environmental influences on nutrition and physical activity behaviors: where should we look and what should
 we count? Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2006 ; 3 : 33 . CrossRef Medline 39. ↵ 
 Wells NM , Ashdown SP , Davies EHS , Cowett FD , Yang Y 
 . Environment, design, and obesity: opportunities for interdisciplinary collaborative research . Environ Behav 2007 ; 39 : 6 – 33 . Abstract / FREE Full Text 40. ↵ 
 Black JL , Macinko J 
 . Neighborhoods and obesity . Nutr Rev 2008 ; 66 : 2 – 20 . CrossRef Medline 41. ↵ 
 Schroeder BE , Binzak JM , Kelley AE 
 . A common profile of prefrontal cortical activation following exposure to nicotine- or chocolate-associated contextual cues . Neuroscience 2001 ; 105 : 535 – 45 . CrossRef Medline 42. ↵ 
 Goldstein RZ , Volkow ND 
 . Drug addiction and its underlying neurobiological basis: neuroimaging evidence for the involvement of the frontal cortex . Am J Psychiatry 2002 ; 159 : 1642 – 52 . CrossRef Medline 43. ↵ 
 Lowe MR , Butryn ML 
 . Hedonic hunger: a new dimension of appetite? Physiol Behav 2007 ; 91 : 432 – 9 . CrossRef Medline 44. ↵ 
 Forman EM , Hoffman KL , McGrath KB , Herbert JD , Brandsma LL , Lowe MR 
 . A comparison of acceptance- and control-based strategies for coping with food cravings: an analog study . Behav Res Ther 2007 ; 45 : 2372 – 86 . CrossRef Medline 45. ↵ 
 Powell LM , Auld MC , Chaloupka FJ , O&apos;Malley PM , Johnston LD 
 . Access to fast food and food prices: relationship with fruit and vegetable consumption and overweight among adolescents . Adv Health Econ Health Serv Res 2007 ; 17 : 23 – 48 . Medline 46. ↵ 
 Etter JF , Perneger TV 
 . Analysis of non-response bias in a mailed health survey . J Clin Epidemiol 1997 ; 50 : 1123 – 8 . CrossRef Medline 47. ↵ 
 MacKinnon DP , Luecken LJ 
 . How and for whom? Mediation and moderation in health psychology . Health Psychol 2008 ; 27 : S99 – 100 . CrossRef Medline 
 « Previous | Next Article » Table of Contents 
 This Article 
 
 First published January 20, 2010 ,
 doi: 10.3945/ ajcn.2009.28648 Am J Clin Nutr March 2010 vol. 91 no. 3 771-776 
 
 Abstract Free » Full Text Free Full Text (PDF) Free All Versions of this Article: 
 ajcn.2009.28648v1 91/3/771 most recent 
 
 
 Purchase Article 
 
 Classifications 

 
 Nutritional epidemiology and public health 
 
 
 Services 

 Email this article to a colleague Alert me when this article is cited Alert me if a correction is posted Article Usage Statistics Similar articles in this journal Similar articles in Web of Science Similar articles in PubMed Download to citation manager Reprints and Permissions 
 
 Citing Articles 

 Load citing article information Citing articles via Web of Science Citing articles via Google Scholar 
 
 Google Scholar 

 Articles by Paquet, C. Articles by Dubé, L. Search for related content 
 
 PubMed 

 PubMed citation Articles by Paquet, C. Articles by Dubé, L. 
 
 Agricola 

 Articles by Paquet, C. Articles by Dubé, L. 
 
 Related Content 

 Load related web page information 
 
 Navigate This Article 
 
 Top Abstract INTRODUCTION SUBJECTS AND METHODS RESULTS DISCUSSION Acknowledgments REFERENCES 
 
 Current Issue 
 
 July 2012, 96 (1) 
 
 
 
 Alert me to new issues of Am J Clin Nutr 
 
 About AJCN Information for Authors Manuscript Submission Editorial Board Reprints Permissions Advertising Feedback Advances in Nutrition The Journal of Nutrition Nutrition Notes 
 
 
 
The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition®
 Copyright © 2012 by the American Society for Nutrition 

9650 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, MD 20814
 
 Print ISSN: 0002-9165 Online ISSN: 1938-3207 
 For an alternate route to AJCN Online use this URL: http://intl.ajcn.org
	</body>
</document>
