<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007486" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/even-vegetarian-cant-stay-away-boston-market-474013.html" time="2012-07-13-00:27" support="4" score="0.006693570124859218" bingtitle="Even a Vegetarian Can&apos;t Stay Away from Boston Market! - Yahoo ..." webtitle="Even a Vegetarian Can&apos;t Stay Away from Boston Market! - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>... you may think it&apos;s not a great place to sit and eat. However, Boston Market is slightly better than a fast food restaurant as ... Plus, the drinks are serve yourself with ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Even a Vegetarian Can&apos;t Stay Away from Boston Market!
 Suzanne Rose , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Aug 5, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Boston Market 
 Flag Close Post a comment Mmmmm, just thinking about Boston Market makes me want to go get some NOW! I&apos;ve been to many Boston Markets in the metro Detroit area and had good experiences at all of them.
 What is it? 
Boston Market is kind of like a &quot;subway&quot; for dinner foods. You walk through the line just like subway, telling them what you want on your meal, and watch them put your plate together right in front of you. You pay at the end of the line, and then either go sit at a table or go home. They have most the meal items premade and kept warm so it&apos;s really a quick process. I&apos;ve seen them go through a line of 10 people in about 10 minutes! Multiple people work the line so that every person is waited on as quickly as possible.

 Do you really want to sit and eat there? 
Since I compared it to Subway, you may think it&apos;s not a great place to sit and eat. However, Boston Market is slightly better than a fast food restaurant as they have tables and chairs more like a normal restaurant. The locations I&apos;ve been to have plenty of seats so you can sit and relax with your friends almost as if you are in a normal restaurant and not feel like you are in a fast food joint.

Plus, the drinks are serve yourself with free refills - if you go home you&apos;ll miss out on the additional cups of soda or lemonade or whatever else is on tap for the day! It&apos;s a great place to grab your lunch because it runs fast without being &quot;fast food&quot;.

 What&apos;s it like to take it home? 
Although you can easily eat in the restaurant, getting your food to go is very easy. They just put the food into plastic containers (one for each &quot;plate&quot; or if you&apos;d rather individual cartons for each menu item) They bag it up nicely and if you can get home in 20 mins you&apos;ll still have a warm meal to eat!

The to-go containers are divided into 3 sections so you can fit 3 items and they will generally not leak from one to the other. You might request the gravy be put in a separate carton, but otherwise you&apos;ll be fine.

 So what can you eat???? 
The reason I dream of this place is their Macaroni and Cheese! as well as their Mashed Potatoes! but there is a lot more you can eat. The main theme is getting chicken, turkey or some kind of meat along with 2 side items. However if you are a vegetarian like me, you can get a meal called the &quot;Side Item Meal&quot; that is just 3 side items of your choosing. Each meal comes with a little cornbread which is also very delicious.

I almost always get 2 servings of the absolutely creamy and delicious Mac and Cheese along with 1 serving of Mashed Potatoes if I&apos;m being bad...or 1 serving of Steamed Veggies if I&apos;m being good! For the non-vegetarian you can get main meal items such as Hand-Carved Roasted Turkey or Original Rotisserie Chicken - but the Chicken seems to be the main pull for most of my friends.

They also have sandwiches made from all the meat items. My boyfriend has had these a few times but he usually opts for the Chicken meal instead just because you get more food that way.

My sister and mom love the Chicken Caesar Salad and I&apos;ve had the regular Caesar Salad once. They are really good, but I usually would rather get the Macaroni...did I mention it was so so creamy! I&apos;m usually tempted to get a cookie or brownie at the end of the line, but I think about all the carbs I&apos;m eating and say NO...which is hard because they look so good.

Finally, here&apos;s a quick list of the side items they rotate through that I have tried and loved (but they always have the Mac and Cheese!!)
Homestyle Mashed Potatoes, Savory Stuffing, Sweet Corn, Macaroni&amp;Cheese, Steamed Vegetable Medley, Hot Cinnamon Apples... mmmm, I wish I could go there for lunch today!

 Is it expensive? 
The prices are reasonable based on the quality of food you get. I would say it&apos;s close to the price you pay at Subway for a full &quot;meal&quot; so it&apos;s not bad at all. However if there are a lot of people it can get pricey which is why you have to get the Family Style meals.

A family style meal can be made to serve 3-6 people. All you do is say &quot;Meal for Three&quot; pick a meat and pick Three large sides. The sides they&apos;ll give you are (obviously) bigger then getting a one-person side so it&apos;s plenty to share! They put each side into individual containers so when you go home you can have a whole spread and each person chooses what to eat. These work well if you are having a few friends get together. I believe I paid just around 16$ for the meal for three last time I got it. 5.33$ a person? Not bad at all!

 Conclusion 
If you like eating Homemade food but don&apos;t like making it, Boston Market is a great solution. The downside is they are limited to their specialties such as Chicken or Turkey, but the upside is that it is high quality food every time! Boston Market is a healthy alternative to TV dinners! It&apos;s fresh, it&apos;s hot and it&apos;s very yummy! Visit http://www.bostonmarket.com/locations today to find out if there is one by you. Enjoy your meal!
 
Published by Suzanne Rose 

I write for fun and enjoy any site where I can share my knowledge and opinions. I like to review products, vacations, and my favorite TV shows :) I also randomly have advice to share, so I hope it helps som...  View profile 
 
 Cheap and Easy Meals Starting with a Box of Macaroni and Cheese You can take a box of macaroni and cheese and make a meal out of almost nothing. Macaroni and Cheese with Ham The author shares her families favorite homemade macaroni and cheese recipe. Super Easy&amp;Delicious Macaroni and Cheese for the Kids A recipe for a macaroni and cheese that your kids will ask for again and again. Baked Macaroni and Cheese Casserole The very best macaroni and cheese casserole that&apos;s a complete meal all in one. How to Make the Best Homemade Macaroni and Cheese The first step in making homemade macaroni and cheese is boiling the macaroniThe second step in making homemade macaroni and cheese is getting the first set of cheese readyT... 

 Homemade Spicy Macaroni and Chee... 
 
 Easy Meal Planning: Meal Assembly Saves Time and Money How to Create a Gourmet Thanksgiving Meal How to Take an Ordinary Meal and Make it an Extraordinary Summer Treat Iowa Kids Eat Free Meal Deals Macaroni and Cheese Review: Annie&apos;s Shells and Real Aged Cheddar Macaroni and Cheese FiberGourmet Macaroni and Cheese: Food Product Review Product Review: The New Kraft Macaroni and Cheese Crackers Are Put to the Play-da... 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.bostonmarket.com 
 
2 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Suzanne 2/9/2011 
According to the Boston Market website, which lists all the ingredients, the Mashed Potatoes DO NOT have gelatin in them.
 Really? 2/9/2011 
The author should have done their research before going to Boston Market. The mash potatoes have gelatin in them and cesar dressing (I&apos;m guessing that comes on the cesar salad) usually contains anchovies.
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
