<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007586" url="http://www.wjhg.com/news/headlines/20749554.html" time="2012-07-13-00:33" support="1" score="0.0005541853850913062" bingtitle="Unemployment Pay - WJHG - Home" webtitle="Unemployment Pay">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Florida’s unemployment pay is among the ... You could make more money working at a fast food restaurant. ... Caps have Cup champ Bruins on the brink ...</description>
	<body>
		July 12, 2012 
 Home News 
 News 

 NewsChannel 7 Today Regional National Noon Show Medical Minute Money Entertainment News Tips Videos 
 Weather 
 Weather 

 Interactive Weather Live Online iMap Radar Tropics Vipir 7 Hurricane Tracking Map Citizen Journalist Weather Weather Blog 
 Sports 
 Sports 

 Fish/Game Forecast Scoreboard 
 Community 
 Community 

 Around Town Birthday Club Health Links Home Pros MomsEveryday Military Greetings Pet of the Week Schools 
 Crime 
 Crime 

 Arrests Crime Stoppers Traffic Crash Data 
 Florida Lottery Connect Contests/Games 
 Contests/Games 

 Birthday Club Shipwreck Island Contest Checkered Flag Challenge Daily Deals Fantasy Golf Contest Jeopardy EXP Online Games iPad 2 Giveaway Ugliest Grill Contest 
 Station Info 
 Station Info 

 Contact Us Jobs at WJHG Job Search News Team Sales Team Program Guide Order a Copy of a News Story 
 Newschannel 7 Today 
 Newschannel 7 Today 

 Around Town Birthday Club Blooomberg Business Report NC7T Give-Aways 
 
 
 Around Town Healthlinks Home Pros Moms Everyday Contact Us 
 Posted: Tue 3:11 PM, Jun 24, 2008 A A Reporter: Whitney Ray Updated: Tue 10:16 PM, Jun 24, 2008 Back to News 
Unemployment Pay
 
Florida’s unemployment pay is among the lowest in the nation at a time when more people are out of a job. The state’s unemployment rate is up from a year ago and it could get worse.

For the last 6 months Renee Bryant has been looking for a job.

“The job market is very tight.”

Bryant use to make more than 30-thousand dollars a year. When she got her unemployment check it was less than half of her old salary.

“It’s shocking knowing that you’re normal pay is much much more than what that unemployment check really is.”

The maximum unemployment pay in Florida is 275 dollars a week. Someone whose old job paid one-hundred thousand dollars a year would receive the same employment check as someone with a salary of 30-thousand.

275 dollars a week breaks down to 6.88 cents an hour, that’s just 9 cents more than minimum wage.”

You could make more money working at a fast food restaurant. Tiffany Frazier, who will be a laid off at the end of the month, is shocked at the news.

“that’s ridiculous. I wouldn’t be able to live off of that.”

Work Force Plus is a state agency helping people find jobs and receive unemployment benefits. Kimberly Moore is a regional director for the agency. Moore says the low wages have motivated some people to job hunt.

“Our numbers in terms of individuals accessing our services though our one stop centers across the region have grown tremendously as a result.”

As the unemployed search frantically for jobs… more people are being laid off and the cost of gas continues to increase.

Hundreds of state, county, and city workers are expected to join the more than half million unemployed Floridians as budget cuts go into effect in July.

 Next Story &gt; Please enable JavaScript to view the powered by Disqus. powered by Disqus 
Most Active Stories

 Two Florida Boys Bitten By Gators 12 People Arrested in Internet Sex Sting in Bay County Bay Co Jail, Panama City, FL., Arrest Logs - July, 2012 4 Jailed as West Side Meth Lab is Raided 3 People Dead in Panama City Shooting Single Vehicle Accident Near Vernon Kills Recent Bay High Grad Small Plane Crash Lands In Pond Woman Posing as an Attorney Arrested Glenn Burkett, US Senate Candidate at the Capitol Long Beach Area Fire 
 
Website Policy

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy/YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS Advertising EEO Statement Mobile Version 
 
Quick Links

 Station Info Around Town Search FCC Form 398 
 
Categories

 News Weather Sports Community Crime 
 8195 Front Beach Road
Panama City Beach, FL 32407
Station: 850-234-7777
News: 850-230-5221
Fax: 850-233-6647 
Gray Television, Inc. - Copyright © 2002-2012 - Designed by Gray Digital Media - Powered by Clickability

User Agent: Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 6.0; Windows NT 5.0) - 20749554
	</body>
</document>
