<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007115" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/40/1547551/restaurant/South-Southwest/City-Barbeque-Indianapolis" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="9" score="0.02905092350910375" bingtitle="City Barbeque - South/Southwest - Indianapolis | Urbanspoon" webtitle="City Barbeque - South/Southwest - Indianapolis | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001322" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000764" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>... the premeditated pulled pork, I couldn&apos;t put ... but the dining room looked like a typical fast food restaurant. ... in line 3 people brought back their tray because ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Indianapolis » Indianapolis » South&amp;Southwest » City Barbeque 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Chicago Cincinnati Columbus Lexington Los Angeles Louisville New York More... 
 
City Barbeque
 
(317) 865-1220
 South/Southwest 7863 US 31 South 
 Indianapolis , IN 46227 
 citybbq.com 
 on facebook.com 

Added by FLOeatsIndy 
 See all 16 reviews Cuisine Barbecue , Southern/Soul Features Kid Friendly , Outdoor Dining Menu $$ $10-15 per entree Pulled pork, greens&amp;vinegar slaw, Sampler View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   107 people have voted 85 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Bob&apos;s Tu Your Door Pizza 86% $ Greenwood - Pizza 510 N Meridian St 
 
 China Garden 92% $ South/Southwest - Chinese 7015 Madison Ave 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 September 18, 2011 Likes it Barbecued Adventures The company’s slogan is, “All Smoke. No Mirrors.” We found that statement to be true. The brisket in particular was excellent and perhaps the best we’ve had since crossing th More from Barbecued Adventures September 12, 2010 Likes it FLOEats Indy City Barbeque, a small chain out of Ohio, made the south side the lucky recipient of a new bbq place last week! You can&apos;t have too many bbq joints! We had been watching for weeks as the... More from FLOEats Indy 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 14, 2012 Really likes it Don&apos;t listen to the naysayers... by J Annen ( 4 reviews ) I don&apos;t get why people who have one bad experience feel like it&apos;s their responsibility to rip a place apart. I&apos;ve been to City BBQ in Greenwood about a half dozen times in the last few months and it has been enjoyable every single time. Not once have I had bad service or bad food. Anyone that complains about a little gristle or fat shouldn&apos;t be going to a bbq joint in the first place. Being from the South I didn&apos;t have many good expectations for the Northern interpretation of bbq, but I have to say that I am impressed every time I go back. And if you have to wait in line deal with it; that&apos;s the sign of a good restaurant. April 28, 2012 Mobile review by Victoria Peard Karamanski ( 1 review ) Very good pulled pork sandwich!!! Tender meat, no fat soft bun! Yummy March 15, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by indyfoodie ( 41 reviews ) Fresh salads and i could eat their potato salad by the bucket! Their pulled meats tend to be dry. January 22, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Outside Smokers were Cool, BUT.......! by mhav2k ( 314 reviews ) My wife, daughter, and I tried this BBQ joint chain last weekend. The food proved to be less than uneventful. I must admit that none of the meat we sampled was fatty, grisly, or chewy, compared to other BBQ we&apos;ve had around town from other chain based BBQ restaurants.. My wife loves sides of green beans and she is pretty forgiving as long as any vegetables are green. Apparently with the flat worm looking and over cooked version of green beans they managed to turn her off the pods for a few days. Didn&apos;t think it was possible. I myself was looking forward to some Carolina style BBQ (vinegar flavored) pulled pork. Even after I ordered the premeditated pulled pork, I couldn&apos;t put enough of the table squirt bottled supplied vinegar based sauce to even taste the difference..... As much as I&apos;ve seemed to give this place a bad review, you should try yourself and form your own opinion. BBQ is so subjective!! We&apos;ve had much much much worse BBQ, but we will not purposely drive towards Greenwood to seek out this joint again. We did however enjoy the&quot;down south&quot;BBQ shack ambiance decor with the chain purchased art. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful December 31, 2010 Likes it Great Q! by Soup Fork ( 139 reviews ) WOW! So happy to eat here. Pulled pork sandwich was piled high with moist, smokey meat. Side of greenbeans was very flavorful. Cannot wait to try it all! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 4, 2011 Likes it good but... by YodaLover ( 230 reviews ) My husband and I stopped here Friday night. We were initially turned off by the prices. Their prices for their meat, sandwiches and sides were comparable to Squealers or GT South&apos;s but the dining room looked like a typical fast food restaurant. I have a problem paying sit-down restaurant prices for a fast food environment. We both ordered the pulled chicken sandwiches. For sides, he got Mac and cheese and hush puppies. I got mac and cheese and smashed potatoes. The chicken bbq was good. Sometimes with pulled chicken bbq, there is fat/gristle and we didn&apos;t find any in our sandwiches which was good. The meat is marinated/tossed with some sort of broth/juice that keeps it moist... I really liked it but my husband thought it had too much pepper in it. The Mac and cheese was really good as were the smashed potatoes and my husband liked the hush puppies but did note that they were sweeter than the Long John Silvers variety. Their sauce selection was nice... there were 4-5... more» My husband and I stopped here Friday night. We were initially turned off by the prices. Their prices for their meat, sandwiches and sides were comparable to Squealers or GT South&apos;s but the dining room looked like a typical fast food restaurant. I have a problem paying sit-down restaurant prices for a fast food environment. We both ordered the pulled chicken sandwiches. For sides, he got Mac and cheese and hush puppies. I got mac and cheese and smashed potatoes. The chicken bbq was good. Sometimes with pulled chicken bbq, there is fat/gristle and we didn&apos;t find any in our sandwiches which was good. The meat is marinated/tossed with some sort of broth/juice that keeps it moist... I really liked it but my husband thought it had too much pepper in it. The Mac and cheese was really good as were the smashed potatoes and my husband liked the hush puppies but did note that they were sweeter than the Long John Silvers variety. Their sauce selection was nice... there were 4-5 to choose from. I do have to wonder about the food safety of the sauces sitting out on the tables all day... all the bbq sauces i&apos;ve ever purchased say refrigerate after opening. It was nice that they had both diet mountian dew and diet doctor pepper on their fountain. So, it was a decent meal. portions were nice, but for the price it wasn&apos;t as comfortable as other places that are sit-down restaurants. Yes, we would have had to pay a tip, but if i&apos;m going to spend almost $30 for 2 meals by the time you add sides and a drink... i&apos;d rather be comfortable. May 5, 2011 OK, but... by CDP ( 39 reviews ) Our group of golfers first trip to City BBQ was on a Tuesday with Buck a Bone Ribs on tap. We all enjoyed the food and the service was fast&amp;efficent. Most liked the ribs, and I thought the sausage was very good. I still prefer Famous Dave&apos;s for the sausage and the others had mixed reviews for the ribs compared to Dave&apos;s. I thought the cuke salad was pretty good but undersized. Our group is kinda sold on Famous Dave&apos;s for franchise BBQ. November 20, 2010 Likes it wow! great new bbq place! by local first ( 13 reviews ) Had North Carolina Pulled Pork, smashed potatoes (seasonal side) and hush puppies - Wow what portions! They had a a small toppings bar (pickles, onions, hot peppers...) and 3 Warm bbq sauces to choose from. Also 6 kinds of sauce at your table. No waiters - no tipping but dinning room was staffed to keep it clean and stocked. Noticed a sign about fried pickles while I was there - Can&apos;t wait to try those next! The only thing I wished they had was fried biscuits. Will be back and bringing my bbq loving friends! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 7, 2012 city barbeque by stucknorthrip ( 1 review ) Dont waste your money!!! I ordered the bbq chicken, stuck my fork in it and the blood came squirting out. I have never seen chicken so under cooked. The fries was greasy and limp and just plain nasty. There was us and another couple that decided to try City, we had headed to Daves famous bbq, and oh how I wished we hadnt stopped at Citys and wasted our money. Citys did refund my money and brought me out a pulled pork sandwich(this was brought out on a piece of paper I might add) upon biting into it I just about broke a tooth on a bone. The only other remark I have to say is DAVES IM SORRY FOR BETRAYING YOU AND GOING TO CITYS, IT WILL NEVER HAPPEN AGAIN. March 25, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Kevin H Spencer ( 5 reviews ) Famous Daves had good food and kitsch. City BBQ keeps its concentration on food and in generous options. Tuesday is always Buck A Bone night. Overall rib quality is a very tiny bit below competitors but they easily make up for it with service speed, quality smoked goods, and very friendly service that doesn&apos;t feel corporate. August 13, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Not one of the best BBQ joints in Indy by Mark ( 3 reviews ) I went to eat at City BBQ last Tuesday at noon. I first had to stand in line for 15 minutes while one cashier took orders. You would think at Lunch time they would have at least two cashiers. While standing in line 3 people brought back their tray because something was wrong with the order and one guys chicken was overcooked. I almost left and I should have. At least I decided to just order a sanwich. It was $6.00 for the sandwich. Litterally just a sandwich. Not even 20 cents worth of chips. They wanted $3.00 for two small sides, and I passed. I took my order to go. It was up quickly. I went home and open the bag. Inside was my wrapped sandwich. The first thing that caught my eye was the bun. Just a cheap small bun about the size of a fast food $1 menu sandwich bun. The next thing that caught my eye was all the fat and gristle on the meat. Took me forever to pick that nasty stuff off. Good thing I did because there was a big bone in my sandwich. Scary! if I would have just... more» I went to eat at City BBQ last Tuesday at noon. I first had to stand in line for 15 minutes while one cashier took orders. You would think at Lunch time they would have at least two cashiers. While standing in line 3 people brought back their tray because something was wrong with the order and one guys chicken was overcooked. I almost left and I should have. At least I decided to just order a sanwich. It was $6.00 for the sandwich. Litterally just a sandwich. Not even 20 cents worth of chips. They wanted $3.00 for two small sides, and I passed. I took my order to go. It was up quickly. I went home and open the bag. Inside was my wrapped sandwich. The first thing that caught my eye was the bun. Just a cheap small bun about the size of a fast food $1 menu sandwich bun. The next thing that caught my eye was all the fat and gristle on the meat. Took me forever to pick that nasty stuff off. Good thing I did because there was a big bone in my sandwich. Scary! if I would have just eaten the sandwich. The sauce was about a 5 out of 10. Nothing special. There is just too many great BBQ joints in Indy to waste time going back to this one. For under $7.00, I can get a much larger sandwich, chips and a side from other BBQ joints. Overall, below average food, average sauce and very little value for the $$. October 3, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Jeff Peterson ( 1 review ) Good selection of well prepared meats. Sides simple but compliment nicely. Will go back again. March 20, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jamie ( 2 reviews ) Great food! Had the pulled pork sandwich with fries and green beans. I like the self-service aspect of it. Wish there was one on the northside of Indy. November 7, 2010 Likes it Delish by M ( 1 review ) My fiance and I love going to City Barbeque. The wait in line is worth it. Sure, it&apos;s price is comparable to Famous Dave&apos;s or Smokey Bones, but you don&apos;t have the 20% tip and that does help out the wallet. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by mhav2k Street View by mhav2k Mac&amp;Cheese 
 All 8 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Boston Market $$ South/Southwest - Fast Food, Chicken, Diner La Bamba 85% $ South/Southwest - Mexican, Fast Food, Southwestern Noodles&amp;Company 82% $ South/Southwest - Noodle Shop, Asian, American Moe&apos;s Southwest Grill 86% $ South/Southwest - Tacos, Fast Food, Tex-Mex Dunkin&apos; Donuts (US 31S) $ South/Southwest - Donuts, Coffee, Breakfast/Brunch 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 city barbeque city barbeque prices city bbq indianapolis city bbq prices city barbeque reviews 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
