<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007071" url="http://trend-dir.net/interior-design/interior-designs/the-interior-design-of-fast-food-restaurants-buns-telo/" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="1" score="0.0016074227861682456" bingtitle="The interior design of fast food restaurants buns Telo | Interior ..." webtitle="The interior design of fast food restaurants buns Telo  | Interior Design Trends and Ideas">
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>Although a fast food restaurant with ... TABLES Tables; Terrace furniture; The role of the fireplace; Luxury and modern fast food restaurant ... phase and the end ...</description>
	<body>
		Interior Design Trends and Ideas 
 ﻿ 
 
Recent Posts

 Foyer as a transitional space terrace and living room / foyer as the transition space Part 2 Arranging workspace joining bedroom / Setting Foyer as a transitional space terrace and living room / foyer as the transition space Part 1 Tips renovating house become place effort / Add a Business SaveIfXMLInvalid ins a house Part 2 Designing a small mosque in our homes The canopy protects the home from heat and rain / canopy to protect houses from heat and rain Interior kitchen (kitchen set) is simple and effective with breakfast table Interior design kitchen and dining room opposite the park The interior design of fast food restaurants buns Telo Learning from the work of architect IM Pei Part 1 Some questions about the Kitchen Part 1 Some questions about the Kitchen Part 2 Learning from the work of architect IM Pei Part 2 Architecture of Antonio Gaudi. Learning from the maestro of organic architecture dedicated Decorative world of Frank Lloyd Wright (part 1) 
 
 
 Jan 12 2011 

 The interior design of fast food restaurants buns Telo 
 
Published by lima at 12:21 pm under Interior Designs 
 
The interior design is made for requests from the buns Telo who want to make interior design INTELOKTUAL cafe, a cafe a liaison between the two cities of Surabaya and Malang. Cafe is expected to provide a comfortable feel for the businessman as well as motorists who cross the main road between the towns of Malang and Surabaya. The concept: smart impressed because there are facilities for wi-fi internet connection, fast food, free ticketing and so on.

 Beds–attention to detail beds and furniture for the living blinds for your sun room 

 

 Ultra modern fast food restaurant design 

In concept, try to adapt the situation of buildings which have become, with so many elements of wood and aluminum doors and window frames, which actually contributed very large as a decorative element . Therefore, the design is made with more simple to neutralize the number of lines of wood and frame it so not too crowded, as well as to make it more cozy.

 House Design ECONOMIC MOUNTAIN Lighting: lamps and chandeliers living room interior design- armchair and sofas 

 

 Luxury McDonald’s Design

Although a fast food restaurant with innovative dishes made from Telo, this design is expected to be a comfortable place for visitors and is able to embody a lifestyle that smart, fast and innovative. Product Telo’s famous dumplings with innovation attempted to be adapted with smart interior which also (hopefully

 Wool mattresses, latex foam, spring 

 a bedroom and a well-articulated range of proposals a chair–both elegant and simple 

 

 Luxury Waku Waku fast food restaurant design 

This design is still under consultation and the end result might be different.

BAHASA VERSION: Interior Design for buns Telo Fast Food Restaurant
This interior design is made by requests from WHO Telo buns Want To make INTELOKTUAL cafe interior design, as the cafe liaison Between the two cities of Surabaya and Malang. The cafe is expected to Provide a comfortable feel for the businessmen and motorists WHO cross the main road Between the city of Malang and Surabaya. The concept: smart impression Because there are facilities for wi-fi internet connection, fast food, free tickets and so forth.

 TABLES Tables Terrace furniture The role of the fireplace 

 

 Luxury  and modern fast food restaurant 

In concept, Trying to adapt to situations of the building of the which is already built, with lots of wood elements and aluminum frame doors and windows, the which in fact have Contributed so much as a decorative element. Therefore, the design is made with more simple to neutralize many lines of wood and frame it so That not too Crowded, and make it more cozy.

 Prefabricated house design MOUNTAIN Sliding interior doors Sofa set: distinction and modernity 

 

 Luxury fast food interior design 

Although this is a fast food restaurant with innovative dishes made from Telo (sweet potato), design is expected to be a comfortable place and cans accommodate Lifestyles That is smart, fast and innovative . Telo buns products are known for the innovation, attempted to be adapted with smart interiors Also the which (hopefully:)

This design is still in consultation phase and the end result Would probably be different.


 Share | 
Related Posts

 Tips renovating house become place effort / Add a Business SaveIfXMLInvalid ins a house Part 2 Designing a small mosque in our homes The canopy protects the home from heat and rain / canopy to protect houses from heat and rain A studio feminized Modern Bamboo House Construction 

You might also like

 
 “Residential Green”which Attractive 
 Embodied in a resort setting in the land area of 1600 m? is located in the township areas in South Jakarta.... 
 
 Morocco home WITH STYLE 
 The house is located in Serpong is a residence of Ir. R. Sulistyo Wicaksono, IAI is fondly called by... 
 
 The concept of Occupancy“Light”Synergize 
 The building that stands on an area 9m x 22m with elongated shape to the back of this place needs a space... 
 
 GALLERY concept MULTIFUNCTION design 
 he idea to build a very exotic place comes as the Mulyadi, who is also the owner of an export businessman... 
 
 TROPICAL, modern and elegant 
 Shelter located in the elite house in Semarang, Central Java is indeed different. Two-storey house with... 
 
 Luxury Ideas 
 No responses yet 
 
 Trackback URI | Comments RSS 
 
Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (hidden) (required) 

 Website 

 

 
 

 
 
Categories

 Bathroom Bathroom designs Bedroom Bedroom designs Child room Decor Decoration ideas Dining Room Designs Furniture Interior Designs Kitchen Kitchen designs Living room Luxury interior Office Designs Outdoor ideas 
 Search for: 
Tags
 
Archives

 January 2011 December 2010 
 
 
 Powered by Interior Design Trends and Ideas Interior Design Trends and Ideas Copyright©2012 All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
