<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007121" url="http://www.edmunds.com/hyundai/equus/2012/consumer-reviews.html" time="2012-07-13-00:06" support="1" score="0.0004802576498049745" bingtitle="2012 Hyundai Equus Consumer Reviews - New Cars, Used Cars, Car ..." webtitle="2012 Hyundai Equus   Consumer Reviews">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Get Monthly Payment; Incentives &amp; Rebates; Search Inventory; True Cost to Own® ... opened it up yet, but it obviously has worlds of power. 0 to 60 probably near 5 secs.</description>
	<body>
		edmunds.com Ask the Car People. SM | | | Mobile | Help | Newsletter | Inside Line is your current car. Change it .

 
 New Cars 
 Calculators Car Finder Compare Cars Find a Dealer Get Monthly Payment Incentives&amp;Rebates Search Inventory True Cost to Own ® 
 Used Cars 
 Search Inventory Appraise Your Car Certified Cars Selling Tips True Cost to Own ® 
 Inventory 
 New Car Inventory Used Car Inventory 
 Car Reviews 
 Car Reviews and Road Tests Consumer Car News Best Cars Lists Awards Long-Term Road Tests Dealer Ratings and Reviews Read and Write Consumer Reviews 
 Tips&amp;Advice 
 Buying a Car Leasing a Car Selling a Car Family and Car Safety Fuel Economy&amp;Green Cars Car Technology Auto Financing Auto Insurance Auto Warranty Car Maintenance Driving Tips 
 Forums 
 Answers Browse Discussions Search Forums 
 
 Home &gt; New Cars &gt; Hyundai &gt; Equus &gt; 2012 Equus &gt; Consumer Reviews 

 You have saved this page | See all saved pages 
2012 Hyundai Equus Consumer Reviews
 share cancel 
 Pricing Reviews&amp;Specs Photos Inventory Quick Quotes 
 View photos 
 Average Consumer Rating 5
 Total Reviews
 Write a review 

MSRP from $59,000 
 PRICE WITH OPTIONS Get a Free Price Quote View reviews for a specific Equus model: All Equus models Signature (5.0L V8 8-speed Automatic) - (5 reviews ) Ultimate (5.0L V8 8-speed Automatic) Sort by: Most Recent Highest Rating Lowest Rating Most Helpful Top of the line luxury at a fraction of the cost By peteranger on 07/09/12 10:05 AM (PDT) 
Vehicle

2012 Hyundai Equus Signature 4dr Sedan (5.0L 8cyl 8A)

Review

I traded in my BMW 745i for the 2011 Hyundai Signature Series Equus, and apart from some irritating aspects of the i-pod and navigation systems, I&apos;m delighted with the smooth, comfortable, QUIET! ride of this luxury ride.
To boot, I get 27+ mpg on the highway and 20 mpg overall using regular gas, and the valet service, where the Hyundai dealer delivers a loaner Equus to my house when picking up mine for service is a major plus.


The exterior will remind you of the top of the line Lexus, and the interior is similar to the S600 series Benz (the suede like head liner, analog clock in the dash, etc.).
Compare sticker prices with the competition and you&apos;ll be astounded at the savings.
 Read the full review 
 Comment Report it 11 of 11 people found this review helpful Most Enjoyable Car I Ever Owned!! By markie7 on 02/03/12 18:54 PM (PST) 
Vehicle

2012 Hyundai Equus Signature 4dr Sedan (5.0L 8cyl 8A)

Review

Very luxurious vehicle.
Solid smooth ride. Floats on the highway like being in a cloud. I fell safe, encapsulated from the noisy world, and most of all, feel extremely pampered from the moment I step inside.
Very quick for a big sedan. Great displayes, comfy seats, and intuitive navi systems. All luxury features in competing car manufacturers are here, but for less money.
But, let us be real: $60K is still alot of money. But, nice things cost money.
However, the value for dollar is stronger in this product than the others. Also, there is some exclusivity.
Most people are still eyeing the equus.
Everyone (and their mother) have BMWs and the like. Be different! Stand out! Enjoy the ride.
 Read the full review 
 Comment Report it 16 of 16 people found this review helpful Equus - 2012 with a bigger engine By kabirent1 on 12/11/11 22:01 PM (PST) 
Vehicle

2012 Hyundai Equus Signature 4dr Sedan (5.0L 8cyl 8A)

Review

Just got my 2012 Equus yesterday.
I was on a waiting list. I am a little skeptical of reviewers who got it weeks ago - how did they get the car when mine was one of the first off the boat from Korea?

Anyways, the car, after 2 days is a lot of fun and seems to be a great value.
It rides a little on the soft side, but with the new, more powerful engine, its acceleration is strong.
Its exceedingly quiet, roomy, comfortable, and has a long list of features. The promised support seems to be very nice - time will tell if that turns out to be truth or hype.


In short, if you are looking for a luxurious ride, don&apos;t need to impress anyone , and want to save big $$, this is worth a look.
 Read the full review 
 Comments (3) Report it 29 of 76 people found this review helpful My new Equus- 2012 model By jfred on 11/08/11 12:45 PM (PST) 
Vehicle

2012 Hyundai Equus Signature 4dr Sedan (5.0L 8cyl 8A)

Review

I have just had the car a short time and I held out for the 2012 model due to vastly improved engine and transmission. (429 HP and 8 speed).

I haven&apos;t opened it up yet, but it obviously has worlds of power. 0 to 60 probably near 5 secs.

It is ultra quiet and very comfortable. The seat has many adjustments and the control for same is very handy.

It is priced many thousands (20 to 35K) less than M-B S series, BMW 7 series, or the big Lexus, or Audi A8.

Go drive it and see for yourself!r Audi A8 to 30K) less than any equivalent car from BMW, M-B,
 Read the full review 
 Comments (1) Report it 9 of 56 people found this review helpful NOT COMFORTABLE By kfd1 on 10/25/11 10:13 AM (PDT) 
Vehicle

2012 Hyundai Equus Signature 4dr Sedan (5.0L 8cyl 8A)

Review

The long distance comfort of this car is of serious concern. I bought this car and took a 900 mile trip a day later. Three hours into trip, my back was screaming in pain. By the end of trip, I was incapacited, with shooting pains in legs, back and arms. I am a long distance driver and convinced the Hyundia Dealer to buy the car back after showing them the articles on Autoblog about the seats (google Equus Long Distance). The dealer purchase a Lexus LS460 (14,000 miles) and I traded up. I just completed a 600 mile trip in the Lexus. No back pain or any other pain. The front seats in the Equus are poorly designed. No way to modify them, I tried and even had a pad made with memory foam.
 Read the full review 
 Comments (3) Report it 
More on 2012 Hyundai Equus
 
 2012 Hyundai Equus Consumer Discussions 2012 Hyundai Equus Consumer Reviews 2012 Hyundai Equus Features and Specs 
 
 2012 Hyundai Equus Review 2012 Hyundai Equus Reliability 2012 Hyundai Equus Safety 
 
Research Models
 Select vehicle make All models All years go 
Advertisement
 
Advertisement
 
Advertisement
 
Edmunds Insurance Estimator
 
TCO ® insurance data for this vehicle coming soon...

For an accurate quote, contact our trusted partner below.
 * Explanation 
Advertisement
 
Advertisement
 
Recently Viewed


 Select your vehicles COMPARE 
Explore Edmunds
 


 Site Map | Glossary | Inside Line | Industry News | Auto Shows | About Mobile 

©Edmunds.com, Inc.
 Favorite Listings ( 0 ) Favorite Listings ( 0 ) Close Sync to Your Mobile Device 
A text message will be sent to your cell phone with a link to access your Favorites Listings from our mobile website.
 * Cell Phone: (Required Field) 
 - - 
 Send Cancel 
 Message sent successful! 

Expect to receive a text message on your cell phone within the next 15 minutes

You must tap the link in the text to make your Favorites Listings accessible from our
 mobile website.
 Track Your Favorite Listings 
 Keep track of your favorite View your listings anytime No need to sign-in or register 
 (All listings are saved to this computer) Edmunds can email this dealer ( 0 ) 
 No longer available
	</body>
</document>
