<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007849" url="http://www2.asd.wednet.edu/Pioneer/barnard/wri/exp.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:48" support="3" score="0.002083357104745394" bingtitle="Expository Essay Prompts" webtitle="Expository Essay Prompts">
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>Select one of the math problems ... doctor&apos;s office, sports stadium, fast food restaurant ... they do to make our community a better place. Your ...</description>
	<body>
		Expository Essay  Prompts 

 Expository  (informative) writing communicates information to the reader to share  knowledge or to convey messages, instructions, and ideas. It involves  communicating information at various levels of understanding, such as  describing information, explaining or interpreting information, clarifying  a process, or evaluating information. Examples include writing reports  or letters. 

 The  informative topics in 1998 National Assessment of Educational Progress  writing assessment required students to write on specified subjects in  a variety of formats, such as reports, reviews, and letters. Several of  the informative topics asked students to respond to letters, cartoons,  or articles. The writing assessment prompts presented students with a  variety of tasks, such as offering advice to younger students and reporting  to a school committee. 
 
 If  you could make changes in your school lunchroom what would they be? Most  people like one particular animal more than others. What is your favorite  animal? Why is it your favorite? Everyone  has days that they will always remember as being very special. Think  about a special day that you have had. Write an essay telling why it  was so special. Rules  are important. What are the most important rules at your school and  why are they important? If  you could choose any animal for a class pet, what would you choose and  why? Explain  why it is important to learn to read. If  you could change places with another person for a whole day, who would  you change places with and why would you choose that person? We  are learning all the time. Some of our learning takes place in school  and some outside of school. Write about something you have learned recently  and how it has affected you. Think  of the ideal job for you when you grow up. Now think of reasons why  this would be a good job for you. Write an essay to explain why this  is your ideal job. Think  of a book that you have read and really enjoyed. Write an essay explaining  why you really enjoyed that book. Imagine  that time travel to the past was possible. Think of where and when you  would like to go for a visit. Write an essay telling where and when  you would go in the past and explain why you choose to go there. Your  cousin is moving to your town. Write a letter explaining why your town  is such a wonderful place to live. Imagine  that you had no TV, computer, or video games for one week. Think of  some activities that you can do instead to keep you busy and out of  trouble. Write an essay to explain what you can do to keep occupied  in a week of no TV, computer, or video games. We  all have a place where we can imagine or go where we want to be alone  and relax. Think of your favorite place. Now write an essay explaining  why this place is your favorite. Think  about your favorite year of school. Explain why it was your favorite  year. Friends  are important, but everyone has a different opinion of what makes a  good friend. Explain what, in your opinion makes a good friend. Some  teachers are special. Explain why one particular teacher in your life  was so special. If  your principal asked you to write your opinion about what needed to  be changed in your school what would you write? Due  to trouble on the playground, the principal has sent home a letter stating  there will no longer be an after-lunch recess. Write a letter to convince  your principal to continue after-lunch recess. Before you start writing,  think about the problem during recess. Think about why students need  recess. Think about the benefits for the teachers. Decide what students  and teachers can do to correct the problem. Think about the results  of keeping recess during school. Now write a letter to convince the  principal to continue after-lunch recess. Your  brother or sister is having a birthday. Your grandparents have asked  for ideas for a present. Write a letter to your grandparents suggesting  a gift your brother or sister might like. Before you start writing,  think about what the gift could be. Think about why your younger brother  or sister would like the gift. Think about how your grandparents can  locate this gift. Now write a letter to your grandparents suggesting  a birthday gift for your younger brother or sister. Your  class has been studying ways of improving our environment. One of these  ways is by recycling items you would normally throw away. This might  be an empty paper towel roll, empty milk carton, or an old telephone  book. Write 3 - 5 paragraphs for your teacher explaining how you can  create or recycle something from a discarded item or throwaway. Before  you start writing, think about what item you are going to recycle. Think  about what new item you are going to create from it. Decide on the materials  needed for this project. Think about the clear, step-by-step directions  for making your recycled item. Decide how this recycled item will be  useful. Now write a paragraph or more for your teacher explaining how  you will create something new from a discarded item. Your  teacher has asked you to write an essay answering the question, &quot;Why  do you like your favorite subject in school?&quot; Before you begin writing,  think about which school subject you like best. Consider exactly what  it is you like about that subject. Think about interesting things you  have learned or done in that subject. Now write an essay for your teacher  telling why you like your favorite school subject. Your  teacher has scheduled a unit test for Monday. Write a letter to your  teacher requesting this unit test be rescheduled for another day. Before  you start writing, think about why this test should be rescheduled.  Think about what could be done to better prepare the students for the  test. Consider the benefits for the students and the teacher for rescheduling.  Now write a letter to your teacher requesting a unit test be rescheduled  to another day. You  lost your watch while visiting a friend in another town. Your friend&apos;s  mother found your watch and mailed it to you. Write a letter to your  friend&apos;s mother thanking her for returning the lost watch. Before you  start to write, think about why your watch is important to you. Think  about why you need your watch. Think about how you felt when your watch  was returned to you. Now write a letter to your friend&apos;s mother thanking  her for returning the lost watch. Describe  a favorite place you have visited. Write 3 - 5 paragraphs or describing  the place. Before you begin writing, think about the location of your  favorite place. Think about when and why you like to visit this place.  Think about the benefits of visiting this place. Now write a description  of your favorite place. Your  friend wants to come to your house. Write directions telling how to  get to your house from school. Before you start writing, think about  the details you will need in your directions. Think about landmarks  you pass and the order in which you pass them. Think about any roads  you will need to travel. Consider having a map to illustrate your directions.  Now write a paragraph or more explaining to your teacher how to get  to your house from school. You  have just received a letter from a friend inviting you to go along on  a family hiking trip in the Cascade Mountains. Write a letter to your  friend accepting the invitation. Before you start writing, think about  what you need to know about the trip. Think about what activities might  take place. Think about any special equipment you may need. Now write  a letter to your friend accepting your friend&apos;s invitation to go on  a hiking trip. A  classmate of yours had an accident on the playground during recess and  had to be taken to the doctor&apos;s office. Write 3 - 5 paragraphs for the  principal explaining what you saw. Before you start to write, think  about exactly where you were and when the accident took place. Think  about the others who were involved in the accident. Consider (think  about) any details that would be helpful in your report. Now write a  paragraph or more to your principal explaining what you saw when your  classmate had an accident on the playground. Most  people have a favorite toy. Think about your favorite toy and why it  is your favorite. Now write 3 - 5 paragraphs to tell about your favorite  toy and explain why you like it. The  gym teacher has just announced that field day will be at the end of  the month. Write 3 - 5 paragraphs to describe the events that  take place at field day to a new student at your school. What  do you think is the most significant invention ever made and why do  you think so. Each  child has a special position in their family. Explain the advantages  and disadvantages of the position you hold in your family--youngest  child, only child, middle child etc. You  are an astronaut on a peaceful, exploratory mission to Planet Q. As  a representative from Earth, you are to present three gifts from our  planet. What items will you take? Write a proposal to the sponsors of  your mission explaining why you think these will make excellent tokens. When  solving a math problem, you and your neighbor reached the same answer,  but had different calculations and processes. Explain to your math teacher  how this can happen. Select  one of the math problems completed for homework. Explain to a classmate  who got the answer wrong how you computed your answer. You  are (an element, a seed, a piece of precipitation). Introduce yourself  to a young child, explaining your typical day, your life processes,  and how you deal with any dangers you routinely face. In  our science class, we have completed several lessons on the six simple  machines: lever, pulley, wheel and axle, wedge, inclined plane, and  spiral incline plane. Select one machine and clearly explain to a younger  student how it works. You  have been asked to help your classmates make decisions about meals they  would like added to the cafeteria menu choices. As a nutrition expert,  recommend choices for athletes. Explain the advantages of your selections. Explain  how music can affect one&apos;s mood. As the person in charge of providing  the background music for a (shopping mall, law firm, doctor&apos;s office,  sports stadium, fast food restaurant, fine dining establishment), explain  to your employer what type of music you will use and why. Using  your knowledge of (science, geography, health), explain to a new inhabitant  how to orient to a new place, such as a desert, or the jungle, or a  new planet. As  a student familiar with this school, explain the procedure for (fire  drills, forming a line, moving between classes, moving into learning  groups, finding a sentence pattern, outlining a chapter, solving an  equation) to a new student. There  are many concerns facing the student council in your school. As a member  of the student council, write an editorial for the school newspaper  about one concern and what you think can be done to solve the situation. Choose  something you know about (a place you have visited, something you saw  while traveling, something you have studied in school, a hobby you wish  to share). Write a letter to your pen pal in another country telling  about your topic. You  are the class president and have been asked to write an introduction  for a person you admire greatly. Write an essay describing the most  admirable qualities of the person. Think  of some things you learned outside of school. For example, you learn  from pet care, television, or grandparents. Explain what you learned. The  restaurant association of Snohomish County is seeking nominations for  &quot;Local Restaurant of the Year.&quot; Nominate the restaurant you like by  writing a letter to I.M. Phul (the restaurant association president)  describing why this restaurant should win. Sign your letter, &quot;M.T. Stomak.&quot; Cascade  Valley Hospital is seeking volunteers. Your friend asks you to write  a letter to the Hospital Volunteer Coordinator recommending this friend  for the volunteer job. Sign your name, &quot;F.S. Perfect.&quot; Your  local paper has been running a series of articles on local attractions  to inform new comers of places they might visit. Describe such a place  in a letter to the editor of the local newspaper. Sign your name, &quot;A.  B. See.&quot; Write  a letter to the editors of Invention magazine. Name three inventions  you could not live without and explain why they are so important to  you. If  you could visit anywhere on Earth, where would it be and why would you  want to visit there? What things would you do there? Write a letter  to the judges of a travel agency contest for a free vacation trip. If  you had the opportunity to meet any person (living or dead) who would  it be, why would you choose that person, and what would you want to  say when you met? You  have been asked to write an essay about a day in the life of a fourth  grader to be placed in a time capsule that will be buried this year  and opened in 2500. Think  about how new computers can benefit your school. Your principal has  decided that students in your school can have several new computers  in your classroom. Write an essay for the school newspaper about how  the new computers will be used to benefit your learning. Transportation  is a necessary part of modern life. Write an essay that explains how  American families use the car. Explain how it is used for business,  pleasure, and emergencies. Your essay will be in a new social studies  book. Write  an essay about the differences between two different types of insects.  Give examples of how each type is adapted to its environment. Write  a letter to your (future) grandchildren. Choose any two major events  occurring during your lifetime that you believe would be important enough  to pass along to your grandchildren. A  home in the community has burned. Tell how you would help the family  recover from the loss. Choose  one of your favorite authors. Write a letter telling why you like his/her  work. Write  the directions for &quot;how to&quot; do something. Choose  a book or TV show that that you have enjoyed. You are to write an essay  telling the reader why you enjoyed it. The  telephone has become a most important part of everyone&apos;s life. Most  of us have difficulty imagining what it could be like to live without  it. Write an essay explaining how the American family uses it for business,  pleasure, and emergencies. Assume that this will be published as a part  of an encyclopedia article. Each  of us had a teacher that we consider to have been really good. It may  not have been a person that we really like at the time. But, in looking  back, we realize that that person presented and saw to it that we knew  some things that would be really important. Sometimes it was how that  person presented things and not just what opportunities were supplied.  That person does not have to be a classroom teacher. Think about that  person and the reasons that they are positively memorable. Write a five-paragraph  essay and explain why this person is an excellent teacher. The  arts (music, art, drama, dance etc.,) and sports have important effects  on people&apos;s lives. When begun at a young age, they can be pursued for  a long time and can shape future interests, careers, and life styles.  One does not have to become a superstar, but the effect can be there  and shown in many ways. Choose one of the arts or a sport. Explain how  it could shape a person and influence one&apos;s life if begun when one is  young. Everyone  has jobs or chores. Explain why you do one of your jobs or chores. The  fourth grade at your school has decided to elect a class president.  The class president will take attendance each morning, help plan parties,  and collect money for field trips. Write an article for the class newspaper  describing what kind of person would make a good president and why. We  hear all the time about endangered species. Write an account of the  rediscovery of an animal once considered extinct. Choose  an existing animal and write an article about it as if it were an endangered  species. Weigh  the risks and rewards of space flight by explaining why you would or  would not like to be a passenger on the Space Shuttle. Describe  an experiment to be conducted on board the Space Shuttle. Think  of something that you just learned how to do. Explain how to do it. Your  friend was absent from school yesterday. Write a note to tell what he  or she missed. Think  of something nice that your teacher did for you or something important  that your teacher taught you. Write a thank-you note to your teacher. Your  class is having a party. You want other students to come to it. Write  a sign about the party. Write  in your journal about a time that someone helped you. Imagine  that you could visit any place in the world. Describe where you would  like to go. Imagine  that you are going on vacation and need to leave your pet with a friend.  Make a list of things your friend needs to do to take care of your pet. What  is your favorite book? Write an advertisement that will convince your  classmates to read it. A  new restaurant that is fun for kids is opening in your town. Write a  sign for the Grand Opening. Your  class has decided to have a &quot;Get-To-Know-Each-Other&quot; party. Write an  invitation asking students throughout your school to come to your party. Where  is the most unusual place you have ever been? Write a description of  the place. Your  class is making a classroom cookbook. Write a recipe for something you  like to eat at home to include in the book. A  baby-sitter is coming to your house. What does the baby-sitter need  to know? Write a letter telling her/him important information. The  mayor has to make a big decision--should some land in your community  be used for a new shopping mall or for a park? Write a letter to the  mayor telling what you think. A  musical group that everyone likes is going to perform a special concert,  and it&apos;s at your school! Write an announcement to read over the school  intercom. Your  school cafeteria wants to try a new menu--one with foods that kids will  really like. Your principal has asked each student to write an opinion  about what the cafeteria should serve. It  is Science Week at your school. Write a report about your favorite science  topic. You  are on a committee that is doing a presentation on good health for kids.  It is your responsibility to write an announcement for the presentation. You  have been hired by the mayor to promote your city as a wonderful place  to live. Write an advertisement to convince people to move there. Most  people go on vacation to have fun, but sometimes vacations don&apos;t turn  out as expected! Think about a vacation you went on that had some unexpected  surprises. Write a travel diary about your experience. Imagine  receiving an invitation to the Boston Tea Party or the first Thanksgiving  dinner! Choose an historical event and write an invitation to it. You  are on the school safety committee. Write directions for fire-drill  procedures for your class. Many  schools in the United States require students to participate in service  projects in order to graduate. Do you think community service should  be mandatory for students? Write an editorial for your school newspaper. Think  of a saying, such as &quot;Every cloud has a silver lining&quot; or &quot;Don&apos;t count  your chickens before they hatch.&quot; Write about an experience you had  that proves that the saying is true. It&apos;s  &quot;Career Day&quot; at your school, and your classmates want to know about  different occupations. Choose a job that interests you and write a report  about it. You  saw a help wanted ad for a job that is perfect for you. Write a letter  to apply for the job. Imagine  that you could &quot;invent&quot; the perfect sibling. What would this dream brother  or sister be like? Write a description. You  are a reporter for your school newspaper. You write about products kids  like and use. Besides giving basic information about the products, you  tell what you think of them. Write a news article for the next edition  of the newspaper. Next  year you&apos;ll be in a different class with a new teacher. Write a letter  to your next teacher, telling the most important things you learned  this year. A  friend asked you to come to a party. Write a note telling your friend  whether or not you will be able to attend. You  are a helper at a party for young children--and the children are bored!  Think of a game for the children to play. Write directions for playing  the game. Your  school did a special project. Write a letter to a newspaper telling  what you did. A  tract of land is being sold in your community. Fictitious bidders include  the National Park Service, a children&apos;s hospital, a shopping-mall developer,  an oil drilling company, and the U.S. Armed Forces. Choose one and become  a lobbyist for one that group writing arguments on behalf of their interests. Assist  your students in learning how to use laboratory equipment by having  them choose a scientific instrument form your lab, and write directions  on how to use it. Your  students can learn about the history of inventions by writing about  the origin of everyday objects, such as roller skates, safety pins,  or ice-cream cones. Form  &quot;exploration groups&quot; of about five students. Starting with an opening  line for a story, pass the story around the group, each student adding  a sentence or two to the story. Write  down as many questions about a new unit of instruction as you can BEFORE  the unit begins. Choose  some thing that you could imagine being (an asteroid, a cactus, a volcano),  and describe why you would choose to be that thing. Write  a word on the board. Have your students make a list of words that they  associate with that term. Compare the lists to demonstrate to students  that they do not all have the same mental picture of the concept. Picture  yourself as part of a scientific phenomenon, and write about the experience.  Phenomena include respiration, blood flow, transmission of nerve signals,  chemical reactions, heat transfer, lightning, combustion, and propagation  of radio waves. Describe  a museum exhibit that might have been, but was not, present at a museum  that you visited. Make  up a new planet. Describe the important features of the landscape, what  the climate is like, and what lives there. Write from the viewpoint  of the first visitor to this planet. Gather  illustrations of plants with unusual names. Give students one name,  and ask them to describe what it might look like. Give the same name  to more than one student so that they can compare their descriptions.  Show them the illustration of the plant after they have completed their  descriptions. You  have discovered a new type of plant. Give it a name and describe it  for the newspaper. Almost  everyone has had at least one teacher who is hard to forget. Think about  what makes it so hard to forget. Tell what happened. Describe  a person or an animal that you will never forget. Your  students can grapple with issues concerning form and function by writing  about how the world would be different if cockroaches were the size  of poodles (or other such distortions of scale and size). Write  directions telling how to do something. Name/describe the items to be  used and describe the steps needed to complete the task. Write  an invitation to a party. Write  a letter to your keypal recommending your favorite book. Choose  a person you admire and write a letter nominating that person for an  award. Write  a letter thanking an adult (teacher, bus driver, Scout leader, Sunday  school teacher, etc.). Write  a letter thanking someone for being a good friend. Your  teacher has told your class that you may have a class pet. Explain what  animal you would like to have as a classroom pet. Write  a letter to an inhabitant of another planet explaining basic things  on Planet Earth. Imagine  that you are a talk-show host getting ready to interview a famous person.  Prepare for the interview by writing some questions that will elicit  useful, interesting information from your guest. Make  up a writing prompt for your class. Use your imagination; they sharpen  their language skills in a science class. Most  people know of an animal they would like better than any other as a  pet. Before you write, think about what animal you would like most as  a pet. Think about why you would like that animal as a pet. Write to  explain why the animal you like would be a great pet. There  has recently been much discussion about violence in the music, film,  and television that children enjoy. Some experts argue that the media  is one major reason crime rates are on the rise. They believe the violence  that youths hear and see through TV, film, and music leads them to behave  in violent ways. On the other side of the issue, people say kids can  make their own decisions concerning such influences and filmmakers and  musicians must be free to create their art. Write an editorial for your  local newspaper in which you tell what you think about the issue. Write  a letter to a friend who has moved away to tell how third grade is different  from second grade. Write  a letter to a friend about why you like to read books or magazines about  a certain topic. Write  a letter to a friend telling about something you do well. Write  a letter to your favorite television star telling why you like his/her  show. Write  a formal letter to the President asking him for an autographed picture. Write  a letter to a city recreation department requesting information about  park in your area. Write  a letter to a local animal shelter requesting information about their  volunteer program. Write  a letter to your town&apos;s newspaper explaining why someone you know should  get a Special Person of the Year Award. Write  directions for a new student explaining how to get to the town&apos;s library  from your school. Write  a paper giving step-by-step instructions on how to make your favorite  sandwich. Write  instructions to your friends on how they can recycle at school. Write  a paper explaining how to study for a test. Write  a paper explaining how to find a book in the school library. Write  a paper explaining how to earn good grades at school. Write  a paper explaining the lunch room rules to a new student. Write  about what you do and don&apos;t understand about multiplication. Go  into a natural setting and write a log of your observations and questions. Describe  your favorite or your least favorite meal. Describe  a person you respect. Describe  something you collect or would like to collect. Describe  the perfect picnic lunch. Describe  your favorite teacher. Eating  healthy food is important for good health. Think about healthy foods  and why it&apos;s important to eat them. Now explain why it is important  to eat healthy foods. Most  people have a television show they like to watch. Sometimes they like  it because of one of the stars and sometimes they like it because of  what it is about. Think about the TV show you like the best. Think about  the things that make the show interesting or the start of the show.  Explain why this TV show is a good one. Everyone  has at least one thing that he/she does well, something he/she is an  expert at. It may be something he/she does at home or at school. Think  about something you do well, something you are an expert at doing. How  did you became an expert. What do you do that shows you are an expert?  Explain why you are an expert at doing something. Everyone  has something that is special to them. This may be something special  that people like to do or it may be a special place to go. Think about  what is special, when do you do it, where do you do it, who you are  doing it with, and how often you do it. Explain why you feel this is  something special to do or a special place to go. Congratulations!  You have just won a million dollars in the lottery. Think about the  things that you would do with your money. Tell what you will do with  the money that you have just won. You  are a gum drop on the grocer&apos;s shelf. A young person has just put you  in their cart. Think about your adventures in the cart. Write a story  about this gumdrop&apos;s adventure. One  day you woke up and discovered that you had been turned into an animal.  Think about what animal you have become. Tell what happened to you on  the day you discovered that you had been turned into an animal. Most  of us have had an experience that we will never forget. Think about  an experience that you remember very clearly. What happened? How did  you feel? Tell about an experience that you will never forget. Tonight  you have been asked to cook dinner for your family. Think of the foods  you will make, how you will prepare them and serve them. Explain how  you will prepare a dinner for your family. You  are a principal. You have to hire some new teachers for your school.  Think about the qualifications that this person should have to be hired  for this job. Explain what would make a good teacher. DANGER!!!  Occasionally, we find ourselves in a dangerous situation. Think about  what types of situations you consider dangerous. Explain what types  of situations you consider dangerous. Parents  would rather have handmade gifts from their children than store-bought  gifts. Think about the handmade gifts that you could make for one of  your parents. Explain what types of gifts you might make. Most  of us have had to do something that was difficult. It might have been  catching a softball, making the bed, washing the dog or saying &quot;I&apos;m  sorry.&quot; Think about something that was difficult for you. Explain to  the reader of your paper something difficult that you had to do. We  all have something we really want. What do you really want? Why do you  want it? Write about something you really want. Explain why you really  want it. We  all have things we like to do. Think about something you really like  to do. How do you do it? Write about something you really like to do.  Explain exactly (step by step) how you do it. We  all have things we like to do with our friends or family. Think about  something you really like to do with your friends or family. Why do  you really like to do this thing? Explain what you like to do and why  you like to do it. Have  you ever made mud pies? Think about what you do to make mud pies. What  would you need? What would you have to do? Write step by step, what  someone would need to do to make mud pies. We  all have someone important in our lives. It might be a teacher, a friend  or family. Think about the important people in your life. Pick one person  who is especially important to you. Why are they important? What are  they like? Why are they important to you? Explain who is an important  person in your life and why that person is important to you. Think  about a pencil. What does it look like? How do you use it? What makes  a really good pencil? Explain what a pencil looks like so someone will  be able to see it through your words. Think  about your desk. What makes a really good desk? What would you do to  make a desk? Explain exactly what you would need to do to make a desk. We  all have jobs or chores to do to help out at home or at school. Think  about a job (or chore) you have at home or in school. Why is this job  important? How does it help? Explain why your job is important. Your  class has been given money to buy a classroom pet and no one knows how  to go about choosing it. Think about how that pet should be chosen.  Who should decide which pet is best? Should the class vote? Should the  teacher choose? Explain how your class should choose a pet to be the  class pet. Imagine  that you are to choose an animal to be your classroom&apos;s pet. Think about  the animal you would choose. Why would you choose that animal? Why would  it be good for the classroom? What would your class learn from having  this pet? Explain what animal you would choose to be a class pet and  why. You  are going to decide which animal your class pet will be. Think about  that animal. What is it and what would you need to do to keep it healthy?  What would it eat? Would it need exercise? How would you get it to exercise?  What kind of cage would it have to have? Tell about what pet you would  choose for your classroom and what you would do to care for it. Write  a composition for your classmates, describing the most interesting place  you have ever visited, Describe in detail where the place is, how you  got there, what you saw, and how you felt. For  a children&apos;s magazine, describe your first attempt at playing a particular  sport. The sport might be one that looked easy but turned out to be  a real challenge, or it might be one that came quite naturally to you.  Be sure to describe everything you did and how you felt. What  are some of the more important or interesting experiences you have had  in your life? Have you moved, lost something that was important to you,  or overcome a big fear? As you grow older your memory of the events  is bound to fade. So capture one of these experiences now in as much  detail as possible by writing a journal entry about it. Be sure to tell  why the event was important to you. Enter  a magazine contest by writing an essay about somebody you admire. According  to the contest rules, your hero should be a person you know well or  a historical figure - male or female, living or dead - that you&apos;ve heard  or read about. Tell how you feel about your hero, what qualities you  admire, and the ways in which you would like your life to be like your  hero&apos;s. Have  you seen a particularly skillful feat or performance by an athlete,  a dancer, or an acrobat recently? Try to visualize the physical movements  of the person, and write a description of the performance for the sports  and entertainment section of your local newspaper. Use concrete details  and imaginative comparisons to help your readers appreciate what you  saw. Is  there a special object or family tradition that is important to everyone  in your family? For example, do you have an heirloom that has been handed  down through generations, a quilt your grandmother made, or a special  way of celebrating birthdays? For a younger relative - perhaps even  for someone who hasn&apos;t been born yet - describe this family treasure  or tradition in as much detail as you can. For  an audience of your classmates, write a description of a particular  time and place that you know well, such as your room on a rainy afternoon,  the video arcade after school, or the waiting area at your doctor&apos;s  office on a busy day. Use as many specific sensory details a you can.  Try to capture the moment - and share how you felt about it. For  a class anthology, describe a bird, an insect, or animal that you have  strong feelings about. Choose one that scares amuses, or puzzles you.  Be sure you know enough about the animal to describe it fully. Use sensory  details that will make your classmates feel the same. Imagine  you&apos;ve been asked to explain to a group of students from a foreign country  how to prepare a hot dog for lunch. They have never eaten a hot dog  before and do not know anything about them. Tell them each step you  take in preparing a hot dog. You  have been chosen to represent your school at an international convention  for students. This convention will take place during your family&apos;s scheduled  summer vacation, and it is being held in Paris, France. You will be  traveling alone. Write a composition as if you were explaining this  situation to a friend. Write about the good and bad aspects of attending  this convention. Explain each of your points completely. Many  young people your age read very little. They get their news and information  from television and the movies. They would rather read a magazine than  a novel. No one is quite sure why this is true, but many people are  concerned about the situation. Your teacher has asked you and your classmates  to write essays which explain your thoughts about the causes of this  situation. Your essays will be shared with other students in your school.  Your teacher hopes that these essays will help the school develop a  program to increase the popularity of reading for pleasure. Are  there any problems in your school? Do you get too little time to eat  lunch? Between classes is it hard to find a water fountain that works?  In a letter, make your school principal aware of the problem and suggest  a solution. Be sure to explain what the causes of the problem are, who  is affected by it, and how something could be done to solve it. Your  school is having a health awareness day. For the occasion, write a short  composition about a health problem you think is avoidable. Begin with  a brief explanation of the problem - how it comes about, who is affected  by it, and how. Then tell how you think people could prevent this problem.  In conclusion, either urge your readers to follow your advice or warn  them what may happen if they don&apos;t. Does  somebody do something that really drives you crazy? Do you have a friend  who always insists on being in charge? Is there someone in your class  who always takes credit for other people&apos;s work? Choose something that  bothers you. Now take a moment to figure out a way to solve this problem.  Then write a composition in which you describe the problem and explain  your proposed solution to it. Address your composition to others who  are also troubled by this behavior. Think  about some of the problems in your community that affect you and your  friends. Choose a problem that concerns you. Then prepare a brief written  report in which you state the problem, and offer a solution to it. In  your report, make clear to your neighbors why they should do something  about the problem. Do  you have a special relationship with someone? Take a moment now to consider  why this person matters to you and what he or she adds to your life.  Then write an essay in which you define the role of this individual  in your life. You might begin with words like &quot;An aunt is someone who...&quot;  Plan to share this essay with the person about whom you are writing. Most  hobbies and sports have special words to describe the equipment and  the plays unique to that activity. For example, chess players talk of  rooks and pawns, and baseball players speak of knuckle balls and sliders.  Imagine you are helping to write a manual for beginners in a hobby or  sport you know well. Write an explanation of an important term that  all beginners need to understand. Choose  a custom or holiday that you enjoy or that has special meaning to you.  For instance, do you love celebrating Independence Day? Hanukah? In  a letter to a pen pal, explain the practice or event you have chosen.  As you write, remember that this pen pal lives in another country and  knows nothing of your customs or holidays. A  magazine for children is conducting a survey on children&apos;s taste in  movies. The editors want you to compare and contrast a movie that is  in the theaters now with your favorite film of all time, and then draw  a conclusion about what makes a movie great. The best responses will  appear in a future issue of the magazine, so be sure to write for an  audience of magazine readers your own age. Your  principal is considering a new dress code requiring all students to  wear uniforms. State whether you think this is a good policy. Support  your answer. Name  a favorite book and give reasons why you think it&apos;s worth reading. Think  about your favorite activity when you are out of school. Write about  this activity and tell why it is your favorite activity. Think  about an animal you would like to be for one day. Write about this animal  and tell why you would like to be this animal for one day. If  you could go anywhere in the world, think about the place where you  would go. Write about this place and tell why you would go there. Think  about the famous people you know and choose one you would like to meet.  Write about this person and tell why you would like to meet them. Think  about a place where you like to go to be alone. Write about this place  and tell why you like to go there to be alone. Lucky  you! You are going on a trip to the moon. Think about three things you  would take with you and tell why you would take these three things. Name  one goal you would like to accomplish and give specific reasons why.  Give enough details so that your teacher will understand your ideas. Your  teacher has asked you to write about one person you would choose to  be if you could be someone else for one day. Name that person and give  specific reasons why you would like to be that person for one day. Give  enough details so your teacher will understand your ideas. Your  teacher has asked you to write about one person who has made a difference  in your life. Name that person and give specific reasons why that person  has made a difference in your life. Give enough details so your teacher  will understand your ideas. You  wake up at night and find your room filled with smoke. Describe the  problem and explain how you would solve it. After  he takes your lunch money every day, a bigger kid warns he&apos;ll hurt you  if you tell anyone. Since you don&apos;t believe in fighting to solve problems,  what other actions might you take? Your  family has just moved to a country where you don&apos;t speak the language.  What will you do to get through your first week of school? Students  in your school are unhappy with the student bathrooms. Write a letter  to your principal describing the problem and suggesting ways to solve  it. The  students in your school think that there is a problem at recess. Write  a letter to your principal stating the problem and suggesting ways to  solve it. A  classmate is being picked on during recess. Describe the problem. What  could you do to help him/her solve it? Write  a letter to your principal explaining a problem in your school cafeteria  (library, playground, bus, etc.) and offer a solution to the problem. Think  about a problem in our environment such as air pollution, overcrowding  or endangering species. Write a letter to a younger child identifying  this problem and offering a possible solution to the problem. Imagine  you have just been given the name and address of a penpal. Describe  yourself to that person. Describe  your favorite park or playground. Describe  your favorite relative. Describe  a really fun day. Describe  your favorite meal. Describe  your favorite outfit including any accessories. Think  about a new invention you would like to create. Describe this invention  and tell what it can do. Think  about an outdoor scene, such as a mountain, a beach, a waterfall, a  park, that you consider interesting. Describe this sight so that your  reader will be able to picture it. Select  a particular place you have come to know well and that is special to  you. It can be a back yard, a setting in the woods or on the water,  a store, a secret hideout, a certain room or any other spot that is  special to you. Name the place and describe it so your reader can picture  it. What  is your favorite room in your house. Explain why it is your favorite. What  is your favorite pastime? Name the activity and give reasons why you  like it. You  have the chance to be the first student astronaut to explore another  planet. Would you accept the job? Give reasons why or why not. Almost  everyone has had at least one teacher who is hard to forget. Think about  what makes it so hard to forget. Tell what happened. What&apos;s  your pet peeve? Is it graffiti? Too many television commercials? Violence  in movies? Write an editorial for your school newspaper. Clearly state  what your gripe is and what you think should be done about it. Try to  persuade your readers to accept your opinion. It  is ten years from now. Write a letter to an old classmate telling where  you are. Where do you live? What do you do? How did you get where you  are? What goals have you reached? etc. Write  a letter to a teacher you&apos;ve had in your past that really made a difference  in your life. Describe a specific experience that you remember vividly.  Thank this person for taking the time to care about you. (replace teacher  with person or adult.) Write  a story about something that has been recycled, like a can, newspaper,  or plastic bag, and its adventures along the way. Write  a story about a ride in a hot air balloon. Choose  a problem from last night&apos;s homework assignment, and write an explanation  to your teacher of the steps you used to solve that problem. Be sure  you list and explain the steps you took to solve the problem. Include  enough information and details so the reader will understand your steps. You  are a Confederate/ Yankee soldier of the Civil War. You fought valiantly  in the Battle of Gettysburg. You are cold, tired, and hungry, yet before  you fall asleep, you must first write a newspaper account of your experiences  for your hometown paper. Describe your experience. Give  details that are specific and relevant to your experience. Imagine  that someone invented a time travel machine and offered you the opportunity  to invite and transport any person to your classroom from any time in  the past. If you had your choice of the most interesting person with  whom you could share the class day, who would it be? This person could  someone from any part of life: politics, military, media, the arts,  sports etc. Write a five-paragraph essay to explain how this person  could be of benefit and interest to your class. Invention  and technology have always been an important part of changing the way  one lives. Things that did not exist when your parents or grandparents  were young, now have changed the way most people in this country live.  Some of those inventions are large and others are small. No mater what  their size, they have altered the lives of the average person today.  Think about an invention that came about in the last hundred years or  so. Write an essay on how that invention changed the lives of the people.  Explain how life was then, how it is different today, and whether the  result is positive or negative. You  have studied about the early settlers to this country. You know about  the hard times that they encountered and know that most of the settlements  survived and prospered. They lived in environments that were often difficult,  but they overcame those difficulties. Many of the simple everyday acts  required individual creativity and effort. They had to live everyday  being resourceful enough to meet their needs and the needs of their  family and community. Even at an early age, each member was expected  to contribute. Write an essay about how the colonists used their creativity  and resourcefulness to survive and succeed. You  probably have read many interesting books or watched an exceptional  TV show recently. It probably stands out in your mind for many reasons.  It is the kind of show that many people really enjoyed and would not  mind watching again. Maybe it was a painless way to learn, perhaps it  dealt with a subject that you particularly enjoy. Maybe it stimulated  the imagination. Whatever the reasons, you know that many people found  it interesting. Choose a book or TV show that that many people enjoyed.  Write an essay telling the reader why many people enjoyed it. Your  class has been discussing the problems in our environment such as littering  the land and water, using products that cannot be recycled, burning  toxic chemicals and other waste products, cutting down trees, filling  in the wetlands, and killing rare kinds of birds and animals. Your teacher  has asked each of you to choose one problem in our environment, explain  why it is a problem, and suggest things that can be done to help solve  it. Your  class discussed the different kinds of workers in our society and the  things they do to make our community a better place. Your teacher has  asked you to choose one type of worker and explain how the work is important  to your school, your community, or the country as a whole. Write an  essay telling how the work is important for you and your town, the school  or the country. Describe  your best friend. Describe  how you make your favorite sandwich. What  this class needs to make it better is... Describe  your favorite place to eat. We  all have favorite objects that we care about and would not want to give  up. Think of one object that is important or valuable to you. For example,  it could be a book, a piece of clothing, a game, or any object you care  about. Write about your favorite object. Be sure to describe the object  and explain why it is valuable or important to you. Regardless  of where they live, everybody knows of a special place. Describe your  special place, wherever it is. What does it look like? How does it feel  to be there? Who shares it with you? 
 
 Return  to: Writer&apos;s  Web 
 
 This is a large site with navigation in a left frame. If it is missing go to Mrs. Barnard&apos;s Classroom Launcher . 
 Contact Paula Barnard at Pioneer Elementary School , Arlington Public Schools ,  Arlington, WA, USA
Updated06/17/2005
	</body>
</document>
