<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007655" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/253126-Why-are-Ebay-amp-Paypal-wanting-my-pin-number-today" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="1" score="0.0006982590653023266" bingtitle="Why are Ebay &amp; Paypal wanting my pin number today?" webtitle="Why are EbayPaypal wanting my pin number today?">
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>) along with my credit/debit card number, 3 digit ... if these idiots making their viruses put their ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum More from YDF Ebay Tips, Tricks&amp;Advice Why are Ebay&amp;Paypal wanting my pin number today? 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Page 1 of 2 1 2 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 10 of 11 
Thread: Why are Ebay&amp;Paypal wanting my pin number today? 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 
 03-10-2009,  10:31 AM #1 dinah500 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2002 Posts 861 
Why are Ebay&amp;Paypal wanting my pin number today?
 Today when I try to log-in to either Ebay or Paypal they both ask for my personal info (name, address, etc. . ) along with my credit/debit card number, 3 digit security code&amp;pin number--why? I do not believe they have needed this info before&amp;I do not want to enter it just to log in to my accounts! Anyone know what&apos;s going on? Is this real or a phishing scam? Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  10:45 AM #2 Gooddealie 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Dec 2004 Posts 6,360 Are you typing in the address or are you clicking a link to get to the sign in page? Type in the address directly (http://www.paypal.com or http://www.ebay.com ) and see if you get a different sign in page.

It sounds like you ended up on a phishing site somehow. Neither Paypal nor Ebay require you to enter that kind of info. Ever. For any reason.

If you&apos;re still getting a page that asks you for personal info, I&apos;d run an virus/malware scan on your computer - preferably an online scan like this one: http://www.bitdefender.com/scan8/ie.html 

The reason I&apos;d suggest an online scan is because if your computer is infected with a virus, it can interfere with an antivirus program you have installed on your computer. An online scan uses the most up-to-date signatures and you won&apos;t have&quot;interference&quot;problems.

If that comes up clean and you&apos;re still being asked for that info, call Paypal customer service and confirm whether or not they are actually requiring this info. Chances are that you&apos;re using a bad link or have some malware, though. Last edited by Gooddealie; 03-10-2009 at 10:49 AM . Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  10:48 AM #3 opuscat1 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Mar 2007 Location PA Posts 343 I got one of these a few months ago, I wouldn&apos;t give out your credit info, you can forward it to ebay/paypal, that&apos;s what I did, and they told me it was a phishing e-mail, be careful! Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  10:58 AM #4 dinah500 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2002 Posts 861 This isn&apos;t an email! It happens whenever I try to log-in to my accounts after directly typing in the address www.ebay.com or www.paypal.com . I don&apos;t know what it could be unless maybe my computer has a virus or something? That&apos;s why I am asking--to see if it&apos;s my computer or if it&apos;s happening to other people too?

I think it must be my computer--I just tried logging in on my work-mate&apos;s computer and it is fine--no message to enter my personal info Last edited by dinah500; 03-10-2009 at 11:05 AM . Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  11:36 AM #5 debdog42 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 chat Join Date Mar 2001 Location North Central Idaho Posts 4,854 You need to run a virus scan and also Ad-Aware. Make sure your programs are up to date before you do so. Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  04:13 PM #6 Gooddealie 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Dec 2004 Posts 6,360 No, I&apos;m not seeing anything like that for either eBay or Paypal - just the usual sign in pages.

It sounds like you may have a virus or piece of malware that is redirecting your browser to a different site whenever you type in Paypal or Ebay&apos;s address.

Run the online scan and see if it finds anything. It probably will. Reply With Quote 03-10-2009,  06:37 PM #7 Gooddealie 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Dec 2004 Posts 6,360 Actually you seem to be the victim of pharming, not phishing.

From: http://www.michigan.gov/cybersecurit...415---,00.html 

&quot; Pharming involves Trojans programs, worms, or other virus technologies that attack the Internet browser address bar and is much more sophisticated than phishing. When users type in a valid URL they are redirected to the criminals&apos; websites instead of the intended valid website.&quot;

So.....

Do any of these sound or look like what you&apos;re experiencing?

 http://www.vnunet.com/vnunet/news/21...-attack-paypal 

 http://www.informationweek.com/news/...leID=197008230 

 http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worl...rt-on-web.html 

Until you clean your computer, be really careful with using passwords and when doing anything financial. Reply With Quote 03-24-2009,  12:27 PM #8 hayleybun 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jul 2008 Posts 44 
Me too!
 I just got the message the OP did when trying to use paypal. I won an item on ebay and when I try to pay to redirects me to a page asking all kinds of personal info, including full social and even ATM Pin, do they think we are that stupid? How was this resolved OP? Please help! Reply With Quote 03-25-2009,  06:21 PM #9 bethhorn31 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Mar 2005 Location Indiana Posts 74 same happened with me. I had gotten an email about my account,but always delete them. BUT.......today when I wanted to send money to sheri for chat....I tried logging in and it said I needed to update stuff. I typed it myself...did not click on a link. I tried to fix it online,but ended up calling paypal by phone,then everything was fine. YAY ! I don&apos;t know what the problem is/was though. Reply With Quote 03-26-2009,  03:03 PM #10 scarhead 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2006 Location PA Posts 1,073 Thanks for the scanner! I didn&apos;t have any issue with paypal but I like double checking. . if these idiots making their viruses put their time to something more useful who knows what they could do!! cure cancer! argh! Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
