<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007163" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/48932666/fast-food-deepak-original-Data-Analysis" time="2012-07-13-00:08" support="6" score="0.02054066425987651" bingtitle="fast food deepak original Data Analysis - Scribd" webtitle="fast food deepak original Data Analysis">
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>... requirements involved in opening up a fast food ... through&quot; service which allows customers to order and pick up food ... restaurant segment of the food industry is expected ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download     FAST FOOD INDUSTRY Introduction Fast food is the term given to food that can be prepared and served very quickly. While any meal with low preparation time can be considered to be fast food, typically the term refers to food sold in a restaurant or store with low quality preparation and served to the customer in a packaged form for take-out/take-away.   Outlets may be stands or kiosks, which may provide no shelter or seating, or fast food restaurants (also known as quick service restaurants ) . Franchise operations which are part of restaurant chains have standardized foodstuffs shipped to each restaurant from central locations. The capital requirements involved in opening up a fast food restaurant are relatively low. Restaurants with much higher sit-in ratios, where customers tend to sit and have their orders brought to them in a seemingly more upscale atmosphere may be known in some areas as fast casual restaurants and there when it comes the matter of capital investment it is very high in most of the cases as most of these fast food joints or restaurants are operated under franchisee model which a very costly affair to adopt. H istory The concept of ready-cooked food for sale is clo sely connected with urban development. In Ancient Rome cities had street stands that sold bread and wine. A fixture of East Asian cities is the noodle shop. Flatbread and falafel are today ubiquitous in the Middle East. Popular Indian fast food dishes include vada -pav, panipuri and dahi vada. In the French- speaki ng nations of West Africa, roadside stands in and around the larger cities continue to sellas they have done for generationsa range of ready-to-eat, char-grilled meat sticks known locally as brochettes . of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
fast food deepak original Data Analysis
 Download or Print 384 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 02/16/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
