<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007132" url="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB119560391050099871.html" time="2012-07-13-00:06" support="3" score="0.002926805323573092" bingtitle="Subway&apos;s Diet: Less Oil, More Recycling - WSJ.com" webtitle="Subway&apos;s Diet: Less Oil, More Recycling - WSJ.com">
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="17"/>
	<description>... its impact on the environment, including recycling bins for customer trash. ... they haven&apos;t installed recycling bins for customers because wrappers, napkins ...</description>
	<body>
		WSJEurope 
 WSJEurope Facebook Twitter 
 Market Watch 
 Market Watch 
 Barron&apos;s 
 Barron&apos;s 
 All Things Digital 
 All Things Digital 
 WSJ Live 
 WSJ Live 
 Financial News 
 Financial News 
 BigCharts 
 BigCharts 
 Factiva 
 Factiva 
 More 
 SmartMoney FINS Europe Virtual Stock Exchange WSJ Classifieds WSJ Classroom WSJ Radio 
 
 SEARCH 
 headline gold man 
 
 Companies GOLD Ran gold Resources Ltd. ADS U.S. 
 
 View All Search Results» 
 
 
 | 
 The Wall Street Journal Franchising 
 Welcome, Logout 
 Customer Center My Journal Help Message Center ( new) 
 
 
 Europe Edition Home ↓More 
WSJ.com is available in the following editions and languages:
 
 U.S. Asia 
 India China Japan 
 Europe 
 Deutschland 
 Americas 
 en Español em Português 
 
 Register for FREE 
 Register for FREE 
 
Thank you for registering.

We sent an email to: 

Please click on the link inside the email to complete your registration
 
Please register to gain free access to WSJ tools.
 
An account already exists for the email address entered.

 Forgot your username or password? 
 
This service is temporary unavailable due to system maintenance. Please try again later.
 
The username entered is already associated with
another account. Please enter a different username
 
The email address you have entered is already in use.
Please re-enter the email address.
 
 First Name Last Name Email (your email address will be your login) Confirm Email Create a Password Confirm Password Company Size (Optional) Please make a selection 1-99 100-499 500-999 1,000-2,499 2,500-4,999 5,000-9,999 10,000-14,999 15,000-24,999 25,000+ Not Applicable 
 
From time to time, we will send you e-mail announcements on new features and special offers from The Wall Street Journal Online.

 
Create a profile for me in the Journal Community 
 
 Why Register? 

 Privacy Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
As a registered user of The Wall Street Journal Online, you will be able to:

 
Setup and manage your portfolio
 
Personalize your own news page
 
Receive and manage newsletters
 
 
 Login/Register to set your edition 
 
 Today&apos;s Paper Video Blogs Emails Journal Community Mobile Tablet 



 Subscribe Log In 

 
 
 
 World »More 
 
 World »More 
 Loading… 
 Europe »More 
 
 Europe »More 
 Loading… 
 U.K. »More 
 
 U.K. »More 
 Loading… 
 U.S. »More 
 
 U.S. »More 
 Loading… 
 Business »More 
 
 Business »More 
 Loading… 
 Markets »More 
 
 Markets »More 
 Loading… 
 Market Data »More 
 
 Market Data »More 
 Loading… 
 Tech »More 
 
 Tech »More 
 Loading… 
 Life&amp;Style »More 
 
 Life&amp;Style »More 
 Loading… 
 Opinion »More 
 
 Opinion »More 
 Loading… 
 Real Estate »More 
 
 Real Estate »More 
 Loading… 
 Jobs »More 
 
 Jobs »More 
 Loading… 
 
 
Dow Jones Reprints: This copy is for your personal, non-commercial use only. To order presentation-ready copies for distribution to your colleagues, clients or customers, use the Order Reprints tool at the bottom of any article or visit www.djreprints.com 
 See a sample reprint in PDF format. Order a reprint of this article now 
 
 FRANCHISING November 21, 2007 

Subway&apos;s Diet: Less Oil, More Recycling
 
 Article Stock Quotes Comments 
 more in Franchising | Find New $LINKTEXTFIND$ » 
 smaller Larger 
 
By JANET ADAMY 

The Subway sandwich chain is testing recycling bins, switching its napkins, cutlery and plastic cups and cutting down on the gasoline used to transport its restaurant supplies in an effort to minimize the chain&apos;s impact on the environment.
 
If Subway&apos;s new recycling bins are successful, other chains could add them, too.
 
The nation&apos;s largest restaurant chains have made scant progress in offering recycling for customers. No other major fast-food chain, including McDonald&apos;s Corp., Burger King Corp., Yum Brands Inc.&apos;s KFC and Taco Bell and Wendy&apos;s International Inc., said it has recycling bins for customer trash at its restaurants in the U.S. Starbucks Corp. has recycling bins at some cafes on the East Coast, but they don&apos;t accept the chain&apos;s paper coffee cups because those can&apos;t be recycled, according to the coffee company.

Restaurants said they haven&apos;t installed recycling bins for customers because wrappers, napkins, cups and other packaging that is soiled with food is difficult, and in some cases impossible, to recycle in the U.S. McDonald&apos;s said most cities won&apos;t accept recycled material with food on it. Some food-tainted packaging can be recycled, but it is expensive to do, said Susan Daywitt, chief executive of SLM Waste&amp;Recycling Services Inc. in Sellersville, Pa., which helped Subway create its recycling program.

Ms. Daywitt said she has talked to other chains about adding recycling bins for customers and found that their franchisees typically don&apos;t want to do it because it usually costs more. A 96-gallon container of bottles and cans costs between $18 and $25 to recycle, she said. &quot;When you&apos;re looking at an expense side and their margins are 2%, they&apos;re going to say, &apos;I don&apos;t need that,&apos; especially when it&apos;s not mandated,&quot; Ms. Daywitt said.

If Subway can make recycling bins work, it could prompt other chains to add them too. The chain, owned by Doctor&apos;s Associates Inc., has about 22,000 locations in the U.S., making it the country&apos;s largest restaurant chain as measured by units.

Subway is testing the new initiatives at a so-called &quot;eco-store&quot; it opened this month in Kissimmee, Fla. In addition to recycling bins, the restaurant was constructed using some recycled materials, and it uses more efficient heating and cooling systems, has plumbing systems that conserve water and uses high-efficiency lighting. Subway worked with the U.S. Green Building Council to develop the store and is planning to build others like it.

Nationally, the company has switched to napkins that use 100% recycled materials, of which 60% is post-consumer recyclable material. Recycled material can include material such as wood chips, while post-consumer recycled material is paper that has already been used by consumers. Subway estimates it will save about 147,000 trees a year. The company also switched to cutlery and plastic drinking cups made of polypropylene instead of polystyrene, which it estimates will save 13,000 barrels of oil annually because it no longer needs to use as much of that material. The chain also will save gasoline after it reconfigured a facility in Utah that keeps it from having to slice deli meat in Iowa and send it to Colorado for distribution.

The waste bin at the Kissimmee store is divided into three baskets for paper, plastic and trash. Only the plastic waste is actually recycled. The chain hasn&apos;t figured out how to recycle the paper material that has food waste on it. The company said it is dividing out that material to raise awareness about recycling. The plastic waste that is recycled in the Florida store includes plastic bottles, straws, straw wrappers, drink lids, cutlery and salad bowls. If the plastic recycling is successful in this location, Subway plans to put it in more of its restaurants.

Subway officials said when they first began looking into customer recycling, they were surprised by how difficult it is. One problem is that the regulations governing recycling vary by city. &quot;It&apos;s not an easy job to tackle when you&apos;re looking at a chain this big,&quot; said Tina Fitzgerald, director of produce and sustainability for Subway&apos;s purchasing co-operative.

 Write to Janet Adamy at janet.adamy@wsj.com 
 Printed in The Wall Street Journal, page B4 
Copyright 2012 Dow Jones&amp;Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved

This copy is for your personal, non-commercial use only. Distribution and use of this material are governed by our Subscriber Agreement and by copyright law. For non-personal use or to order multiple copies, please contact Dow Jones Reprints at 1-800-843-0008 or visit

 www.djreprints.com 
 Join the discussion More In Franchising» 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Das Erfolgsmodell Brasilien hat ausgedient 
 
 Chinas Konjunkturdaten könnten geschönt sein 
 
 Der Anlagenotstand wird eskalieren 
 
 
 
 Back To 
 
 
 
 Voltar ao 
 
 
 Back To 
 MSN Money Homepage 
 
 MSN Money Investing 
 
 
Available to WSJ.com Subscribers

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Madrid Austerity Plan Boosted 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Monti: Italy Faces Economic &apos;War&apos; 
 

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Work Perk: Free-Meal Rule Widens 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Monti&apos;s Blunt Words Mark Shift for Italy 
 
 
 From the HomePage 

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 GM Ousts Head of European Operations 

General Motors has ousted the head of its struggling Opel/Vauxhaull division amid frustration with the pace of the turnaround of the European business.
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Car Plant Closure Reflects Europe&apos;s Troubles 

Peugeot will slash 8,000 jobs and close one of France&apos;s biggest car factories, as Europe&apos;s auto industry begins a painful downsizing to cope with recession across swaths of the continent.
 
 Troops Called In to Plug Olympic Security Gap 

Just two weeks before the Olympics begin, the U.K. government is increasing the role of the military to help secure the event, a last-minute expansion that is prompting questions about how security plans are being managed.
 
 Saudi Arabia to Send Women to Games 

Saudi Arabia confirmed it will send two women athletes to the London Games later this month, the International Olympic Committee said.
 
 
Want to be an entrepreneur?

Find opportunities in our business and franchise databases.
 Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Business Categories RETAILING BUSINESSES  - Apparel and Accessory Stores  - Automotive Dealers  - Bars/Taverns  - Blding Mat., Hardware, Garden  - Convenience Stores  - Florists  - Gasoline Service Stations  - General Merchandise Stores  - Home Furniture&amp;Furnishings  - Liquor Stores  - Marine Dealers&amp;Equipment  - Miscellaneous Retail  - Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places  - Other Food Stores  - Pet Shops&amp;Supplies  - Restaurants  - Supermarkets  - Vending Machines SERVICE BUSINESSES  - Agents&amp;Brokers  - Amusement&amp;Recreation  - Auto Repair, Parts&amp;Services  - Beauty Salons, Barber Shops  - Computer&amp;Software Services  - Drycleaning/Laundry Services  - Educational Services  - Engineering&amp;Accounting Svcs  - Finance, Banking, Loans, etc.  - Freight, Moving/Delivery  - Health, Medical&amp;Dental  - Hotels&amp;Other Lodging Places  - Landscaping&amp;Yard Services  - Legal Services  - Marine Repair, Parts&amp;Services  - Membership Organizations  - Miscellaneous Repair Services  - Miscellaneous Services  - Motion Pictures  - Museums, Art Galleries, Zoos  - Other Business Services  - Other Personal Services  - Other Travel&amp;Transportation  - Passenger Transportation  - Pet Care&amp;Grooming  - Social Services  - Storage&amp;Warehousing  - Travel Agencies INTERNET BUSINESSES  - Business Services (B2B)  - Consumer Services (B2C)  - Domain Name/Basic Site  - General Internet  - ISP/ASP Services  - Software  - Web Design/Tech Services MANUFACTURING BUSINESSES  - Apparel&amp;finished fabrics  - Chemicals&amp;Allied Products  - Electronic&amp;Electrical Equip.  - Fabricated Metal Products  - Food and Kindred Products  - Furniture and Fixtures  - Industrial&amp;Comm. Machinery  - Leather and Leather Products  - Lumber and Wood Products  - Measuring&amp;Analyzing Instr.  - Miscellaneous  - Paper&amp;Allied Products  - Petroleum Refining  - Primary Metal Industries  - Printing, Publishing  - Rubber and Plastic Products  - Stone, Clay, Glass, Concrete  - Textile Mill Products  - Tobacco Products  - Transportation Equipment WHOLSALE/DIST. BUSINESSES  - Durable Goods  - Nondurable Goods CONSTRUCTION BUSINESSES  - Building  - Heavy  - Special Trades BUSINESS REAL ESTATE  - For Lease  - For Sale Agriculture Communications Electric, Gas, Water, Sanitary Svcs Mining Non-classifiable Establishments State   Alabama   Alaska   Arizona   Arkansas   California   Colorado   Connecticut   Delaware   District of Columbia   Florida   Georgia   Hawaii   Idaho   Illinois   Indiana   Iowa   Kansas   Kentucky   Louisiana   Maine   Maryland   Massachusetts   Michigan   Minnesota   Mississippi   Missouri   Montana   Nebraska   Nevada   New Hampshire   New Jersey   New Mexico   New York   North Carolina   North Dakota   Ohio   Oklahoma   Oregon   Pennsylvania   Rhode Island   South Carolina   South Dakota   Tennessee   Texas   Utah   Vermont   Virginia   Washington   West Virginia   Wisconsin   Wyoming U.S. Territories Africa Asia/Pacific Australia/New Zealand Canada Caribbean Mexico/Central America Europe South America County Search Advanced Search Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Franchise Categories Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Child Related Cleaning And Maintenance Computer And Internet Food And Restaurant Health, Beauty, and Fitness High Capital Franchises Home Based Businesses Home Services Low Cost Franchises Retail Franchises Sports And Recreation Travel And Lodging State Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming All Amounts to Invest Up to $25,000 Up to $50,000 Up to $100,000 Up to $250,000 Up to $500,000 Up to $1,000,000 Up to $5,000,000 Search Advanced Search Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Opportunities All Business Categories Auctions Business Connections Business Opportunities Business Services Capital Available Capital Wanted Financial Services Internet Services Legal Services Marketing Services Professional Services Search   
marketplace

 Own an Energy Conservation Biz Find Small Business Software Franchise Opportunities Rewarding Executive Careers Advertise Locally on WSJ.com 
 
More in Franchising

 
 Tough Times for Franchising 
 
 Franchising 2012 Outlook: Better Than 2011 Reality 
 
 Arbitration Holds Steady For Franchising Disputes 
 
 Franchise Sales Pull Back 
 
 Is a Franchise the Right Business for You? 
 
 
 Most Popular In Europe 

 Read Emailed Video Commented 
 
 1. 
 Opinion: Karl Rove: Obama&apos;s Shrinking Majority 
 2. 
 Mystery Solved: Mogul Bought &apos;Scream&apos; 
 3. 
 Madrid Austerity Plan Boosted 
 4. 
 Housing Passes a Milestone 
 5. 
 Monti: Italy Faces Economic &apos;War&apos; 
 
 
 1. 
 Housing Passes a Milestone 
 2. 
 Sleeping Anytime, Anywhere 
 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 3. 
 Fed Weighs More Stimulus 
 4. 
 Deeper Slowdown Suspected in China 
 5. 
 In Iran, a Public Debate on Syria 
 
 
 1. 
 Sisters Spend $150 Million for Two Houses 
 2. 
 Top &apos;Knifeletes&apos; Compete for Cutting Championship 
 3. 
 Buyer of Munch&apos;s &apos;The Scream&apos; is Revealed 
 4. 
 A Luxury Penthouse With Outdoor Shower and Hot Tub 
 5. 
 The Quest to Build a 90,000 Square Foot Mansion 
 
 
 1. 
 Obama Intensifies Tax Fight 2248 comments 
 2. 
 NAACP Cool Toward Romney&apos;s Overtures 1193 comments 
 3. 
 Opinion: Holder&apos;s Jim Crow Politics 632 comments 
 4. 
 Opinion: Obama&apos;s Shrinking Majority 481 comments 
 5. 
 Opinion: Henninger: Mitt Romney&apos;s Summer Vacation 479 comments 
 
 
 Most Read Articles Feed Most Emailed Feed Most Popular Video Feed Most Commented Feed Most Popular Feeds 
 
Editors&apos; Picks

 
 Subscriber Content Read Preview 
 
 Brokerage Scandal Shakes Iowa Town 
 
 Web Video Inflames Fight Over TV Fees 
 
 Keeping a Close Eye on Shoppers&apos; Retinas 
 
 A Cut Above: In These Knife Fights, Only Pride Gets Wounded 
 
 Loading... 
 Market Data Center 
 
Footnotes*

Real-time U.S. stock quotes reflect trades reported through Nasdaq only; comprehensive U.S. stock quotes reflect trading in all markets and are delayed at least 15 minutes. All quote volume is comprehensive and reflects trading in all markets, delayed at least 15 minutes. International stock quotes are delayed as per exchange requirements.
 
 Video 

 previous   next 

   
 Tax Surprise In Restricted Stock 
 1:24   
 Women: Now Is The Time To Plan For Retirement 
 2:18   
 Wealth: How To Ignore the Noise 
 2:33 
 
Most Recommended

 Comments Comments Commenters Commenters 

 1. 
 “Much of which goes to show that...;” 
 - Mark Johnson 184 Recommendations 2. 
 “Dear Dr Lucio, I&apos;m not a...;” 
 - Maureen DiRienzo 154 Recommendations 3. 
 “Where is the leftist legacy medi...;” 
 - Jonathan Murray 144 Recommendations 4. 
 “Thank you Dr. Lucio. I am also a...;” 
 - Carol Sandor 126 Recommendations 5. 
 “The socialists don&apos;t care. It&apos;s...;” 
 - Henry Newbold 122 Recommendations 

 William Encanta 1839 Recommendations Peter Venetoklis 1707 Recommendations Mary Childs 1512 Recommendations Matilda Anders 1481 Recommendations Gary Myers 1346 Recommendations 
 
Most Active Discussions

 Journal Community 
 
 
Religion&amp;Ethics

 Do we need religion to have ethics? Is it possible that a world without religion can be, on the whole, a better place to live? 
 
Question of the Day

 Should the Bush-era tax cuts be extended for one year for families earning less than $250,000? 
 
Question of the Day

 What does the housing market look like in your area? 
 
Small Talk

 Would you pay a surcharge to use a credit card instead of cash? 
 
General Forum

 How do you feel about this statement? Most rich people in the U.S. deserve their wealth. 
 

 See all Discussion Groups 
 
More in Franchising

 
 Tough Times for Franchising 
 
 Franchising 2012 Outlook: Better Than 2011 Reality 
 
 Arbitration Holds Steady For Franchising Disputes 
 
 Franchise Sales Pull Back 
 
 Is a Franchise the Right Business for You?
	</body>
</document>
