<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007481" url="https://www.txdot.gov/about_us/commission/2006_meetings/transcripts/sep28.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:27" support="18" score="0.028928749786727614" bingtitle="September 28 Transcript - Texas Department of Transportation Home Page" webtitle="September 28 Transcript">
			<query id="000668" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001297" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000605" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000794" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000137" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001422" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001170" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000262" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000700" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001014" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001454" bing-rank="108"/>
	<description>The CDA was only basically put in place and we ... Minute Order Number 110479, dated March 30, 2006 ... and there&apos;s a filling station there and a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Contact Us | Site Map | Español Business with TxDOT | Careers | Drivers&amp;Vehicles | Local Information | News | Projects | Public Involvement | Safety | Travel | TxDOT Library | About Us 
 
 
 E-Mail Us 
 Districts, Divisions, Offices I&apos;m not sure Audit Aviation Bridge Construction Design Environmental Affairs Finance General Counsel General Services Government and Public Affairs Human Resources International Relations Maintenance Motor Carrier Occupational Safety Office of Civil Rights Public Transportation Research and Technology Implementation Right of Way Technology Services Texas Turnpike Authority Traffic Operations Transportation Planning and Programming Travel Information TxDOT Administration Texas Transportation Commission Abilene Amarillo Atlanta Austin Beaumont Brownwood Bryan Childress Corpus Christi Dallas El Paso Fort Worth Houston Laredo Lubbock Lufkin Odessa Paris Pharr San Angelo San Antonio Tyler Waco Wichita Falls Yoakum Web Administrator 

 About Us Overview Inside TxDOT Mission, Goals and Values Strategic Plan Strategic Policy Innovative Connectivity in Texas Contact Us Open Records Policy Public Involvement About This Site Get Engaged e-Subscribe to Updates TxDOT Administration About the Administration Organizational Chart Districts Texas Transportation Commission About the Commission Commission Meetings Audit Subcommittee Frequently Asked Questions Former Commissioners Other Resources Funding Sources TxDOT Modernization District and County Statistics (DISCOS) Fraud Hotline Accessibility Policy Disclaimer Privacy and Security Policy TxDOT History Administrative Rules 
 

 September 28 Transcript


 Texas Department of Transportation Commission Meeting 

Commission Room
Dewitt Greer Building
125 East 11th Street
Austin, Texas 78701-2483

Thursday, September 28, 2006

COMMISSION MEMBERS:

Ric Williamson, Chairman
John W. Johnson
Hope Andrade
Ted Houghton, Jr.


STAFF:

Michael W. Behrens, P.E., Executive Director
Bob Jackson, Interim General Counsel
Roger Polson, Executive Assistant to the
Deputy Executive Director
Dee Hernandez, Chief Minute Clerk

 PROCEEDINGS 

MR. WILLIAMSON: Good morning.

AUDIENCE: Good morning.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It is 9:06 a.m., and I would like to call the 
 September 2006 meeting of the Texas Transportation Commission to 
 order. It is a pleasure to have each and every one of you here with 
 us this morning.

Please note for the record that public notice of this meeting, 
 containing all items on the agenda, was filed with the Office of 
 Secretary of State at 11:38 a.m. on September 20, 2006.

Before we begin today&apos;s meeting, let&apos;s all take a moment to reach in 
 our pockets and purses, notebooks and valises and pull out our 
 pagers, cell phones and all of our electronic devices and place them 
 on the silent or vibrate mode so that no one will be interrupted 
 when they&apos;re addressing the commission.

And I thank you very much for that.

It is our custom to open with comments from the commission, and we 
 begin with Commissioner Houghton from the far west reaches of our 
 great state. Ted?

MR. HOUGHTON: Just proud to be here, Mr. Chairman. Thank you very 
 much, and thanks for coming today. There&apos;s a few noteworthy events 
 on our agenda, and I see some great friends out in the audience. Mr. 
 Chairman, I noted that we don&apos;t have a full house today. We must not 
 be giving anything away. But thank you for being here today.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Hope?

MS. ANDRADE: I also would like to welcome everyone to Austin and to 
 our commission meeting for this month. And I&apos;d like to, if I may, 
 Mr. Chairman, remind everyone, in case you haven&apos;t heard, that our 
 slogan&quot;Don&apos;t Mess With Texas&quot;is up for a national award and voting 
 ends tonight, and so I would like to encourage you to support this 
 by going to www.votedmwt.com, and place your vote. Voting ends 
 tonight and we&apos;re competing with some other slogans like&quot;You Got 
 It&quot;and the Las Vegas slogan about&quot;What Happens Here Stays Here&quot;but I don&apos;t think&quot;Don&apos;t Mess With Texas&quot;we&apos;ve all taken ownership 
 and are proud of that slogan, so if you all would support it, we 
 would appreciate it.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, Hope.

MS. ANDRADE: Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: John?

MR. JOHNSON: Hope, I think that&apos;s an excellent point and suggestion.&quot;Don&apos;t Mess With Texas&quot;is clearly recognized in a lot of areas and 
 it&apos;s been a great slogan for our cleanup efforts around the state, 
 and so I&apos;d encourage you, as Hope has, to get online and vote to 
 support it.

It&apos;s wonderful to see so many people here from the Valley. We&apos;ve got 
 a couple of items on the agenda from the Valley, very important to 
 what&apos;s going on all up and down the Rio Grande River. There&apos;s just 
 so much commerce going on, it&apos;s the gateway to Texas, and we&apos;re glad 
 to be able to assist that commerce.

We have some financial issues which I think are exciting which will 
 show you not only is a lot of work going on presently across this 
 great state, but in the next few years even more work will continue 
 to be done.

Welcome and delighted that everyone is here.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, John. And I associate myself with the 
 remarks of my three colleagues. We appreciate you taking the time 
 out of your valuable day to be with us, whether you have business 
 with the commission or you&apos;re simply observing the business of 
 others.

Let me remind everyone if you wish to address the commission during 
 today&apos;s meeting, we ask that you complete one of two speaker cards 
 which you can find at the registration table to your immediate right 
 in the lobby. If you&apos;re going to comment or discuss an item that&apos;s 
 on our agenda, we ask that you complete a yellow card, such as the 
 one in my left hand, and please identify the agenda item upon which 
 you wish to speak. If you wish to comment during the open comment 
 period which will occur at the end of this meeting, we ask that you 
 fill out a blue card, similar to the one in my left hand, and 
 identify, again, the item upon which you&apos;re going to be commenting.

Regardless of the color of the card, we ask that you try to limit 
 your comments to three minutes so that everyone will have the 
 opportunity to voice their opinion before the commission.

Mike, before we go to the minutes, let&apos;s take a moment and address 
 items of a more personal nature.

MR. BEHRENS: Thank you. We always like to honor people that have put 
 in long service with the department, and I&apos;m going to yield the 
 floor to Commissioner Johnson to make that presentation.

MR. JOHNSON: Thank you, Mike.

It&apos;s a pleasure to recognize people who are part of the fiber and 
 fabric of this great agency. There are almost 15,000 employees, and 
 believe me, they do a tremendous job, but today I have the 
 significant honor of recognizing one who has helped me over the 
 course of almost eight years stay abreast of what is going on. She&apos;s 
 kept me out of lawsuits and a few other issues that we run the risk 
 of being a party to. And she&apos;s devoted so much time on my behalf, I 
 have a personal stake in this, and so I&apos;m delighted to be able to 
 recognize Phyllis Chandler who has been my very able and capable 
 administrative assistant since I was sworn in almost eight years 
 ago.

Phyllis has served this state and this agency for 15 years. She 
 started in the Paris District and then came to the Austin area, and 
 she&apos;s just done me a tremendous job and I&apos;m deeply grateful and 
 beholding to her. Likewise, everything she does and everyone she 
 comes in contact with, she represents this agency and this state in 
 magnificent fashion.

So Phyllis, if you would come forward, I have the distinct pleasure 
 of giving you a plaque with your name and 15 years of service, along 
 with a token that our service awards allow us to present to people 
 like yourself who truly have done a great job.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Phyllis, do you want to like take a moment and blast 
 all four of us at once?

(General talking and laughter; pause for presentation and photos.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Phyllis has worked for John the last few years or 
 worked with John the last few years, and I can&apos;t let it go, John, 
 without a comment about Phyllis. We have, as you said, nearly 15,000 
 great employees, and for the most part, I think, down the line 
 dedicated to the mission and the plan of the agency.

And I think of a lot of adjectives when I think of Mike or Steve or 
 Amadeo or Coby or Jefferson or when I think of Maribel Chavez in my 
 area. The adjective I think about with Phyllis is grace and dignity. 
 In the six years I&apos;ve been here, you have always conducted yourself 
 with grace and dignity, and that&apos;s frequently not easy, particularly 
 in the last couple of years of the firestorm we&apos;ve had to go through 
 with the new Texas transportation plan. So I add my appreciation for 
 15 years well done.

Mike, I think that we were going to change the agenda a bit.

MR. BEHRENS: Yes, sir. I&apos;d like to start out with agenda item number 
 9. Do you want to take care of the minutes before we do that?

MR. WILLIAMSON: Mike, are you telling me I need to take care of the 
 minutes?

MR. BEHRENS: Yes, sir.

MR. JOHNSON: No. He&apos;s just advising you.

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, we need to approve the minutes from the 
 August 24 meeting. They&apos;re in your packet, you&apos;ve had time to read 
 them, no doubt. Do I have a motion?

MR. JOHNSON: So moved.

MS. ANDRADE: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: We&apos;ll take up agenda item number 9 which concerns 
 Finance, and this is recommending approval of financial documents 
 that are needed for issuance of the Texas Mobility Fund bonds. 
 James?

MR. BASS: Good morning. For the record, I&apos;m James Bass, chief 
 financial officer of TxDOT.

Through this minute order, the commission directs the department to 
 execute any necessary documents and to issue no more than $1.3 
 billion of Texas Mobility Fund bonds.

The finance plan for this issuance includes a constant maturity swap 
 which has been reviewed by and recommended for commission 
 consideration by the Derivative Committee. The commission would also 
 approve the documents in the exhibit which are associated with the 
 bonds and would authorize the department representative to approve 
 any necessary revisions to those documents.

Additionally, the minute order would approve certain entities as 
 swap counter-parties to the commission and would also approve a 
 custodial bank to assist the department with certain investments for 
 the Mobility Fund.

I&apos;d be happy to answer any questions you might have, and staff 
 recommends approval.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation of this agenda item. Have you questions or comments?

MR. HOUGHTON: What is, James, the capacity for authorization under 
 the Texas Mobility Fund?

MR. BASS: Currently the authorization that we&apos;ve received from the 
 Bond Review Board is the ability to issue up to $4 billion of bonds. 
 After this issuance, although it approves us up to $1.3-, the 
 current plan is for $1.25-. That would put us at having issued $3- 
 out of the $4 billion approved. We do believe there&apos;s additional 
 capacity above and beyond that from the revenues coming in, however, 
 that would require us to go back to the Bond Review Board to receive 
 that approval.

MR. HOUGHTON: We know what the capacity might be?

MR. BASS: It varies depending upon various structures that the 
 commission might approve as we go forward. Conservative, I&apos;d say 
 five and a quarter billion, on up.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Other questions, comments, members?

MR. JOHNSON: My observation is that&apos;s a great-looking tie.

And I think this is significant because the voters of this state 
 approved the Mobility fund, and it shows what we were able to do in 
 terms of leveraging our resources to get more work done more 
 quickly, and I just salute everybody who has been involved, from our 
 financial advisors to your very capable staff. I think this is a 
 great step.

MR. BASS: Thank you. I would also say the districts have done a 
 truly amazing job of putting this money to work.

MR. JOHNSON: Absolutely.

MR. BASS: And there&apos;s billions of dollars of activity in play today 
 that wouldn&apos;t be other than for the Mobility Fund.

MR. HOUGHTON: Can we identify that activity by district?

MR. BASS: Yes, we can.

MR. HOUGHTON: And the follow-up question there is with the 
 increasing capacity, it would then increase the amount of capacity 
 to the districts. Do they know that yet?

MR. BASS: We continue to work through that with our financial 
 planning group that meets monthly to discuss that on how to allocate 
 that.

MR. HOUGHTON: But we have not added that new capacity into their 
 allocation to the major metros. Correct?

MR. BASS: Not that I&apos;m aware of.

MR. WILLIAMSON: James, I have a couple of questions similar to that 
 of John and Ted from a slightly different aspect. Recently I&apos;ve been 
 asked about whether or not we&apos;re deploying the Mobility Fund fast 
 enough to address the state&apos;s congestion problems. For the audience 
 that doesn&apos;t keep up with the arcane-ness of our department, as I 
 understand it, we&apos;re basically a cash flow operation, we have three 
 major sources of input: that&apos;s the gasoline tax collected at the 
 state level; that&apos;s the federal gasoline tax, 70 percent of which we 
 pay is returned to our transportation program; and we have the motor 
 vehicle registration fee. The Mobility Fund is underwritten by a 
 series of fees and taxes not associated with those three cash flow 
 inputs, so this is now our fourth major source of cash flow coming 
 in.

Now, cash flow out, besides the administrative overhead, the 
 transfer to other departments, the things that keep the entire 
 operation working, as I understand it, breaks into two pieces: a 
 distribution to our districts based upon plans they develop with 
 local and regional leaders; and a smaller, perhaps in the range of 
 15 percent, distribution directly from the commission primarily 
 targeted at pass-through toll and military base expansion 
 operations.

When someone opines that the Mobility Fund has not been deployed 
 fast enough, would they most likely be making that observation based 
 upon the cash coming in without realizing that the contracts are 
 being executed to spend that money going out on the district side?

MR. BASS: I would agree. I think it&apos;s a misunderstanding of how the 
 department operates and that we are truly operating on a cash flow 
 basis. For example, the amount of activity that is going on that has 
 been advanced through the Mobility Fund is roughly $5 billion. 
 There&apos;s $5 billion in our accounting system that&apos;s targeted and 
 working from the Mobility Fund. However, I mentioned after this 
 issuance we will have only issued $3 billion from the Mobility Fund, 
 and that&apos;s what a lot of people tend to focus on is when we issue 
 the bonds, therefore, there must only be $3 billion worth of work 
 going on.

As we all know, the larger construction projects take two, three, 
 four years sometimes to build and complete, therefore, we only issue 
 the bonds as the cash flow of those thousands of projects dictate, 
 and that&apos;s why the projects, the dollar amount that&apos;s been advanced 
 today exceeds the amount of bonds that we&apos;ve issued, however, over 
 the next 18 to 24 months we think those two will catch up as all 
 those projects come to completion.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It&apos;s like two disconnected but parallel lines: 
 they&apos;ll cross occasionally, they&apos;ll separate, and they&apos;ll cross.

MR. BASS: Almost always the amount of projects advanced will lead 
 the amount of bonds issued out of this program.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And Ted asked for some information and I want to 
 echo that, and I know Hope has spoken to me several times about 
 wanting to know some of this data on a detailed level, and that is 
 we all know that, for example, in Montgomery County there is a 
 tremendous pass-through toll program soon to be started that&apos;s a 
 direct result of the department&apos;s financial ability to make 
 guarantees to Montgomery County. We know that State Highway 121 in 
 North Texas will soon probably be awarded to a private sector 
 consortium. All of those things are possible because of the cash 
 flow in the department has and projects it will have.

I think it would be very interesting to know -- and I may need to be 
 directing this to Coby if he&apos;s not left the room; he must have 
 anticipated I was going to call him up -- I think it would be 
 interesting to know the economic impact, not just on highways, Ted, 
 but on the state&apos;s employment base, the result of this expansion of 
 highway construction over the last six years. It would be 
 interesting to know the probable reduction in congestion and the 
 probable improvement in air quality. If we can quantify the enhanced 
 safety, the number of jobs -- again not related to construction -- 
 that we&apos;ve brought in, and how much we&apos;ve been able to preserve our 
 system as a result of this. I think perhaps if the financial and GBE 
 divisions can work on that data and produce it for us, I think we&apos;d 
 like to see it.

MR. HOUGHTON: Well, there&apos;s kind of two components to it. One is the 
 Mobility Fund as we ramp up and you have kind of when you peak out 
 on the Mobility Fund, but then you have your CDA program that&apos;s 
 going parallel with that. But from a Mobility Fund standpoint, 
 there&apos;s a bubble there that we&apos;re going to hit that the revenue 
 stream is going to be able to support so much of debt.

MR. BASS: Correct. At some point we will fully leverage the first 
 wave of the Mobility Fund and then we&apos;ll have to wait a period of 
 time as that debt is retired before we can issue additional, or 
 receive additional funds into that we could then leverage as well.

MR. HOUGHTON: The other question is I&apos;ll go back to one of my 
 original questions, if you have the capacity based upon the revenue 
 sources, the tickets and things like that, is the increase to the 
 eight major metros under the Mobility Fund, what they will see, 
 realize in cash to leverage projects.

MR. BASS: There&apos;s, as in most cases, always good news and bad news. 
 The good news is we believe there&apos;s additional capacity from the 
 Mobility Fund because the revenue is coming in, the estimate is 
 continuing to grow as Texas grows. The thing that&apos;s combating that, 
 that we face not only in the Mobility Fund but in all of our 
 programs, is the increased construction cost. And so how much does 
 that additional money truly equate to additional projects or is it 
 helping us come closer to matching inflation over time. And that&apos;s 
 going to vary on a region-by-region basis, but that&apos;s the other I 
 want to, I guess, tell you the cloud associated with the silver 
 lining as well.

MR. HOUGHTON: Good news/bad news.

MR. BASS: Right.

MS. ANDRADE: Mr. Chairman, if I may say, I&apos;m glad that you&apos;re asking 
 for information as to how we can translate what this means to the 
 normal citizen about that it does create many more job 
 opportunities, and it does bring economic opportunity. The last tour 
 that I took of our SH 130 from the helicopter, I could see lots of 
 people working, I could see lots of new roofs which means it&apos;s 
 attracted new development, and I would appreciate you translating 
 that into what does this mean for the districts that we live in. 
 Thank you.

MR. BASS: And Chairman, you mentioned pass-through tolls and 
 Montgomery County. I&apos;m not sure if they&apos;ve closed the initial 
 issuance of their debt to advance that project that will then 
 partially repay over time. If they haven&apos;t, they&apos;re very close to 
 it. And I know Williamson County, as well, is very close to 
 providing the initial funding for their project. So even that 
 program is advancing projects throughout the state and delivering 
 those years ahead of otherwise.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And hopefully our Cameron County partners are fixing 
 to kick it up into about fourth gear and get after it down in -- 
 what did I call you, the far west end of the state -- that would be 
 the far southern entrance to the state.

Anything else members?

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Do I have a motion?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MR. BASS: Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, James.

MR. BEHRENS: Now we&apos;ll move to agenda item number 2 which will be a 
 report given to you by Amadeo on TTC-35, about the comprehensive 
 development agreement procurement process, and also other activities 
 that are happening along the TTC corridor. Amadeo?

MR. SAENZ: Good morning, commissioners. For the record, Amadeo 
 Saenz, assistant executive director for Engineering Operations. I 
 apologize for my voice this morning. I think I&apos;m coming down with a 
 little bit of a cold. And I thought I sounded bad until I talked to 
 a couple of our guys this morning that sounded much, much worse, so 
 I feel I&apos;m better off.

But the agenda item number 2 is a status report that I would like to 
 give you on the activities that are going on with our Trans-Texas 
 Corridor 35, we&apos;ve reached a couple of milestones. But before I 
 start, I wanted to go through and give you a status. I will have 
 some PowerPoints, it will start kind of in the middle of my 
 presentation; I didn&apos;t have PowerPoint for the whole thing. We&apos;ll 
 get to it in a minute.

I wanted to kind of give you a status of where we&apos;re at on some of 
 the different projects that we have been developing through the 
 TTC-35 procurement process. The first one I want to talk about is 
 the State Highway 130 Segments 5 and 6. If you all recall, at the 
 end of June, our June commission meeting, TxDOT signed a commitment 
 agreement approving the facility implementation plan and moving 
 forward to agree to enter into a facility agreement with 
 Cintra-Zachry, provided that the 23 elements that were outlined in 
 the commitment agreement were delivered. We have been working on 
 those diligently to get those approved.

The biggest item was, of course, the re-evaluation of the 
 environmental for 130 Segments 5 and 6, and I&apos;m happy to say that 
 that&apos;s moving forward. We have been having some public hearings. We 
 had a public hearing on the 26th, we had a public hearing yesterday, 
 and we have a public hearing tonight, and that will complete the 
 public involvement process of that re-evaluation of that document. 
 And we anticipate having clearance from Federal Highway by 
 Thanksgiving of this year. That will clear one of the biggest things 
 that needed to be looked at.

There&apos;s also Cintra has been working on some of the requirements 
 that they have, Cintra-Zachry. Of course, they had to submit some 
 interchange justification reports for connections to Interstate 10. 
 That has to have Federal Highway approval and that&apos;s been done.

We&apos;ve been finalizing the price reasonableness evaluation, and a 
 value engineering report and study that has to be done for the 
 project because of the size. Those are well underway and will be 
 completed this month. Preliminary schematics have been submitted to 
 Federal Highway for them to review and approve; that&apos;s also a 
 requirement. So we&apos;re well underway to completing all our 23 items 
 that were pending as part of that commitment agreement.

Where we go from here, of course, the environmental will be cleared. 
 Once that&apos;s done, we will finalize the facility management plan that 
 Cintra is also developing, and sign the concession agreement, and 
 then Cintra will have the time that was allowed for them to close 
 financing and get the project moving. So that project is well 
 underway and is moving just like we had planned.

If you recall, also we did receive from Cintra-Zachry -- they&apos;re 
 able to bring projects forward -- they identified a railroad project 
 from north of Dallas-Fort Worth down to Laredo as a project that was 
 ready for development. We agreed with them, and on July 31 we did 
 reply to them that we agreed that that rail project was ready for 
 development, and we have been working closely with Cintra-Zachry to 
 put together the facility implementation plan or where they will put 
 a facility implementation plan together that basically outlines how 
 they plan to develop or plan and develop that project and implement 
 that project.

At the same time, we are working closely with Federal Highway 
 Administration and the Surface Transportation Board. This project of 
 constructing rail is a project that has never been done before, at 
 least a project of this magnitude, so we have been working and 
 trying to coordinate with Federal Highway Administration and the 
 Surface Transportation Board because Surface Transportation Board is 
 the federal agency that approves the construction of rail projects.

We have a meeting next week in Washington, meeting with both federal 
 agencies to finalize the process of how we clear the environmental 
 and get that project moving. At the same time, as I mentioned, 
 Cintra-Zachry is doing their agreement and facility implementation 
 plan, and then those processes will merge together and we&apos;ll move 
 forward on that process.

The last project that I wanted to bring up on here, a project that 
 we did receive from Cintra-Zachry, a letter that Loop 9 in the 
 southern part of the Metroplex was ready for development, and they 
 identified a project from Interstate 30 east of Dallas, then south 
 and west around Dallas and Fort Worth, and come back to Interstate 
 30 west of Fort Worth. They&apos;ve also said that this was a project 
 that falls under the connectivity projects that the facility 
 agreement allows them to bring forward.

We have been reviewing their submittal and agree with them that 
 because a lot of environmental work had been done on a portion of 
 that project, the portion in the Dallas District that goes from 
 about 35 East all the way to 30, because we have a lot of 
 environmental investigations that we have done, that project, we 
 agree, is also ready for development and we want to initiate moving 
 forward with that project.

The portion of the project west of 35, from west of 35 West all the 
 way to 30, no environmental work has been done to date, so we have 
 been in communication with the RTC and are looking at initiating the 
 environmental study so that we can have more data before we proceed 
 with that portion of the project. So in that case, what we&apos;re doing 
 is basically breaking the project into two where we will initiate 
 the environmental study to catch up the western leg but not slow 
 down the eastern leg because the western leg has not been done. So 
 we will approach that project in two different scenarios but move it 
 forward.

That&apos;s what we&apos;ve been doing on project-specific for TTC-35. I&apos;ll be 
 happy to answer any questions. Then I&apos;m going to jump into our 
 master development agreement, but I&apos;d like to see if you have 
 questions on these first.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, please feel free to ask or comment. I&apos;m 
 going to have an extensive -- not extensive -- I&apos;m going to have a 
 list of questions for Amadeo that are designed to establish certain 
 things for the record and they can wait till the end. So please if 
 you have questions, go ahead.

MR. SAENZ: Well, I&apos;ll be happy to go through and we&apos;ll just do the 
 questions at the end.

MR. WILLIAMSON: John?

MR. JOHNSON: Well, my question was what I interpreted, Amadeo, is 
 the treatment as the TTC-35 approaches the Metroplex that both 
 elements we&apos;re proceeding on, we&apos;re just in various stages: 
 environmental on the western leg, if you will, and then we&apos;re 
 actually proceeding further than that on the eastern leg. But we&apos;re 
 not neglecting one for the other, it&apos;s just one is further along.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. What it is is one portion of the project was 
 further along than the other, we want to be able to do the 
 environmental so that we can make the right decisions as we move 
 forward on the western leg. But both projects will be moving 
 forward.

MR. JOHNSON: Thank you.

MR. HOUGHTON: And this is, for lack of a better word, the donut 
 concept that the RTC has been endorsing, as well as the locals.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. The Loop 9 project has been a project that has 
 been in the Metroplex long-range plan as an identified need.

MR. HOUGHTON: And had not been able to fund that project.

MR. SAENZ: Not been able to fund it. They had identified it, and 
 through some commitment with Dallas County, had decided to move on 
 that southeastern leg. The southwestern leg, they had not initiated 
 any environmental studies, and that&apos;s why that one is a little bit 
 further behind, but it is a project that the Metroplex had 
 identified and has been looking at. And of course, when we look at 
 it and we look at the grand scheme, those projects are projects that 
 are potential connectivity projects. With respect to whether they 
 will be designated TTC-35 or not, the environmental process will 
 determine that as we get to the completion of that process.

MR. HOUGHTON: And Cintra-Zachry has determined that that project 
 will self-fund?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. In their letter they said that the project was 
 a project that was ready for development and they felt that it could 
 self-perform.

MR. HOUGHTON: Which means that the transfer risk for building that 
 is to the private sector, not on either Dallas County or the State 
 of Texas. Correct?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct. And then, of course, this is based, as 
 always, on preliminary studies, preliminary financial information, 
 kind of 30,000-foot view. As we drill down into the project, we&apos;ll 
 be able to have a lot more detail, but most of the time our original 
 numbers are very conservative and they only get better.

MR. HOUGHTON: And we&apos;ve decided this is about the same footprint 
 project as 5 and 6 on 130, would you not say?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. What the Metroplex had been looking at 
 developing on Loop 9 was a controlled access expressway type 
 facility on about 400 to 500 feet of right of way.

MR. HOUGHTON: And how many miles?

MR. SAENZ: I believe it was over 140 miles.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, that&apos;s not this project.

MR. HOUGHTON: I&apos;m just talking about the Loop 9 on the southeastern 
 side.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, the southeast side.

MR. HOUGHTON: From Interstate Highway 20 down to 35.

MR. SAENZ: Okay. I&apos;m talking about the whole thing that was 
 submitted.

MR. HOUGHTON: I&apos;m just talking about the one.

MR. SAENZ: About 40 miles.

MR. HOUGHTON: Right. About 40 miles?

MR. SAENZ: Yes.

MR. HOUGHTON: And I understand you&apos;ve committed to have a facility 
 implementation plan done by December 31. Is that correct?

MR. SAENZ: Some people are going to have to work a lot of hours to 
 do that, but we are going to work diligently to move this project 
 forward.

MS. ANDRADE: Amadeo, remind me how long --

MR. SAENZ: Excuse me, Commissioner, but one of the things is we have 
 been working to put together a program where we have identified 
 business terms and technical requirements and specifications that 
 will allow us to be able to move forward through those procurements 
 at a much faster pace than we have in the past without having to 
 reinvent the wheel every time.

MR. HOUGHTON: As a result of our experience on the 130, 5 and 6.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MS. ANDRADE: Amadeo, remind me how long these projects have been 
 waiting for funding.

MR. SAENZ: I don&apos;t know exactly.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Loop 9, 35 years.

MR. SAENZ: Loop 9, about 30-35 years, and it was not funded in the 
 next ten years. It was in their plan as identified over the next 25 
 years, but it was not funded within the next ten years, so it was 35 
 plus ten, 45 years before they could get to it.

MR. HOUGHTON: I may be stretching this out a little bit, Amadeo, but 
 what is the back-of-a-napkin type of cost estimates to build this 
 project, this southeastern portion of Loop 9?

MR. SAENZ: I will have to ask staff and get that to you, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: I&apos;m just curious.

MR. SAENZ: Forty miles, I would say somewhere between about $400- to 
 $600 million for that first segment, ballpark figure based on $10- 
 to $12 million a mile.

MR. JOHNSON: Amadeo, to follow up on Hope&apos;s question about time, how 
 long has this project been in the wishful stage, if you will, have 
 we or can we make a calculation as to projects of that nature that 
 have been around for a long time but unfunded that are going to come 
 to fruition as a result of the development of these corridors and 
 the way that we&apos;re able to do it, and in essence, are coming at no 
 cost to the people -- not the people who drive the roads, but at no 
 cost out of our normal funding mechanisms.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir, we can. Of course, we have just asked the eight 
 metropolitan areas to update their Metropolitan Mobility Plan, and 
 now they&apos;re taking and identifying these projects that are what I 
 call revenue-positive projects or self-performers which means that 
 this project can be built without any public money. And of course, a 
 lot of these projects also will result in an additional concession 
 fee, and that concession fee they can then apply to a second tier of 
 projects.

So we&apos;re getting to that point where the MPOs, and in this case the 
 RTC will identify if I build 121, if I build 161 through a CDA 
 process, I&apos;ll be able to generate a billion dollars more and now I 
 can apply that billion dollars to these other projects.

So we&apos;ll be able to come up with a list of what I would call the 
 second tier projects -- well, the first tier and second tier 
 projects that can be done without any public money, and we&apos;ll be 
 able to provide that to you.

MR. JOHNSON: I think, one, the total amount of dollars is 
 staggering, but also the amount of time, as Hope mentioned and you 
 said, that we have had these projects literally in abeyance waiting 
 on funding, that that answer is going to be staggering too, and it&apos;s 
 incredible what is going on in terms of moving projects and 
 corridors through the pipeline and getting them done so everybody 
 can benefit.

MR. SAENZ: Right. If I remember correctly, about three months ago 
 when the Metroplex folks were here with us making their 
 presentation, Michael Morris in his presentation identified that the 
 new tools were bringing in about $5 billion worth of projects that 
 they could not do prior to implementing some of the new tools. So 
 it&apos;s a staggering number, it&apos;s a great number.

MS. ANDRADE: Amadeo, and I think that&apos;s a key message that we need 
 to communicate to our public, because I know that even to me that 
 I&apos;m involved in everyday transportation, it&apos;s astounding to hear 
 that these projects have been waiting for 30 years and that if we 
 don&apos;t do it this route, that we would probably wait another ten to 
 15 years, and I don&apos;t think that&apos;s quite a message that&apos;s 
 communicated as well because I&apos;m surprised when we hear that.

MR. SAENZ: Well, I think a couple of things that you all have done 
 have really helped, and one is for, I guess, the longer past when 
 the commission was the one that selected all the projects statewide 
 for mobility, the region never knew when a project was going to get 
 selected, or if a project was going to get selected, or maybe a 
 portion of a project was going to get selected. When you all 
 initiated the change that now we are allocating to them the 
 resources and we let them put together their plan and identify their 
 priorities, they now realize that the money that&apos;s available can 
 only carry them so far and they have to learn and they have to 
 utilize all the tools to be able to leverage those.

And now they get to prioritize. They use the Fund 6 for their 
 priorities, leverage that Fund 6 to catch the next set of projects 
 that will bring in that additional resource so they can do the 
 future projects. And now they can see in their plan how their system 
 is going to evolve by one project, in essence, helping the other, 
 very similar to the system financing that the toll agencies use, 
 they take one project to help another.

The next item that I&apos;d like to talk about is give you a status 
 report on the development of the master development plan that was 
 part of the requirement of the TTC-35 procurement. And of course, 
 just as a little bit of history, what we tried to accomplish with 
 our CDA is we wanted to bring on board a long-term strategic partner 
 to work along with TxDOT, we wanted to minimize the public sector 
 financing contributions that would be required to develop a corridor 
 like TTC-35, and maximize the private sector financial 
 contributions, and we also wanted to see how we could accelerate the 
 delivery of that project. We&apos;ve been working on all of those.

The master development plan is a 50-year partnership that shows 
 near-term projects, mid-term projects and long-term projects that 
 will be developed for Trans-Texas Corridor from Oklahoma all the way 
 down to Mexico. The CDA was only basically put in place and we had 
 the first item of work, and the only item of work that Cintra was 
 required to do was for $3.5 million they were committed to putting 
 together this master development plan which is what we&apos;re talking 
 about right now. And the master development plan included a project 
 development plan, it included a project financial plan for the 
 projects that would be developed over the 50-year period, and then 
 as well as some quality plans and some project management plans on 
 how they would do the projects.

The CDA did not authorize Cintra-Zachry to construct any named 
 facility in the MDP. It did have a requirement or a commitment that 
 they would have the right of first negotiation on at least $400 
 million of the CDA.

The master development plan was basically broken up into milestones 
 of how we wanted to accomplish this thing. Our first milestone was 
 kind of basically a planning document. We want them to tell us how 
 you&apos;re going to approach projects through a project management plan, 
 tell us how you&apos;re going to ensure that what you give us is done 
 with quality and how you would manage that, and of course, give us a 
 schedule of how you&apos;re going to put together this master development 
 plan. That was done very early on in the project; we reached 
 milestone one very quickly.

The second milestone, basically we asked them to tell us and show us 
 the demographics that they were going to be using, what are the 
 trends, what&apos;s the population demographics, what&apos;s the population 
 growth rates that you&apos;re going to be using, what are your traffic 
 growth rates you&apos;re going to be using, so that we could make sure 
 that as we&apos;re putting something together we get something that is 
 realistic and not something that&apos;s not realistic.

The third part is basically once you have your demographics, we want 
 you to then apply and list the potential projects that need to be 
 developed or that would be developed under this master development 
 agreement, and also put together some draft financial models of how 
 you would finance these projects.

The fourth milestone was basically to take those projects in 
 milestone number three, do a risk and financial analysis on each of 
 those projects, do some sketch level traffic and revenue studies, do 
 some conceptual engineering, kind of drill down and get as much 
 information as you can, and apply it to those projects so that we 
 can see exactly, with the best information we have, how much will 
 the project cost, what will the financial requirements be, and how 
 could we do that.

And then, of course, under milestone five we started phasing the 
 facilities into which facilities should be done first, which should 
 be done second, which should be done in a longer term. The near-term 
 facilities are the facilities that could be developed in the first 
 five years; the mid-term facilities are from year five to about year 
 ten; and the long-term facilities are facilities that are after year 
 ten.

Milestone number six then took all that information that we got and 
 all the research and work that was done, and it was put together and 
 we updated the documents that were part of the earlier milestones in 
 two through five, as well as updating the conceptual financial plans 
 and conceptual project management plans that were part of the CDA 
 document. Those were then all put together and submitted to us in 
 one document that identified the near-term projects, the mid-term 
 projects, and the long-term projects, as well as the financial.

Milestone number seven, because this master development plan is a 
 living document, as we go through and other projects are identified, 
 or as we go through and the environmental process determines where 
 projects are located that are different than the assumptions that 
 were made as part of this plan, then this plan needs to be updated 
 to conform to that. If you have a different route that requires a 
 different length of project, of course, the project will have a 
 different cost. As we go through time, you have to update estimates. 
 So this document will always be a living document and we have to 
 have a methodology in place so that we can update the document in 
 the future.

Some of the elements of the plan, for all the potential projects -- 
 or facilities, as we call them in the plan -- the master development 
 plan identifies their characteristics: kind of where is it going to 
 be located; what mode is it, is it rail, is it highways, is it truck 
 lanes, is it utility corridors; if it&apos;s highways, how many lanes 
 will it have. From that we come up with conceptual design and cost. 
 We look at phasing and sequencing, how would you phase and sequence 
 the project. And then also we look at the revenues that this project 
 can generate over time, and in addition, what potential funding 
 sources are available to finance the project. We did that for all of 
 the projects.

Now, as we look at the projects, the near-term projects are the 
 projects that we would say are ready to go in the short-term. 
 They&apos;re projects where the need is there and the financial is there, 
 so for near-term projects, we did a more comprehensive financial 
 model which included the estimated concessions that could be 
 realized if the project was built.

All the proposed planning in this document is based on what 
 Cintra-Zachry identified in working with us, where they thought, and 
 we agreed, that the project may go. As I said, this is a living 
 document. NEPA will determine where the final location of each one 
 of those facilities will be, and if it&apos;s different from the 
 assumptions that were made in this document, then this document will 
 have to be updated.

We have to make sure that all our projects will comply with all the 
 environmental approvals; we&apos;ll have coordination with the MPOs, the 
 cities, the counties; Federal Highway will also have to approve all 
 our; and of course, we ourselves do a lot of review and approvals. 
 The final traffic and revenue forecast will depend on the financial 
 models of the final projects. So the document is a living document 
 and will be subject to change.

Just in moving forward, if you recall when the proposal came in and 
 Cintra-Zachry&apos;s proposal had identified projects from the Metroplex 
 all the way down to San Antonio and they stopped at Interstate 10, 
 and those were their near-term projects. And if you recall, they 
 identified that the cost of those projects at the time was about $6 
 billion and the concession fee that they would be willing to provide 
 for the right to operate over a 50-year concession was about $1.2 
 billion.

The near-term projects that the facility agreement identified starts 
 up from north of the Metroplex, connecting 35 over east around 
 Dallas, continues east around Dallas and south, and when we look at 
 all these projects, there are several things that I need to show you 
 on this slide. One, these are the near-term facility projects that 
 are part of TTC-35, those are shown in the green. And then, of 
 course, the lines that are shown in the dash are some of the 
 connecting projects that they&apos;ve also identified at this time and 
 they&apos;re working.

So you see the Loop 9 projects is shown as a connecting project that 
 is being worked on. The final numbers have not been determined for 
 that project, but at this time it&apos;s not TTC-35, it&apos;s a connectivity 
 project. The environmental process will determine whether Loop 9 in 
 the future becomes TTC-35 or remains as a connectivity project, but 
 they can both be developed under this procurement.

Then around the Austin area you see the black dashed line, of 
 course, that&apos;s the 130, 1 through 4, that&apos;s being developed, and of 
 course, the green is the 130, 5 and 6 that&apos;s shown on there. And of 
 course, the new projects that were added to near-term projects are 
 the loops around the San Antonio area.

When we take a look at these projects and we total them up, these 
 projects total to about $8.8 billion which would be the cost of the 
 facility, and under the development plan those projects can be 
 built, and in addition to getting those projects built, we would get 
 almost $2 billion of potential concession fees.

What you will notice in this list that some of the projects have 
 parentheses around them, and these show that not every project has a 
 positive cash flow or every segment of the project has a positive 
 cash flow. But if you look at the corridor as a whole, the corridor 
 as a whole does result in an additional almost $2 billion. This is 
 just kind of a recap.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a series of questions I&apos;m going to ask, 
 Amadeo, but just one pops up as appropriate right now.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: What will happen to that $2 billion? Take your time, 
 go slowly.

MR. SAENZ: The $2 billion, of course, can be used to address 
 connectivity projects.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, don&apos;t talk in engineer-ese. How will the $2 
 billion be spent?

MR. SAENZ: The $2 billion, of course, comes to the department as a 
 concession fee, it goes into Fund 6. Commission will work with the 
 locals to identify other projects. We can either extend the corridor 
 to other parts along the 35 corridor, we can use it to build 
 connection projects from the corridor back into the metropolitan 
 areas. For example, the plan identifies some projects that connect 
 Waco to the corridor, that connect Temple to the corridor, the Loop 
 9 project, there&apos;s other connectivity projects in the Metroplex. 
 Some of this concession fee can be used for that.

The concession fee can be used to fund other modes of transportation 
 projects, like some of the rail projects and such that are needed 
 for the corridor.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So two points to be made. First, we frequently hear, 
 well, this is just a revenue scheme. Well, it&apos;s a revenue scheme to 
 do what? Solve transportation problems. It&apos;s not a revenue scheme to 
 pump up other state government, it&apos;s not a revenue scheme to help 
 higher education. The $2 billion will be used to address the state&apos;s 
 transportation problem.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: That&apos;s the first point to be made.

The second point to be made is that local and regional leaders will 
 identify which problems most address their congestion, air quality 
 and safety goals, and together with us will decide which projects to 
 build to address those problems.

For example, if Temple, Austin and San Antonio were able to persuade 
 those corporate citizens, the Union-Pacific Railroad to abandon 
 their tracks through the city center to permit the various transit 
 systems to take those tracks over for commuter rail and move to a 
 higher speed freight rail in the corridor, that would be an 
 appropriate project for the concession revenue to be targeted 
 towards. Yes or no?

MR. SAENZ: Yes.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Please continue.

MR. SAENZ: Okay. Just as a summary, the plan, as it&apos;s updated now, 
 identifies $8.8 billion in the near-term transportation construction 
 projects, and also provides for a concession fee above and beyond 
 that of $1.9 billion for TxDOT to use as we&apos;ve just discussed.

Looking at the plan, we have less information or less detailed 
 information for the mid-term and long-term projects, so what I tried 
 to do here is just basically identify. And of course, they did 
 identify the rail project that they had submitted earlier as ready 
 for development in their mid-term projects, but that&apos;s because rail 
 projects will take much longer to develop. We spoke earlier of the 
 coordination that will have to happen for the environmental side 
 between the Surface Transportation Board, Federal Highway 
 Administration and ourselves, so they did place that project, to be 
 a little bit more realistic, that it could be done but would be done 
 probably as a mid-term project.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Can higher speed freight rails, steel rails, can 
 they also be used for higher speed passenger rails?

MR. SAENZ: Higher speed passenger rails and higher speed freight 
 rails use the same facility.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So what is possible in terms of a interregional rail 
 system between Dallas-Fort Worth and San Antonio: 90 miles an hour 
 non-stop?

MR. SAENZ: Between 80 and 90 miles per hour non-stop, yes, sir.

They also showed some additional connectivity loops east and around 
 Dallas to TTC-35, and also some connections in Hillsboro and some 
 other projects that are identified in the plan. There&apos;s a countless 
 number of other projects that are in there.

In the long-term projects they did show the need for the high speed 
 rail facilities between Dallas-Fort Worth and San Antonio, and some 
 of the primary roadway work south of San Antonio to Laredo are shown 
 as long-term projects. And that makes sense in that if you look at 
 the congestion that we&apos;re seeing on 35 south of San Antonio to 
 Laredo, we still have a lot of capacity on the existing facilities. 
 They also showed the western loops around Dallas-Fort Worth to be on 
 the longer term, again because there&apos;s less of a need there. And of 
 course, they also identified some of the utility facilities.

I must remind you all that if you look at 2017, it is only ten years 
 away from here, so long-term is just post ten years.

MS. ANDRADE: I have a question. When you say primary roadway between 
 San Antonio and Laredo, could that possibly be truck lanes?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, ma&apos;am, that could be additional truck lanes or 
 additional multipurpose lanes that they can add capacity within the 
 median like we&apos;re doing on some of the other projects.

The environmental process will determine where the final route for 
 TTC-35 is going to be along the entire corridor, but if you remember 
 on the draft EIS, it showed that south of San Antonio the preferred 
 draft EIS corridor was parallel to the existing 35, so it would be 
 expansion of 35, if it stays that way through the environmental 
 process.

And as we move forward, and as I mentioned earlier, the MDP is a 
 dynamic document that will be changed as needed. The final route for 
 TTC-35 will be determined during the environmental process and we&apos;re 
 committed to including public involvement in every step of the 
 process, as we&apos;ve been doing already. And we must continue to do the 
 planning now rather than wait for congestion to grow out of 
 proportion and then try to stop the gap later.

That pretty much concludes my presentation. I do have a couple more 
 comments, but I&apos;d ask for questions before we move forward.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I&apos;ll ask a few and then rest a moment.

A great deal has been made about -- a great hubbub has been raised 
 by some members of the free press and some candidates for public 
 office about the unusual secrecy connected to this contract. For the 
 record, I want to establish what this contract is. We asked for 
 proposals from the private sector to develop a master development 
 plan. The plan was the core of a contract that had a cost of how 
 much money?

MR. SAENZ: The cost of that contract was $3.5 million.

MR. WILLIAMSON: That&apos;s million with an M?

MR. SAENZ: Million with an M.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It&apos;s not a $7 billion contract, as some have 
 assumed.

MR. SAENZ: It&apos;s a $3-1/2 million contract.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It is a $3-1/2 million contract to develop a master 
 development plan.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And there were three proposers, and the partnership 
 of Cintra, a Spanish firm, and Zachry America, or whatever they&apos;re 
 called, a third-generation San Antonio construction firm, had, in 
 our judgment, the best approach to developing this contract. Is that 
 correct?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Had we not been able in the time line specified to 
 reach an agreement with Cintra-Zachry on the development plan, would 
 we have then moved to our second choice and begun negotiations with 
 them to develop a plan?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir. What would have happened, because we did execute 
 the comprehensive development agreement, we would have to reopen and 
 re-procure the entire CDA.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And when we did that, had we exposed the 
 Cintra-Zachry proposal, the Fluor proposal, and the other one -- the 
 name escapes me -- we would have exposed their proprietary and 
 financial data to their competitors, who would then be re-proposing 
 for the second procurement. Correct?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: In your engineering judgment, given that this is a 
 complex transaction, have you handled this contract any differently 
 than you would have handled a typical design-blind bid-build 
 contract?

MR. SAENZ: They&apos;re handled exactly the same way.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And why has the commission instructed staff and 
 reminded themselves to generally remain silent and not argue with 
 those who have lodged illogical and inaccurate complaints?

MR. SAENZ: If we were to move forward and release the data, we, in 
 essence, would not have anyone that would want to propose to us 
 because they would not be able to bring in any innovation, bring in 
 any ideas on how to develop projects, and in essence, the program 
 would die.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And in your experience in state government, Amadeo, 
 do other agencies headed by elected officials screen and protect the 
 intellectual and financial data of their private sector proposers in 
 much the same way?

MR. SAENZ: We do everything exactly like all the other agencies.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So we haven&apos;t treated this contract any differently 
 than we have treated other contracts or as other contracts in other 
 state agencies in this state are treated?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Has there actually been a secret contract?

MR. SAENZ: No.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you for that.

Now, I am told that we are doing an internal study on the amount of 
 money which will be saved on the maintenance -- this is very 
 critical to distinguish this -- not the expansion of Interstate 35 
 but the maintenance of existing lanes and future expanded lanes, 
 we&apos;re doing a study on the cost savings of maintenance as a result 
 of traffic shifting to this parallel road.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. We&apos;ve got a consultant that&apos;s working on that, 
 they&apos;ve submitted some preliminary information that&apos;s still being 
 reviewed by our folks.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And let&apos;s assume for a moment that that figure is 
 going to be in the, say, $500 million on the low end, $750- on the 
 high end -- I think that&apos;s a good range -- is that $500- to $750 
 million money that would have been distributed out of the taxpayers&apos;tax revenue to maintain 35?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So to the extent that we&apos;re eliminating $500 million 
 of maintenance on 35 as a result of traffic patterns shifting to the 
 parallel, that&apos;s $500 million we have to invest in solving other 
 transportation problems in the state.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And is it also my understanding that we have a 
 congestion relief study ongoing to determine what percentage of 
 traffic moves off of Interstate 35 and onto the parallel?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir, it&apos;s part of the same study that&apos;s looking 
 numbers.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Is it safe to say that no less than 2.5 percent and 
 no more than 10 percent of the traffic is going to fall somewhere in 
 that range?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So for those who live in, for example, Hillsboro who 
 believe that Interstate 35 is their economic lifeblood and the 
 parallel might have the same impact on their city as Route 66 had on 
 some cities in Oklahoma, we can represent to them that it appears, 
 least case your traffic shrinks 2-1/2 percent, worst case it shrinks 
 10 percent, and in no circumstance should that be enough to markedly 
 impact your local economy?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct. The other thing that I think we need to 
 continue to stress is people will always have a choice: they can 
 come on the toll road if they so choose, but if they don&apos;t want to, 
 they can stay on the existing 35.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, you&apos;re leading into my next series of 
 questions. We&apos;ve been studying for two years now the actual cost and 
 tax revenue associated with the state&apos;s transportation grid. At this 
 point in time is it safe to say that we&apos;ve identified no tax road in 
 the state that generates enough revenue to pay for itself?

MR. SAENZ: So far, in all the work that we&apos;ve done, we&apos;ve not been 
 able to find a road that pays for itself.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Some roads get as high as 57 percent, most roads are 
 around 21 percent, as far as we can tell right now.

MR. SAENZ: The one that I&apos;ve seen that has the most was around 55 to 
 60, most of them run somewhere in the teens to low twenties.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And is it safe to say in our demographic studies 
 we&apos;ve determined that the flat rate gasoline tax is one of the 
 single most regressive taxes the state levels because there are no 
 exemptions, the state doesn&apos;t recognize rich or poor, it collects 
 the same fee from everybody?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Whereas, TTC-35 will be paid by someone volunteering 
 to pay the toll to achieve whatever purpose they wish to achieve.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Leaving the tax road to be used by those who don&apos;t 
 wish to volunteer to pay that toll.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: My final question before a I rest a moment. Is it 
 accurate to say, after three years on this mission, that we&apos;ve 
 determined that high speed rail, higher speed rail and the transfer 
 of freight out of downtown Texas could not possibly occur unless we 
 moved to the side and built it on a parallel with private financing?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct, we&apos;d not be able to do it.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I&apos;m going to rest a moment. Please ask whatever 
 questions you wish to. I&apos;ve got a few more I need to establish for 
 the record but I want to think about it.

MR. HOUGHTON: We need to spend a little bit more time on something 
 the chairman just brought up on the rail piece as a mid-term. We 
 have a letter from Cintra-Zachry believing that that project is 
 ready for development. Is that correct?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: And we&apos;re analyzing that or we agree with them that 
 that project is ready for development?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. As I mentioned earlier in the early part of the 
 presentation, we agree that that project is ready for development. 
 We&apos;re working to coordinate with Surface Transportation Board. 
 Because of the rail project, the cost, the type of project, the 
 different type of development it was put in as a mid-term project 
 which means that it&apos;s between five years and ten years instead of 
 between zero and five years, but it is a project that is being 
 worked on now. But we feel that probably it will take us a little 
 longer to put that project in place than it would allow us in the 
 first five years.

MR. HOUGHTON: And this is a project you can&apos;t really build in 
 stages, Amadeo, because you can&apos;t stop a rail line at Seguin.

MR. SAENZ: You have to build segments of independent utilities so 
 that someone is willing to use it, because if you build it and stop 
 it, we just can&apos;t get anywhere. It&apos;s very hard to make the railroad 
 do a U-turn.

MR. HOUGHTON: Yes, pretty tough to get a freight train to go the 
 other way.

MR. SAENZ: Yes.

MR. HOUGHTON: So from the standpoint of air quality and what we&apos;re 
 trying to accomplish, especially in the San Antonio, Austin and the 
 Tower 55 issues in Fort Worth, would you say this is a significant 
 project?

MR. SAENZ: Oh, this is a significant project that will allow for the 
 movement of freight rail from the metropolitan areas, improve air 
 quality, improve safety, improve congestion, and of course, by 
 moving it over, you would allow for economic opportunity along the 
 new corridor. There could be some instances, as you develop this 
 master rail project or this long rail project, that you can break it 
 up and have some usable segments that will allow you some short-term 
 gains that will even help finance the project.

And I&apos;ll give you an example off the top of my head. This is not in 
 the plan, but off the top of my head, I say okay, if we do something 
 to Tower 55 to separate those two railroads and you&apos;re able to then 
 charge a tax or a toll on the movements that go across this 
 grade-separated structure, that money then can be used to expand the 
 rail somewhere else. So just this one little idea that may be able 
 to be used to piece together the bigger project.

MR. HOUGHTON: So those trains sitting at Tower 55 waiting to cross 
 --

MR. SAENZ: Now they can just go straight across, there&apos;s no stopping 
 them.

MR. HOUGHTON: -- degrading the air, now we&apos;re talking about 
 significant economic opportunity.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Hope, anything?

MS. ANDRADE: Amadeo, I was in Chicago this week at a seminar and I 
 learned that Cintra actually currently manages 47 projects 
 worldwide, so I&apos;m glad to hear that we have such an experienced 
 partner.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, ma&apos;am.

MR. WILLIAMSON: John, anything?

MR. JOHNSON: I asked my questions before.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay. Then my last series of questions are about the 
 contract itself, Amadeo. Again, I&apos;m establishing some things for the 
 record.

Much has been said about what was originally $6.9 billion, what is 
 now $8.1 billion -- and I&apos;ll get back to that in a moment -- 
 construction --

MR. SAENZ: $8.8 billion.

MR. WILLIAMSON: -- $8.8 billion enuring to the benefit of a firm 
 that&apos;s located in Spain. When we execute plans with this development 
 agreement, that $8.8 billion will be forwarded by or be the legal 
 obligation of the private sector. Is that correct?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And that $8.8 billion will be spent on what?

MR. SAENZ: Building a state asset, building TTC-35.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Will they have to hire people?

MR. SAENZ: Oh, yes.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Will they hire people in Spain and bring them across 
 on a boat and house them here?

MR. SAENZ: I don&apos;t think so. I think that a project of that size 
 they&apos;re going to go out and contract with people there locally to 
 get the project built.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So they&apos;ll probably hire Texas citizens or United 
 States citizens who move to Texas to work on this particular project 
 for ten years, much like the Alaskan Pipeline.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Will they go mix the concrete up in Spain and bring 
 it across on a boat?

MR. SAENZ: No. Everything will be done here.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So the concrete will probably be purchased, or the 
 asphalt -- I don&apos;t want the asphalt guys to go nuts; we don&apos;t know 
 what they&apos;re going to use.

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: They&apos;ll probably mix the concrete or concoct the 
 asphalt locally in the state of Texas.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, what about the iron, what about the long steel 
 rods that go into the concrete, will they bring that in from maybe 
 France?

MR. SAENZ: No.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Because France is right next to Spain.

MR. SAENZ: That will also be here. There are some requirements. Some 
 of the financing that is being used is through TIFIA loans -- which 
 is just a loan that they will borrow, it&apos;s a source of money that&apos;s 
 available to anyone, including the private sector.

MR. WILLIAMSON: But not from the state of Texas, it&apos;s from the 
 federal government.

MR. SAENZ: It&apos;s from the federal government, it&apos;s a federal program. 
 When you use TIFIA, in essence, you federalize the project and then 
 there&apos;s federal requirements with respect to steel products of Buy 
 America, that you have to be able to show that the product that you 
 are using is 25 percent cheaper if you&apos;re bringing it from abroad. 
 So you will still have a lot of product that is here from the U.S., 
 maybe not Texas but here from the U.S.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So we&apos;ve established that most of the $8.8 billion 
 will be spent paying Texas citizens and purchasing products made or 
 manufactured in the United States of America.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. One other thing that we have added into this 
 agreement that regardless of where the project has federal dollars 
 or no federal dollars that it will have compliance with DBE 
 programs, extensive training programs. This is going to require a 
 lot of people to work on this project, and we want to make sure 
 that, one, we have a trained workforce, but we don&apos;t want to go out 
 there and take people from other contracts that are doing work on 
 other projects to do this project.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Driving up the cost of the tax-supported projects 
 that we have across the state.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: A few more questions along the same lines. Which 
 entity or which organization or which individual will hold title to 
 the ground beneath the asset?

MR. SAENZ: It will be the State of Texas through the Texas 
 Department of Transportation, just like any other highway.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And who will actually own the asset itself?

MR. SAENZ: We will.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We being?

MR. SAENZ: TxDOT.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So the State of Texas, acting through its designated 
 agent, the Texas Department of Transportation, will actually own the 
 asset.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So when someone says toll roads owned by somebody 
 from Spain, that is actually a misstatement of the truth.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Now, much has been said about well, okay, so the 
 money is going to be spent here and you&apos;re going to hold the title 
 but they&apos;re going to control it all. Who sets the toll rates on the 
 corridor?

MR. SAENZ: By agreement, through statute requirement, you all, the 
 Texas Transportation Commission. When you approve the contract, you 
 approve the toll rate as well as the toll escalation rate process 
 that was incorporated into that agreement.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And are we guaranteeing any of their debt?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Now let&apos;s talk about the only privately financed 
 toll road in the state that we&apos;re aware of to date. That would be 
 the Camino Colombia in South Texas.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir, that was built.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Did the state put any money into that toll road when 
 it was built?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Much like TTC-35, the private sector put the money 
 up.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Now, did those private sector entrepreneurs perhaps 
 make a bad decision to build that toll road, or did they perhaps put 
 more money into it than they should have, or did the economy not 
 advance like they thought it would?

MR. SAENZ: I think they made some assumptions as to what was going 
 to come forward with respect to development in traffic, and based on 
 those projections, they didn&apos;t get their return because the traffic 
 did not come up.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So they put their money up and they took a risk, and 
 they risked wrong. And did that cost the State of Texas anything 
 when they went under?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Did the State of Texas have the opportunity to buy 
 that asset?

MR. SAENZ: We did and we have.

MR. WILLIAMSON: What was the original cost of that asset?

MR. SAENZ: Original cost of the asset, I think, based on the 
 financing, was close to $90 million.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And what did the State of Texas pay for that asset?

MR. SAENZ: We paid right at $20 million.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And what would it have cost the taxpayers of the 
 state to build that asset had that asset not been there?

MR. SAENZ: If it had been built just as a regular road of that type, 
 about between $35- and $40 million.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So the private sector took a risk, they guessed 
 wrong, they lost maybe $70- or $80 million, the state got the asset 
 at less than what the state would have paid to build the asset in 
 the first place, and the road is being used today.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: If these fellows from Spain, who appear to be 
 intelligent men, have guessed wrong, will the State of Texas have to 
 pay their liabilities?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Will we have the opportunity to purchase the asset?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, we will.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And do we have an agreement on how we would value 
 that, or would we just simply pay whatever in our judgment was what 
 we could afford to pay?

MR. SAENZ: The only one that we have that is for 130, 5 and 6, 
 because each agreement will have its own buy-back or default 
 clauses. For 5 and 6, should the company go bankrupt because the 
 traffic is not there, then we have no responsibility at all, we just 
 take it over. Very similar to Camino Colombia, it would go through 
 foreclosure and then we would have the opportunity to procure it.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Very good. And then the last question -- which I 
 know will relieve the audience greatly -- much has been said about 
 the taking of private property and we have spoken, we hope clearly, 
 from this position that we understand how painful that is, but that 
 we also understand that if you make a decision to expand your road 
 system, whether you expand the existing footprint or whether you 
 build parallel to the existing footprint, you&apos;re probably going to 
 be taking someone&apos;s property.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You&apos;re either tearing down the restaurant and the 
 service station and the church in downtown Waco, or you&apos;re taking 
 somebody&apos;s property on the outside edge of Waco. There&apos;s no way to 
 escape that.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: But in parallel to the criticism that the project 
 will take land unnecessarily, it is often said, and we will get not 
 benefit from that. I was attending a meeting in Rockwall County 
 about a month ago and a county commissioner, who I know and who I 
 believe to be an intelligent person, looked me straight in the eye 
 and said, Why would we want you to build this when you&apos;re not even 
 going to put an exit in Rockwall County? And I looked at this person 
 for a moment and I said, Whatever are you talking about? And she 
 said, Well, everyone knows the contract provides for no exits and 
 entrances.

And I looked at her for a full five seconds and I said, Now, does 
 that make sense to you, is that logical to you that someone would 
 build a road that they need to entice individuals and companies to 
 use in order to get their money back and then would not provide 
 exits and entrances to it, does that make sense? And this person 
 thought for a moment and said, Well, no, I don&apos;t guess it does.

I said, are you sure you&apos;re not confusing the definition of a 
 controlled access road which means no frontage roads and limited 
 entrance and exit with this idea you have in your head of no ramps? 
 And after a moment, this person had to admit that this person had 
 not given a lot of thought to this person&apos;s concern.

So my question to you is: Are there entrances and exits on this 
 road, if it&apos;s to be built?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And how will those entrances and exits be 
 determined, the location of those?

MR. SAENZ: Part of those have already been identified through 
 statute that says that we will connect all of the major highways, 
 State and U.S., but then through the engineering study, all the 
 other major roads, both on the system and some of the major ones 
 that are off system, based on traffic, we&apos;ll have to connect to them 
 and allow people to be able to get on and get off.

MR. WILLIAMSON: But there will be no frontage roads.

MR. SAENZ: There will be no frontage roads. There will be some local 
 access roads to allow people to get to their property where we 
 severed property.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And the reason that we take the position that we 
 should not build frontage roads on the corridors, not just 35 but 
 69, 20, all of them, is because the cost associated with that. Is 
 that correct?

MR. SAENZ: The cost associated with that, but also more important is 
 to be able to preserve that this is a through corridor and not 
 necessarily a local collector street corridor.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Because what we really want in building our 
 parallels is we want Interstate 35 to remain the local and regional 
 boulevard of choice for the taxpayers of the state, while the 
 corridor becomes the regional and national transportation corridor 
 of choice.

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have finished establishing the facts I wished to 
 establish for the record. I appreciate your patience, Amadeo.

MR. SAENZ: I do want to just cover a few more items, really because 
 they&apos;ve been in the news. Of course, this master development plan 
 took the original conceptual financial plan and the original 
 conceptual project management plan that were part of the proposal 
 requirements, and we have updated them and now we make them part of 
 this plan as we accepted this plan. And this morning we were able to 
 get Mr. Behrens to sign off and we have let Cintra-Zachry know that 
 the plan is accepted and now becomes property of the department. The 
 master development plan is a public document and will be released to 
 the public.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So he&apos;s signed it?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You&apos;re in agreement?

MR. BEHRENS: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Good. I&apos;m glad to get that out of the way.

MR. SAENZ: What this does is basically that plan becomes public 
 document and it should be available on our website, and whoever 
 wants it, I think can get it.

Now, in looking at this and in our conversations with Cintra-Zachry, 
 because these are updates to their conceptual plan that were part of 
 litigation that has been going on and is ongoing, since this plan is 
 an update of the original plan and now it is completed and 
 incorporated and accepted by TxDOT and a public document, then our 
 recommendation to Cintra, and they&apos;re also in agreement, is that the 
 matter of the lawsuit that we were pursuing due the proprietary 
 property and the intellectual property that was part of the original 
 proposal is really no longer needed, so we are moving forward with 
 the dropping of that lawsuit.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay. Well, obviously that&apos;s an administrative 
 decision, not a decision for the commission to make, and I don&apos;t 
 think we want to interfere with that, but I just want to be sure in 
 the process of doing this we&apos;re not frightening anyone away from 
 making proposals to us in the future.

MR. SAENZ: No, sir, because this basically follows the same process 
 on any contract. Once we have everything, nothing that is protected 
 or nothing that is proprietary, then the document becomes a public 
 document.

MR. WILLIAMSON: One more time the amount that Cintra originally 
 suggested they would spend in the state of Texas to build roads was?

MR. SAENZ: Was $6 billion for near-term projects from San Antonio to 
 north of the Metroplex.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And that&apos;s now how much?

MR. SAENZ: $8.8-.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And the original concession fee was how much?

MR. SAENZ: $1.2- and it&apos;s now $1.9-.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So it would be fair to say that we are soon to make 
 a $10 billion dent in our $86 billion problem.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Which one great young American walked up to me this 
 morning before the meeting and said, I said I woke up this morning 
 worrying about how to close the gap -- which is what I like to hear.

MR. HOUGHTON: Let&apos;s do some math here. It&apos;s a $6-, $7-, $8 billion 
 road project and you layer in on top the rail.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: So if you layer in on top the rail, you&apos;re looking at 
 another $6- to $7- billion worth of transportation assets being 
 built for the state of Texas.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir, because I don&apos;t have the rail in the original 
 numbers, true.

MR. HOUGHTON: And at the same time, I want to make sure of one 
 thing. Does Cintra-Zachry have a leg up on building any of these 
 assets?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir, because, of course, they have completed the 
 requirement of the plan, the plan is now ours. They&apos;re our partner, 
 our long-term partner for 50 years. They have the right to submit 
 projects from this plan that they say are ready for development, but 
 the final decision-maker whether we proceed with Cintra-Zachry or we 
 open it to an open procurement rests on you all.

MR. HOUGHTON: Open procurement would be something like we do today?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: We procure it based upon a blind bid.

MR. SAENZ: Procured based on a blind bid.

MR. HOUGHTON: Or what we&apos;ve done on 130, a design-build?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: We could do one or all or a multiple of those.

MR. SAENZ: We could pursue the project in whole different methods, 
 either design-bid-build which is our normal process, or a 130 
 design-build, or a separate individual concession.

MR. HOUGHTON: So at the end of the day you&apos;re looking at about $14- 
 to $15 billion worth of projects that somebody else is going to pay 
 for.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You know, I&apos;m glad you started asking that question 
 because that triggered something in my mind. I had a conversation 
 with a guy in Dallas -- I won&apos;t name the guy -- but he asked me 
 about the Loop 9 proposal that the Cintra people put in, and he 
 said, Well, isn&apos;t that just politics? And I said, Well, no, what do 
 you mean politics? And he said, Well, aren&apos;t you just doing that 
 because there&apos;s an election? And I kind of laughed and I said, You 
 know, I think these guys want to build stuff whether there&apos;s an 
 election or not. And he said, Well, I won&apos;t believe it till I see it 
 -- I think his exact words were: I&apos;ll believe it when I see the 
 contract. And if that fellow is watching, he knows who he is.

Is it not the case, Amadeo, that when they notify us under the plan 
 that an item is ready, that&apos;s the beginning of the process?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s the beginning of the process.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It&apos;s not a matter of we&apos;d like to go do this, it is 
 we are ready to put the money up to build this asset right now, give 
 us the environmental document, we&apos;re ready to go.

MR. HOUGHTON: And I wasn&apos;t being flippant when I discussed having a 
 facility implementation plan by December 31. That comes from our 
 partner that says we would like to get to the table to start 
 negotiating the terms of that Loop 9. So I&apos;m not saying we&apos;ll do it 
 by December 31, but I think we need to do it as soon as possible. 
 That came from our partner.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, I know that we have a great transportation in 
 southeast Dallas County, North Texas, Grady Smithy, and I know Grady 
 was just apoplectic because he knew that this was a real deal and no 
 one seemed to be paying much attention to it. And this conversation 
 I was having with this particular individual, I was not successful 
 in persuading him that this is how the process works: when the 
 developer says this is ready to go, it&apos;s them saying we&apos;ll do it and 
 no one else will and it won&apos;t cost you anything.

MR. HOUGHTON: Well, I think somebody needs to talk to Commissioner 
 John Wiley Price about handing the keys over and him believing and 
 endorsing the concept that he believes that this can get done.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Hasn&apos;t he been a wonderful partner to deal with, 
 John Wiley Price?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: Outstanding.

MR. WILLIAMSON: It&apos;s been an amazing thing to deal with that guy and 
 see his commitment to southeast Dallas and improving that part of 
 the county.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Anything else? This requires no action of us, this 
 is an administrative matter?

MR. SAENZ: No, sir. This was a report and just for your information 
 to let you know where we&apos;re at in the project.

MR. WILLIAMSON: For the commission, I want to express to Mike, who 
 has made many trips up and down 35, to yourself, to Steve Simmons, 
 who has caught some of this, to Coby -- who else has caught a lot of 
 this grief?

MR. BEHRENS: Phil.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Phil Russell.

MR. SAENZ: Of course, all our district folks.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Everybody in the districts and in the public hearing 
 process, for the commission, we deeply appreciate the patience -- 
 and I&apos;ll use the same word I used with Phyllis a while ago -- the 
 grace and dignity with which we&apos;ve all handled at times some pretty 
 rough treatment over something that we&apos;ve all been rather confused 
 about because this contract has been handled no differently than any 
 other contract, nor will the next one be handled any different than 
 any other contract. You&apos;ve done well in a difficult situation.

I also want to publicly thank Mr. Cintra and Mr. Zachry for 
 suffering the indignities you have suffered during this process as 
 well. You can&apos;t build those assets fast enough for us, if you are 
 out there in the audience.

MR. HOUGHTON: So we&apos;ve determined today there&apos;s no black helicopters 
 running up and down 35?

MR. WILLIAMSON: I was going to have a line of questions about that, 
 but I&apos;m afraid it would just trigger more confusion than it&apos;s worth. 
 The only black helicopter is the one Behrens uses to fly around to 
 the public hearings, owned by the State Aircraft Pooling Board, the 
 subject of a recent audit.

MR. SAENZ: I thank you, for all our folks. We have a lot of great 
 people that are working on this project, that spent countless hours 
 with great dedication, and we appreciate your comments, and I will 
 pass that on to them.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We&apos;re going to take a break and let everybody kind 
 of catch up with their personal business. We&apos;ll be back in 17 
 minutes.

(Whereupon, a brief recess was taken.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: We&apos;ll return from our break and we thank you for 
 your patience. Mike, do we have some friends from the southern 
 entrance to our state that wish to speak?

MR. BEHRENS: Yes, we do. I would suggest that we take agenda item 
 number 6 under Transportation Planning, and that will address 
 several items which will include items that pertain to Hays and 
 Travis County, and also to Cameron County.

So Wayne, if you will go ahead and take your items under agenda item 
 number 6, starting with 6(a) which is our district discretionary 
 programming authority.

MR. DENNIS: Good morning, Mr. Chairman, commission members, Mr. 
 Behrens. For the record, my name is Wayne Dennis. I&apos;m the deputy 
 director of the Transportation Planning and Programming Division.

The minute order that we&apos;re bringing before you today provides 
 additional district discretionary programming authority for project 
 development, as shown in the attached Exhibit A. Minute Order 
 105320, dated April 27, 1995, established district discretionary 
 programming authority for project development. District 
 discretionary programming authority gives the districts the 
 flexibility to prepare plans and purchase right of way for projects 
 with high local interest.

Subsequently, Minute Order 106304, dated October 26, 1995, and 
 Minute Order 108177, dated April 27, 2000, increased this 
 programming authority to help the department achieve its projected 
 letting goals. As construction costs have continued to increase 
 statewide, so has the need for increased DEVELOP authority.

With your approval, this minute order would provide additional 
 DEVELOP authority for each district for project development. The 
 program will be distributed to the districts based on the allocation 
 formula for Category 11, District Discretionary Program of the 2006 
 Statewide Mobility Program. Statewide, this would increase the 
 programming authority from $3.3 billion to $4.75 billion.

Projects will be identified and programmed for the entire 
 construction cost estimate within this program, however, no project 
 will be funded for construction until authorized funds are 
 identified from one of the department&apos;s categories.

Staff recommends approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation on item 6(a). Do you have questions or comments?

MR. JOHNSON: Wayne, the formula that was used in the calculations to 
 determine the allocation for each of the districts, has that formula 
 been one that we&apos;ve used historically for this?

MR. DENNIS: Yes, it is, and it&apos;s 70 percent vehicle miles traveled 
 and 30 percent registered vehicles.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Ted or Hope, anything?

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have just one and that&apos;s more in the nature of a 
 comment and a compliment to you, Michael Behrens. This agency has 
 evolved, the focus of this agency has evolved a lot in the last six 
 years, and I want to tell you how much I appreciate you and the 
 staff constantly escalating your focus on an entire corridor, on 
 planning ahead, on working with local and regional governments, in 
 development complete solutions as opposed to just figuring out which 
 projects can be laid down within the cash flow. This is exactly what 
 the state needs to solve its problem by 2030, and this is a good 
 move, this is a great move, shows good staff thinking, I think.

What&apos;s your pleasure, members?

MR. JOHNSON: So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MR. DENNIS: Item 6(b). This minute order tenders a proposal to 
 Brazoria County to authorize the purchase of right of way and 
 utility adjustments for a project on State Highway 36 from the Fort 
 Bend County line to FM 1495, a distance of approximately 31.35 
 miles.

State Highway 36 is a hurricane evacuation route and serves as a 
 major transportation corridor in Brazoria, Fort Bend, and Austin 
 counties. Improving this corridor is essential and will facilitate 
 traffic flow in these counties during an evacuation.

If this minute order is approved, the county will acquire 100 
 percent of the necessary right of way and utility adjustments once 
 the project receives environmental clearance. The department will 
 obtain environmental clearance and work with the county in 
 developing the project. Staff hereby recommends approval of this 
 minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation on item 6(b).

MR. HOUGHTON: Is this the contribution by Brazoria County on the 
 pass-through that they&apos;re proposing, Amadeo? Right? Okay. So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: This is a hurricane evacuation route. Correct?

MR. DENNIS: Yes, sir.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MR. DENNIS: Item 6(c). This minute order amends Category 6 
 Structures Replacement and Rehabilitation Program of the 2007 
 Statewide Preservation Program. With your approval, three off-system 
 bridges will be authorized CONSTRUCT authority in the Austin, San 
 Antonio, Childress and Paris districts.

The first bridge is located on County Road 240, also known as Sculls 
 Crossing, over the San Marcos River between Caldwell and Guadalupe 
 counties. This structure is on a direct route to the closest 
 emergency facility, the Central Texas Medical Center, located in 
 southern Hays County. It is a one-lane, wooden structure that is 
 load posted and frequently floods. This bridge is functionally 
 obsolete. The State Office of Rural and Community Affairs awarded a 
 grant to the reconstruction of three bridges in Caldwell County. 
 There&apos;s approximately $100,000 remaining in the grant and it is 
 being reserved for this bridge. If project development is not 
 underway by the end of the year, the grant money will no longer be 
 available.

The second bridge is located in the Childress District in Hollis 
 Road over the Red River, and it spans between Hardeman County in 
 Texas and Harmon County in Oklahoma. The bridge is structurally 
 deficient but was not included in the 2007 Statewide Preservation 
 Program due to the issues related to the bridge&apos;s ownership. The 
 ownership problem has been resolved and Hardeman County owns their 
 half of the bridge in Texas. Each state will be responsible for 50 
 percent of the project cost.

The third bridge is located in the Paris District and is on County 
 Road 1410 over the Little Mustang Creek Relief in Red River County. 
 The most recent inspection in June of this year determined the 
 structure was unstable and it required it to be closed. Since the 
 inspection, a large scour hole has developed and water levels have 
 fallen, exposing an additional three feet of abutment support.

Approving this minute order will facilitate project development 
 before the next update of the Statewide Preservation Program. Staff 
 recommends approval of the bridge projects listed in the attached 
 Exhibit A for an estimated construction cost of $5,050,000.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation.

MR. JOHNSON: So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MR. DENNIS: Item 6(d). This minute order authorizes the department 
 to provide $1,838,000 to the National Railroad Passenger 
 Corporation, also known as Amtrak, to fund the Heartland Flyer 
 Passenger Rail Service. The Heartland Flyer is a state-supported 
 route and provides daily passenger rail service between Fort Worth 
 and Oklahoma City, with an additional Texas stop in Gainesville. The 
 Heartland Flyer travels over the BNSF Railway line.

Since the Heartland Flyer route is not part of the Amtrak system 
 originally designated in 1971, the State of Oklahoma funded this 
 service through a contract with Amtrak to cover operating losses. 
 Oklahoma has covered these losses since service was established in 
 1999. Due to budget limitations in Oklahoma, the DOT can only 
 provide $2,138,000 of Amtrak&apos;s projected total loss of $3,976,000 
 for fiscal year 2006. This leaves a funding shortfall of $1,838,000.

In order to continue this service, it is necessary for Texas to 
 provide $1,838,000 to offset the operating losses on the Heartland 
 Flyer. Staff recommends your approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation on item 6(d).

MR. JOHNSON: I have a question. Wayne, is this a common occurrence 
 where states or departments of transportation or local jurisdictions 
 might subsidize Amtrak rail service?

MR. DENNIS: Yes, it is in some states. There&apos;s Amtrak&apos;s base system, 
 again, that was established back in&apos;71; there were several other 
 later coming state-supported routes that are funded by the federal 
 government, but there are also some routes that are funded by the 
 states. In other words, the states came to Amtrak desiring this 
 service. In this case, Oklahoma has been doing a lot of rail 
 development on the Oklahoma side to improve track operations, and 
 they just have a budget shortfall.

I guess the other issue is, a concern that we have is once you tend 
 to lose these passenger routes, you&apos;re going to have difficulty 
 re-establishing them. The freight companies will come in and they&apos;ll 
 use those time slots to move more freight. They can be 
 re-established and Amtrak has that legislative authority, but it&apos;s 
 very difficult once you lose that slot.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And what time element, how long are we guaranteed 
 that this passenger route will remain open by our taking this 
 action?

MR. DENNIS: This will take care of federal fiscal year 2007 which 
 starts October 1.

MR. JOHNSON: And ends?

MR. DENNIS: September 30.

MR. JOHNSON: September 30 of&apos;07?

MR. DENNIS: Yes, sir.

We&apos;ve done some analysis on this roadway, and what we&apos;ve seen due to 
 the ridership that is there, we estimate that there is a retail tax 
 impact of about $2.2 million to the State of Texas. Also, based on 
 the ridership that they have, you&apos;re going to be taking about 50,000 
 per year cars off the road between here and Oklahoma City.

MR. JOHNSON: That&apos;s a good point. So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: All those in favor of the motion will signify by 
 saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MR. DENNIS: Item 6(e). This minute order tenders a proposal to the 
 City of Buda in Hays County to construct a new location facility on 
 the state highway system from I-35 at Main Street to State Highway 
 45 southeast. It realigns FM 2001 and it constructs interchanges at 
 I-35 and FM 2001, and at I-35 and Main Street.

Minute Order 110508, dated April 27, 2006, tendered this same 
 proposal to the city and the county, however, due to a series of 
 complex transactions required for the project, the city informed us 
 that they would not be able to meet the original July 27 acceptance 
 deadline that was established in that minute order. This minute 
 order proposes the same provisions as the previous minute order and 
 gives the city and county 90 days to fulfill the agreement 
 requirements.

Both the city and the county continue to have a considerable 
 interest in development of these projects as the area is becoming 
 increasingly urbanized and is experiencing rapid development. The 
 proposed projects will provide for north-south mobility by enhancing 
 utilization of State Highway 45 and State Highway 130 toll roads. In 
 addition, the projects will provide improved access to area 
 developments and facilitate incident management along Interstate 35.

The estimated cost to the department is $22.4 million and the cost 
 to the city and county are $23.2 million. If agreed to by the city 
 and county, the local governments will submit a SIB loan to the 
 department, not to exceed $15 million, for the construction of the 
 Main Street extension project.

Staff recommends approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s recommendation and 
 explanation on item 6(e).

MR. HOUGHTON: This is a timing issue then, Wayne. Right?

MR. DENNIS: Yes, sir. When we originally submitted it, it was pretty 
 complicated and they came back and asked for some more time.

MR. HOUGHTON: Just need a little bit more time.

MR. DENNIS: And there&apos;s really no way to extend a tender minute 
 order without bringing it back to you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And we do have a witness, the mayor of Buda. Would 
 you like to hear from the witness first?

John -- that&apos;s easy to pronounce. I&apos;m sorry. I know you&apos;ve been here 
 before and I was sitting here trying to remember how to pronounce 
 your name, and I apologize.

MAYOR TRUBE: No problem. Thank you, Chairman, commissioners, staff. 
 Appreciate the opportunity.

We would, first off, like to apologize. It is a complicated minute 
 order, it took a little more time than we had anticipated to work 
 out the moving parts in terms of financing this particular project, 
 as well as working with the county and the other parties involved. 
 But at this time we&apos;re glad to say that we have gotten the minute 
 order passed at the county level, the city level, we have our 
 financial agreements all written in place and placed through a 
 variety, an agreement and a SIB loan as well.

So at this time we would like to, A, really make sure and express 
 our appreciation and our enthusiasm for doing another partnership 
 with TxDOT. Mr. Behrens and Bob Daigh, our district engineer, have 
 been very, very good partners to us, very productive for the Hays 
 County, particularly northern Hays County transportation needs. We 
 are here standing by for anything that we can do for you as well. 
 Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Questions or dialogue with the mayor?

MR. JOHNSON: Appreciate your being here.

MR. HOUGHTON: And his service on CAMPO. I understand he&apos;s got that 
 tour of duty also.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, I wasn&apos;t sure about this, so I went down to 
 northern Hays County last night and drove all around just to make 
 sure that it&apos;s still a congestive nightmare, and I can tell you, 
 Mayor, that we&apos;re probably not doing enough to help you fix your 
 problems.

MAYOR TRUBE: We have experienced a lot of congestion and growth in 
 our area, all the way down to San Marcos. But I&apos;m glad to say, in my 
 opinion and I think in the opinion of at least my city council and 
 the county, TxDOT has stepped up, and again, with the team we&apos;ve got 
 and the leaders we&apos;ve got in the area, the district engineer, Mr. 
 Behrens and this board, we&apos;re not feeling left out, we&apos;re feeling 
 like we have the attention that we need and we&apos;re accomplishing our 
 goals and hopefully accomplishing some of your goals as well.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I was amazed at the houses, the businesses, it&apos;s 
 incredible.

Members, What&apos;s your pleasure?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MAYOR TRUBE: Thank you very much.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, Mayor.

MR. BEHRENS: Amadeo is going to present item 6(f) concerning the 
 Brownsville West Rail Relocation Project in Cameron County.

MR. SAENZ: Thank you, Mr. Behrens. Again for the record, 
 commissioners, Amadeo Saenz, assistant executive director for 
 engineering.

Item 6(f). The minute order before you tenders a proposal to Cameron 
 County for a project to construct the Brownsville West Rail 
 Relocation Project.

Minute Order Number 110479, dated March 30, 2006, authorized three 
 grade separation projects on US 281, FM 802 and FM 3248 in Category 
 6, Structure Replacement and Rehabilitation under the railroad grade 
 separation replacements of the 2007 Statewide Preservation Program.

Title 23, USC Section 130 states that railroad relocation costs may 
 be reimbursable expenses when the relocation of a portion of a 
 railroad eliminates the hazards of railroad highway crossings and 
 therefore, the need for the grade crossing or the grade separation 
 and the cost of the relocation is less than what the grade crossing 
 would have cost.

The county has considerable interest in developing the Brownsville 
 West Rail Relocation Project. The project will improve the 
 transportation network of the area through the proposed rail system 
 improvements and thereby improve the safety and traffic flow of the 
 three named highways. By relocating the rail, the existing rail line 
 will no longer be needed, will be abandoned for another 
 transportation corridor, thus, the grade separations will no longer 
 be needed.

If approved, the minute order will then be tendered to Cameron 
 County that within the next three years they would have to obtain 
 all the necessary agreements with the railroad that states that they 
 will relocate to the new rail line proposed location; they will 
 obtain from the railroad company, in the State&apos;s name, the 
 railroad&apos;s property interest along the current location of the line 
 from which the service is being relocated; they will notify the 
 department that the international bridge and the connecting 
 facilities of the rail line in Mexico is under construction.

In turn, the department will amend the Unified Transportation 
 Program to authorize no more than $13 million from eliminating the 
 grade separations and apply them to this project, and then we will 
 also cancel development and construction of the railroad grade 
 separation projects on 281, 802, and FM 3248 along the existing rail 
 alignment.

Staff recommends approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, to refresh your memory, this minute order 
 was before us either last month or the month before.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And we had collectively some concerns about the 
 committing resources for an indefinite period of time when we 
 weren&apos;t sure of the commitment from the Republic of Mexico. I think 
 that Amadeo has visited with local officials, I know the governor 
 has, I think my good friend Rene Oliveira has done some visiting as 
 well, and I believe they&apos;re ready to represent to us that we can 
 make this thing work.

We do have two witnesses, the county judge of Cameron County, 
 Gilberto Hinojosa, and David Allex with the Cameron County RMA. Do 
 you want to hear the witnesses first, do you want to deal with the 
 letters first?

MR. HOUGHTON: I was going to ask Amadeo the total cost of the 
 project, Amadeo, on the relocation. We&apos;re going to put $13 million 
 at the maximum.

MR. SAENZ: We&apos;re putting $13 million. I believe the total cost of 
 the project, including half of the international bridge -- and I&apos;m 
 going to look back and ask the Cameron County folks to help me a 
 little bit -- about $25- to $26 million is the cost of the project 
 to build half of the international bridge plus the rail line to 
 connect to the existing line that&apos;s in Brownsville.

MR. HOUGHTON: And we&apos;re re-allocating $13 million to that project.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir, we are re-allocating $13 million of railroad 
 grade separation dollars that will no longer be needed and applying 
 them to this project. And the $13 million was what we had allocated 
 for those railroad grade separations.

MR. HOUGHTON: Right. And as a result, the Union Pacific, I believe, 
 will then exit that facility and the facility will be in the name, 
 the title in the name of the State. Is that correct?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. The right of way under which the roads and the 
 railroad cross will be transferred over to the name of the State.

MR. HOUGHTON: What about the rail bed?

MR. SAENZ: The existing rail bed?

MR. HOUGHTON: Right of way.

MR. SAENZ: The existing rail bed is going to be used and developed 
 under a transportation project that the district and Cameron County 
 and the City of Brownsville are working to develop that they call 
 the West Loop project.

MR. HOUGHTON: And where do we derive the authority, or under what 
 legislation do we derive that authority to do this?

MR. SAENZ: The elimination of the rail crossings -- let me get back 
 to my notes -- of course, we&apos;re eliminating the railroad crossings 
 which is what we were doing with the grade separation project, and 
 by relocating the line, that will also eliminate the rail crossings, 
 so it accomplishes the same thing.

MR. HOUGHTON: And they will build a transportation facility inside 
 the old rail bed?

MR. SAENZ: Yes.

MR. HOUGHTON: Is that the RMA project?

MR. SAENZ: That&apos;s one of the projects, that was the project that was 
 submitted by the RMA, the West Loop project.

MR. HOUGHTON: Under what legislation was that derived, RMAs?

MR. SAENZ: RMAs were so many numbers: 3588, 2702.

MR. HOUGHTON: Which one of the visions of Governor Rick Perry. 
 Correct?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: Okay. Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Other questions or comments, members?

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Let&apos;s hear from the witnesses and then we&apos;ll read 
 some letters into the record.

Judge, I&apos;m going to let you decide who goes first.

JUDGE HINOJOSA: I&apos;ll go first. Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman and 
 members of the commission.

This railroad relocation project, I believe, is probably the first 
 in the state of Texas, and it&apos;s consistent with what Governor Perry 
 has proposed to the legislature and that the voters voted recently 
 to work on a statewide program for railroad relocation projects. 
 It&apos;s only about a four- to five-year project, it will move all rail 
 lines in Brownsville to the west about six miles, moves an 
 international bridge to the west as well. The minute order talks 
 about three at-grade crossings that will be eliminated. In reality, 
 when it&apos;s all said and done, it will eliminate a total of seven 
 at-grade crossings that were in the future scheduled for 
 construction.

At 1998 costs, the total cost for the seven at-grade crossings were 
 $48 million, so it&apos;s significantly more today. You were talking 
 about closing that gap just a little while ago. If you calculate at 
 1998 costs, the savings to the State of Texas by the accomplishment 
 of this project, it&apos;s something like $27 million, probably a lot 
 more today. We already have the $13 million in place that you are 
 matching, essentially.

We believe that this project will fast-track, given what this 
 commission has done today, and we will be able to get a diplomatic 
 note to begin construction on the bridge relatively quickly and have 
 this project well on its way when the next legislative session gets 
 underway. So that you can use it as a model to begin working on 
 projects all across the state of Texas and greatly enhance the 
 safety and the railroad traffic&apos;s ability to move products in and 
 out of different communities without creating the congestion that 
 some of these rail lines have created and the dangers that are 
 associated with hazardous materials, flammable materials that could 
 create significant problems in congested communities.

So thank you very much for your help on this project, and I think 
 the vision of this commission and the governor to move forward on 
 this project is to be commended.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, questions or comments for the judge?

MR. JOHNSON: I&apos;ve got a question.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Please.

MR. JOHNSON: Judge, you mentioned some of the benefits, and clearly 
 there are several benefits that the community is going to benefit 
 from. When we visited in April, we came and had our commission 
 meeting there in Brownsville, we spent time at the port and came to 
 recognize what a great resource the port is for your community and 
 the region. How does this rail relocation affect the port and the 
 multimodal aspects that the port has? Is there any effect, and what 
 are sort of the future plans that relate to surface transportation, 
 be it rail, vessel?

JUDGE HINOJOSA: There&apos;s been a lot of discussion on that issue with 
 the port in recent years. The port, you probably have read in the 
 news, spent about $21 million trying to develop an international 
 bridge at the Port of Brownsville crossing into Mexico. That was not 
 successful. I think the clear indication from Mexico is that they&apos;re 
 not interested in a rail bridge at that particular point because of 
 the problem that it would cause in going all the way around 
 Matamoros. And so the Port of Brownsville really is in need of an 
 alternative method by which it can move the rail that is moving 
 products from the Port of Brownsville into Mexico and back.

And this will allow them, I believe, a much better transportation 
 corridor for their rail traffic because it takes all the rail out of 
 Brownsville, it gives them the ability to put together longer trains 
 that will move faster without any danger that there might be any 
 collisions with automobiles, and it will, I believe, enhance their 
 ability to do business.

You know, we think this is a win-win thing for Brownsville, Cameron 
 County, Mexico, the Union Pacific, obviously, because they get a new 
 rail and a bridge, and the Port of Brownsville.

MR. JOHNSON: Can the customers of the port be cost-competitive by 
 utilizing this freight rail? I mean, it occurs to me that that&apos;s 
 sort of out of their control which is going to possibly affect the 
 competing ways of moving freight.

JUDGE HINOJOSA: Well, one of the things that is going to happen with 
 the bridge that is going to be constructed, you remember that the 
 bridge that is already there today is 100 years old, and that bridge 
 can only handle certain types of cargo, of railroad cars. The large 
 container vehicles cannot cross through that bridge, so the port is 
 very limited in being able to bring container cargo that would be 
 transported on rail because it can&apos;t cross it under the current rail 
 system that they&apos;ve got today.

MR. JOHNSON: And the port is outfitted for containerized cargo?

JUDGE HINOJOSA: Well, they&apos;re working in that direction. They&apos;ve got 
 proposals before Congress to allow them to deepen the port and build 
 a turn basin that will allow them to bring in large containers, and 
 this works perfectly into their future plans. The new international 
 bridge that will be built will be able to handle the container cars 
 that they&apos;re hoping to bring into the Port of Brownsville. So it 
 actually enhances their attractiveness as a port internationally.

MR. JOHNSON: Thank you.

JUDGE HINOJOSA: I forgot to mention, also we have with us today our 
 commissioner from Precinct 2 which is in the area, Commissioner John 
 Wood; and you mentioned David Allex, the chairman of the regional 
 mobility authority -- in my opinion, the best in the state of Texas; 
 Richard Ridings from HNTB, the engineers that have put this project 
 together in record time -- we got our presidential permit with their 
 efforts, and they&apos;re in the final stages, if they haven&apos;t already 
 completed the engineering plans for that project; Pete Sepulveda, 
 Department of Transportation director; David Garcia, his assistant; 
 Charlie Cabler who is the city manager for our partner, the City of 
 Brownsville; and our city commissioner, Commissioner Carlos 
 Cisneros.

Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, Judge. We appreciate you being here.

David?

MR. ALLEX: Thank you. For the record, I&apos;m David Allex, chairman of 
 the Cameron County Regional Mobility Authority, serving at the 
 pleasure of Governor Perry.

I want to express my deep appreciation on this item on your agenda 
 to the governor of the State of Texas, who has intervened on our 
 behalf to some degree, but most importantly, to each one of you, 
 individually and collectively, for your support for the Cameron 
 County Regional Mobility Authority and what we&apos;ve tried to achieve 
 over the last two years.

I want to digress for just a moment, but the vision of the 
 Trans-Texas Corridor, the crystallization of projects in Cameron 
 County were so far off you could hardly see them. We can almost 
 start to touch them now. And this is one of the things I think that 
 the vision of the governor and what you have implemented over the 
 last couple of years, because of RMAs is something that will create 
 hundreds, if not thousands, of jobs in areas like Cameron and 
 Hidalgo counties along the border.

Let&apos;s not forget -- and I keep harping on this every time I get 
 before you all -- that the engine that fuels our economy in South 
 Texas and in Cameron and Hidalgo counties is indeed Mexico. I work 
 Mexico three days a week, and if you eliminate 23 intersections that 
 the rail is going to go through Matamoros and through the city of 
 Brownsville, and you save an hour or hour and a half time on rail, 
 that&apos;s the money we&apos;re going to save, commissioners.

You know, you talk about what&apos;s the value of having a new rail. 
 Well, you eliminate all that traffic going through Matamoros and 
 Brownsville and you save time for freight going through there. So 
 this is one of, I think, most important projects as far as economic 
 impact to our area.

Pete Sepulveda and I met with some individual businessmen in Mexico 
 just a couple of weeks ago. They&apos;re building an intermodal freight 
 terminal that will have cargo and freight on the Mexican side of 
 where this bridge is going to be, this new rail bridge. We estimate 
 there will be hundreds, maybe as many as a thousand jobs over the 
 next five or six years on recent development of industrial parks on 
 the Mexican side. In fact, we know of two industrial parks on the 
 west side of Matamoros that are under development as we speak.

Those jobs will translate into retail sales for Brownsville and for 
 Cameron County; those jobs will provide for warehousing and 
 distribution facilities in Cameron County; those jobs that are 
 created -- 3,700 is projected right now -- in those new industrial 
 parks and at the container and trucking terminal on the Mexican, 
 will be the economic generator that will have economic impact on 
 Cameron County. And your RMA is going to do it and we&apos;re going to do 
 it with your leadership, and thanks a lot for that.

The second thing, there&apos;s been a lot of talk about -- and we&apos;ve done 
 some projections on this -- the Cameron County Regional Mobility 
 Authority, if you include everything that we&apos;re going to do in the 
 next ten years, it&apos;s going to be in excess of about a billion 
 dollars, that&apos;s a lot of money. But when you consider that that&apos;s a 
 billion dollars worth of construction and over a ten-year period -- 
 and I&apos;m the eternal optimist and I&apos;m probably a little bit liberal 
 in my projection of population growth -- in the next ten years to 15 
 years we&apos;ll have 10 million people in South Texas and northern 
 Mexico, as we know it today with only 4 million.

And I&apos;ve said this to Commissioner Hope a million times, the only 
 thing that divides this area is a street with water in it. Our 
 cultures, our education, our families, what we do as everyday 
 activity is no different than walking across the street and buying a 
 hamburger in that place next door. That street with water in it is 
 no barrier at all, and you know that as well as I do in the El Paso 
 area. So anything we can do on either side of that street with water 
 in it is going to have an economic impact on both areas.

If we&apos;re going to do a billion dollars worth of construction work 
 over the next ten years, that will be 20,000 in construction jobs 
 over the ten-year period, not all at one time, but 20,000 
 construction jobs over the next ten years. If we&apos;re successful in 
 doing that in the next ten to 20 years, ten to 15 to 20 years, it 
 will create another 20- to 40,000 permanent jobs, hot dog stands, 
 hotels, restaurants on South Padre Island, on the mainland, all over 
 the place. So you&apos;re looking at some real significant economic 
 impacts that the RMA and the leadership of Cameron County, with the 
 leadership of the state government can do to create jobs in an area 
 that needs the jobs.

So I can preach this all day long because I live it every day; 
 that&apos;s my job is to create jobs in Mexico and Cameron County. So I 
 just wanted to bring that up to you.

The 19,000 you have working in the Texas Department of 
 Transportation, this is one of the most valuable assets you have. 
 And Mr. Chairman, when you start talking about how great they are, 
 they&apos;ve spent 15 years working for you, Commissioner Johnson, these 
 are the most important assets that this department has. And I can&apos;t 
 say enough about your regional engineers, Amadeo, Mike, and 
 everybody else who has helped us at the Cameron County RMA to make a 
 success. We would not be here today if it wasn&apos;t for them, and I 
 sincerely appreciate their time and their effort and yours too. 
 Thank you very much.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Questions or comments for David?

We do appreciate so much the work you do with your RMA, in addition 
 to the work you do in your community and your business.

MS. ANDRADE: David, I just want to echo that. Your commitment, your 
 leadership has just been incredible out there. Thank you for 
 everything that you do. To Commissioner Wood, thank you, and the 
 judge and Pete, it&apos;s been a pleasure to work out there with you. And 
 I just love the fact that you&apos;re creating jobs and improving safety 
 for your citizens. You&apos;re doing a great job, so we&apos;re very happy to 
 be part of it.

MR. ALLEX: That&apos;s what it&apos;s all about, and I&apos;m honored to be part of 
 it myself.

MS. ANDRADE: Working together.

MR. HOUGHTON: And David, I appreciate you allowing Pete to come out 
 to El Paso a week or so ago for our RMA educational conference. We 
 had both your and the NET RMA, and I hold you all up as the poster 
 child of RMAs in the state of Texas. You got out there, got out 
 there quick, and took it by the horns, and I appreciate very, very 
 much what you&apos;re doing for the State of Texas.

MR. ALLEX: Thank you, commissioners.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, David.

Members, I also want to make you aware we have received some letters 
 from people that are significant to our daily lives. Without reading 
 all of them, Rene Oliveira, who is a House member from the area, a 
 close friend of mine, wrote saying: Today we&apos;ll consider the minute 
 order; there&apos;s a sizable funding gap; the final phase of the 
 international bridge will enhance safety in our area; thank you for 
 your consideration.

Senator John Cornyn wrote: As we move forward with the planning of 
 the West Rail Relocation Project, he wants to reiterate his strong 
 support for the project, and the impact of the international bridge 
 component. We&apos;ll put his letter into the record.

The chairman of the House Transportation Committee, a great friend 
 of this body, Mike Krusee, wrote and spoke about goals -- things we 
 like to talk about around here -- the impact on Brownsville as well 
 as Matamoros, and the impact on safety. He was very eloquent in his 
 letter. That will be part of the record.

And then finally, our boss, Mr. Perry wrote. After talking with some 
 people down in the area, he considered it to be of highest 
 importance and directs us to please proceed. That letter also will 
 be part of the record.

Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation, the witnesses&apos;testimony, you&apos;re aware of the letters. What&apos;s your pleasure?

MS. ANDRADE: So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no. Motion carries. Thank you.

Thank you for your patience and thanks for coming halfway up the 
 state again. One day we&apos;re going to just move the transportation 
 department down to the southern entrance to the state and then 
 everybody will have to come south and spend some money to talk about 
 transportation.

Good to see each one of you. Thank you very much.

MR. SAENZ: Mr. Chairman, we also received letters from the State of 
 Tamaulipas, where they&apos;re endorsing the project, as well as the City 
 of Matamoros.

MR. WILLIAMSON: That&apos;s good.

MR. SAENZ: I&apos;ll also pass them along to Roger to put in the record.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We&apos;ll put them in the record also.

MR. SAENZ: Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, Amadeo.

Mike, do you want to return to the agenda, or do we need to do any 
 more skipping around?

MR. BEHRENS: No. I think we can go back to our regular ordered 
 agenda, and we go back to agenda item number 3. We&apos;ll have Coby come 
 up and continue his discussion and talk about recommendations that 
 the commission might consider for our next legislative session. Coby?

MR. CHASE: Good morning. For the record, my name is Coby Chase and 
 I&apos;m the director of TxDOT&apos;s Government and Business Enterprises 
 Division. Today I will further discuss the formulation of your 
 legislative agenda for the 80th Session of the Texas legislature.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And you wish to announce that you wore that tie in 
 honor of Michael Behrens. Right?

MR. CHASE: As long as I have at least one Longhorn up there, it&apos;s 
 not to career limiting to wear this tie. It&apos;s also kind of autumnal, 
 it is the beginning of fall.

MR. HOUGHTON: Looks like a University of Tennessee tie to me.

MR. CHASE: Well, okay then. Anybody else want to weigh in on what I 
 wore today? I&apos;ll start clearing the fashion choices before I appear.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, John had a comment on a tie, I&apos;m sure Hope and 
 Ted are going to have a comment later on today, I wanted to get mine 
 in.

MR. CHASE: Thank you. I do appreciate that, Horn to Horn.

(General laughter.)

MR. CHASE: As mentioned in past meetings, statutory changes that 
 would improve the operation of the department, recommended to the 
 Texas Legislature by the Transportation Commission, are authorized 
 by law. The purpose of this ongoing dialogue is to make these issues 
 public.

Since January you have listened each month as I&apos;ve described our 
 in-depth development of the legislative agenda. Throughout this 
 process, my staff and I have reviewed and researched several issues, 
 all the while keeping in mind how these issues assist the department 
 in reaching the goals outlined in our strategic plan. Not only are 
 we correlating these issues and their relevancy to reducing 
 congestion, enhancing safety, expanding economic opportunity, 
 improving air quality, and increasing the value of our 
 transportation assets, we are also looking for opportunities to 
 incorporate strategies to meet these results-driven goals. We also 
 try our best to make choices that do not limit options in the 
 state&apos;s mobility future.

We began this process by soliciting input from you, TxDOT staff, and 
 members of the legislature through interim hearings and through 
 conversations. As I mentioned last month, we decided to take this 
 process further by sending letters to over 1,900 interested parties, 
 detailing the issues we are considering for inclusion in your 
 legislative recommendations. While the response has not been 
 overwhelming -- but from a marketing standpoint, it would have been 
 a success -- we heard back from a little over 3 percent of the 
 recipients.

Of that 3 percent, about one-third actually did comment on the list 
 of issues, and the others pretty much just wanted their addresses 
 updated which is actually very valuable information to us, it 
 actually served another purpose.

We sent out this information hoping not only to reinforce our 
 message to the state but also to get a pulse of what is going on in 
 Texas. We have heard from a good cross-section of recipients, 
 including groups like the Houston-Galveston Area Council and smaller 
 municipalities such as Nacogdoches.

Last month I detailed some of the major issues being considered for 
 the agenda. This month I would like to focus on the issues that seem 
 to have created the most direct reactions from the responses we&apos;ve 
 received from our mail-out.

Several municipalities have expressed their concern over the outdoor 
 advertising relocation issue. As you may recall, sometimes the 
 removal of a billboard is required when improving a highway. When 
 this happens, the department and the owner often compromise on a 
 relocation of the billboard, however, many cities have ordinances 
 limiting the placement of new billboards, thereby requiring the 
 purchase of it at a cost to taxpayers or to the highway system, as 
 the case may be.

This is an expensive endeavor and it would be helpful to see a 
 variance in city ordinances allowing for these relocations, or 
 cities could opt to purchase the billboard to be removed if they 
 would prefer to enforce their own ordinance. All this would not 
 result in a net increase in the number of billboards in a given 
 area. Many cities view this as an expensive solution to a problem 
 they currently do not have to deal with, meaning it&apos;s pushed back on 
 the state to deal with and to pay for.

We have received very positive feedback on several issues. It is 
 widely agreed that fees collected from oversize/overweight trucks 
 should be deposited into the Texas Mobility Fund as opposed to the 
 current process of depositing these fees into general revenue. One 
 can certainly argue that these fees are directly related to 
 transportation and we&apos;d also like to investigate re-evaluating and 
 raising these fees.

We&apos;ve also seen consistent support for the early acquisition of 
 right of way. As opposed to waiting for the environmental work to be 
 completed before acquiring right of way, it would assist the 
 department greatly to be able to acquire property sooner if the 
 owner is willing to do so, again, only in a willing situation, not 
 to condemnation.

Several of the respondents also agreed with the prospect of local 
 transportation planning authority. Allowing counties the ability to 
 designate property as part of a future transportation corridor would 
 most certainly save the department and taxpayers funds which could 
 be utilized in other areas.

As a matter of fact, I was in Lufkin with Phil Russell and Denise 
 Pittard a couple of Fridays ago, talking to the I-69 Alliance there, 
 and one, I understand, fairly new county commissioner of one of the 
 member counties, I don&apos;t think he heard me exactly right. He thought 
 I said that this priority exists and he wanted to know how he could 
 get it started right away. And so that was actually a good sign, and 
 we&apos;ll build on that enthusiasm, mark my words.

Of course, we have several issues to be considered, and one of our 
 top priorities will be to capitalize the Rail Relocation and 
 Improvement Fund. This strategy will certainly help TxDOT in meeting 
 all of our goals. I have nothing new to report on this front since 
 my last report, but we will continue to work on a solution and keep 
 you informed on any developments.

In an effort to enhance safety on Texas roadways, we have researched 
 several options for your consideration. Some of these include the 
 establishment of sobriety checkpoints as a tool to be utilized by 
 local municipalities to assist in the enforcement of drunk driving 
 laws, the implementation of variable speed limits to help motorists 
 respond to changes in roadway conditions. We&apos;ve also researched the 
 benefits of exclusive truck lanes and how they can not only enhance 
 safety but reduce congestion and increase the value of current 
 transportation assets.

All of that being said, we are nearing completion of the research on 
 all the issues which have been brought to your attention so far. At 
 this point I would speculate that we would have a draft report 
 available to you for your review in the month of November, with an 
 eye towards final adoption in December. We will amend that schedule 
 if you would like us to, but looking at everything we have in place, 
 we should be able to have something to your offices and to your 
 staffs and in front of you in early November. We can discuss it at 
 greater length at the November commission meeting, and then December 
 adoption. If you want to change that, let me know and we&apos;ll be happy 
 to do that, and as I wrote in here, however, if the commission has a 
 different preferred future, please let me know.

And to follow up on something raised at the last meeting, 
 Commissioner Houghton requested an update on the Oregon Road User 
 Fee pilot program. This program is being explored in Oregon as an 
 alternative to traditional funding methods through the development 
 of a revenue collection system funded by a pay-as-you-drive method. 
 As part of the pilot program, vehicles are equipped with a GPS 
 device which tracks miles driven at certain times of the day. 
 Motorists would be charged accordingly based on the time of day and 
 the average daily traffic of the roadway traveled.

We are currently working with our own executive staff and the staff 
 of the Oregon Department of Transportation to coordinate a visit to 
 further discuss this program and other ideas. Commissioner Andrade 
 will be participating in that visit with us.

These are my prepared remarks for today. I&apos;ll be more than happy to 
 answer any questions you may have.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard Coby&apos;s explanation of where he 
 is in his process at this time. Do you have questions or comments 
 for Coby?

MS. ANDRADE: My only question, Coby, as you know, Public Transit 
 will come before the November meeting with the outcome of their 
 study group also. Will this give you enough time in 30 days to 
 include that in the draft?

MR. CHASE: Yes. Our preferred future for November, it&apos;s still an 
 open, living, organic document at that point, we consider our final 
 draft a draft, and if it needs to be amended. And we will work with 
 the Public Transportation Division, so kind of like doing a master 
 development plan for Trans-Texas Corridor, we will have an idea of 
 what happens when we all come together.

MS. ANDRADE: I just wanted to remind you and make sure that you&apos;re 
 aware that&apos;s coming.

MR. CHASE: Yes, ma&apos;am, absolutely.

MR. HOUGHTON: Coby, we talked about the opportunity of researching 
 the cap on CDAs being raised to 99 years.

MR. CHASE: Yes, sir, still there. I just didn&apos;t touch on all the 
 issues today, but yes, sir, that is still there. If I&apos;ve said it 
 before, it&apos;s still there, absolutely.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Anything else? John? A few things, Coby. Am I given 
 to understand there is no fuel tax on bio-diesel, or do you know?

MR. CHASE: I don&apos;t know off the top of my head; I don&apos;t believe that 
 there is.

MR. WILLIAMSON: What about ethanol?

MR. CHASE: There&apos;s a federal tax on it.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I&apos;m not proposing and wouldn&apos;t want anybody in the 
 audience to not understand the nature of my question. I want to know 
 two things in order to see if we want to add it to our list. I want 
 to know the extent to which alternative fuels are taxed in the same 
 manner as traditional fuels at the state level, and I want to know 
 the extent to which railroads, public transit agencies, airlines, 
 and whatever other mode of transportation I have left out, are or 
 are not subjected to the same clean air standards as are the 
 internal combustion machine burning traditional gasoline and diesel.

MR. HOUGHTON: Could I add to that list a little bit?

MR. WILLIAMSON: Please.

MR. HOUGHTON: Rail companies, diesel for locomotion, my 
 understanding, is not taxed in the state of Texas.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So maybe amend, this is a semi-research and possible 
 discussion point for next month.

MR. CHASE: What about all fuels that propel all forms of 
 transportation?

MR. WILLIAMSON: If we&apos;re going to stand for using the one thing in 
 common that everything has, that is the cost of something, as a 
 matter of addressing congestion, improving air quality, then it&apos;s 
 incumbent upon us to consider everything that happens in our state 
 and decide whether or not we want to discuss that with the 
 legislature.

Again, I&apos;m not suggesting we tax, necessarily, bio-diesel, I&apos;m 
 generally not a tax guy, but if bio-diesel is being consumed in ever 
 greater proportions and there&apos;s no significant difference in the 
 emissions of bio-diesel and traditional diesel, then there&apos;s no 
 reason for us not to at least put on the table the impact of 
 bio-diesel on the air quality and whether or not it&apos;s paying its 
 share of the road it consumes and the air it dirties.

MR. CHASE: Sure. Do you want us to add aviation fuel in there too? 
 That&apos;s not taxed.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Yes. So aviation fuel input and aviation exhaust 
 output, we want to kind of know about those things.

MR. CHASE: I don&apos;t think they pay for the roads.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Then the second thing is part of the reason we 
 started this several years ago was so no one could honestly accuse 
 of catching them by surprise when we went to the legislature with 
 proposals. I know that Bob Jackson, our head lawyer, has some 
 recommendations that will be made at some point on administrative 
 matters about RMAs. Lest I have overlooked discussing this with him, 
 I don&apos;t want us to forget we want to make an examination of how 
 boards are reformed when counties are added to an existing RMA. That 
 might be a weakness in the law we didn&apos;t anticipate four years ago.

But to be more specific, it is my understanding that the North Texas 
 Toll Authority, and perhaps the Harris County Toll Road Authority, 
 might wish our partnership and assistance in expanding their 
 existing authority with some of the flexibility of regional mobility 
 authorities, and while we want to be partners with those two groups 
 in addressing the state&apos;s problems, we don&apos;t want to be on record as 
 supporting changes in the law which, in our view, will act to 
 restrict regional planning and execution as opposed to expanding it.

So as you do your research and as you communicate with your NTTA and 
 HCRTA partners, we don&apos;t want to indicate for a moment that we&apos;re 
 interested -- you know, we have four strategies to solve the state&apos;s 
 transportation problem, one of those strategies is empowering local 
 and regional leaders to act locally and regionally. We view regions 
 more like our department districts or combinations of our districts, 
 we don&apos;t view regions as just one, two, three or four counties that 
 choose to call themselves a region, and I don&apos;t think any of us want 
 to mislead them into thinking that we do -- for what that&apos;s worth.

MR. CHASE: What I hear in there, we don&apos;t want to make sure we&apos;re 
 not doing anything that would limit the transportation future of a 
 region.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We&apos;re very sensitive to that. And we don&apos;t want to 
 mislead them into thinking that we would.

MR. CHASE: Right, absolutely.

MR. WILLIAMSON: As we&apos;ve been four things over the last six years, 
 we&apos;ve tried to be professionally clear about the things we&apos;re not 
 for, we&apos;re not for any more demo projects, we&apos;re not for piecemeal 
 building things, we&apos;re not for continuing to localize the power and 
 thus the problem, we are interested in regionalizing the authority 
 to solve those problems.

MR. CHASE: Absolutely.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Anything else, members?

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay, thank you, Mr. Behrens.

MR. BEHRENS: Thank you, Coby. We&apos;ll forgive that tie today.

Going on to agenda item number 4, Aviation, Dave Fulton will 
 recommend projects to be approved for funding for the month of 
 September.

MR. FULTON: Thank you, Mike. For the record, my name is Dave Fulton, 
 director of the TxDOT Aviation Division.

This minute order contains a request for grant funding approval for 
 eight airport improvement projects. The total estimated cost of all 
 requests, as shown in Exhibit A, is approximately $3.3 million: 
 approximately $1.2 million federal, $1.8 million state, and $300,000 
 in local funding.

A public hearing was held on August 17, no comments were received. 
 We would recommend approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, I don&apos;t see the Robert Nichols Memorial 
 Airport in here anywhere.

MR. JOHNSON: Fortunately, it&apos;s not memorial.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You&apos;re right.

(General laughter.)

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MR. FULTON: Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item number 5 is our rules for this month. 
 Agenda item 5(a)(1) would be proposed rules concerning Chapter 2 and 
 our Environmental Policy. Dianna?

MS. NOBLE: Good morning, commissioners. For the record, my name is 
 Dianna Noble, director of Environmental Affairs for TxDOT.

Agenda item 5(a) proposes a repeal of Subchapter A concerning 
 Comprehensive Policy on the Environment and the repeal of certain 
 sections in Subchapter C concerning Environmental Review and Public 
 Involvement for Transportation Projects, and simultaneously proposes 
 new subchapter titled Environmental Review and Public Involvement 
 for Transportation Projects.

The new subchapter redefines the policy, reorganizes the rules, 
 restates several of the requirements from the repealed rule, and 
 creates new provisions regarding federal and state environmental 
 requirements that affect environmental processing for transportation 
 projects.

The new sections continue to implement the requirements concerning 
 environmental processing for federal aid projects and satisfy 
 Transportation Code 201.604 that the department provide for, by 
 rule, the environmental review of the department&apos;s transportation 
 projects that are not subject to review under the National 
 Environmental Policy Act.

New 2.1 provides for general procedures and emergency actions, 
 including the policy. New 2.2 is a definition section and defines 
 terms used in this chapter. New 2.3, the federal aid transportation 
 project section, restates requirements repealed in 2.42; it also 
 includes new provisions to implement portions of SAFETEA-LU. This 
 new sections recognizes that the Federal Highway Administration and 
 the department may enter into a memorandum of agreement under which 
 the Federal Highway delegates to a state transportation agency the 
 authority to issue approvals of environmental documents and take 
 other actions. The new section authorizes the department to request 
 that Federal Highway publish in the Federal Register a notice that 
 issues a permit, license or approval is final, and therefore, that 
 any claims on the project must be filed within 180 days.

New 2.4 also is related to project coordination. It restates the 
 duties of the districts and Environmental Division on exchanging 
 information with other governmental entities concerning projects. 
 This section also implements SAFETEA-LU and establishes new 
 requirements for environmental processing that apply to federal aid 
 projects and that are classified as environmental impact statements 
 for projects.

New 2.5, Public Involvement, restates the requirements for public 
 involvement concerning a project, and there are also new provisions. 
 For federal aid projects, the SAFETEA-LU requirements apply if the 
 original notice of intent -- which is for an EIS type project -- was 
 published in the Federal Register after August 10, 2005. For 
 purposes of consistency for a state project, the requirements apply 
 if the original notice of intent was published in the Texas Register 
 after August 10, 2005. The new section also provides additional 
 requirements for the notice of availability of the final 
 environmental impact statement for the Trans-Texas Corridor project.

The next three sections deal with public involvement. New 2.6, 
 Meeting with Affected Property Owners, new 2.7 dealing with Public 
 Meetings, new 2.8 dealing with the Opportunity for Public Hearings, 
 all restate the requirements for these types of public involvement.

New 2.9, related to Public Involvement/ Public Hearings, restates 
 the requirements for this type of public involvement. It also lists 
 the types of projects for which a public hearing is mandatory.

New 2.10 deals with Categorical Exclusions, and it restates the 
 environmental review requirements for a project classified as a 
 categorical exclusion. New 2.11 deals with Environmental Assessments 
 and restates the environmental review requirements for a project 
 classified as requiring an environmental assessment.

New 2.12 relates to Environmental Impact Statements and restates the 
 environmental review requirements for a project classified as 
 requiring an environmental impact statement. It also includes new 
 provisions on developing the preferred alternative to a higher level 
 of detail. This implements SAFETEA-LU. It also adds new requirements 
 for preparation of a draft environmental impact statement for the 
 Trans-Texas Corridor project.

New Section 2.13 relates to re-evaluations and it restates the 
 environmental review requirements for when a project must undergo a 
 re-evaluation.

New 2.14 is related to Supplemental Environmental Assessments and 
 authorizes the department to prepare a supplement environmental 
 assessment. This new section requires the preparation of a 
 supplemental environmental assessment when there are changes to the 
 project that were not evaluated in the environmental assessment or 
 when there is new information or circumstances that were not 
 evaluated in the environmental assessment.

New 2.15 is related to Supplemental Environmental Impact Statements 
 and restates the requirements for a DIS.

New 2.16, related to Mitigation, restates the requirements for 
 mitigating the environmental impacts of a project and there are also 
 new provisions that before the department acquires by purchase or 
 condemnation real property to mitigate an adverse environmental 
 impact that the department, if authorized by the regulatory 
 authority, must offer to purchase a conservation easement from the 
 owner of the real property.

New 2.17 which deals with Special Right of Way Acquisition restates 
 the requirements concerning the acquisition of right of way under 
 certain circumstances, including the acquisition of private land 
 having an agricultural conservation easement and the taking of 
 certain public land in public or private historic sites. Subsection 
 (e) concerns Early and Advance Acquisition and specifies a method 
 for conducting the environmental review for early and advance 
 acquisitions.

New 2.18 relates to the Maintenance Projects and Programs and 
 restates the requirements concerning the environmental review and 
 approval for maintenance type projects and programs.

New 2.19, Rail Transportation Projects, restates the requirements 
 concerning the environmental review and approval for a rail 
 transportation project.

New 2.20, titled Public or Private Entity Receiving Financial 
 Assistance from the Department for a Project, restates the 
 environmental processing requirements for such projects, including 
 the information the entity must submit to the department.

If proposed for adoption, the department would conduct a public 
 hearing on November 9, 2006 to solicit comments on these proposed 
 rules.

That concludes my presentation and I&apos;ll be glad to answer any 
 questions.

MR. JOHNSON: Any questions of Dianna?

MR. HOUGHTON: I do have. Dianna, these are by statute and by rule 
 under SAFETEA-LU?

MS. NOBLE: Yes, sir, Commissioner. It&apos;s, in essence, accomplishing 
 two things: one is implementing requirements in SAFETEA-LU, and the 
 other one is implementing a state requirement that requires the 
 department to have environmental procedures for projects that are 
 not covered under NEPA which is a federal provision.

MR. JOHNSON: There is going to be a public hearing on November 9?

MS. NOBLE: Yes, if the commission so chooses to propose the 
 adoption.

MR. JOHNSON: And it&apos;s most likely place would be where it would be 
 held?

MS. NOBLE: It would be here at the Greer Building at, I believe, 
 nine o&apos;clock would be when we would have it.

MR. JOHNSON: And should this be passed, comments will be accepted 
 till November 13?

MS. NOBLE: That is correct. And so they will be posted, of course, 
 in the Texas Register.

MR. HOUGHTON: What kind of attendance do you get at these types of 
 hearings?

MS. NOBLE: Generally when there is attendance, it tends to be from 
 those that tend to be environmental advocacy type groups are the 
 ones that generally attend the meetings.

MR. JOHNSON: Any questions, Hope?

MS. ANDRADE: I have a question. There&apos;s something in here that says 
 about published in newspapers in English. Do we publish these 
 notices also in Spanish? I realize that the dominant language is 
 English, but is there an opportunity for us to get more people to 
 participate?

MS. NOBLE: I didn&apos;t state the full requirement indicates that the 
 notice must also be published in any other languages that might be 
 dominant in the area. For example, in Houston there tends to be a 
 lot of dialects, either Chinese or Vietnamese, so in essence, it 
 would require the publication in at least another newspaper to 
 announce that public meeting or hearing. And of course, Spanish is 
 another language that we likely also publish another notice.

MS. ANDRADE: So we do do that?

MS. NOBLE: Yes.

MS. ANDRADE: Thank you.

MR. JOHNSON: Any other questions? What would your pleasure be?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MS. ANDRADE: Second.

MR. JOHNSON: There&apos;s a motion and a second. All in favor of the 
 motion, signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. JOHNSON: Those opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. JOHNSON: Motion carries. Thank you, Dianna.

MS. NOBLE: Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item number 5(a)(2) is proposed rules under 
 Contract Management that deal with amendments to the Disadvantaged 
 Business Enterprise Program. J.D.?

MR. DOSSETT: Good morning, commissioners, Mr. Behrens. For the 
 record, my name is James Dossett. I&apos;m the director of the Business 
 Opportunities Program Office.

This minute order proposes adoption of amendments concerning the DBE 
 Program to conform to the federal rules for the administration of 
 the DBE Program. The Federal Highway Administration performed a 
 compliance review on the department&apos;s DBE Program last fall and 
 raised several issues and provided recommendations to address the 
 issues. The proposed rule revisions are intended to comply with the 
 recommendations and specific federal rules. The current rules do not 
 now comply with federal rules and the revisions will amend 9.53 to 
 comply with federal rules and Federal Highway Administration 
 recommendations.

Staff recommends approval.

MR. JOHNSON: Any question, comments?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MS. ANDRADE: Second.

MR. JOHNSON: There&apos;s a motion and a second. All in favor, signify by 
 saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. JOHNSON: Those opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. JOHNSON: Motion carries.

J.D., it&apos;s nice to know that your name is James.

(General laughter.)

MR. DOSSETT: Thank you, sir.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item 5(a)(3), more proposed rules, these under 
 Traffic Operations concerning our Logo Sign Program. Carlos?

MR. LOPEZ: Thank you, Mike.

Good afternoon, commissioners. My name is Carlos Lopez and I&apos;m 
 director of the Traffic Operations Division.

The minute order before you provides for the preliminary adoption of 
 revisions within our existing Logo Sign Program rules. This 
 amendment proposes revisions to Sections 25.401, Definitions, and 
 25.406 concerning Major Shopping Area Eligibility.

We recently became aware of some errors in our existing rules 
 related to two definitions. The definitions for Major Shopping Area 
 and Eligible Highway did not totally conform to that contained in 
 the statute. This proposed amendment is designed to ensure that 
 these definitions, as contained in the rules, accurately correspond 
 to state law.

We recommend approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Now, Carlos, is this the one that&apos;s going to permit 
 us to put billboards up on our property without having to apply for 
 a permit with the state?

MR. LOPEZ: I think that may be under John Campbell&apos;s purview.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I know Mr. Johnson is interested in that.

Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and recommendation. Do 
 you have questions or comments?

MR. JOHNSON: Carlos, I noticed that one of the things that this 
 affects is the way we identify shopping malls. Does this narrow or 
 widen our ability to do that? And what is an IAW statute?

MR. LOPEZ: Well, what it&apos;s going to do is make the rule correspond 
 to the statute. The statute is a little tighter than what we have in 
 our rules, but we have been signing for the malls that are under the 
 rules right now through a variance process. We wrote in our rules 
 that if you had 650,000 square feet and didn&apos;t have to be under a 
 covered roof, that opened it up to the outlet malls, so we&apos;ve been 
 signing for the outlet malls and we think it&apos;s a good thing because 
 they generate a lot of traffic. We&apos;ll continue to be able to do that 
 but we&apos;ll have to do it by a variance now.

MR. JOHNSON: And this program for shopping malls will fall under our 
 new contract for all the logo signs which is a little more advanced 
 in terms of the mechanism, the way the state receives their 
 compensation.

MR. LOPEZ: That is correct. It&apos;s bundled in with our regular Logo 
 Sign Program and a new Tourist-Oriented Destination Sign Program.

MR. JOHNSON: Now, would a filling station or a restaurant pay the 
 same amount that a shopping mall would for their identification?

MR. LOPEZ: No. The mall signing is a little more costly simply 
 because they are typically located on highways with higher traffic 
 volumes. In fact, this time around the payment structure for various 
 logo signs is dependent on the amount of traffic on a road which 
 makes sense.

MR. JOHNSON: Well, it does, and I think that&apos;s a tremendous 
 advancement. But what my question is if Exit 34 on a particular 
 roadway and there&apos;s a filling station there and a fast food 
 restaurant and a shopping mall, would, in essence, they pay the same 
 amount or is there a difference because the shopping mall has 
 650,000 square feet and a service station might have 25,000 square 
 feet and the restaurant 12,000 square feet.

MR. LOPEZ: In most cases it&apos;s going to be a difference in cost 
 because the mall sign will not be part of that blue sign with all 
 the logos, it will be its own sign, have a lot bigger lettering, and 
 stand on its own structure.

MR. JOHNSON: So there are some variables involved besides the 
 traffic counts.

MR. LOPEZ: That&apos;s correct.

MR. JOHNSON: Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Other questions or comments, members?

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: What&apos;s your pleasure?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MR. LOPEZ: Thank you, commissioners.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Good to see you, Carlos.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item 5(a)(4), proposed rules concerning 
 Oversize/Overweight Vehicle Loads. Carol?

MS. DAVIS: Good morning. I&apos;m Carol Davis, director of TxDOT&apos;s Motor 
 Carrier Division.

The minute order before you proposes amendments to Chapter 28 
 concerning Oversize/Overweight Vehicles and Loads. Specifically, 
 these amendments clarify policies concerning manufactured housing 
 permits, update statutory citations, and streamlines the process for 
 permits issued by Chambers County to transport loads with Cedar 
 Crossing Industrial Park.

We are recommending approval of the proposed amendments at this 
 time.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay, members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation 
 and recommendation on item 5(a)(4). Do you have questions or 
 comments?

MR. HOUGHTON: We&apos;re not talking about small home movers this week?

MS. DAVIS: No, sir. I thought I&apos;d give you a break.

MS. ANDRADE: I must say we missed you.

MS. DAVIS: Thank you. I&apos;ll be back next month.

MR. HOUGHTON: You&apos;re becoming very familiar on that podium.

(General laughter.)

MR. JOHNSON: So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MS. DAVIS: Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item 5(b)(1) is a rule for final adoption. This 
 would be concerning Access Management. Mark?

MR. MAREK: Thank you, Mr. Behrens, Mr. Chairman, commissioners. I&apos;m 
 Mark Marek, director of the Design Division for TxDOT.

This minute order proposes final adoption of amendments to 11.50 
 through 11.52 and 11.55 and a new section 11.56 relating to the 
 connection of a regionally significant highway to the state highway 
 system, to be codified under Title 43, Texas Administrative Code, 
 Part 1.

Transportation Code Chapter 203 provides that the Texas 
 Transportation Commission may lay out, construct, maintain and 
 operate a modern state highway system. Access management is one 
 method of preserving the substantial investment in the ground 
 transportation system by preserving the roadway level of service.

Senate Bill 637 of the 79th Legislative Regular Session 2005 amended 
 Transportation Code 203.032 to allow a county with a population of 
 3.3 million or more or a county adjacent to a county with a 
 population of 3.3 million or more to adopt access permitting 
 authority on the state highway system in a manner similar to that 
 delegated process available to municipalities. Counties meeting 
 these requirements are defined as eligible counties.

Sections 11.51 and 11.52 are amended to allow the delegation of 
 access permitting authority to these eligible counties. 11.52(f) is 
 amended to require compliance with the department&apos;s environmental 
 review rules. 11.55 is amended to expedite the approval process for 
 entering into agreements to provide local access roads in 
 conjunction with department projects.

The new Section 11.56 is added to provide a uniform means by which 
 public and private entities, with the authority to construct and 
 maintain and operate regionally significant highway facilities, may 
 obtain permission to connect those facilities to the state highway 
 system. While most such entities are required to obtain commission 
 approval to construct regionally significant highways, certain 
 entities with independent authority may construct a regionally 
 significant highway and not necessarily conform to the 
 Transportation Improvement Program, or the TIP. Adding regionally 
 significant highways that are not in the TIP, especially in 
 non-attainment areas, can threaten the entire area&apos;s transportation 
 conformity under the Federal Clean Air Act, resulting in sanctions 
 that could severely hamper the state&apos;s Federal Highway Program.

The current rules govern connection to the state highway system but 
 do not give the department the ability to deny connections based on 
 these conformity concerns, design and construction issues, or 
 non-compliance with federal requirements. This new rule will ensure 
 that proper statewide planning is employed in the construction of 
 major highway facilities that connect to the state highway system 
 and that those facilities are properly designed and constructed in 
 compliance with federal laws and that environmental impacts are 
 adequately considered.

No comments were received on these proposed rules. Staff recommends 
 approval of this minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Member, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation on item 5(b)(1). Do you have questions or comments?

MR. HOUGHTON: Just one. How many counties meet this?

MR. MAREK: There are about seven of those counties.

MR. HOUGHTON: Seven?

MR. MAREK: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Do I have a motion?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MS. ANDRADE: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item 5(b)(2) is another rule for final adoption 
 in our Vehicle Titles and Registration area dealing with specialty 
 plates. Rebecca?

MS. DAVIO: Good afternoon. For the record, my name is Rebecca Davio. 
 I am the director of the Vehicle Titles and Registration Division.

We have before you requesting final adoption of amendments to 17.28. 
 These rules deal with how we administer the Special License Plate 
 Advisory Committee. We posted the rules and didn&apos;t get any comments, 
 and so we request your approval.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff explanation and 
 recommendation. Do you have question or comments of staff?

MR. HOUGHTON: How many specialty plates do we have now?

MS. DAVIO: We have approximately 119.

MR. HOUGHTON: What&apos;s the most popular?

MS. DAVIO: What&apos;s the most popular?

MR. HOUGHTON: Number one.

MS. DAVIO: The State of the Art.

MR. HOUGHTON: Number two?

MS. DAVIO: The Animal Friendly.

MR. HOUGHTON: Really?

MS. DAVIO: And we&apos;ve actually sold, collectively, the most 
 personalized license plates. There&apos;s still a few good ones out 
 there, though, if you&apos;re interested. I&apos;d be happy to take your 
 order.

MR. JOHNSON: In your calculations, have you included the 
 universities?

MS. DAVIO: Yes, sir. All the university plates have sold about 
 16,000, collectively.

MR. HOUGHTON: Where would that be included in that one, two, three, 
 four, five calculation?

MS. DAVIO: It would probably come up about number five.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Where does Vanderbilt sit on that one?

MS. DAVIO: I have that information here for you; let me look. I was 
 ready for you this time.

MR. JOHNSON: Just out of curiosity, the universities, how do they 
 sort of fall, the top four or five?

MS. DAVIO: The executive director&apos;s alma mater is number one.

MR. JOHNSON: Okay. And who might be number two?

MS. DAVIO: The University of Texas is number two.

MR. JOHNSON: They moved back into the number two slot ahead of the 
 Texas Technological College or University in Lubbock?

MS. DAVIO: Yes. They&apos;re number three.

And our newest plate that we just started receiving orders for is 
 the Texas Rangers plate.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Is that Rangers as in the gun-toters, or Rangers as 
 in the guys that don&apos;t have any pitching?

(General laughter.)

MS. DAVIO: The last one. We&apos;ll also start selling Texas Astros.

MR. JOHNSON: Texas Astros plates. We have a new team.

MS. DAVIO: Houston Astros. Same thing.

MR. JOHNSON: They have pitchers and no hitters.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I don&apos;t know. They hit last night.

MR. JOHNSON: Well, it took them a long time.

MR. HOUGHTON: Took them a long time to win.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Seconded.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. You notice that we didn&apos;t embarrass 
 Steve Simmons by asking you about the University of Houston.

MS. DAVIO: I would have been ready.

MR. JOHNSON: Rebecca, one other question. Just for the record, so my 
 good friends from Lubbock might know how many more plates they need 
 to subscribe to so they can move back into the number two position. 
 How far is Texas Tech behind the University of Texas?

MS. DAVIO: About 700.

MR. HOUGHTON: What&apos;s Mr. Behrens&apos;alma mater?

MS. DAVIO: 6,138 plates. UT Austin, 3,510.

MR. HOUGHTON: Two to one.

MS. DAVIO: Texas Tech, 2,806.

MR. WILLIAMSON: And University of Houston?

MS. DAVIO: 558.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I didn&apos;t know you had that many cars, Steve.

(General laughter.)

MS. DAVIO: Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: We&apos;ve taken care of agenda item number 6, we&apos;ll go to 
 agenda item number 7. This will be a comprehensive development 
 agreement and a recommendation to issue a request for proposals for 
 detailed proposals on TTC-69. Phil?

MR. RUSSELL: Thanks, Mike.

Good afternoon, commissioners and Roger. For the record, I am 
 Phillip Russell, director of the Turnpike Division. And I probably 
 should state right off the bat, not to preempt any of your 
 questions, but I should state this morning when I woke up and looked 
 at the agenda item being for 69 and that it ultimately would go 
 through or could go through Louisiana, that I selected the color of 
 my tie, I think it&apos;s representative of LSU, and I certainly didn&apos;t 
 want to use my burnt orange tie, I knew I would irritate either Mr. 
 Behrens or Commissioner Houghton, so it seemed to be the better part 
 of valor to choose a nondescript tie color.

MR. WILLIAMSON: LSU.

MR. RUSSELL: I think it&apos;s LSU.

MR. JOHNSON: So the record will be perfectly clear, what color do 
 you have on your tie?

MR. RUSSELL: Uh-oh, you&apos;re calling my bluff. I think their colors 
 are kind of yellowish and blue.

MR. JOHNSON: They would prefer purple and gold probably.

MR. RUSSELL: I was close, though. But actually, I was going to ask 
 what are Vanderbilt&apos;s colors now?

MR. JOHNSON: I deflect that question ahead of our Aviation Division. 
 They&apos;re old gold and black.

MR. RUSSELL: Okay. I was thinking through but I couldn&apos;t recall.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I thought they were orange and black. No?

MR. JOHNSON: They only get orange scuff marks on their headgear 
 about the third Saturday of November.

MR. RUSSELL: That would be Tennessee, Mike.

(General laughter.)

MR. RUSSELL: Very well. Commissioners, as Mr. Behrens pointed out, 
 the minute order before you relates to TTC-69. As you recall, 
 earlier this year we initiated a process to bring onboard a 
 long-term strategic partner for Trans-Texas Corridor 69, similar to 
 the one that we&apos;ve currently employed on 35.

We have initiated the process, request for qualifications earlier 
 this year. We received two submittals. We have thoroughly reviewed 
 both of those submittals and determined that both should be 
 short-listed.

The minute order before you, should you choose to approve it, would 
 essentially do two things: number one, it would authorize us to go 
 out with a request for detailed proposals to these two developers; 
 second, it would set the stipend amount at $750,000 to the 
 unsuccessful proposer. Again, that would be a cap of sorts. It would 
 authorize payment for the intellectual properties up to an amount 
 including $750,000.

Staff would recommend approval, and I&apos;d be happy to address any 
 question you might have.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Phillip, earlier in the morning a member of the free 
 press came up and asked me a couple of questions about this. I fear 
 I might have misled her into thinking that this would come sooner on 
 the agenda than it did. I was going to apologize to her if she&apos;s 
 still here, but I think she&apos;s left.

She did ask a couple of probing questions about the stipend, and I 
 want to repeat for the record in case she&apos;s watching by video or she 
 watches the tape later, we have two issues we have to sort of 
 confront with the stipend. One is the fact that engineers under the 
 law of the state really can&apos;t work prospectively, they have to work 
 on a product, and the tight-fistedness of the commission won&apos;t 
 permit us to disburse money unless we receive something for it. So 
 this is a method we&apos;ve developed to assure that the engineering 
 component of these consortia are paid something for their work, and 
 to also assure that the taxpayers of the state get something of 
 value for the payment.

Could you kind of clarify for the record and for whoever might be 
 watching, live or the tape, what it is we will buy when we pay this 
 up to $750- to the consortia that might not be selected.

MR. RUSSELL: Right, Chairman. And she visited with me at the break, 
 as well, and so I was able to discuss that issue with her. And 
 you&apos;re right, it really does two things: it defrays some of their 
 cost, but ultimately what it does for us is it provides us that 
 intellectual property on that proposer. So we have free use of that 
 information that we can impart on the successful proposer on that 
 project or any other project that we deem appropriate. So it 
 essentially purchase the intellectual property rights up to an 
 amount of $750,000.

MR. WILLIAMSON: So one of the things that we think happens in this 
 process, members, is each individual competing or each consortia 
 looks at the same objective differently. One might think that the 
 trade corridor between Laredo and Corpus Christi is more valuable 
 than any other piece of the system and so they might spend a lot of 
 time and money looking at truck routes, freight company routes, how 
 much Wal-Mart or Target or H.E.B. uses rail as opposed to truck 
 along that route, and that information is incorporated into their 
 proposal. Whereas, the other consortia might believe that the Port 
 of Houston to extreme northeast Texas route is more important 
 because of the number of cars that are willing to get off of 
 congested 59 onto a toll road might be.

In either case, the State of Texas, the taxpayers will receive the 
 benefit of that data when they make that payment. We&apos;ll know what 
 that truck traffic is between Laredo and Corpus Christi, and we&apos;ll 
 know what that probable passenger toll traffic is between Texarkana 
 and Houston. Just so everyone knows, we don&apos;t pay things for nothing 
 around here.

MR. RUSSELL: That&apos;s exactly right.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay, members, this is a fairly significant event in 
 our lives. Do you have questions or comments?

MS. ANDRADE: I have a question. Phil, would you once again walk me 
 through the time line of the process? Is this going to happen in 
 December? How long will they have?

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, ma&apos;am. We&apos;ll work with those two consortia during 
 the intervening couple of months to make sure our documents are 
 correct and appropriate. We anticipate issuing the actual request in 
 December. We typically give about 90 days for their return 
 submittal. We&apos;ll evaluate those carefully, and I would anticipate 
 probably somewhere around next mid-year we&apos;ll have a developer 
 selected and we&apos;ll bring it back to you all for an award.

MS. ANDRADE: So mid&apos;07?

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, ma&apos;am.

MR. JOHNSON: Phil, I&apos;m under the impression that you&apos;ve recently 
 received an award. Is that correct?

MR. RUSSELL: What&apos;s that now?

MR. JOHNSON: I&apos;m under the impression, I&apos;ve got it in the cobwebs of 
 my mind that you have recently received a recognition or an award. 
 Is that correct?

MR. RUSSELL: I&apos;m not sure. The one up in the Little League ballpark 
 in Georgetown?

MR. JOHNSON: So I have you confused with someone. Is that what 
 you&apos;re telling me? I wanted to congratulate you for whatever you&apos;ve 
 been recognized for in the Little League ballpark or wherever.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Tell us about that.

MR. RUSSELL: Mike might know more than I.

MR. BEHRENS: The award is still forthcoming.

MR. JOHNSON: Obviously you shouldn&apos;t have let me know.

(General laughter.)

MR. RUSSELL: Thank you.

MR. JOHNSON: Only two consortia submitted proposals?

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, sir.

MR. JOHNSON: I find it fascinating that Cintra and Zachry have taken 
 their experience along TTC-35 and each has gone out, and in essence, 
 recruited, organized and developed their own separate teams and now 
 they&apos;re in competition with one another. I do think that&apos;s 
 exceptional for many reasons, but primarily the benefit is they are 
 the most experienced in terms of using this approach in the state of 
 Texas and we will benefit from their experience and their 
 competition one with the other -- we being the people who utilize 
 these corridors and travel the roads of this state. So I&apos;m 
 fascinated by that and I&apos;m going to be curious to see how this 
 unfolds.

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, sir. Commissioner, there have been several 
 comments about that. My experience on not just these procurements 
 but whether you&apos;re talking about consultants or anything, all of 
 those guys try to team up with appropriate members that will give 
 them the advantage on that particular project. So from one 
 standpoint, I&apos;m not particularly surprised. I think what you&apos;ll see, 
 whether it&apos;s 121, 161, whatever the next project is, you&apos;ll see all 
 sorts of different permutations between equity partners, designers, 
 contractors, and again, their goal is to try to create a team, 
 ultimately, that will be successful and they&apos;ll win that 
 competition.

So I think you&apos;ll see more of that, and I think the offshoot is 
 exactly what you&apos;re saying: you&apos;re going to have a 
 cross-pollenization out there through the industry, ultimately we&apos;re 
 going to grow the industry, and create more competition. That&apos;s 
 pretty good for all of us.

MR. JOHNSON: Well, the keener the competition, the better served we 
 all are.

MR. RUSSELL: Absolutely.

MR. HOUGHTON: What can be released to the public regarding the 
 developers? Can their teams be released?

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: When you look at the teams, it&apos;s fascinating to see 
 who&apos;s on them and you kind of get an inkling what&apos;s going to happen 
 in the transportation business, especially multimodal types of 
 transportation.

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, sir, I think you&apos;re exactly right. Again, we&apos;re 
 transitioning from the way we&apos;ve traditionally done business to 
 something that&apos;s a bit different. As Amadeo whispered to me just a 
 second ago, it&apos;s already on the website, so this information is out, 
 but clearly you&apos;ll see certain components on all these teams, 
 whether it&apos;s design, construction, financing, traffic and revenue 
 guys.

MR. HOUGHTON: Some non-traditional transportation folks are on those 
 teams which is fascinating in itself.

MR. RUSSELL: Absolutely. And it seems to always be that mix, that 
 Commissioner Johnson was alluding to, of different folks, whether 
 they&apos;re domestic partners or folks from global markets, they&apos;re all 
 coming together for this unique project trying to bring the best and 
 the brightest. I think it&apos;s a pretty good deal for us.

MR. HOUGHTON: Great.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Anything else, members? I, too, am fascinated but 
 from a different perspective. And obviously 69 is a different asset 
 than 35, but this is a pretty significant deal and it&apos;s drawing far 
 less attention the second time through, and it fascinates me that 
 having once gone through the fire and brimstone of 35, it may be the 
 case that as TTC-20 and TTC-45 and ultimately TTC-10 and whatever 
 other Ports to Plains ends up being -- and I&apos;m sure there will be 
 one -- perhaps it will become everyday business for the department 
 and we can go about our business of solving the transportation 
 problem.

MR. RUSSELL: Yes, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: It&apos;s becoming old hat, I think is part of the problem. 
 They&apos;ve cut their teeth on 35 and this is nothing new. It&apos;s 
 unfortunate because this is big, it&apos;s huge.

MR. RUSSELL: Well, I think step by step, brick by brick we&apos;re kind 
 of re-educating. Mr. Behrens and I talked about a meeting I had this 
 morning, and you know, there&apos;s still a lot of misunderstanding and 
 myths that are out there, and as we go through piece by piece and 
 let people understand clearly what we&apos;re talking about, some of the 
 transportation challenges we have in front of us, they get it, but 
 it takes a lot of that one-on-one discussion for people to fully 
 understand a very complex subject.

But I think you&apos;re right. As they become more familiar, slowly but 
 surely we&apos;re going to be gaining momentum on this.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Any other questions or comments, members? Do I have 
 a motion?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you, Phil. Godspeed, buddy.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item number 8 under Right of Way, this is a 
 recommendation to allow the use of options for advance acquisition 
 of right of way in the Dallas area. John?

MR. CAMPBELL: Good morning. For the record, my name is John 
 Campbell, director of the Right of Way Division.

I&apos;d like to present for your consideration this morning agenda item 
 number 8 to authorize the use of option agreements to secure the 
 right for potential purchase of required right of way along the 
 proposed route for two separate IH-35 projects in the Dallas County.

The minute order provides the authority for the Dallas District 
 engineer to negotiate the execution of option contracts and to 
 expend funds for option fees and related administrative costs.

Staff recommends your approval of the minute order.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard an explanation and a 
 recommendation regarding the agenda item. What&apos;s your pleasure?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion, signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries, John.

MR. CAMPBELL: Thank you.

MR. WILLIAMSON: All that waiting for just 41 seconds.

MR. CAMPBELL: It&apos;s my pleasure to be here, sir.

MR. HOUGHTON: He can talk about billboards if you want him to talk 
 about LEDs real quickly.

MR. CAMPBELL: Didn&apos;t Carlos cover billboards for me earlier in the 
 program?

MR. WILLIAMSON: How are on going ahead and codifying the fact that 
 LEDs are not the same as paper billboards?

MR. CAMPBELL: How far are we along that end?

MR. WILLIAMSON: I know we&apos;re working on that, I&apos;ve told John that.

MR. CAMPBELL: We&apos;re in the dialogue on that topic.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We&apos;re in the dialogue stage?

MR. CAMPBELL: We&apos;re in the dialogue stage.

MR. HOUGHTON: Demonstration projects.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, you&apos;re so unflappable, it&apos;s the only thing 
 that I&apos;ve ever seen you flap over.

MR. CAMPBELL: Over LED signs?

MR. WILLIAMSON: Billboards, any billboard.

MR. HOUGHTON: Have we determined whether that Godzilla over there is 
 in compliance?

MR. WILLIAMSON: I think we have an official determination that it is 
 an on-premise sign.

MR. CAMPBELL: It&apos;s an on-premise sign, therefore exempted from 
 regulation.

MR. HOUGHTON: It&apos;s an on-premise sign, John?

MR. CAMPBELL: Yes, sir.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Over the objection of our Aggie administrator.

MR. CAMPBELL: And technically, it probably exceeds the limit from 
 the controlled highway.

MR. HOUGHTON: It does? Even though you can see it from the top of 
 35?

MR. CAMPBELL: It&apos;s big, isn&apos;t it?

MR. WILLIAMSON: Coby Chase said he sat under it during a ball game 
 and got a suntan.

MR. JOHNSON: It was a night game?

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Thank you, John.

MR. BEHRENS: Okay, we&apos;ll go on. We&apos;ve covered 9, we&apos;ll go to agenda 
 item number 10. This is our SIB loan with the City of Kerrville. 
 James?

MR. BASS: Good afternoon. Again, for the record, I&apos;m James Bass, 
 chief financial officer at TxDOT.

Item 10 seeks your final approval of a loan to the City of Kerrville 
 in the amount of $2.8 million to pay for roadway and drainage 
 improvements to Holdsworth Drive. Interest will accrue from the date 
 funds are transferred from the SIB at a rate of 4.1 percent, with 
 payments being made over a period of 20 years.

Staff recommends your approval.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Members, you&apos;ve heard the staff&apos;s explanation and 
 recommendation. Do I have a motion?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MS. ANDRADE: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you, James.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item number 11, our contracts for the month of 
 September, both our highway maintenance contracts and building 
 construction, and then the second part will be our regular 
 construction projects.

MS. BOSWELL: Good afternoon. For the record, my name is Elizabeth 
 Boswell. I&apos;m the director of the Construction Section of the 
 Construction Division.

Reference agenda item 11(a)(1), authorization of this minute order 
 provides for the award or rejection of highway maintenance projects 
 let on September 7 and 8, 2006 whose engineers&apos;estimated costs are 
 $300,000 or more.

Staff recommends rejection of one project as follows. This is a 
 two-year project located in Bowie County and consists of the 
 installation of traffic signals at various locations. Staff 
 recommends rejection of this project so that it may be redesigned as 
 a one-year contract to attract additional bidders and lower bid 
 prices.

Award is recommended for all remaining projects as shown in Exhibit 
 A.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Hang on a second, I&apos;m looking at the one that&apos;s over 
 and you&apos;re recommending to accept.

MS. BOSWELL: Okay.

(Pause.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: I&apos;ve seen what I needed to see. Members, need to 
 keep looking?

MR. JOHNSON: So moved.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries.

MS. BOSWELL: Construction projects. Reference agenda item 11(a)(2), 
 authorization of this minute order provides for the award or 
 rejection of highway construction projects let on September 7 and 8, 
 2006, as shown in Exhibit A. Staff recommends rejection of two 
 projects as follows.

The first project is located in McLennan County and provides for the 
 non-site specific installation of traffic signals at various 
 locations throughout the district. Staff recommends rejection of 
 this project so that the project may be redesigned to clarify 
 bidders&apos;uncertainty and attract additional bidders.

The second project recommended for rejection is located in Starr 
 County and provides for the reconstructing, widening and extending 
 Atkins Street from US 83 at FM 650 to US 83 to Aurora in the city of 
 Roma. Staff recommends rejection of this contract due to 
 insufficient competition as only one bid was received on this 
 project and the bid submitted was approximately 66 percent over the 
 engineer&apos;s estimate. In addition, staff feels a redesign is in order 
 to reduce cost and attract additional bidders.

Award is recommended for all remaining projects as shown in Exhibit 
 A.

MR. HOUGHTON: I have one question that&apos;s semi-related to this, 
 Amadeo. We just completed our fiscal year. Correct? What was the 
 total amount of awards for construction projects in the fiscal year&apos;06?

MR. SAENZ: For the record, Amadeo Saenz. It was around $5.3 billion.

MR. HOUGHTON: Is that a record?

MR. SAENZ: So far that&apos;s the highest we&apos;ve done.

MR. HOUGHTON: We did not publicize that at all, did we? I don&apos;t 
 remember seeing that number.

MR. WILLIAMSON: No, but we should have.

MR. HOUGHTON: $5.3-?

MR. SAENZ: Around $5.3-, I think, is the last report I saw.

MR. HOUGHTON: What is that over fiscal year&apos;05?

MR. SAENZ: About $300 million.

MR. HOUGHTON: $300 million?

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. I think 2005 was right at $5-. We will get 
 numbers because we let projects that we let through the commission, 
 and that&apos;s what I&apos;m talking about the $5.3-, the projects that are 
 let and awarded here. We also have projects that are awarded locally 
 in the maintenance area for projects less than $300,000, and then we 
 also have some projects that are being awarded through a local 
 entity, a city, a county, some of those are enhancements. So when 
 you sum up those, I think we&apos;ll be up in almost $5.4- or $5.5-.

MR. HOUGHTON: That is something significant, Mr. Chairman.

MR. JOHNSON: I tell you what makes it as much significant as the raw 
 numbers is that we&apos;re doing that with the same number of full-time 
 equivalents that we&apos;ve had for a decade At one time I think we had 
 17- or 18,000 in the early&apos;90s and now we&apos;ve got 14,000, and our 
 full-time equivalent numbers has remained pretty constant, and yet 
 the volume of business that comes through here has increased 
 substantially. So I think that&apos;s remarkable and a tribute to the 
 people of this agency.

MR. SAENZ: Yes, sir. And this is the first month of the fiscal year 
 so we can still put something out to let you know what we&apos;ve done in 
 fiscal year 2006.

MR. HOUGHTON: I think this should be a big issue across the state.

MR. SAENZ: We&apos;ll do that.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Wait a minute, don&apos;t leave. I&apos;ll call for a vote on 
 this item in a minute, but I have a couple of questions. Is my 
 memory failing me, or am I seeing an unusual number of in excess of 
 engineer&apos;s estimate and recommend that we go ahead and approve the 
 contract?

MR. SAENZ: Go ahead and answer.

MS. BOSWELL: Are you referencing for this month an excess of over 
 the engineer&apos;s estimate recommending award? I would say our numbers 
 are less this month. We had fewer projects that required 
 justification.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Recommend award of nine construction projects, 
 multiple bidders, 20 percent or more, and above engineer&apos;s estimate. 
 So this is down as opposed to up?

MS. BOSWELL: It was down from last month.

MR. SAENZ: It&apos;s down from prior months.

MS. BOSWELL: Yes.

MR. JOHNSON: What&apos;s the dollar amount of those contracts? Are they 
 fairly small by comparison?

MR. WILLIAMSON: Well, it may just be because they&apos;ve been rising 
 over the last six months that I&apos;m paying more attention to it, John. 
 I&apos;m aware that with all of the innovation that the legislature has 
 permitted us to have and with all the activity at the local level, 
 there&apos;s still a finite amount of cash flow available to invest in 
 this stuff, and I just am growing more concerned, Mike, about the 
 cash flow commitments we&apos;re making to our partners and balancing 
 that against the known cash flow of the state. The worst thing that 
 can happen to us is to have to cut a letting or have to cut three or 
 four lettings in a row by a large amount, as opposed to recognizing 
 the cost is going up right now and choking back a little bit at a 
 time.

John, you and I are in the business and we know the price of oil and 
 gas rises and falls, but the price of oil and gas isn&apos;t the only 
 reason these prices are going up. I&apos;m paying three times today for 
 concrete what I was paying a year ago, and I&apos;m paying almost twice 
 as much for steel, and I suspect that&apos;s where a lot of the increase 
 in price is.

MR. BEHRENS: And even actually going back to the August letting in 
 September, and that&apos;s on the letting side, it&apos;s not on the 
 Construction Division side, we actually are looking at each month&apos;s 
 letting and we&apos;ve actually decreased the amount of letting to try to 
 stay in balance with our cash flow.

MR. JOHNSON: Elizabeth, in our books we have a one-page summary 
 which has a total number of projects, total number of bids, et 
 cetera, and when we lump together all of these projects from let&apos;s 
 say $100,000 to $50 million, we&apos;re sort of getting a distorted 
 picture because in all probability there are going to be more 
 bidders for the lesser amount of contracts than let&apos;s call them the 
 super contracts, and it would be helpful to me if we went through 
 the same thing but broke the contract amount size into categories. I 
 don&apos;t know what the right thresholds are but I&apos;m thinking under $5 
 million and then $5- to maybe $20- or $25-, and then $25- and above, 
 but where we catch a number of projects that has meaning and we can 
 follow the chairman&apos;s suggestion of over and under, but also how 
 competitive these things are in terms of the average number of 
 bidders, et cetera.

MS. BOSWELL: We can do that.

MR. JOHNSON: Good.

MS. ANDRADE: I have one comment.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Please.

MS. ANDRADE: Amadeo, I know that we want to let the state know how 
 much money we&apos;re putting out there, but also in the local district 
 offices. I know in San Antonio we celebrate because the local 
 district office is having record-breaking construction years. We 
 might want to encourage our district offices so that communities 
 take ownership of the fact that we are having record-breaking years 
 in local communities.

MR. SAENZ: And I think a lot of our districts are doing that. I know 
 San Antonio has done it for the last two years or maybe three years 
 -- three years at least, and I think a lot of our districts are 
 already doing the same thing.

We review every project that is over the engineer&apos;s estimate by 10 
 percent when we only have one bidder, and we review every project, 
 no matter how many bidders, when it&apos;s over 20 percent and evaluate 
 and make a recommendation on those projects. Some we recommend for 
 rejection and some we recommend for award.

I guess when we look at the total projects -- and they may be 
 distorted because we&apos;ve lumped everything together -- I think we&apos;ll 
 be able to present you a much better picture by breaking up the 
 projects. We are still getting almost four bidders per contract in 
 total, and really our bids, based on what we are awarding, we were 
 almost 7 percent under our estimates. We do have some projects that 
 either we missed the estimate or we had some errors in it. For 
 example, we talked about the Starr County project. That project also 
 had some errors in quantities that showed the difference that was 
 not included in the presentation. But we will look at that.

One of the other things, and I mentioned it earlier, is this used to 
 be a much bigger problem because when we were selecting projects and 
 people would get their project and say that&apos;s my project no matter 
 what it costs, but now as the regions get their allocations, it&apos;s 
 like they have their checkbook and they&apos;re balancing and keeping 
 their checkbook, so as projects overrun, they&apos;re keeping track of 
 the impacts to their allocation based on those overruns and 
 underruns.

I have a request from a district that says my project underran by a 
 million dollars, does that mean I still have my money available? 
 Yes, you do. But by the same token, another district says my project 
 overran by a million dollars, where do I have to get it from? But by 
 giving it to them and making them and holding them accountable, 
 they&apos;re beginning to see and understand how they manage their 
 resources.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Can&apos;t be a bad thing.

MR. JOHNSON: Good stuff.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Do I have a motion?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

MS. BOSWELL: Thank you.

MR. BEHRENS: Agenda item number 12 is our Routine Minute Orders. 
 They&apos;ve all been duly posted, as required. I went through all of 
 these minute orders; I don&apos;t see any that would affect or where 
 there&apos;s anything associated with any of you individually as 
 commissioners. So I recommend approval of the Routine Minute Orders.

MR. HOUGHTON: Where are they going to spread seed for Keep Brazos 
 Beautiful, on what highways?

MR. JOHNSON: Most of them are going to be around El Paso.

MR. HOUGHTON: I was going to say we&apos;ve had enough rain out there to 
 sprout something.

MR. BEHRENS: It&apos;s going to on various highways in Brazos County.

MR. WILLIAMSON: They&apos;re going to spread it on Highway 6 right next 
 to all of those electronic devices we&apos;re fixing to put up.

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Speed limits, where is that?

MR. BEHRENS: Speed limits would be 12(e).

MR. WILLIAMSON: We haven&apos;t raised anybody&apos;s speed limits, have we?

MR. BEHRENS: I don&apos;t think we have any.

MR. HOUGHTON: I hope so.

MR. BEHRENS: We have a number of construction speed zones in there, 
 and the other is just regular speed zones that are being adjusted.

MR. HOUGHTON: We need to go faster in far west Texas.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Okay, members, what&apos;s your pleasure on this one?

MR. HOUGHTON: So moved.

MR. JOHNSON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second. All those in favor of 
 the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. Thank you.

Mike, do we have any reason to go to executive session?

MR. BEHRENS: I don&apos;t have any reason. We may ask our new general 
 counsel if he has any reason.

MR. HOUGHTON: Did everyone sign the appointment? Is he general 
 counsel yet?

MR. WILLIAMSON: I think we appointed him general counsel, and didn&apos;t 
 we put him in charge of the Amarillo Maintenance Division as well?

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Bob, do we have any reason to go to executive 
 session?

MR. JACKSON: No, sir, we don&apos;t.

MR. WILLIAMSON: Do we need to say welcome aboard?

MR. JOHNSON: Congratulations.

MR. WILLIAMSON: We can congratulate ourselves.

I was thinking about the continuity of the employee base when we 
 were recognizing Phyllis and the different spots that she&apos;s been in, 
 and then thinking about Bob and the different places he&apos;s been, and 
 now we look up and he&apos;s our head lawyer. Pretty impressive, head of 
 the best engineering and construction law firm in the state.

Do we have any open comment testimony?

MR. BEHRENS: We have none.

MR. WILLIAMSON: This is not a record but it&apos;s close. The most 
 privileged motion is in order.

MR. JOHNSON: Before I proceed to make that, I do want to set the 
 record straight. To the best of my knowledge, Vanderbilt and the 
 University of Texas at Austin have met eleven times on the gridiron, 
 and the University of Texas at Austin has won two of those games.

MR. WILLIAMSON: You know, John, I think your memory is absolutely 
 perfect, although it must have taken some time to dig back all the 
 way into the&apos;20s to find all those records because I think it was&apos;28 when we last played, wasn&apos;t it?

MR. JOHNSON: It was in that neighborhood, but we were dominating the 
 series so much that the University of Texas at Austin didn&apos;t want to 
 schedule us anymore. In lieu of us, they now have Sam Houston State.

MR. WILLIAMSON: They didn&apos;t think they were scheduling Vanderbilt 
 all those years, they thought they were scheduling the University of 
 Mississippi. I don&apos;t know how they confused Vanderbilt and the 
 University of Mississippi, but back then things were probably 
 different.

MR. JOHNSON: Vanderbilt was just a little farther away.

MR. WILLIAMSON: By train.

MR. JOHNSON: By anything.

(General laughter.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Did you make that motion?

MR. JOHNSON: Move we adjourn.

MR. HOUGHTON: Second.

MR. WILLIAMSON: I have a motion and a second that we adjourn. All 
 those in favor of the motion will signify by saying aye.

(A chorus of ayes.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: All opposed, no.

(No response.)

MR. WILLIAMSON: Motion carries. We are adjourned, Mr. Jackson, at 
 12:47 p.m.

(Whereupon, at 12:47 p.m., the meeting was concluded.)




 C E R T I F I C A T E 


MEETING OF: Texas Transportation Commission
LOCATION: Austin, Texas
DATE: September 28, 2006
I do hereby certify that the foregoing pages, numbers 1 through 170, 
 inclusive, are the true, accurate, and complete transcript prepared 
 from the verbal recording made by electronic recording by Carol 
 Oppenheimer before the Texas Department of Transportation.



10/03/2006
(Transcriber) (Date)

On the Record Reporting, Inc.
3307 Northland, Suite 315
Austin, Texas 78731

 back to top 
 
 
 Home | Contact Us | Site Map | Español 
 Business with TxDOT | Careers | Drivers&amp;Vehicles | Local Information | Projects | Public Involvement | Safety | Travel | TxDOT Library | About Us 

 Homeland Security | Open Records | Fraud Hotline | texas.gov | Statewide Search | Compact with Texans | Texas Tourism 
 Disclaimer | Privacy and Security Policy | Accessibility 

 125 East 11th Street . Austin, Texas 78701   
 Copyright 2012. Texas Department of Transportation. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
