<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007685" url="http://www.gaytlvguide.com/do-see-go/tel-aviv-restaurants" time="2012-07-13-00:39" support="1" score="0.0012353836499288304" bingtitle="Tel Aviv Restaurants | Tel Aviv Guide | Travel Israel, Nightlife ..." webtitle="Tel Aviv Restaurants | Tel Aviv Guide | Travel Israel, Nightlife, Clubs and more">
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>It doesn&apos;t matter if you enter the restaurant in 10:00 in the ... The pizza is baked in rectangle trays, in an ... This hip fast food restaurant offers 2 or 3 small (80 grams ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Start here 
 Gay Tel Aviv Gay Culture in Israel Frequently Asked Questions Tel Aviv Weather Gay Rights in Israel Gay Israel in the media 
 Gay Guide 
 Gay Tel Aviv map Gay Nightlife - Bars&amp;Clubs The Gay Beach Accommodation - B&amp;B Hotels Gay Saunas, Sex Shops&amp;more Gay Pride Parade HIV Information Useful links 
 Do, See, Go 
 Best things to do in Tel Aviv Gyms in Tel Aviv Tel Aviv Restaurants Tel Aviv Museums Events in Tel Aviv Travel Israel Beaches in Israel and Tel Aviv 
 Photos 
 Gay Parties The City of Tel Aviv Gay Pride Parades Sightseeing in Israel Upload your photos 
 About 
 Contact us Help needed Login 
 
 Home Do, See, Go Tel Aviv Restaurants 
Recommended Tel Aviv Restaurants
 
We love Tel Aviv, just love it, and one of the reasons is the variety of culinary adventures one can experience here.
We have picked our favorite restaurants throughout the city so that you can fall in love with Tel Aviv as well.
Here is a list of recommended tel aviv restaurants.
Bon Appetite.

Choose your category: Italian , Sushi , Meat , Thai , Breakfast , Burgers , Tapas Bar , Hummus , Sandwich Bar , Pizza , Asian , Bistro , Chocolate Bar , Sheek and Tasty , Gourmet 
 
Italian restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Rustico 

This fine italian tel aviv restaurant has two branches in town and excellent food. An Italian mama prepares their desserts, so be sure to book a table in advance if you&apos;d like to enjoy those as much as we did.

Address 1: 15 Rothschild Blvd, Tel Aviv
Phone 1: 03-5100039

Address 2: 42 Bazel Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 03-6026969


 
Sushi restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Moon 

The most known Sushi bar in Tel Aviv, Moon, was first opened 10 years ago and offers the best Sushi in town. One can sit either at the bar, where you can just pick up your favorite sushi from the conveyor belt or ask for a private table.

Address: 58 Bugrashov Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 03-6291155


 
Meat restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Rak Basar
 

The english translation of &quot;Rak Basar&quot; is &quot;Meat Only&quot;, and best describes what this restaurant is all about. The diners pick their meat on their own at the beginning of the meal, which promises the best culinary experience. In addition, free wine all night long for only 15NIS per person.

Address: 19 Derech Shlomon, Tel Aviv
Phone: 057-9442924 


 
Thai restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 The Thai House
 

This specially designed restaurant in tel aviv really preserves the thai culture with all the wood and plans that are all around. The restaurant is managed by a thai chef who sticks to traditional cooking, so that your culinary experience will truly be original.

Address: 8 Bugrashov Street
Phone: 03-5178568


 
Breakfast restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Benedict 

It doesn&apos;t matter if you enter the restaurant in 10:00 in the morning, or 3:00 after midnight, &quot;Good Morning&quot; is the greeting you will hear when sitting down at your table. This 24 hour restaurant serves only breakfast in so many ways one can&apos;t imagine until they get the menu. Great way to start your day, but beware that many Tel Avivians think the same way, so you may be waiting a bit for your table.

Address 1: 171 Ben Yehuda Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 1: 057- 9443406 

Address 2: 29 Rothschild Blvd, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 03- 6868657 


 
Burgers restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Wolfnights 

If you&apos;re into quality burgers, and not just fast food, give woolfnights a try. This is a classic tel aviv restaurant, open till late, good food, nice beer, exactly what is needed after a long clubbing night :)

Address 1: 40 Lilenblum Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 1: 03-5177155

Address 2: 53 Yehuda Macabbi Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 03-5177155


 
Tapas Bar restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Tapas Ahad Ha&apos;am 

For those of you who like to try all sort of foods in one night, give this tapas bar a try. Located in the heat of Tel Aviv, this restaurant draws the attention of many locals and tourists.

Address: 27 Ahad Ha&apos;am Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 03-5666966


 
Hummus restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Abu Dabi
 

One can&apos;t visit Israel without eating hummus, and Abu Dabi is one of the favorite hummus places in town.

Address: 81 King George Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 03-5259090

 Abu Hassan
 

One hummus dish doesn&apos;t taste like the other, and this is why we had to include one of the most famous and well establishes hummus places in Tel Aviv - Abu Hassan. Dont&apos; get there too late (close around 15:00), as they prepare a cetrain amount of hummus a day and that&apos;s it :)

Address: 1 Ha&apos;Dolfin Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 03-6828255


 
Sandwich Bar restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Olive 

Sometimes a good sandwich is just what you need for lunch or a light dinner. Olive provide a vast variety of sanwiches, and you can always just make your own combination of favorite ingrediants.

Address 1: 24 Lilenblum Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 1: 03-5106680

Address 2: 1 Karlibach Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 03-5623336


 
Pizza restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Tony Vespa
 

Using a secret recipe which was brought from Italy, Tony Vespa is certainly a must-to-taste pizza. The pizza is baked in rectangle trays, in an original italian oven, and are sold by the weight.

Address 1: 267 Dizengoff Street, Tel Aviv
Phone 1: 03- 5460000

Address 2: 140 Rothschild Blvd, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 057-9424625


 
Asian restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Giraffe 

Another restaurant in tel aviv which you should check out - great asian food in affordable prices, Giraffe attracts many people for lunch/dinner meals. Big tasty dishes, and good service, who needs more?

Address: 49 Iben gabirol Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 057-9417933


 
Bistro restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Brasserie 

The Brasserie Tel Aviv Restaurant resides in the center of the city, and is open 24 hours a day. With a menu in the french language, crowdness that reminds one of New York City, and waiters in uniform, the Brasserie is the perfect place for an excellent meal. Prices are a bit above average, but worth it.

Address: 70 Iben gabirol Street, Tel Aviv
Phone: 03-5666966


 
Chocolate Bar restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Max Brenner
 

Max Brenner is a whole new special and different way of experiencing chocolate. If you&apos;re a sweets lover, and even if not, check out this great restaurant in tel aviv for a good breakfast, tasty lunch, or great dinner evening.

Address 1: Old Tel Aviv Port
Phone 1: 03- 5445480 

Address 2: 45 Rothschild Blvd, Tel Aviv
Phone 2: 03- 5604570 


 
Sheek and Tasty restaurants in tel aviv 

 
 Burgerim
 

This hip fast food restaurant offers 2 or 3 small (80 grams) burgers in different tastes, and a side dish of your choice. Good and tasty.

Address: 27 Ahad Ha&apos;am Street, Tel Aviv
Phone:03-5666966

 Carpaccio Bar
 

If you&apos;re into a nice snack, check out this great place which offers a vast amount of carpaccio choices in all kinds of flavors and tastes. In addition you can find salads, sandwiches and a few sea food dishes.

Address: 8 Iben Gabirol Street, Tel Aviv
Phone:03- 9443663 


 
Gourmet restaurants in tel aviv 

 The numer of restaurants in tel aviv, and good ones in perticular, increase daily. Still, there is nothing like a good gourmet restaurant from time to time, and Tel Aviv is not disappointing in that field as in others. Here is a selection of only a few from Tel Avivs famous chef restaurants.



 Messa 

Messa offers diners haute cuisine by Chef Aviv Moshe in a gorgeously designed setting that redefines the Tel-Aviv dining experience. Aviv defines the restaurant’s cuisine as “thrilling, far from simple, and with a subtext of Mother’s kitchen”. The menu is grounded on Provencal cookery techniques. Locally sourced materials are used extensively, there’s a strong emphasis on the quality of raw materials, plus games with different textures…so each dish is imbued with captivating complexity.

Address: 19 Ha&apos;Arbaa Street, Tel Aviv
Phone:03-6856859 (extension 2).

 Herbert Samuel
 

The Herbert Samuel restaurant is located on the Tel Aviv boardwalk by the sea, and offers creative, contemporary dining from the kitchen of Jonathan Roshfeld. The menu offers a colorful display of appetizers, some of which can be ordered as half-portions (tapas), resulting in a satisfying meal made up from a wide variety of the best quality ingrediants..

Address: 6th koifman st. Bet Gibor Tel Aviv
Phone:03-5166516



 Hotel Montefiore
 

Located on the main floor, Hotel Montefiore&apos;s restaurant serves brasserie cuisine under Vienamese spell. The restaurant is the new addition to the city&apos;s Dining life, joining the owners &quot;Coffee Bar&quot;, &quot;Brasserie&quot; and the &quot;Bakery&quot;. The restaurant keeps the tradition of serving wonderful food in an impeccable atmosphere.

Address: 36 Montefiore Street, Tel Aviv
Phone:03-5646100
	</body>
</document>
