<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007897" url="http://www.pe.com/business/business-headlines/20120315-retail-chevrolet-builds-goodwill-one-french-fry-at-a-time.ece" time="2012-07-13-00:52" support="5" score="0.008305732995627726" bingtitle="RETAIL: Chevrolet builds goodwill one French fry at a time ..." webtitle="RETAIL: Chevrolet builds goodwill one French fry at a time | Breaking News | PE.com - Press-Enterprise">
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000515" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>... night to take a ride in a Chevrolet to the fast-food restaurant of ... long gravitated toward import brands, than in places ... Check the &quot;Delete browsing history on exit&quot; box.</description>
	<body>
		pe.com Web Search Story Archive Business Directory Member Submitted Events Calendar 
 Home 
 Video Photos Twitter Facebook About Us Contact Us Advertise With Us 
 Local News 
 Riverside County 
 Corona-Norco Hemet-San Jacinto Lake Elsinore Menifee Moreno Valley Murrieta Perris Riverside Temecula The Pass Wildomar 
 Southwest San Bernardino County Archives Columns Obituaries Politics Special Reports Traffic Weather 
 Other News 
 California Nation World Lottery Noticias En Español 
 Sports 
 MLB 
 Angels Dodgers Padres Cal League Headlines 
 NBA 
 Lakers Clippers 
 Boxing College 
 UCLA Football USC Football 
 NFL Golf HS GameTime NHL 
 Ducks Kings Reign 
 Motor Sports Other Outdoors Soccer 
 Business 
 National Local Profiles Real Estate News Stock Market Business Wire Marketwire PR Newswire 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Letters to the Editor Local Views Write Your Legislator 
 iGuide 
 Arts Attractions Casinos Celebrities Dining Events Family Movies&amp;TV Music Puzzles Theater TV Listings Video 
 About You 
 Readers&apos; Choice Horoscopes Your Photos Girl Scouts 
 Tools 
 E-mail Newsletters Mobile Sites&amp;Apps RSS Feeds 
 Cars 
 Buy a Car Sell a Car Browse Newspaper Ads 
 Real Estate 
 Search Homes for Sale Search Rentals Search Foreclosures Inland Home Sales Listings 
 Jobs 
 Search for a Job Post Your Resume Post a Job Opening 
 Marketplace 
 Business Directory Deal of the Day Search Classifieds Place Classified Ad Legal Guide Legal Notices Browse Print Ads Shopping 
 
 Home &gt; Business &gt; Business Headlines March 15, 2012 04:13 PM PDT March 15, 2012 06:00 PM PDT RETAIL: Chevrolet builds goodwill one French fry at a time 
RETAIL: Chevrolet builds goodwill one French fry at a time
 
 
  FRANK BELLINO/STAFF PHOTOGRAPHER UCR students Myrian Lamas,18 and Maria Araujo, 21 step out of a 2012 Chevy Camaro with free food during a Chevy promotino on college campuses in Riverside, Ca. Mar.14, 2012. Chevy is reaching out to younger buyers with a new marketing promotino on college campuses by bringing a bunch of cars to campus for two nights, offering free rides to students to local restaurants for free meals.  
 
 1 of 5 
 
 
BY TIFFANY RAY
 BY TIFFANY RAY The Press Enterprise 
STAFF WRITER

 tray@pe.com 

 Published: 15 March 2012 04:13 PM
 A Text Size 
UC Riverside students Chris Watkins and Deandre Fahie took their first ride in an electric car this week and got a free dinner to boot.

They were among hundreds of UCR students who lined up Wednesday night to take a ride in a Chevrolet to the fast-food restaurant of their choice — in their case, it was a Chevy Volt to Carl’s Jr. — as part of a statewide marketing campaign intended to introduce the brand to the next generation of car buyers.

“It’s just a great way for us to establish a relationship right at the outset,” said Dave Barthmuss, a communications manager for General Motors in the western region.

Chevy launched the Drive-Thru Finals program last year, and it has traveled to seven California campuses so far. About 4,000 students have been fed.

At UCR, students got to pick from several models, including the Camaro and Terrain, the Cruze Eco and electric Volt. At the restaurant, students order what they want, and Chevy drivers pay the cost, up to $8 or so per person. Students are equipped with a Flip camera they can use to shoot videos to post online.

Back on campus, they get a packet of school supplies and use of a photo booth where they can take pictures to post on social media sites.

Barthmuss said the campus events are a no-pressure way to get future buyers in seats and to build awareness of the brand, along with a sense of fun. “You’ve got to do things different. We have to humanize our company and make people feel good about shopping in a Chevrolet or a Buick or a GMC dealership,” he said.

That’s a much bigger challenge in California, where buyers have long gravitated toward import brands, than in places like the Midwest, where domestic cars are the norm, Barthmuss said. “We’ve lost so many generations of buyers here.”

Watkins and Fahie, both 20, said they got word of the event on Facebook and came out for the free food. They hopped into the Volt at random, but once inside they peppered the driver with questions about range and speed and price.

Along the way, Watkins picked up the camera and began to film, narrating the scene and lobbing mock-interview questions back and forth with his friend. Asked by Fahie whether he plans to purchase a Volt, Watkins said, “I am a broke college student, so no, I will not.”

Chevy gave rides to about 475 students Wednesday, a one-day record for the campaign. A second round was scheduled for Thursday night.

Derek Roberts, a fourth-year student and senator for the Associated Students of the University of California, Riverside, said he wasn’t surprised by the turnout, given the free food and substantial promotion by the student-government group.

The ASUCR helped coordinate the program on campus, sending Facebook invites and emails and handing out fliers on campus. Barthmuss said Chevy works with student government groups at each school to avoid being perceived as “big bad corporate America coming to campus to market to students.”

Jessica Caldwell, senior analyst for Edmunds.com, said Chevy has made a significant investment in the small-car market with its new Cruze and Eco models, and a smaller Spark on the way. With its budget-friendly pricing, that’s a market that tends to skew young.

The Cruze has sold well since its introduction last year, but a lot of young California consumers are unfamiliar with Chevy vehicles, and California is the largest car market in the U.S., Caldwell said.

If Chevy is looking to expand, this is the place to do it, “not (with) baby boomers in the Midwest; they already have that market.”
 Comments PE.com is now using Facebook Comments. Comments are subject to Facebook&apos;s Privacy Policy and Terms of Service on data use. If you don&apos;t want your comment to appear on Facebook, uncheck the &apos;Post to Facebook&apos; box. To find out more, read the FAQ . Copyright 2011 The Press Enterprise. All rights reserve. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Business Headlines 
 RIVERSIDE: Hard Hat Bid gives shareholders two choices 
 
 REAL ESTATE: San Bernardino bankruptcy linked to foreclosure 
 
 REAL ESTATE: California leads nation in foreclosure activity for first time since ‘05 
 
 FOOD: Technology helps limit drought losses 
 Follow Us Your Photos 
Want to contribute?

 View photos | Submit photos 
 Search Events Events Restaurants Movies Venues 
 
   What When Where Within Miles   
 
   What Price Range Any $0-$14 $15-$30 $30-$50 $50+ Where Within Miles   
 
   Movies When Where Within Miles   
 
   What Where Within Miles   
 
 Most Popular 
 Most Read 
 
 MORENO VALLEY: Motorcyclist killed in crash with unlicensed driver 
 LOS ANGELES: Riverside county girl rescued in sex trafficking 
 UPDATE: ‘Kidnapped’ Perris woman found safe 
 S.B. BANKRUPTCY: Police and Fire chiefs vow to protect city 
 SAN BERNARDINO: New officials discovered financial mess 
 Most Commented 
 
 Most Recommended 
 
 View More Jobs 
 If you see this, your Javascript is off. 
MAINTENANCE MECHANIC

Galassos Bakery

Has an opening for a maintenance mechanic. Knowledge of PLC preferred. Qualified candidates please send resume: 10820 San Sevaine Way, Mira Loma, 91752 - EOE - Fax: (951) 685-9586
 
ADVERTISING MANAGER

ICSN, Inc.

Responsible for all aspects of co&apos;s advertising, etc. REQ: BA in Communications (Advertising);&amp;must have taken &quot;Ad&amp;Brand Comm Mgmt&quot;&amp;&quot;Internet Ad&amp;Promotion Comm&quot; courses.
SUBMIT RESUME TO:
ICSN, Inc.
Attn: Mr. Kenny Kim
1826 Pomona Road
Corona, CA 92880
 
GENERAL

Company Confidential

F/T AR CLERK W/STRONG DATA ENTRY AND MS OFFICE, INT. EXCEL EXP. DUTIES BILLING/COLLECTIONS/RECON./MAINT. CUST ACCTS. EMAIL RESUMES TO CLERKRESUME2012
@GMAIL.COM
 
LEAD GROUNDS PERSON

Plymouth Village

FT benefitted position to direct and work beside team on 37 acre retirement campus. Must have extensive knowledge of plants, landscaping, cultivating lawns, pruning trees and shrubs. Prefer 3-5 yrs exp with grounds inc. supervisory knowledge. Plymouth Village 900 Salem Dr, Redlands CA 92373 909-793-1233, fax 909- 255-7520
 
RN

Plymouth Village

2 full-time positions, to work in a skilled nursing environment. Must have current CA license, prefer 1-2 yrs exp. in long-term care, strong in med.administration and customer service. Some weekends required. Benefits include med/dental/vision/ annually receive 2 week vac and 11 pd holidays. Plymouth Village 900 Salem Dr, Redlands CA 92373 909-793-1233, fax 909- 255-7520
 
 ELECTRICAL PROJECT MANAGER 

Stronghold Engineering

Are you an experienced Electrical Project Manager looking for an opportunity to reach a new level of success?
 
RESTAURANT

Lone Star Steakhouse

Become a LEGEND with us!
We are looking for the very best&amp;talented people to staff our new restaurant.
If you are passionate about food&amp;great customer service, we would like to invite you to apply for an exciting opportunity in a fast paced environment.
Now Interviewing Servers, Hosts/Hostesses, Line Cooks&amp;Bartenders.
If you are interested in these great opportunities, please
APPLY IN PERSON!
On-site interviews
Wed. - Fri. 9am-5pm
Lone Star Steakhouse
18601 Dexter Ave.
Lake Elsinore, CA 92532
EOE
 
ALL POSITIONS

New American Funding

Mortgage Banker Opening 80,000 square foot facility next to MetroLink Station.
Now Hiring All Positions!
Loan Officers • Processors • Underwriters • Funders • Production Assistants • Post Closing • Wholesale Account Managers • Wholesale Jr. Account Managers • Wholesale Account Executives • Wholesale Set Up Coordinators • Wholesale Doc Drawers • QC Auditors • Compliance Managers • Sales Trainer • Executive Assistants • Administrative Assistants • Marketing Coordinator • Graphics Designer • HR Assistant • Programmers
Call 877-478-5476 for more information or email your resume to: resumes@nafinc.com 
 
CONSTRUCTION

Company Confidential

Temecula Valley area Construction Mgr/GC looking for Architectural Construction Administrator. Duties include working w/Precon Dept. interacting w/owner and owners reps, maintain and/or build detailed project schedules, QC of drawings&amp;specs, estimating; scopes of work, etc. Some training provided, however solid Construction Mgmt or Arch. Admin. background req’d. Field experience a plus! Excellent salary and benefits. Send resumes w/history&amp;references to: recruitingad30@gmail.com 
 
Featured Business
 
 Riverside Yellow Pages 
 
 Home About Us Site Map Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms Advertising Solutions PE Careers 
 ©2012, Enterprise Media. All Rights Reserved •3450 Fourteenth Street, Riverside, California 92501 Powered by the Parse.ly Publisher Platform (P3).
	</body>
</document>
