<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007317" url="http://thestir.cafemom.com/food_party/124609/the_real_reason_americans_love" time="2012-07-13-00:17" support="28" score="0.030132872695803038" bingtitle="The Real Reason Americans Love Their Drinks With Ice | The Stir" webtitle="The Real Reason Americans Love Their Drinks With Ice | The Stir">
			<query id="001056" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001338" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000304" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001465" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000773" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000210" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001024" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000775" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="110"/>
	<description>... and I&apos;ve had a LOT that say &quot;well I cant fill your cup ... I also don&apos;t do it at any fast food restaurant because of a sciece ... Day Jobs: Because Looking for Love Doesn&apos;t Pay ...</description>
	<body>
		Cafemom 
 Mom Groups&amp;Conversations Videos for Moms The Stir 

 Log In Join Now 
 The Stir 
 Pregnancy Baby Toddler Big Kid Teen Food &amp; Party Healthy Living Love &amp; Sex In The News 

 Entertainment Sports Technology Beauty &amp; Style Home &amp; Garden Writers Columns 
 Search Cafemom&apos;s The Stir 
 Facebook Twitter Pintrest YouTube RSS 
 BUZZING Giveaways Moms Matter 2012 Recipe a Day Summer Family Fun More 
 How Your Astrological Sign Can Help Plan Your Vacation Suri&apos;s Scientology Childhood Sounds Kind of Awesome One Simple Way to Lose Weight Must See: Mom Gives Baby Yucky Peas (VIDEO) These Couples Would Make &apos;50 Shades of Grey&apos; Even Hotter (PHOTOS) Is This Republican Protest of Michelle Obama Racist? 15 Things I Would Tell My 15-Year-Old Self Natural Remedies for Migraines (VIDEO) 20 Most Bizarre Celebrity Aliases 9 Things Not to Say to a Vegetarian 52 Wackiest Celeb Baby Names of All Time Adorable&amp;Delicious Watermelon Cupcakes 7 Most Annoying Internet Sensations (VIDEO) 5 Cheap Ways to Fight Cellulite Reality Show About Extended Breastfeeding: Good Idea? 
 
 Food &amp; Party 
 
The Real Reason Americans Love Their Drinks With Ice
 Posted by Adriana Velez on August 16, 2011 at 5:39 PM 
 Comments (23) | Likes (4) 
 
 I read a funny piece in The New York Times recently about how Russians don&apos;t like ice in their drinks -- but I thought the same thing that another blogger thought: It&apos;s not them; it&apos;s us. Americans are unique in our obsession with ice. Travel just about anywhere else in the world and you rarely see people fill a glass with it.

So what&apos;s the deal? Why do Americans love drinks with ice so much? There are a few theories out there, but I think I&apos;ve zeroed in on the main reason, and it has to do with our kitchens.

It&apos;s our refrigerators! In general, American houses are larger than houses in other places, including Europe. Which means we have larger kitchens . Which means we have room for hulking mega-sized refrigerators that make and dispense ice cubes. 

When it comes to appliances, America is the country of More Is More. A larger, separate compartment for frozen foods? Our idea, 1940s. Chilled water dispenser and ice-maker? Our baby, 1970s. Those ice dispensers have become standard, which means if you CAN fill a glass with ice before pouring in a drink, of course you&apos;re going to, because it&apos;s a big, hot country filled with deserts and swamps. And because there&apos;s a seemingly endless supply of cubes coming from the magic ice maker. You fill a glass with ice cubes and the darn thing just makes more!

Meanwhile, people elsewhere in the world, if they have a refrigerator, they have a 25-incher with maybe a small freezer compartment. Maybe you&apos;ll keep a couple of ice cube trays in there (which you&apos;ll have to carefully ration). Or maybe you&apos;ll skip the ice cube trays altogether and keep ice cream in there because ice cream is more delicious than ice.

How do I know this? I live in, shall we say, a European-sized apartment in the city with 25 inches for a refrigerator. Our refrigerator is nearing the end of its life, so I&apos;ve been checking out new ones -- and guess what? Little fridges are not so plentiful in the U.S., and they definitely don&apos;t come with ice dispensers. 

So enjoy that big glass full of ice. Fill&apos;er up for me.

 Do you like ice in your drinks? 

 
 

 Image via Andrew Mason /Flickr
 
 About the author Adriana Velez 
 is a staff writer who dabbles in food, parenting, news, entertainment, molecular biology, and anything else that that pops into her head. She lives with her husband and elementary school-aged son in Brooklyn, land of urban farms and artisan everything.  
 More Filed Under: drinks , kitchen products 
 Comments (23) | Likes (4) 
 Extra Sugar 
 
Featured Videos

 After Losing Her Hair to Chemo,... Sex Myths Debunked World&apos;s Largest Strapless Bra Makes a... 5 Guys and a Breast Pump! 
 Tasty Treats from Our Partners Partner Headlines 
 Man Attempts to Abduct 7-Year-Old in Walmart (VIDEO) - Mommyish &quot;Real Housewives&quot; Surgery Revealed -- Before&amp;After Photos! - tooFab! Miley Cyrus: No Bra, No Pants, No Problem! (PHOTOS) - Wetpaint Robert Pattinson Describes Kristen in the Most Romantic Way - Zap2It Sammi Sweetheart Flaunts Hot Body In Super Short Dress (PHOTOS) - Wetpaint 
 ﻿ Add Comment 
Comments (23) 
 momtolittleg on Aug 16, 2011 at 5:53 PM 
I HATE ice! I typically request my drinks without it, unless it is ice water. I don&apos;t like the ice to melt and water down my drink. I even get my iced coffee without ice (yeah, they look at me a little funny). I also like that I get *more* drink for the same price when the ice isn&apos;t taking up all the room in the cup! If I do have ice (say, in sweet iced tea), I have to drink it with a straw. Ice touching my lips is one of those things that skeeves me out.
 Report this comment Peajewel on Aug 16, 2011 at 5:54 PM 
I do love ice. I put it in my drinks all the time.
 Report this comment buffalove23 on Aug 16, 2011 at 6:02 PM Hate ice unless its in water or iced tea/coffee. Report this comment PonyChaser on Aug 16, 2011 at 6:31 PM 
Love ice, even when I didn&apos;t have an ice maker (the first 15 years or so of our marriage). I stocked up on ice trays and kept a big bowl in the freezer. I&apos;d make it all the time to keep that bowl full, because my favorite thing to drink is ice water, and I&apos;m drinking it ALL the time. I think I&apos;d do it even if I lived in a place like yours... I did it when I lived in a dorm and had one of those cube-refrigerators!
 Report this comment cocobeannns on Aug 16, 2011 at 6:45 PM I like ice. I don&apos;t have a fancy refrigerator with an ice maker though, I&apos;m still rocking ice cube trays. I&apos;m a big ice water, and ice tea drinker. I like ice in my diet coke too, with a straw please. Report this comment Shell__Beach on Aug 16, 2011 at 6:50 PM 
I hate ice, always have. My fridge doesn&apos;t have an ice cube maker either.
 Report this comment Nonmember comment from Julianne on Aug 16, 2011 at 6:52 PM I like ice because I prefer my drinks very cold. Report this comment TC00 on Aug 16, 2011 at 7:37 PM 
I have sensitive teeth so I hate ice and always ask for my drinks with no ice. What irritates me to no end is when I ask for no ice I still get a huge glass of ice. I always hand the drink back and say I asked for no ice and usually they get mad and I&apos;ve had a LOT that say &quot;well I cant fill your cup up all the way if you want it without ice&quot;.......I shouldn&apos;t have to explain I dont ask for no ice to get more drink it&apos;s because my teeth can&apos;t handle really cold things.
 Report this comment fryshannon34 on Aug 16, 2011 at 8:06 PM 
I LOVE ice I cant have adrink without it
 Report this comment GlowWorm889 on Aug 16, 2011 at 8:21 PM 
I don&apos;t usually when I&apos;m at home. My ice hates me. Invariably, I get a chunk of ice that makes me spill my drink all down the front of my shirt. No matter how careful I am! I also don&apos;t do it at any fast food restaurant because of a sciece fair experiment a teenager did a few years ago that found the ice at her McDonald&apos;s had more bacteria in it than the toilet water. Yeah...yuck.
 Report this comment 1-10 of 23 comments 1 2 3 next Last Add a Comment To leave a comment on this story, please log in with: 
 FACEBOOK CafeMom GUEST 
 
Leave your comment below. When you click &quot;Submit&quot;, you will be prompted to log in to Facebook to continue. After logging in to Facebook, your comment will appear on The Stir with your first name, last name, and Facebook avatar.
 Your Comment Comment As a Guest 
Guest comments are moderated and will not appear immediately.
 Your Name: Your Email Address: Your Blog URL (Optional): Your Comment Use Your CafeMom Profile 
 Join CafeMom or Log in to your CafeMom account. CafeMom members can keep track of their comments.
 Your Comment you are logged in as (logout) Submitting comment, please wait... 
 Sign Up for The Stir Daily Ten Newsletter
 
You&apos;ve signed up for The Stir Daily Ten! Look for it in your inbox each evening.
 Please enter a valid email address. 
 Piping Hot Posts Buzz in Comments 
 
 Finally, Perfect &apos;Christian Grey&apos; Emerges for the &apos;50 Shades&apos; Movie Role Kate Middleton’s ‘Rotten’ Teeth Reveal the Secret Behind Her Smile Baby Falls Into Washing Machine Full of Scalding Water Katie Holmes Might Seriously Regret Changing Suri&apos;s Last Name (VIDEO) 6-Year-Old&apos;s Suggestive &apos;Booty Pop&apos; Rap Video Goes Viral&amp;Parents Go... &apos;Real Housewives of Orange County&apos; Heads May Roll Man Arrested for Enslaving Wife in Chains for 10 Years Creepy Grandmother Caught Breastfeeding Her Newborn Grandson Lesson 37: An Open Letter to Teenagers Wanting Babies &apos;Bachelorette&apos; Emily Maynard Should Run for Her Life if Jef Is Really Mormon 
 
 haha wow never read the book but this was really funny! I hate books like th... When my grandfather died we were at the funeral home for visitation all day.... the &quot;but i can change him&quot; is my biggest problem with the book. I will not even go into exactly what I think of this piece of...er...literat... Look at me!!! I&apos;m so brave!!! And edgy and LIBERAL. Maybe if I blog my abort... This is great. I wonder what power scooter does she have. Its good to know... Mitt&apos;s Lie of the Day: 
http://www.boston.com/news/politics/articles/2012... Hopefully they will make this as well known and publicized as they would if ... This is crazy, who the fuck changes their babies diaper on the washing machi... Very disturbing! He&apos;s a sick freak, not a man, nor a father. Good thing he&apos;s... 
 
Video Picks
 previous 1 of 27 next 
 After Losing Her Hair to Chemo, Joanna is Bald and Proud It&apos;s Cancer, Baby play play Sex Myths Debunked Mom-Ed: In the Bedroom play World&apos;s Largest Strapless Bra Makes a BIG impact! The Daily Stir play 5 Guys and a Breast Pump! Mom vs Man play A Day at the Museum with Her Two Moms Mya and Her Moms play Kim Kardashian Attacked by a Giant Flower! The Daily Stir play Sarah&apos;s 5 Minute Makeup Routine! The Sarah James Show play Kristen Stewart and Robert Patinson in Fifty Shades of Grey? The Daily Stir play JoAnn&apos;s House Cleaning Tips! JoAnn from Bensonhurst play Are Scientologists Stalking Katie Holmes? The Daily Stir play My Baby was Born by Vacuum Extraction Birth Stories play Dance Like a Bollywood Star! I&apos;ll Take that Dare! play Unable to Breastfeed, Joanna found a Lactation Goddess It&apos;s Cancer, Baby play Sex Diaries of a New Dad Mom-Ed: In the Bedroom play Does Justin Bieber Have Marriage Plans? The Daily Stir play School Project Face-Off! Mom vs Man play With Two Moms, Who Wears the Pants? Mya and Her Moms play Kesha&apos;s 50 Shades of Gray Inspired Tattoo? The Daily Stir play Relax, Destress, Take Time for You! The Sarah James Show play Tom Cruise Divorce Meltdown! Week&apos;s Best Videos! The Daily Stir play What to do With Illegal Immigrants JoAnn from Bensonhurst play Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes are Splitsville The Daily Stir play After 3 Days of Labor My Husband Wanted a Burrito! Birth Stories play Take a Flying Trapeze Lesson! I&apos;ll Take that Dare! play Mark Holds his Wife&apos;s Hand through Chemotherapy It&apos;s Cancer, Baby play Recharge Your Sex Life After Kids Mom-Ed: In the Bedroom play Eat Like an Olympian! The Daily Stir 
 All Our Shows 
Featured Contributors
 previous next 
 
 Linda Sharps 
 Parents Who Need Social Media to Name Their Baby Are in Serious Trouble 
 Gabrielle Blair 

Inspiration Scout
 Step Inside This Happy Nursery Full of Punchy Colors&amp;Fun Treasures 
 Lindsay Ferrier 

Behind the Vote
 Are Corporations People? 

 
 Jenny Lawson 

Ill-Advised
 Lesson 37: An Open Letter to Teenagers Wanting Babies 
 Jill Smokler 

Countdown With Scary Mommy
 15 Things I Would Tell My 15-Year-Old Self 
 Janelle Harris 
 5 Signs You&apos;re Just Desperate for a Man 

 
 Aunt Becky 
 8 Great Ways to Arouse a Woman 
 Deborah Cruz 
 Public School Puts Boys&amp;Girls Into Different Classrooms 
 All Our Writers 
Slideshows
 
 Celebrity Sugar Daddies 9 Celebs With the Worst... Sexiest Words Robert Pa... 5 Life-Changing Beauty ... Avoid &apos;Cankles&apos; in Thes... Most Stylish Celeb Tots... 
 
Comment Overload
 previous 1 of 14 next 
 
Woman Blogs Her Abortion So the World Can See the Truth
 138 
Creepy Grandmother Caught Breastfeeding Her Newborn Grandson
 107 
Dad Leaves Baby to Die in Hot Car&amp;It Could Happen to Anyone
 55 
Mitt Romney Has a Swiss Bank Account (Gasp!)
 53 
Finally, Perfect &apos;Christian Grey&apos; Emerges for the &apos;50 Shades&apos; Movie Role
 48 
Obamacare Will Make Doctor Shortage Even Worse
 36 
2 Million Families Could Go Hungry Soon, Thanks to Congress
 35 
Baby Falls Into Washing Machine Full of Scalding Water
 28 
&apos;Real Housewives of Orange County&apos; Heads May Roll
 27 
Mom Who Left Disabled Daughter at a Bar Was Doing Her Best
 24 
&apos;Bachelorette&apos; Emily Maynard Should Run for Her Life if Jef Is Really Mormon
 22 
6 Celebrity Couples Who Would Make &apos;50 Shades of Grey&apos; Movie Even Hotter (PHOTOS)
 20 
Suri Cruise&apos;s Scientology Childhood Sounds Kind of Awesome
 19 
Lesson 37: An Open Letter to Teenagers Wanting Babies
 19 
 
From Our Partners
 
 Jessica Biel Shows Off Massive Engagement Ring at ESPY Awards! Jennifer Lopez on&quot;Idol&quot;:&quot;I Am Thinking It&apos;s Time For Me To Go&quot; Hayden Panettiere, Maria Sharapova Stun at ESPY Awards 
 
 How Important Is Kissing Compatibility? [EXPERT] Mick Jagger Was Obsessed With Angelina Jolie For Two Years Photos: Sexy Stars Dominate The ESPY Awards Red Carpet 
 
 Rookie Blue Recap: Season 3 Episode 6 ‘Coming Home’ 7/12/12 New Kate Middleton Anorexic Rumors Force Palace To Bury Honeymoon Photos Check Out Tom Cruise’s Leading Lady Olga Kurylenko (Photos) 
 
 Get more of The Stir

 facebook twitter pinterest youtube rss 
   
 Vicki Gunvalson on Boyfriend Brooks Ayers:“I’m Not Settling” Cheryl Burke Names Which Athletes She Wants to See on Dancing With the Stars Grey&apos;s Anatomy Season 9 Speculation: What Will Happen to Richard? 
 
 A Modern Minnie Mouse Birthday Party A Hawaiian Adventure Without Leaving Home: Turkey Pineapple Meatballs 102 Indoor Activities For Rainy Summer Days 
 
 &apos;Hollywood Exes&apos;: A place for nice girls in reality TV? Comic-Con 2012: Keep up even if you can&apos;t make it Comic-Con 2012: Kristen Stewart tells Stephenie Meyer she would do another &apos;Twilight&apos; film 
 
 Evening Feeding: Don’t Ignore Your Kids To Text And Email Sorry Gossip Peddlers, Seal Wasn’t Partying In His Hotel While The Kids Slept A New York Nanny’s Thoughts on Beverly Hills Nannies 
 
 Steven Tyler Leaving American Idol Taylor Swift Highest-Paid Young Celeb 47 Years Later, Dylan&apos;s Iconic Electric Guitar May Have Surfaced 
 the Stir - a cafemom blog 
 About The Stir Contact Us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Mobile Version 

©2012 CMI Marketing Inc. All rights reserved.
 X Welcome to The Stir. It&apos;s easy to keep in touch with us: &quot;Like&quot; us on Facebook Receive our Hottest Stories Daily Subscribe to our Daily Newsletter 
 
You&apos;ve signed up for The Stir Daily Ten! Look for it in your inbox each evening.
 Please enter a valid email address.
	</body>
</document>
