<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007515" url="http://www.myencinitas.com/north-san-diego-county-community-news_4723/" time="2012-07-13-00:29" support="4" score="0.0033984109761766297" bingtitle="North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car show to honor …" webtitle="North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car show to honor">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car ... drugs and uses a 12-step recovery program to change ... Fast-food restaurant robbed; Feds Seek Source Of Encinitas Ocean ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 
North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car show to honor…
 
North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car show to honor…

North County Times–Escondido,CA,USA
ENCINITAS—San Dieguito Adult School will host its third annual
Job Fair from 6:30 to 8 pm May 23 at Oak Crest Middle School, 675 Balour
Drive.…

ESCONDIDO—The American Heritage Car Show will take place from 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. May 26 at Grape Day Park, with parking on the grass. The show, organized by and benefiting the Escondido History Center, will feature hundreds of domestic and imported pre-1974 vintage, classic, muscle and hot rod cars.

The event also will include music, awards, a raffle, vendors, pancake breakfast, tours of the museum and a display of new vehicles from sponsors Mercedes-Benz of Escondido and Toyota of Escondido.

This year, the car show will honor Escondido racing legend Ted Cyr, two-time National Hot Rod Association champion. Cyr held numerous mile records driving both gas- and nitro-burning dragsters and was also known as an innovative builder.

Admission is free for spectators. Information: (760) 743-4382, http://www.escondidohistory.org.

‘Desert Poets’reading set for June 3

ESCONDIDO—Poets Inc. and the Escondido Arts Partnership will host a“Desert Poets”reading featuring Lori Davis and Ruth Nolan at 1 p.m. June 3 at the Municipal Gallery, 142 W. Grand Ave. The free event is part of the new First Sunday Literary Events Series. A reading or writing workshop will be held the first Sunday of every month (except May).

A reception for the featured readers will be held at 12:30 p.m., followed by the reading at 1. An open mike opportunity will follow the featured readers. Information: (760) 480-4101.

Vision-impaired can remain independent

ESCONDIDO—The Braille Institute will offer a free program for people with fading vision from 10 to 11 a.m. Mondays, from June 4 through July 24, at The Springs of Escondido, 1261 E. Washington Ave. The program is designed to teach people how to remain independent despite loss of vision. For information or to sign up, call Vicki Zimmerman-Fox at (858) 452-1111, Ext. 5033.

Square dance lessons to begin

ESCONDIDO—Square dance lessons will be held at 6:30 p.m. Mondays, starting June 4 and continuing for 17 weeks, at the Joslyn Senior Center, 210 Park Ave. Registration closes after June 11. Singles are welcome. For information, call (760) 728-0355.

Seniors offered trip to Las Vegas

ESCONDIDO—The Joslyn Senior Center Travel Office is offering a trip to Las Vegas from June 19 through 21. A few double-occupancy rooms are still available; no singles available.

Cost of $125 per person includes deluxe motor transportation, lodging at the Golden Nugget, one free meal, luggage handling and all gratuities. Call (760) 745-5414 or stop by the senior center at 210 Park Ave.

Toastmasters club meets Tuesdays

ESCONDIDO—The Felicita Humor Toastmasters Club meets from 7 to 8:30 p.m. Tuesdays at the Cypress Court retirement facility, 1255 N. Broadway.

Drop in and see how easy it can be to increase speaking skills and opportunities in a small, comfortable and supportive club. Information: CJ Conard, (760) 522-6570.

Hemophilia Association golf tourney on tap

SAN DIEGO—The Hemophilia Association of San Diego County will hold its 14th annual golf tournament at noon June 14 at the Sycuan Resort to help raise funds for hemophilia and other chronic bleeding disorders. Foursome and single golf packages are available, as well as corporate sponsorship and donor opportunities. For information, call (619) 325-3570.

Easter Seals annual fundraising walk set

CHULA VISTA—Easter Seals Southern California Disability Services will hold its fifth annual“Walk With Me”3K family fundraising walk at 9 a.m. June 16 at Knott’s Soak City. Proceeds will support services for people with disabilities such as autism, Down syndrome and cerebral palsy.

Channel 8 news anchorwoman Kathleen Bade will host the event that will feature refreshments and a pre-walk warm-up with a disc jockey spinning tunes.

Registration and information: http://www.walkwithme.org; Debbie Ball, (760) 737-3990, Ext. 83.

Young surfers can learn sport from pros

SAN DIEGO—Teen shark attack survivor Bethany Hamilton and other professional surfers will share their love of surfing with kids this summer. Walking On Water, a nonprofit Christian organization founded by professional surfer and native San Diego Bryan Jennings in 1995, will host surf camps where youths can learn the sport of surfing from their favorite top pro surfers.

Walking On Water Dream Surf Camps are open to male and female students between the ages of 11 and 18. Campers will stay in dorms at UC San Diego. For information and registration, go to http://www.walkingonwater.org or call (858) 509-7977.

American Red Cross seeks local heroes

SAN DIEGO—The American Red Cross is accepting nominations from San Diego and Imperial county residents, companies and media for the 2007 Real Heroes Breakfast scheduled for Oct. 5 at the Town and Country Resort and Convention Center.

The American Red Cross will host the breakfast to honor individuals in 11 categories who have taken action in a time of crisis to help others and show extraordinary human compassion.

Nominations can be submitted for any heroic act that occurred between July 1, 2006, and June 30, 2007. Send to http://www.sdarc.org/realheroes or, for a nomination form, call (858) 309-1212. Deadline for nominations is July 13.

EHS to hold 45-year reunion

ESCONDIDO—The Escondido High School class of 1967 will hold its 45-year reunion Aug. 10, 11 and 12. For information, contact J’lene Settles Harrison at 503 E. Ninth Ave., Escondido, CA 92025; jlene@cox.net; or http://members.cox.net/euhs-1967.

Adult school Job Fair set

ENCINITAS—San Dieguito Adult School will host its third annual Job Fair from 6:30 to 8 p.m. May 23 at Oak Crest Middle School, 675 Balour Drive. Representatives from more than 20 businesses will interview potential employees. For more information, call (760) 753-7073.

Toastmasters meets Thursdays

ENCINITAS—The Encinitas Toastmasters meets at 7 p.m. Thursdays at the Atria Retirement Center, 504 S. El Camino Real. The group’s mission is to assist others in improving his or her public speaking skills. Call Tandi South at (760) 271-5812 or visit the Web site at http://encinitastoastmasters.org.

Senior legal services offered

ENCINITAS—Del Mar Community Connections offers many legal services (advanced healthcare directive, power of attorney, wills, and more) free for seniors 60 and older in the 92014 ZIP code area. Private consultations with attorney from Elder Law&amp;Advocacy are offered, by appointment only. To reserve a spot, call (858) 792-7565.

Cuvee hosts Jazz group

DEL MAR—The Del Mar Jazz Trio will perform from 6 to 9 p.m. May 24 at Cuvee Wine Country Cuisine, 2334 Carmel Valley Road. Call (858) 259-5878.

Seniors learn to make chocolate

ENCINITAS—The hands-on candy making class Chocolate Candymaking for Seniors will introduce seniors to melting chocolate and the basic fundamentals of chocolate dipping from 1 to 3 p.m. June 6 at the Encinitas Senior Center, 1140 Oakcrest Park Drive. Cost is $20, which includes all supplies. Call (760) 943-2250.

Ballroom dance for seniors

ENCINITAS–Learn the basic dance steps, how to lead and how to follow during the Ballroom Dance for Seniors class at 1:30 p.m. June 6 at the Encinitas Senior Center, 1140 Oakcrest Park Drive. The beginner class offers a rotating partner system so no partner is required. Cost is $15. Call (760) 943-2250.

Center offers body conditioning for seniors

ENCINTAS—A total body workout emphasizing Pilates mat-work, yoga, floor barre, stretching, and strengthening will be offered during the Body Conditioning for Seniors class at 12:15 p.m. June 6 at the Encinitas Senior Center, 1140 Oakcrest Park Drive. Wear comfortable clothing and bring an exercise mat and a large towel to class. Cost is $15. Call (760) 943-2250.

Artist offers one-week ceramics classes

ENCINITAS—Artist Carla Funk will offer one-week ceramics art camp from June 18 through Aug.10 at a private home in Encinitas. Students will learn hand building with clay, pottery wheel, color mixing and painting, plus a mosaic project. Classes for age 6 to teens are from 9 a.m. to 12:15 p.m. Mondays through Fridays. Cost is $175. Classes for ages 4 and 5 will be held from 2:30 to 4 p.m. Mondays through Fridays. Cost is $90. Call Carla Funk at (760) 943-6313 or visit the Web site at http://www.arttilesbycarla.com.

Diet planning for seniors offered

CARLSBAD—Tri-City Hospital Medical Center dieticians will provide individual nutritional planning for seniors from 9:30 to 11:30 a.m. on the first and third Thursdays of the month at the Carlsbad Senior Center, 799 Pine Ave. Call (760) 602-4650.

Caregivers meet Wednesdays

CARLSBAD—Brighton Gardens will host the caregiver support group facilitated by licensed therapist and author Sandy Braff at 6 p.m. each first and third Wednesday at the facility’s second floor Country Kitchen, 3140 El Camino Real. Call (760) 720-9898.

Food addicts meet Mondays

CARLSBAD—Food Addicts Anonymous meets at 11 a.m. Mondays in Room 4 at St. Michael’s Church, 2775 Carlsbad Blvd. The group treats sugar, flour and wheat as substances that can be abused like alcohol or other drugs and uses a 12-step recovery program to change the way participants act, think and feel about food. Call Jack at (760) 433-0886 or visit the Web site at http://www.foodaddictsanonymous.org.

Senior center offers free day trips

CARLSBAD—The North County Transit District and the Carlsbad Senior Center have partnered to coordinate the Senior BREEZE Sprees. Trips will occur from approximately 10 a.m. to 2 p.m., but specific times vary. The campaign aims to teach seniors how to use the BREEZE bus system through free day trips, scheduled from several senior centers. Seniors who participate in a day trip, or a“spree,”through their senior center will enjoy a day out and about to a fun destination such as a mall or casino. The day trips will begin and end at the Carlsbad Senior Center, 799 Pine St., and will last approximately 4 hours. NCTD’s travel trainer will lead the group and answer questions along the way. Once on board the bus, the travel trainer will show first-hand how to purchase bus fare, read a rider’s guide, how to let the driver know when to stop the bus and more. Participants will learn all the ins and outs of riding the bus so as to take the fear out of the experience. Seniors from the Carlsbad Senior Center will visit the Westfield Plaza Camino Real Mall on May 23. Call (760) 966-6500 or visit the Web

site at http://www.goNCTD.com.

Newcomers meet at Heritage Hall

CARLSBAD—Carlsbad Newcomers will hold its monthly meeting at 10:15 a.m. June 6 at Heritage Hall, Magee Park, Garfield Street. Ted Owen, chief executive officer of the Carlsbad Chamber of Commerce, will share what is on the drawing boards for Carlsbad what is currently being constructed in the mall and downtown.

Lagoon center hosts birding workshops

CARLSBAD—Noted birding expert Barbara Moore (formerly education director of the Chula Vista Nature Center) will lead the nine-part comprehensive birding series from 9 a.m. to noon June 9 at the Agua Hedionda Lagoon Discovery Center, 1580 Cannon Road. There are nearly 500 species of birds in San Diego County, and this workshop will provide an overview of many of them including water birds, land birds and perching birds. Topics will include behavior and habitat, shape and posture, color and pattern, and beak variety and function. There will be extensive handouts, videos and field trips. Additional workshops will offered from 9 a.m. to noon Saturdays through Aug. 4. Cost is $50 for members, $75 nonmembers. Reservations are required. Call (760) 804-1969.

Performing Arts honors volunteers

SAN DIEGO—The San Diego Performing Arts League’s Annual Tribute to Volunteers in the Arts will be held from 6 to 9 p.m. June 12 at the San Diego Marriott Hotel and Marina, 385 W. Harbor Drive. Star Awards will honor more than 70 of the 20,000 arts volunteers who work behind the scenes for San Diego arts and cultural organizations. Call (619) 238-0700, e-mail starawards@sdpal.com, or visit the Web site at http://www.sandiegoperforms.com.

Donations of formal wear needed

RANCHO PENASQUITOS—Westview High School is seeking donations of gently-used formal wear (dresses, purses, shoes and jewelry) for its upcoming prom shopping event.

Operation Fairy Wolverine is scheduled from 3:30 to 5:30 p.m. May 24 in the Dance Room on the Westview campus, 13500 Camino del Sur. All high school girls with school identification are invited to shop for their prom dresses and accessories at low prices. Dresses will cost $10 and shoes, purses and accessories will be $5.

Bring formal wear donations to the Westview High School front desk by May 23. For information, call Westview ASB Adviser Laurie Norcross at (858) 780-2000, Ext. 3268.

Dog adoption event planned

RANCHO BERNARDO—The Foundation for the Care of Indigent Animals, a nonprofit pet rescue organization specializing in small dogs, will hold a dog adoption event from 10:30 a.m. to 1:30 p.m. May 26 at Kahoots Animals and Supplies, 11965 Bernardo Plaza Drive. For information, call (619) 466-0426.

Card making class offered

POWAY—Lynell Harlow will teach a“Memories Mists and Black Embossing Paste”card making class from 10 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. and again from 1:30 to 4 p.m. May 27 at Stamping Details, 14009 Midland Road.

Students can learn simple techniques for creating collage stenciled cards using Memories Mists ink sprays and highlighting with matte black embossing paste.

Cost of $30 includes all class supplies. Information: http://www.stampingdetails.com or (858) 513-8024.

RB Woman’s Club to meet

RANCHO BERNARDO—The Rancho Bernardo Woman’s Club will hold a luncheon meeting June 7 at the Rancho Bernardo Inn, 17550 Bernardo Oaks Drive.

Social time will begin at 11:30 a.m. followed by lunch, the meeting and entertainment by the Hot Flashes Follies.

Cost is $22. Reservations are required by June 4. Call (858) 674-5941.

SM Lions seek new members

SAN MARCOS—The San Marcos Lions Club is looking for people to join its biweekly meetings. The Lions Club is a nonprofit service organization that provides an opportunity for its members to give something back to their communities. Lions are recognized worldwide for their service to the blind and visually impaired.

The San Marcos Lions Club meets from noon to 1 p.m. the first and third Thursdays of the month. For meeting location and information, call Ish Lopez at (760) 744-5203.

VFW plans dinner fundraiser

SAN MARCOS—Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 3795 and its Ladies Auxiliary will hold a fundraising dinner from 5 to 7 p.m. May 25 at the post, 212 W. Mission Road.

Dinner plates will include two tamales with rice and beans. Cost is $6 per person. Proceeds will help the post remain open.

Large parties are encouraged to make reservations. Call (760) 744-3795.

‘Concert in the Garden’set for May 26

SAN MARCOS—The city and the Rotary Club of San Marcos will host a concert by Southbound Jonny, a country music band, as part of their“Summer Concerts in the Gardens”series at 7:30 p.m. May 26 at Wood House in Woodland Park, 1148 Rock Springs Road.

Bring low-back beach chairs or blankets for picnic seating. Desserts and beverages will be available for purchase.

Tickets cost $5; free admission for children younger than 10. Tickets can be purchased at the door or in advance at the San Marcos Community Center, 3 Civic Center Drive. For information, call (760) 744-9000.

CEC offers enrichment lectures

RANCHO BERNARDO—The Continuing Education Center at Rancho Bernardo offers college-level, non-credit enrichment lectures on a variety of subjects.

Upcoming lectures include the following:

# Economic theorist Adam Smith will be the subject of a presentation by Dr. Vicki L. Golich’s at 1:30 p.m. May 23.

# Dick Streeper, author of the monthly RoseMan column in the San Diego Union-Tribune, will discuss“Care of Roses: Simple Steps for Robust Roses”at 1:30 p.m. May 24.

# In preparation for the forthcoming exhibit at the San Diego Natural History Museum, Dr. Russell Fuller will speak on“The Dead Sea Scrolls”at 10 a.m. May 29.

The CEC’s classrooms and office are at the Remington Club Phase II, 16916 Hierba Drive. Lecture fees are $7; $5 for members. Preregistration is preferred for all lectures.

Information and registration: (858) 487-0464, http://www.cecrb.org.

Scoliosis support group to meet

VISTA—The Scoliosis Association of San Diego will host a support group meeting at 2 p.m. May 26 in the Community Room at the Vista Library, 700 Eucalyptus Ave.

The meeting is open to anyone dealing with scoliosis or seeking information and support for a loved one. New information and handouts from the recent American Association of Orthopedic Surgeons conference in San Diego will be available.

Information: http://www.sdscoliosis.com or Jennifer, (619) 825-9332.

No LIFE meeting May 25

OCEANSIDE—LIFE a MiraCosta, a lifelong learning group, will not meet May 25 because of commencement at MiraCosta College. For future meeting information, call (760) 721-8124.

All-Class reunion slated at O’side park

OCEANSIDE—The Friends of Heritage Park Village Museum will sponsor its annual All-Class Reunion for Oceanside-Carlsbad Union High School, Oceanside High, the Junior Colleges, and Old Timers from 11 a.m. to 5 p.m. June 10 at Heritage Park, Peyri Road, N. Camino Real and Mission San Luis Rey. Call (760) 433-8297.

City offers summer camps

OCEANSIDE—The city of Oceanside Parks and Recreation Division has opened online registration for its summer 2007 day, specialty, and aquatic adventure camps. Camps begin June 18 and run for 10, one-week sessions through Aug. 24. Call (760) 435-5041. Surf camp and aquatic camps require successful completion and passing of a swim test prior to registration and online registration is not available for those camps. Call (760) 435-5225.

Senior center seeks vendors

OCEANSIDE—The Oceanside Senior Center is now accepting applications for booth space for the 10th annual Senior Citizens Day Expo from 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. Oct. 13 at the Oceanside Civic Center Plaza, 300 N. Coast Highway. The event, sponsored by the Neighborhood Services Department, Parks and Recreation Division and the Oceanside Senior Commission, will feature entertainment, senior provider information booths, crafts booths and great food. Call Maureen Fleming or Doug Moon at (760) 435-5250.

Park walk, health fair set

VISTA—The annual Park Walk and Health Information Fair will be held at 9 a.m. May 24 at the Gloria McClellan Senior Center, 1400 Vale Terrace Drive. All park walkers will receive free badge holders. A free continental breakfast will be held from 9 to 11 a.m. and the health fair will be held from 9 a.m. to noon. To have an exhibit or sponsor the fair, or for questions, contact Maureen Cooper at (760) 726-1340 or e-mail mcooper@cityofvista.com.

Nutritional planning offered to seniors

VISTA—A volunteer from Tri-City Medical Center will do individual nutritional planning for seniors from 9:30 to 11:30 a.m. on the second Thursday of each month in the conference room at the Gloria McClellan Senior Center, 1400 Vale Terrace Drive. To schedule an appointment, call Leisa at (760) 639-6162.

AARP safe driving program set

VISTA—The AARP Driver Safety Program, which teaches safe driving practices for seniors, will be held in two four-hour sessions from 12:30 to 4:30 p.m. May 29 and 31 at the Gloria McClellan Senior Center, 1400 Vale Terrace Drive. Cost is $10 to cover course materials. Reservations can be made by calling (760) 639-6160. Seniors who complete both sessions will receive a discount on their auto insurance premiums for a three-year period.

Knee pain seminar offered

OCEANSIDE—A free educational seminar on Treatment Options for Severe Knee Pain will be held from 4 to 5 p.m. May 31 in the French Room at Tri-City Medical Center, 4002 Vista Way. Speaker will be Dr. James Helgager. Find out about knee replacement, knees designed to bend and rotate, gender specific knees and rehabilitation and recovery. To R.S.V.P., call (800) 256-1146 or go to http://www.events.kneereplacement.com.

Vista clinic seeks volunteers

Vista Community Clinic needs assistance with administrative tasks in support of the medical records department at its Pier View Way and North River Road locations in Oceanside. The hours are flexible and there are no minimum hours required. Because the work is in a clinic setting, all volunteers must take a TB test, provided free by the clinic, or show proof of a TB test within the last 12 months. Information: (760) 631-1135, Ext. 1135, or sfichter@vistacommunity.

Clinic offers physical exams for children

Vista Community Clinic offers physical exams for children who will participate in summer sports, camps and activity programs. Costs start at $20. Exams are administered Monday through Friday at 1000 Vale Terrace Drive, Vista; 161 Thunder Drive, Suite 212, Vista; 818 Pier View Way, Oceanside; and 4700 North River Road, Oceanside. The Vale Terrace clinic also gives exams on Saturdays. To make an appointment, call (760) 631-5000.

Memorial Day service set

FALLBROOK—A Memorial Day service will take place beginning at 11 a.m. May 28 at the Masonic Cemetery on Santa Margarita Road about one mile from the East Mission Road intersection.

The program begins with the presentation of service flags of the Army, Marine Corps, Navy, Air Force and Coast Guard by the Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 1924 Color Guard, followed by the invocation by post Chaplain Dave Marvin.

The pledge of allegiance will be led by post Commander Mitch Chandler. Phyllis Bush will sing the national anthem, and the Fallbrook Chorale will provide music.

Guest speaker will be Gunnery Sgt. Nick Willoughby, who had two tours of duty in Iraq, and by special invitation, attended the Joint POW/MIA Accounting Command in Vietnam this year to recover the remains of fallen comrades from the Vietnam War.

The program will conclude with benediction by Marvin, followed by refreshments at the post at 1175 Old Stage Road.

Blood drive scheduled

FALLBROOK—The San Diego Blood Bank will sponsor a blood drive from 10 a.m. to 3 p.m. May 29 at Fallbrook Hospital, 624 E. Elder St. The bloodmobile will be parked in the parking lot.

Participants will have the opportunity to join the San Diego Blood Bank’s new Donor Difference program, which includes access to an on-line store for donors and the ability to track cholesterol, pulse and blood pressure after each donation.

Anyone who is at least 17 years old, in good health and weighs at least 110 pounds may be eligible to give blood. A good meal is recommended prior to donation.

For donor requirements or to make an appointment, call the San Diego Blood Bank at (800) or visit www.sandiegobloodbank.org.

Boys&amp;Girls Clubs sponsoring drawing

FALLBROOK—The Boys&amp;Girls Clubs of North County is offering an opportunity drawing to win $10,000 cash. Tickets are $100, and only 300 have been printed. Second prize is a flat screen TV and third prize is a laptop computer. Call (760) 728-5871 or visit www.bgcnorthcounty.com.

Running club continues to gather

FALLBROOK—The Fallbrook Running and Walking Club meets for the following events:

# Fun Walk and Run at 7:30 a.m. Saturdays starting from the parking lot behind the Fallbrook Library, with participants meeting for coffee afterward at the Farm House.

# Fun Walk and Run at 6:30 a.m. Sundays starting from the Pala Mesa Resort parking lot.

# Track Walk and Run at 6 p.m. Wednesdays at the Fallbrook High School track.

People of all ages and abilities are invited, and members are encouraged to strive to achieve a goal of 10,000 steps per day, which is the standard now generally accepted as the minimum activity necessary to maintain good health. They also are encouraged to bring friends and family members. For information, contact hammerin77@yahoo.com.

Investment club meets monthly

FALLBROOK—The Fallbrook Investment Club meets at 4 p.m. the second Monday of the month at the Fallbrook Public Utility District building, 990 E. Mission Road. For information, call Mary Lou Kollar, (760) 723-0480.
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
 
Recent Posts

 DSC_3304 Ultimate Ears and Switchfoot Bro-Am 2011 Part 1 Nice Encinitas photos Nice Encinitas photos Cool Encinitas images Wavecrest Woodie Meet Encinitas chiropractor Cool Encinitas images Cool Encinitas images Riding the San Diego Coaster from Oceanside to San Diego–6/12/11 Cool Encinitas images Cool Encinitas images Nice Encinitas photos point break 9′6″classic style single fin surfing The Smoking Tooth, Part 1 of 3–Mercury Filling Removal Cool Encinitas images Do you See it? Cool Encinitas images 2–Tijuana Makes Me Happy–Nortec Collective Live @ Lou’s DSC_3557 Nice Encinitas photos IMG_0419.JPG Switchfoot–“Mess of Me”[HD] Surfer 9059 DSC03945 Saloon Cocktails Jim TV More ER Stone Steps Beach cardiff state beach chariots of fire? Root Canal Pain, Tooth and Facial Pain: San Diego Headache and Facial Pain Center Newcurb_1902 The Arnold Family DSC_3331 Nice Encinitas photos Nice Encinitas photos Moonlight Beach Surfer Krishna Das in Concert Cool Encinitas images Nice Encinitas photos 
 
Encinitas
 Select Category American Food Restaurant American Food Restaurants Bagel Bagels Bakery Bar Bar and Grill Barbecue Restaurant Barbecue Restaurants BBQ Restaurant BBQ Restaurants Beacon’s Beach bluff failure Brazilian Restaurant Brazilian Restaurants Breakfast Restaurant British Restaurant British Restaurants Burger Restaurant Burger Restaurants Cajun Restaurant Cajun Restaurants California Coastal Commission Californian Restaurant Californian Restaurants Casual Restaurant Casual Restaurants Chinese Restaurant Chinese Restaurants Coffee Coffee House Coffee Shop Continental Restaurant Continental Restaurants Creole Restaurant Creole Restaurants Deli Deli Restaurant Deli Restaurants Encinitas Encinitas Hotels Encinitas News Encinitas Photos Encinitas Post Office Encinitas Restaurant Encinitas Video English Restaurant English Restaurants Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant Fast Food Restaurants Fine Dining Fine Dining Restaurant Fine Dining Restaurants French Restaurant French Restaurants German Restaurant German Restaurants Greek Restaurant Greek Restaurants Grill Hawaiian Restaurant Hawaiian Restaurants Health Food Restaurant Health Food Restaurants Ice Cream Ice Cream Place Ice Cream Restaurant Ice Cream Restaurants Indian Restaurant Indian Restaurants Irish Restaurant Irish Restaurants Italian Restaurant Japanese Restaurant Japanese Restaurants Juice Bar Juice Bars Leucadia Marijuana Mediterranean Restaurant Mediterranean Restaurants Mexican Restaurant Mexican Restaurants Middle Eastern Restaurant Middle Eastern Restaurants Neptune Avenue oil spill Pizza Police Blotter Restaurant Restaurants Ribs Restaurant Ribs Restaurants San Dieguito Academy Sandwich Restaurant Sandwich Restaurants Seafood Restaurant Seafood Restaurants Sport’s Bar Restaurant Sport’s Bar Restaurants Sports Bar Steak House Steak House Restaurant Steak House Restaurants Sushi Restaurant Sushi Restaurants Swamis Tavern Turkish Restaurant Turkish Restaurants Uncategorized Vacation Rentals Vegetarian Restaurant Vegetarian Restaurants Vietnamese Restaurant Vietnamese Restaurants Volleyball Volleyball Magazine 
 
 
Pages

 101 x 1–A Roadtrip up California’s Coast Highway 10News Leadership Award Winner Karen Hesley 20/20 segment to feature local E. coli tragedy 2001 beach benefits short-lived 2007 Encinitas Open 2007–the year of Man Nipple 400000, or 31 percent, of local jobs have the potential to be… 96k Cardiff Plan unpopular A Great Restaurant Find in Leucadia A Massive Sideswipe Leaves Driver Critically Injured A Proliferation of the Devices A ride up the coast A Sea Change: Worries Over Rising Tide AB Seas: Part of proceeds from children’s surf book will go to… About About 920 North County Homes Without Power Saturday Accepting “What The Market Dictates” In California Adoption Event in Encinitas CA Sunday 6/3/07 11 AM to 2 PM Age-old game of bocce flourishes in Encinitas Agency explores quality-of-life tax Agenda Item#9 on tonight’s city council meeting Ailing surfer suing groups over Cardiff beach pollution Airport bus service could expand All beaches in Encinitas now safe for public use Amateur Smith skates like a pro: Up and coming Encinitas 12-year… An uncertain future Another fire breaks out in Oceanside riverbed Answers must go past Army Corps solution Anti-aging clinic in Encinitas opens a stem cell bank Antique cars rumble into Encinitas Appetizers in San Diego North County? Apple of their eyes Applications are many for Encinitas Planning Commission seat Aquatics jobs for lifeguards, swimming instructors, coaches, pool Arange Sandbags? Gee, thanks. Are we pushing teens behind the wheel? Arizona’s Chase Budinger Named US Bank Pac-10 Men’s Basketball… Armed Robbery In Encinitas Leaves Police Searching Art exhibit helps heal mind, body Ask LiveGreen / Tell LiveGreen AST Dew 2007 Free Flow Tour Award-Winning Artist Launches Brand, Inpeloto and Holds Fundraiser Bali Banking For The Future Bay Point, Pittsburg explore benefits, risks of annexation Beach Fuel Spill Part III Beach Fuel Spill Part III Beach-cottage chic is comfortable, feminine Beaches are likely to reopen Beacon’s Access is Top Priority of 40 Projects Beacon’s Beach Beacon’s Beach , Encinitas: fun in the surf Sunset–Find Articles Beacon’s Beach Leucadia State Beach Encinitas California Beacon’s Beach Leucadia State Beach Encinitas California Beacon’s Beach report criticized at meeting Beacon’s Beach Trail Access Beacon’s Roundabout Debuts BEACONS BEACH IN LEUCADIA ON N. SAN DIEGO COUNTY COAST BeaconsBeach.com–AboutUs Bells are ringing: Holiday concerts abound this Christmas seaon Beloved cypresses get fond farewell Benefit bash for diabetes research Beware the Children Bicyclist injured in Encinitas crash Bicyclists using bumpy Encinitas Boulevard will soon get relief Big Beach Closure Big M, Little M, What Begins With M? Bikini bed and breakfast Blog Feed Blue Light Special Blufftop in Encinitas Border Patrol Sweep, Encinitas california Breaking In Your Hiking Boots In San Diego Author: Richard Chapo… Breast-Feeding Campaign Sparks Debate In Maternity Wards Bro Deal Bro! Brothers Accused Of Running Pot Operation Plead Not Guilty Brunch at Le Papagayo Business News in Brief: Bank’s earnings up in 4Q Business News in Brief: Bank’s earnings up in 4Q But who else except for surfers would notice…? California Coastal Commission California Poinsettia Farm Digs In After Zoning Loss (Update1) Captain Ambiance at Leucadia Nights Car crashes into Encinitas business Cardiff horseman wins Grand Prix at dressage Cardiff rail area vs Leucadia rail area Cardiff sculpture will mark town’s love for surfing, art Cardiff superintendent to retire, focus on art dream Cardiff-by-the-sea restaurants/attractions Carlsbad Looks to Prevent Sewage Spills With High-Tech System Carlsbad panel to consider private school plan Carlsbad police chase speeding suspect into Encinitas Caroline Thompson resigns from Encinitas Planning Commission Carpetbagger Steve Aceti moves to Leucadia so he can run for… Cartoon America book signing scheduled Cause of Buena Vista sewage spill in Carlsbad being probed Challenges likely for Encinitas park plan Chamber insider gets Encinitas Planning Commission seat Chamber Notes–For the week of April 3-9 Chamber Notes: For the week of Dec.12-18 Changes Charities to benefit from wine festival Charter school offered new home at Ocean Knoll Elementary Charter school, district reportedly close to agreement Chien is inspired for final go-round Children With Deformites Receive Free Surgery Christmas 1989 I was sailing on board the Golden O… City backs plan to limit downtown to retail space City Council increases sewer, other rates City council meetings live on the internets? City Of Encinitas Statistics City to decide on Leucadia improvements this week Clean Energy Index founder does well at doing good Clean Water Program Flush with Cash CMR Welcomes OC/San Diego/Young Dem Contributor, Brian Van Riper Coast Guard investigating possible fuel spill near Encinitas Coast Hwy Billboard Hack Coastal cities are issued warning on condo-hotels Coastal Community News Briefs Coastal Community News Briefs: City offers surf classes Coastal Community news briefs: Library hosts yoga for seniors Coastal Community News: Historical society seeks volunteers Coastal cronyism Coastal Leucadia, their Highway or our Mainstreet? Coastal North County Community News: Solana Beach hosts tree… Coastal panel to weigh Encinitas vacation rentals Coastal Prep Arts Briefs Coastal Prep arts Briefs Coastal San Diego County Community News Briefs: Start Smart class… Coastal School News: Independent school plans meetings College choir delights Encinitas churchgoers Come Along It’s sunny and offshore this morning,… Community Media: Selected Clippings–05/20/07 Community news Community News Briefs: Polar plunge raises funds for Special Olympics CompUSA to close North County stores Condo-hotel delay to be considered Congressman Bilbray Pushing for Tough Immigration Reform Contaminted Beaches Possibly Reopen Sunday Cool weather keeps crowds away from beaches Correction: Van Haitsma reappointed Council OKs work on Leucadia Blvd. Council to consider road improvements Council to plunge into election on clean-water fee Council to tackle improvement plans Councilwoman’s libel suit over sign advances County Confirms Adult Cases Of Rare Blood Disease County to hold pet clinic Sunday Couple hurt in Encinitas motorcycle crash Court says Encinitas adult-business law is constitutional Crash blocks northbound I-5 in Carlsbad Crashes, closure mar North County commute Crossing Over to Cadmus-Pros and Cons Cult of the Sand People Curfew sweep nets 18 juveniles customers say the dumbest things Cypress tree wood to come back to Encinitas; ceremony to plant… Dalager Closing Family Tool Shop to Hunt Squirrels (?) Danny Davis on Nixon Day Trip with the Cuzâ€™ Dead Crow In Encinitas Tests Positive For West Nile Degree mills Del Mar council to consider water, sewer rate hikes Deputies nab burglar today in Encinitas Deputies, citizens corral escaped horses Destruct-o Developer Barratt American again sues Encinitas over fees Developer might pay for train quiet zone Developer proposes extra units at Encinitas subdivision Developer wins ruling on height of homes Developer’s fee offer short of Encinitas demands digihitch.com–On Beacon’s Beach, There’s A Mellow Mixture Of… Dim Forecast for Lighting Budget Do You Go to Farmers Markets? Documentaries present Iraq war in words of the troops Donations please- Encinitas Community Resource Center Downtown Encinitas Plan Downtown Encinitas project faces challenge Downtown Encinitas project won’t include short-term rentals Downtown Encinitas school site the topic of meeting Dozens comment on draft Ponto environmental report Dream-home class begins again Driscoll feels at home on Ranch Drive Thru Caribbean premiere hits La Paloma Theatre Driver of stolen car arrested after chase Driver sought in reported hit-and-run at restaurant Drug trafficking No.1 issue for gang task force Dudley scores 30 to lead BC to win E Street Cafe, Encinitas Ecke Breeds New Improved Poinsettia Elizabethan Desserts in Encinitas- YUM! Encinitas–Traffic Calming Intersections Make for Safer Pedestrian Crossings Encinitas 2006/2007 Encinitas 2XU Triathlon–May 20th Encinitas 2XU Triathlon–Results Encinitas actor enjoys the realism of his title role in‘Brooklyn Boy’ Encinitas announces top-10 list of projects Encinitas approves $10K for survey Encinitas approves 20 percent raise for city manager Encinitas approves budget adjustments Encinitas Approves Downtown Development Project Encinitas artist combines‘Organic Elements’in hometown exhibit Encinitas artist receives 2007 stART Up Award Encinitas backs plan to limit downtown to retail space Encinitas backs proposal to keep downtown a retail district Encinitas banner pulled for singling out politician:‘Demon of a… Encinitas beaches shut down as fuel spill reaches shore Encinitas behind the curve in broadcasting, Webcasting Encinitas board questions TIP Academy’s finances Encinitas burglary suspect subdued with Taser Encinitas chamber chief resigns Encinitas charity raises 20k from garden tour, plant sale Encinitas Citizens for Residential Stability is the greatest name ever Encinitas city staffers: Beacon’s Beach should be top-priority project Encinitas civic gallery to host art exhibit Encinitas considering increasing trash collection rates Encinitas considering MainStreet coordinator to promote economic… Encinitas council debates deputy mayor’s job: Teresa Barth takes… Encinitas council OKs downtown restrictions Encinitas developer would get‘bonus’for low-income home Encinitas district offers classrooms to charter school Encinitas Environment Day educates, enlightens Encinitas exploring‘retail-only’regulations Encinitas exploring‘retail-only’regulations for Ground Floors Encinitas eyes two sites for downtown parking Encinitas Fire Department to host workshop Encinitas fire station replacement making headway Encinitas follies bring smiles to seniors Encinitas group demands report on environmental progress Encinitas Group Seeks Volunteers to Conduct Homeless Count Encinitas home sales boasts‘strong upward trend’ Encinitas Hooters sign a hoax Encinitas Little League celebrates 50 years of baseball Encinitas man designs ads, apparel Encinitas man dies after crash Encinitas Man Pleads Guilty In Marijuana Case Encinitas man pleads guilty in marijuana case Encinitas mayor delivers state of the community address Encinitas mayor is saluted in final bow Encinitas Musicians Encinitas names new public works director Encinitas needs sports fields at Hall site Encinitas needs sports fields at Hall site Encinitas neighbors say Scripps report should examine traffic… Encinitas Parks and Recreation commission plans for first… Encinitas Poinsettia Festival set for Sunday Encinitas Post Office Encinitas postpones action on housing fee Encinitas Ranch Encinitas, California Encinitas Real Estate Market update February 2007! Encinitas reports headway on pedestrian rail crossings Encinitas rings in season with Christmas concert, parade Encinitas salon forgoes gratuity Encinitas school district teaches healthy nutrition Encinitas sets goals for 2007: Hall property park, highway… Encinitas sets hours for door-to-door solicitors Encinitas shows love of surfing, art with new sculpture Encinitas singer finds her muse in front of a band Encinitas Sketches Encinitas spring boxing competition today Encinitas student names newsletter, wins iPod Encinitas Tabbed as Second Locale to Treat Cancers Using Gamma Device Encinitas Tabbed as Second Locale to Treat Cancers Using Gamma Device Encinitas teen to play in LPGA event Encinitas to consider 102k sewer line for fire station Encinitas to consider donation of surfing sculpture Encinitas to unveil public works plans Encinitas to unveil roadside banners today Encinitas Vacation Rental Limits Rejected Encinitas’delays hurt today’s youth Encinitas’Froese switches gears, goes singer-songwriter mode Encinitas’Fuhr, Hernandez win again at San Dieguito Half Encinitas’great auto glut Encinitas’lighting bills are outta sight Encinitas’Susan Sbicca winning awards for her cooking, philanthropy Encinitas, at the Edge of a Continent Encinitas, California–Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Encinitas, city of 13000 pooches, plans first full-time dog park ENCINITAS, Jan. 24 (UNION-TRIBUNE): Encinitas-based Moxie stages original holiday one-acts Encinitas: Great beach town with some great places to eat Engaged: Lessons from parents entertainment.signonsandiego.com&gt;Feature Environmental report to examine proposed Encinitas subdivision Environmental report to examine Scripps Encinitas expansion Erica and Stan’s Half and Half Session Erosion near lagoon inlet imperils Coast Highway Even More Beacon’s-post planning commission thoughts Exclusive: A Preview of Surfâ€™s Up ! (Surfing News) Exhibit brightens, calms Civic Center gallery Extreme makeover needed at new Encinitas public works facility… Fallen eucalyptus prompts vow to save the others Fast-food restaurant robbed Feds Seek Source Of Encinitas Ocean Fuel Spill Feds seek source of ocean fuel spill Feinstein goes to bat for beach project Final round of Koastal Kaos readies for Moonlight Beach Find some enlightenment at Encinitas Imports Fine Paintings by the Brown Brothers Firefighters battle suspicious fires Firefighters continue battling Oceanside riverbed blaze Firefighters douse Encinitas brush fire Flower from Another World–Photo of the Week Flying high Food Briefs: Mike’s Choice Meats opens second store in Oceanside Food Briefs: Restaurants offer Father’s Day specials Four From North County Considered for California Coastal Panel Four from North County considered for state coastal panel Four Shillings Short Concert Free Sign Language Class for parents and infants, North County San… Fresh Egg for You From Big Red Productions From Germany to Encinitas: Ecke family poinsettias Fuel samples negative, Encinitas council told Fuel samples negative, Encinitas council told Fuel spill clean-up costlier than original estimates Fuel spill clean-up costly Fuel spill fouls 2 1/2 -mile stretch of Encinitas coast Fuel spill fouls 2 1/2 -mile stretch of Encinitas coast Fuel spill leads to beach closures Fuel Spill Off Encinitas Coast Affects Coastline Fuel spill off Encinitas is all but gone FulaBula Festival returns with new location and beneficiary Fundraiser for A Courageous 2 Year Old G2G tonight!! Giovanniâ€™s Sandwich Shop GLOBAL COOLING HITS SUNNY SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA Right down to the… Going around and around Google Directory–Sports&gt;Water Sports&gt;Surfing&gt;Surf Reports… Google Directory–Sports&gt;Water Sports&gt;Surfing&gt;Surf Reports… Great Day Greens We Dig: Earth Friendly Moving Greg Noll this Saturday, April 21st at Hansen’s in Encinitas Groups seek to use Carlsbad golf course at discount rate Guilty plea in federal pot case Gunman takes cash from video store Hall Park Overview Hall property report Happy Happy Joy Joy Hat Trick Beverage Says Two Beverage Moguls Are Better Than One Health Briefs: Escondido family chosen as March of Dimes ambassadors Health Briefs: Relay for Life plans taking shape Health Notes Heaven’s Gate tragedy remains the country’s worst mass suicide Herb asks, Wouldn’t it be prudent? High School–MANSFIELD SCHOOL BOARD High Winds Create Havoc Highway 101 groups back hiring coordinator Highway improvements a top goal in Encinitas Hiking the Elfin Forest Hit-And-Run Suspect Charged With Manslaughter Holy Week Events Home&amp;Garden Briefs: Water district to hold landscape workshop Home and Garden events Home and garden events Home, garden looky-loos are abundant this time of year Housing plan ready for Encinitas council How to close a great divide I Ching business workshop in Encinitas I forget and then remember I’m down with this Norby dude Identity theft topic of Encinitas forum iExplore Community: Top Surfing-Swami’s&amp;Beacon’s Beach–Cardiff… If I were in charge… If only it were a little bigger Ignoble antics in North County councils In da Newz In the ribbons: David Kerr’s Chinese pickled eggs Inability to develop property prompts auction Invasion of the canopy snatchers…. Is there any way that I can apply to be illegal retroactively? It was a day to hang onto your hat It’s beginning to look a lot like… It’s lights out for the AMC Encinitas 8 It’sa Travelin’ Bear Christmas #4: A Night At The Picture Show James Ray Jean-Luc Ponty 10/23/76 early La Paloma Theater, Encinitas, CA sbd… Jewish community frustrated again in Encinitas John Daly Sings, Go Long or Go Home in New Maxfli Brand Campaign… John Singer Sargent Juanita’s Taco Shop (Encinitas, CA) reviewed by tulrich (7/10) Just Rare Fish Your online Marine Fish and Kelp Cam Kitchen fire damages Rancho Santa Fe home Koastal Kaos Series Concludes At Moonlight Beach L101 Guardrail does it’s job LaJolla- The Wrap Up Lakeside resident gets award for saving life Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 10) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 11) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 13) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 14) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 15) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 2) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 4) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 5) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 6) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 7) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 8) Let’s Tour North Leucadia (part 9) Leucadia Leucadia Leucadia–Our Weekly Tradition Leucadia artist, teacher finds beauty in un-modern art Leucadia Blog Leucadia Boulevard plan heading to Encinitas Planning Commission… Leucadia Hwy 101 MainStreet Association–Home Leucadia Hwy 101 MainStreet Association–Home Leucadia Nights Leucadia Property Owners Supply Massive Tax Base with Little Return Leucadia SB Leucadia SB Leucadia sidewalks on path to reality leucadia surf school Leucadia wastewater project moves forward Leucadia woman led a starry childhood Leucadia! Leucadia/Encinitas will absorb Carlsbad’s Traffic Libel lawsuit should be tossed into the street Lifeguards warn beachgoers of crumbling cliffs Lines In the Sand Lines In the Sand links–ashtanga yoga montrÃ©al (Ashtanga yoga) Little and Kim to Visit Pacific Q Billiards Little hands are busy preparing for Encinitas Christmas Parade Little League’s 50th anniversary brings back memories Live Encinitas City Council broadcasts to begin June 13 Local High School Celebrates Debate Tournament Win Local Man Celebrates 105th Birthday Local News Look Into My Light (As I Lighten Your Wallet) Looking for good italian in San Diego Louie Vito Rides Unicycle With No Seat From Ohio To Encinitas Love&amp;basketball: Hoops helps Encinitas family get through tough… LPGA News Major New Desalination Plant To Be Built In Southern California… Man Accused In Encinitas Hit-And-Run Pleads Not Guilty Man arrested after scuffle with deputies Man arrested in alleged sexual assaults Man linked by DNA to burglaries is held Man Pleads Not Guilty To Burglaries Linked To Discarded Cigarette .. Man robs North County bank Man stabbed six times in a face-off; arrest made Man’s death by train ruled suicide Map of italy–Special options are available to registered members. Marijuana operation impresses officials Mark Freeman Brings Local Poetry Scene to Life Mayor Bond does his his level best to eat that elephant in a cost… Mayor Bond Speech Highlights McGrath begins stock-car career Memorial Day skies expected to be mostly cloudy Memory Lane: Highway 101 had its day as the way Minor crashes mar morning commute Minstrel makes annual visit to Carlsbad MiraCosta eyes ways to reflect community Mojo Pages marries social networking with business search Moonlight Beach drum circle brings‘joy’to players, passers-by Moonlight Beach Sand Check Moonlight State Beach to Beacon’s Beach | CA: Southern California… More holes in head, Quality-of-life tax proposed. More Leucadia Lights Morning commute mostly routine in North County Morning commute traffic has usual slowing Mosaic Arts International 2007–Sama Exhibit–Mesa, Arizona… Most North County beaches score well in annual water-quality report Mothers get, give support at MamaFest Motorcyclist hurt in freeway crash Motorcyclist injured after pursuit My Burning Roundabout Questions My Encinitas: Your Encinitas Mysterious Fuel Spill at Beacon’s Beach Mysterious Fuel Spill at Beacon’s Beach Natural Sand Replenishment Currently Underway NCT to hold public round table in Cardiff Negotiations in priest sex-abuse cases to resume this week Neighbors object to sea wall plan New ANUSARA yoga studio in Encinitas New Gas Station Question and Comment New library now visible from downtown Enc New library well on its way to completion inside and out New Mystery Am New Rip-Off Duplicate New trail opens at San Elijo Lagoon NIMBY Michael D Pattinson faces worst nightmare in Santee Nixon to host High Tide Hold‘Em poker on Tavarua, Fiji no large tracts of vacant land remain in Encinitas No major crashes reported during morning commute No money left at the atm ? No simple formula tells when a child is too sick to go to school No tourney freebies at golf course North County beaches mostly calm over holiday North County Cities Recover From High-Wind Damage North County Community News briefs: Coaches’fundraiser is tonight North County FYI North County FYI North County FYI North County FYI North County guru gone North County is a Mecca for Car Thieves North County mayors speak on Chargers stadium North County morning commute slows in usual places North County morning commute tougher than usual today North County Times–Escondido,CA,USA Chamber Notes: For the week of Jan. 16-22 North County Times closes Encinitas office North County, San Diego? Or San Diego North North San Diego County Community News Briefs:‘In the Park After… North San Diego County Community News Briefs:‘My Big Fat Greek… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Angel’s Depot holds… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Ashleigh Roach… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Car show to honor… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Cartoonists Society… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Cut-athon to benefit… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Easter Egg Hunt set… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Men’s club forming… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Miss San Marcos… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Old-time Christmas… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Senior Santa program… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: SuperCamp Preview… North San Diego County Community News Briefs: Woman’s club plans… North San Diego County Comunity News Briefs: Young Entrepreneur… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Charger Rivers to host… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Essay contest announced North San Diego County School News Briefs: Independent school… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Plans for golf… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Sierra Madre plans open… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Student Speakers… North San Diego County School News Briefs: Take Your Family to… Nursing home employee sentenced for credit-card theft nyc chowhound in san diego for a weekend wedding in june Oak Knoll may lend 11 rooms to charter Object resembling hand found at coast Ocean bluffs fail as Army Corps fiddles Oceanside to launch free senior shuttle program Oceanside, stay focused on hotel Officials Call for Sand Replenishment Project to Save Eroding Beaches Officials call girl’s death a homicide Offshore Yellows Start Snapping, Local San Diego Action Hot Oil Slick Fouls North County Beaches Oil Spill Threatens North County Beaches Olivenhain water district offers irrigation controller rebates Olivenhain water district OKs rate hike On a Mission: My daughter Allie is in fourth gra… On the edge of a solution for bluffs One piece at a time One runner takes turn for the worse ONLINE CALENDAR Balboa Park, gallery and museum listings, ongoing… Online info may shape future of boardmaking Orange County Man Spends Almost Full Day Locked in Trunk of Car Our group explored the Torrey Pines Beach picking up shells and… Our guide to San Diego’s nightlife Overpaid and Under Worked Pacifc Station,&quot;a beautiful sardine can&quot;, Approved Pacific Station development on agenda for Thurs. Feb 1st meeting Pacific Station expected to revive downtown Pacific View rezoning proposal heading to Encinitas council Pacific View School Development Panel taking public comment on report Parents air wish list for new Cardiff schools chief Park plans provoke noise, traffic concerns Park, beach within Easter’s reach Park-site study flags traffic, toxin issues Peder Norby: Hwy101 Overlord or Friend? People news People on the move: Qualcomm makes some changes People on the move: Rotary honors two teachers People on the move: West a manager for Connect Pets need shelter from domestic violence, too Physician flies solo Pickup slams into patrol car Pinus Torreyana Planes, Trains and Automobiles (not to mention light rails and… Plastic banned in San Francisco Poetry slam, documentary on event find stage at La Paloma Poinsettias can be restored to re-bloom another year Police later found a bungee cord Bicycle Trailer to Freund. Police seek public’s help in finding stalker suspect Police Trying To Return Stolen Property To Owners Police: Burglar enters two Encinitas homes with occupants inside Police: Cigarette Butt Leads To Suspect Arrest Police: Man Uses Skateboard To Smash Windows Political consultant Jack Orr dies in Oceanside PONTO BEACHFRONT VILLAGE VISION PLAN Possible oil spill off Encinitas reaches beaches–Beacon’s Beach Practice your francais and enjoy a nosh, too Producer still looking for military families Project expected to transform downtown Encinitas Proposed bill could affect Oceanside beach resort project Proposed budget includes big-ticket items Purchases and Leases Quail Botanical Gardens lights up the holidays Quail Gardens Quail Gardens – great for kids and adults alike! Rabies shots, dog licences offered at Encinitas clinic Racers to crowd downtown Encinitas for weekend Rain forest photographer at Swami’s on Sunday Rain leaves wet roads, no major commute crashes Rainy Easter. Random San Diego Sunset : Moonlight Beach, Encinitas Re: Stolen Bass Re: Vibrational Cities on the West Coast??? Red-light camera violations are worse for on-duty law enforcement Regional Roundup Relaxation Magic–Hypnosis, Meditation, Visualization Religion and ethics calendar Religion events Remembering Robert Douglas replinishment at Business.com Residents critical of Encinitas park study Residents happy with quality of life offered Residents use program to clean up crime problem Rich Memories Rider Killed When Motorcycle T-Bones Car Road work OK’d near middle school Roadside fires threaten Encinitas buildings Rob Machado aids Bubble Gum Surf Wax renaissance Robber waits to finish Encinitas holdup Robbery Attempt at Coast Highway Market in Encinitas Rock‘n’roll house in Encinitas to be dismantled Rockinâ€™ in a hard place ENCINITAS – Lou’s Records (MP3 File Sharing) Roses raspberries Roses raspberries Roundabouts Proposed for Leucadia Blvd Roxy swimwear–Encinitas Electronic Web Village: Roxy Restaurant… Sales down 24% from 2006 San Diego Beaches Washing Away San Diego Coastal information–North San Diego County Beaches… San Diego Garden Clubs San Diego happenings San Diego Restaurant Week back to spotlight local favorites San Diego Reviews: Restaurants, Doctors, Bars, Salons and more. San Diego’s most comprehensive guide San Dieguito Academy Volleyball Player Kenzie Aries Appears in Volleyball Magazine San Dieguito gets best of rival Eagles San Dieguito schools shine in school rankings San Marcos grants K-8 charter; Tech high school on track to open… Sand SANDAG Profile Warehouse Santa Claus replaces sleigh with the Coaster Santa’s COASTER Express runs Sarah Munoz School Coffers Feel Drag of Slowing Housing Market School district cuts 10 part-time jobs School plan would make site 75% residential School tries to stand out Schools feeling the chill of housing slump Scripps Encinitas expansion the topic of upcoming environmental… Scripps Encinitas says thanks to military families Scripps Ranch woman plans memorial videos for war dead SD gets cut of state funds for improving local highways Search suspended for Hall property EIR report See you all at the end of the week… Self-Realization Fellowship (Swami’s) Senator proposes bill for wider-range in housing prices Senior fair offers information, freebies Sentencing Scheduled For Man Who Admitted To Kidnapping Boy Sentencitng postponed for confessed cub scout kidnapper Seven apply for Sigafoose’s council spot, so far Sex offenders move into neighborhood Sharpening store will shut down Sidewalk sale Saturday in downtown Encinitas Sierra Club member to talk on Powerlink Sisler’s goal turns to gold Sitemap Six-bed unit ready to open at Scripps Encinitas Sixth sense crucial in golf Skateboarding the Encinitas YMCA Slam! Slick Smoking debate resurfaces Snowboarding for the first time ever! SoCal singer found first inspiration in Indonesia SoCal Train Severs Man’s Leg Social workers, volunteers tally the homeless Solar energy’s day is dawning Some Cardiff parents want multitasking superintendent Some Encinitas beaches reopen after fuel spill Some Encinitas beaches reopen after fuel spill South Swells Bring Sand to Leucadia Special St. Patrick’s Day events Spill temporarily halts Encinitas swimming, surfing Sports at its best Stalemate on sand Stayin’alive–Four local comics remain in national competition… Steve Aceti moving to Encinitas, entertaining 2008 council run Still Shaping After All These Years Storm brings heavy showers, few problems to North County Strumming The Night Away Students need safer streets Students Raise Money For Boy With Rare Disease Subdivision proposed on family farm Surf Reports, Wave Cams, Beach Cams and Weather–Boardfolio.com… Surf Reports, Wave Cams, Beach Cams and Weather–Boardfolio.com… Surf sentinels Surf Theatre News: Pipeline Posse plays at La Paloma SurfAid International first annual Swim 4 Life raises 40K Surfer dies, cause unknown Surfing Surfing Photo of The Day. Surfrider to challenge Beacon’s Beach study Surfrider to challenge Beacon’s Beach study Suspected robbers arrested after train hits their truck Swami’s Beach: Fellowship Successful In Preventing Collapse Sweet 16 with the San Diego Trojan Club Take a Tour of Encinitas Ranch Take a Tour of Leucadia in Encinitas, CA Teens can apply for Japan exchange program The Big List of dumb things we gotta do this year The Ebb and Flow of Our Sand Drama The Fight for Net Neutrality is The Fight for Free Speech The last southern California coastal open space, thank you Camp… The Quest for Rob Crow The San Diego Vegan Group February Meetup The Surveys Usefulness is Dubious The Top 5 Reasons Chocolate Lovers Love San Diego The Transit Coalition eNewsletter, Mon., Jan. 23, 2007 things i have realized/discovered/decided over this weekend, in no… This Weekend in San Diego Thousands turn out for Encinitas Poinsettia Festival Three apply for Planning Commission seat TIP Academy conducts lottery for 2007-08 school year TIP Academy Open Application Period Tirade about restaurants Tirade about restaurants To preserve its quirky downtown core, city may limit ground-floor… Toasting a new concept: Encinitas store sorts wines with customers… Today is National Buy Local Day Today is National Buy Local Day Today’s Events–SanDiegoReader.com Calif. city says vulgar sign too large Too much fried food? Swamiâ€™s Cafe has the cure Trademarking Wollemi Pine Trader joes gift baskets Traffic: Crashes mar Highway 78 commute Treating war’s‘silent injury’ Tree trimmers stop work to save Egrets nests in Solana Beach call… Trial date set for man accused of attempted kidnapping at… Trial ordered for suspects accused of bilking elderly couple Trio charged with cultivating marijuana Two arrested in North County stolen property ring Two hurt in Encinitas rollover crash Two new pizzerias to raise dough for schools Two workers hurt on construction sites Undaunted by age, local women hooping it up Underground Parking UNION-TRIBUNE EDITORIALS UNIV BRINGS BRAVE ART SHOW TO ENCINITAS Untitled32 A California moment:&quot;in this fleeting moment, what… Update from La La Land… USA Road Travel: On Beacon’s Beach , There’s A Mellow Mixture Of… Vacation Rental Bans Vacation rental limits rejected Video producer seeking online memorials to Iraq war dead Vintage car show has been canceled Vista Holiday Parade morphs: It’s a Christmas Parade again… Volunteer buys biscuits from disabled relative, gives to humane… Volunteers bring smiles to Scripps Encinitas Volunteers sought to tally homeless people Vote postponed on Encinitas subdivision Want to Live in A Musical Community? Try the Composer District in… Washing Away Tax Dollars? Waste Land Water district chief’s contract terminated Water district’s man with vision looks forward – to retirement Water rates increase; housing vote delayed Water-fee ballot is approved, but council waits to set a date We don’t need no education We don’t need no education? We got tacos at Karina’s and ate‘em under the trees. We have to ride bikes 3 days a week We have to ride bikes 3 days a week We make hundreds of decisions a year, this is one of them, Weekend Update What are your goals in life young man? What began as Encinitas Hotel had many faces What to do…… What’s Your Favorite Local American Food Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Bagel? What’s Your Favorite Local Bakery? What’s Your Favorite Local Bar and Grill? What’s Your Favorite Local Barbecue / Ribs/ BBQ Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Brazilian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local British / English Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Burger Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Cafe? What’s Your Favorite Local Cajun / Creole Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Californian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Casual Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Chinese Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Coffee House / Shop? What’s Your Favorite Local Continental Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Deli? What’s Your Favorite Local Fast Food Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Fast Food Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Fine Dining Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Fish / Seafood Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local French Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local German Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Greek Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Hawaiian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Health Food Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Ice Cream Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Indian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Irish Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Italian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Juice Bar? What’s Your Favorite Local Mediterranean Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Mexican Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Middle Eastern Restaurant?What’s Your Favorite Local Middle Eastern Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local OTHER Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local OTHER2 Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Pizza? What’s Your Favorite Local Sandwich Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Sport’s Bar Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Steak House Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Thai Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Turkish Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Unclassified / Other Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Vegetarian Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Local Vietnamese Restaurant? What’s Your Favorite Restaurant for Breakfast? What’s Your Favorite Sushi / Japanese Restaurant? Where to go, what to do Winter Garden Gallery Wish you were hear?? Wish You Were Here–LA to Encinitas Wishing all a Merry Christmas! With a brush of health, Encinitas artist unveils first exhibit Wooden’s Sweet presence is felt in the North County Worker Admits To Stealing From Nursing Home Patients Workers build a retaining wall on Vulcan Avenue in Encinitas on… Writing Contest. Deputy Says Hes Focus Of Leak Inquiry X Corps Action Sports TV #20.) XPO seg.4 Xcorps Action Sports TV #7.) SPEEDSKI seg.2 Xcorps Action Sports TV #7.)SPEEDSKI seg.3 Your government @ transparency ‘20/20 segment to feature local E. coli tragedy–(North County… 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 
 
Categories

 American Food Restaurant (1) American Food Restaurants (1) Bagel (1) Bagels (1) Bakery (1) Bar (1) Bar and Grill (1) Barbecue Restaurant (1) Barbecue Restaurants (1) BBQ Restaurant (1) BBQ Restaurants (1) Beacon&apos;s Beach (3) bluff failure (1) Brazilian Restaurant (1) Brazilian Restaurants (1) Breakfast Restaurant (1) British Restaurant (1) British Restaurants (1) Burger Restaurant (1) Burger Restaurants (1) Cajun Restaurant (1) Cajun Restaurants (1) California Coastal Commission (1) Californian Restaurant (1) Californian Restaurants (1) Casual Restaurant (1) Casual Restaurants (1) Chinese Restaurant (1) Chinese Restaurants (1) Coffee (1) Coffee House (1) Coffee Shop (1) Continental Restaurant (1) Continental Restaurants (1) Creole Restaurant (1) Creole Restaurants (1) Deli (1) Deli Restaurant (1) Deli Restaurants (1) Encinitas (199) Encinitas Hotels (52) Encinitas News (15) Encinitas Photos (361) Encinitas Post Office (1) Encinitas Restaurant (8) Encinitas Video (108) English Restaurant (1) English Restaurants (1) Fast Food (1) Fast Food Restaurant (1) Fast Food Restaurants (1) Fine Dining (1) Fine Dining Restaurant (1) Fine Dining Restaurants (1) French Restaurant (1) French Restaurants (1) German Restaurant (1) German Restaurants (1) Greek Restaurant (1) Greek Restaurants (1) Grill (1) Hawaiian Restaurant (1) Hawaiian Restaurants (1) Health Food Restaurant (1) Health Food Restaurants (1) Ice Cream (1) Ice Cream Place (1) Ice Cream Restaurant (1) Ice Cream Restaurants (1) Indian Restaurant (1) Indian Restaurants (1) Irish Restaurant (1) Irish Restaurants (1) Italian Restaurant (1) Japanese Restaurant (1) Japanese Restaurants (1) Juice Bar (1) Juice Bars (1) Leucadia (1) Marijuana (1) Mediterranean Restaurant (1) Mediterranean Restaurants (1) Mexican Restaurant (1) Mexican Restaurants (1) Middle Eastern Restaurant (1) Middle Eastern Restaurants (1) Neptune Avenue (1) oil spill (2) Pizza (1) Police Blotter (1) Restaurant (1) Restaurants (1) Ribs Restaurant (1) Ribs Restaurants (1) San Dieguito Academy (1) Sandwich Restaurant (1) Sandwich Restaurants (1) Seafood Restaurant (1) Seafood Restaurants (1) Sport&apos;s Bar Restaurant (1) Sport&apos;s Bar Restaurants (1) Sports Bar (1) Steak House (1) Steak House Restaurant (1) Steak House Restaurants (1) Sushi Restaurant (1) Sushi Restaurants (1) Swamis (1) Tavern (1) Turkish Restaurant (1) Turkish Restaurants (1) Uncategorized (29) Vacation Rentals (1) Vegetarian Restaurant (1) Vegetarian Restaurants (1) Vietnamese Restaurant (1) Vietnamese Restaurants (1) Volleyball (1) Volleyball Magazine (1)
	</body>
</document>
