<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007902" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/209/1345866/restaurant/Minnesota/Neighbors-Italian-Bistro-Mankato" time="2012-07-13-00:52" support="2" score="0.003027150105426637" bingtitle="Neighbor&apos;s Italian Bistro - Mankato | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Neighbor&apos;s Italian Bistro - Mankato | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>Carrie the manager checks on each table, chats ... is great and they have a very nice wine selection. ... of a food guy, what are you doing at a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Minnesota » Mankato » Neighbor&apos;s Italian... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Des Moines Green Bay Kansas City Los Angeles Milwaukee New York Twin Cities More... 
 
Neighbor&apos;s Italian Bistro
 
(507) 625-6776
 Mankato 1812 S Riverfront Dr 
 Mankato , MN 56001 See all 10 reviews Cuisine Italian Feature Gluten-Free Friendly Menu $$$ $15-25 per entree Caesar View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   68 people have voted 82 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Mazatlan Mexican Restaurant 95% $$ Mankato - Mexican 1525 Tullamore St 
 
 Pub 500 89% $$ Mankato - American 500 S Front St 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 11, 2012 Mobile review by Aly C. ( 1 review ) Last time I was there I was with a big group. Great food and great service. This time I was there with just my husband. Seated in a back corner and forgotten until we finally got tired of waiting for someone to even take our drink order. The waitress went to the table next to us twice to check on them. We ended up leaving having never ordered. Went somewhere else. Happy Mother&apos;s Day dinner? November 2, 2011 Likes it not just mankato-good by mermanda ( 159 reviews ) Engagement Dinner-- -Peasant bread with red pepper and blue cheese butter -House salad with House Italian Dressing -Rigatoni Primavera with Spring vegetables, ie roasted parsnips, eggplant, onion, red pepper, broccolini After just my first visit yesterday, this spectacular restaurant is haunting me. I could not believe my mouth. Words cannot describe! I can&apos;t wait to go back. June 23, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Food Geek ( 47 reviews ) Fantastic! Can&apos;t wait to come back. January 22, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Omar ( 18 reviews ) Delicious. The owner checked on us. The Caesar was great...ask for anchovies. The shrimp gnocci was rich and decadent. A friend had the lobster gnocchi and loved it...the lobster was served lazy. Another in our party had the new York strip and loved it. The mashed potatoes were fantastic with the bacon. Strong recommend. February 5, 2011 Mobile review by B Dahl ( 5 reviews ) Best italian in town. February 19, 2010 Likes it Wonderful staff and good food by Yvonne ( 4 reviews ) Carrie and Sonja at Neighbors are the best. Carrie the manager checks on each table, chats with you when you come in and asks how things went as you leave. Sonja is the best waitress we&apos;ve had in years. She checks in just enough, makes sure you never are without something to drink, works hard to help you select things you&apos;ll like from the menu. The food is great and they have a very nice wine selection. A super place for a night out relaxing and having someone else cook. My husband and I got engaged at Neighbors, it&apos;s a special place for us! February 23, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by A.j. Mickelson ( 1 review ) Amazing food and service. May 16, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Joe Smith ( 1 review ) Poor service. Cold food. 40 minutes to get entree December 22, 2009 Likes it Very Pretenios II by Kenny ( 1 review ) Say Bart I read your review of the Neighbor&apos;s. Funny for a guy that goes to and writes a reveiw of Long John Silver, You loose ALL food credibility. I have been to The Neighbor&apos;s web site, 3 on line sites and to the restaurant it&apos;s self. No PLACE do they claim that the are Gourmet. The just have good home made food. My server had the Chef come to our table. about to only thing they don&apos;t make is the pasta. I&apos;m not sure of any place that does. Do us all a favor go back to Long Johns so we don&apos;t have to wait as long next time. Ps I like to wait at restaurants! Means the food is good. PSS If you are this big of a food guy, what are you doing at a fast food restaurant? August 5, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Very Pretentious..... by Bart ( 10 reviews ) Websters: 1 : characterized by pretension: as a : making usually unjustified or excessive claims (as of value or standing) b : expressive of affected, unwarranted, or exaggerated importance, worth, or stature 2 : making demands on one&apos;s skill, ability, or means They make the claim that it is a gourmet restaurant. When asked what is prepared in house, the answer is nothing! It seems they do not make their own pasta, sauce or anything else. Everything seems to be from frozen, canned, or bagged. The service is lackluster at best, and they appear to like to make you wait. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Omar Caesar 
 View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Burger King $ Mankato - Burgers, Fast Food Dairy Queen $ Mankato - Fast Food 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 neighbors mankato neighbors italian bistro dress code neighbors mankato do they have shakes 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
