<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007066" url="http://www.shopping.com/guilloche-enamel/products" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="2" score="0.0019389755801362263" bingtitle="&quot;guilloche enamel&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="guilloche enamel- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant ... Riegel Topaz Enamel Beveled Mirror Vanity Tray 11 ... The Museum’s gold-plated hand-enameled frame with ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Vintage sterling silver enamel charm ,  David andersen ,  Chatelaine ,  Antique scent bottle ,  more» Guilloche ,  Guilloche enamel box ,  Guilloche enamel compact ,  Guilloche enamel vintage ,  Guilloche enamel bracelet ,  Guilloche enamel sterling ,  Guilloche enamel heart ,  Guilloche enamel earrings ,  Enamel guilloche cigarette ,  Guilloche enamel jar ,  Enamel guilloche cross ,  Antique enamel ,  Guilloche enamel locket ,  Guilloche perfume    less» Shopping 
 guilloche enamel 
 Showing results for &quot;
guilloche enamel
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ 
 Michele Watches Sport Sail Diamond Head, Gold Michele Watches Sport Sail Diamond Head, Gold 
 Ship Free at Any Price w/ code JULYFS ( In stock ) 
The Sport Sail style features a multifunction utility dial, surrounded by diamondsthe luxurious side of sportswear. 18-karat yellow gold plated round stainless steel case. Diamonds on... More 

The Sport Sail style features a multifunction utility dial, surrounded by diamondsthe luxurious side of sportswear. 18-karat yellow gold plated round stainless steel case. Diamonds on bezel; 0.46 total diamond carat weight. White enamel guilloche dial with three-hand chronograph movement; Arabic numerals, gold markers, and swirl design. Three subdials; date window; stopwatch function. Sapphire crystal. Water resistant to 5 ATM. Interchangeable with any 20mm Michele Watches strap. Imported. Less 
 Neiman Marcus 47 store reviews See Store Info /michele-watches-sport/vlucn6cidYPOE3MuNyd9PA==/info Neiman Marcus $1,395.00 +$32.00 shipping Visit Store 
 SNOW white guilloche enamel &amp;mother-of-pearl by Julia Knight - 5x7 SNOW white guilloche enamel &amp;mother-of-pearl by Julia Knight - 5x7 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
picture frames / photo frames: This gorgeous piece from the Julia Knight collection is a wonderful example of genuine hand inlay work. Set into a fine silver finish base this piece is... More 

picture frames / photo frames: This gorgeous piece from the Julia Knight collection is a wonderful example of genuine hand inlay work. Set into a fine silver finish base this piece is fabulous when one examines its intricate mother-of-pearl detail and white French guilloche style hand enamelling. Because of the nature of hand inlay work each piece may have minute differences that enhance its beauty. SendAFrame proudly carries this entire collection for your photo frame shopping convenience. To view the complete collection click Julia Knight Collection Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /snow-white-guilloche/Ngin8jBpOJ01mmi3qdwc2w==/info $92.00 Free Shipping Visit Store 
 Michele Watches Sport Sail Noir Diamond Watch Head Michele Watches Sport Sail Noir Diamond Watch Head 
 Ship Free at Any Price w/ code JULYFS ( In stock ) 
118 diamonds surround this dark stainless steel timepiece. The Sport Sail Noir boasts multifunction utility, wrapped up in elegant tone-on-tone styling. Noir stainless steel 42mm case... More 

118 diamonds surround this dark stainless steel timepiece. The Sport Sail Noir boasts multifunction utility, wrapped up in elegant tone-on-tone styling. Noir stainless steel 42mm case. Tone-on-tone diamond bezel; 0.56 total diamond carat weight. Tonal guilloche enamel dial with three-hand chronograph movement; &quot;12&quot; numeral, ton-on-tone hour movement. Three subdials; date window; stopwatch function. Sapphire crystal. Water resistant to 5 ATM. Interchangeable with any 20mm Michele Watches strap. Imported. Less 
 Neiman Marcus 47 store reviews See Store Info /michele-watches-sport/UH_lV984LSSK5xB87l5DFA==/info Neiman Marcus $1,345.00 +$32.00 shipping Visit Store 
 Titanic Guilloche Green Enamel Sterling/14K Clad Ring Titanic Guilloche Green Enamel Sterling/14K Clad Ring 
 QVC has a Hassle-Free, 30-Day Return Policy. See site for details. ( In stock ) 
Timeless elegance. Inspired by authentic artifacts recovered from the RMS Titanic, this 14K yellow gold-clad sterling silver ring is always a beautiful choice, crafted in an oval Guilloche... More 

Timeless elegance. Inspired by authentic artifacts recovered from the RMS Titanic, this 14K yellow gold-clad sterling silver ring is always a beautiful choice, crafted in an oval Guilloche style, highlighted by green epoxy enamel at the center. From the Titanic Collection. For more details on this ring&apos;s fit, please refer to the Ring Size Guide above. Less 
 QVC 7,894 store reviews See Store Info /titanic-guilloche-green/Cjrig5lBemP_2cQ50ghX8g==/info $68.00 +$4.97 shipping Visit Store 
 Olivia Riegel Lancaster Swarovski Crystal Orange Guilloche Enamel Picture Frame Olivia Riegel Lancaster Swarovski Crystal Orange Guilloche Enamel Picture Frame 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES&amp;HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Lancaster -- Orange Hand Enameling&amp;Swarovski Crystals Multi-Toned Orange Guilloche Style Hand Enameling Hand Set Smoked... More 

OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES&amp;HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Lancaster -- Orange Hand Enameling&amp;Swarovski Crystals Multi-Toned Orange Guilloche Style Hand Enameling Hand Set Smoked Topaz Swarovski Crystals Gold Tone Metal Finish Luxurious Black Velvet Back Elegant Beveled Glass Frame Window Overall Frame Sizes: 4&quot; x 6&quot; Photo Size = 5.25&quot; x 7.25&quot; 5&quot; x 7&quot; Photo Size = 6.5&quot; x 8.5&quot; 8&quot; x 10&quot; Photo Size = 9.25&quot; x 11.25&quot; Perfect for Weddings&amp;Other Special Occasions Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /olivia-riegel-lancaster/rYd0QquUlS5tot6pS9KLeA==/info $84.95 Free Shipping Visit Store 
 Peach guilloche style from the Metropolitan Museum - 2x2 Peach guilloche style from the Metropolitan Museum - 2x2 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
picture frames / photo frames: Our Guilloche frames are adapted from gold and enamel originals circa 1910 that once held photographs of Olga and Tatiana the eldest daughters of Czar... More 

picture frames / photo frames: Our Guilloche frames are adapted from gold and enamel originals circa 1910 that once held photographs of Olga and Tatiana the eldest daughters of Czar Nicholas II Russia&apos;s last emperor. Gold-plated pewter with gold-plated brass face. Length is 5¼&quot; width 4¼&quot; display window diameter 2&quot;. Available in peach or green. Made expressly for the Metropolitan Museum of Art and available exclusively in their museum shop in NYC and here on SendAFrame. To view the complete collection visit The Metropolitan Museum of Art Collection Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /peach-guilloche-style/dKfq77wLBuZVRyu6ltl8lw==/info $50.00 +$7.95 shipping Visit Store 
 Faberge Pine Cone Egg Faberge Pine Cone Egg 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
This egg was originally made for Varvara Kelkh, a wealthy Russian heiress, who commissioned seven Easter eggs which rivaled in importance and beauty those given to Empress Fedorovna.The... More 

This egg was originally made for Varvara Kelkh, a wealthy Russian heiress, who commissioned seven Easter eggs which rivaled in importance and beauty those given to Empress Fedorovna.The Kelkh Daster eggs have, on occasions, been sold as Imperial eggs. This egg is composed of overlapping disks enameled blue over a guilloche ground with more than 1000 Austrian crystals. The egg holds a miniature elephant inside which in turn holds a cobalt blue egg pendant. Signed with included certificate. Size: 2 1/2&quot;Diam. X 3 3/4&quot;H without stand; Weight: 20 oz; Color: Blue Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /faberge-pine-cone-egg/1hQH9kRO4kHVvmIY1ryCKg==/info $2,750.00 +$16.95 shipping Visit Store 
 Olivia Riegel Warner Luxury Guilloche Hand Enameled Picture Frame Pick Size Olivia Riegel Warner Luxury Guilloche Hand Enameled Picture Frame Pick Size 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Warner -- Hand Enameled Picture Frame Your Choice of Size - Use Drop Down Menu Above to Make Your Selection - Price Will... More 

OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Warner -- Hand Enameled Picture Frame Your Choice of Size - Use Drop Down Menu Above to Make Your Selection - Price Will Change Depending on Size Selected FREE Shipping, Insurance Delivery Tracking -- No Hassles Tangerine Chocolate Colored Guilloche Style Hand Enameling Gold Tone Metal Finish Luxurious Black Velvet Back Elegant Beveled Glass Frame Window Overall Frame Sizes Measure: 2&quot; x 2&quot; Photo Size = 3.75&quot; x 3.75&quot; (Also With Topa Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /olivia-riegel-warner/yDG-cnA1lL1Ftw9dUUU8rg==/info $44.95 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6b/6b/62/71705679427449536554736566564a792d5a67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Glam Rock Women&apos;s GK2001 Monogram White Enamel Dial Black Leather Watch Glam Rock Women&apos;s GK2001 Monogram White Enamel Dial Black Leather Watch 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) Add an understated look to your outfit with this unique and detailed Glam Rock watch. This timepiece offers a silver guilloche dial in a stainless steel case. Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /glam-rock-womens-gk2001/kkbqpVyBtISeTsefVJy-Zg==/info $311.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/68/75/2d48307a6d6c514e615f7a383448504f753851-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson End Of Days Opaque Hard Enamel Pistachio Green Fountain Pen David Oscarson End Of Days Opaque Hard Enamel Pistachio Green Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The 2012 Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise... More 

The 2012 Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. Using a mortar and pestle, a composition of glass, water and metal oxides is ground for hours by hand. When settled, the water is removed, leaving the fine paste that is the basis for hard enamel. A quill is then used to apply each coat of the mixture to the surface of the metal, ensuring that the entire guilloché area is completely covered in enamel. The components are then fired in a furnace at temperatures exceeding 1,000° F, fusing the enamel to the metal and forming a layer of glass.After cooling, the pieces are manually ground with a diamond file, restoring their proper shape and surface. This tedious process is repeated at length until the level of enamel reaches the depth required to cover the peaks and fill the valleys of each intricate guilloché pattern. When the final stages of firing are completed, the pieces are polished and buffed, revealing the velvet finish of translucent hard enamel. Production of translucent hard enamel demands the highest levels of patience, experience and skill. A five-year apprenticeship is required to ensure that the highest levels of quality will be met in each individual Collection piece.Please see other collection in David Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer only , with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-end-of/Whu-H0zmlQNa_z84HPOu8Q==/info $4,900.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/31/6c/68/63486f51744c67367534736269506545673067-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Glam Rock Women&apos;s GK4000 Palm Beach White Enamel Dial Stainless Steel Watch Glam Rock Women&apos;s GK4000 Palm Beach White Enamel Dial Stainless Steel Watch 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) Add an understated look to your outfit with this unique and detailed Glam Rock watch. This timepiece offers a silver guilloche dial in a stainless steel case. Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /glam-rock-womens-gk4000/1lhcHoQtLg6u4sbiPeEg0g==/info $385.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/4d/46/5748796b75725859484a484a584a647a5a4d41-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 30&quot;W x 12&apos; 1&quot;L Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 30&quot;W x 12&apos; 1&quot;L 
 ( In stock ) 
Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you... More 

Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding for this rectangle-shaped table. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Width: 30&quot; Length: 12&apos;1&quot; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /mobile-table-enamel/2MFWHykurXYHJHJXJdzZMA==/info $629.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store -35% http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/76/52/56/485859675a736b486331724d34385855343567-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Enamel Print Racks black Enamel Print Racks black 
 ( In stock ) 
 Enamel Print Racks feature welded steel construction, baked enamel finishes, and rolling casters. Use for easy access and storage of unframed prints, posters, and paintings in galleries,... More 

 Enamel Print Racks feature welded steel construction, baked enamel finishes, and rolling casters. Use for easy access and storage of unframed prints, posters, and paintings in galleries, stores, studios, and at shows. Available in black or white. Open size is 32 in. high and 34 in. wide. Bed size is 6 in. x 18 in. deep. Less 
 MisterArt.com 12 store reviews See Store Info /enamel-print-racks-black/vRVHXYgZskHc1rM48XU45g==/info MisterArt.com $179.95 $116.97 35% Off +$7.48 shipping Visit Store -17% http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4b/50/5f/4c62686769595f333248383863476758685351-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Joan Rivers Classic Enamel Button Earrings Joan Rivers Classic Enamel Button Earrings 
 QVC has a Hassle-Free, 30-Day Return Policy. See site for details. ( In stock ) 
Brilliant buttons! A goldtone rope border surrounds the vibrant, domed epoxy enamel guilloche button at the center of these classic earrings. From Joan Rivers Classics Collection(R)... More 

Brilliant buttons! A goldtone rope border surrounds the vibrant, domed epoxy enamel guilloche button at the center of these classic earrings. From Joan Rivers Classics Collection(R) Accessories. Black, Royal Blue, Chocolate Brown, Emerald Green, or Red. Pierced or Clip. Less 
 QVC 7,894 store reviews See Store Info /joan-rivers-classic/KP_LbhgiY_32H88cGgXhSQ==/info $34.50 $28.62 17% Off +$4.47 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/68/57/51/66534654724653575f4a353945504168706941-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Personalized Enameled Wide Band Class Ring Personalized Enameled Wide Band Class Ring 
 ( In stock ) 
Love the idea of a class ring but want something more unique? This not-so-traditional class ring is carved into solid Sterling Silver. The outside features raised lettering against an... More 

Love the idea of a class ring but want something more unique? This not-so-traditional class ring is carved into solid Sterling Silver. The outside features raised lettering against an antiqued back to spell out your school story. Specify 1 name, up to 8 characters, graduation year, up to 4 character and school name, up to 14 characters, each separated by a star. We engrave inside the band any message, up to 25 characters. Band is 10mm or 3/8&quot; width. Available in full&amp;half sizes, 5 thru 13. Less 
 Personal Creations 697 store reviews See Store Info /personalized-enameled/hWQfSFTrFSW_J59EPAhpiA==/info $159.99 +$17.99 shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/59/65/7262715a516f4a726b64796a63523754717951-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Broad Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Broad Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Broad Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Broad Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief.Please see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/gYerbqZQoJrkdyjcR7TqyQ==/info $5,400.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/78/30/64/58334e35713738347345414c765575704e6b51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Beveled Mirror Tray Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Beveled Mirror Tray 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) Designed by Jon Morris for Olivia Riegel. Dozens of hand-set topaz Swarovski crystals with chocolate colored guilloche style hand-enameling in antique brass metal finish. Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /olivia-riegel-topaz/x0dX3N5q784sEALvUupNkQ==/info $225.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/53/53/38/5632674a575551736a5f6c2d4b5553426c3077-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Guilloche design - Bottle Cap Opener Keychain Ring Guilloche design - Bottle Cap Opener Keychain Ring 
 ( In stock ) The bottle cap opener keychain listed is chrome plated with the 3D urethane encased design as shown. Buy.com Marketplaces 4,766 store reviews See Store Info /guilloche-design-bottle/SS8V2gJWUQsj_l-KUSBl0w==/info $9.99 +$2.45 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/37/59/38/58782d4a44684a7652726671376a48536c6841-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 36&quot;W x 10&apos; 1&quot;L Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 36&quot;W x 10&apos; 1&quot;L 
 ( In stock ) 
Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you... More 

Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding for this rectangle-shaped table. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Width: 36&quot; Length: 10&apos;1&quot; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /mobile-table-enamel/7Y8Xx-JDhJvRrfq7jHSlhA==/info $649.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6e/38/72/617869644f4e47584d37707a674c6467686951-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis Azure Blue and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis Azure Blue and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis Azure Blue and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis Azure Blue and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief. Translucent Azure Blue and Opalescent White Enamel with Rhodium VermeilPlease see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/n8raxidONGXM7pzgLdghiQ==/info $4,900.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6f/57/5a/2d42317439366b745839776254315046303351-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis Black and White Medium Rhodium Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief.Please see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/oWZ-B1t96ktX9wbT1PF03Q==/info $5,400.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/31/70/68/3157372d444567725972396b73527943445a77-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 White Enamel, 14 watts, 22-7/8 inches, 3000K Warm White, Microfluorescent Adjustable T5 Grounded Light Fixture White Enamel, 14 watts, 22-7/8 inches, 3000K Warm White, Microfluorescent Adjustable T5 Grounded Light Fixture 
 ( In stock ) 
This grounded, 3-wire, microfluorescent T5 light fixture includes a 360 degree adjustable light shield for those applications where shielding light is important. It also includes the lamp,... More 

This grounded, 3-wire, microfluorescent T5 light fixture includes a 360 degree adjustable light shield for those applications where shielding light is important. It also includes the lamp, mounting brackets and screws, direct connector, and built-in, instant-on, energy- efficient, silent, electronic ballast. A very versatile light fixture for both home and office, the microfluorescent adjustable T5 grounded light fixture can be used for backlighting, cabinet lighting, cove lighting, desk lighting, display case lighting, exhibits, merchandising, over cabinet lighting, shelf lights, showcase lighting, task lighting, trade show lighting, and under cabinet lighting. Less 
 Pegasus Lighting 46 store reviews See Store Info /white-enamel-14-watts/1ph1W7-DEgrYr9ksRyCDZw==/info $39.90 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/50/6d/68325f776c4f31477172504541555f52613051-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Mirror Vanity Tray 11.25x9.5x1.25&quot; Swarovski Crystals Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Mirror Vanity Tray 11.25x9.5x1.25&quot; Swarovski Crystals 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Beveled Mirror Vanity Tray 11.25&quot;L x 9.5&quot;W x 1.25&quot;H Swarovski Crystals FREE Shipping, Insurance... More 

OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES Olivia Riegel Topaz Enamel Beveled Mirror Vanity Tray 11.25&quot;L x 9.5&quot;W x 1.25&quot;H Swarovski Crystals FREE Shipping, Insurance Delivery Tracking -- No Hassles Dozens of Hand Set Topaz Swarovski Crystals Chocolate Colored Guilloche Style Hand Enameling Antique Brass Metal Finish Elegant Beveled Mirror Glass Luxurious Black Velvet Bottom Perfect for that Special Gift or Home Decor Accent In Stock -- Leaves Our Office Same/Next Business Day Up Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /olivia-riegel-topaz/WPmh2_wlO1GqrPEAU_Ra0Q==/info $199.95 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/69/42/5168515a656d36625052636d41394c42736341-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame 
 ( In stock ) Forzieri Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame Forzieri 891 store reviews See Store Info /sterling-silver/_iBQhQZem6bPRcmA9LBscA==/info Forzieri $338.00 +$11.95 shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/46/44/47/504751475477536b724958504a325377746f67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 7 Piece Enamel Blue Cast Iron Set 7 Piece Enamel Blue Cast Iron Set 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
This enamel cast iron cookware set conducts and retains heat while withstanding the rigors of daily use. Porcelain enamel interior finish requires no seasoning and resists scratches and... More 

This enamel cast iron cookware set conducts and retains heat while withstanding the rigors of daily use. Porcelain enamel interior finish requires no seasoning and resists scratches and chips. Goes easily from oven to table for beautiful presentation. No seasoning required. High quality porcelain enamel coating is impermeable to odors and stains. Safe on all cook tops and in the oven to 475 degrees F. Hand washing is recommended to preserve the cookware&apos;s original appearance. 12&quot; Round Grill Pan: Cut the fat, retain the flavor. Ribbed base separates the fat from the food allowing for healthier cooking and sears food evenly with characteristic char lines. Dimension: 7-qt. Oval dutch oven: 13 1/4&quot;Length (Not INCLUDE the handles) x10 1/2&quot; Width x 4 1/2&quot; Depth. 10-Inch Round Skillet: Diameter 10&quot; x Depth 2&quot; 12-Inch Skillet: Diameter Length 19 1/2&quot; x Diameter 12&quot;x Depth 2 1/2&quot; 12-Inch Round Grill Pan: Length 19 1/2&quot; x Diameter 12&quot;x Depth 2 1/2&quot; 11-Inch Rectangular Roasting Dish: Length 11&quot; x Width 8 1/2&quot;x Depth 1 3/4&quot; 10-Inch Oval Roasting Dish: Length 10 1/2&quot;x Width 6 1/4&quot;x Depth 1 1/2&quot;. Product Features: Enameled Cast Iron Exterior: Enamel Coated Blue Interior: Enamel Coated Beige Please see other colors at website: paylesscookware. com Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /7-piece-enamel-blue-cast/FDGPGQGTwSkrIXPJ2Swtog==/info $349.99 +$75.24 shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/69/75/30/786359426579367a69536f4b375158574f5041-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Faberge Reproduction 2-color Emerald/Topaz enamel frame from The Metropolitan Museum of Art - 5x7 Faberge Reproduction 2-color Emerald/Topaz enamel frame from The Metropolitan Museum of Art - 5x7 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
picture frames / photo frames: A master jeweler celebrated for his fanciful creations Peter Carl Fabergé elevated the art of exquisite guilloché enameling to new heights. Fabergé was the... More 

picture frames / photo frames: A master jeweler celebrated for his fanciful creations Peter Carl Fabergé elevated the art of exquisite guilloché enameling to new heights. Fabergé was the world’s greatest master of this art form a time-intensive technique in which polychrome enamel is layered over circular straight or wave patterns engraved on metal. The Museum’s gold-plated hand-enameled frame with crystal stones is based on a gold picture frame with guilloché enamel in the Museum’s collection created by Fabergé’s studios about 1916.  Features h and-enameling with gold overlay and faceted cyrstals. Frame displays a 5&quot;x7&quot; photo or print. To view the complete collection visit The Metropolitan Museum of Art® Collection Produced in cooperation with the British Royal Collection. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /faberge-reproduction/iu0xcYBey6ziSoK7QXWOPA==/info $72.00 +$7.95 shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/59/73/77/796b686647454c5777664c784863306d493551-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Mobile Table - Enamel Legs- 30&quot;W x 5&apos;L Mobile Table - Enamel Legs- 30&quot;W x 5&apos;L 
 ( In stock ) 
Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you... More 

Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding for this rectangle-shaped table. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Width: 30&quot; Length: 5&apos; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /mobile-table-enamel/YswykhfGELWwfLxHc0mI5Q==/info $429.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/30/79/73/4e4c714e327a4b6238527069776f70706f3651-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 30&quot;W x 10&apos; 1&quot;L Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 30&quot;W x 10&apos; 1&quot;L 
 ( In stock ) 
Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you... More 

Space-saving design and easy-roll casters make Midwest Folding Products&apos; Mobile Table a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding for this rectangle-shaped table. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Width: 30&quot; Length: 10&apos;1&quot; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /mobile-table-enamel/0ysNLqN2zKb8Rpiwoppo6Q==/info $609.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/45/64/55/566a4d434339484a4a6d504f6f36587a434b51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Round Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 6&apos; Diameter Round Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 6&apos; Diameter 
 ( In stock ) 
With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Round Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety... More 

With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Round Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. The round shape allows for interaction between all students at the table. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Diameter: 6&apos; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /round-mobile-table/EdUVjMCC9HJJmPOo6XzCKQ==/info $559.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/48/62/59/775645775534686d3261477667437158324477-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Olivia Riegel Cooper Luxury Topaz Swarovski Crystal Picture Frame Pick Size Olivia Riegel Cooper Luxury Topaz Swarovski Crystal Picture Frame Pick Size 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES&amp;HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Cooper -- Luxury Picture Frame With Swarovski Crystals Hand Set Topaz Swarovski Crystals Copper&amp;Chocolate Colored... More 

OLIVIA RIEGEL - LUXURY PHOTO FRAMES&amp;HOME DECOR ACCESSORIES The Cooper -- Luxury Picture Frame With Swarovski Crystals Hand Set Topaz Swarovski Crystals Copper&amp;Chocolate Colored Guilloche Style Hand Enameling Gold Tone Metal Finish Elegant Beveled Glass Frame Window Luxurious Black Velvet Back Overall Frame Sizes Measure: 2&quot; x 2&quot; Photo Size = 3.75&quot; x 3.75&quot; 4&quot; x 6&quot; Photo Size = 5.5&quot; x 7.5&quot; 5&quot; x 7&quot; Photo Size = 6.5&quot; x 8.25&quot; 8&quot; x 10&quot; Photo Size = 9.25&quot; x 11.25&quot; Perfect for Weddings&amp;Other Special Occasions Order Qty (1) = (1) Frame in Chosen Size - Price Will Change Depending on Size Selected Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /olivia-riegel-cooper/HbYwVEwU4hm2aGvgCqX2Dw==/info $84.95 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/68/72/50/5971776833356543364c3776316b4f78443041-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Low-Cost and Durable Baked Enamel Signs - 18x12 - Minimum Order 50 Low-Cost and Durable Baked Enamel Signs - 18x12 - Minimum Order 50 
 ( In stock ) 
Custom Baked Enamel SignsCustom Baked Enamel Signs - 18x12 Size - Horizontal Rectangle -  Low-Cost and Durable Oven Baked Enamel Rust-Free Aluminum SignsMinimum Order of 50 - FREE UPS... More 

Custom Baked Enamel SignsCustom Baked Enamel Signs - 18x12 Size - Horizontal Rectangle -  Low-Cost and Durable Oven Baked Enamel Rust-Free Aluminum SignsMinimum Order of 50 - FREE UPS Ground Shipping! Three Easy Steps to Buy Custom Baked Enamel Signs: Design your sign and place your order online right now! Be sure to include your email address and phone number during checkout. We will email a proof to you in 1-2 days, so you can see how your custom sign will look. We will make any revisions you may need, at no extra charge, until you&apos;re happy with the look of your sign. After you OK the proof, your custom signs will ship FREE in just 15 Work Days! Your Custom Baked Enamel Signs Will Be: Constructed of rust-free, .040 gauge, durable aluminum The sign face will be Oven Baked for many years of no-fade outdoor service Typeset with Official Federal Highway Administration fonts Pre-drilled Less 
 STOP Signs and More Store not rated See Store Info /lowcost-and-durable/hrPYqwh35eC6L7v1kOxD0A==/info STOP Signs and More $10.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/38/6b/57/5844775f4242692d6f77475142573538416a77-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis White and Black Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis White and Black Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis White and Black Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis White and Black Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief. Opalescent White and Translucent Black Enamel with 18-kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil.Please see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/8kWXDw_BBi-owGQBW58Ajw==/info $4,900.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/65/50/48/3064552d4a306c35346b347571584b676a4751-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 White Enamel Repair Kit White Enamel Repair Kit 
 ( In stock ) 
Nicks in enamel can make your kitchen appliances and bath fixtures look old before their time - let this kit rejuvenate them. Just dab on a bit of repair fluid (applicator brush is... More 

Nicks in enamel can make your kitchen appliances and bath fixtures look old before their time - let this kit rejuvenate them. Just dab on a bit of repair fluid (applicator brush is included), nicks disappear, and your bathtub, stove, fridge, or washer looks new again. Temperature- resistant. Easy directions. 1 oz. Less 
 Miles Kimball 27 store reviews See Store Info /white-enamel-repair-kit/ePH0dU-J0l54k4uqXKgjGQ==/info $5.49 +$5.98 shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/70/64/4f6c696672644d79624962546a747662383867-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis Sapphire and White Broad 18kt Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis Sapphire and White Broad 18kt Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis Sapphire and White Broad 18kt Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis Sapphire and White Broad 18kt Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief. Translucent Sapphire Blue and Opalescent White Enamel with 18-karat Yellow Gold Vermeil.Please see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/PpdOlifrdMybIbTjtvb88g==/info $4,900.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/56/31/6a/5a7877554963667a55745177653174366c3367-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 David Oscarson Trellis Red and White Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen David Oscarson Trellis Red and White Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The David Oscarson Trellis Red and White Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing... More 

The David Oscarson Trellis Red and White Broad 18kt. Yellow Gold Vermeil Fountain Pen. The Trellis Collection is the seventh in the David Oscarson™ series of Limited Edition writing instruments. Produced in five color variations, each will be limited to production of 88 pieces (including fountain pens and roller balls). The Trellis Collection continues in the spirit of artistic mastery and the tradition of Old World craftsmanship by combining the centuries-old technique of Guilloché with the art and expertise of Hard Enamel. The Trellis Collection incorporates multiple levels of Guilloché on each Collection piece. The four colors of translucent hard enamel in the Trellis Collection are accented with opalescent white hard enamel and finished in 18-karat Yellow Gold and Rhodium vermeil. The fifth Trellis Collection piece features opalescent White hard enamel accented in translucent black, finished in 18-kt. Yellow Gold vermeil. The &quot;leaf and bud&quot; motif of the Trellis Collection requires multiple stages of engraving; the entire body of the pen is first cut down to the level of the guilloché pattern underneath. The pattern is then engraved onto the background of the body of the pen, omitting the trellis, and leaf and bud designs which remain in high relief. Translucent Red and Opalescent White Enamel with 18-karat Yellow Gold Vermeil.Please see other collections in David-Oscarson Fountain Pen.We also sell other Fountain Pen Refill. ADDITIONAL INFO: Genuine Product from David-Oscarson. Buy from Authorized Major dealer Only, with confidence.Brand New Product. Guaranteed for quality. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /david-oscarson-trellis/V1jZxwUIcfzUtQwe1t6l3g==/info $4,900.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/49/72/5464796e42346c3974494c457947754e4a4c51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Round Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 4&apos; Diameter Round Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 4&apos; Diameter 
 ( In stock ) 
With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Round Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety... More 

With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Round Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. The round shape allows for interaction between all students at the table. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding. Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Diameter: 4&apos; Height: 29&quot; (standard), 27&quot;, or 42&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /round-mobile-table/WIrTdynB4l9tILEyGuNJLQ==/info $449.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/64/52/36/6f5438423765754861632d667345336b653277-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Oval Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 5&apos;W x 6&apos;L Oval Mobile Table - Enamel Legs - 5&apos;W x 6&apos;L 
 ( In stock ) 
With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Oval Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety... More 

With its space-saving design and easy-roll casters, Midwest Folding Products&apos; Oval Mobile Table is a great choice for your school cafeteria or multipurpose room. Shur-Lok automatic safety locks mean you can fold and roll the table out of the way without the worry of accidents. When the table is unfolded and in place, casters lift off the ground to ensure stability. The oval shape allows for interaction between all students at the table. Backed by a 15-year warranty. Choose from several attractive colors for the top and edge banding.   Key Features Shur-Lok safety locks keep your table in place Available in a great selection of colors High-pressure laminate top w/ enamel legs Backed by a 15-year warranty Specifications Top Material: 5/8&quot; thick particleboard core Top Finish: High-pressure laminate Frame Material: 14-gauge tubular steel Leg Finish: Enamel Edge Finish: Vinyl T-mold Width: 5&apos; Length: 6&apos; Height: 29&quot; Number of Casters: 4 Caster Diameter: 4&quot; Warranty: 15 years Less 
 SCHOOLSin Store not rated See Store Info /oval-mobile-table/dR6oT8B7euHac-fsE3ke2w==/info $529.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/31/67/4b/756e7868584e4e382d554a3873545535745f67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Versace Men&apos;s 68C99SD009 S009 Reve Chrono Black Genuine Leather Diamond Watch Versace Men&apos;s 68C99SD009 S009 Reve Chrono Black Genuine Leather Diamond Watch 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) 
One of Versace’s most appreciated-and successful- collections, is augmented once more by new and captivating proposals. The logo, as always, is the protagonist, but what is totally new is... More 

One of Versace’s most appreciated-and successful- collections, is augmented once more by new and captivating proposals. The logo, as always, is the protagonist, but what is totally new is the combination of contemporary materials. The stainless steel watchcase has the Greek logo on its wide lugs, and the bezel is engraved with the brand logo on both sides. The dial is black guilloche enamel with 6 diamonds and the Medusa logo. The watchstrap is black genuine leather with a butterfly buckle. Reve Ceramic mounts a Swiss quartz movement and a chronograph feature with a 40 mm diameter. Always perfect on the wrist of the most dedicated follower of fashion. Less 
 Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /versace-mens-68c99sd009/1gKunxhXNN8-UJ8sTU5t_g==/info $1,550.00 Free Shipping Visit Store -67% http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/59/6a/74755f316334646b5a745f56434b355a426e51-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Personalized Burgundy Enamel Post-it Holder Personalized Burgundy Enamel Post-it Holder 
 ( In stock ) 
Add feminine flair to her desk with these ornate metal desk accessories. The unique Victorian- inspired scissors, pen, and Post-It holder make a beautiful and functional gift idea. Give her... More 

Add feminine flair to her desk with these ornate metal desk accessories. The unique Victorian- inspired scissors, pen, and Post-It holder make a beautiful and functional gift idea. Give her one piece for a touch of fancy in her workspace, or go all-out and give the whole set. Personalize a photo on the scissors or pen and three initials the Post-It holder. Photos have a special coating applied over them for durability. Features Scissors Brass over a white metal and enamel base Stainless steel scissor blades Made in the USA Pen Brass over a white metal and enamel base Made in the USA Post-It Holder Holds a 3&quot;x3&quot; Post-It notes pad Gold tone over a white metal base Made in the USA Order by December 7 to ensure Christmas delivery. Personalization: Scissors Personalize with your favorite photo Pen Personalize with your favorite photo Post-It Holder Personalize with up to 3 initials No returns on personalized items unless the item is damaged or defective Specifications: Scissors 6 1/2&quot; long Pen 5 1/4&quot; long Post-It Holder 5&quot; long x 3 1/2&quot; wide x 1/2&quot; high Shipping: No express delivery Please allow 2-3 weeks for delivery We apologize for any inconvenience however these items are not available for shipment to Canada Less 
 Exposures 9 store reviews See Store Info /personalized-burgundy/_Yjtu_1c4dkZt_VCK5ZBnQ==/info Exposures $45.00 $14.99 67% Off +$10.99 shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/62/55/71/4e445f716f504c4b6f637079746d5a5f4a6151-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame 
 ( In stock ) Forzieri Sterling Silver Guilloche&apos; Picture Frame Forzieri 891 store reviews See Store Info /sterling-silver/bUqND_qoPLKocpytmZ_JaQ==/info Forzieri $339.00 +$11.95 shipping Visit Store 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Enamel Restoration 
 Hot method fired enamel applied to jewelry, metal, clocks, signs. 
 www.restorationworld.com/enamel.htm 
 Guilloche 
 Jetzt viel Geld sparen. Guilloche hier bestellen! 
 www.shopmos.de/Guilloche 
 Security Design System 
 Giotto high security design system 
 www.pitagora.ch/ 
 Guilloche 
 Finden Sie den günstigsten Preis In Online-Shops 
 www.preissmart.de/ 
 Create Guilloche Patterns 
 Guilloche designs, ornaments, and borders in minutes. Pattern plug-in 
 www.artlandia.com/symmetryworks 
 
   
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -35% Enamel Print Racks black $116.97 $179.95 MisterArt.com -50% Men&apos;s Stainless Steel And Black $70.00 $140.00 eBay -43% Spray Enamels gloss beige $6.35 $11.14 MisterArt.com -36% Cleaning Pad, for Enamel $6.99 $10.99 Amazon Marketplace 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9068
	</body>
</document>
