<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007264" url="http://www.lawgazette.co.uk/news/djanogly-reveals-lawyers039-pay-legal-aid" time="2012-07-13-00:13" support="4" score="0.003125749453509716" bingtitle="Djanogly reveals lawyers&apos; pay from legal aid | The Law Gazette" webtitle="Djanogly reveals lawyerspay from legal aid | The Law Gazette">
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001063" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>... the last year, ahead of the publication of the bill ... London firm Duncan Lewis topped the table for the ... concluding that the bloke standing outside a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Navigation&apos; Privacy and cookies 
Djanogly reveals lawyers&apos;pay from legal aid
 Monday 20 June 2011 by Catherine Baksi 


The justice minister Jonathan Djanogly has provided details of the barristers and law firms paid the most from legal aid over the last year, ahead of the publication of the bill setting out the governments planned legal aid cuts.

The figures prompted the Law Society to repeat its call for the government to look at alternative ways of saving the required £350m without cutting the £2.1bn annual legal aid budget.

It suggested a £250,000 cap on the amount that solicitors or barristers could earn in any year from publicly funded cases.

Mechanisms for achieving this would include aligning QCs and leading juniors fees at the rate paid to leading juniors, and reducing the £2310 ‘event rate’ paid to QCs in family cases to attend certain case meetings regardless of their length.

Djanogly provided the figures for the highest paid barristers and firms in response to a question tabled in the House of Commons in March 2011 by Conservative MP Stewart Jackson.

London firm Duncan Lewis topped the table for the firm paid the most from the community legal service budget. It received £15,324,024, ahead of London firm Blavo&amp;Co, which received £5,994,951 and third-placed northern firm Stephensons, which got £5,770,453.

National firm Tuckers was the highest paid criminal legal aid firm, receiving £10,293,997. London firm EBR Attridge was in second place earning £6,870,842, followed by midlands firm The Johnson Partnership with £6,765,248.

Leonard Smith QC, of London’s Carmelite Chambers, was the highest-earning criminal barrister, receiving £841,960. Family barrister Paul M Storey QC, of London’s 29 Bedford Row, received the most from the community legal aid fund, receiving £582,374.

The figures represent payments made in the financial year 2009/10, and include sums for VAT and disbursements incurred.

The Ministry of Justice pointed out that the sums include work done in previous years and that overall payments may have been increased by one exceptional case lasting a number of years.

A Law Society spokesman said the figures paid to solicitors merely represents the turnover of businesses that employ large numbers of people and carry out high volumes of work, and merely confirms that the firms listed are the largest legal aid providers.

Its chief executive Des Hudson pointed out that the average legal aid lawyer earns £25,000 a year.

Bar chair Peter Lodder QC said: ‘This list shows the fees received by those at the very top of their profession. However, it does not take into account that these are payments for work which may have been carried out over a number of years; that in some cases other barristers will have carried out some of the work, for which they will have to be paid from this sum; nor the associated overhead costs of being self-employed.’

He added: ‘The vast majority of publicly-funded barristers are struggling to provide a quality service for relatively low levels of remuneration, and have not seen their fees increase for years and are now facing further cuts.’

Meanwhile, the Leader of the House of Commons said last week that the much-anticipated bill setting out the government’s reforms, which he called the Legal Aid and Sentencing Bill, will be introduced ‘shortly’.

Having been expected for the last couple of weeks, it now seems likely that it will be published before the end of this week, with some sources suggesting it will be on Tuesday.
 Subscribe to the weekly email newsletter from Gazette Online 

 Printer-friendly version 
 Join our group Follow us on Twitter Like our page 
News

 Final consultation launched on advocacy accreditation Neuberger gets top job at Supreme Court Judicial applications up 17% SDT slammed by black lawyers Rights bill commission seeks opinions for the second time Olympics cases to be fast-tracked Law applicants unfazed by tuition fee rise LinkedIn &apos;can help profession innovate&apos; Support for shot solicitor Court pioneer retains funding despite &apos;failure&apos; CILEx president in new rights plea Law firm bids for TV licence Hope over asbestos claims fund ABS pioneer condemns ‘over-qualification’ in firms LSC improvements fail to satisfy auditor Don’t cut corners, LeO warns firms Cuts opponents fuelled by self-interest, says Clarke All claimants to benefit from costs-shifting, Djanogly says Bar-solicitor divisions ‘music to government’s ears’ SRA eases insurers’ disclosure rules Freshfields and Linklaters dampen magic circle celebrations PC fee up 5%, Law Society council agrees Legal Ombudsman delays complaints publication Top-100 annual results show PEP up by 8% Society advice on SRA diversity data SRA outlines ‘race bias’ action plan Company markets &apos;first criminal legal insurance policy&apos; Law Society steps up pressure on Fiji Barclays ‘faces $6bn in Libor scandal claims’ IFA rule under scrutiny Society plans accreditation scheme for will-writing Indian call for legal liberalisation News focus: who will bring a Libor claim? Review of super-regulators calls for more openness Wills and probate company goes ABS Merger mania continues as 22% of firms report tie-ups Solicitor shooting: man charged A&amp;O;profits steady as magic circle reporting week kicks off 
 
Comments
 
 Legal Aid Pay 
 Submitted by Stephen Mannering on Tue, 21/06/2011 - 16:05. 
Did Stewart Jackson, I wonder, ask for details of those lawyers/firms who received the least in legal aid payments?

If not, aren&apos;t we entitled to ask why?

We also ought to ask Mr Jackson if he talked to the MOJ and LSC about their deliberate policy of encouraging larger &quot;suppliers&quot; to do more and more work, thus receiving more and more via Legal Aid.

Or would he be unlikely/unwilling to ask a question, the answer to which would destroy the nasty vindictive point he clearly is intent on making, willingly aided and abetted by the government?
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Legal Aid pay v Stewart Jackson&apos;s Expenses 
 Submitted by Stephen Mannering on Tue, 21/06/2011 - 16:12. 
Just to place matters in context, in 2008/9 according to They Work for You.co.uk, Stewrart Jackson MP was paid, in addition to his salary as an MP (£65,000 or so) expenses totalling just under £145,000 - so a total income of around £210,000.

I suppose him to be a fairly average MP in terms of earnings.

Wonder why he chose not to ask Mr Djanogly how much the average legal aid lawyer received?????
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Legal aid pay and government cuts 
 Submitted by Stephen Mannering on Tue, 21/06/2011 - 16:37. 
Here&apos;s a few more facts.

Stewart Jackson, according to They Work for You.co.uk, has no overt interest in lawyers or legal aid.

He is conservative MP for Peterborough.

His Party colleague Jonathan Djanogly is, on the other hand, very invloved in legal aid and the governments&apos; declared intention to kill it with a thousand cuts.

Jonathan Djanogly is, in addition to being a junior minister in the MOJ responsible for legal aid, Conservative MP for............Huntingdon, a near neighbour of Peterborough.......

His close (geographical) Party colleague with no overt interest in legal aid just happens to ask a very convenient question about how much the top earning lawyers got from legal aid which just happens to be answered in Parliament very shortly before the government publishes the legal aid and justice bill, which is its&apos; contemptuous reply to the 5000 responses it received to the &quot;consultation&quot; exercise on the legal aid green paper...........a bill which is reported to confirm that savage cuts will go ahead despite massive opposition...............

................because, of course, all legal aid lawyers are rich &quot;fat cats&quot; whose massive and undeserved luxury bought from incomes derived from the public purse should be curbed now, once and for all.................

As Sir Humphrey sometimes said, &quot;NO, MINISTER&quot;.
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Not sure why the government don’t employ firm 
 Submitted by Anonymous on Wed, 22/06/2011 - 10:56. 
Not sure why the government don’t employ firm on fix fee or use off shore law firms to to leg work and only pay to court time of expert also cutting the time that cases last would also help not sure why they take so long
I’m sure if one of these fancy lawyers took their car into garage and the mechanic tell you you’ll be charged for car parts, labour coffee boy , time takes the mechanic to get to work overalls etc you’d say that unreasonable – sorry some law firm creaming the system has too change –
yes i’m bitter i lost 20,000 on fee because i used dodgy lying lawyer who still traded
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Outsourcing 
 Submitted by Anonymous on Thu, 23/06/2011 - 12:03. 
The Government does use fixed fees and has done for years. For criminal legal aid the Magsitrates&apos; Court fees were fixed in April 2001 and have not risen since.

They don&apos;t use off-shore firms as court work still requires us to attend.

You would thnk that the best thing to do for criminal work would be to have a public defender system like the USA wouldn&apos;t you - lawers employed by the State to represent all criminals at the police station and in the courts - like the CPS in reverse.

*Slaps head* Of course they tried that didn&apos;t they - the Public Defender offices which turned out to be more expensive than those in private practice.

My garage mechanic charges more than I get on legal aid but I know that it pays the overheads.

I have to pay overheads as well.

Creaming the system? I wish.
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Legal Aid punchbag 
 Submitted by Anonymous on Wed, 22/06/2011 - 12:29. 
The overall tenor of the information released is of course &quot;Legal Aid is a gravy train, fat cat lawyers, public purse blah blah blah&quot;-but statistics never ever tell a story by themselves as the first poster succinctly points out. These figures are analogous to publishing Tom Cruise` s annual income and concluding that the bloke standing outside a fast-food restaurant handing out leaflets dressed as a chicken is an actor-therefore he`s paid as much as Tom Cruise. Basically, the cynical manipulation of these and other statistics by the Government results in poor Governance and a corresponding lack of faith in same by the public. I believe that the poodle Tory press will only be able to dissemble over the widening gaping wounds in society as a result, for so long...
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Fixed fees and offshore firms 
 Submitted by Stephen Mannering on Thu, 23/06/2011 - 10:54. 
@ Anonymous 09.56

You have an incorrect understanding of the legal aid system.

Unlike the health and education sectors, lawyers conducting work funded by legal aid are not employed by government. They have never been so employed. Such lawyers are running their own businesses, or working for those who do.

Why is it that if a local engineering firm wins a £6m government contract it is good news for the local economy, but if a local firm of solicitors receives the same they are &quot;greedy fat cats sponging off the public purse&quot;? In the first five months after the last general election an outsourcing firm, Capita, was paid £33m by this government. There was no outcry when that information was released.

Legal aid pays for the cost of a client&apos;s case, in the same way as insurance does if you make or defend a claim under most forms of insurance policy. The cost to the taxpayer has been strictly limited on a case by case basis for nearly twenty years, and is approximately one quarter of what is commercially charged in privately funded cases. Far from introducing a free market in publicly funded legal services governments of all political hues created a fixed, false &quot;market&quot; - not a market at all, in fact.

The total spend on legal aid has been fixed since 2007 at £2.2bn a year, and is now to be cut by £350m. That sounds like a lot of money. However, £2.2bn is enough only to run the NHS for one week. I repeat - one week. Annual spend on the NHS approx £108bn, and on education approx £40bn, and those budgets have increased year on year. That puts the spend on legal aid in context.

Government will in the next twelve months spend £8bn (four times the legal aid budget) on international aid.

The vast majority of fees received by lawyers in publicly funded cases are fixed fees and have been for some years. The fees paid in family cases have just been reduced by 10%. Djanogly and other members of KC and the Sunshine Gang don&apos;t mention this, and we have to ask why?

Your suggestion that offshore firms should do the leg work is unworkable. For anything other than general advice on simple issues, face to face contact is vital in the areas of law covered by legal aid, family work in particular. Yes you can outsource typing and other document production, and that does help to cut costs, but the vast majority of the work done in most cases needs to be done in this country by qualified and regulated people. Law isn&apos;t a supermarket shelf product, however much government, media and some sections of the public would like it to be. It is a complex and difficult subject that constantly changes and has to be applied to the facts of each individual case. Sometimes clients must be advised that what they want to achieve cannot be achieved, because it is simply not possible, or it is unlawful, or both. It isn&apos;t like telling Tesco you will shop at Asda because Tesco does not give you what you want as a consumer.

You suggest that only time in court should be paid for. That is rather an astounding proposal. Advocacy consitutues only part of a lawyers&apos; work. What if a lawyer manages to avoid court completely by negotiating an advantageous settlement for his client? It does happen, all the time, although KC and the Sunshine Gang would have the public believe otherwise.

I agree experts&apos; fees are a disproportionate amount of the cost of cases. They are paid, roughly, three times the rate paid to the lawyers - and government does almost nothing to stop this. We have to ask - why?

The factors influencing the length of time cases take are many and varied. For an overview on this take a look at the Booth Report (commissioned by the then government in the 90&apos;s and ignored ever since). There are plenty of other studies as well. Additionally, government policy and law-makng is an integral cause of delay. Labour created 3000 new criminal offences during its&apos; last period in power, without giving the legal systen the resources (judges, courts, staff and technonloy) to deal with the inevitable increase in workload. Obviously the systen will run less quickly and less efficiently in those conditions.

As for rates charged by garages, London main dealers charge more than double the hourly rate paid by government to lawyers in London conducting many legal aid cases. Peope pay those rates because they need their cars. I suggest the complex social and legal problems dealt with by lawyers conducting cases funded by legal aid are far more important to the fabric of society than cars, e.g.life threatening/catastrophic injuries, permanent removal of children from families, possible loss of one&apos;s home through debt, divorce, relocation of children by one parent abroad etc.

Why do you deride lawyers conducting cases funded by legal aid by referring to them as &quot;fancy&quot;? Do you refer to doctors working in the NHS as &quot;fancy doctors&quot;? Gratuitous insults detract from rather than add to your argument.

If you used a &quot;dodgy lying lawyer&quot; you should use the complaints system rahter than inappropriately use this forum to bash legal aid lawyers. Sadly there will always be rotten apples in any barrel, but that is no reason to lump us all in the same category.
 
 Report abuse 
 
 An excellent and lucid 
 Submitted by Anonymous on Thu, 23/06/2011 - 11:55. 
An excellent and lucid response explaining the facts and setting out the problems succinctly.

This is the sort of stuff which should have been produced by the Law Society and constantly repeated until understood by the public.
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Fees&amp;Earnings 
 Submitted by David on Sat, 25/06/2011 - 14:20. 
I wonder out of curiosity what Mr Djangoly&apos;s fees and also his profit share amounted to in his last year as a practising Solicitor.Anyone know ?
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Djanogly&apos;s Income as a Solicitor 
 Submitted by Stephen Mannering on Sat, 25/06/2011 - 14:54. 
He was a partner in a City of London firm - S J Berwin - so I would guesstimate somewhere between £200,000 and £800,000.

But isn&apos;t that really irrelevant? Although it may provide a small sense of satisfaction to demonstrate that he made a packet out of the law, does&apos;t that rather detract from the real issues, which are;

1. Whether we as a society want to have a legal system that denies to the poor what it throws in abundance to the wealthy (especially the corporate wealthy)?;

2. What lies behind the intention of government to &quot;reform the legal profession&quot;? Those words are used in the forward by Ken Clarke (the head of the legal profession, as Lord Chancellor) to the Government response to the&quot; consultation&quot; on reform of legal aid. Note - the Green Paper was about reform of legal aid. All rather siister, and dangerous, and if we don&apos;t stop it in its&apos; tracks it will result in serious implications for our consitution and democratic process, including the independence of the legal profession and doctrine of separation of powers (both of which appear foreign concepts to most politicians, civil servants and the general public).

We cannot say we have not been warned!
 
 Report abuse 
 
 Home News 
 News archive Obiter Lawyer in the news 
 In Practice 
 Law reports Practice advice Q&amp;A Solicitors Disciplinary Tribunal 
 In Business Features 
 Book reviews Charity Explorer Supplements 
 Opinion 
 Letters 
 Blogs 
 News blog In Business blog Euro blog Newsletter sign up RSS feeds Social media 
 Moving On 
 Submit move 
 Jobs 
 
 Supplements Subscribe RSS Charity Explorer Advertising Contact us Site policies Editorial policy 

Copyright 2012 Law Society All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
