<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007796" url="http://www.activediner.com/fast-food/restaurant/west-covina/ca/us/region-152" time="2012-07-13-00:45" support="1" score="0.0001573356497919685" bingtitle="fast food Restaurants in west covina, ca" webtitle="fast food Restaurants in west covina, ca">
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>1 - 10 of 30 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt; ... Moral is awesome here for Pick Up or delivery. Every time I order here they are fast, very ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Mexican 
 Chinese 
 Japanese 
 Thai 
 Burger 
 Brazilian 
 Continental 
 
 more... 
 American Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Brazilian Breakfast Buffet Burger Casual/Family Catering Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Coffee Shop Coffee/Donut Shop Continental Dance Floor Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Dinner Early Bird Special Fast Food Fireplace Happy Hour Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Japanese Karaoke Kids Friendly Late Night Dining Live Entertainment Lunch Mexican Outdoor Seating Pizzeria Romantic Scenic View Seafood Senior Discount Smokers Friendly Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Take Out/Carry Out Thai TV/Satellite Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access 
 
 




Popular Cities
 Los Angeles 
 Long Beach 
 Torrance 
 Pasadena 
 Santa Monica 
 Glendale 
 North Hollywood 
 Gardena 
 Burbank 
 Whittier 
 
 more... 
 Alhambra Arcadia Beverly Hills Canoga Park Carson Covina Culver City Downey El Monte Encino Huntington Park Inglewood La Puente Lancaster Manhattan Beach Montebello Northridge Norwalk Palmdale Pomona Redondo Beach Rowland Heights San Gabriel San Pedro Sherman Oaks Studio City Upland Van Nuys West Hollywood Woodland Hills 
 
 



 
 
 
   
 
 



 
   United States  &gt;  California  &gt;  west covina 
fast food Restaurants in west covina, ca
 1 - 10 of 30 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt;   
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Carl&apos;s Jr No 7391 
Fast Food
2980 East Workman Avenue, West Covina
(626) 331-3705   LATEST REVIEW   
Hi!
Well i visit this place because i love the food from there, also the prices are really affordable.
Plus the biggest two factors that make me come to this location is that my job is really close to it, and the SERVICE they offer there is AWESOME...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Pizza Hut 
American, Pizzeria, Fast Food
504 S Vincent Ave, West Covina
(626) 962-8300   LATEST REVIEW   
Moral is awesome here for Pick Up or delivery. Every time I order here they are fast, very friendly, and efficient. The pizza is good and the pastas are great&lt;3
The girl driver (J) is always recommending new specials which I can appreciate. Thank y...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Adrienne&apos;s Place 
Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food
1501 West Cameron Avenue, West Covina
(626) 856-3823   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   advertisements 
 
 
   Boca Del Rio 
Fast Food
934 Plaza Drive, West Covina
(626) 960-7963   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Burger King 
American, Burger, Fast Food
2401 S Azusa Ave, West Covina
(626) 965-4992   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Burger King - Restaurants- West Covina 
Burger, Fast Food
245 North Citrus Street, West Covina
(626) 967-9905   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   California Chicken 
Fast Food
822 Plaza Drive, West Covina
(626) 338-1088   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Carl&apos;s Jr Restaurant 
Fast Food
2400 South Azusa Avenue, West Covina
(626) 965-4455   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Dairy Queen 
Fast Food
1200 Plaza Drive, West Covina
(626) 962-4537   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Del Taco 
Mexican, Fast Food
1200 Plaza Drive, West Covina
(626) 338-4466   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   


 
 Next &gt;&gt; 



 Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for? Try searching here...
 
      Know of a restaurant we don&apos;t have?   Click here to add it. 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
