<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007399" url="http://www.feedingyourkids.com/eating-out-checking-menu.html" time="2012-07-13-00:22" support="2" score="0.0009175835814688282" bingtitle="Feeding Your Kids - Guide to feeding your kids healthy food" webtitle="Feeding Your Kids - Guide to feeding your kids healthy food">
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="130"/>
	<description>- President Bill Clinton RESULTS. Here are some of ... with planning, if you go to a restaurant / fast food restaurant ... Would you consider sharing an order of French fries?</description>
	<body>
		How to Feed Your Kids Healthier HOME | FOUNDATION | ABOUT ESZTER ERDÉLYI | CONTRIBUTORS | SUPPORT | DONATE      
ENDORSEMENTS
 
 “Since 2005, the Clinton Global Initiative has brought together thousands of business leaders, directors of nonprofits, and heads of state to make a measurable impact on pressing global challenges. The Feeding Your Kids program tackles childhood and teenage obesity by providing concrete ways to help families eat healthier and serves as a tremendous example of how our members are improving lives around the world.&quot; 
- President Bill Clinton
 

RESULTS

 Here are some of our favorite comments from people who took the program, and the survey responses from this year.

 

BREAKFAST

 Hot Cereal More Good Cereal Smoothies Eggs Protein More Ideas More Involved 

LUNCHBOXES

 Leftovers More Involved Laptop Lunchboxes The LunchBox 

SNACKS

 General Ingredients Traveling Snacks 

EATING OUT

 Checking Menu Ordering 


 
 

AROUND THE WORLD

The program has been used in 50 countries this year!

 

HOW TO SHOP

 Planning Meals Levels of Shopping Store Behavior Involving Kids 

WHAT TO SHOP

 Food Emergencies Food Inspiration Shopping Under Budget 

HOW TO COOK

 Learn to Cook in 24 Hours Almost-No-Cooking Basics Favorite Sites Books Upgrading Your Meal 

TOOLS

 Tables Used In The Program Favorite Sites Books Parent Resource Guide Planning Method 

 
 

 
Checking the Menu

Just like with planning, if you go to a restaurant / fast food restaurant with your child you can do incredible damage control if you do a few things in advance.

If you can, check out the website of the restaurant. You would be surprised to see the differences in calories between two hamburgers can reach hundreds! Would you rather pick a meal for your child or yourself which has 500 calories less? Would you consider sharing an order of French fries?

Check the children&apos;s menu, it is mind-boggling that these items are all fried, include sugar, no vegetables and fruits. Agree with your children in advance that you will substitute some items and be smarter than the restaurant.

 

 
 
 
Use of the Feeding Your Kids program or of this site constitutes acceptance of the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Feeding Your Kids®is a trademark of Eszter Erdélyi.
	</body>
</document>
