<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007718" url="http://www.ehow.com/business-accounting/" time="2012-07-13-00:40" support="2" score="0.002790940390521873" bingtitle="Business Accounting - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Business Accounting - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="5"/>
	<description>When replying to a breach of contract from a credit card company you will have to ... Narrow Your Selection. Accounting; Financial Statements; Balance Sheets; Depreciation</description>
	<body>
		money section 
 Saving&amp;Spending 
 Budgeting Banking Credit Cards Loans 
 Real Estate 
 Buying a Home Home Loans Selling a Home 
 Careers 
 Career Advice Land the Job Work for Yourself 
 Your Business 
 Starting a Business Managing Employees Running a Business 
 Insurance 
 Insurance Basics Auto Insurance Life Insurance 
 Retirement 
 Get Started Plan Ahead Make It Last 
 
 
 More eHow 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Business Business Accounting 
 
Business Accounting

 
 RSS Show Newest in Business Accounting 
 The Advantages of Larger Depreciation Expenses 
Larger depreciation expenses have a wide variety of advantages that you&apos;re going to want to be aware of. Find out about the advantages of larger depreciation expenses with help from an investment and finance professional in this free video clip.
 Division Shortcuts With Factors of 5 
When working with factors of five, certain shortcuts can make the division process a lot easier. Learn about division shortcuts with factors of five with help from an MIT Masters Candidate in Aero/Astro Engineering in this free video clip.
 Factors of a Function With the X-Intercept at Zero 
Finding the factors of a function is easy, as long as you&apos;re using the right methods. Learn about the factors of a function with the X-intercept at zero with help from a longtime mathematics educator in this free video clip.
 Can a Constant Be a Coefficient&amp;a Factor? 
Whether or not a constant can be a coefficient and a factor depends on your understanding of a few key concepts. Find out if a constant can be a coefficient and a factor with help from an experienced educator in this free video clip.
 Can X Squared Plus Anything Be Factored? 
Whether or not &quot;X squared&quot; plus any other number can be factored depends on your understanding of a few key concepts. Find out if &quot;X squared&quot; plus anything can be factored with help from a high school mathematics tutor in this free video clip.
 What Is Being Audited in Oracle? 
No matter how secure your company&apos;s database configuration, if your employees are misusing their access privileges, security breaches or downtime on critical systems may result. While you can&apos;t personally supervise every action by your employees in the company&apos;s Oracle database, you can enable one of Oracle&apos;s auditing features. These features create usage records to audit, potentially pinpointing issues with your database access.
 How to Factorize Using the Highest Common Factor 
Factorizing using the highest common factor may be necessary to complete certain types of math problems. Learn how to factorize using the highest common factor with help from an experienced math tutor in this free video clip.
 How to Post Accounting Stock Received Reports 
Giving and taking is the essence of business; every transaction involves an exchange of stock in the form of goods or services of comparable value. Posting stock received reports is easy using accounting software. You can purchase Microsoft Office Professional for $349.99 or Intuit QuickBooks for $183.95, at the time of publication. You also can opt to use freeware, such as GnuCash, Grisbi and Lazy8Ledger, among other programs.
 Canon XL1 With Nikon Lens Crop Factor 
The Canon XL1 is a standard-definition miniDV camcorder designed for both professional and personal use. This camera supports the use of lenses manufactured by different companies including Nikon with the use of an adapter. When selecting a lens for the XL1 camera, crop factor is an important consideration. The crop factor of any digital video camera determines how much of the scene the camera captures during filming.
 Internal Factor Evaluation for Google 
An internal factor evaluation (IFE) is an internal management tool and matrix used for auditing or evaluating the primary strengths and weaknesses within the operations of a company. Using this tool can help evaluate how well the company performs in any given area selected for review. When approaching such an analysis, the company completing the review may choose to use the&quot;Balanced Scorecard&quot;method when it comes to completing an IFE for Google.
 What Does the Civil Court Need From Me to Reply to a Breach of Contract From a Credit Card Company? 
When replying to a breach of contract from a credit card company you will have to supply the civil court with a few specific documents. Find out what the civil court needs from you to reply to a breach of contract from a credit card company with help from an attorney in this free video clip.
 Why Is it Necessary to Factor Both the Numerator&amp;Denominator? 
It is necessary to factor both the numerator and the denominator in a fraction for a few distinct reasons. Find out why it&apos;s necessary to factor both the numerator and the denominator with help from a high school math tutor in this free video clip.
 A Disadvantage of a Low Profit Margin 
A low profit margin certainly has its advantages, but you also need to be aware of its disadvantages. Learn about a disadvantage of a low profit margin with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 How to Reduce the Scale Factor to Original 
Reducing the scale factor to original can be accomplished in just a few quick steps. Reduce the scale factor to original with help from a high school math tutor in this free video clip.
 Steps Involved in Conducting an Internal Audit in Accounts Receivable 
Conducting an internal audit in accounts receivable is a process that can be broken down into a few basic, easy to manage steps. Learn about the steps involved in conducting an internal audit of accounts receivable with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 Accounts Receivable Financial Tips 
When it comes to accounts receivable, every small business owner could use a few tips every now and again to keep things on the right track. Get accounts receivable financial tips with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 The Four Steps of Preparing an Income Statement 
Preparing an income statement can be broken down into four easy to manage steps. Find out about the four steps of preparing an income statement with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 Invoicing, Cash Bookkeeping and the Separation of Duties 
Invoicing and cash bookkeeping are a large part of the separation of duties of any small business. Learn about invoicing, cash bookkeeping and the separation of duties with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 What Does the Audit of the Income Statement Try to Verify? 
The audit of the income statement exists to verify a few very important pieces of information. Learn what the audit of the income statement tries to verify with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 What Is Summarized on an Income Statement? 
An income statement is designed to summarize a number of different things for your convenience. Learn what is summarized on an income statement with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 Why Is a Profit Margin Negative? 
A profit margin can be negative for a few different reasons. Learn about why a profit margin is negative with help from an employee recruiter and trainer in this free video clip.
 Things to Ruin Auditions 
Knowing how an audition can be ruined can help you avoid these pitfalls out in the real world. Learn about things to ruin auditions with help from a professional actress and performer in this free video clip.
 Drama Audition Ideas 
When auditioning for a drama role you have to keep a few very important things in mind. Get drama audition ideas with help from a professional actress and performer in this free video clip.
 The Major Activities&amp;Procedures Performed by the Auditor in Each of the Four Phases of an Audit 
An auditor plays a very important role in the four phases of an audit. Find out about the major activities and procedures performed by the auditor in each of the four phases of an audit with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 The Difference Between Compliance Audits&amp;Operational Audits 
Compliance audits and operational audits are very different in a few key areas. Learn the difference between compliance audits and operational audits with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 How to Make the Power Factor Zero 
Making the power factor zero requires you to keep a few very important things in mind. Learn how to make the power factor zero with help from a high school math tutor in this free video clip.
 How to Factor Out Constant Monomial Terms 
Factoring out constant monomial terms is something that requires you to follow a few basic, easy to manage steps. Factor out constant monomial terms with help from a professional math teacher in this free video clip.
 Factorization Rules 
Factorization has some very important rules associated with it that you need to be familiar with. Learn about factorization rules with help from a professional math teacher in this free video clip.
 How to Figure the Least Common Factor 
Figuring out the least common factor requires you to keep a few specific things in mind. Figure the least common factor with help from a high school math tutor and teacher in this free video clip.
 How to Remove Variable Factors in Simplifying Radicals 
Removing variable factors in simplifying radicals requires you to follow a few basic, easy-to-manage steps. Remove variable factors in simplifying radicals with help from an expert in mathematics in this free video clip.
 What Is a Bonds Payable Classified Balance Sheet? 
When going through a balance sheet you may come across a heading titled &quot;Bonds Payable Classified.&quot; Learn about bonds payable classified on a balance sheet with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 How to Factor Common Terms From Binomials 
Factoring common terms from binomials requires you to follow a few basic, simple steps. Factor common terms from binomials with help from a distinguished math teacher in this free video clip.
 The Least Common Factor of Monomials 
Finding the least common factor of monomials doesn&apos;t have to be the most difficult thing you attempt to do in a day. Learn about the least common factor of monomials with help from a longtime math teacher in this free video clip.
 What Is a Trailing Gross Profit? 
The gross profit of a business is the total sales. Learn about trailing gross profit with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 How to Compress Your Vocals in an Audition 
Compressing your vocals can be accomplished in a very specific way. Find out how to compress your vocals in an audition with help from a professional singer and musician in this free video clip.
 Proportions With Conversion Factors in Algebra 
Certain proportions in algebra have what are known as &quot;conversion factors.&quot; Learn about proportions with conversion factors in algebra with help from a mathematics educator in this free video clip.
 How to Multiply by a Factor 
Multiplying by a factor of a certain number requires you to know just what that factor is. Multiply by a factor with help from a mathematics educator in this free video clip.
 What Do Measurable Factors Mean? 
&quot;Measurable factor&quot; is a term used to describe a very specific aspect of mathematics. Find out what &quot;measurable factors&quot; means with help from a high school math tutor in this free video clip.
 What Is the Factor String for 52? 
Finding a factor string for a number can be accomplished by starting at the beginning. Find out about a factor string for 52 with help from a high school mathematics tutor in this free video clip.
 Distributive Property to Multiply the Factors 
The distributive property often takes over when multiplying a problem with factors involved. Find out about the distributive property and using it to multiply the factors with help from a mathematics educator in this free video clip.
 What Items Would Be Affected on a Financial Statement by Perpetual and Periodic Inventory Systems? 
Certain types of items would be affected on a financial statement by perpetual and periodic inventory systems. Learn what items would be affected on a financial statement by perpetual and periodic inventory systems with help from a certified financial planner in this free video clip.
 What Is the Crop Factor for a Sony DSC-H2? 
The crop factor of a camera refers to a relative measure of the camera&apos;s sensor size. Because this number impacts lens reach and imaging performance, it is an oft-discussed benchmark of camera quality. Crop factor is more commonly related to discussions of more advanced digital SLR cameras, but it applies to compact cameras such as the Sony DSC-H2 as well.
 How to Create a Purchase Order From Outstanding Invoices in QuickBooks Online 
If you use QuickBooks Online Plus, you can create a purchase order from an outstanding invoice or vendor transaction. QuickBooks Online Essentials and QuickBooks Online Simple Start versions do not offer the purchase order feature; you must have QuickBooks Online Plus. In addition, you must activate the purchase order feature before you can create purchase orders.
 What Is Meant by Disclosure in Auditing? 
Disclosure of information is critical to the auditing process from beginning to end. Accounting employees disclose all financial information to auditors before an audit, and auditors disclose all findings from the audit after it is completed. Without disclosure, auditors cannot ensure that their findings are correct, making the audit worthless to a business and its investors.
 Data Needed to Prepare an Accounts Receivable Report 
Financial statements are used to communicate accurate and reliable financial information to end users in an efficient and effective manner. Often, financial statements intended to help end users internal to the organization differ from those intended to help external end users because of differing needs and focuses. Accounts receivable reports, also called aging accounts receivable reports, are financial statements intended to help management understand the chances of collecting on short-term debts owed to its organization. Information needed to prepare such reports can be either calculated or found on source documents such as bills and receipts.
 The Typical Backscatter Factors of Nickel and Copper 
Backscatter is a technique used to determine the depth of a metal coating by bouncing particles in the form of waves or rays off a second layer of metal beneath the surface. Backscatter started out as a way to measure cast-steel rolls, but advances in technology have allowed the measurement of thinner materials. Two metals that may be the subject of backscatter measurements, either as coatings or substrates, are copper and nickel.
 What Is a Good Accounts Receivable Turnover Ratio for Food&amp;Beverage? 
Accounts receivable turnover rates can provide you with a strong indication of how well your company is doing in the food and beverage distribution industry. Accounts receivable is the accounting term that refers specifically to the money owed to you by the vendors who rely upon you for their food service needs. Restaurants, hotels and even grocery stores rely upon short-term credit to purchase their supplies. The short-term debt they incur generally has to be paid back in 60 days or fewer. The turnover ratio in accounts receivable will tell you how often suppliers are moving their food products.
 Cycle Count Accounting Procedures 
Cycle count accounting procedures can make your life better, so long as you understand what they mean. Learn about cycle count accounting procedures with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 Resignation of an Audit 
&quot;Resignation of an audit&quot; is a very important term for all business owners to know. Learn about resignation of an audit with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 The Correlation Between an Increase in Foreign Workers&amp;Profit Margin 
Increase in foreign workers and profit margin are related in a very specific way. Learn about the correlation between an increase in foreign workers and profit margin with help from a business consultant and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 
 
Narrow Your Selection

 Accounting Financial Statements Balance Sheets Depreciation Accounting Information Systems Internal Controls Miscellaneous Business Accounting Factoring Accounting Management Audits General Ledgers Software for Accounting Financial Accounting Gross Profit Accrual Accounting Cash Flow Statements Audit Procedures Invoices Income Statements Accounts Receivable CPAs Accounting Terms Managerial Accounting Profit&amp;Loss Statements Audit Checklists Depreciation Methods Accounting Systems Accounting Procedures Company Credit Cards Financial Statement Analysis Prepare Financial Statements Receipts Bookkeeping Audit Reports Purchase Orders Collect a Debt Cost Accounting Asset Accounting Accounts Payable Accounting Standards Profit Margins Accounting Policies Tax Accounting Accounting Principles Forensics Accounting Compliance Audits Pro Forma Pro Forma Financial Statements Accounting Rules Expense Reporting Set Up Accounting Systems Amortization Accounting&amp;Finance Software External Audits Pro Forma Invoices Accounting Ethics Accounting Journals Accounting Training Open Book Accounting Start an Accounting Business GAAP Accounting Ledgers Internal Audits Set Up Quickbooks Accounting Books Corporate Credit Cards Demand Letters Peachtree Accounting Accounting Technicians QuickBooks Information Chart of Accounts Audit Tools 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
