<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007567" url="http://www.celiac.com/gluten-free/topic/28504-mcdonalds-french-fries/page__st__15" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="6" score="0.013991870568487967" bingtitle="Mcdonald&apos;s French Fries - Celiac.com Celiac Disease &amp; Gluten-Free ..." webtitle="Mcdonalds French Fries - Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum - Page 2">
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000634" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="17"/>
	<description>I haven&apos;t been to fast food restaurant since My Last Hurrah (the 3 ... comment I have is: Why must you continue to pick ... Most fryers are located front -left of the counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Celiac.com Sponsor: 
 

 

 Ads by Google: 
 
Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum: Mcdonald&apos;s French Fries - Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum

 Jump to content 
 Sign In» 
 New user? Register Now! Help 

 Advanced Search 
 Gluten-Free Forum Home Members Gluten-Free Mall Celiac.com Home Journal of Gluten Sensitivity Calendar Blogs 
 
 Follow us: | Support Us: 
 Subscribe to FREE Celiac.com email alerts 
 Subscribe to Journal of Gluten Sensitivity 
 Share us: 
 
 Ads by Google: 
 

 

      Shop At: The Gluten-Free Mall 
 Dozens of Daily Specials - Up to 50% OFF! 
 
 Celiac.com Sponsor: 
 
 
 Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum &gt; Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum &gt; Gluten-Free Ingredients&amp;Food Labeling Issues 

 Board Rules/Privacy View New Content Mark Board As Read 
 
 2 Pages ← 1 2 

 You cannot start a new topic You cannot reply to this topic 
 
 Mcdonald&apos;s French Fries They say gluten-free but ingredients prove otherwise! Rate Topic: 
 
 #16   angelbender   
 
 Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 63 Joined: 17-January 07 
 
Posted 20 January 2007 - 12:08 AM 
 Hi!I haven&apos;t been to fast food restaurant since My Last Hurrah (the 3 months I went off the gluten free diet in order to undergo testing including a biopsy. I don&apos;t DARE since I&apos;ve been poisoned at a regular restaurant where I carefully explain how to prepare my food. I missed fries too so here is what I do for MY Fry Fix: Ore Ida Extra Crispy Easy Fries, Golden Crinkles. They are microwave ready in 4 minutes. The ingredients are as follows: potatoes, partially hydrogenated vegetable oil (soybean, canola and/or cotton seed), salt, dextrose, disodium dihydrogen pyrophosphate , annatto (vegetable color). And it lists CONTAINS SOYBEANS. Are they&quot;healthy?&quot;.....uh, doubtful.....are they good?.....you bet!With LOTS of Heinz ketchup!I don&apos;t think they are crispy, in fact they remind me of the fries from White Castle, for those of you that are in the Chicago or MidWest United States area. I&apos;ve&apos;found them at all major food stores; the cheapest is Meijer&apos;s for 99 cents. I think that&apos;s probably about what they cost at a fast food store for one serving. Hope this helps somebody satisfy that craving for a goody!
Oh yeah, and I&apos;ve never felt that I&apos;ve been&quot;glutened.&quot;
 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #17   JodiC   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 121 Joined: 02-May 06 
 
Posted 18 February 2007 - 02:06 PM 
 McDonalds can make anyone feel glutened. My non celiac family takes turns in the bathroom after eating that junk. Did you know a McDonalds hamb can keep for nine years without molding. I think if you are trying to be healthier by remaining celiac free... fast food should also be off the menu.
 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #18   broncobux   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 1,235 Joined: 12-January 05 
 
Posted 18 February 2007 - 07:12 PM 
 
 angelbender, on Jan 20 2007, 12:08 AM, said:
 Hi!I haven&apos;t been to fast food restaurant since My Last Hurrah (the 3 months I went off the gluten free diet in order to undergo testing including a biopsy. I don&apos;t DARE since I&apos;ve been poisoned at a regular restaurant where I carefully explain how to prepare my food. I missed fries too so here is what I do for MY Fry Fix: Ore Ida Extra Crispy Easy Fries, Golden Crinkles. They are microwave ready in 4 minutes. The ingredients are as follows: potatoes, partially hydrogenated vegetable oil (soybean, canola and/or cotton seed), salt, dextrose, disodium dihydrogen pyrophosphate , annatto (vegetable color). And it lists CONTAINS SOYBEANS. Are they&quot;healthy?&quot;.....uh, doubtful.....are they good?.....you bet!With LOTS of Heinz ketchup!I don&apos;t think they are crispy, in fact they remind me of the fries from White Castle, for those of you that are in the Chicago or MidWest United States area. I&apos;ve&apos;found them at all major food stores; the cheapest is Meijer&apos;s for 99 cents. I think that&apos;s probably about what they cost at a fast food store for one serving. Hope this helps somebody satisfy that craving for a goody!
Oh yeah, and I&apos;ve never felt that I&apos;ve been&quot;glutened.&quot; 

Angel, cook them in the oven and they wil taste much better and be crispy...
 No-Gluten-in-Vegas 

 Formerly&quot;NO-Gluten-In-San-Diego&quot; 
 Formerly&quot;GLUTEN-FREE-IN-OHIO&quot; 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #19   blueeyedmanda   
 
 York Fair 2009 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 5,569 Joined: 24-January 06 
 
Posted 18 February 2007 - 07:29 PM 
 I prefer the french fries I make in my own oven. Much tastier, healthier, and safe.
 ~~~~Gluten Free since 9/2004~~~~~~ 


Friends may come and go but Sillies are Forever!!!!!!!

 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #20   larry mac   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 1,176 Joined: 04-January 07 
 
Posted 18 February 2007 - 08:11 PM 
 
 JodiC, on Feb 18 2007, 04:06 PM, said:
 ..... Did you know a McDonalds hamb can keep for nine years without molding...... 

I&apos;m not trying to defend mcdonalds because personally, I&apos;ve never been a Mcdonald fries lover anyway. They&apos;re OK, but I prefer others. However, my son worked there and they only fry fries in a dedicated fryer. The Mcdonalds in our Walmart is small and you can see all the cooking. They have very set procedures for everything. I don&apos;t have any concerns regarding CC of the fries at our Mcdonalds. I wouldn&apos;t eat anything else though. Their burgers made me marginally ill even before I had celiac.

As regards the statement jc makes (quoted above). What is that supposed to mean? Are you saying mold won&apos;t grow on the bun? Or bacteria won&apos;t grow on the meat patti? Come on, that&apos;s really a silly statement now isn&apos;t it?

best regards, lm
 gluten-free 12-18-06

colonoscopy
blood, urine, stool tests
prometheus testing
endoscopy, positive biopsies
diagnosed celiac by GI 12-18-06


 &quot;Sobriety sucks. That&apos;s why they invented booze in the first place.&quot;Denis Leary - Rescue Me 

 Beware the chocolate of Chiapa 

 Liquidum non frangit jejunum 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #21   Juliebove   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 3,086 Joined: 22-December 06 
 
Posted 18 February 2007 - 11:55 PM 
 
 larry mac, on Feb 18 2007, 11:11 PM, said:
 I&apos;m not trying to defend mcdonalds because personally, I&apos;ve never been a Mcdonald fries lover anyway. They&apos;re OK, but I prefer others. However, my son worked there and they only fry fries in a dedicated fryer. The Mcdonalds in our Walmart is small and you can see all the cooking. They have very set procedures for everything. I don&apos;t have any concerns regarding CC of the fries at our Mcdonalds. I wouldn&apos;t eat anything else though. Their burgers made me marginally ill even before I had celiac.

As regards the statement jc makes (quoted above). What is that supposed to mean? Are you saying mold won&apos;t grow on the bun? Or bacteria won&apos;t grow on the meat patti? Come on, that&apos;s really a silly statement now isn&apos;t it?

best regards, lm 

CC wasn&apos;t the issue. The issue was the wheat and milk used somewhere along the line in the process of making the fries that was previously undisclosed. And the mumbo jumbo they threw at us to explain why the wheat and milk won&apos;t affect us.

But not all McD&apos;s use a dedicated fryer. There are many different sizes of establishments with different menus.
 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #22   blueeyedmanda   
 
 York Fair 2009 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 5,569 Joined: 24-January 06 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 04:52 AM 
 I am not sure if ours has a dedicated fryer or not, they do cook the chicken fingers, and sometimes I found crumbs in with my hubbies fries. So thats enough of a reason for me to stay away. Plus...I was never fond of the fries, they were either dried up or too salty. There were very few times when the fries were very good.
 ~~~~Gluten Free since 9/2004~~~~~~ 


Friends may come and go but Sillies are Forever!!!!!!!

 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #23   darlindeb25   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Banned Posts: 2,324 Joined: 21-January 04 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 05:07 AM 
 I too am very sensitive to gluten and I was never glutened by McDonald&apos;s fries. My son used to bring them to me all the time. At the time, he was a manager of a local McD&apos;s. I haven&apos;t tried fries in a while because I can&apos;t have potatoes anymore, yet my sister still eats them and she is very sensitive too.

The biggest comment I have is: Why must you continue to pick on McD&apos;s? Burger King is no different, nor Wendy&apos;s, nor restaurants. You can be CC&apos;d at any of these. Your safety is at the hands of the person preparing your food, not the actual food. The McD fries have been found gluten-free, give them a break--they came out with the ingredients, they had them tested, they have proved themselves. I think that says a lot for the company. If you do not feel comfortable eating there, then don&apos;t, yet let those who feel ok with McD&apos;s enjoy their fries.

Any time you eat anything away from home that you did not prepare or someone you trust prepared, then you are taking a risk, that is the choice we make.
 Deb
Long Island, NY

Double DQ1, subtype 6

We urge all doctors to take time to listen to your patients.. don&apos;t&quot;isolate&quot;symptoms but look at the whole spectrum. If a patient tells you s/he feels as if s/he&apos;s falling apart and&quot;nothing seems to be working properly&quot;, chances are s/he&apos;s right!

&quot;The calm river of your life approaches the rocky chute of the rapids - flow on through. You are the same water. The rocks cannot hurt you. Remember, now and then, that you are the water and not the boat. Flow on! 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #24   Viola 1   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 610 Joined: 23-December 06 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 12:54 PM 
 
 darlindeb25, on Feb 19 2007, 08:07 AM, said:
 I too am very sensitive to gluten and I was never glutened by McDonald&apos;s fries. My son used to bring them to me all the time. At the time, he was a manager of a local McD&apos;s. I haven&apos;t tried fries in a while because I can&apos;t have potatoes anymore, yet my sister still eats them and she is very sensitive too.

The biggest comment I have is: Why must you continue to pick on McD&apos;s? Burger King is no different, nor Wendy&apos;s, nor restaurants. You can be CC&apos;d at any of these. Your safety is at the hands of the person preparing your food, not the actual food. The McD fries have been found gluten-free, give them a break--they came out with the ingredients, they had them tested, they have proved themselves. I think that says a lot for the company. If you do not feel comfortable eating there, then don&apos;t, yet let those who feel ok with McD&apos;s enjoy their fries.

Any time you eat anything away from home that you did not prepare or someone you trust prepared, then you are taking a risk, that is the choice we make. 

Well said Deb!
I react to the smallest things, and can eat their fries with no problem.

Having said that ... Make your own choice!That&apos;s what life is all about, if you are an adult you have the freedom to chose.
 Shirley 


 [Save the Earth, It&apos;s the only planet with chocolate and wine. 

 It isn&apos;t about waiting for the storm to pass...
It&apos;s about learning to dance in the rain.

Gluten free since 1989 

 West Kootenay.... British Columbia 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #25   gf4life   
 
 Our family&quot;photo&quot;as drawn by my daughter Hannah 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 1,634 Joined: 31-December 03 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 01:31 PM 
 I personally don&apos;t eat McDonald&apos;s food, but that is for weightloss/health reasons. I do believe they are gluten free because they had them tested and they were fine. So for my kids, I let them eat the fries once a month, not usually more than that because all that grease isn&apos;t healthy. They never have had a reaction to them. Occasionally two of the three kids will get a bunless burger (usually my daughter just wants the Happy Meal toy!), and sometimes I let them get a sundae or an M&amp;M McFlurry.

Besides In-N-Out Burger, McDonald&apos;s is the only other fast food place we eat at.
 ~West Coast-Central California~ 

 Mariann, gluten intolerant and mother of 3 gluten intolerant children 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #26   JohnnieHamill   
 
 New Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Members Posts: 10 Joined: 08-February 07 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 02:48 PM 
 As a former employee of McDonald&apos;s if you are in a hurry and there is no room in the nugget fryer or the fish fryer, you do use the french fry fryer. Been there. Done that.
 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
 Johnnie Ruth Hamill 

 Gluten-Free Since 1993 
Never formally diagnosed as DH (told eczema), but improved within 3 months after dietary change
Mother has DH since 1987
Niece possibly has DH but has not seen a doctor 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #27   gf4life   
 
 Our family&quot;photo&quot;as drawn by my daughter Hannah 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 1,634 Joined: 31-December 03 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 03:02 PM 
 But they don&apos;t deep fry the nuggets or fish anymore, they bake them on trays in a little oven thing, right? I&apos;ve seen them pulling them out of the ovens. Or are those just warming ovens?
 ~West Coast-Central California~ 

 Mariann, gluten intolerant and mother of 3 gluten intolerant children 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #28   anerissara   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 200 Joined: 03-February 05 
 
Posted 19 February 2007 - 08:15 PM 
 Sadly, I just checked both the website and another source http://www.celiacsoc...com/default.asp 


 http://app.mcdonalds.com/countries/usa/foo...s/allergens.pdf 

Both say that the fries contian wheat :o(

I don&apos;t know how much or if it&apos;s a matter of not being able to *prove* there&apos;s none, but I&apos;m not up for taking any chances. Sigh. Oh, well....it wasn&apos;t my healthiest habit anyway!
 &quot;I will say of the Lord,&apos;He is my refuge and my fortress, my God, in whom I trust.&apos;&quot;-Psalm 91

gluten-free since January 26th, 2005
Feeling up and down, but better!

Mommy of a gluten-free 8 yr old, a 6 yr old who (much to her dismay) will be gluten-free soon and a 2 yr old who is so far symptom-free. Contemplating putting the whole family on the gluten-free diet since crumbs have become my nemisis! 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #29   johnsoniu   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 151 Joined: 20-February 07 
 
Posted 21 February 2007 - 01:26 PM 
 All McDonald&apos;s are set up and designed to have dedicated fryers, that is corporate policy. However, after the restaurant is opened it is up the the franchise owner and manger as to how they decide to utilize the equipment. Most, probably 90%+, operate them as dedicated fryers as that is the way they have been trained. Of course, in the case of a rush, you never know what an unsupervised,experienced fry cook might pull to save a little time.
If you are really jonesing for a McD fry fix and want to minimize CC issues, go in at non-peak traffic times, watch for a few minutes, and order when they drop a new batch. Most fryers are located front -left of the counter and you can watch the entire handling process.

As far as a Mc D hamburger sitting on a shelf for nine years :P , 80% urban legend, 20% truth. I&apos;ve heard date ranges from five years to infinity. The recommended frozen shelf life is 30 months. I think the main point is that with all the preservatives and enzymes they contain, the patty itself is fairly resistant to decay. It wouldn&apos;t surprise me one iota if you let a cooked one sit for a year and it still looked edible :o
 John


 positive blood tests 2/07
positive endoscopy 2/07 
 colonoscopy with benign polyps 2/07 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 
 #30   JodiC   
 
 Advanced Community Member 
 

 
 Group: Advanced Members Posts: 121 Joined: 02-May 06 
 
Posted 21 February 2007 - 03:08 PM 
 
 larry mac, on Feb 18 2007, 10:11 PM, said:
 I&apos;m not trying to defend mcdonalds because personally, I&apos;ve never been a Mcdonald fries lover anyway. They&apos;re OK, but I prefer others. However, my son worked there and they only fry fries in a dedicated fryer. The Mcdonalds in our Walmart is small and you can see all the cooking. They have very set procedures for everything. I don&apos;t have any concerns regarding CC of the fries at our Mcdonalds. I wouldn&apos;t eat anything else though. Their burgers made me marginally ill even before I had celiac.

As regards the statement jc makes (quoted above). What is that supposed to mean? Are you saying mold won&apos;t grow on the bun? Or bacteria won&apos;t grow on the meat patti? Come on, that&apos;s really a silly statement now isn&apos;t it?

best regards, lm 



Ever watched Nightline, 20/20 or CNN? The burger and bun looked the same, just alittle dry. So no, I don&apos;t think that&apos;s a&quot;silly statement&quot;!!!!
 0 
 Back to top of the page up there ^ 
 Forum Home Celiac.com Celiac Disease&amp;Gluten-Free Diet Forum   |-- Gluten-Free and Celiac Disease Calendar of Events   |-- Board/Forum Technical Help   |-- Celiac Disease - Coping With   |-- Celiac Disease - Doctors   |-- Celiac Disease - Friends and Loved Ones of Celiacs   |-- Celiac Meeting Room   |-- Celiac Disease - Parents of Kids or Babies With Celiac Disease   |-- Celiac Disease - Post Diagnosis, Recovery/Treatment(s)   |-- Celiac Disease - Pre-Diagnosis, Testing&amp;Symptoms   |-- Celiac Disease - Pregnancy   |-- Celiac Disease - Publications&amp;Publicity   |-- Celiac Disease - Related Disorders&amp;Research   |-- Celiac Disease - Sleep   |-- Celiac Disease - Support Groups   |-- Celiac Disease - Teenagers&amp;Young Adults Only   |-- Dermatitis Herpetiformis   |-- Gluten-Free Recipes - Baking&amp;Cooking Tips   |-- Gluten-Free Diet&amp;Weight Issues   |-- Gluten-Free Restaurants   |-- Gluten-Free Foods, Products, Shopping&amp;Medications   |-- Gluten-Free Ingredients&amp;Food Labeling Issues   |-- Gluten-Free Sports and Fitness   |-- Gluten-Free Travel   |-- Gluten-Free International Room (Outside USA)   |-- Gluten Intolerance and behavior   |-- Super Sensitive Celiacs&amp;Gluten Sensitive   |-- Other Food Intolerance and Leaky Gut Issues   |-- Gab/Chat Room - To Discuss Anything BUT Celiac Disease / Gluten-Free Diet 
 ←Previous Topic Gluten-Free Ingredients&amp;Food Labeling Issues Next Topic→ 

Share this topic:

 

 
 2 Pages ← 1 2 

 You cannot start a new topic You cannot reply to this topic 
 
 
1 User(s) are reading this topic
 0 members, 1 guests, 0 anonymous users 
 
Delete Post
 Remove From View 
The post may still be visible to moderators in this topic

Reason: 
 Delete From Topic 
The post will be removed from this topic completely

 
 
 
Skin and Language
 Language: English (USA) 
Execution Stats

 Time Now: Jul 12 2012 02:32 PM 
 
 Back To Top Forum Home Delete My Cookies Mark Board As Read
	</body>
</document>
