<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007487" url="http://myworldreviews.com/reviews/Einstein_Bros_Bagels-105.html" time="2012-07-13-00:27" support="5" score="0.011135909847107956" bingtitle="Review of Einstein Bros. Bagels at MyWorldReviews.com" webtitle="Review of Einstein Bros. Bagels at MyWorldReviews.com">
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000276" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>When paying, they ask your name, and confirm your order for ... It&apos;s a fast food restaurant - reservations aren&apos;t available or ... This was a fairly large glass of orange juice ...</description>
	<body>
		MyWorldReviews.com 

Your Reviews About the World
 
 About Add Review Browse Search My Account Random Review 
 
MyWorldReviews.com

Let the world know what you think
 
Einstein Bros. Bagels

Las Vegas, Nevada, United States
 4626 South Maryland Pkwy
Las Vegas, Nevada, United States
89119
702-795-7800
www.einsteinbros.com View Map Overall Experience: 8 / 10 Date Visited: Friday, October 12, 2007 Visited: Breakfast Seating: Indoor Seating Area 
Einstein Bagels is a chain of breakfast fast food restaurants. They offer bagels and bagel sandwiches at affordable prices. This particular store is located across from the University of Nevada, Las Vegas.

At Einstein Bagels, you give them your name when placing your order, and then move to the payment line. When paying, they ask your name, and confirm your order for you. I like how this system tries to help eliminate ordering mistakes.

Dress

Shorts and a t-shirt are acceptable.

Reservations

It&apos;s a fast food restaurant - reservations aren&apos;t available or needed.

Cost

Fairly affordable - a toasted bagel is $1.49

Items Ordered

Sesame Seed Bagel
 Sesame Seed Bagel Cost: $1.49 
The bagel was toasted and buttered (somewhat irregularly). There was nothing notable about it - it was a typical toasted sesame seed bagel.

Asiago Cheese Pretzel
 Asiago Cheese Pretzel Cost: $1.99 
Pretzels are always fun, especially a pretzel with asiago cheese on top. This pretzel was served toasted/warm.

Freshly Squeezed Orange Juice
 Freshly Squeezed Orange Juice Cost: $3.49 
This was a fairly large glass of orange juice - it was quite good, and a reasonable value at $3.49.


 
review contents
 Dress Reservations Cost Items Ordered Sesame Seed Bagel Asiago Cheese Pretzel Freshly Squeezed Orange Juice 
related reviews

More reviews of this restaurant

 Einstein Bros. Bagels 


More reviews in Las Vegas, NV

 View 

Been here? Want to write your own review of this restaurant?

 Review this restaurant 


 Contact Us | Disclaimer | Privacy Policy | Sitemap | Logout
	</body>
</document>
