<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007802" url="http://www.wowjobs.ca/job/Front+Counter+Attendant-mcdonalds+restaurant-parksville+bc-7077850" time="2012-07-13-00:45" support="12" score="0.03791170327137753" bingtitle="Front Counter Attendant Job - PARKSVILLE - McDonalds Restaurant ..." webtitle="Front Counter Attendant Job  - PARKSVILLE - McDonalds Restaurant Job Id: 7077850 -WowJobs Canada">
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000531" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000219" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>... Queen Grill &amp; Chill Saskjobs.ca Front Counter... - Package take-out food ... Stock refrigerators and salad bars - Take Food assembler - fast food (Fast Food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Employers My.WowJobs Sign In 
 
 
 Keywords (Job Title or Skill) Location (City, Province or Postal)   Advanced Search 
 


 
Front Counter Attendant job - PARKSVILLE - McDonalds Restaurant
 



 
 Front Counter Attendant (Expired) McDonalds Restaurant PARKSVILLE Front Counter Attendant McDonalds Restaurant Terms Wages Hours/wk Part Time $8.00-$12.00 10+ Term of Job Date Posted Job ID 10/26/2009 8390 Requirements: Front Counter Attendants perform the following duties: take customers&apos; order, receive payment, assemble and serve the order, stock refrigerated and dry products, ensure service areas are cleaned according to corporate procedures and uses approved cleaning agents. The Front Counter Attendant adheres to corporate sanitation procedures and policies, ensures appearance is neat, professional and clean at all times. Applicants must be available to work evenings and week-ends. We strive to create a team environment, regular wage and performance reviews. Perks include 50 % Employee Food Discount and free uniforms. How To Apply: Please apply with resume in person to McDonalds Restaurant, 310 W Island Hwy, Parksville, BC - Attention: Manager on Duty. Deadline is November 25, 2009. View These Job listings as a PDF file using Acrobat Reader --&gt; Calendar | Oceanside Works | McDonalds Restaurant careercentre.org Front Counter Attendant Jobs .... Found at careercentre.org on 2009-10-26 16:49:05 



 
 Recent
	</body>
</document>
