<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007930" url="http://www.buybusiness.com/US/Michigan/Oil-Change-Businesses-For-Sale" time="2012-07-13-00:54" support="1" score="0.0012038490662409382" bingtitle="Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Michigan | $5,000,000,000 Selection" webtitle="Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Michigan | $5,000,000,000 Selection">
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="5"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant For Sale ... have steadily increased in this beautiful 3 bay oil change shop in western suburban Wayne county.</description>
	<body>
		$5,000,000,000 of Businesses For Sale! 2462 Buyers Online Now 
 Buy Business Sell Business Business Brokers My Account 
 
 
Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Michigan
 
 
 Business For Sale Showcase 
 More 
 Sorry, but we do not currently have any Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Michigan. Please browse our site for Oil Change Businesses For Sale near Michigan . If you have any Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Michigan, please feel free to sell your business here, on the leading Michigan Oil Change Businesses For Sale website. 
 
 
 
 Businesses For Sale Totaling $6,352,781,074 
 More 
 
 Auto Repair Shop For Sale Alberta, Canada $2,490,000 Restaurant For Sale Iuka, Mississippi, United States $99,500 Clothing Store For Sale Bonita Springs, Florida, United States $23,900 Gas Station For Sale New Smithville, Pennsylvania, United States $1,250,000 
 
 
 
 Businesses For Sale in Over 400 Categories 
 More 
 
 Hospitals For Sale Payday Loan Stores For Sale Massage Businesses For Sale Pawn Shops For Sale Vocational Schools For Sale Bistros For Sale Answering Services For Sale Billiard Halls For Sale Diners For Sale Tile Shops For Sale Seminars For Sale Dance Studios For Sale Photo Labs For Sale Fence Businesses For Sale Gift Shops For Sale Pharmacies For Sale Frame Stores For Sale Salons For Sale Drywall Businesses For Sale Museums For Sale Jewelry Stores For Sale Pretzel Shops For Sale Mobile Stores For Sale Yogurt Shops For Sale Auto Paint Shops For Sale Recording Studios For Sale Restaurants For Sale Beauty Businesses For Sale Muffler Shops For Sale Skate Shops For Sale Car Washes For Sale Truck Stops For Sale Roofing Businesses For Sale 
 
 Sell Your Business Fast! 
 
 Place Your Ad Today! Standard Featured 50,000+ Buyers Every Month Standard 3x Leads Google™, Bing™, Yahoo™,&amp;More Real-Time Charts&amp;Analytics Customized Marketing Tools Unlimited Business Photos Multiple Category Advertising Preferred Listing Position Showcase Exposure Additional options available 
 
 
 
Related Resources
 Provided by Google™, Bing™,&amp;Yahoo™ 
 
 
 
 
 
 Gas Stations For Sale In Michigan Towing Businesses For Sale In Michigan Truck Stops For Sale In Michigan Gas Stations In Michigan Towing Businesses In Michigan Truck Stops In Michigan Muffler Shops For Sale In Michigan RV Rental Businesses For Sale In Michigan Truck Rental Businesses For Sale In Michigan Muffler Shops In Michigan RV Rental Businesses In Michigan Truck Rental Businesses In Michigan 

 Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Dearborn Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Redford Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Livonia Oil Change Businesses In Dearborn Oil Change Businesses In Redford Oil Change Businesses In Livonia Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Warren Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Farmington Hills Oil Change Businesses For Sale In Saginaw Oil Change Businesses In Warren Oil Change Businesses In Farmington Hills Oil Change Businesses In Saginaw 
 
 Oil Change Businesses For Sale Business For Sale Sell A Oil Change Business for Sale Ads Search thousands of Oil Change Businesses for Sale. at the moment Car Wash: @ present averaging $20.00 per car Permits are in place to expand the present location to a Mi http://www.businessbroker.net/Keyword/Oil%20Change-Businesses_For_Sale.aspx Oil Change Businesses For Sale, Lube&amp;Tuneup Shops For Sale SELL BUSINESS $10/m★ or Buy OIL CHANGE BUSINESSES FOR SALE, LUBE&amp;TUNEUP SHOPS FOR SALE, Buying, Selling Maintenance&amp;Tuneup Business Online, Maintenance Arizona Arkansas California Connecticut Florida Hawaii Idaho Illinois Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maryland Mass. Michigan http://www.businessnation.com/Businesses_for_Sale/Automotive/Maintenance-Tuneup/ Oil Change Businesses For Sale Business For Sale Sell A 2,754 Listings Found: Oil Change Businesses For Sale. Your search generated the following Oil Change businesses for sale. To view additional details about an individual Oil Change business for sale, including contact information, simply MI http://www.businessbroker.net/Keyword/Page2_Oil%20Change-Businesses_For_Sale.aspx Quick Lube Businesses For Sale Buy A Quick Lube Business Well Established Oil Change Shops in Michigan For Sale #BFS292692 Industry: Quick lube/10 minute oil facilities located in Toledo, Ohio area near the Michigan/Ohio border for sale, business only. 2 of the best locations in http://www.mergernetwork.com/index/quick-lube-and-oil-change-businesses-for-sale Midmichigan Quick Oil Change Franchises: Business For Sale If you are within driving distance of Lansing, Jackson, Ann Arbor or Kalamazoo and would like to own your own business, consider owning these two well run oil change facilities. You will learn everything you need to know from a well known Michigan franchisor. Last year one of the stores was http://www.bizbuysell.com/Business-Opportunity/Mid-Michigan-Quick-Oil-Change-Franchises/558720/ Buy A Mid Michigan Quick Oil Change Franchises Business For Buy a Mid Michigan Quick Oil Change Franchises For Sale business for sale. Search more than 54,000 businesses for sale in the US, UK and over 80 countries. http://us.businessesforsale.com/us/Mid-Michigan-Quick-Oil-Change-Franchises-For-Sale.aspx Oil Change Business For Sale Businesses For Sale In Directory Oil change business for sale Yearly fast lubricate resume, is it still practicable? I desire to point out about the fast lubricate Oil change business ATM business for sale; Business for sale Michigan Macomb County; Profitable Commercial Pressure Wash http://business-sale.biz/businesses/oil-change-business-for-sale/ Charlevoix County, Mi Businesses For Sale Bizbuysell.Com Browse the following Charlevoix County, MI businesses currently available for sale on BizBuySell. Find a Charlevoix County business opportunity to meet your needs, from absentee owner businesses to established high cash flow businesses. http://www.bizbuysell.com/michigan/charlevoix-county-businesses-for-sale/ Directory Of Franchise Opportunities&amp;Business Franchises Michigan ; Minnesota ; Mississippi ; Missouri ; Montana Own a franchise in the booming oil change category of the automotive industry and you’ll Explore the wide variety of franchises and business opportunities for sale in this category by clicking on the http://www.franchise.com/automobile-car-wash/oil-change.cfm Acfs: Automotive Lube Centers For Sale And Lease Automotive express oil change business: for sale or lease in , ca corner oil change location. heavy retail, next to kohls, remax, radio shack, starbucks, ralphs and m. http://www.autocentersforsale.com/auto_centers/business_type_1.asp 
 Home Help Terms of Service Privacy Policy Business For Sale Sell Business ©2012 BuyBusiness.com.  All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
