<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007299" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/burger-king-providence-551888" time="2012-07-13-00:16" support="3" score="0.004822010340273636" bingtitle="Burger King - Reviews &amp; Menu - Olneyville - 60 Hartford Ave ..." webtitle="Burger King - Reviews&amp;Menu - Olneyville - 60 Hartford Ave, Providence 02909">
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="131"/>
	<description>If you took a fast food restaurant and hired a bunch of untrained chimps, you would ... The untrained chimp repeats back, whopper NO cheese, little order confirmation sign ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 Burger King Menu 

 Burger King Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Providence Restaurants » Olneyville » Burgers » Burger King Share | Jul 8 - 21 102 restaurants with special menus during Providence Restaurant Week ! 
 
Burger King
 
 1.0 star rating           
  1.0 rating over 1 review 
 (401) 831-1035 

 60 Hartford Ave ( ) 

 Providence , RI 02909 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (1) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Burger King is a Burgers , Breakfast , and American restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go . Tags: Burgers, Good For Kids, Providence, Olnyville, Burger King, Delivery, Kid Friendly, Cheap Eats, Breakfast, and American Stats: 
 90 dishes entered by diners at Burger King 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Burger King? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Burger King
 Write a review 
 1 review First reviewed by OhEnry 
 
 0 helpful votes over 1 review 
 OhEnry 
 1 Restaurant Review 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Burger King OhEnry 
 July 18, 2010 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Just drive by...don&apos;t even stop
 
If you took a fast food restaurant and hired a bunch of untrained chimps, you would end up with this poor excuse for a Burger King. I’ve gotten screwed here a few times but today was the last straw.

I asked for a Whopper with NO CHEESE . Pretty simple request and it’s not dinner rush so this should be easy. The untrained chimp repeats back, whopper NO cheese, little order confirmation sign says whopper NO cheese–guess what I got when I arrived home? What seemed like a week old whopper WITH cheese and the bag reeked of that smell when you put something metallic in the microwave.

Untrained, LAZY chimp grabbed whatever was nearest, tossed the bag into the microwave and tried to cover it up. Just avoid this place like the plague.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
WHOPPER®
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
tossed into the garbage and rummaged through the refrigerator
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
Best Dishes at Burger King

These dishes from the Burger King menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Double Whopper
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
Big Daddy Bacon Cheeseburger
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
Original Chicken Sandwich
 
 4.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Rent-A-Center Easy Money Pawnbrokers Rent-A-Center Supply Depot Walgreens Enchanted Florist Keith Stromberg Jephry Floral Studio 
 3 reviews 3.0 stars AT&amp;T;Mobility Gonzalez Cab Inc 
 Burger King is located near the cities of East Providence, Perth Amboy, Cranston, North Providence, and Rumford. People found this by searching for: Burger King Olneyville Ri, Crown Chicken Onlyvill, Burger King Onlyville, Burger King Olneyville Number, Burger King Olneyville, Burger King North Providence Ri Complaints, Olneyville Burgers, and Burger King In Olneyville. 
Featured in Providence
 
 5.0 star rating           
 Caserta&apos;s Pizzeria 
 3.25 star rating           
 Costanino&apos;s Ristorante-Caffe 
 3.5 star rating           
 Chef Ho&apos;s 
 5.0 star rating           
 Buono&apos;s Italian Bakery 
 4.0 star rating           
 Don Jose Tequilas Restaurant 
 4.0 star rating           
 Sicilia&apos;s Pizzeria 
 4.5 star rating           
 Cassarino&apos;s 
 4.0 star rating           
 Ri Ra 
 4.5 star rating           
 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s 
 3.5 star rating           
 Sakura Restaurant 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 68 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Olneyville New York System Diner in Olneyville N Y Systems Restaurant Weade&apos;s Soul Foods Soul Food in Olneyville Beatrice&apos;s Kitchen Dunkin&apos; Donuts Bakery&amp;Pastries in Olneyville 
Link to Burger King
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
