<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007141" url="http://www.denverpost.com/business/ci_7606895" time="2012-07-13-00:07" support="1" score="0.0011152501856405877" bingtitle="CineMedia reels in ads - The Denver Post - Colorado Breaking News ..." webtitle="CineMedia reels in ads - The Denver Post">
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>The network allows advertisers to pick the ... during First Look, and Wendy&apos;s was the first fast-food restaurant ... Some of 1,180 credit-card theft cases linked to MetroLux ...</description>
	<body>
		Commenting: Sign In   |   Register 
 Home | Media Kit | Sign up for breaking news email alerts | Photo Galleries 
 
 

 
 weekly ad specials from the denver post Site Yahoo 
 

 

 
 
 Home &gt; Business News 
 
 
 
 Print    Email    Font Resize business 
CineMedia reels in ads
 By Andy Vuong
 The Denver Post denverpost.com Posted: 12/02/2007 01:00:00 AM MST 
 Kurt Hall, National CineMedia&apos;s CEO, works out of the company&apos;s network operations center in Centennial.(Brian Brainerd, The Denver Post 
 ) 
CENTENNIAL—From the company&apos;s network operations center, National CineMedia engineers can see which commercials are being shown, and in what order, to moviegoers.
Staffed 24 hours a day, the center closely monitors a digital network that beams advertisements via satellite to computer servers at more than 950 movie theaters, including 26 in Colorado.
The network is the linchpin for a company that has helped transform cinema advertising, an industry booming amid the marketing shift from traditional broadcast and print media.
&quot;The beauty and the power of our network is this combination of being able to distribute nationally and target locally,&quot; said National CineMedia chief executive Kurt Hall. &quot;The digital network has National CineMedia employs 500 people, including 350 in Colorado. Denver financier Philip Anschutz holds a large ownership stake.( Brian Brainerd, The Denver Post 
 ) really allowed advertisers to treat cinema ... very much like television. The lead times are somewhat similar. They have the ability to change out ads whenever they want.&quot;
National CineMedia, which launched 2 1/2 years ago as a joint venture among the nation&apos;s three largest theater chains, has deep ties to Qwest Communications founder Philip Anschutz. The Denver financier holds a large ownership stake but is not involved in the company&apos;s operations.
Cinema advertising was once relegated to being shown on the same 35-millimeter film as the movies themselves, which is more costly and time-consuming to distribute. That also made it difficult for an advertiser to change or update a commercial.
With satellites installed on the roofs of each of the theaters in its network, National CineMedia can easily distribute and make changes to its First Look program, the roughly 25-minute preshow that includes four commercial segments and behind-the-scenes previews of movies and TV shows.
The network allows advertisers to pick the theater locations and movies they want to target. They can even target by a movie&apos;s rating.
Major cinema advertisers include the military, automobile and entertainment industries, although a number of new industries are testing the medium.
In the third quarter, J.C. Penney became the first department store to run ads during First Look, and Wendy&apos;s was the first fast-food restaurant, said Eric Handler, an analyst with Lehman Brothers, which has had an investment banking relationship with National Cine Media in the past year.
While still just a small fraction of the overall advertising industry, cinema marketing revenues grew from $357.5 million in 2004 to $455.7 million in 2006, a 27 percent increase, according to the Cinema Advertising Council.
During the same time frame, broadcast advertising grew by about 6 percent and newspaper advertising declined slightly, according to the Television Bureau of Advertising.
 &quot;New&quot; advertising
 &quot;There&apos;s clearly a lot of money moving out of existing mediums, whether it&apos;s television, radio, newspaper, toward the Internet, toward cinema, toward what I&apos;ll call new advertising platforms that are being developed,&quot; Hall said. &quot;We&apos;re one of those platforms. We&apos;re benefiting from that movement of money out of those other mediums in just the same way Goog le is benefiting from that.&quot;
Specifically, television advertising has been hurt by the growing use of digital video recorders, which allow viewers to skip through commercials.
&quot;What&apos;s going on right now in the overall advertising market, in terms of video advertising, is television continues to face an eroding audience base,&quot; Handler said.
Cinema advertising is more effective because &quot;once you&apos;re in your seat, you can&apos;t change your channel,&quot; Handler said. &quot;You&apos;re pretty much sitting there and you see the program and it&apos;s on this big 40-foot screen.&quot;
Wall Street welcomed National CineMedia&apos;s initial public offering in February. Shares sold for $21, above the pre-IPO target price of $18 to $20 a share.
Nine of 12 analysts tracked by Bloomberg financial services have a &quot;buy&quot; rating on the stock, which closed Friday at $27.68 a share. Two have a &quot;sell&quot; rating and one has a &quot;hold.&quot;
Shareholders own a 44 percent stake in the company, and the three founding partners—Regal Entertainment Group, AMC and Cinemark—hold a 56 percent stake.
The three theater chains&apos; joint venture created a national footprint for what was once &quot;a highly fragmented industry,&quot; Handler said.
&quot;These three players, when combined, have a national footprint that covers about 50 percent of all screens in the United States,&quot; Handler said.
 Crisis and opportunity
 The groundwork for this network was laid from 2000 to 2002, when the opportunistic Anschutz swooped in amid an industry crisis. After rushing to build megaplexes with stadium-style seating in the late 1990s, operators were left with an overcapacity of screens and a heavy debt burden.
Anschutz spent less than $500 million acquiring the debt of Regal, United Artists and Edwards Theatres Circuit on the cheap, and gained control of the companies when they each filed for bankruptcy protection.
Anschutz combined the companies, later adding the Hoyts chain, to create the largest theater operator in the nation, Regal Entertainment Group.
Hall, formerly the head of United Artists, was appointed co-CEO of Regal to focus on boosting the company&apos;s revenue, while his counterpart, Mike Campbell, was assigned to focus on existing operations.
&quot;My main job was to look for other things to do with the asset,&quot; said Hall, 48.
In March 2005, Regal combined its advertising arm with AMC&apos;s to create National CineMedia, which employs 500 people, including 350 in Colorado. Cinemark, the nation&apos;s third-largest theater chain, joined as a founding member later that year.
Anschutz is the majority owner of Regal, which holds roughly a 23 percent stake in National CineMedia.
 Medium offers message
 In addition to advertising, National CineMedia has two much smaller business divisions—CineMeetings and NCM Fathom. CineMeetings works to fill off-peak theater hours—essentially Monday through Thursday—with corporate events and meetings.
&quot;If you&apos;re delivering a message or something like that, it&apos;s a really good medium to do that, especially if you have offices in multiple cities,&quot; said Mike Hickey, an analyst with Janco Partners in Greenwood Village. &quot;It&apos;s a lower margin business ... but I absolutely believe that that&apos;s a real opportunity for them.&quot;
Companies that are using theaters as meeting spaces include Burger King and Microsoft.
NCM Fathom distributes to its theaters concerts, sporting events and other live and recorded entertainment content, such as the Metropolitan Opera and St. Olaf Christmas Festival.
The bulk of National CineMedia&apos;s revenue comes from the advertising arm. The company has one primary competitor, privately held Screenvision.
Analysts say National CineMedia is likely to emerge as the industry&apos;s leader.
&quot;It&apos;s kind of a duoply, and National CineMedia appears to be the clear champ,&quot; Hickey said.
Both companies have about the same number of total screens, roughly 14,000, but National CineMedia will take the lead next year when Loews Cineplex and Kerasotes Theatres join its network. Kerasotes is switching from Screenvision.
National CineMedia has 30-year deals with the theaters in its network, while Screenvision&apos;s deals are much shorter, Handler said.
&quot;There&apos;s always the potential for National CineMedia to pick off the top affiliates of Screenvision,&quot; Handler said.
National CineMedia&apos;s digital network covers 12,600 of its 14,000 screens. By the first quarter of next year, Screenvision will have 7,000 digital screens, according to chief executive Matthew Kearney.
Kearney notes that Screenvision has several marquee independent theater chains in its network, such as California&apos;s Pacific Theatres and Mann Theatres. Screenvision&apos;s network includes 34 theaters in Colorado.
&quot;We are both winning dollars from other advertising platforms,&quot; Kearney said.

National CineMedia

 Headquarters: Centennial

 Chief executive: Kurt Hall
 Employees: 500, including 350 in Colorado
 Founded: March 2005
 IPO price: $21 a share (Feb. 7)
 Stock price: $27.68
 Ticker symbol: NCMI
 Market capitalization: $1.16 billion
 Revenue: $213.7 million (since IPO to quarter ended Sept. 27)
 Net income: $16.6 million (same period)
 Ownership: Public shareholders own 44 percent of the company while the nation&apos;s three largest theater chains—Regal, AMC and Cinemark—own the rest. The company was initially formed as a joint venture among the three theater operators.
 Andy Vuong: 303-954-1209 or avuong@denverpost.com 
 Copyright 2012 The Denver Post. All rights reserved. (CLICK TO ENLARGE) Print    Email    Font Resize Return to Top    
 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 Like this article? Recommend it ()  all reader-recommended news 

 Login | Sign Up | Email Support 
Article Comments

 Is your comment not appearing on the article? Read this .

 
 Note: Our article pages automatically refresh every ten minutes. We cannot change this. If you start writing your comment on this page, please refresh the page before you do so—this will reset the ten-minute counter .

 You must be registered to comment (your comment will be saved for you while you register). It&apos;s quick (it takes about 30 seconds) and we only require your email and name. Comments that include any offensive material are prohibited. By using our site you agree to our terms of use .
 
 
You have javascript turned off. To comment on this article from the article page, javascript must be turned on. Alternately, you can search for this topic thread in our forums .
 
 Comment: 

 Use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; link when necessary (you don&apos;t have to be a member, or be logged in) Keep it clean and respect others—don&apos;t use language you wouldn&apos;t use with your parents Read the Post&apos;s Article Commenting Ground Rules here (link will open in a new window) 

 
 
 More Business headlines MORE MORE BUSINESS HEADLINES HEADLINES Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight day Sun Microsystems co-founder Scott McNealy to keynote Demogala Denver tech conference Denver Metro Chamber selects chair-elect Wells Fargo to pay $175M in lending settlement 485,000 high chairs recalled after injury reports Buffett says general economy slowing this summer All eyes on JPMorgan as banks report earnings More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June Fewer auto closings reduce US unemployment claims Boeing claws back ground lost to Airbus Carbondale and its economic advisors will continue to work together Basalt gives first-round approval for new bus station Drilling company hopes for compromise with Routt County Basalt votes to support open space purchase at Saltonstall Ranch Avon moving forward on settlement with Village at Avon developers Restaurant at Aspen&apos;s Little Nell Hotel to get $2.5 million upgrade Pitkin County agricultural landowners appeal valuations Yahoo investigating reported mass password breach Hyundai, Kia unions to stage 8-hour strikes Colorado wheat farmers buoyed by high prices after average harvest Unemployment hitting Black middle class in the U.S. Task force convened to review Colorado&apos;s enterprise zone program Airbus receives firm $2.3 billion order for 10 long-haul A330 aircraft Philadelphia quarterback Michael Vick launches sports clothing line Stocks close lower for 5th straight day   
 
 
 
 Blogs Front Page Aurora | Boulder | Denver | Feeds | More 

 Denver&amp;the West 
 
 Highlands Ranch, Denver dentist may have contaminated patients for 12 years ATF would consider aiding Denver to fight violent crime Thornton grandpa wins Water World belly-flop scholarship contest   
 
 Rockies | Avs | Nuggets | Preps | RSS | More 

 Sports 
 
 Broncos&apos; situation at linebacker looks murky Boulder&apos;s Laura Bennett attempts to medal in triathlon at London Games Mark Kiszla: NBA&apos;s joke of parity is on the Nuggets   
 
 Balance Sheet Blog | Techknow Bytes 

 Business 

 
 
 Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight day Sun Microsystems co-founder Scott McNealy to keynote Demogala Denver tech conference Denver Metro Chamber selects chair-elect   
 
 
 
 Movies | Music | TV | RSS | Video 

 Entertainment 
 
 Steven Tyler exiting as &apos;American Idol&apos; judge Bumped from Dish, AMC makes Breaking Bad available online Video: Christian Louboutin partners with Disney to create Cinderella shoe   
 
 Columnists | Letters | Cartoon | RSS 

 Opinion 
 
 Editorial: Penn State failed kids in favor of football Editorial: Hot shots earn health insurance Editorial: Richard B. Scudder, 99   
 
 Arcade | Crossword | Sudoku 

 Watercooler 
 
 Cop accused of stealing driver&apos;s iPhone from wreck Court: Ore. police can seize $1M lottery prize German town designates tricky parking &apos;men only&apos;   
 
 
 
 
 POPULAR TALKERS RECOMMENDED YEAR AGO 
 



 
FRESH DAILY. Subscribe to our
Afternoon Newsletter
 
Email Address
 
» See a sample afternoon newsletter here 
 
 Front Page: Business News Denver public transit system ranks high in connecting workers to jobs Colorado&apos;s 10 appointed public trustees resign Englewood-based Gevo to try new process for production of isobutanol Polk Majestic Travel Group joins Australian travel firm   
 
 Most Popular: Business: Past 3 Days 
 
 Most-Commented: Business: Past 144 hours 
 
 Denver Olympic committee recommends Colorado pursue 2022 Winter Games    19 Colorado solar-panel maker Abound prepares bankruptcy filing    13 Honda electric vehicle option: collision insurance without deductible    8 Trial rescheduled in child prostitution case against founder of Boulder&apos;s Wild Oats    7 Denver&apos;s soon-to-be built patent office will generate $440 million    7 
 
 Most-Commented, Past Hour 
 
 Carroll: Would you have sided with the Patriots in 1776?    4 Ask Amy: Father&apos;s porn history creates awkward situation (7/3/2012)    3 USOC to pass on 2022 bid, consider &apos;24 and &apos;26    3 Ex-Commerce secretary won&apos;t be charged in hit-run    2 Hank Brown, Mike Rosen to help lead CU-Boulder&apos;s search for visiting conservative scholar    1 
 
 Recently Recommended 

 Sanctuary wolves displaced by High Park Fire find new home in Keenesburg (about 18 minutes ago) Carroll: Would you have sided with the Patriots in 1776? (about 29 minutes ago) Sen. Pat Steadman and Rep. Edward Casso face personal tragedies (about 59 minutes ago) Beloved actor Andy Griffith dies at 86 (about 2 hours ago) Colorado wildfire: Waldo Canyon fire leaves door, window frames (about 3 hours ago)
   
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
All contents Copyright 2012 The Denver Post or other copyright holders. All rights reserved.
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed for any commercial purpose.

 Advertise / Media Kit | Archives | Careers | Contact Us | Ethics Policy | E-mail Alerts | Mobile | Privacy Policy | Web Feeds | RSS | My Yahoo | Repurposing Denver Post content - Guidelines | Site Map | Home Delivery | Terms of Use 

Our other sites: Viva Colorado | Boulder Daily Camera | Boulder&apos;s Colorado Daily | Broomfield Enterprise | Sterling Colorado Journal-Advocate 
 Estes Park Trail-Gazette | The Lamar Ledger | The Fort Morgan Times | Brush (Colorado) News-Tribune 
 Tweet 

 Privacy Policy   |   Terms of Use   |   MNG Corporate Site Map   |   Copyright
	</body>
</document>
