<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007311" url="http://www.tgdaily.com/mobility-brief/58539-update-google-wallet-nfc-app-is-now-live" time="2012-07-13-00:17" support="1" score="0.0011965705116768807" bingtitle="Update: Google Wallet NFC app is now live | TG Daily" webtitle="Update: Google Wallet NFC app is now live | TG Daily">
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>In order to be able to use the app, users will ... That is, when they go to a drug store or fast food restaurant ... open the app on their phone, tap it to the credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		velum media news web dev mobile dev the cloud networking music fitness bestcovery 
 
 Home Technology 
 Hardware Mobility Networking Security Software 
 Science 
 Sustainability General Sciences Space Trendwatch 
 Entertainment 
 Consumer Electronics Games and Entertainment 
 Business Last 7 Days 
 
Update: Google Wallet NFC app is now live
 Posted on September 19, 2011 - 07:09 by Raven Lovecraft Tweet Share Email Share 
Google&apos;s app for paying at stores with your phone may be officially rolled out later today.

 

With limited restrictions, the Google Wallet app that will allow NFC-enabled phones to be used like a PayPass credit card will be among the first uses of the cell phone-based technology in the US. 

In order to be able to use the app, users will need to have a Nexus S phone with Android 2.3.4 or later insallted, in addition to an existing PayPass-enabled Citi Mastercard.

Finally, it will only work with Nexus S customers running on Sprint, according to what appears to be a leaked memo circulating the Internet.

In the app, users will be able to link their Citi card with Google Wallet. That is, when they go to a drug store or fast food restaurant, or take a cab, or anywhere else that has a contactless payment terminal, all users will need to do is open the app on their phone, tap it to the credit card terminal, and that&apos;s it.

What&apos;s unclear is how long the process will be to start offering Google Wallet on other Android NFC phones, which are expected to burst in popularity over the next several months, as well as when there will be compatibility with other payment providers.

 Update: The Google Wallet NFC app is now live for Nexus S owners. Website GigaOM reported being able to use it successfully at a coffee shop, which means it should be working at any store with a contactless payment (&quot;tap payment&quot;) terminal.
 See more about:
 Mobility Brief Android google nexus s nfc Sprint 
 
Advertisement
 View the discussion thread. Loading... 
 
MOST POPULAR
 
 MOST VIEWED TRENDING TAGS 
 1 Steve Ballmer&apos;s Winston Churchill moment Posted 6 hours ago by Rob Enderle 2 First Americans arrived in three waves from Siberia Posted 13 hours ago by Kate Taylor 3 BMW rolls out ConnectedDrive 2012 Posted 6 hours ago by Shane McGlaun 4 Huge turtle was round like a truck tire Posted 9 hours ago by Kate Taylor 1 # Android Read all stories about # Android 2 # microsoft Read all stories about # microsoft 3 # servers Read all stories about # servers 4 # dnschanger Read all stories about # dnschanger 5 # internet access Read all stories about # internet access 
 Workout of the Day 
 
Awake&amp;Evolve Workout of the Day
 
 Psoas and Inner Groin Flow 
 Open and release the spine, psoas, inner groin and hamstrings in the deep mindful flow. Take time to calm the mind moving through each pose finishing in a deep twist. 
Mature Athlete Workout of the Day
 
 Mature Athlete: Cycle 1, Week 2, Day 2 
 The first cycle of the Mature Athlete workouts by Tom Kelso. Train progressively using basic exercises and training protocols to safely enhance fitness and strength. 
Mommy Workout of the Day
 
 Mommy Workout: Week 2, Day 2 
 Welcome to the Mommy Workouts! The first cycle is designed for women in the first trimester, but it&apos;s also appropriate for any woman who wants to improve strength, stability, and mobility. 
RKC Kettlebell Workout of the Day
 
 RKC Kettlebell: Cycle 1, Week 11, Day 2 
 Get a total body workout and increase strength and mobility with the second cycle of RKC Kettlebell WODs by RKC II Dini Leopoldo. 
Strength&amp;Conditioning Workout of the Day
 
 Strength&amp;Conditioning - Greg Everett: Week 1, Day 4 
 Welcome to the first week of workouts by Greg Everett. These workouts are inspired by Olympic weightlifting, but will benefit anyone who wants to gain strength and improve lifting technique. 
Sport Specific Workout of the Day
 
 Sport Specific: Football - Week 2, Day 1 
 This is a 12 week linear progression program for football players. The goal of this program is to safely progress in your strength training without sacrificing power. 
Women&apos;s Workout of the Day
 
 Women&apos;s Workout: Cycle 10, Week 12, Day 2 
 This 12-week cycle of the Women’s WOD will focus on building all over body strength, as well as flexibility and core stabilization. Bestcovery 
 Best LED LCD TV Best AV Receiver Overall Best Digital SLR Camera Overall Best Netbook Overall Best Wireless Router Overall 

 More... 
 TG Daily 
 About TG Daily | Contact Us | Advertising | Terms of Use | Legal | Privacy | ELC 
 ©2012 DD&amp;M;Inc. All rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
