<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007240" url="http://www.funny2.com/health.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:12" support="5" score="0.001335945616711232" bingtitle="FUNNY2™ - Health Related True Facts #1" webtitle="FUNNY2 - Health Related True Facts #1">
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>How To Give Pills To Pets. True Facts. True Facts ... healthy behavior, such as wearing seat belts ... If you order a shake at a fast food restaurant, the good news is: a 16 ounce ...</description>
	<body>
		Jokes Of All Types 
 A Guy Goes Into A Bar Changing A Light Bulb Bumper Stickers Daffynitions Insults You Can Use Longer Jokes&amp;Stories 50 Movie Things Cute Jokes One Liners State Mottos Canadians Unanswered Questions World&apos;s Funniest Joke? Worst Westerns Ever SCOTLAND&apos;s Funniest Joke 
 Men&amp;Women 
 Pickup Lines Wife Software Men Are Happier The Husband Store Men&apos;s Rules The Guy Test Learn About Women Learn About Men Men vs. Women Pregnant Men What Women Say What Women Want The Woman&apos;s Code The Perfect Day 
 Women&amp;Men 
 Rejection Lines Definitions: Female Definitions: Male Womanspeak Manspeak Secrets of Women More Definitions Bedroom Golf Men vs. Women Oil Change Women Employees Road Trip! How to Use an ATM Gender Specific 
 Humor About Animals 
 Chicken Crossing The Road Quotes About Dogs Cats Should Remember Cat Laws Dogs Should Remember Learn This From Your Dog Dogs&amp;Cats Viewpoint How To Give Pills To Pets How To Clean the Toilet 
 True Facts 
 True Facts True Facts DEBUNKED Substantiated True Facts False Facts Human Body Facts Healthy Facts What Are The Odds? US Budget Crisis Real Life vs. Movies Incorrect Lyrics Country Music Song Titles Shopping Mall Facts 
 Fun At The Office 
 Performance Evaluations Business Facts Computer Help Desk Calls Politically Correct Dictionary Employee Handbook Experience Job Interview Fun Resume Fun Sick Employees Excuses Thoughts For A Crisis To Keep Your Workday Sane Company Christmas Party 
 Sports 
 True Baseball Injuries Chris Berman Names Announcer Jerry Coleman Golf Quotes 
 Quotes from Famous People 
 Albert Einstein Mitch Hedberg Henny Youngman Homer Simpson Elvis Presley Ralph Wiggum Steve Jobs Andy Rooney Rita Rudner Will Rogers Steven Wright Yogi Berra Fray Pascual Other Famous People Fake Quotes 
 Food And Drink 
 Howard&apos;s Famous Fried Rice Quesadillas! Stir Fry Recipe The American Barbecue Are You A Heavy Drinker? Too Much Coffee! Holiday Fruitcake Water Vs. Coke 
 Wordplay 
 Acronyms Rules Of Proper English Your Fly is Open! Microsoft Haiku Newspaper Headlines Merged Books Huh? Jonco&apos;s Thoughts Bad Literature Oxymorons Paraprosdokians Palindromes Old Chinese Proverbs Puns Bad Analogies Real Acronyms 
 Teachers 
 School Excuses Teaching Math Science Fun 
 Kids&amp;Old Folks 
 Things Mother Taught Me Thoughts On Aging Children&apos;s Books Learn From Your Kids Dating My Daughter College Taught Me This Are You Old? The Stages Of Life Grandpa Says Teen Poverty Humans Should Learn This 
 Pranks 
 Answering Machine Hijinx Fun In An Elevator Fortune Cookie Prank Keep Your Sanity Alive Dealing With Telemarketers Wal-Mart Fun 
 Occupational Humor 
 You Know You&apos;re a Cop Doctor! Doctor! Air Traffic Controllers Librarian Questions Doctor&apos;s Notes Inflight Humor Real Insurance Stories Military Humor Surgery Woes Welfare Stories Weird Workers Comp Injuries You&apos;re Fired! 
 Miscellaneous Stuff 
 Real Signs The Purple Donut World&apos;s Shortest Books Funny Or Not? Redneck Jedi Knight Etch-A-Sketch Instructions Tweets on Steve Jobs New Year&apos;s Resolutions Gifts You&apos;ll Never See It&apos;s Great To Be Alive Never Be A Hallmark Card Hollywood Squares Humor Other Great Websites Never Wiki-Pie-Dia The Snow Shoveler Dave&amp;Pamela World Tour 
 About 
 
 
Health Related True Facts #1

Absolutely True!


 PAGES 1 2 3 

The safest number of times to reuse a disposable razor is only 3. Disposable razors have thinner blades than other razors, and are thus more prone to producing microscopic cuts in the skin. The longer you keep using a disposable razor, the more germs it will collect, and the greater the chance that a nick will become infected.

When you walk uphill, the level of harmful fats in the bloodstream goes down. When you walk downhill, blood sugar levels are reduced. Alter your patterns of exercise depending on your health needs!

90% of the calories in cream cheese come from fat! It&apos;s the most fattening cheese.

Make sure your television set is securely supported if you have young children in your house. At least 28 kids were killed by toppling television sets in 1997.

If you have an impaired immune system, don&apos;t eat alfalfa sprouts. Some sprouts have caused outbreaks of E. Coli and salmonella!

Coffee does not increase the risk of heart attacks. A recent study showed that even 4 or more cups daily didn&apos;t increase heart attack risk.

Sweet potatoes contain no more calories than white potatoes, and virtually no fat.

As people age, they burn fewer calories. This often results in increased body fat and loss of muscle. All it takes, however, is a brisk 2 mile walk daily to balance energy intake and energy needs.

If you have symptoms of a heart attack, such as chest pain, chew and swallow one adult aspirin tablet (325 mg) immediately, while you seek medical help. If you have only baby aspirin at home, chew four of them.

The number one vegetable in the US is the potato. Per capita consumption is 84 pounds each year! One third of those end up as french fries. 5% are in the form of potato chips.

Knuckle cracking does NOT cause arthritis, enlarged joints or any other harm. It&apos;s just irritating to some people.

Many studies show that married people tend to be healthier than unmarried ones. One theory is that being married encourages healthy behavior, such as wearing seat belts, being physically active and having blood pressure checked.

Watch out for cars turning left at traffic lights! A high proportion of accidents (with other cars or pedestrians) involve a left-turning vehicle!

If you order a shake at a fast food restaurant, the good news is: a 16 ounce shake provides about 400 mg of calcium. The bad news: it also supplies about 400 to 600 calories and at least 9 grams of fat!

Measure your waist to find out if you are at risk for weight-related health problems. For women, a waist measurement of 34 1/2 inches signals a serious risk. For men, the cutoff point is 40 inches.

Watch out! Grapefruit juice can greatly boost the concentration of certain drugs in the bloodstream. These include some popular cholesterol-lowering drugs, calcium channel-blockers, tranquilizers and some antihistamines.

If you drive with a small child in your car, make sure you use the child safety seat properly! Only about 60% of children age 4 or younger ride in such seats! In addition, 80% of these safety seats are improperly used.

Per-capita Mozzarella cheese consumption has risen five-fold since 1972. Mozzarella is the second most popular cheese, next to cheddar.

Walkers and hikers who apply an aluminum-containing antiperspirant to their feet daily for at least three days before a long hike can reduce the risk of blisters!

If you take more than 500 mg of calcium supplements daily, take half later in the day. The body absorbs smaller amounts of calcium much more efficiently than large doses. Taking the calcium with meals also improves absorption.

Moderate exercise may reduce the risk of gallstone attacks by 20 to 40%! People who watch more than 40 hours of TV per week have double the risk of gallstone symptoms compared to those watching little TV.

Disinfect your loofah sponge occasionally with diluted bleach. Sponges like this can become contaminated with bacteria that can cause skin irritation.

High-fiber foods are recommended on weight-loss diets because they&apos;re filling and nutritious. In addition, boosting your fiber intake reduces the number of calories your body absorbs from the food you eat!

If all adult American smokers had quit five years ago, there would have been an estimated 15% fewer overall deaths in the United States since then, according to a study from Rutgers University.

An easy way to tell about your sun protection in the summer: if your shadow is shorter than your height, it&apos;s sunburn time. In most parts of the country, that&apos;s between 10 am and 4 pm.

If a lightning storm occurs, you are safe in a car with a solid metal top with the windows and doors shut, as long as you aren&apos;t touching a metal part of the car! A bad place to stand is right outside the car during the storm. Never stand under a lone tree in a lightning storm. A forest is safer.

Don&apos;t let the fact that you are using a tanning lotion give you a false sense of security in the sun. You need a sunscreen with an SPF (sun protection factor) of at least 15 in the summer for adequate protection.

 PAGES 1 2 3 
 
SEARCH FUNNY2 

 
 FUNNY2 MEDIA 
 
 
 
 
 FUNNY2 STUFF Jokes / Videos / Submissions / Facebook / Twitter 

 FUNNY2 About / Site Map / Advertise / Contact 

 FUNNY2 MEDIA Funny2 / Criggo / Always Funny / Bad Menu / Veegle
	</body>
</document>
