<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007774" url="http://www.wlbt.com/story/17095179/canton-mcdonalds-manager-shot?autoStart=true&amp;topVideoCatNo=default&amp;clipId=6815417" time="2012-07-13-00:44" support="1" score="0.009785330249670397" bingtitle="Canton McDonald&apos;s manager shot - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS" webtitle="Canton McDonald&apos;s manager shot - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS">
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>Four arrested for credit card fraud and ... Sheppard, claiming he messed his order up. Wilks then fled the fast-food restaurant to ... led them to his room, where he was put ...</description>
	<body>
		WLBT.com - Jackson, MSCanton McDonald&apos;s manager shot
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 St. Jude Dream Home Video Landing Page Decision 2012 Jackson Gas Prices Editorials America Now Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts Contact Us 
 
 Decision 2012 Editorials MDOT Traffic Cams Wednesday&apos;s Child Look Around Mississippi Most Wanted Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Olympic Zone Sign up for Alerts 
 
 MedNOW Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 SkyCopter 3 Community Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Sign up for Alerts Contact Us Closed Captioning This TV Network 
 
 WLBT Community St. Jude Dream Home SkyCopter 3 Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Contact Us Fresh from the Flame 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Canton McDonald&apos;s manager shot
 Posted: Tuesday, March 6, 2012 6:30 PM EST Updated: Wednesday, March 7, 2012 6:40 PM EST 
 
 Most Popular Stories Most Read More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 

 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:34 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:34:44 GMT A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl that he met on Facebook. More &gt;&gt; A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl whom he met on Facebook, according to police. More &gt;&gt; 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:53 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:53:55 GMT The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; 
 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 

 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 11:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 03:44:46 GMT A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. Virgie Peterson was More &gt;&gt; A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now, her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Sponsored Information More&gt;&gt; 
 
 sponsored information: 

 Personal Injury Attorney 

 Personal Injury Attorney 
 
 CANTON, MS (WLBT) - 
Canton police have identified the assailant in the Tuesday evening Canton McDonald&apos;s shooting.

36-Year-Old Michael Wilks of Jackson was given $750,000.00 bond in court Wednesday.

Wilks was arrested for shooting McDonald&apos;s Manager Maurice Sheppard, claiming he messed his order up.

Wilks then fled the fast-food restaurant to the nearby America&apos;s Best Value Inn, where he rented a room, trying to flee police.

Officers say eyewitnesses led them to his room, where he was put in custody, and the gun used in the shooting was recovered.

Sheppard was struck in the arm, and is now recovering.

Investigators say Wilks is being investigated in connection with other crimes in Hinds County.

 Copyright 2012 WLBT. All rights reserved. 
 
 
Explore WLBT.com
 Home Local News Decision 2011 Gas Prices America Now Point of View Sound Off News Most Read Local News Skycopter 3 Most Wanted Look Around Mississippi 3 On Your Side Wednesday’s Child Taking Back our Neighborhoods Red Blue Review Medical Matters Weather Local Weather Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Interactive Radar 4-Day Pollen Forecast Sports Sports National Sports Mississippi Sports Friday Nite Lites Video Latest Videos Most Watched Video Center Contact Us Contact Us Sign Up for Email Alerts Our Team Birthday Club All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WLBT, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
