<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007762" url="http://democratherald.com/news/local/public-safety-log-feb/article_2f939522-5138-11e1-b00a-001871e3ce6c.html" time="2012-07-13-00:43" support="1" score="0.0011191225821185063" bingtitle="Public safety log (Feb. 7)" webtitle="Public safety log (Feb. 7)">
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>Initial charges often change as a ... arrested Winningham at a fast-food restaurant in Corvallis after he tried to use a stolen credit card ... Linn County Jail ...</description>
	<body>
		e-Edition Mobile Apps e-Newsletters Subscriber Services Contact Us Mobile Site Advertise 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 Contribute 
 Article Event Photo Video 
 My Account 
 Edit Profile Logout 
 
 75° Clear 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 85° 52° Saturday 85° 55° Sunday 79° 48° Monday 77° 50° 
 Current Roads National 
 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 Local Oregon National World Public Safety Business Calendar Blogs Weird 
 
The Latest
 
 ODOT to repair freeway lanes tonight 

Lane restrictions are planned Thursday night on I-5 northbound near milepost 235  in the Albany area as ODOT crews will repair pavement damage…
 
 Council approves loan for brewery 

A young couple intend to open a new microbrewery on Albany’s riverfront this fall after securing a $45,000 loan for their startup company from…
 
Recent

 Jefferson meeting about rave scheduled Hazy days of summer Train carrying logs derails north of Talbot; no one injured Woman accused of preying on elderly Two Albany women accused in bottle cap scam Walmart announces store in Corvallis 
 
 Obits Sports 
 
Topics

 Beavers Sports High School College Oregon Outdoors Community Blogs NFL NBA MLB 
 
The Latest
 
 Mid-Valley boxer gets a shot at a title 

In the gritty Victory Gym near downtown Albany, Rusty Hand prepares for the fight of his life in the most unforgiving sport.
 
 Mid-Valley Rockets keep up hot streak 

The Mid-Valley Rockets continued their recent surge Wednesday with a 9-6 win over the Humbolt Sluggers at West Albany High School.
 
Recent

 Knights baseball: Bats go cold in loss to Wenatchee OSU men&apos;s soccer: Beavers add assistant coach to staff OSU rowing: Forde qualifies for world rowing championships Mavericks hope to get spark from Cunningham, other draft picks Knights baseball: Corvallis starts fast, then holds off Wenatchee for second straight win OSU football: California receiver Villamin becomes third commitment 
 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Editor&apos;s Mailbag Submit a letter Blogs 
 Entertainment 
 
Topics

 Music On Stage Visual Arts Movies Calendar Dining View Entertainment Blog TV Listings 
 
The Latest
 
 Monday music medicine 

Week of July 6-13, 2012
 
 The Corvallis sound 

Week of July 6-13, 2012
 
Recent

 Week at a glance Movie bits Box office Music lineup Friday to Friday On display 
 
 Special Sections 
 Oregon Outdoors Calendar People Religion Sunday Lifestyle Food 
 Photos&amp;Video 
 Staff Photos Share Your Photos Galleries YouTube 
 Classifieds 
 Garage Sale Map Place an Ad 
 Get It! 
 Get It! Marketplace Today&apos;s Deal Contests Garage Sale Map Newspaper Ads Place an Ad Local Coupons 
 Homes Cars Jobs 
 Local Jobs Jobs with Us 
 
 
 Home / News / Local 
 
Public safety log (Feb. 7)
 Print Email 2012-02-07T07:00:00Z 2012-02-06T19:03:17Z Public safety log (Feb. 7) Democrat-Herald democratherald.com February 07, 2012 7:00 am  •  Democrat-Herald (0) Comments 
 People arrested are innocent unless proven otherwise in
court. Initial charges often change as a case progresses. 

 Albany Police 

 Bicycles taken — Someone used bolt cutters to
steal nine bikes Monday morning from the 2000 block of Queen Avenue
at the Periwinkle Creek Apartments.

 Spoiled opening — A window in the front door at
the new Eye Candy Eye Wear in the 300 block of Main Street S.E. was
broken early Monday morning. Someone entered the building and took
a laptop.

The new business’ grand opening will still happen today.

 Motorcycle crash — Leslie Allen Kelley, 61, of
Albany stopped his motorcycle about 1:35 p.m. Sunday in the 1900
block of 14th Avenue to let a woman with a stroller cross the
street. James Biago Perrone, 52, no city available, could not stop
his Toyota in time and struck Kelley from the rear.

Kelley said he was OK and declined to be transported to a
hospital. Perrone was not injured.

No citations have been issued.

 iPad tracked — A man accidentally left his iPad
in his shopping cart when he left Walmart about 2:15 p.m.
Sunday.

A woman found it and took it. The iPad’s application allowed the
man to track the device to a woman in a car parked near 22nd Avenue
and Waverly Drive. Police were called. An officer returned the iPad
to its owner without incident.

 Lebanon Police 

 Dumped transformer — A man discovered what
looked like a power transformer in the Albany-Santiam Canal on
Saturday morning near River Drive and Mountain River Drive. Pacific
Power was contacted and workers were on their way to remove the
equipment.

 Steel door wrecked — A security firm reported
early Saturday morning that a steel door to an equipment room at
Star Car Wash, 1720 S. Main St., had been cut open with a
blowtorch. Entry was made but nothing was taken.

Damage to the door and a broken window was estimated at
$1,050.

 Items missing — Someone broke into a garage in
the 400 block of A Street sometime Friday, taking millwright tools,
a .22-caliber pistol, a .22 magnum derringer, 12-gauge shotgun and
a Mossberg 500 shotgun, valued together at more than $15,000.

 Intoxicated man on bike — Police cited a
51-year-old man on a bicycle Friday afternoon for driving under the
influence at Second and Cox streets. The man had ridden his bicycle
down the center of a street then fell off, got back on and then
turned onto another street going the wrong way where he nearly was
hit by a car, and then he fell off his bike again.

He was not injured.

 School incidents — A Lebanon High School
student was suspended Friday for making alleged racial slurs to
another student, according to that student and one of his parents.
An officer will meet with the suspended student when he returns to
school.

Later on Friday, the parent of a student at Seven Oak Middle
School said his son had been assaulted by two students. The parent
said he wanted the situation resolved or he would file charges. An
officer intends to contact all of the students.

 Linn County Sheriff 

 Generator gone — A Honda generator valued at
$1,015 was reported stolen Monday morning from the back of a home
beauty shop in the 39200 block of Crawfordsville Drive. The owner
said a young woman came into the shop and a man waited for her
outside. When the owner checked the back of the house, the
generator was not there.

 Mail thief — Robert Raymon Winningham, 46, of
Albany was booked into the Linn County Jail on Sunday on multiple
charges: first-degree forgery, identity theft and 10 counts of mail
theft.

Corvallis police arrested Winningham at a fast-food restaurant
in Corvallis after he tried to use a stolen credit card to buy
food. Officers found a stolen credit card and mail that didn’t
belong to him. Most of the mail was taken from boxes on Riverside
Drive.

 Not that muddy — Deputies were called Sunday
morning to a report of a lot of mud in the 32000 block of Hidden
Valley Road. The caller wanted the mud cleaned off the roadway,
saying it was a hazard. A deputy determined there was not that much
mud on the road. The caller was mostly irritated that his vehicle
was getting dirty going through the muck.

 Tossed trash — Neighbors in the 900 block of
Isabella Street in Lebanon were counseled Sunday afternoon about
throwing garbage into a neighbor’s yard. The neighbor has goats and
was concerned about their welfare. The trash included cigarette
butts, glass and yard debris.

 Bullets fly — A caller told a deputy early
Sunday evening that someone fired shots in the 33500 block of
Bellinger Scale Road, hitting a tree next to where his girlfriend
was standing. The deputy couldn’t find anyone shooting a gun and
neighbors said they hadn’t heard any shots.

 Be nice — Lebanon hospital workers called the
sheriff’s office early Sunday evening to report a case of possible
elder abuse in the 39800 block of Mount Hope Drive near Lebanon. A
woman came to the emergency room for treatment, when the staff
heard the woman’s daughter verbally abuse the mom. The mom was seen
shaking and almost cowering, the hospital staff said. A report was
taken.

 Oregon State Police 

 Minor injury — State police said a
single-vehicle rollover happened about 5:25 a.m. Monday on Highway
228 near milepost 13 outside Sweet Home. The driver, Denise
Mitchell, 43, of Vida, crashed into a utility pole causing a power
outage.

Trooper Casi Hegney-Bach said Mitchell was westbound in a pickup
when she lost control on an icy corner. The pickup spun off the
highway, rolled onto its top and then hit the pole. The pole
snapped, falling next to the pickup.

Mitchell got out of the pickup without help. She was transported
to the hospital in Lebanon with a minor injury.

Power was restored to all 406 customers that lost power by noon,
said Tom Gauntt, spokesman for Pacific Power in Portland.
 
Tags
 James Biago Perrone , Leslie Allen Kelley , Albany Police , Robert Raymon Winningham , Lebanon Police , Albany-santiam Canal , Denise Mitchell , Lebanon High School , Seven Oak Middle School , Linn County Jail , Oregon State Police , Corvallis Police , Tom Gauntt , Pacific Power , Linn County Sheriff View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
More Local stories
 
 
 ODOT to repair freeway lanes tonight 
 
 Council approves loan for brewery 
 
 Jefferson meeting about rave scheduled 
 
 Hazy days of summer 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 democratherald.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Follow Us!
 
Facebook
 
Like on Facebook
 
Twitter
 
Follow on Twitter
 Follow @dhnews/ 
Email
 
Get email updates from

 Email Updates 
 
RSS
 
Follow via RSS

 RSS Feeds 
 


OSU Beat Writer: Cliff Kirkpatrick
 
 Jordan Poyer a Nagurski candidate 
 
Offers&amp;Announcements
 
 Oregon State Bench Press&amp;Dead Lift 
 
 See Our Available Products! 
 
 Sign up today for a Free trial class for Lil Kickers ages 18 months – 12 years old. 
 
 Downing&apos;s World Famous Gym Membership Special 
 
 Look Great This Summer! 
 View More Offers... 

 
Featured Businesses
 
 Security Alarm Corporation 
 
 Cool&apos;s Feed And Pet Supply 
 
 University Honda 
 
 Downing&apos;s World Famous Gym 
 
 New Life Nutrition 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
 Local Blogs 

 Jordan Poyer a Nagurski candidate Thursday Top 7: Ernest Borgnine Heaven on wheels Various Beavers notes Another recruit Cunningham could miss summer league games with injured hamstring Pac-12/OSU promo All-star day Football construction, recruiting Former Beavers in pro baseball 
 
Most Popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 
 A dog day afternoon in Albany I-5 crash kills Marion deputy Public Safety Log (July 7) Natasha Cortni Putnam Five people injured in Highway 34 rollover east of Corvallis Public Safety Log (July 6) Public Safety Log Public Safety Log (July 10) 
 
 Town hall is your chance to sound off (37) Mailbag: The court versus life (30) Council approves loan for brewery (30) Mailbag: Stop maligning pit bulls (28) A dog day afternoon in Albany (22) Editorial: Keep her out (16) Mailbag: Hurry up, November! (13) Mailbag: Mexico’s troubles (12) 
 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
Marketplace

 Homes Jobs 
 
Share Your Photos
 
Staff Photos
 
Links&amp;Services

 Classifieds e-Edition e-Newsletters Advertise Facebook Jobs Contact Us Mobile Apps Photo Store Twitter Obituaries Subscriber Services RSS Feeds Area Businesses YouTube 

Our Other Websites

 Albany Democrat-Herald Corvallis Gazette-Times Lebanon-Express Wheels For You Today&apos;s Deal Mid-Valley Real Estate Extra Mid-Valley Media Group Mid-Valley Blogs 
 ©Copyright 2012, democratherald.com , 600 Lyon St. S.W. Albany, OR | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Albany Apartments Albany Attorneys Albany Auto Dealers Albany Auto Parts Albany Auto Repair Albany Beauty Salons Albany Car Rental Albany Dentists Albany Doctors Albany Flowers Albany Hotels Albany Insurance Albany Loans Albany Mortgages Albany Movers Albany Pizza Albany Realtors Albany Restaurants Albany Storage Albany Tax Preparation Albany Travel More Albany… Tangent Apartments Tangent Attorneys Tangent Auto Dealers Tangent Auto Parts Tangent Auto Repair Tangent Beauty Salons Tangent Car Rental Tangent Dentists Tangent Doctors Tangent Flowers Tangent Hotels Tangent Insurance Tangent Loans Tangent Mortgages Tangent Movers Tangent Pizza Tangent Realtors Tangent Restaurants Tangent Storage Tangent Tax Preparation Tangent Travel More Tangent… Crabtree Apartments Crabtree Attorneys Crabtree Auto Dealers Crabtree Auto Parts Crabtree Auto Repair Crabtree Beauty Salons Crabtree Car Rental Crabtree Dentists Crabtree Doctors Crabtree Flowers Crabtree Hotels Crabtree Insurance Crabtree Loans Crabtree Mortgages Crabtree Movers Crabtree Pizza Crabtree Realtors Crabtree Restaurants Crabtree Storage Crabtree Tax Preparation Crabtree Travel More Crabtree… Jefferson Apartments Jefferson Attorneys Jefferson Auto Dealers Jefferson Auto Parts Jefferson Auto Repair Jefferson Beauty Salons Jefferson Car Rental Jefferson Dentists Jefferson Doctors Jefferson Flowers Jefferson Hotels Jefferson Insurance Jefferson Loans Jefferson Mortgages Jefferson Movers Jefferson Pizza Jefferson Realtors Jefferson Restaurants Jefferson Storage Jefferson Tax Preparation Jefferson Travel More Jefferson… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing democratherald.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with democratherald.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
