<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007472" url="http://bestlethbridgerealestate.com/listings-2/" time="2012-07-13-00:26" support="1" score="0.0008645599251938869" bingtitle="Listings « Best Lethbridge Real Estate" webtitle="ListingsBest Lethbridge Real Estate">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>Backs on to park, great for keeping an eye on the ... Detached 1.5 car garage and fenced yard. ... Here is a great opportunity to own a fast food restaurant in the ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Listings Downloads Testimonials About 
 Privacy Policy 
 Contact 
 
 
 Best Lethbridge Real Estate 


 Comments Posts 
     
Menu
 
 Home Listings Downloads Testimonials About 
 Privacy Policy 
 Contact 
 
Affordability Calculator
 
 Monthly Gross Income $ Monthly Debt Expenses [?] 
Monthly Debt and Obligations Should Include:

 Monthly Credit Card Payments Monthly Auto Payments Monthly Child Support Monthly Association Fees Other Monthly Obligations, but NOT utility bills. 
 $ Down Payment: $ Interest Rate: % See more mortgage rates at Zillow.com 
 
 
Mortgage Calculator
 
 Price of Home $ Down Payment   % Mortgage Term   yrs Interest Rate   % Monthly Payment $ See more mortgage rates at Zillow.com 
 
 
Closing Cost Estimator
 
 Loan Information Loan Amount $ View/Edit Closing Cost Details 

 Traditional Closing Expenses Discount Points   Origination Fee % Lender Processing Fees $ Credit Report $ Appraisal $ Title Insurance $ Reconveyance Fee $ Recording Fee $ Wire and Courier Fees $ Endorsement Fee $ Title Closing Fee $ Title Document Prep Fee $ Other Fees $ 
 
Listings
 
Please click thumbnail to view more information on the property your interested in
 
 

69.6 Acres, NW 15-6-19 W4TH, Stirling

Three bedroom, 2 bath bungalow on 69.6 acres in County of Warner. This home is on town water, has 2 high efficiency furnaces, new plumbing, new electrical, new main gas line. Wood burning fireplace and wood stove in basement. 30×42 heated workshop with 3 pce bath.. Horse shelter, 58 acres irrigated with turn-outs to fill dugout. Municipal water to fill 2000 gallon cistern.

 

 
 
 

1410 43 ST S # 109

Nice 3 bedroom mobile with large covered deck. Backs on to park, great for keeping an eye on the kids. Quiet South side mobile park, must be approved by the park administration. Property includes all appliances. Good sized rooms for the small family. Immediate possession, move in by Christmas!!!

Reduced
 
 416 BRAINARD ST N Barons

Geothermo heating, on demand hot water system, vaulted ceilings are just some of the excellent value in this home. 3+1 bedrooms, 2 family rooms, a kitchen to die for and awesome tile work throughout. Has both a front and back deck.

 
 



 

 
 
 

3615 20 AVE S

2+1 bungalow with single detached garage on south side of Lethbridge, great location, close to schools, nice quiet neighborhood

 

 

 
 
 1611 22 AVE Coaldale

 

Very nice Executive style bungalow with 1851 sqft on the main floor, 3 bedrooms upstairs and 1 bedroom downstairs, 3 bathrooms. This home has a large family room on the main floorwith a wood burning fireplace, in the huge living room their is a gas fireplace, Main floor laundry with lots of storage.This home is situated on a Large corner lot and is just waiting for the perfect family because it is centrally located close to schools and shopping.

 

 
 
 268 RED CROW BLVD W

AS IS WHERE IS at closing.

 

 SOLD 

 


 
 

54 HERITAGE LANE W

4 level split with vaulted ceilings in kitchen and living rooms. Walk-in closet in master, 3rd floor family room with walk-out basement. 3 bedroom newly developed on 4th level with 2nd 3 pce bath. Deck and off-street parking.

 

 

 
 
 

5301 2 ST # 87, Coalhurst

Cozy mobile in Coalhurst, 2 large bedrooms, fenced yard, close to schools. Purchaser must meet park requirements

 

 

 
 
 2903-31 Ave. Lethbridge

Very nice doublewide located in Parkridge Estates. Double carport, nice wrap around deck with 9×16 sunroom, 3 bedrooms, two 4-piece bathrooms, central air conditioning, 7×8 shed, nicely landscaped. Best deal in park.




 
 
 1124-25 Ave Coaldale

Very nice well cared for bi-level. Eleven years old, 3+1 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, 1086 sq. ft. with attached garage. Extra large family room down(sunshine basement) and good sized bedrooms throughout. Professionally landscaped yard, both front and back. Extra off street parking. Priced for quick sale.

 

 
 
 #7, 1712-23 st Coaldale

Here is your opportunity to own one of the nicest mobiles in a great park. 1520 sq. ft, 4 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, 45×14 ft deck with 6-man hot tub, central air conditioning, ensuite to die for, select spa steam shower, jetted tub. Lot rent only $325. includes water, sewer, garbage.

 

 

 
 
 1206 20 AVE COALDALE

This house has been totally redone, great location close to schools, shopping, swimming pool and skating rink. New gas fireplace, some new windows, nice deck, super single detached garage in back, new fence.

 

 

 
 
 1403-22 Ave, Coaldale

Nice starter home in a good location. Total of 5 bedrooms with hardwood under the main flooring, sone new windows, Adora kitchen and all oak trim. Great property for kids, close to schools and playgrounds.

 

 

 
 
 2223 11 ST Coaldale

Beautiful 4-bedroom home with 2 full baths, comes with central air conditioning. Close to both elementary and junior high schools, and hospital. Here is your opportunity to own a great family home. Double attached garage plus a dog run for your baby




 
 609 9 ST S Lethbridge

Solid bungalow in great downtown location.

 SOLD 

a

a
 
 2012 18 AVE COALDALE

Nice house with large yard. New kitchen cupboards and tile backsplash. Large living room with patio doors to backyard. Very large master bedroom with walk-in closet. Bonus large front sun room. Nice living in a small town.

3 sheds, all rods and window coverings, ceiling fans, hood fan.

 SOLD 

 
 
 #36, 2312-18 St., Coaldale

One of the nicest condo plexes around. Condo fees $300 includes heat, guest suite available, single garage, extra RV parking, 1 stall free.

 

 

 
 
 64 RIVERMILL LAND W Lethbridge

Beautiful executive style home with open floor plan, central air conditioning, vaulted ceilings, kitchen to die for, granite countertops, pantry with rollouts, large deck off kitchen plus walk out to large back yard. Double attached garage, 5 bedroom, 4 bathrooms, 2 jetted tubs,main floor laundry, vaulted ceilings, OPEN floor plan, close to schools, and parks.

 

Reduced
 
 

 216-2 Ave West, Granum

Get away from it all. Here is your opportunity to own an almost new 2 bedroom bungalow, close to school and parks in the nice quiet town of Granum.

 

 

 
 
 3.93 Acres Lethbridge

here is your opportunity to have 3.93 acres with a wonderful coulee view to build your dream home, located just north of Lethbridge next to Deerview Estates. Co-op water available, power on site, gas on edge of property. Don`t miss this opportunity. View property borders in documents attached.

 

 
 
List your home with us today

Call Gary 403 330 4598
 
 4505 3 ST W CLARESHOLM

Large 3+2 bedroom, 2 bath bungalow in a good location. Hardwood floors and large rooms, developed basement with large family room and rec room. Central air, gas fireplace and wood stove.

Back yard has small sun deck and patio, and backs onto large playground.

Double attached insulated garage and underground sprinklers.

Reduced
 
 709 MAIN ST Milk River

Updated 2 bedroom mobile home with addition on its own land.

New hot water tank. Detached 1.5 car garage and fenced yard.

 

 

 
 
 69E 200N, Raymond

1150 sqft 3 bedroom bungalow with a huge yard 62 x 264ft and a 14 x 24ft detached garage, 16 x 16ft deck for summer BBQing. Close to schools and downtown.

a

a

a
 
 4914-51 Ave, Taber

Check out this 3+1 bedroom home, with 2 full baths, bright kitchen and dining area, large bright living room with gas fireplace. Huge yard which has single attached garage plus single detached garage, covered and enclosed carport.


 

 
 
 LETHBRIDGE 2300 13 ST N # 39

Immaculate 3 year old custom built 3 bedroom, 2 bath in Bridge Villa. Ensuite and walk-in closet off master bedroom. Open plan, very nice patio off kitchen area,

nicely maintained landscaped yard.Large workshop.

 

 
 
 LETHBRIDGE 95 MT BLAKISTON RD W

Deal of a lifetime, formally used as a daycare, this home can be easily converted back to a single family dwelling or suiteable, or open your own daycare, ready and waiting for you. Great location, close to university, mall just down the street and just off a major route from Paradise Canyon. Lots of shelving, child friendly colours an a playhouse in the fenced yard. Off street parking.

 

Sold
 
 110 4 AVE Warner

Commercial storefront property located in the quaint little town of Warner. Excellent opportunity for your new business. Has a 1000 sqft 3 bedroom living quarters attached to the store. 35×47 (1645 sqft) steel shop, 40×28(1000 sqft) warehouse. Storefront is 3000 sqft.

 

 
 
List your business with us today

Call Gary 403 330 4598

 

 
 
 Wok Box west

Business only plus inventory.

Here is a great opportunity to own a fast food restaurant in the hub of the University

Great income potential.

 
 
Calendar
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S         1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
Links
 
 
 
Photos of other listings
 
Copyright©2012 Best Lethbridge Real Estate - All Rights Reserved
Powered by WordPress &amp; Atahualpa 
 Site design&amp;hosting by DBD Web Solutions
	</body>
</document>
