<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007661" url="http://fastfood.ocregister.com/2009/10/29/costco-says-new-food-stamp-policy-to-start-soon-in-california/39415/" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="1" score="0.001755248743058766" bingtitle="Costco program to help growing O.C. food stamp users - Fast Food ..." webtitle="Costco program to help growing O.C. food stamp users - Fast Food Maven : The Orange County Register">
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="71"/>
	<description>Report: Small firms get worst of credit card deals 28 minutes ago; SPORTS. Angels ... Galanti said Costco must get regulatory approval to accept food stamps in each state.</description>
	<body>
		REAL ESTATE JOBS CARS DEALS CLASSIFIEDS PLACE AN AD 
 
 SUBSCRIBE E-REGISTER CUSTOMER SERVICE TODAY&apos;S PAPER 
 Orange County Register 

 
 SURF REPORT/CAMS |  WEATHER  | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 HOME NEWS SPORTS BUSINESS ENTERTAINMENT LIFE TRAVEL OPINION 
 
 Newsletter RSS Mobile Facebook Twitter 
 Beaches | Best of OC | Blogs | Columns | Comics | Contests | Food | Gift of Giving | Health and Fitness | Home and Garden | Horoscopes | OC Moms | OC People | Outdoors | Pets | Photos | Puzzles and Games | Shopping and Deals | Video «Previous Post Next Post» All Posts 
 Costco program to help growing O.C. food stamp users 

October 29th, 2009, 11:48 am· ·posted by Nancy Luna, Staff Writer 
 
 In a phone interview today, Costco’s Chief Financial Officer Richard Galanti addressed consumer concerns about the chain’s new policy to accept food stamps at its 407 locations.

He also laid out a time frame for starting the program at Costco, which operate 12 warehouses in Orange County.

Galanti said Costco must get regulatory approval to accept food stamps in each state. Each location must get a separate approval, as well.  The goal, he said, is to have all 407 warehouses accepting food stamps by the end of the year.

Costco already accepts food stamps at a San Diego-area warehouse in El Centro. It should take“only a few weeks”before more California Costcos get approval, he said.  Locally, the move should help the increasing number of people receiving food assistance.

In Orange County, 134,965 people received food stamps in August, a 22 percent increase compared to the same month in 2008, said Terry Lynn, a spokeswoman for the county’s Social Services agency. (see more food aid data below)

Galanti said the company’s decision to accept food stamps has received mostly positive feedback from consumers. Still, he addressed customer concerns during our talk:

 

 Q: Some customers say accepting food stamps will make wait-times even longer at the register. True? 
 A: Galanti said people on government aid don’t have individual food stamps for various food items. Instead, they use a single debit-style card to swipe at the checkout stand. Cash registers deduct the value of the card from the total, and then the customer pays the difference. So there are only two transactions that occur.

 “We don’t see it as a slowdown,”Galanti said, referring to test markets in El Centro and New York.“It’s a smooth process.”

 
 
Warehouses to accept food stamps.
 
 Q: Can food stamps be applied to membership fees, and non-food items such as big screen TVs? 
A:  No.

 Q: How many food-stamp eligible items does Costco sell? 
 A: Of the 4,000 items we sell in stores—from tires to mayonnaise—about half are eligible, he said. In fact, Galanti  said“most every food item”in the store is eligible.

 Q: How many members do yo have? And, of those, what percentage are on food stamps? 
 A: We have 30 million members worldwide, and 25 million in the U.S.“I don’t know”how many of those are on food stamps.
 
 More on food assistance: According to recent data , food stamp assistance is at an all-time high with 36 million receiving aid.  In California, Orange, Los Angeles and San Diego counties were recently dubbed“high need”regions for food assistance, according to a report by state health officials.  In Orange County, food stamp use in August was up 22 percent, compared to August 2008. The average amount of aid given, per person, in Orange County is $145.14.*
 
 Tell us: What do you think of Costco’s new food stamp policy? Cast your vote here .

*assistance given varies and is based on several factors, including housing costs, number of people per household and income.
 
Northwest Wall and Ceiling Bureau’s Annual Convention and Trade Show: May 10-12, Coeur d’Alene Resort, Coeur d’Alene, Idaho.(2007 CONVENTION COMPANION)

Walls&amp;Ceilings April 1, 2007 The Northwest Wall and Ceiling Bureau’s annual Convention&amp;Trade Show will be held May 10 to 12 at the Coeur d’Alene Golf&amp;Spa Resort, in Coeur d’Alene, Idaho. The theme of this year’s event is“Set the Sails!”Attendees will enjoy educational programs, informative exhibits, important industry meetings and great tours and golf while experiencing a spectacular lakeside location about 40 minutes east of Spokane, Wash. go to website coeur d alene resort 

If you haven’t been to Coeur d’Alene recently, you will find that the city has grown tremendously and the Coeur d’Alene Resort is grander than ever. The resort has just made significant investments to upgrade the property, including the addition of a world-class spa, top-to-bottom renovation of the guest rooms, complete redecoration of the conference center and lobby, and extensive upgrades to the infamous Coeur d’Alene Golf Course.

The convention starts off Thursday morning with men’s and women’s golf tournaments at the Coeur d’Alene Golf Course. In addition to golf, groups can head out on a speedboat-and-bicycle tour, horseback riding excursion or a scenic lunch cruise on Lake Coeur d’Alene.

The official convention agenda begins later Thursday afternoon with the Opening Ceremonies and the 2007 Outstanding Project of the Year Awards showcase. Keynote speaker Carrie Stuart Parks, a fine artist and a forensic artist and investigator, will deliver a fascinating and entertaining presentation on memory–how we forget and remember. The Trade Show begins immediately following the opening session with the President’s Welcoming Party.

Friday morning begins with industry-segment meetings for the delegates while the spouses get an invigorating start for the day with a yoga class. The exhibit hall hosts a breakfast event, after which there will be a seminar on load-bearing steel framing for attendees and area architects. At the same time, there will be an intriguing seminar by Parks on how to evaluate personal communication and determine if you are being told the truth. This program is followed by a session titled“Hidden Risks&amp;Liabilities of Electronic Records,”presented by Seattle Attorney Jim Yand of Stafford Frey Cooper. this web site coeur d alene resort 

[ILLUSTRATION OMITTED] While the technical forums for interior and exterior topics are going on Friday afternoon, the spouses have a rare opportunity to learn sushi-making hands-on with the chef at Bonsai Garden.

Friday will wrap up with the anticipated manufacturer- and dealer-sponsored party at the golf course. Guests can put their tee-shots to the test at the floating green, enjoy a great buffet dinner and dancing in a large, comfortable tent, or sit at a bonfire on the beach. The only theme of this year’s party is“Fun”–attendees are invited to come as they are to this refreshing social event.

Saturday morning brings everyone to the trade show for one final opportunity to see the exhibits and to make and renew vital industry contacts. After breakfast in the exhibit hall, attendees can choose from two powerful seminars:“Succession Planning for Wall and Ceiling Businesses,”presented by Dan Gaffney, CPA, of Moss Adams LLP, and“Effective Project Management,”by Dr. Gerry Williams of R. Brown Consulting Group LLC.

The NWCB Annual Meeting is scheduled for 11:30 a.m. on Saturday. The afternoon includes technical sessions on exterior sealants and computer-aided evaluation of labor productivity and an informal, non-sanctioned group ride for motorcycle enthusiasts organized by a group of delegates. Finally, the convention will wrap up with a reception and a closing banquet with dinner, entertainment and the anticipated presentation of the Industry Person of the Year Award.

The convention is built around an informative trade show, where all the latest products, tools, systems and services are displayed. The exhibitors and delegates get an opportunity to meet face to face during the effective exhibit hours, with no competing events on the schedule.

Coeur d’Alene is a destination that the whole family can enjoy, and spouses and families are welcome at the convention. Special programs have been organized for the spouses.

For more information on the convention, call NWCB at (800) 524-4215 or visit www.nwcb.org. Registration forms and online registration are now available on the association’s Web site.

If you read this article, please circle number 370.
 Posted in: Fast food news • Costco • food stamps 

 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 
 You can skip to the end and leave a response. Pinging is currently not allowed. 

 
Reader Comments
Comments are encouraged, but you must follow our User Agreement .
 Keep it civil and stay on topic. No profanity, vulgarity, racial slurs or personal attacks. People who harass others or joke about tragedies will be blocked. 

 

 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Email (required) 

 Website 
 
 

 

 
 
 Posh Party Box $40 for $100 towards Your Party Box at PoshPartyBox.com ADVERTISEMENT 
Things to do

 
 
 Latest food trends: Register food blogger Nancy Luna recently attended the restaurant industry&apos;s biggest conference in Chicago. Check out her coverage on her Fast Food Maven blog and on her social pages: Facebook and Twitter . 
Recent Posts

 Olive Garden owner to buy Yard House for $585 million El Torito Grill closing at Fashion Island Menchie’s celebrates Irvine opening with 2-for-1 froyo deal OC Fair 2012: Your ultimate food guide Taco Bell feeds a small town in Alaska KFC launches new bite-sized fried chicken bites Wendy’s debuts Son of the Baconator 118 Degrees to expand raw food revolution with 2 new locations Updated: The Point set to open in Dana Point Porn star Ron Jeremy talks about his rum venture 
 
Mobile Food Alerts
 Fast Food Text Alerts : Subscribe to free O.C. fast food news alerts. About three to five are sent each week on breaking news, and fast-food deals. Text OCRFASTFOOD to 56654. More OCRegister news alerts. 
Contact the Fast Food Maven
 Follow the Fast Food Maven on Twitter or &apos;Friend Me&apos; on Facebook .
Send tips, reviews, gripes to nluna@ocregister.com . About the blog and blogger .



Nancy Luna, the Fast Food Maven
The Orange County Register
625 N. Grand Ave.
Santa Ana, CA 92711-1626

 

 
Register Food Writers
 
 Paul Hodgins is The Register’s wine columnist. He pens the Booze on a Budget column focusing on beer, wine and Happy Hour news every Tuesday and Friday on the Fast Food Maven blog. Marla Fisher is our Deals Diva blogger . She writes often about restaurant and grocery deals. The Food Frenzy blog gives readers daily reviews on local hidden gems in Orange County. 
 Top Food Stories: 
 Biggest fast-food flops of the 2011 Top Foods You Must try in 2011 Top Money Making Burger Chains My Morning as a Carl’s Jr. Biscuit Maker Sneak peek: Inside Thrifty Ice Cream’s factory Maven tours lettuce fields that serve McDonald&apos;s in California Inside look at McDonald’s bun factory Behind the scenes at In-N-Out’s Baldwin Park food plant 
 
2011 Top Slide Shows
 
 Is this Orange County&apos;s next best burger? Biggest fast-food flops of the 2011 Gourmet waffle shop makes waffle burger Top foods you must try in 2011 The making of an 8-pound Burger Top 10 Best Bars in O.C. (The anti-Yelp edition) Best, worst fast-food mascots 
 The recession is forcing many Orange County restaurants to shutter, and we&apos;re trying to track them all for you. Check out our O.C. Restaurant Closure List for the latest updates. 
 Restaurant Closures 

 Red Robin closing at Irvine Co. retail center Pei Wei in Irvine closes Hometown Buffet, Carl’s Jr. among four restaurant closures Daily Grill closing at Fashion Island Shore House Cafe closes 
 
New Restaurants
 The latest Restaurant Openings in Orange County . 
 The Latest Restaurant Openings 

 Menchie’s celebrates Irvine opening with 2-for-1 froyo deal 118 Degrees to expand raw food revolution with 2 new locations Another Broken Egg Cafe expanding in Southern California MainPlace: New restaurants now open, coming soon New breakfast cafe by Burger Parlor owner set to open in Fullerton Opening alert: Top Chef’s Fabio Viviani planning O.C. restaurant Opening alert: Umami reveals Anaheim opening date 
 
Fast Food Maven Awards
 
 2009 Best Blog, Orange County Press Club Best Food Blog, Just Spotted 2009 O.C. blog awards 2010: Best food blog (3rd Place) Orange County Press Club 2010: Best Transition from Traditional Media-Individual, Orange County Press Club Also, check out my OCR Wiki Page 
 
Fast Food Maven in the News
 
 Chain Leader: National trade &apos;zine interviews the Fast Food Maven Maven talks fast food value wars with CBS2 NPR: Nancy Luna on the future of In-N-Out WSJ: Maven talks burgers with Wall Street Journal 
 
 Food Truck News 

 OC Fair 2012 food truck lineup Food trucks to face off at Costa Mesa cooking contest Guide: Where to find food trucks in Orange County Food trucks 101: How to roll out a crave worthy mobile restaurant Free food prizes at Maven/OC Fair food truck gathering 
 
Audio: Interview with Jack Box
 
 More Deals From OC Deals Blog 

 Krispy Kreme doughnut deal is tomorrow! Buy 1 entree get 1 free at Denny’s 2-for-1 coupon for new Cantina Bowl meal at Taco Bell Buy 1 Mimi’s Cafe breakfast, get 1 free Fundraising for your group at Marie Callender’s 
 
Kids Eat Free
 LIST: Where do Kids Eat Free in O.C. 
Blog Watch

 Destination Irvine/Restaurants EaterLA Fast Food Weblog Food Frenzy McChronicles OC Deals OC Retail Orange County Mexican Restaurants So Good 
 
Tags
 Baja Fresh bankruptcy barbecue bbq Booze on a Budget Breakfast Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. cheap chic dining Chick-fil-A Chipotle Mexican Grill cupcakes Del Taco Denny&apos;s El Pollo Loco Farrell&apos;s Ice Cream Parlour Fashion Island Financial Five Guys Burgers&amp;Fries food events food reviews Food safety food trucks Fried food frozen yogurt grocery shopping grocery stores happy hour hot dogs Irvine Co. Jack in the Box Jamba Juice John Wayne Airport KFC Kogi BBQ Mobile food new menu Quiznos restaurant remodels Ruby&apos;s Diner Subway Taco Bell upscale dining Wahoo&apos;s Fish Taco Wendy&apos;s 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 Return to Top 
 home news sports business entertainment life travel opinion Real estate Jobs Cars Deals Classifieds Place an Ad 
 
 
ADVERTISE OPTIONS

 Self Service Place an Online Ad Place a Print Ad Place a Classified Ad Media Kit Advertising Contact Info 
 
CONTACT OCREGISTER

 About Us Careers Contact Us Corrections Customer Service Subscribe Today Subscriber Services Site Help Site Feedback 
 
OCR SERVICES

 Archives Buy Our Photos California Lottery Deals OCRegister Fanshop Orange County Businesses Register Insider Register in Education Obituaries Facebook Comments FAQs 
 
NEWS YOUR WAY

 Blogs E-Mail Newsletters E-Register Mobile RSS Article Map Site Map Video 
 
ADVERTISING

 Classifieds Cars Deals Jobs Real Estate Place a Classified Ad View our Media Kit Interactive 
 
PARTNERS

 KDOC-TV MSNBC OC Excelsior Coast Magazine Preferred Destination OrangeCounty.com FreedomPolitics.com Freedom Printing 
 
 
 Privacy Policy | Site Help | User Agreement | Site Map SEO Powered by Platinum SEO from Techblissonline
	</body>
</document>
