<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007760" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/61370532/Apeaking-Activities" time="2012-07-13-00:43" support="1" score="0.002063984364610855" bingtitle="Apeaking Activities - Scribd" webtitle="Apeaking Activities">
			<query id="001181" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Tell Us Some Things That You Dislike Everyone has things that they don’ like to do ... because its more fun when we can make a joke : What would you do say think order give ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Speaking Activities for the Classroom Copyright 2004 Compiled by David Holmes . . . . . . . .   3 Contents Preface : To The Teacher Chapter One : Warm-up Activities Chapter Two : Words, Phrases and Sentences Chapter Three : Grammar and Speaking Chapter Four : Interactive Role-Play Chapter Five : Traveling and Touring Chapter Six : Finding the Right Words Chapter Seven : Fables, Tales and Stories Chapter Eight : Talking Tasks Chapter Nine : A Bit of Business Chapter Ten : Pronunciation Chapter Eleven : How to Improve Your Diction Chapter Twelve : Sound and Rhythm Chapter Thirteen : More Pronunciation Practice Chapter Fourteen : Curriculum Development . . . . . .   4 Preface The materials in this text were compiled over a period of ten years, in Thailand from 1993 to 2003, while I was teaching at The Faculty of Arts at Chulalongkorn University and later at the Department of Language at KMUTT. I started a file of speaking activities because there were too many tasks and ideas to keep in my head, and I wanted to be able to access them when I needed them in the future. Eventually, the file grew thicker and thicker, until it was big enough to become a book. The speaking activities in this text come from a variety of sources: A lot of the tasks sprang from my own imagination, stimulating me to go into the classroom, feeling motivated by the freshness that accompanies a new inspiration and being eager to share it with my students. This could be compared to cooking on impulse rather than following a set recipe. I got many additional ideas from talking to fellow- teachers about what worked for them in their classes. I even picked up some good examples from the handouts of various courses that I was required to teach, all of which taught me a lot of time-proven tricks that almost always work. Curiously, when I told my Chula students that I was compiling a collection of speaking tasks for publication, they responded by getting involved and suggesting ideas of their own. I would often divide the class into groups of five students and tell them to make up a dramatic scene or dialogue or game, or whatever else they wanted to try, and come back and perform it in the next class. Many of these activities were effective learning tools and have been included in the book. For many years, I also facilitated English programs for Arthur Andersen, SGV Na Thalang, KPMG, Yontrakit Group, Amari Group, and Bank of Ayuddya, TOT, DEP and TAT, and other organizations, in Thailand, for which I had to keep creating new materials, so that it has become second nature for me develop speaking activities for the classroom. One final thing that I would like to add is that, at KMUTT, I learned a great deal about student-centered, self-access, task-based learning, and curriculum development, working with Richard Watson Todd of the Faculty of Applied Linguistics, so it follows that much of what you see in this book also illustrates the Theory and Practice of Curriculum Development as it was being created at that time in the International Program at KMUTT. David Holmes Bangkok, 2003 of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Apeaking Activities
 Download or Print 1,521 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 08/01/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
