<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007565" url="http://www.tarot.com/articles/bysign/datesbysign.php" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.0015821502412456002" bingtitle="Best Dates for Every Sign - Tarot, Astrology, I-Ching, Numerology ..." webtitle="Best Dates for Every Sign">
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>Crash somebody’s wedding reception. Better yet, head for a local fast-food restaurant and deck your table with silverware, candlesticks, and fine china.</description>
	<body>
		Psst ... Tarot.com Beta is now open to everyone!
 Visit Tarot.com Beta Hide 

 Login 
 Logout 
 
You Have 0 KCs
 Get More
 Karma Coins Join Tarot.com 
 Tarot Astrology Numerology I-Ching Feng Shui Love Live Psychics 
 
 New! 
 2012 Forecasts Mercury Retrograde Central Tarot Birthday Card Look-up Yes/No Tarot iPad App Horoscope Deluxe iPhone App Daily Insight Bundle Planet Pulse Video Big Picture Love Forecast Free Cosmic Profile Live Psychic Readings Daily Reflection Reading &quot;Tarot Stuff&quot; Store Yes or No Tarot Reading 
 Readings 
 Weekly Forecast Tarot Daily Reflection Tarot Passion Quest Reading Yes or No Tarot Happily Ever After Tarot Celtic Cross Love&amp;Relationships Daily Insights Specialized Readings Mandala Readings Traditional Spreads Hands-On Spreads Tarot Tools Tarot Compatibility Meter Samples Tarology Report Live Tarot Readings FREE Tarot Readings 
 Horoscopes 
 Daily 
 Daily Horoscope Planet Pulse Video Mobile Horoscopes Tarot Card of the Day Number of the Day Planet Pulse Podcast Daily I Ching Hexagram 
 Forecasts 
 Weekly Video Horoscope New&amp;Full Moon Horoscopes Weekend Lunar Love Horoscope Weekly Love Horoscope Monthly Forecast Monthly Love Forecast Monthly Career Forecast Yearly Astrology Forecast Yearly Love Forecast Yearly Career Forecast Yearly Numerology Forecast New Moon Report Our Changing Sky Solar Return Birthday Report 
 Compatibility 
 AstroBaby Finder Parent Compatibility Sibling Compatibility Astrology Love Compatibility Friend Meter Work Meter 
 Chinese 
 Chinese Astrology Profile Chinese New Year Predictions Chinese Sign Lookup Chinese Compatibility Meter 
 General 
 Moon Central Mercury Retrograde Zodiac Sign Central Free Cosmic Profile Karma Central Past Lives Central News Central Savings Central Birthday Central Free Downloads 
 2012 Forecasts 
 Yearly Astrology Forecast Yearly Love Forecast Yearly Career Forecast Yearly Numerology Forecast 
 
 Karma Coins 
 What are Karma Coins? How to Use KCs Karma Coins FAQ Buy Karma Coins KC Gift Certificates Cosmic Gift Guide Meaningful Gifts FREE Karma Coins 
 About You 
 Your Settings Your Profile Your Other Profiles KC Account Your Journal Your Cosmic Profile Reading Analyzer Reading/Report Credits Emails Subscriptions 
 About Tarot 
 Tarot Birthday Card Look-up Tarot Forums Tarot Blogs FAQs Your Question Karma Central Tarot Library Tarot&amp;Astrology Tarot Decks Authenticity Meet the Authors FREE DOWNLOADS Article Archives 
 Fun&amp;Games 
 Tarot Birthday Card Look-up Planet Pulse Video Horoscope Deluxe iPhone App Daily Insight Bundle Cool Sites Free Cosmic Profile Free Online Games Free Podcasts Weekly Video Horoscope Moon Horoscopes Free Brain Games Free Downloads Free Egreetings Karma Sutra Meter Free Love Meter Friendship Compatibility 
 Community 
 Blogs Forums Community Central Events Calendar Astrology Podcasts 
 Articles 
 Mercury Retrograde Central Article Archive 
 Sale 
 &quot;Tarot Stuff&quot; Store Numerology Reflection Reading Cosmic Gift Guide Savings Central Meaningful Gifts KC Gift Certificates Free Readings&amp;Reports Program 
 
 
 
 

 
 ARTICLES :: Astrology :: Dates That Dazzle by Sign 
 
 by Stephanie Dempsey 

There are few better ways to celebrate love and romance than with a hot date. Of course, what constitutes a hot date for a domestic Cancer could translate to a yawn-fest for adventurous Sagittarius. If you’d like to avoid disaster and fuel the right romantic heat, check out the following suggestions for the best dates by sign.

 Aries (March 21 - April 19) 
Aries needs to go where the action is. Nothing less than the hottest play, the hippest club, or the trendiest restaurant will do. If you move heaven and earth to get the Ram into an exclusive venue, you’ll be repaid with passionate kisses.

Want to reignite a long-term relationship? Take Aries someplace you’ve never been before. The venue doesn’t have to be conventionally romantic; a boxing match or the stock car races may well appeal to this extremist sign. A controversial movie is also a good bet, as Rams love the vociferous arguments that usually ensue after such flicks.

 Taurus (April 20 - May 20) 
Taurus likes tradition, so anything involving flowers, chocolate, and poetry is sure to appeal to their sensual senses. Of course, Bulls are not willing to settle for chintzy tokens. Quality is everything to this sign. That means roses instead of carnations, Godiva rather than Russell Stover and Shakespeare most definitely in lieu of Hallmark.

If you’d like to add spice to a well-seasoned relationship, take your favorite Bull out to a comedy club. Laughter always puts this sign in the mood for love. Of course, you’ll want to follow up with dinner at the finest restaurant in town. Choose a place with tablecloths, candlelight and soft music.

 Gemini (May 21 - June 20) 
People-watching is a favorite sport of Gemini. If you’d like to capture this sign’s imagination, propose taking in a session of night court together. You’re sure to encounter some terrific characters there, making for great dinner conversation afterward. Take The Twins to an eatery that is bustling with activity, like a popular bistro or hip café. Gemini likes to be where the action is.

Want to turn up the heat on a committed relationship? Keep mum about your date plans, no matter how hard your lover begs and pleads. Slip a black silk blindfold over their eyes and then escort him or her to the bowling alley, miniature golf course, or karaoke bar. The more lighthearted the venue, the more fun you’ll have.
 Tips for Lasting Romance What themes brought you two together... or could nudge you apart? Get advice to help you make your relationship last with a FREE Romantic Compatibility Report .

 Do your numbers spell L-O-V-E? Discover how your names and birthdates influence your chances for long-term love with a FREE Numerology Compatibility Report .
 
 Cancer (June 21 - July 22) 
Cancer is the caretaker of the zodiac. And while this sign is usually found attending to the needs of others, Moon Children secretly want to be on the receiving end of tender loving care. Go ahead and grant this wish by treating your favorite Crab to a day at the spa. It’s a great way to win Cancer’s everlasting devotion.

If you’re in a committed relationship with a Cancer, rekindle your romance with a trip to a flea market, antique fair, or estate sale. This sign loves being surrounded by things from bygone days. Moon Children also can’t resist a good bargain. If your lover is lucky enough to pick up some rare and collectable trinket, you can be sure their bliss will carry over into the bedroom!

 Leo (July 23 - August 22) 
Leo expects the royal treatment every day of the year, but especially so on a special night out. Plan something alluring for your favorite Lion, whether it’s a hot air balloon ride at sunset or a horse and carriage ride through the park. The best way to impress this date is to demonstrate that you’ve put a little extra thought and effort into your outing.

Want to do something extra special for your committed Leo lover? Go someplace where he or she can strut their stuff and get oodles of ogling -- like the ballet, symphony, or Oscar Awards. Don’t grumble if you have to wear a tuxedo or evening gown. Act like you’re Leo’s most precious accessory and you can’t go wrong on this date.

 Virgo (August 23 - September 22) 
Actions speak louder than words with Virgo. If you want to make a good impression on this sign, cook a gourmet dinner featuring the freshest ingredients from the local market. Craft a card with your own two hands using stylish recycled paper and super glue. Forget cut flowers that will wither within days. Instead, lovingly present a potted perennial safely cushioned in ceramic.

If you’re already involved with a Virgo, give the gift of service. Offer to relieve your lover of some dreaded chore for the next month. Be sure to live by your word, though. Nothing puts Virgo’s nose out of joint like a broken promise!

 Libra (September 23 - October 22) 
Libra’s looking for a lover that embodies style and sophistication. If you’ve got good moves, show them off on the dance floor or on the ice rink. If you’re a klutz, rent a luxury car and go for a spin through the countryside. Be sure to wear something special on your date ... Librans have a deep appreciation for stylish clothes that feature rich fabrics and flattering cuts.

If you’d like to pay tribute to a long-standing Libran lover, do it with jewelry. Monogrammed cufflinks or drop earrings are sure to make this sign’s eyes sparkle as brightly as diamonds. Choose something elegant and simple…Libras have the last word on good taste!

 Scorpio (October 23 - November 21) 
Scorpio doesn’t mess around when it comes to love. If you’re planning to ask out this sign, propose a place that is conducive to deep conversation. Reserve a corner table at a candlelit restaurant that plays soft, sensual jazz. Have three or four probing questions ready, like“If you were stranded on a desert island, what’s the one book you would take?”or“Which has a bigger influence on you: friends or family?”The more thought-provoking your queries, the better your date will go.

In the event you’re in a long-term relationship with a Scorpio, rekindle the flames of passion with the gift of lingerie. This sign is also fond of bedroom toys of all shapes and sizes. Scorpions like water sports, so a scented bubble bath is also a good way to boil up some steamy romance.

 Sagittarius (November 22 - December 21) 
Sagittarians are hopeless animal lovers. If you’d like to make a good impression on an Archer, get tickets to a dog or cat show. Better yet, plan a day of horseback riding. If you’re skittish around four-footed creatures, Sag will be happy to act as an intermediary. This sign adores introducing people to new worlds.

Want to keep the love alive between you and Sagittarius? Plan a camping trip together. Swallow your complaints and criticisms if you loathe living outdoors; if there’s anything Archers can’t stand, it’s a party pooper. A trip to a place neither of you has ever visited is also a good bet, as Sagittarians love to travel.

 Capricorn (December 22 - January 19) 
Dating is a serious business to Capricorn. The best way to capture this sign’s heart is to suggest a destination that involves some investment on your part. Choose a restaurant that requires reservations. If you don’t have a lot of money, you can always propose a nature walk. Although such an outing doesn’t cost anything, it does demonstrate a serious commitment in getting to know Capricorn.

If you’re in a long-term relationship with a Goat, give him or her a lasting token of your affection. Capricorn is an Earth sign, which suggests a deep appreciation of gemstones. Even a pair of geode bookends can elicit a delighted smile from this sign. A multi-faceted paperweight is also a good possibility, since Capricorns love gifts that are both useful and beautiful.

 Aquarius (January 20 - February 18) 
Special dates might not mean much to Aquarius, who is short on sentimentality. Still, if you demonstrate a deep appreciation for this sign’s offbeat sensibilities, you’re sure to make inroads to the Water-bearer’s heart. Propose a midnight croquet match. Crash somebody’s wedding reception. Better yet, head for a local fast-food restaurant and deck your table with silverware, candlesticks, and fine china.

To add zest to a committed relationship, look through cookbooks and choose a meal that neither one of you has ever prepared before. Go shopping together and fix a gourmet feast for the two of you. Water-bearers are excellent collaborators, and enjoy embarking on new adventures.

 Pisces (February 19 - March 20) 
Pisces and romance go together like strawberries and cream. If you’d like to treat this sign to a night they’ll never forget, take a yoga class together. Yoga is a great way to open the mind and heart to the possibility of love. Alternately, you can invite your favorite Fish over for a romantic movie and dessert. Making chocolate fondue together can be very conducive to kissing and cuddling.

To pay tribute to a committed Pisces lover on a special occasion, write out the story of your relationship and have it bound into a beautiful book. Be sure to include photographs, concert tickets, wedding announcements, party invitations and any other mementoes that elicit fond memories of your time together.
 

 
 
Find out which date idea is the best for you or your love interest at Tarot.com by reading our Best Dates by Sign article. You can also learn more about your astrology sign and astrology sign characteristics as well as those of your friends and family at Tarot.com. Come and get free astrology readings at Tarot.com. 
 

 Looking for Love by Sign 

 Finding Your Ideal Lover 

 Seduction by Sign 


 
 
 
 
 Home   |   Astrology   |   Tarot   |   Numerology   |   I Ching   |   Feng Shui   |   Psychics   |   Site Guide   |   Partner Program 
 ©Tarot.com 2012. All rights reserved.  |   About Us   |   Copyrights&amp;Legal   |   Advertise On Tarot.com   |   Privacy Policy   |   Contact Us   |   Help 
 VISIT OUR
MOBILE SITE Part of the Daily Insight Group 
 Tarot.com DailyHoroscope.com Numerology.com Decoz.com Twittascope.com FreeHoroscope.com
	</body>
</document>
