<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007758" url="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2012/01/19/Expect-insanity-defense-in-LA-killings/UPI-15901326991904/" time="2012-07-13-00:42" support="3" score="0.002338402373052168" bingtitle="Expect insanity defense in LA killings - UPI.com" webtitle="Expect insanity defense in LA killings - UPI.com">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>... the stabbing death of a homeless man behind a fast-food restaurant ... Order reprints ... Authorities in Maryland said they arrested an ice ...</description>
	<body>
		UPI en Español   |   UPI Arabic   |   UPI Asia   |   About UPI   |   My Account Search: Articles Photos Go 
 Home 
 
 Top News 
 U.S. News World News Special Reports Analysis News Photos Audio Archives 
 Entertainment 
 Movies Music TV Entertainment Photos Theater News 
 Odd News 
 Horoscope Almanac Best of Odd News 
 Business 
 Real Estate Energy Resources Security Industry Crude Oil Report Analysis: Economic Outlook Consumer Corner 
 Sports 
 Football Baseball Basketball Tennis Golf Sports Photos College Basketball College Football 
 Science 
 Technology 
 Health Photos 
 News Photos Features Entertainment Sports Photos of the Day Photos of the Week Archives 
 Columns&amp;Blogs 
 Auto Outlook Consumer Corner Daily Mix Economic Outlook Politics 2012 SciTech Talk Supreme Court 
 Analysis 
 Commentary: Arnaud De Borchgrave Walker&apos;s World Outside View 
 
 
 Obamacare repeal vote • Syrian defector • Jesse Jackson Jr. • ESPY Awards • ASEAN summit • Salvia: Stopping child sex trafficking 
 You are here:  Home / Top News / U.S. News / Expect insanity defense in LA killings 
 U.S. News 
 
Expect insanity defense in LA killings
 | | |   Tweet    Published: Jan. 19, 2012 at 11:51 AM 
 LOS ANGELES, Jan. 19 (UPI) -- A California prosecutor said he expects an insanity defense or post traumatic stress claim from an Iraq war veteran accused of killing four homeless men.

District Attorney Tony Rackauckas of Orange County said if the attorney for Itzcoatl Ocampo attempts such a defense it&apos;s &quot;not going to fly,&quot; the Los Angeles Times reported.

Ocampo, 23, didn&apos;t enter a plea when he appeared Wednesday for a brief court hearing.

His attorney, Randall Longwith, told the judge he didn&apos;t know what kind of a defense to mount because he spent no more than &quot;15 seconds&quot; with his client.

Ocampo is accused of hunting down and brutally stabbing four homeless men in suburban Los Angeles over a period of several weeks this month.

He was arrested last Friday following the stabbing death of a homeless man behind a fast-food restaurant in Anaheim, Calif.

Friends and family have described Ocampo as someone who had a longstanding empathy for the poor and homeless but returned from Iraq in 2010 as a changed man.
 Recommended Stories 
 Accused serial killer eluded police Suspected homeless killer called &apos;monster&apos; Accused killer is son of homeless man Alleged serial killer &apos;stressed&apos; after war Man suspect in slayings of 4 homeless men SoCal transient death not part of series Feds search for serial killer of homeless 
 ©2012 United Press International, Inc. All Rights Reserved. Any reproduction, republication, redistribution and/or modification of any UPI content is expressly prohibited without UPI&apos;s prior written consent.

 Order reprints Tweet    Featured Stories Tom Brady stares down CVS customers McDonald&apos;s Big Mac sauce revealed Woodchucks steal flags from graves Woman protests sausage ad ban Join the conversation Most Popular Collections 
 Victoria&apos;s Secret cycle ride for cancer PETA holds veggie dog day in D.C. Street animals of China Notable deaths of 2012 &apos;Magic Mike&apos; premieres in London 2012: The year in space 

 Additional U.S. News Stories Top News 
 Child porn and drugs sold at restaurants SAN ANTONIO, July 12 (UPI) -- Child pornography and heroin was available at two San Antonio restaurants by employing code words when ordering, a sentencing hearing revealed. 5 chimps escape Hanover Zoo, injure child More evidence released in Zimmerman case Family receives text from missing girl Colombia air force aircraft shot down 
 Entertainment News 
 LeBron James wins big at ESPY awards LOS ANGELES, July 12 (UPI) -- Miami Heat star LeBron James earned the prizes for Best Male Athlete, Best NBA Player and Best Championship Performance at the 20th annual ESPY Awards. Keith Richards says Rolling Stones &apos;rehearsing&apos; &apos;Call Me Maybe&apos; still No. 1 on U.S. record chart Florence Welch suffers throat ailment Gwyneth Paltrow producing Stand Up To Cancer show 
 Business News 
 McDonald&apos;s Big Mac sauce revealed NEW YORK, July 12 (UPI) -- Dan Coudreaut, executive chef for McDonald&apos;s fast food restaurants, has revealed the secret behind the Big Mac&apos;s secret sauce. Angry Birds creator unveils new game Iraq Kurds defy Baghdad over oil to Turkey Oil sands pipelines concern NRDC Fixed mortgage rates at record lows 
 Odd News 
 Tom Brady stares down CVS customers WOONSOCKET, R.I., July 12 (UPI) -- Customers at a Rhode Island CVS store said they were shocked when their opponent in a staring contest turned out to be Patriots quarterback Tom Brady. Woman protests sausage ad ban Male organ carved into stump Residents banned from flying U.S. flags Canada denies its plastic banknotes melt 
 
 Most Popular 1. X-ray reveals baby in carry-on bag 2. Police arrest drunken nude walkers 3. Baby born in 7-Eleven parking lot 4. AT&amp;T;offers to drop $1.4 million lawsuit 5. Pets boost infant immunity to infections 
 Stories Photos Comments 
 
 sign up to receive our daily newsletter UPI News Photos ESPY awards 2012 PETA holds veggie dog day in D.C. Michelle Obama in Florida Israel releases Palestinian soccer player Mahmoud Sarssak Obama Campaigns in Ohio Featured Photos 1 of 25 View Caption Enlarge Photo A PETA model hands out vegan hot dogs in front of the House Rayburn Office Building on July 11, 2012 in Washington, D.C. The action marks National Veggie Dog Day, PETA&apos;s annual answer to the meat industry&apos;s National Hot Dog Month. UPI/Kevin Dietsch Never buy store-brand diapers or macaroni and cheese.&quot;Too orange&quot; For just $60 an hour you can be the big spoon to this cute girl&apos;s little spoon. Just no forking After being valuated in the hundreds of millions just four years ago, Digg finally sold for the... Nielsen&apos;s top 20 most powerful TV moments. (Yes, that&apos;s on there. Yes, that too. Wait, what the... Christian and Muslim scholars unite to save you from the evils of hotel porn. See? We can all get... Let&apos;s go climb Mont Blanc, I hear it&apos;s hugely popular with climbers and only 50 people get killed... Official Government Wires  |  About UPI  |  Site Map  |  Terms of Use  |  Privacy Policy  |  Advertise Online  |  Contact Us  |  UPI Mailing Address 
 Top News  |  Entertainment News  |  Odd News  |  Business news  |  Sports News  |  Science News  |  Health News  |  Real Estate News  |  News Photos 
 Archive  |  Job News  |  World News  |  Local News  |  U.S News  |  Special Reports Resources: Auto Dealers ©2012 United Press International, Inc . All Rights Reserved. UPI.com is your trusted source for world news, top news, science news, health news and current events.
We thank you for visiting us and we hope that we will be your daily stop for news updates. ©2012 United Press International, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
 UPI.com contains copyrighted material, trademarks and other proprietary information 
 of United Press International, Inc. (&quot;UPI&quot;) and its third-party licensors, including, but not limited to, text, photos, 
 videos, and graphics. Visitors to UPI.com may use this Web site solely for their own personal and non-commercial use. 
 Any reproduction, republication and/or redistribution of any content on the Web site is expressly prohibited without the 
 prior written consent of UPI or its applicable third-party licensors. UPI and United Press International are registered 
 trademarks in the United States and in other countries.
	</body>
</document>
