<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007480" url="http://shaukinfoods.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:26" support="2" score="0.009832155428939457" bingtitle="Shaukin Foods" webtitle="Home">
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>Shaukin Indian Fast Food Phone number: 765 743 2222 Fax number: 765 743 6666 Address:</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content 
 
 
 
 Shaukin Indian Fast Food 
 
 For those craving the true taste of India! 
 
 
 
 
 Home Contact Us Menu Catering Comments 
 
 Welcome to Shaukin Foods! We are bringing the true taste of roadside Indian fast food to the streets of West Lafayette! 
 Welcome to the Shaukin Foods website where you can view our menu, any upcoming specials and directions to our place 
 What do you think of when you think of Indian food - tandoori chicken, paneer makhani, or butter naan? Traditional Indian cuisine has not done justice to the true taste of India - the tastes of roadside snacks as experienced by a majority of Indians back in India! That&apos;s where we come in - we are here to bring the foods you get by the beachside in Bombay or in the movie theatres of Delhi. We invite you to explore the menu on our website and then print the directions to devour it first hand (or you could just follow the heavenly aroma right to our doors!) 

 

 News and Events 
 Tuesday, July 3rd - Sunday, July 8th, 2012: The restaurant will be CLOSED. We apologize for any inconvenience. Like us on Facebook to stay current with the latest updates, specials and deals! 


 
 West Lafayette, IN 
 Updated Thursday, July 12, 2012 5:54 PM 

 
Clear 92°F High:   93°F 
 Low:   70°F 
 Wind:  9 mph
 Humidity:  24%
 
 MSN Weather Data provided by iMap 
 
 
 
 Shaukin Indian Fast Food 
 Phone number: 765 743 2222 
 Fax number: 765 743 6666
 
 Address: River Market Apartments,
138 S. River Road, West Lafayette, IN 47906 food@shaukinfoods.com 
 NEW Hours : Tuesday - Thursday : 4:30 p.m. - 10:00 p.m.
 Friday - Sunday: 12:00 p.m. - 10:00 p.m. 
Monday: CLOSED
	</body>
</document>
