<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007107" url="http://shineaslights.org/ideas.php" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="3" score="0.0170496506477918" bingtitle="Shine as Lights: Ideas" webtitle="Shine as Lights: Ideas">
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>When you pull up to the drive-through window at a fast food restaurant, tell the cashier that you ... When you are eating at a &quot;sit-down restaurant&quot;, pick another person ...</description>
	<body>
		Shine as Lights
 
 Home Why? Who? Stories Ideas Tag, You&apos;re It! Contact Credits 
 
Ideas

 

This page is a place where&quot;Shiners&quot;can share their ideas for anonymous random acts of kindness, and can come to get inspiration from other people&apos;s ideas. If you have an idea for an anonymous random act of kindness, either one that you have already implemented or just an idea that you think would be cool to implement as part of the&quot;Shine as Lights&quot;project, please go to the Contact page and send us a message with the details of your idea. We will update this page with new ideas on a regular basis, as those ideas are received.

 

 When you pull up to the drive-through window at a fast food restaurant , tell the cashier that you would like to pay for the people in the car behind you. When you give the cashier payment for their order, hand her a ShineAsLights.org business card and ask her to give it to the people in the car behind you when she hands them their paid-for order.

 Mow someone&apos;s yard when they are not home. You could leave an anonymous note on their door saying you mowed their yard just because you wanted to do something nice, and either leave a ShineAsLights.org business card with the note or just write&quot;ShineAsLights.org&quot;on the bottom of your note.

 When you are eating at a&quot;sit-down restaurant&quot; , pick another person, couple, or family whose meal you would like to pay for. Ask your waiter to bring you their check. When you pay for their meal, hand your waiter a ShineAsLights.org business card and ask him to give it to your beneficiaries and tell them that their meal has been paid for by an anonymous person. (When you pay for your own meal, you might add a little extra to the tip and include a note to your waiter saying,&quot;Thanks for your help.&quot;) 
 
 
 (see Credits page) 
 Copyright©2010 ShineAsLights.org
	</body>
</document>
