<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007614" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Zero" time="2012-07-13-00:35" support="4" score="0.006942515998152732" bingtitle="List of Codename: Kids Next Door episodes - Wikipedia, the free ..." webtitle="List of Codename: Kids Next Door episodes - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>The adults grab the KND while the condiment kannon is ... their concern, and gives her a simple &apos;mission&apos;: to order a kids meal from the newest fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		List of Codename: Kids Next Door episodes 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia (Redirected from Operation Zero ) Jump to: navigation , search The logo of the series 
This is a list of episodes of the American animated television series Codename: Kids Next Door , broadcast on Cartoon Network . Each season consists of 13 episodes, most of which are composed of two eleven-minute stories. There are also several full length twenty-two minute episodes. Codename: Kids Next Door premiered on December 6, 2002 and ended on January 25, 2008. [ 1 ] [ 2 ] There are a total of 78 episodes.

A TV movie, Operation: Z.E.R.O. , aired on 11 August 2006. In addition, there were two specials, one being a crossover with The Grim Adventures of Billy&amp;Mandy and the series finale Operation I.N.T.E.R.V.I.E.W.S [ 3 ] 

 Color Part one episode Part two episode Out of continuity episode 30 minutes episode Infogrames game 

 
Contents
 
 1 Pilot: 2001 2 Season 1: 2002–2003 3 Season 2: 2003–2004 4 Season 3: 2004 5 Season 4: 2004-2005 6 Season 5: 2005–2006 7 Season 6: 2006–2007 8 Films and specials (2006–2008) 9 References 
 

 [ edit ] Pilot: 2001 

 # Title Operative Appearance by Number Villain appearance Original airdate Production Code 00a &quot;Operation: C.A.K.E.D.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 DCFDTL 
January 31, 2003  ( 2003-01-31 ) 000a Expanded Acronym :Capturize And Kidnapify Enemy Dessert 
The Kids Next Door attempts to stop a birthday party for their arch-enemies, the Delightful Children From Down The Lane. But a surprise, and a monstrous guest stands between them and the greatest birthday cake ever.  00b &quot;Kenny and the Chimp in Diseasy Does It!&quot; Prof. XXXL 1999  ( 1999 ) 000b A little kid named Kenny takes Chimpy to Professor XXXL&apos;s lab. While the Professor suspects Kenny will knock open the mysterious disease containers, it is actually Chimpy who causes the havoc.  00c &quot;No P in the OOL&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5 Mr. Wink and Mr. Fibb 2001  ( 2001 ) 000c When the villainous Mr. Wink and Mr. Fibb extend the adult swimtime to extreme lengths at the neighborhood pool, the Kids Next Door plan to strike back with a vengeance.  

 [ edit ] Season 1: 2002–2003 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door (season 1) 
 # Title Operative Appearance by Numbuh Villain Original airdate Production Code 02a &quot;Operation: I.-S.C.R.E.A.M.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 DCFDTL December 6, 2002  ( 2002-12-06 ) 
May 15, 2004  ( 2004-05-15 ) ( Kids&apos; WB! ) 102a Expanded Acronym : Important – Steal Creamy Refrigerated Edibles Avoid Meltdown 
The KND catch wind of some ice cream men who refuse to give ice cream to kids, so they interrogate them and get the password to their ice cream factory, only to be in for a major surprise from the DCFDTL.  02b &quot;Operation: C.A.N.N.O.N.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 999 DCFDTL December 6, 2002  ( 2002-12-06 ) 
May 15, 2004  ( 2004-05-15 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 102b Expanded Acronym : Cannon And Naptime Not Occurring Normally 
Numbuh 4 forces the other operatives to build a &quot;clam cannon&quot; when Numbuh 1 temporarily leaves.  03a &quot;Operation: N.O.-P.O.W.U.H.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 DCFDTL and Gramma Stuffum December 13, 2002  ( 2002-12-13 ) 
May 22, 2004  ( 2004-05-22 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 103a Expanded Acronym : New Orders – Pulverize Opposition Without Utilizing Hamsters 
The hamsters that power Sector V&apos;s weapons go on vacation. Meanwhile, the DCFDTL look for villains to attack Sector V, so they send an old lady named Gramma Stuffum, who is fixated on fattening kids, to Sector V&apos;s powerless HQ.  03b &quot;Operation: T.E.E.T.H.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Knightbrace December 13, 2002  ( 2002-12-13 ) 
May 22, 2004  ( 2004-05-22 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 103b Expanded Acronym : Tooth Extracting Enemy Terrorizes Headquarters 
Numbuh 3&apos;s teeth are cleaned by a dental-obsessive villain.  04a &quot;Operation: P.I.R.A.T.E.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Stickybeard December 13, 2002  ( 2002-12-13 ) 
June 5, 2004  ( 2004-06-05 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 104a Expanded Acronym : Pirates Invade Repository And Treats Extracted 
Candy pirates steal Sector V&apos;s candy, including Numbuh 5&apos;s secret stash.  04b &quot;Operation: C.O.W.G.I.R.L.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Mr. Wink and Mr. Fibb December 13, 2002  ( 2002-12-13 ) 
June 5, 2004  ( 2004-06-05 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 104b Expanded Acronym : Crazy Old Woman Goes Increasingly Really Loco 
An adult, Lasso Lass, that acts like a kid, wants to help Sector V defeat Mr. Wink and Mr. Fibb.  05a &quot;Operation: T.U.R.N.I.P.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Turnip Farmer December 20, 2002  ( 2002-12-20 ) 
June 12, 2004  ( 2004-06-12 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 105a Expanded Acronym : Turnips Unfortunately Reaching Near Infestation Point 
When turnips are found everywhere in Sector V&apos;s treehouse, they go to the source: a giant turnip.  05b &quot;Operation: M.I.N.I.-G.O.L.F.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Great Puttinski December 20, 2002  ( 2002-12-20 ) 
June 12, 2004  ( 2004-06-12 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 105b Expanded Acronym : Miniaturization Is Now Issue – Golfing Opposite Looney Fanatic 
After Numbuh 2 beats a mini-golf champion at mini-golf, the golfer shrinks Numbuh 2, and a whole lot of sights from around the world.  06a &quot;Operation: O.F.F.I.C.E.&quot; 3, 4 Mr. Boss January 3, 2003  ( 2003-01-03 ) 
June 19, 2004  ( 2004-06-19 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 106a Expanded Acronym : On Fourteenth Floor Is Corporate Evil 
When his father brings Numbuh 4 to work for &quot;Bring Your Daughter To Work Day&quot;, Numbuh 4 discovers his father&apos;s boss plans to send him and all the girls to Pluto .  06b &quot;Operation: A.R.C.T.I.C.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 30C Prof. XXXL, Professor Bob January 3, 2003  ( 2003-01-03 ) 
June 19, 2004  ( 2004-06-19 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 106b Expanded Acronym : Am Really Cold That Is Certain 
A fellow operative, Numbuh 30c, is sent to help Sector V stop a villain from using a weather machine to make no more snow days for school.  07a &quot;Operation: L.I.C.E.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 DCFDTL January 10, 2003  ( 2003-01-10 ) 
June 26, 2004  ( 2004-06-26 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 107a Expanded Acronym : Lice Interrupt Cheese Eating 
The DCFDTL attack Sector V&apos;s headquarters with an infestation of hair-eating lice. A parody of Aliens .  07b &quot;Operation: L.I.Z.Z.I.E.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Numbuh 1, Lizzie Devine January 10, 2003  ( 2003-01-10 ) 
June 26, 2004  ( 2004-06-26 ) (Kids&apos; WB!) 107b 
 Expanded Acronym : Love Is Zesty Zany Insanity Eh? 
Numbuh 1 has a secret girlfriend who he often neglects because of his KND responsibilities, forcing her to use a boyfriend helmet to mind control Numbuh 1.
 NOTE : This is Kids&apos; WB! &apos;s final episode.  08a &quot;Operation: T.H.E.-F.L.Y.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 DCFDTL January 17, 2003  ( 2003-01-17 ) 108a Expanded Acronym : Tiny Horsefly Examines – Five Little Youngsters 
A fly finds its way into Sector V&apos;s headquarters. All dialogue is censored out of this episode.  08b &quot;Operation: P.O.I.N.T.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Sector V January 17, 2003  ( 2003-01-17 ) 108b Expanded Acronym : Prowling Operatives Investigate Naughty Teenagers 
All the teenagers in Sector V&apos;s hometown have formed a place called &quot;The Point,&quot; and Numbuh 1 suspects that they are helping the adults.  09a &quot;Operation: C.A.B.L.E.-T.V.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5 Mr. B January 24, 2003  ( 2003-01-24 ) 109a Expanded Acronym : Crazy Arrogant Baby Loses Every – Television Viewer 
A villainous half man and half baby named Mr. B gives the Kids Next Door a TV show.  09b &quot;Operation: C.A.M.P.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 Chester January 24, 2003  ( 2003-01-24 ) 109b Expanded Acronym : Children Are Miserable Parents 
A lost baby skunk interferes with a mission to rescue brainwashed campers.  10a &quot;Operation: T.O.M.M.Y.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, T Tommy, Common Cold February 7, 2003  ( 2003-02-07 ) 110a Expanded Acronym : Totally Obnoxious Moronic Meddling Youngster 
Numbuh 2&apos;s little brother, who is shunned by Sector V, joins forces with a villain.  10b &quot;Operation: C.H.A.D.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 44, 45, 46, 67, 68, 69, 274 Mega Mom and Destructo Dad February 7, 2003  ( 2003-02-07 ) 110b Expanded Acronym : Charming Hero Avoids Destruction 
Two parental villains are stupefying KND operatives around the world. An operative named Chad (Numbuh 274) enlists the help of Sector V.  11a &quot;Operation: P.I.A.N.O.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Truck Driver February 21, 2003  ( 2003-02-21 ) 111a Expanded Acronym : Pesky Instruments Advances New Operative 
Sector V tries to destroy some pianos in a truck with a hamster that acts as Numbuh 4&apos;s replacement.  11b &quot;Operation: Z.O.O.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Ms. Goodwall February 21, 2003  ( 2003-02-21 ) 111b Expanded Acronym : Zoologically Obsessed Octogenarian 
Sector V is put into a &quot;kids zoo&quot; and must unite with the DCFDTL to escape being fed to the zoo&apos;s cannibal bully .  12a &quot;Operation: Q.U.I.E.T.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Toiletnator, Lizzie Devine, Laura Limpin/The Big Badolescent, Stickybeard, The Common Cold, and Professor XXXL February 28, 2003  ( 2003-02-28 ) 112a Expanded Acronym : Quiet Unlikely In Entire Treehouse 
Numbuh 5 tries to keep the treehouse quiet so Numbuh 1 can sleep.  12b &quot;Operation: R.A.I.N.B.O.W.S.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Mr. Mogul and Simon February 28, 2003  ( 2003-02-28 ) 112b Expanded Acronym : Running Amok In Nature&apos;s Bounty Observing Wild Simians 
The boss of Rainbow Monkeys Inc. uses Numbuh 3 to find real Rainbow Monkeys for him.  13 &quot;Operation: G.R.O.W.-U.P.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Father and DCFDTL March 7, 2003  ( 2003-03-07 ) 113 Expanded Acronym : Getting Really Old Will – Upset Plans 
The frustrated DCFDTL turn to their Father for help destroying Sector V. Their leader is turned into an adult, the treehouse is destroyed, and their faith is shattered; Sector V is forced into a showdown with their most dangerous foe to date.  




 [ edit ] Season 2: 2003–2004 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door episodes (season 2) 
 [ edit ] Season 3: 2004 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door episodes (season 3) 
 [ edit ] Season 4: 2004-2005 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door episodes (season 4) 
 [ edit ] Season 5: 2005–2006 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door episodes (season 5) 
 [ edit ] Season 6: 2006–2007 
 Main article: Codename: Kids Next Door (season 6) 
 # Title Operative Appearance by Numbuh Villain Original airdate Production code 66 &quot;Operation: S.A.F.E.T.Y.&quot; 2, 4 Safety-bots August 25, 2006  ( 2006-08-25 ) 601 
 Expanded Acronym: Senator Attacks Foes Endangering Today&apos;s Youth 
When a kid-friendly minister receives a funding of approximately eleven-billion dollars, he uses it to build an army of Safety-bots, to make the world a safe place for children. But the robots grow more and more extreme in their actions, eventually planning to eliminate adults, and cover the Earth in bubble wrap.
 Note: the Safety-bots are a parody of the Sentinels from the X-Men comic books.  67a &quot;Operation: E.N.G.L.A.N.D.&quot; 1, Sector E Operatives RHFATS September 15, 2006  ( 2006-09-15 ) 602a Expanded Acronym : Evidently Not Getting Language Annoys Nigel Desperately 
When Numbuh 1 is taken to England, someone gives him a book, resulting in Numbuh 1 getting followed by 3 kids. A precursor to &quot;Operation: Z.E.R.O.&quot;.  67b &quot;Operation: A.W.A.R.D.S.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 All Villains September 15, 2006  ( 2006-09-15 ) 602b 
 Expanded Acronym : Attack Will Amazingly Ruin Dinner Show 
Sector V attempts to sabotage the Villain&apos;s Choice Awards.
Parody of Nickelodeon Kids&apos; Choice Awards and Ocean&apos;s 11 .  68a &quot;Operation: R.E.C.E.S.S.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Principal Smelling September 22, 2006  ( 2006-09-22 ) 603a Expanded Acronym : Recreation Ended &apos;Cuz Enemies Savor Salad 
When salad oil is discovered in the school playground, Numbuh 1 must find a way to save recess, while still keeping a promise to Lizzie. Principal Smelling and his assistant somewhat parody Klink and Burkhalter in Hogan&apos;s Heroes .  68b &quot;Operation: H.A.M.S.T.E.R.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 SFFATL September 22, 2006  ( 2006-09-22 ) 603b Expanded Acronym : Hungry Archenemy Meowers Strike To Entrap Rodents 
While the team is off on their recess-rescuing mission, the hamsters are attacked and captured by the Sinister Felines from Atop the Litterbox, but end up battling the Hamsters Next Door. A parody of Tom and Jerry .  69 &quot;Operation: W.H.I.T.E.H.O.U.S.E.&quot; 1, 74.239, Numbuh 124, Numbuh 1,600, Numbuh 5,000, Numbuh Infinity, Adult 1, Adult 2, Adult 3, Adult 4, Adult 5, Adult 86, Adult 274, other future Sector V operatives Adult Numbuh 2, Adult Numbuh 3, Adult Numbuh 4, other Adult KND September 29, 2006  ( 2006-09-29 ) 604 
 Expanded Acronym : What Happens If The Existing Head Of United States Escapes 
Numbuh 1 wakes up to discover that he is the president of the United States in another reality, who is about to sign the Declaration of No Kids&apos; Rights .
The end of the episode parodies The Wizard of Oz   70a &quot;Operation: S.P.I.N.A.C.H.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Spinach Armada January 5, 2007  ( 2007-01-05 ) 605a Expanded Acronym : Salad Pushing Invaders Now Attempt Crusade Here 
Amerigo Vespinaccio tries to spread spinach throughout the school, and it&apos;s up to Sector V to stop him. A parody of the Spanish Armada and the Spanish Inquisition .  70b &quot;Operation: M.E.S.S.A.G.E.&quot; 2 6 Gum Gang January 5, 2007  ( 2007-01-05 ) 605b Expanded Acronym: Make Express Shipment Safely Avoiding Gummy Enemies 
Numbuh 2 attempts to deliver the fourth grade president&apos;s message.  71a &quot;Operation: B.R.I.D.G.E.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 11-Teen, 20,000, other Sector P.h.d. operatives Sector P.h.d. January 12, 2007  ( 2007-01-12 ) 606a Expanded Acronym : Before Really Incredible Destruction Gotta Evacuate 
Numbuh 20,000 and his Squid Squad work with Sector V to destroy the bridge leading into Le Sissie, a store in the mall that sells horrible back-to-school clothes for kids.  71b &quot;Operation: S.I.X.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 6 Mr. Fizz January 12, 2007  ( 2007-01-12 ) 606b Expanded Acronym : Soda Is X-changed 
Numbuhs 2, 3, and 6 are tricked and must get a truckload of soda to a girl&apos;s birthday party and keep Mr. Fizz and Lieutenant Seltzer from getting the soda. (The truck, which is revealed to not have the stated cargo inside, is strongly reminiscent of, and perhaps borrows from, the plot line in the movie The Road Warrior ).  72 &quot;Operation: T.R.I.C.Y.C.L.E.&quot; All Operatives Numbuh 2 January 19, 2007  ( 2007-01-19 ) 607 Expanded Acronym : Tommy&apos;s Ride Is Calamity You Can&apos;t Let Escape 
Tommy loves Numbuh 2&apos;s cruddy, old tricycle but gets laughed at when the other kids see him riding it. Using his 2x4 technology expertise, Tommy rebuilds it into the &quot;Best Bike in the Whole World&quot;, but the bike turns evil trying to impress Numbuh 2. One of the last scenes when the tricycle arrives is a parody of Independence Day .  73a &quot;Operation: C.R.I.M.E.&quot; 2, 3, 4, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5 Crayon Boy January 26, 2007  ( 2007-01-26 ) 608a Expanded Acronym: Crayon Renderings Implicate Mostly Everyone 
When Gallagher Elementary students are being arrested by the School Safety Patrol for crimes they are envisioned to commit, including detective Numbuh 2, it&apos;s up to Numbuh 3 to investigate a psychic member of the School Safety Patrol while trying to finish her social studies homework. A parody of Minority Report and Heroes .  73b &quot;Operation: P.A.R.T.Y.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 9, 11, 274 Teenagers January 26, 2007  ( 2007-01-26 ) 608b Expanded Acronym: Party Animals Rule Teens Yell 
With Father away for the day, The DCFDTL invite Cree and the teenagers to their mansion to plan a new strategy against the Kids Next Door, but instead, the teenagers turn it into a wild house party, leaving the DCFDTL to call Sector V for help.  74a &quot;Operation: D.O.G.H.O.U.S.E.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 The Were-Poodles June 1, 2007  ( 2007-06-01 ) 609a 
 Expanded Acronym : Desperate Operative Grabs Homework Outta Unusually Spooky Environment 
Numbuh 5 goes into the Haunted Doghouse to get Sector V&apos;s cinder block back, but later comes out different.
 Note: This is the only episode Numbuh 4 is seen wearing his hood.  74b &quot;Operation: P.L.A.N.E.T.&quot; 2, 3, 4, 71.562, 74.239, 321 Rainbow Monkeys June 1, 2007  ( 2007-06-01 ) 609b 
 Expanded Acronym : Poor Little Astronauts Never Expected This 
Numbuhs 3 and 4 are launched into space to break the &quot;Ridiculous&quot; space barrier, but black out in mid-flight and wake up on a world ruled by anthropomorphic, talking Rainbow Monkeys.
A parody of the first Planet of the Apes movie  75a &quot;Operation: S.C.I.E.N.C.E.&quot; 2, 2x4, 13, 30C, 42, 74.239, 80 123, 202, Sector C Operatives, Sector F Operatives, Sector H Operatives none November 2, 2007  ( 2007-11-02 ) 610a Expanded Acronym : Sooper Cool Inventions Encourage New Commercial Enterprises 
This episode illustrates a day at the annual kids&apos; 2x4 tech science fair. Numbuh 2 is present, shoving his &quot;I Can&apos;t Believe It&apos;s Not Booger&quot; product down the judges&apos; throats.  75b &quot;Operation: A.M.I.S.H.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 42, Jebidiah, Ezikiel, Rebecca, Sector F Operatives none November 2, 2007  ( 2007-11-02 ) 610b Expanded Acronym : All Machines Illegal Seethes Hoagie 
Continues from Operation: S.C.I.E.N.C.E. . Sector V sends Numbuh 2 into hiding at an Amish sector to his extreme dismay.  76 &quot;Operation: G.I.R.L.F.R.I.E.N.D.&quot; 1, 65.3, 74.239, 362, Infinity Sector V Treehouse November 9, 2007  ( 2007-11-09 ) 611 Expanded Acronym : Guess It&apos;s Realistic Lizzie Finally Realizes Its Essentially Nigel&apos;s Dysfunctions 
Lizzie thinks Nigel has found a new girlfriend.  77a &quot;Operation: C.A.R.A.M.E.L.&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, Alternate 1, Alternate 2, Alternate 3, Alternate 4, Alternate 5, Sector U Operatives, Alternate Sector U Operatives Heinrich von Marzipan November 16, 2007  ( 2007-11-16 ) 612a 
 Expanded Acronym : Candies Are Really Altering Many Extraordinary Lives 
Heinrich uses a ritual involving sacred golden caramels to take away the qualities the Sector V operatives value the most. (Numbuh 1&apos;s leadership, Numbuh 2&apos;s intellect, Numbuh 3&apos;s giddiness, Numbuh 4&apos;s toughness, and Numbuh 5&apos;s Coolness) Numbuh 5 eventually teaches Heinrich that he needs to share his candy to revert to his original form. She is then seen leaving with a young Blonde girl (Which, disturbingly, is implying that Heinrich was a girl before the transformation.)
In Operation: C.A.R.A.M.E.L. the incident in Guatemala 5 years ago between Numbuh 5 and Heinrich Von Marzipan is explained.  77b &quot;Operation: M.O.O.N.&quot; All Operatives Adults November 16, 2007  ( 2007-11-16 ) 612b Expanded Acronym : Moving Out Of Neighbourhood 
Adults send Numbuh 4&apos;s family to the Moon to colonize it. But Sector V diverts the colony to Hollywood, where they stage a fake colonization, tricking the Beatles family and the adults at mission control to prevent them from discovering the KND Moonbase. A parody of The Truman Show .  78 &quot;Operation: T.R.E.A.T.Y.&quot; All Operatives Teenagers December 7, 2007  ( 2007-12-07 ) 613 Expanded Acronym : Teens Readily Extend Armistice To Youngsters 
The KND and the Teens are about to sign the &quot;You don&apos;t mess with us-We don&apos;t mess with you&quot; Kid-Teen treaty. It is going to be signed by Numbuh Infinity (KND) and the Teens&apos; leader, but it turns out to be a trap for the KND, making Numbuhs 1 and 274 set out to prevent it after being falsely convicted by the KND.  




 [ edit ] Films and specials (2006–2008) 

 # Title Operative Appearance Villain Appearance Original airdate Production code M1 &quot;Operation: Z.E.R.O.&quot; All Operatives All Villains and Grandfather August 11, 2006  ( 2006-08-11 ) M01 
 Expanded Acronym : Zero Explanation Reveals Origins 
An all powerful villain Grandfather puts into action a world domination plan by turning everyone into evil senior citizens. The KND also speak of the legend Numbuh 0 who defeated Grandfather, which makes him their only hope.
 Note: This special was supposed to represent the last episode of KND   S1 &quot;The Grim Adventures of the KND&quot; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 60, 362, T,Grim The Delightful Reaper,Mandy,Billy,and DCFDTL November 11, 2007  ( 2007-11-11 ) S01 
In the crossover with The Grim Adventures of Billy&amp;Mandy , when a scythe-related mishap puts Billy stuck in his Dad&apos;s lucky pants, only the Kids Next Door can save him from a grounding of a lifetime.
 Note: Ed, Edd n Eddy , Blossom, Bubbles and Buttercup from The Powerpuff Girls , Andy from Squirrel Boy , Adam from My Gym Partner&apos;s A Monkey , Dexter, Dee Dee and Mandark from Dexter&apos;s Laboratory , Bloo and Mac from Foster&apos;s Home For Imaginary Friends , and other Cartoon Network characters make brief cameos at the end of the Cartoon Network crossover episode.  M2 &quot;Operation: I.N.T.E.R.V.I.E.W.S.&quot; All Operatives All Villains January 25, 2008  ( 2008-01-25 ) M02 Expanded Acronym : It&apos;s Now The Extra Really Very Interesting End Wrap-Up Story 
Series Finale. In live-action interviews, Numbuhs 2–5 are re-commissioned as adults and tell what happened to Numbuh 1 on the final mission.  

 [ edit ] References 
 
 ^ &quot;Cartoon Network&apos;s Codename: Kids Next Door Challenges Tyrannical Rule of Adults Starting Tomorrow – December 6&quot; . Businesswire.com . 2000 . http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m0EIN/is_2002_Dec_5/ai_94934182 . Retrieved 25 October 2008 .   ^ &quot;PR: Codename: Kids Next Door Embarks on Its Final Mission&quot; . Toonzone.net . 2008-01-15 . http://news.toonzone.net/article.php?ID=20846 . Retrieved 25 October 2008 .   ^ &quot;CN Upfront: Three &quot;Billy&amp;Mandy&quot; Movies, More Specials&amp;Crossovers Planned – Updated&quot; . Toonzone.net . 2007-02-16 . http://news.toonzone.net/article.php?ID=15133 . Retrieved 25 October 2008 .   
 Retrieved from &quot; http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List_of_Codename:_Kids_Next_Door_episodes&amp;oldid=501517777#Films_and_specials &quot; Categories :
 Lists of American animated television series episodes Lists of American television series episodes 
 Hidden categories:
 Episode list using the default LineColor 
 
Personal tools

 Create account Log in 
 
Namespaces

 Article Talk 
 


 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to Wikipedia 
 
Interaction
 
 Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact Wikipedia 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Cite this page 
 
Print/export
 
 Create a book Download as PDF Printable version 
 
Languages
 
 Español Italiano Polski Português 
 
 This page was last modified on 10 July 2012 at 06:29.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License ;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc. , a non-profit organization.
 Contact us 

 Privacy policy About Wikipedia Disclaimers Mobile view
	</body>
</document>
