<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007960" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/49/531016/restaurant/Downtown/Kenn-Tico-Cuban-Bar-Grill-Richmond" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="1" score="0.0006388307782495299" bingtitle="Kenn Tico Cuban Bar &amp; Grill - Downtown - Richmond | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Kenn Tico Cuban BarGrill - Downtown - Richmond | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="156"/>
	<description>I would recommend a Fast Food restaurant over this POS excuse ... We had no silverware, had to ask for napkins after ... is insanely fresh and I got a small cup to go</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Richmond » Richmond » Downtown » Kenn Tico Cuban Bar&amp;... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Baltimore Hampton Roads Los Angeles New York Philadelphia Research Triangle Washington DC More... 
 
Kenn Tico Cuban Bar&amp;Grill
 
(804) 225-9216
 Downtown 204 E Grace St 
 Richmond , VA 23219 
 kennticocubanbargrill.com 
 See all 21 reviews Cuisine Cuban Menu $ Under $10 per entree Cubito, Mojito Cubano View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   75 people have voted 93 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Elephant Thai 86% $ West Franklin Street - Thai, Vegetarian 1100 W Cary St 
 
 Kobe Japanese Steak&amp;Sushi 82% $$$ Downtown - Steakhouse, Japanese, Sushi 19 S 13th St 
 
Critic reviews

 January 10, 2011 Style Weekly Of the mains, classic Cuban pork (lechon asado, $9.95) stands out with a light marinade of lime and garlic on tender... More from Style Weekly 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 July 1, 2011 Likes it Eating Video Games A nice meal good friendly service. More from Eating Video Games 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 4, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Reservation not honored, poor service, lackluster food by beatnikgal ( 3 reviews ) We had reservations for five and when we arrived at the restaurant they gave us the option of squeezing around a bar table or waiting for the only five top that was near turn over. We chose the bar table and good thing we did - the other table didn&apos;t clear for another half hour! The service was really slow, the mojito&apos;s are NOT the best in town, they were very weak actually, and the food was extremely overpriced. We asked for seperate checks and were ignored and given one check. Just an all around bust of a night out. There are just too many good restaurants in town to suffer through, and pay for, this one. July 29, 2011 Likes it Bravissimo! by JD ( 28 reviews ) Scored a&quot;$30 for $15&quot;coupon from Richmond Livingsocial . . . I will hit it twice the next time the offer runs! We loved the place! My bride had Camarones al Ajilo (sautéed Shrimp) $11.99 andI I had the Ropa Vieja (shredded flank Steak w/ peppers, onions) $12.95. The meal includes a salad and 2 sides . . . a lot of food! I had the Frijoles Negros . . . GOOD! . . . and Filling! The House Dressing is Cilantro, Parsley, Garlic, Lime juice, Spices&amp;Olive Oil. Tasty stuff, as long as you like garlic - We Do! Split a Flan for desert . . . yum, yum! Check it out . . . and if you get the coupon off Livingsocial . . . It&apos;s 1/2 Price! Happy Hour drink prices, M-F, 5-7PM ! Standard Kids Menu - Chix Fingers, Cheese Burger, Hot Dog ($2.50), Grilled Cheese - $3.75 2 out of 2 found this review helpful January 24, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Alan Crawford ( 57 reviews ) Excellent food, good atmosphere, very well priced. Service a bit slow, but so what, you&apos;re here for the great food. April 14, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Stephanie Franklin Fitzgibbons ( 1 review ) Wonderful staff even better food and still craving the jalapeño sauce. The staff is very attentive and offered great suggestions. I wish I lived in walking distance. April 6, 2012 Likes it Great Food by Julie ( 1 review ) We were staying in a nearby hotel and found this on the website, the best mojitos ever, the cuban sandwich was amazing and the rest of the meal was just as good. The Cuban salad dressing was fantastic, I hope they bottle it soon. The service was great, we will be back the next time we are in Richmond. December 12, 2011 Likes it Best Mojitos in RVA by TAMMY ( 168 reviews ) I have had my fair share of mojitos in my day. I can say that this is the best one I have ever had. I also had the cujito, which is the mojito with coconut, which in my taste was even better. April 1, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Juan lopez ( 1 review ) Wonderfull place friendly staff I go there at list 3-4 times a month with my wife we love it love the food great atmosphere can&apos;t get any better then that they have real Cuban bread and you will not find a Cuban sandwich in Richmond with the Cuban bread mojitos are great only $ 7.00 freshly made , and 57 Chevy very strong you should try it March 30, 2012 Worst Place Ever by klotzerkn ( 1 review ) Horrible owners, and the employees are even worse. Loud, perverse conversations that all customers can hear and obscene language in front of children. Very unprofessional environment. Only thing they have going for them is the drinks. I would recommend a Fast Food restaurant over this POS excuse of a restaurant. March 20, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Jen Mitchell ( 3 reviews ) We had a great dinner. The mojitos were fantastic! My husband can&apos;t handle garlic, so he opted for the sirloin which was cooked well, but wasn&apos;t special. I ordered the pan con bistec which was phenomenal. We split a piece of tres leches cake, which was very rich and delicious. We will definitely be back. January 22, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Kevin P ( 7 reviews ) Saturday night and the place was full. We had a few mojitos. The mango mojitos were great. We had the Cuban classic and the Cuban with chorizo and they were fantastic. Now for the down side. You better not be in a hurry. We waited at the bar for over ten minutes while looking at our eventual table sit empty until I finally asked if we could sit there. We had no silverware, had to ask for napkins after our food arrived and never got a glass of water after asking twice. Of course we had to also ask for the check when we were done. I will go back for the good food but only when I am not on a schedule. February 29, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it HORRIBLE! by sharon ( 1 review ) We recently attending the Virginia Wine Expo at the Richmond Convention Center. Before making our trip, we researched nearby restaurants. Our interest was piqued by the relatively good reviews of the Kenn Tico and it was within walking distance of our hotel. We were starving upon arrival and looking forward to a hopefully authentic cuban meal. The restaurant was fairly empty, which surprised us, because it was peak dinner hour and the reviews had indicated quite a wait time to get a table. We were waited on fairly quickly for our drink order; however, it took a relatively long wait for the arrival of the actual (albeit weak) drinks. We placed an order for appetizers, which took FOREVER and now I know why....it must take a lot of skill to make a resemblence of food out of sawdust! We decided not to order any more food, even though we were still hungry. Why throw good money after bad? To make matters worse, we waited forever for our check! Don&apos;t bother going here unless you like getting agitated. January 22, 2012 Not for big groups! by Mike Zuk ( 2 reviews ) Our group of 12 (we had reservations) obviously overwhelmed the bar/wait staff and kitchen. Good drinks, good, cheap food, but long waits for big groups. I&apos;ll go with a small group next time. July 16, 2011 Really likes it Delightful Surprise by Jen20003 ( 16 reviews ) Stumbled across this while walking down the street from our hotel. The menu looked decent and it wasn&apos;t that busy but we took a chance. It was just awesome, fresh food with good service. I had the Ropa Vieja with Yuca Frites and Arroz Moro. Their Cuban salad dressing is insanely fresh and I got a small cup to go. Don&apos;t sleep on this spit Richmond! It&apos;s good July 13, 2011 Really likes it &quot;REAL&quot;Cuban Food by Jessie Mejias ( 2 reviews ) This is the third&quot;Cuban&quot;restaurant we have tried out in Richmond and it is the first one we can say is&quot;REALLY&quot;Cuban! The items on the menu are all the items you would expect to find at a traditional Cuban restaurant and the food was delicious, seasoned and cooked just right. We will go back...and bring others with us. September 21, 2011 Mobile review by Holly Cruz ( 1 review ) The best cuban food in virginia also really good drinks, love this place one of my favorite September 17, 2011 Real cuban by Maritza Read Amadeo ( 1 review ) My husband and I are always looking for authentic cuban food every city we go. Being both from the caribbean we truly miss our food. Look no further... this is as authentic as you can find. Food was delicious. Had my doubts when a critic wrote a review on the place...obviously he never had cuban food before or at least real one. November 14, 2011 Awful by Kristen ( 1 review ) We went to Kenn Tico for the first time and had the worst pork I have ever had and poor customer service. The portions were small for the price too (although that didn&apos;t matter since the food was terrible). Don&apos;t waste your money! February 9, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jane ( 2 reviews ) Insanely good and authentic. No cutsie stuff on the walls, just really good food. February 8, 2011 excellent by David C Keller ( 1 review ) Ive had some cuban sandwiches in my day , but this was one of the best i have ever had. Service was excelent and their expresso yummmm!!! cant wait to try the mojitos owner promised to get some Don Q Rum! You want to experience real cuban food Ken Tico is the place. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by TAMMY Cubito. Mojito... by Derick Rivers Enjoying GREAT... 
 All 3 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Pizza Movers Downtown - Pizza Valentino&apos;s Italian Pizzeria 86% $$ Downtown - Pizza, Sandwiches/Subs Romanza Pizzeria $ Downtown - Pizza, Italian Perlys 93% $ Downtown - American, Sandwiches/Subs, Breakfast/Brunch Tonys Bar-Be-Que $ Downtown - Barbecue 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Carpenter Center -
600 E Grace St Cotton Club -
N 4th St&amp;E Franklin St Linden Row Inn -
100 E Franklin St Richmond Centre -
101 N 5th St Richmond Convention Center... -
403 N 3rd St 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 kenn tico cuban restaurants in richmond va kenn tico cuban bar cuban restaurant richmond va best mojito in richmond va 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
