<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007620" url="http://www.independentmail.com/news/2010/may/06/lets-do-lunch-five-guys-burgers-and-fries/" time="2012-07-13-00:35" support="6" score="0.011984229292929333" bingtitle="Let&apos;s Do Lunch: Five Guys Burgers and Fries » Anderson ..." webtitle="Let&apos;s Do Lunch: Five Guys Burgers and FriesAnderson Independent Mail">
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>We will tell you about prices, atmosphere ... seem content to jump to the nearest fast food restaurant for ... says “Order Here,” looks above the cashier’s head and order.</description>
	<body>
		Login | Manage Account | Mobile | Contact Us | E-Edition | Subscriber Services | Reader Rewards 
 User Name: 
 Password: Forgotten your password?  | Create an account Register or log in using your account on these websites. site web 
Web Search powered by Yahoo! SEARCH
 Anderson Independent Mail 
 News 
 Local Crime South Carolina Northeast Georgia National World Weather Obituaries Politics 
 Local National South Carolina Georgia 
 Education Columnists 
 Salley McInerney 
 
 Sports 
 OrangeandWhite.com 
 Football Baseball Basketball All Sports 
 Local High School Soccer Pro Football High School Football 
 All Stories Abbeville Belton-Honea Path Calhoun Crescent DW Daniel Dixie Elbert County Franklin Greenwood Habersham T.L. Hanna Hart County Liberty Palmetto Pendleton Seneca Stephens County Walhalla West Oak Westside Wren 
 College 
 Baseball Basketball Football Anderson Trojans Clemson Tigers USC Gamecocks 
 Golf Columnists 
 Greg Wallace Paul Strelow Brad Senkiw Scott Adamson 
 
 Business 
 Local Real Estate Columnists 
 Joe Sangl 
 
 Opinion 
 Editorial Letters to the Editor Politics Columnists Blogs Polls 
 Entertainment 
 Local Arts&amp;Theater Events Calendar 
 Submit Event Anderson Venues 
 Dining 
 Bars&amp;Clubs Food&amp;Drink Specials Restaurants Open Now Submit Restaurant 
 Movies Music 
 Anderson Bands Anderson Venues mp3s Anderson Radio 
 Nightlife Technology Television Columnists 
 Jake Grove 
 
 Lifestyles 
 Local Announcements 
 Anniversaries Birthdays Births Engagements Weddings Hometowner 
 Faith&amp;Values Fashion&amp;Style Food Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden HomeTowner Columnists 
 Home&amp;Garden 
 Juanita Garrison Laura Stokes Bob Polomski 
 Health&amp;Fitness 
 John Defendis Debbie Jackson 
 Books 
 Kathryn Smith 
 Faith&amp;Values 
 Marybeth Evans Joan Kobe 
 
 
 Media 
 Today&apos;s Photos Photo Archive Photo Galleries Photo Galleries by Topic Videos User Submitted 
 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classified 
 
 
NEWS ALERT

 The Main Street Program of Anderson has cancelled tonight&apos;s Block Party. 
 
 
Let&apos;s Do Lunch: Five Guys Burgers and Fries

 By Jake Grove Anderson Independent Mail Posted May 6, 2010 at 10:33 a.m. 

 Discuss Print A A A 
 

 
All too often, we don’t go somewhere new or different because we don’t know what to expect. That is where this new feature, “Let’s Do Lunch,” comes in. Each week, we will highlight a different spot for lunch that you can try. We will tell you about prices, atmosphere and anything else you need to know before showing up and chowing down.

And if you have a place we should go, don’t hesitate to drop a line. It’s always lunchtime around here.

Five Guys Burgers and Fries

3501 Clemson Boulevard Anderson; 864.716.0466

It seems like the lost art of the burger joint has been lost on today’s consumers. These days, people seem content to jump to the nearest fast food restaurant for the newest “Angus” burger or the newest quadruple-decker hamburger patty with bacon, blue cheese and jalapenos to come down the pike. If it’s big enough, has enough stuff on it and comes to us in 15 seconds or less, it must be a pretty good burger.

But the burger joint is so much more than speed and stuff. The burger joint is an institution passed down to us from generation to generation. It’s not about pre-frozen patties that show up on a truck. It’s not about fries that are the same in Japan as they are in the backwoods of the USA. It’s about being able to get a hand-patted burger and some fresh French fries without having to worry about toys or anything other than that growling tummy.

Anderson has a couple places that are known for just that kind of deliciousness and one of them happens to be Five Guys Burgers and Fries on Clemson Boulevard.

Going into Five Guys is a pretty simple process and so is ordering. Walk to the counter where is says “Order Here,” looks above the cashier’s head and order. There is no need to wonder and no need to take forever at this step because Five Guys doesn’t offer all that much in terms of selection. They know you are only there for a couple things and that’s what they give you.

Take your choice between the regular hamburger or cheeseburger, the little hamburger or cheeseburger or a hot dog. That’s it. Nothing fancy, nothing that requires a corresponding number or letter sequence. Just order your burger or dog, tell them if you want fries and a drink or not and move on down the line.

It sounds so simplistic, and it is, but it’s effective and Five Guys does a couple things and does them well.

Now, there is one thing to know, however, before ordering the burger. The regular burger is actually two patties of beefy goodness. The little burger is just one. This is important to know because that one patty can be the difference between a stuffed belly coma around 3 p.m. and being about to stave off that coma until after the workday is done.

It should also be noted that if fries are ordered, there are going to be a lot of fries coming your way. Five Guys fills their standard cup of fries, but then puts an extra scoop in the bag for good measure. It’s a lot of fries and only the biggest of appetites can put them all away.

The nice thing about Five Guys is their toppings. They have all the basics, but also offer up grilled onions or mushrooms, A-1 Steak Sauce, jalapenos, barbecue sauce and more for their burgers. And everything is a la carte. There is no value meal or other mathematical equation to ensure you are getting the best deal possible. If you want it, you order it.

In all, a burger, fries and a drink will cost about $9. If you go little, you get the same for around $7. And if you go the hot dog route, it’s a little cheaper. Plus, their fries are fresh cut and they even tell you where the potatoes came from on a sign as you walk in the door.

They take cash and credit or debit cards. And they will get you your food within 5 to 7 minutes of ordering, depending on the crowd in front of you.
 
 ©2010 Anderson Independent Mail. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
 Discuss Print 
 


 
 
 Also in Dining&amp;Restaurants 

 More 
 
 Order Up: Main Street Deli in Anderson Order Up: Chicken Basket in Anderson Alchemy now open in downtown Anderson 
 
Comments » 2 
 
 May 6, 2010 9:41 p.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 autoguy57#233546 writes:
 
Clean, friendly, and a good atmosphere! Top that off with probably the best burger and fries in town, and you can&apos;t go wrong here. Glad to see this place finally made it to Anderson.
 
 May 17, 2010 8:51 a.m. Suggest removal Reply to this post 
 
 shih writes:
 
My family enjoys Five Guys Burger and Fries. It&apos;s a great place for teens and dads.
 
Share your thoughts

Comments are the sole responsibility of the person posting them. You agree not to post comments that are off topic, defamatory, obscene, abusive, threatening or an invasion of privacy. Violators may be banned. Click here for our full user agreement .
 
 Username * Don&apos;t have an account? Sign up for a new account 

 Password * Can&apos;t remember? Reset your password 

 Comment 
 
 
 
Comments can be shared on 
 
 
 Facebook
 and 
 Yahoo!.
Add both options by connecting your profiles .
 
Most Popular
 
 Viewed Commented Emailed 
 
 Deputy coroner says body in woods that of missing businessman Updated 7/12/2012 at 10:17 a.m. 47 comments Deputy coroner says Anderson businessman was shot in head Updated 7/12/2012 at 2:36 p.m. 7 comments Anderson police arrest two Upstate men accused of using Craigslist to solicit minors Published 7/11/2012 at 5:56 p.m. 2 comments Teen girl killed in west Anderson home invasion Updated 7/9/2012 at 7:07 p.m. 137 comments Records show Iva officer was disciplined at sheriff&apos;s office Published 7/10/2012 at 10:12 p.m. 72 comments 
 
Photo Galleries
 Missing man&apos;s body found near lake 2012 women Olympic athletes Triple shooting in Oconee County 
 Teen girl killed in west Anderson home invasion Published 7/9/2012 at 10:24 a.m. 137 comments Records show Iva officer was disciplined at sheriff&apos;s office Published 7/10/2012 at 10:12 p.m. 72 comments Deputy coroner says body in woods that of missing businessman Published 7/11/2012 at 4:23 p.m. 47 comments Romney draws boos from NAACP at national convention Published 7/11/2012 at 10:46 a.m. 31 comments Dog gone: Winston, The Fox in Anderson&apos;s mascot, not allowed inside Published 7/7/2012 at 10:12 p.m. 65 comments 
 
 Malware may knock thousands off Internet on Monday Published 7/5/2012 at 7:53 a.m. 1 comment B.R. Skelton declared GOP nominee in House race Published 7/9/2012 at 1:39 p.m. 3 comments Bartee indicted for kidnap plot Published 7/10/2012 at 11:58 a.m. 17 comments Ron Wilson&apos;s family farm announces closing Published 7/3/2012 at 5:15 p.m. 2 comments Easley funeral home to offer Starbucks setting Published 7/12/2012 at 6:17 a.m. 6 comments 
 
Weather
 
 Currently 36-Hour Your Photos 
 Currently 79 ° Mostly Cloudy Wind: NE 8mph Today 82 ° 70 ° Fri 07:00 AM Thunderstorms Temp: 73° Fri 07:00 PM Thunderstorms Temp: 78° Sat 07:00 AM Thunderstorms Temp: 73° 
Feels Like: 73°

Humidity: 91%

Precip: 69%
 
Feels Like: 78°

Humidity: 74%

Precip: 55%
 
Feels Like: 73°

Humidity: 90%

Precip: 40%
 End of summer 10/19/11
6:58 p.m.
 End of summer 10/19/11
6:58 p.m.
 End of summer 10/19/11
6:57 p.m.
 End of summer 10/19/11
6:57 p.m.
 Storm across Lake Hartwell 7/25/11
1:25 p.m.
 Snow Bear 1/20/11
10:00 p.m.
 More Weather» 
Business Directory
 
 Search Browse 
 Business: e.g. salon Location: e.g. Anderson, SC 
 Powered by Local.com 
 Auto Dealers Auto Repair Books Carpet Cleaning Child Care Coffee Shops Dentists Doctors Florists Furniture Golf Courses Gyms Hair Salons Hotels Insurance Jewelry Lawn Services Locksmiths Movers Pizza Plumbing Realtors Remodeling Restaurants Storage Veterinarians 
 Powered by Local.com Full Directory» 
Features
 

 
 
 Mobile Apps 

 Get news on your smart phone! Check out our apps for iPhone, Android and more 
 
 Lowest Upstate Gas Prices 

 Find the cheapest fuel where you live 
 
 Follow us on Twitter! 

 Stay up-to-date with your news. Follow us on Twitter, @independentmail. 
 
 Pedaling for Parkinson&apos;s 

 Read Steve Quam&apos;s weekly blog here! 
 
 Looking for some summer fun? 

 Check out our list of summer camps in the Upstate! 
 
 Lake Hartwell&apos;s 50th 

 See stories, a list of events and historic photos here! 
 
 Civil War: 150 years 

 Check out our special section! 
 
 Clemson Fans! 

 Find our Clemson Tigers coverage at our new website: OrangeandWhite.com 
 
 Share Your Photos! 

 Text or upload your best shots here 
 
 Reader Rewards 

 Let your subscription give back. Get discounts and perks at local businesses! 
 
 Calling All Artists 

http://www.independentmail.com/art/&quot; title=&quot;Apps&quot;&gt;Submit your artwork to Anderson Life! 
 
 On the Web: Legal notices Sex offender search Unclaimed Property Gas Prices Lake Levels I-85 Cameras Marketplace eClips Online Exclusives: Today&apos;s Photographs Photo galleries Events Calendar VIP Lounge Wag&apos;n&apos;Brag Useful Links: Local Anderson Job Listings Classified Ads Newspaper archives Area Guide Place an ad! State of South Carolina State of Georgia Send us your news RSS Feeds Community Links: Anderson Area Chamber of Commerce Anderson County Anderson Sports&amp;Entertainment Complex City of Anderson AnMed Health Business Directory: Anderson Apartments Anderson Attorneys Anderson Auto Dealers Anderson Auto Parts Anderson Auto Repair Anderson Beauty Salons Anderson Car Rental Anderson Dentists Anderson Doctors Anderson Flowers Anderson Hotels Anderson Insurance Anderson Loans Anderson Mortgages Anderson Movers Anderson Pizza Anderson Realtors Anderson Restaurants Anderson Storage Anderson Tax Preparation Anderson Travel Featured More... 
 Business Directory 
 Business: e.g. salon Location: e.g. Anderson, SC 
 Powered by Local.com Scripps Interactive Newspapers Group
2012 The E.W. Scripps Co.
 More news from our local partners» Privacy Policy | User Agreement | About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
