<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007749" url="http://www.timesfreepress.com/news/2012/feb/05/chattanooga-fast-food-restaurant-expanding-24-hour/" time="2012-07-13-00:42" support="8" score="0.02041336161004627" bingtitle="Chattanooga fast food restaurant expanding to 24-hour service ..." webtitle="Chattanooga fast food restaurant expanding to 24-hour service  | timesfreepress.com">
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000871" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>• Restaurant eating declined 3 percent between 2007 ... The fast-food restaurant is conveniently located, she said, and ... Or did you do something that makes my food cheaper?”</description>
	<body>
		timesfreepress.com go 
 jobs job seeker: 
 post your resume&apos; 
 search job 
 search companies 
 employers: 
 post a job 
 log in 
 homes find a home 
 foreclosures 
 sell your house 
 find an apartment 
 cars find a car 
 sell a car 
 research a car 
 featured vehicles 
 trucks 
 boats 
 hybrids 
 shop today&apos;s chattadeal 
 todays ads 
 deals 
 coupons 
 businesses 
 classifieds find an ad 
 place an ad 
 public notices 
 announcements 
 find a business 
 garage sale 
 merchandise 
 pets&amp;supplies 
 
 Home latest local business sports life opinion politics my tfp sites:    right2know mobile community obituaries north georgia pix news revolution current get out chatter dining out subscribe to the tn valley rss feed home » business » tn valley »Chattanooga fast food restaurant ... published Sunday, February 5th, 2012 
Chattanooga fast food restaurant expanding to 24-hour service
 share email print font size by Carey O&apos;Neil 
 view bio » The Highway 153 McDonald’s restaurant is now open 24 hours for people using the drive-through service. Photo by Tim Barber . 
 RESTAURANT TRENDS 
 
• Restaurant eating declined 3 percent between 2007 and 2011.

But restaurants sales grew 4 percent in the 1-4 a.m. period since 2007.

• Today, the average consumer eats 195 meals at a restaurant over a year, compared to the peak rate of 215 in 2000.

• Fast food places serve 27 percent of those eating late, second only to convenience stores which account for 34 percent.

Source: The NPD Group
 
Sometimes when Jessica Dintsch gets home around midnight, she just wants a hamburger.

After working the night shift at KFC, the last thing she wants to do is cook. So three or four nights a week, she’ll leave work, drive to her East Ridge home, change clothes and hop back in the car for a late-night McDonald’s run.

“I’m hungry, and it’s cheap,” she said from her car as she waited in line at the East Ridge McDonald’s drive-through just after midnight Thursday morning. “I can get full on three bucks.”

The fast-food restaurant is conveniently located, she said, and one of the only places open when she gets off work.

Dintsch is just one of the many eaters helping the late-night sector of restaurant sales grow in an industry that has seen declines since the recession.

As long as restaurantgoers think like Dintsch, consumers could see an increase in late-night fast food options.

Restaurant eating declined 3 percent between 2007 and 2011, according to consumer marketing research firm The NPD Group. But meals between 1 a.m. and 4 a.m. grew 4 percent in the same period.

“The demands of the consumer are ever changing,” said Art Holekamp, president of McDonald’s Chattanooga advertising co-op. “In most restaurants, at least in Chattanooga, most everybody has extended their hours, either opening earlier or staying open later.”

Only about 3 percent of restaurant meals are served in those early-morning hours, but when retailers see a growing market, they’ll move to capture it. All-night restaurant service has been around for decades at diners, but fast-food restaurants only recently started increasing their 24-hour offerings.

Nationally, almost 40 percent of McDonald’s serve food 24 hours a day, up from 30 percent in 2005, according to The Wall Street Journal. Burger King restaurants stay open until midnight on Fridays and Saturdays and until 11 p.m. the rest of the week.

Local fast-food restaurants still are feeling out whether Chattanooga wants all-night offerings. Fewer than a third of the 47 McDonald’s in Holekamp’s co-op, which stretches from Stevenson, Ala., to Murphy, N.C., have gone to 24-hour service, but several stores are moving that way.

Figuring out where the expanded schedule will succeed can be difficult. If a store sits on a major highway or near a constantly-operating factory, the decision can be easier; but restaurant owners often are best off testing different hours and seeing how customers respond.

“That’s the easiest way to gauge demand — extend the hours and see what happens,” Holekamp said. “There’s not a science to this thing.”

If there is a science to scheduling decisions, Gordon Davenport, Burger King franchisee for most of the stores within 50 miles of Chattanooga, said that science is largely uncharted territory.

None of his restaurants is open 24 hours a day, he said, but many are open 22 or 23 hours. His peak dinner period can go as late as 9 p.m., and the restaurants stay busy right up until midnight on weekends, he said. But it’s not just the late-night market that is changing, he said. It’s the way Americans eat.

“The notion that we eat lunch at noon and we eat dinner at 6 or 7 p.m., we definitely see those broadening,” he said. “Eating habits have changed, and somehow that feeds into the 24/7 restaurant phenomenon.”

But Harry Balzer, chief industry analyst for The NPD Group, said his consumer marketing research firm hasn’t seen a significant change in the way people are eating, just a move toward more convenient eating.

“We really aren’t eating more. We’re choosing different places to consume food,” he said. “The long-term question is, did you do something that made my life easier? Or did you do something that makes my food cheaper?”

For many fast-food restaurants, the answer to those questions is yes. Since the economy crashed, price and convenience have become even more important to the average eater.

So as restaurant markets decline, owners are ready to make whatever changes they can to capture more market share.

“It’s fluid. What didn’t work today may work six months from now,” Holekamp said. “There are still patterns there, but they don’t mimic the patterns of 30 years ago.”
 email Share FB Share Linkedin Share myspace Tweet 
related articles»
 
 Taco Bell enters crowded breakfast arena 
 Jan. 27th, 2012 
LOUISVILLE, Ky. — Yo quiero Taco Bell breakfast burrito!
 
 Georgia based Chik-fil-A&apos;s rising fortunes 
 Jan. 16th, 2012 
If someone asked you to name a fast-food chain off the top of your head, McDonald&apos;s might be the first ...
 
 McDonald&apos;s net income rises 9 percent 
 Oct. 21st, 2011 
McDonald&apos;s Corp. on Friday said its third-quarter net income rose by 9 percent to $1.51 billion, its ninth straight quarter ...
 
 Apple slices in every McDonald&apos;s Happy Meal 
 July 27th, 2011 
An apple a day may keep the doctor away. But when you put it in a Happy Meal, it might ...
 
 videos»          

 photos»          

 e-edition» 
 e-edition advertisement 
 
other tn valley news»
 Chattanooga poor in connecting jobs, workers via public transport July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Foreclosures rise, but lenders see signs of improvement July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Lattimore Black Morgan&amp;Cain shifting to Chattanooga&apos;s Liberty Tower July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Business briefing July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Cannon Equipment closure to end 71 jobs in Chattanooga July 11th, 2012  |   share   |   
top headlines»
 Ben Friberg goes the distance on the Yukon River in Canada July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Katherine Benefield, Rhonda Thurman&apos;diametric opposites&apos; July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Swimmers hit the open water: Club meets each Wednesday to swim in the Tennessee River July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Bradley County boys&apos;core temperatures rose past 105 July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Group gathers in Chattanooga to battle gangs July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   
top commented stories»
 The war on mountain pride July 11th, 2012  |   share   |   25 comments When Pigs Fly July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   48 comments Political Baggage July 10th, 2012  |   share   |   250 comments 5-at-10: Paterno, politics and college football, remakes we want and Dream Team debate July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   14 comments Open letter to Alexander July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   10 comments 
top emailed»
 VW suppliers hiring 100 more workers in Chattanooga July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   Auto supplier Mann+Hummel USA creating 150 jobs in Dunlap, Tenn. Nov. 3rd, 2011  |   share   |   comment Chattanooga featured in plot of ‘Iron Man 3’ blockbuster July 12th, 2012  |   share   |   
 advertisement 
Find a Business
 Search: Popular Searches Apartments in Chattanooga 
 Attorneys in Chattanooga 
 Auto Dealers in Chattanooga 
 Auto Parts in Chattanooga 
 Auto Repair in Chattanooga 
 Beauty Salons in Chattanooga 
 Car Rental in Chattanooga 
 Dentists in Chattanooga 
 Doctors in Chattanooga 
 Flowers in Chattanooga 
 Hotels in Chattanooga 
 Insurance in Chattanooga 
 Loans in Chattanooga 
 Mortgages in Chattanooga 
 Movers in Chattanooga 
 Pizza in Chattanooga 
 Realtors in Chattanooga 
 Restaurants in Chattanooga 
 Storage in Chattanooga 
 Tax Preparation in Chattanooga 
 Travel in Chattanooga 
 Featured 
 More... 400 East 11th St., Chattanooga, TN 37403
General Information (423) 756-6900 site map 
 mobile 
 email updates 
 subscribe archives 
 contact us 
 advertise 
 promotions submit events 
 feedback 
 place an ad 
 rss feeds Copyright, permissions and privacy policy , Ethics policy - Copyright©2012, Chattanooga Publishing Company, Inc. All rights reserved. 
 This document may not be reprinted without the express written permission of Chattanooga Publishing Company, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
