<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007116" url="http://www.befrugal.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:06" support="6" score="0.00992988751526893" bingtitle="Online Coupons, Promotional Codes, Printable Coupons &amp; More at ..." webtitle="Online Coupons, Promotional Codes, Printable Coupons&amp;More at BeFrugal.com">
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="43"/>
	<description>Features 1000s of online coupons, money saving tools, printable grocery coupons ... Things Remembered Coupons. Free Shipping on Any Order Expires: 5/13 Click to Activate</description>
	<body>
		Where It Pays to Be Frugal. 
 Member Login    Join Now 
 
 

 Or Browse By Store 
 
 
 HOME 
 
 ONLINE COUPONS 
 
 PRINTABLE COUPONS 
 
 GROCERY COUPONS 
 
 WEEKLY ADS 
 
 TOOLS 
 
 BLOG 
 
 CASH BACK 
 
 SMALL BIZ 
 
 
 BeFrugal.com 
 Your resource for stretching your hard earned dollars! 

 
 Thousands of Online Coupons Printable Grocery Coupons 
 
 Insider Deals&amp;Thrifty Tips Blog Exclusive Money Saving Tools 
 
 Free Shipping Offers And more! 
 
 
 
Online Coupons for 40,000+ Stores!
 
 
 
 See All Stores 
 
Today&apos;s Top Coupons
 
 Online Coupons: 

 
 Gap Coupons 
 25% Off Any Item 
 Expires: 7/12 
 1277718 Code: Click to Get Code   4% Cash Back 

 
 Pfaltzgraff Coupons 
 40% Off Any Item 
 Expires: 7/16 
 1279039 Code: Click to Get Code   10% Cash Back 

 
 Folica Coupons 
 20% Off Folica&apos;s 4-Star Products 
 Expires: 7/16 
 1265267 Code: Click to Get Code   10% Cash Back 

 
 Kohl&apos;s Coupons 
 15% Off Any Order 
 Expires: 7/16 
 1274870 Code: Click to Get Code   4% Cash Back 

 
 Express Coupons 
 $30 Off $100+ Order 
 Expires: 7/15 
 1277716 Code: Click to Get Code   5% Cash Back 
 
 Free Shipping Offers: 

 
 Victoria&apos;s Secret Coupons 
 Free Shipping on Orders of $50+ 
 Expires: 7/15 
 1279036 Code: Click to Get Code    

 
 dELiA*s Coupons 
 Free Shipping on Any Order 
 Expires: 7/12 
 1277693 Code: Click to Get Code   4% Cash Back 

 
 Bath&amp;Body Works Coupons 
 $1 Flat Rate Shipping on $20+ Purchase 
 Expires: 7/12 
 1279038 Code: Click to Get Code   4% Cash Back 

 
 GNC Coupons 
 Free Shipping on Any Order 
 Expires: 7/12 
 Click to Activate   12% Cash Back 

 
 Alloy Coupons 
 Free Shipping on Orders of $25+ 
 Expires: 7/26 
 1270938 Code: Click to Get Code   4% Cash Back 
 
 
 Printable Coupons: 

 
 Office Depot Coupons 
 $20 Off $100+ Purchase 
 Expires: 7/16 
 Click to Print    

 
 Lord&amp;Taylor Coupons 
 20% Off Regular Sale&amp;Clearance Items 
 Expires: 7/16 
 Click to Print    

 
 Aeropostale Coupons 
 15% Off Any Order 
 Expires: 7/31 
 Click to Print    

 
 Staples Coupons 
 20% Off Canon Cameras 
 Expires: 7/14 
 Click to Print    

 
 Yankee Candle Coupons 
 $10 Off $25+ Purchase 
 Expires: 8/5 
 Click to Print    
 
 Restaurant Coupons: 

 
 Longhorn Steakhouse Coupons 
 Complimentary Appetizer 
 Expires: 7/29 
 Click to Print    

 
 Denny&apos;s Coupons 
 Get a Smoothie W/ Purchase of Any Entree 
 Expires: 7/14 
 Click to Print    

 
 Papa John&apos;s Coupons 
 Bonus Large 3-Topping Pizza With $10+ Online Order 
 Expires: 7/25 
 Click to Print    

 
 Red Robin Coupons 
 Buy 2 Entrees Get Bonus Sweet Potato Fries 
 Expires: 7/13 
 Click to Print    

 
 KFC Coupons 
 $3 Off 12 Piece Meal 
 Expires: 7/31 
 Click to Print    
 
 
Latest From the BeFrugal Blog:
 
 Deals of the Day - 7/11/12 
 Wednesday July 11, 2012 by TODD 
 Our deal hunters have searched low and high today to bring you the best deals from around the Web. See below for today&apos;s top d... more 
 
 
 
Tools For Shoppers:
 
 

 Fly or Drive Calculator™ 
Planning your next trip and wondering whether to fly or drive? Compare the cost and time of driving vs flying. more... 


 

 Amazon Discount Finder 
Find secret savings&amp;hidden discounts at Amazon.com! more... 


 

 Amazon Free Shipping Filler 
Want to qualify for Amazon&apos;s Super Saver Free Shipping Offer but haven&apos;t met your $25 purchase price? more... 


 

 Discounted Gift Card Finder 
Using our Discount Gift Card Finder, you can purchase gift cards for many of your favorite stores for up to 25% off retail value! more... 


 

 House vs. Car Cost Comparison 
Ever wonder how much you should spend on a car? more... 


 

 Electric Car Calculator 
Compare the environmental and financial costs of buying and electric car to hybrid, diesel and gas-powered vehicles. more... 

 
Tools For Bloggers and Webmasters:
 
 

 Amazon Discount Widget 
Give your visitors access to the most heavily discounted items at Amazon. Best of all, if you have an Amazon Associates Account, you will get paid when your visitors save. more... 


 

 Coupon Widget 
Display the latest online coupons for your favorite stores right on your website. Best of all, if you have an affiliate account you can get paid any time one of your visitors uses a coupon. more... 


 

 Fly or Drive Widget 
Add the BeFrugal.com Fly or Drive Calculator™to your website and let your users compare the total cost and travel time of any trip for both driving and flying. more... 


 

 Weekly Ad Widget 
Give your users instant access to the latest weekly ad circulars. The BeFrugal.com Weekly Ad Finder widget features 200+ weekly ads more... 

 
 
FIND A STORE:
 
 Find Store by Letter: 

 A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z # 

 » See All Stores 

 » Browse By Category 
 
MOST POPULAR CASH BACK STORES:
 
 123 Inkjets Up to 28% Avenue 8% Barnes&amp;Noble 6% Bath&amp;Body Works 4% Blue Nile 5% Drugstore.com 10% eBags 7% Fabric.com 10% Finish Line 8% Foot Locker 6% HP 3% Kohl&apos;s 4% Lowe&apos;s Up to 5% Macy&apos;s 3% Old Navy 4% Personalization Mall 15% PETCO 5% ProFlowers 10% Target 4% Torrid 8% 
 
 »See All Stores 

 »How Cash Back Works 

 
FLY OR DRIVE CALCULATOR™:
 
BEFRUGAL CONTESTS:
 
ADD COUPONS:
 Merchants, do you have a store you would like to promote? Add your store and coupons to BeFrugal through our merchant portal . Get targeted, relevant traffic for your store. Best of all, its FREE! FOLLOW US ON FACEBOOK: 
 
 
 About Us   Terms&amp;Conditions   Privacy Policy   Contact Us   Bloggers&amp;Partners   Bloggers Earn $5 Per Referral   Merchants Add Your Coupons     Press Room   
 
Are you an online merchant?
   
Merchants can add their coupons to BeFrugal.com with a Merchant Account. Do you want to add this feature to your current account?

      
 

 
Thanks!
Your email was successfully sent. 
   Send to a Friend 
 

 
 Code: 
 Your Name: Your Email Address: Friend&apos;s Email Address: Add Another Friend Email Message: I thought you might like this great deal I found on BeFrugal.com. Check it out! 
 

Powered by ReCAPTCHA

 
 
 Coupons   
Click on the link below for your coupon:
 
Sorry, this offer has expired.

Please use the following offer from instead:
 
 Currently, BeFrugal.com does not have any coupons available for this merchant. 
We update our coupons each day so please check back in the near future. To request a store or specific coupon code, please visit our contact page .
 See All Coupons 
This offer is provided to you by BeFrugal.com. Find grocery coupons, restaurant coupons, exclusive promo codes plus earn an 
 average of 5% Cash Back at more than 3000 stores only at BeFrugal.com.
 
GET 5% 

Join BeFrugal.com for free and get an average of 5% Cash Back in addition to savings from specials&amp;promotions and $5 for referring a friend .
 Create a free BeFrugal.com account 


Sign Up for the BeFrugal.com Newsletter
&amp;Get Your Fly or Drive Results Now
 
Get exclusive travel deals plus the hottest coupons, deals&amp;more from your #1 resource for saving money - BeFrugal.com!

   
 


No Spam! We won&apos;t spam you or share your email. Privacy Policy .
 
 No thanks, just show me my results 
 
 Email Address  
 
 
By joining BeFrugal.com, you agree to our Terms of Service 
and our Privacy Policy .

 
 I&apos;m already a BeFrugal.com Member 
 
As seen on:  

 Why join? Get coupons and cash back at 3000+ stores - and even use both to &quot;double-up&quot; your savings. Simply join, then start your online shopping session at BeFrugal.com. There are no points, no forms, no fees - just cash back to you via check or Paypal. Stores pay BeFrugal.com a commission for sending them shoppers and we share that commission with you in the form of cash back.
 
 Type the two words:
	</body>
</document>
