<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007879" url="http://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/shift-schedule.html" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="1" score="0.0009476411842674537" bingtitle="Free Employee Shift Schedule Template for Excel" webtitle="Free Employee Shift Schedule Template for Excel">
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>Add any number of rows depending on the number of employees. Add columns to create a ... Purchase Order Packing Slip Billing Statement Receipt Template Work Order Template Easy ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME EXCEL TEMPLATES WORD TEMPLATES CALCULATORS CALENDARS RESUMES ARTICLES NEXUS BLOG Home &gt; Calendars &amp; Schedules &gt;Shift Schedule 
Shift Schedule Template
 Free Employee Shift Schedule Spreadsheet for Microsoft®Excel® 
Download our free employee shift schedule spreadsheet to help organize work assignments. This template was designed for small businesses and is particularly useful for fast food restaurants, small stores, or departments where employees change stations throughout a work day. Also check out our work schedule template and free calendars .
 

Note: Our Annual Calendar also works pretty well as a shift schedule, especially if you want to create a schedule for many months in advance.
 
Shift Schedule Template
for Excel, OpenOffice,&amp;Google Docs View Screenshot Like This Template? Download Now Type: .XLS (Excel 2003+) 
Size: ~30KB Template Details Requirements 
Microsoft Excel®2002(XP) or Later

 License 
 Company Use 
(not for distribution or resale)

 Questions? 
 Contact Us&gt; 

 Get OpenOffice Version 
 Google Docs Version 

This template was designed to be easy to customize. Every business does thing a little different. Below are some of the things you can do with this shift schedule template:

 Organize work assignments for an entire week. Shade and merge cells to identify shifts, or use task codes to plan a rotating schedule for each work day. Add any number of rows depending on the number of employees. Add columns to create a 24-hour schedule. Customize the key with your own list of tasks. 

 &quot;No Installation, No Macros - Just a simple spreadsheet - An original creation by Dr. Jon Wittwer of Vertex42.com&quot; 
 
Rate and Review this Shift Schedule Template
 
To view and write reviews, click on the button below.
 Show Reviews 
 
Share Our Shift Schedule Spreadsheet

To link to our shift scheduling template, you may use the following URL:

http://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/shift-schedule.html
 
Like This Template?
 
Become a Fan
 Like us on Facebook +1 us on Google+ 
 Timesheets &amp;Payroll
 Timesheet Template Timesheet with Breaks Time Card Shift Schedule Vacation Accrual Paycheck Calculator Payroll Register Travel Expense Report Expense Reimbursement 
 Schedules&amp;Planners 
 Daily Planner Weekly Planner Monthly Planner Meal Planner Cleaning Schedule Baby Schedule Immunization Schedule Class Schedule Shift Schedule Weekly Schedule Work Schedule 
 Invoices 
 New! Invoice Assistant Free Invoice Template Service Invoice Sales Invoice Proforma Invoice Quote Template Purchase Order Packing Slip Billing Statement Receipt Template Work Order Template Easy Invoicing Spanish: Factura VERTEX42.com 
 ©2003-2012 Vertex42 LLC. All rights reserved. 
 Vertex42®is a registered trademark of Vertex42 LLC. Microsoft®and Microsoft Excel®and Microsoft Word®are registered trademarks of Microsoft Corporation. Vertex42.com is not associated with Microsoft. About/Contact Us . Excel Consulting . Support/FAQ . Sitemap . Privacy . Legal Stuff 

Free Shift Schedule Template for Excel
	</body>
</document>
