<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007278" url="http://www.helium.com/knowledge/49622-a-fast-food-observation" time="2012-07-13-00:14" support="1" score="0.009449294878039811" bingtitle="A fast food observation - Food &amp; Drink (Other) - Helium" webtitle="A fast food observation - Food&amp;Drink (Other) - Helium">
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>I grow nervous when I step into a fast food restaurant ... become an integral part of our everyday eating experience. ... Tips on decorating a cheese and cracker tray; Recipes ...</description>
	<body>
		How To Guides | Community 
 
 Where knowledge rules 
 Search Helium 
 Food&amp;Drink 
 Cooking Cuisine&amp;Food Dining&amp;Restaurants Drinks Recipes Food&amp;Drink (Other) 
 
 
 Home &gt; Food&amp;Drink &gt; Food&amp;Drink (Other) 
 
A fast food observation
 
 Top Article All 29 Articles 
 
 1 of 29 
by Jenn Reed 

 Created on : May 02, 2011   Last Updated : December 03, 2011
 
Fast food is a term used to describe food that is sold in restaurants or stores with preheated or precooked
 2 of 29 
by Rex Trulove 

 Created on : October 29, 2008
 
Fast food has a few intended consequences, such as being cheap yet filling, but usually a lot more unintended
 
 
 3 of 29 
by Sam Smart 

 Created on : June 18, 2009   Last Updated : February 03, 2010
 
What comes to your mind when you hear the term &quot;fast food&quot;? Probably hamburgers,
 4 of 29 
by Rachel Howells 

 Created on : April 23, 2011
 
Observing the decaying process of a fast food meal is an exercise in cognitive dissonance. It is passed
 5 of 29 
by Ted Onulak 

 Created on : March 30, 2009   Last Updated : March 31, 2009
 
Even if you really love fast food, everyone agrees that it&apos;s not that good for you, either in terms
 6 of 29 
by Pam Berglund 

 Created on : January 08, 2008   Last Updated : July 28, 2010
 
I come in from a hard day of work. My stomach is growling and I haven&apos;t eaten in almost 10 hours - so
 7 of 29 
by Lisa H Warren 

 Created on : April 30, 2007   Last Updated : May 20, 2007
 
&quot;Fast food&quot; doesn&apos;t have to mean &quot;the worst food you could eat&quot;. It is possible to stop by a fast-food
 8 of 29 
by Joyce D. Sinclair 

 Created on : July 01, 2009
 
During the 1940s and 1950s, fast food restaurants were the thing. It&apos;s innovation in the food industry
 9 of 29 
by Marcus Bentley Wise 

 Created on : January 05, 2010   Last Updated : January 06, 2010
 
I was just a young lad when my brother cam home on leave from the army. We lived in a small village
 10 of 29 
by Joan Inong 

 Created on : December 17, 2008
 
Fast food has always seemed too fast for me. This holds true whether the fast food comes from a national
 11 of 29 
by Das Govind 

 Created on : March 31, 2009   Last Updated : April 01, 2009
 
Fast food is the number one leading cause of obesity, heart disease and diabetes in first world countries
 12 of 29 
by Mark Feldt 

 Created on : June 29, 2010
 
Home cooking is usually my preference for a good meal but sometimes it is not always practical to have
 13 of 29 
by Melissa Miles McCarter 

 Created on : November 02, 2009   Last Updated : November 18, 2009
 
I am a fast foodist. I am ashamed to admit this elitist bent of mine. However, it is a fact. I am bigoted
 14 of 29 
by Michelle Harper Davies 

 Created on : February 02, 2008   Last Updated : September 05, 2011
 
Junk Food

It took all my strength to push open the heavy metal doors of the restaurant, but when I had
 15 of 29 
by M W 

 Created on : February 29, 2008   Last Updated : November 30, 2011
 
I grow nervous when I step into a fast food restaurant during bustling hours. The lines are long and
 16 of 29 
by Barry Williams 

 Created on : February 27, 2008
 
I like fast food. I like fast food because it is fast . I like fast food because it so full of tasty
 17 of 29 
by Catriana McClelland 

 Created on : January 19, 2008   Last Updated : May 03, 2011
 
I would just like to say a few things about fast-food drive-through etiquette.

Ten things you should
 18 of 29 
by Gordon Hamilton 

 Created on : June 12, 2007   Last Updated : January 01, 2010
 
As we all know, fast food has become a multi-national obsession in these past few decades. If one
 19 of 29 
by Jocy Bella 

 Created on : April 05, 2009   Last Updated : April 15, 2009
 
It&apos;s all a matter of convenience. The faster the food is prepared, the better. For me that happens way
 20 of 29 
by Janette Peel 

 Created on : May 09, 2009
 
Fast foods have become an integral part of our everyday eating experience. In our fast paced and hectic
 


 1 2 &gt; 

 
HIDE

 Print 
 
 Related Titles: 

 The pros and cons of fast food Why children are eating too much fast food Effects of fast food on your health How to resist the temptation of fast food How to choose healthy fast foods 
 
 On the home page Most popular titles 
 
 Fun facts and trivia about Eddie Murphy A look at the largest Listeria-related food recalls Prince Fielder wins 2012 home run derby What is the Libor scandal? Survey finds that 45% of executives think social media has a positive impact on the workplace How Obamacare will impact small businesses How robots could help find Amelia Earhart&apos;s plane Flash fiction: Dinner with the ex Ideas for hand-painted wine glasses The best way to clean fruits and vegetables How to find your own personal style Wedding cake options: Cupcake tower 
 
 Recipes: Eye of round roast Recipes: Fast and easy boneless chicken breasts Is it safe to eat raw eggs? Recipes: Easy dishes for college students How to safely remove coffee and tea stains from your teeth How to cook scallops The effects of beer consumption on your health Recipes: Easy meals with one pound of ground beef How to make Alfredo sauce from scratch Recipes: Japanese Ginger salad dressing Recipes: Deep fried chicken wings How to cook okra Recipes: Beef sirloin roast Recipes: Crockpot pulled pork sandwich Lime juice: Uses and benefits The best way to cook trout Tips for improving restaurant service Recipes: Irish soda bread What’s a sure-fire dish to bring to a potluck? How to cook parsnips Food ideas for the ultimate football tailgate party Which is better for you, whole wheat pasta or regular pasta? Easy Spanish dessert recipes Recipes: Slow cooker brisket Recipes: Homemade coleslaw dressing How to cook deer meat Cookware choices: Stainless steel vs.nonstick Tips for decorating your buffet table Recipes: Oven roasted brisket The difference between brandy and whisky The dangers of eating undercooked meat The different types of beans Recipes: How to make ham salad How to roast eggs for Passover How to serve brie The sourest candy in the world How to make simple onion gravy How to cook spaghetti How and why to blanch vegetables Recipes: Yakisoba How to make perfect roast potatoes Recipes: Using canned salmon How to make homemade tortilla chips Recipes: Sweet and sour sauce Does drinking mineral water have health benefits? Recipes: Vegetarian style stuffed peppers Drink recipes: Homemade Baileys irish cream Recipes: Easy mushroom gravy Recipes: Greek salad dressing Recipe: Rolled fondant How to order a martini at a cocktail bar Butter replacements for baking Recipes: Slow cooker mac and cheese Tips on roasting a whole filet mignon Energy drinks: Negative health effects Recipes: Baked pork chops A cheap punch for parties Guide to traditional German desserts and pastries Fund-raising bake sale ideas Recipes: Rum cake How much is a bushel Alcohol drinking: The pros and cons How to make your own brandy Big desserts: How to please a crowd Can drinking tea help you lose weight? Egg substitutes for cake recipes How to soften tough meat through cooking The best way to roast a leg of lamb Recipes: Crab stuffed tilapia Recipes: No cook fudge: Easy for children and adults Romantic dinner ideas for Valentine’s Day Product reviews: Nu-Wave Oven Pro How to stew apples Recipes: Mexican recipes for a dinner party How to make home made salami Recipes: Authentic Italian pasta tomato sauce What is an IPA ? How to make really crisp roast potatoes Vodka drinks that won’t give you a hangover Recipes: Shrimp salad sandwich Recipes: Amazing desserts Recipes: Sugar free cake How to cook ribs How to roast raw peanuts Recipes: Italian recipes for a dinner party Recipes: Soft and chewy oatmeal cookies Best grocery list for a gluten-free diet Recipes: Baked pineapple How to peel or skin a tomato easily How to cook great fluffy rice Recipes: Honey teriyaki sauce Recipes: Venison back strap Recipes: Lemon pound cake Recipes: How to make natto The pros and cons of fast food Authentic Spanish food menu ideas The history of the McDonald’s restaurant chain Cooking: How to cook black beans Foods to avoid eating after giving birth How to cook chickpeas Which French sauces go best with steak? Recipes: Quick&amp;easy chocolate fudge cake Tips for making the perfect cupcakes Almond milk vs. soy milk Tips for cooking with bamboo steamers Monosodium Glutamate (MSG): Effects on health Where to eat when you can’t decide what food you’re in the mood for Recipes: No bake desserts for all seasons Recipes: White chocolate and raspberry cheesecake Recipes: Healthy applesauce cake Which country’s food is the best? Why? Recipes: Chicken, Broccoli and Rice Casserole Knowing the difference between Merlot and Cabernet Sauvignon What is the nutritional value of lentils Styles of crust used by Domino’s Pizza Silicone bakeware: The hype and the truth How to serve wine properly Creative Mexican recipes for potluck parties The disadvantages of organic foods Creative cake decorating ideas Tips for removing coffee stains from your clothing Reasons why fast food restaurants are responsible for America’s obesity epidemic Drink reviews: Firefly Sweet Tea Vodka How long does it take to defrost a chicken? Recipes: Mexican birria Basic cocktails all bartenders should know Recipes: Boneless pork chop bbq How to cook salmon Popular spices and herbs used for cooking Microwave Ovens: Analyzing Consumer Reports February 2009 Best Buys The best spices for Mexican cooking Addiction to energy drinks Quick and easy potluck food ideas How to cook shark meat How to cut a cigar without a cutter Recipes: Rotisserie chicken Recipes: Salsa dip Recipes: Easy to make snickerdoodle cookies Product reviews: Ace of Spades champagne Recipes: Crock-pot pulled pork Product reviews: Slap Chop How long should wine breathe before serving? Some good non-alcoholic beers The nutritional value of red bell pepper Is the cost of fast food more than a financial cost Recipes: Rice Krispie Treats How to cook cabbage Recipes: Ham and bean soup Recipes: German beef goulash Recipes: Fried chicken fingers Recipes: Wine beef pot roast Product reviews: Tramontina stainless steel cookware set Who invented the popsicle? Office party potluck ideas How to make soup less salty Best kitchen gadgets Knowing the difference between Port&amp;Sherry Tips for making the perfect scones How to make a homemade sports drink Why steamed vegetables are the healthiest Recipes: Low fat banana cake Recipes: Fruit punch for adults The nutritional value of hard boiled eggs Store reviews: ALDI food store Home made drink recipes for health Recipes: Low-fat blueberry muffins Caribbean food menu ideas Recipes: Great recipes for weight watchers Recipes: Fragrant Fish Fillets in foil Polenta Recipes: How to make corned beef Recipes: Oatmeal bars using cherry pie filling Do you prefer fast food or home cooking? Common spices and their uses How to roast a rabbit The nutritional benefits of the prickly pear Best cooking method for corned beef and cabbage Drink recipes: Jagertee How yeast makes bread rise The best ways to prepare and cook mushrooms Recipes: Stuffed cabbage rolls Recipes: Pan-fried salmon fillet Do-it-yourself healthy trail mix for kids How to throw a Greek dinner party How to de-scale your kettle and coffee maker Recipes: Crockpot pork chops How to make vegetable chips Recipes: Chicken on a stick How to cook mussels Spanish recipes for a dinner party Drink recipes: Lemoncello Guide to different cuts of meat for pork Recipes: Stinging nettle recipes Recipes: Homemade barbeque sauce How long does it take to defrost a turkey? How to cook a ham Recipes: Old-fashioned English plum pudding How to serve foie gras Recipes: Bacon and water chestnut wraps Does mayonnaise need to be refrigerated after opening or is it okay to keep it in the cupboard? Ten best cracker toppings The history of hummus The perfect custard: Tips and techniques Carving decorative vegetables How to order a steak like an expert How to cook chitterlings Recipes: Homemade candy Alternative uses for pancake mix Recipes: Buckeye candy Risks of reheating cooked rice Using margarine instead of butter when making shortbread How to make the perfect meringue How to cook beans to prevent gas How to freeze pie crusts The history of matzo ball soup Menu ideas: Pork chops An introduction to Cointreau How to arrange an antipasto tray The best cheap red wine for cooking A look at value for money for KFC family packs Coca Cola: Pros and cons How long does it take to fry a turkey? How to cook chicken livers Recipes: Chocolate chip cookies An overview of standing rib roast cooking times Recipes: Quick and easy crockpot recipes The pros and cons of bottled water The pros and cons of processed foods Dinner parties with a touch of mystery, variety and fun The differences between authentic Mexican food and Tex-Mex food How to freeze fresh pumpkin Drink recipes: Macua Recipes: Simple steam cake Best store-bought pie crust The best romantic restaurants in Knoxville, TN Recipes: Fried gator tail Tips for cutting onions without tears What is your favorite snack food and why? Recipes: Low fat tamales The difference between cod and scrod Drink recipes: Buck’s fizz Product Review: Cafe Creme Cigars How to make homemade chicken fajita seasoning Great gift ideas for the hostess Recipes: Snow Queen with raspberries What are the world’s most expensive brands of beer? Recipes: Seafood salad Recipes: Individual salmon en croute The characteristics of mangoes The tradition of a New Year’s breakfast Menu ideas: Pork loin Drink recipes: Jungle juice Recipes: Scottish clootie dumpling How to ripen a pomegranate Recipes: Green beans with bacon Strange facts about cupcakes The best way to clean a coffee maker How to make maids of honor tarts How to keep food cool without the use of a fridge Tips on decorating a cheese and cracker tray Recipes: No-bake holiday desserts and treats The best way to store divinity candy The best gift to bring to a dinner party Recipes: Chicken fettuccine alfredo Recipes: Florentine cookies How to make your own coffee creamer What to drink when eating sushi How to rehydrate chiles How to decorate store-bought cookies to save money Toaster oven recipes Recipes: Cornish game hens The best games at Dave and Buster’s The best way to beat egg whites An overview on importing coffee into the United States Everything you always wanted to know about Greek raki The basics of wine knowledge needed by restaurant server Recipes: Cinnamon monkey bread Recipes: Lentil soup with cumin Recipes: Fried chicken drumettes The best brands of cider Cooking substitutes for brandy How to make a casserole: A simple scientific formula Tips for making the perfect muffins Recipes: Oyster dressing How to make traditional Scottish soda scones Tips for making the perfect pound cakes How to prepare an octopus for cooking Recipes: Cooking for two Which French sauces go best with fish? Recipes: Bacalao How to thicken pasta sauce Where to find free printable recipe cards Product reviews: Sabatier knives Recipes: Smoked Lamb Drink recipes: Appletini or apple martini Recipes: Struffoli Recipes: Beer jelly How to arrange a vegetable tray Maple syrup: Storage, use and purchase How to peel and eat a pomegranate 
 
 Helium Debate 

 Cast your vote! 

 Bottled water or regular water? 

 Bottled or Regular 

Click for your side.
 
 Featured Partner 

 Concepts4Charity Inc. 

Concepts4Charity has partnered with Helium, giving you the chance to write for a cause.


Browse Concepts4Charity featured titles, pick an issue and write!


You can also donate your article earnings.


Share what you know, lea... more 
 
 
CONNECT WITH US
 Follow us
on Twitter Like us on
Facebook Read
our blog 
Write and get published
Share with other writers
Polish your freelancing skills
 Join our active writing community 
Quality articles from proven freelancers
Exclusive rights, fast turnaround
Brand engagement, business blogging -- our writers do it all
 Get custom content today! 
INFORMATION

 About Us Team Helium User Tools User Agreement Privacy Policy DMCA 
 

Copyright©2002-2012 Helium, Inc. All rights reserved.
Helium.com: A Service of RR Donnelley
 Helium, Inc. 200 Brickstone Square Andover , MA 01810 USA #
	</body>
</document>
