<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007032" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080702185800AAHvajZ" time="2012-07-13-00:01" support="28" score="0.10909230975392527" bingtitle="What are the POSITIONS in fast food resturants like taco bell ..." webtitle="What are the POSITIONS in fast food resturants like taco bell, burger king ect? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>Grill is making the food for front counter and drive through. Front counter is when you take orders and put them together inside, or take orders and pass them ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Carlos Member since: June 14, 2008 Total points: 86 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What are the POSITIONS in fast food resturants like taco bell, burger king ect?

 4 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 what is ezer cashier or grill 
 4 years ago 
 by Duckie Member since: January 27, 2008 Total points: 2,264 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 At Mcdonalds there are service and grill workers- and some people who have been cross-trained know both. Positions are- Service: Cashier, Drive thru Cashier, Drive thru Presenter, Runner for Counter and a Runner for Drive Thru, a Fry or Hashbrown Person. For Grill: Meats person, Initiator, Assembler(also known as table worker). As for which is easier grill or service- they both have their ups and downs. Some days it is easier to work service, some days grill. You have to do more physical work in grill, but you have to deal with customers up front- they even out:) Also there are managers of varying degrees 
Source(s):
 Work at Mcdonalds;) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: ty 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by &amp;whoknow... Member since: June 28, 2008 Total points: 400 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well I work at McDonalds, and there are 2 main positions, counter and grill. They might be a little different at taco bell or burger king, but I&apos;m sure it&apos;s the same idea.

Grill is making the food for front counter and drive through.

Front counter is when you take orders and put them together inside, or take orders and pass them out to drive thru.

And there are also the managers, who are assigned to a certain position, like production or keeping track of the workers and when they need breaks.

Hope this helped! :) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Dustin C Member since: July 02, 2008 Total points: 104 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 taco bell- drive thru, front counter, and two positions on the line which is the steamer which deals with the hot products on food ex. (mt, bn, rice) and the stuffer who puts on the cold products ex. (let, chz, tom.) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by amm Member since: June 04, 2008 Total points: 246 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Cashiers, Cooks, Assistant and General Managers, District Managers, Etc. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 What kind of positions are available for fast food services? What positions would fast food restaurants usually give a 15… When to receive notice completing a Taco bell position? Burger King Assistant Manager Position ? What positions do fast food joints offer? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
