<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007579" url="http://www.enquirer.com/editions/2002/01/17/spt_sweet_revenge.html" time="2012-07-13-00:33" support="1" score="0.0017036061422263788" bingtitle="Sweet revenge: billionaire Mavericks owner dishes ice cream" webtitle="Sweet revenge: billionaire Mavericks owner dishes ice cream">
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>... January 17, 2002. Sweet revenge: billionaire Mavericks owner dishes ice cream ... behind a Dairy Queen counter, making good on a promise to manage the fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		NKY.COM  |  ENQUIRER  |  CIN WEEKLY  |  Classifieds  |  Cars  |  Homes  |  Jobs  |  Help 

 
 Currently: 
 80°F Mostly Sunny Weather | Traffic 
 
 

 HOME 
 NEWS 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 SPORTS 
 REDS 
 BENGALS 
 LOCAL GUIDE 
 MULTIMEDIA 
 ARCHIVES 
 SEARCH 
 
 

   
 
  TODAY&apos;S ENQUIRER  
  Front Page  
  Local News  
  Sports  
  Business  
  Editorials  
  Tempo  
  Home Style  
  Travel  
  Health  
  Technology  
  Weather  
  Back Issues  
  Search  
  Subscribe  
 
 


 
  SPORTS  
  Bearcats  
  Bengals  
  High School  
  Reds  
  Xavier  
 
 


 
  VIEWPOINTS  
  Jim Borgman  
  Columnists  
  Readers&apos; views  
 
 


 
  ENTERTAINMENT  
  Movies  
  Dining  
  Horoscopes  
  Lottery Results  
  Local Events  
  Video Games  
 
 


 
  CINCINNATI.COM  
  Giveaways  
  Maps/Directions  
  Send an E-Postcard  
  Coupons  
  Visitor&apos;s Guide  
  Web Directory  
 
 


 
  CLASSIFIEDS  
  Jobs  
  Cars  
  Homes  
  Obituaries  
  General  
  Place an ad  
 
 


 
  HELP  
  Feedback  
  Subscribe  
  Search  
  Newsroom Directory  
 
 
 
 

   

 
 Thursday, January 17, 2002 
 Sweet revenge: billionaire Mavericks owner dishes ice cream 
 
 By JAIME ARON 
 AP Sports Writer 

 
 Dallas Mavericks owner Mark Cuban serves an ice cream cone at a Dairy Queen in Coppell, Texas. 
(AP photo)
| ZOOM | 
     COPPELL, Texas Trying desperately to perfect the curly tip on a soft-serve cone, Mark Cuban licked the remains of another failed effort from his fingertips and handed the messy treat to an excited 3-year-old boy.
    One lick later, the kid dropped it.
    That was about the only thing that went wrong Wednesday when the billionaire owner of the Dallas Mavericks worked two hours behind a Dairy Queen counter, making good on a promise to manage the fast-food restaurant.
    The company&apos;s offer came in response to Cuban&apos;s assertion that he wouldn&apos;t hire Ed Rush, the NBA&apos;s head of officiating,to manage a Dairy Queen.
    The league fined Cuban $500,000 for the comment, a record for an individual. For about $650,000, Cuban could&apos;ve bought a startup DQ franchise.
    So, after doing the job himself, does he still think Rush couldn&apos;t do it?
    It depends on how he treats the customers. That&apos;s the hard part,Cuban said.
    Part of the point I was trying to make with the NBA is that you have to understand your customers and learn to get better as a business.
    Cuban, fined more than $1 million by the NBA in the two years since he bought the team, praised his boss-for-a-day, store owner Parrish Chapman, and took another shot at the league.
    I&apos;d love to send Parrish up to the NBA to have him give them a lesson in exactly how to communicate,Cuban said.When anybody needed to interact with Parrish, he was right there to answer the questions. That&apos;s the way you run a business. If Parrish just went up there and just took a look, we&apos;d be a lot better off.
    Cuban&apos;s presence created a carnival atmosphere at the suburban Dairy Queen and drew more than 1,000 people, many waiting close to an hour to place their order. The crush was so big the restaurant ran out of ice.
    It was worth the wait,Tony Newpower said.It&apos;s not often you see a billionaire serving burgers.
    Wearing a navy denim shirt and a manager&apos;s name tag, and carrying a pencil in his right shirt pocket, Cuban actually spent more time signing autographs than taking orders.
    But he did take his temporary job seriously. He arrived at 6 a.m., after flying home from a Mavericks game in Atlanta, and began training by 6:30.
    Kim Skeffington, a regional field consultant whose duties include working with new managers, spent about two hours teaching him the finer points of curling soft serves and mixing a frozen dessert.
    James Kelly, who waited about two hours to be first in line, ordered a strawberry version of the dessertwhich Skeffington madethen had Cuban sign a novelty $1 million bill.
    Cuban&apos;s first cone for a customer looked squished on top.
    Be patient with me, please. I&apos;m new at this,he said with a wink and a smile.It might not be pretty, but it works.
    Lured by aMark Cuban Here Todaysign, customers were treated to inflatable play areas for children, portable basketball hoops for kids and adults, and more than a dozen TV and radio stations broadcasting live. One station even sent its helicopter.
    The line snaked around the building and up the street, with cars filling several vacant fields. Order was maintained even though only a few customers were allowed in at a time. It probably helped that the store gave away free ice cream bars.
    Another beneficiary was the Children&apos;s Miracle Network, a charity that received a lump sum of $5,000, plus hundreds more through donation boxes on the counter.
     
 Sports Stories 

 Rested Davis lifts Miami 
 Florida wins 11th straight in SEC 
 Just another day in the ACC: No. 1 vs. No. 3 
 College football notebook 
 Fox Sports Net cancels &apos;National Sports Report&apos; 
 Pylypuik joins Cyclones as new president/COO 
 Sweet revenge: billionaire Mavericks owner dishes ice cream
 Blue Jackets blank Rangers 
 Louisville officials discuss possible NBA team 
 Nets blitz Wizards 
 Coming up this week 
 

 Stokes keeps UC on a roll 
 UC notebook 
 XU aims to prove A-10 power 
 DE Strahan named best on defense 
 Favre, Warner need no buildup 
 SULLIVAN: Reese, Reds part ways for good 
 Boone to stay with Mariners 
 Surprising SCPA, 13-1, performing on court 
 Villa reaches All &apos;A&apos; region semis 
 Ohio boys basketball scores 
 Ohio girls basketball scores 
 Kentucky boys basketball scores 
 Kentucky girls basketball scores 
 Indiana boys basketball scores 
 Indiana girls basketball scores 

 
   
 
 
 

 
 Updated Every 30 Minutes 
 
 
 SPORTS NEWS 
 
 
  
 49ers Look to Relocate New Stadium 
  
 Paterno Won&apos;t Coach Penn St.-Temple Game 
  
 San Francisco 2016 Games Bid in Jeopardy 
  
 NCAA: Athletes Graduating at Higher Rate 
  
 Mauresmo Advances at WTA Championships 
  
 Randhawa Takes Lead at HSBC Champions 
  
 Bob Knight Approaches Winning Milestone 
  
 Bears-Giants a Key Game Despite Injuries 
  
 Spurrier Shadow Looms Large in Florida 
  
 A&apos;s, Cisco Reach Deal to Build Ballpark 
 
 
 

 
 

 
 Search our site by keyword:    
 Search also: News | Jobs | Homes | Cars | Classifieds | Obits | Coupons | Events | Dining 
 Movies/DVDs | Video Games | Hotels | Golf | Visitor&apos;s Guide | Maps/Directions | Yellow Pages 
 
 

   CINCINNATI.COM  |  NKY.COM  |  ENQUIRER  |  CIN WEEKLY  |  Classifieds  |  Cars  |  Homes  |  Jobs  |  Help 


 
 Search | Questions/help | News tips | Letters to the editors | Subscribe 
 Newspaper advertising | Web advertising | Place a classified | Circulation 

 Copyright 1995-2007. The Cincinnati Enquirer , a Gannett Co. Inc. newspaper.
Use of this site signifies agreement to terms of service updated 12/19/2002.
	</body>
</document>
