<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007795" url="http://www.petairlimo.com/Untitled_5.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:45" support="2" score="0.0011925536222907086" bingtitle="petairlimo pet transport air and ground" webtitle="petairlimo pet transport air and ground">
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>A work order includes name, city and phone number of shipper and receiver. ... do we meet for the drop off or pick ... fast food restaurant, truck stop or gas station.</description>
	<body>
		PETAIRLIMO or PAL

 

June run air only



June 16th up east the coast to North Louisiana

 

June 18th North Missouri

 

June 19th Mi

 

June 21th El Paso, Tx

 

June 18thth Dallas East Coast

 

[url]www.petairlimo.com[/url]

Captain Bill - 985-966-3776 or 985-966-2061
U.S.D.A. Dog Transport # 72-T-0005
D.O.T # 2151965 Drug Tested-01/2012
Commercial Pilot and Yacht Captain


Real climate controlled Ford LXI High Top Limo Van fully insulated with back up 
generator.
Your hound is safe and comfortable. Husband and Wife Team. Competitive Pricing!

 

 PAL has no set 
schedule. We base our trips on the locations, times, dates and demands of our 
clients. In so much as we will only transport a minimal number of pets during 
any given trip, we ask that you give us as much advance notice so that we can 
work our schedule around yours. 

 

  provides 
24-hour and   With PAL every effort is made to arrive at a 
convenient time, schedules may dictate arrival at any hour day or night. 
Customers are provided with a tentative time for pickups and delivery but these 
times may change due to situations beyond our control. If there should be any 
significant change (12 hours or more) you will be called and updated with the 
revised estimated time of arrival. 
 
 You will be provided with 
a cellular number that we can be reached during transport however we ask that 
calls to us during transit be kept to a minimum. Updates on your pet will be 
given daily via email or telephone. We will also notify you within a few hours 
of reaching your home and throughout the trip should any changes occur. 

 
 
 How do I book a shipment ? 

To book a transport a work order must be completed and to guarantee the
transport for a flight $400.00 deposit and for ground $300.00 deposit must be provided. A work order includes name,
city and phone number of shipper and receiver. Number of dog(s), size,
weight, breed and color. Final pricing will be determined based on distance of
transport, size of dog and location of pick up and drop off. Multiple dog
discounts do apply. Call for pricing.

 What does it 
cost to ship a dog ? 

To determine shipping costs you must call Billy and he will provide you with a
quote. All quotes are flat rates with no additional fees involved unless a 
request to land at a international airport. We have not
raised our rates for two years but our cost of doing business, fuel and
expenses has gone up. In order to provide you with competitive rates all
quotes are based off interstate too interstate. Door to Door is more expensive
and we have found over the years that most people would prefer to save the
money and drive a few miles to meet us at an interstate exit closest to their
house for our ground runs. We have also found that door to door is a hassle for people that work
for a living. Most people are not home during the day and find it easier to meet
near their place of work of close to the interstate or major 4 lane highway for 
ground 

 transport for air we provide drop-off 
at your locale general airport .

 Do you coordinate 
around our work, vacation and holiday schedule for
transports ? 

We are like UPS or FED EX and it is very difficult to work around your
work schedule for pick up and deliveries. You will have to provide a backup plan
if you are unavailable during a pick up or drop off. We have tried to work
around work schedules, vacations and holiday plans in the past but have found
it impossible to coordinate. Have a friend or relative on standby in the event
that you cannot make the appointment.

 Where do we 
meet for the drop off or pick up and do you provide door to door?

 Pick up and drop 
offs are usually arranged at interstate exits or off of a major
4 lane highway closest to your house or business. Usually the meeting place is a
fast food restaurant, truck stop or gas station. This allows us to keep our 
rates
competitive so that you save money. Remember our rates have not gone up in
two years. Diesel has gone up $1.00 in the last year. This also cuts down on the
time your dog spends in our van. Most people are more concerned about how
long will it take to transport the dog than door to door. We pride ourselves on
quick turnaround on deliveries. If we went door to door on every pick up and
delivery then that process would add one day to every three days we are on
the road. Our guarantee is that we will meet you at a location closer than your
local airport thus saving you time and money . We can provide door to door for
the disabled, shut ins or emergency situations or private transports if
requested. Most of our customers volunteer to meet us to help us out anyway.

We learned that communication is very important and we normally call or text
numerous times to update the route and schedule. We also update our
schedule on our web site daily. You will find that we 
are easy to get in
touch with while on the road.

NOTE: We pride our self of being on time. Delivery and Pick Up times are not
guaranteed until the day before the appointment. Weather, Highway
Construction, Accidents and other delays occur and may alter a schedule. Dog
Transport is not an exact science . 
We do provide a rough 10 or so day schedule
but normally it changes due to above conditions. During winter months all bets
are off and safety concerns are our top priority.

 Why should you use 
ground shipping?

 As a breeder for 25 years we had used airline shipping but became
disenchanted with dealing with heat restrictions, cold restrictions, 
cancellations
and discrimination. In 2002 we began using ground shipping and found it to be
a much easier less traumatic on the pet and less hassle. For us ground shipping
is a much better alternative. In some situations airline shipping may be your
best option. Our position has always been that ground shipping is an alternative
to airline shipping.

 Are you a 
coast to coast transporter?

 Yes we do Coast to Coast 
at this time

 Do I need a crate or 
do you provide crates ? 

One of the advantages to ground shipping is that you do not need to buy a
crate. Crates now cost from $30 - $100. We provide the crates in our van.
Note: You do not receive a crate when the delivery is made. Our crates are of
the highest quality and are disinfected after each use.

 If my puppy 
of dog dies in transport will you cover the damages ? 

We offer an insurance plan for your puppy or dog while in transport. Please see
 Pet Insurance!
 PAL provides up to $1200.00 insurance 
policy free of charge with a health certificate.
Note: We have never had a puppy or dog die while in our transport. Although it
is possible death may occur but highly unlikely. We take the utmost care for
your dog. We treat your animal as if it was our own! We have 6 years of injury
and accident free experience shipping dogs to back up our disclaimer.

 How long does it 
take to transport my dog ? 

 It depends on 
the route. We start our route in the New Orleans area. The
national average for a transport, according to the U.S.D.A., is 3.5 days. Our
goal is to keep your pup or dog in our care as minimal as possible. Our average
transport takes 1 to 5 days. Some transports may take up to 5.5 days and in
very rare cased 7 days for east coast to west runs. All parties involved will be informed prior to shipping
arrangements as to the approximate length of shipping time before any final
agreement is made. Normally we will not take on a job if we know in advance it
will take more that 7 days while other companies will.

 Health Certificate 
and Rabies Tags ? 

 While a health 
certificate does not guarantee that an animal is 100% healthy or
free from infectious diseases, it does provide some benefits for not only the
shipper but also the receiver of the pet. A licensed veterinarian will not issue 
a
health certificate on an animal that is sick or unhealthy or has been used for
fighting. This protects the buyer from getting stuck with a sick pet. It also
protects the shipper from boarding a pet that may infect other pets in the van 
or aircraft.
A health certificate also provides clues as to why and when a puppy may have
contracted a disease. And lastly health certificates are required for ground
shippers by State regulations if a pet is shipped across states lines.

 Do you board dogs at 
your facility ? 

 We do not board dogs at our Facility. 

 TERMS AND CONDITIONS
	</body>
</document>
