<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007646" url="http://my.hsj.org/Schools/Newspaper/tabid/100/view/frontpage/articleid/508882/newspaperid/4202/Obesity_epidemic_sees_no_end_in_sight.aspx" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="2" score="0.0022161811528804347" bingtitle="Hi-Lights - Plymouth High School - Obesity epidemic sees no end in ..." webtitle="Hi-Lights - Plymouth High School - Obesity epidemic sees no end in sight">
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Have we done enough to reverse the numbers? Studies ... of picking up a burger or a pizza from a fast food restaurant. ... Obesity epidemic sees no end in sight</description>
	<body>
		Member Login 
 
 Search All News Sites This News Site 
 Show freshest results first Hi-Lights Plymouth High School Plymouth, WI Issue Date: Thursday, April 26, 2012 Issue: Volume 78 Issue 6 Last Update: Thursday, April 26, 2012 
 At-a-glance Front Page News Sports Features Opinion Entertainment 
 
 

 
 
 Calendar Contact Us 
 
 
 {1} ##LOC[OK]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]## 
 
 
 
 

 
 At-a-glance 
 Embed Article Print Article Share Article Short URL for Sharing 
 [ArticleImageHyperLink] Obesity epidemic sees no end in sight Monday, March 12, 2012 By Maggie Paese Advertising Everyone knows of its dangers and why it is happening, but are we taking it seriously? Have we done enough to reverse the numbers?
Studies show that we have not: one in three kids in the United States is affected by the epidemic. The cause is simple; these days, kids spend too much time on the computer and in front of the TV and not enough playing outside. Junk food tastes better than fruit, and McDonalds is an easy, inexpensive and enjoyable meal for busy people. Habits like these can be hard to break and generally carry through into adulthood.
Of course, the government has been taking action to stop the increasing numbers. With her Let’s Move! Campaign, first lady Michelle Obama has helped promote healthy foods and physical activity among children by encouraging parents, schools and kids to work together and prevent obesity. The NFL has launched the Play 60 movement to promote daily exercise that kids will enjoy. The U.S. Department of Agriculture has recently updated nutrition standards in schools to ensure that kids are getting healthy meals as well.
This shows that the country is aware of the dangers of the epidemic and is working to fix it. However, government programs cannot be the only solution. People hear about these campaigns but may not be affected by them. These are likely not going to be enough to change the habits of citizens throughout the country.
Instead, change needs to come from the individuals in this country. It is entirely a personal decision to eat a healthy, home cooked meal instead of picking up a burger or a pizza from a fast food restaurant. No one else will actually dictate when one takes time to exercise. People need the motivation and the desire to keep themselves healthy.
It is still important for the government to be taking action in this situation and keeping the public aware of the rising obesity problem, but this is not enough. There is still too much fast food and junk food being consumed on a regular basis. There are too many video games, social networking sites and TV shows that are keeping people on the couch instead of outside or at the gym.
Unless we find a way to raise motivation and inspire U.S. citizens to truly change their eating and exercising habits, the obesity epidemic may not reverse any time soon. People do not want to change things in their life that are easy, enjoyable and affordable to things that are more difficult, less enjoyable and more expensive. To bring about this change, they must understand that these changes are crucial and will have a lasting impact on their own lives.
 

 Back to the articles list 
 {1} ##LOC[OK]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]## 
 

 
 

 
 0
 COMMENTS - add your comment below ADD YOUR COMMENT 
 Name Email Comments, recommendations or suggestions. Submit 
 
 
 
 Staff View 
 Show 
Tyler Woelfel
Webmaster
 Email Me 
 Online Archives 
 Show There are currently 11 editions on-line. Click on edition name to view articles.


 Mon, Mar 12, 2012 Volume 78 Issue 5 Fri, Jan 27, 2012 Volume 78 Issue 4 Fri, Dec 23, 2011 Volume 78 Issue 3 Tue, Nov 29, 2011 Volume 78 Issue 2 Wed, Oct 26, 2011 Volume 78 Issue 1 Mon, Jun 06, 2011 Volume 77 Issue 7 Tue, Apr 19, 2011 Volume 77 Issue 6 Wed, Mar 16, 2011 Volume 77, Issue 5 Tue, Feb 01, 2011 Volume 77, Issue 4 Wed, Dec 22, 2010 Volume 77, Issue 3 Wed, Dec 01, 2010 Volume 77, Issue 2 
 
 
 
 Live Conditions from Sheboygan, WI - USA 
 Clear Temperature: 80.7°F Wind Speed: 11 mph S Gusts: 16 mph SSE Rain Today: 0&quot; 
 
 
 Advertising 
 
 
 All school newspaper content is copyrighted by individual schools and protected by copyright law. Participating schools provide all content on this site and agree to the publication of that content. Please read our privacy policy . 
 Home 
 Host Your Media With Us 
 About us 
 Contact us
 High School Journalism Wire Service Partnerships Reynolds Institute 
 Journalism links 
 Student Scholarships Test Your Skills News Literacy
 Journalism Schools Student Journalists&apos; Rights Everyday Ethics Great Links 
 Browse Student Media 
 High Schools Middle and Elementary Schools 
 
 
 Social media Join our community on Facebook or follow or tweets on Twitter and get news that matters to you.
 
 Money for surfing Got News?
Get Clicks! 

Find out how my.hsj.org schools
can earn cash in our monthly
visitors contest. Created by The American Society
of News Editors 
 
 Leading America&apos;s
Newsrooms 
 Funded by
	</body>
</document>
