<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007723" url="http://www.dexknows.com/business_profiles/fortune_cookie_chinese_fast_food_restaurant-l807287977" time="2012-07-13-00:40" support="9" score="0.018941238122048" bingtitle="Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant | Labelle, FL 33935 ..." webtitle="Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant | Labelle, FL 33935 | DexKnows.com">
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001358" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>Your email was successfully sent to Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant! ... My Account | Advertise | Help | About Us | Pay Bill | Contact Us | ...</description>
	<body>
		X 
 Log in 
Don&apos;t have an account? Sign Up 
 
Select account:
 Or 
Log in to your DexKnows account:
 Remember Me Forgot Password? 
 X 
 
 In order to save your &quot;Favorite&quot; businesses, please sign up or log in. 
 
Thank you, your review will be posted shortly Sign up or log in to edit, delete and share your reviews. 
 Sign Up 
Already have an account? Log In 
 
Select account:
 Or 
Create a DexKnows account:
 30 characters or less At least 6 characters Optional Enter the words below: Enter the numbers you hear: Yes, I want to find out about great deals, local recommendations and more! I agree to terms of use and privacy policy 30 characters or less Optional At least 6 characters Yes, I want to find out about great deals, local recommendations and more! I agree to terms of use and privacy policy 
 X 
 Activation Link 
Please check your email for an activation link from Dex Customer Service. If you do not receive the email within an hour, check your spam folder.
 
 X 
 Forgot Password 
Please enter your email address so that we can send you an email with a link to change your password..
 
 X 
 Password 
Please enter your new password
 
Email Address: 
 At least 6 characters 
 X 
 Link Accounts 
Welcome !
 
Do you currently have an account with Dexknows?

Should we link this account to the one you just created?
 
Yes link my accounts:
 Forgot Password? Or 
Please provide this additional information to register
 Will be displayed next to your reviews. Optional Yes, I want to find out about great deals, local recommendations and more! I agree to terms of use and privacy policy 
 X 
 
Please share the issue you encountered with our search
 I am a(n): 
 Advertiser Business Owner (non advertiser) Consumer Employee 
 
Issue(s):
 Please check at least one issue checkbox. 
 Wrong phone number Wrong address Invalid URL Duplicate listing Business doesn&apos;t exist 

 Not what I meant by my search Expected more popular results Wrong category Too far away Incorrect business details 
 Comments: 
 Find a Business Find a Person Get Local with Mobile Advertise 

 Log In Sign Up 
 What? (Category or Business Name) Where? (City, State) 
 
 
 Business Overview 
 
 Reviews (1) 
 
 Map 
 Add to Favorites 
 
Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant
 http://www.dexknows.com/business_profiles/fortune_cookie_chinese_fast_food_restaurant-l807287977/ (863) 675-0008 505 W Hickpochee Ave , Labelle , FL 33935 26.7616 -81.4466 
 Send to Phone 
 Write a Review 
Reviews
 by
Barbara T.
-
 08/26/2010 
 
 Good food at a reasonable price - plenty of it - good variety. Staff is friendly&amp;efficient - Read Full Review on Yelp.com. 
 See All Reviews 
Nearby Restaurants
 Log Cabin Bar-B-Que (863) 675-3418 - 480 W Hickpochee Ave, LaBelle, FL Victoria&apos;s Restaurant (863) 675-1028 - 67 N Bridge St, LaBelle, FL Flora&amp;Ella&apos;s Restaurant (863) 675-2891 - 550 Hwy 80 West, LaBelle, FL Popeyes Famous Fried Chicken (863) 674-1469 - 576 W Hickpochee Ave, Labelle, FL Taqueria San Julian (863) 612-9235 - 1100 State Road 29, Labelle, FL Harry The Pizza Man (863) 675-8787 - 111 W Hickpochee Ave, Labelle, FL Beef &apos;O&apos; Brady&apos;s (863) 612-9818 - 21 N Lee St, Labelle, FL Rodeo Grill (863) 675-7006 - 870 W Hickpochee Ave Ste 800, Labelle, FL Jones EZ Foods Inc (863) 675-6262 - 415 S Main St, Labelle, FL 
Details
 This Business Can Be Found In Labelle, FL&gt;Restaurants : Chinese 
The information, assurances and other representations on this page (collectively the &quot;information&quot;) have been provided by the advertiser and have not been verified by Dex. The advertiser is solely responsible for the accuracy and truthfulness of all such information including without limitation information provided concerning any certifications, specialties, licenses or the like and any warranties, pricing and/or discounts. You should contact the advertiser to verify the information contained in this advertisement before relying on it. Dex expressly disclaims any and all liability in connection with the information contained in this advertisement and any use thereof or reliance thereon.

Additional data provided by Localeze.
 See All Reviews 
Reviews
 reviews (0) reviews (1) Write A Review 
 X 
 
Rate&amp;Review This Business on 
 Your Rating Click stars to rate Review Title Choose Display Name What&apos;s this This will be displayed next to your review. Your Email Address Enter the words below: Enter the numbers you hear: Your Review Write your review here...·Tell a story. What were you looking for?·Be specific. What did you purchase?·How was your service /product? Offer suggestions.·What should I know before I use this business? By posting a review, you agree to the DexKnows.com®Ratings&amp;Reviews Policies . 
 View Large Map | Directions | Street View 
 
 
Send To Phone
 
Sending... 

 Your text message was successfully sent! 
 


 To opt out at any time, text STOP to 339669. 
 To receive more information, text HELP to 339669. Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant 505 W Hickpochee Ave
Labelle, FL 33935 (863) 675-0008 
 DexKnows©SMS: To opt out at any time, text STOP to 339669. To receive more information, text HELP to 339669. 

 Not all handset models are supported. Message and Data rates may apply. 

 Supported Carriers: AT&amp;T, Boost Mobile, Cellcom, Cellular South, Dobson / Cellular One, Nextel, nTelos, Sprint, Suncom, T-Mobile, U.S. Cellular, Verizon Wireless, Virgin Mobile 

  I agree to the Terms and Conditions. 

 

 
 
 
Contact Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant
 
Your Name
 

Your Email Address
 

Your Message
 
 Enter the words below: Enter the numbers you hear: Your email was successfully sent to Fortune Cookie Chinese Fast Food Restaurant! 
 
 Close 
 Advertiser Login | Advertise | Help | About Us | Pay Bill | Contact Us | Free Tools | Dex Commercials | Recycle | Select Your Dex | National |
 Telco | Yellow Pages | White Pages | Local Business Directory | DexKnows Weddings | DexKnows Home Improvement | Marketing Matters ©Dex 2012 All Rights Reserved. Privacy Policy and Terms of Use
	</body>
</document>
