<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007576" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20120129051313AAOSEDk" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.002206679579941975" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - What&apos;s a good example and bad example of ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Whats a good example and bad example of customer services youve given/received?">
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>Bad customer service, this lady at a fast food restaurant didnt charge my order correctly and ... Administrative and Office Support; Financial Services; Food ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Other - Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Resolved Question 
 Matt Member since: August 31, 2007 Total points: 29 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What&apos;s a good example and bad example of customer services you&apos;ve given/received?
 I have an interview for a job as a catering assistant tomorrow, which will mainly include serving snacks over the counter to customers and a little bit of cooking.
This question always trips me up because I can&apos;t think of anything that would stand out! I am currently a volunteer in a charity shop, so deal with customers there.
Thanks for any help! 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 by MyHandsA... Member since: August 22, 2006 Total points: 31,854 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 good-being helpful/asking questions
bad-ignoring the customer or being disagreeable with them 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 67% 2 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What&apos;s a good exampl… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Erik Paul Member since: October 18, 2011 Total points: 842 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Good example is a customer ordered a package to arrive at our warehouse&amp;it was estimated to be late since vendor couldn&apos;t fill order. Customer was upset about situation and I apologized sincerely to her relating to her issue. I offered her a replacement product we currently had if it was a time thing for the same price or I could ship it to their home free of charge if she wanted that item. After that she was really happy. Bad customer service, this lady at a fast food restaurant didnt charge my order correctly and when I courteously pointed it out to her, she said in Spanish to charge me for something that was close to the price and ended up charging me more for it. I knew what she said cause I live in SoCal and know the official state language down here. Okay, my girlfriend is a Spanish speaker. 
 Edited 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Sam Jensen Member since: April 28, 2011 Total points: 488 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well, my most memorable experience was over the internet. The best customer service I received from people who understand it best - CRM guys. I am using their system and I had a little trouble figuring out something so I contacted them and I received an answer in 30 minutes (bear in mind it was the middle of the night). They were fast and polite and helped me resolve the thing I was wondering about in a matter of minutes. 
Source(s):
 http://www.webcrm.com/pl/default.asp 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Abby Member since: May 03, 2011 Total points: 378 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well having a very good knowledge about your product and services is good customer service….. and bad customer service is when you&apos;re not able to help your customer …. : ) 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 33% 1 Vote 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Careers&amp;Employment 

 What career should I choose? Why cant I get a job? Where can a 16 year old who loves animals work? I NEED to quit my job...Help? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Careers&amp;Employment 
 Administrative and Office Support Financial Services Food Service Government&amp;Non-Profit Health Care Law&amp;Legal Marketing&amp;Sales Other - Careers&amp;Employment Technology 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
