<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007255" url="http://www.chasingame.com/index.php?id=63" time="2012-07-13-00:13" support="14" score="0.007533647282746094" bingtitle="Chasingame Reviews: Stealthcam" webtitle="Chasingame Reviews: Stealthcam">
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000665" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000979" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>There is both a solar panel and a 12 volt receptacle on ... select just one emitter taped over the array in order ... has been confirmed that the trigger time is near 5 ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Reviews 
 2010 Review Schedule Review Page (all reviews) IR Comparison Page 50ft Flash Tests Battery Life Tests Straight Talk 
 Our Store News/Info 
 Read Newsletters 2009 Announcements Issues/Updates Articles 2009 whats New Press Releases 
 Gettin Started 
 Hints and Tips What you should not do Camera Mounting Camera Projects 
 Gallery 
 Browse Photos Browse Videos Orion LiveCam 
 Links 
 Links Page Community Links 
 Community 
 Discussion Forum Mailing List How to Embed our Logo 
 About Us 
 What our site is about How to use our site 
 Contact 
 
   
 
 
 
 Back to Main Review Page on 
 Chasingame.com StealthCam Camera Review Page 
   
 Stealth Cam DIGRC-XTR   
 Stealth Cam STC-AD2   
 Stealth Cam 
 STC-WD1 Stealth Cam STC-WD2 Stealth 
 Cam STC-WD3 Stealth Cam STC-IR1   Stealth Cam I230 IR (WD2 IR)   Stealth 
 Cam STC-I 450 (2007)   Stealth Prowler STC-DVIR (2007)   Stealth Cam 
Patroller   Stealth Cam STC-V650 (WD-6) (2008)   StealthCam 
 EPIC (2008)   StealthCam 
STC-I540IR (2008)   StealthCam STC-I430IR (2008)   StealthCam 
 STC-I590 (2008) 

 
 
 
 
 

 STEALTH CAM 

 DIGRC-XTR 3.0MP 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
  
 (purchased from Cabelas) 

 This camera was a very poor performer. It had a 10+ second 
trigger time which would only show game in the picture if they stood around for 
a few minutes. It also would use a set of batteries in less than a week. This camera&apos;s manual was written well and most folks would not have a problem 
following the programming procedures. 

 (sorry no sample pics - we did not get any) 

  
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-AD2 2.1MP 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
  
 A couple of years ago we tried the top of 
 the line Stealth Cam DIGRC-XTR and we were super disappointed with its non 
 performance. Now that time has passed we decided to pick a middle of the 
 pack Stealth camera to test. This camera is in the $200.00 range and is 2.1 
 MP. Compact flash media cards up to 256 will work in this camera. The 
 written instruction booklet that came with the camera is written pretty 
 vague. I purposely attempted to program this camera without reading the 
 instructional manual. I was successful to a degree. There were some strange 
 icons that appeared that I had to refer to the manual to figure out there 
 meaning. After an hour of playing the programming was complete. Most of the 
 programming methods are in line with standard digital camera operations. 
 This camera operates off 8 D cells or an external 6v rechargeable battery. 

 The external battery jack on the camera is 
 standard and the plug is available at Radio Shack. I assembled an external 
 power cable in about 15 minutes using a plug from Radio Shack and some wire 
 and a couple of alligator clips. All in shop testing was done using a 6v Moultrie battery. ( forgive me Moultrie folks) I purchased two high capacity 6v lead acid batteries from 
 our local Battery Plus outlet for about $18 a piece for the extended field 
 testing. Instruction manual says to only change out the top 4 batteries then 
 change out the bottom 4 batteries to keep from loosing the program 
 (date-time). This holds true when you are using only external power. I 
 placed 4 rechargeable D cells in the top 4 holes and swapped the external 
 battery and the program was saved. I then stored the D cells by putting one 
 in all 4 compartments upper and lower for future battery changes. The 
 trigger time for this camera is a solid 6 seconds and that is pretty slow. 
 The flash appears to be very good and will reach 
 past 30 feet easily. The security features are basically non existent. There 
 will be a real need for some type of theft protection to be built prior to 
 installing this cam in the field. Field testing will be done using the 
 1600X1200 setting and the three star (highest) quality setting with the one minuet delay. One picture per event will also be 
 selected. Later testing will include the movie 
 mode. 

 This camera will be in the field tomorrow 11-5-05 to begin the field testing. 

 We received E mail from MMFord with his testimonial on this cam. Viewer stated that he was on 
 his second set of batteries (he is using standard D cell batteries) since 
 early July which is very good battery life. Using his figures we calculated 
 that during that time he was getting approximately ten pictures per day with 
 the majority being at night. He stated that he felt the pictures were good 
 but due to the slow trigger time he had some lost pictures. We are taking a 
 very close look at this camera and due to our past experience with Stealth 
 and along with the bad press viewed through out 
 the outdoor forums. We hope that the Stealth folks have turned things around 
 with these later model cameras. They still have some work to do on their 
 trigger time. It appears that the battery life issue may have been addressed 
 to a degree. 
 
 12-21-05 update : This cam was placed in the field for several weeks and was 
 not very successful in capturing any pictures. To call this camera a 
 trail camera would be a stretch, it is more like a corn feeder camera. 
 When placed on a feeder this cam took lots of pictures. The battery life 
 has been good but with the extremely slow trigger time and sensing 
 ability we feel that it would only be of value when placed where the 
 target animals are in front of the camera for an extended period of 
 time. It does work but not very well. 
 
 
 
 Trigger time is 6 seconds 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 
 
  
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-WD1 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
 
  To wear out an old record, we started with a 
couple of Stealth cams and were very unhappy with there lack of function. After 
a year or so we decided to try another Stealth the STC-AD2 and again we are not impressed with this cam. It does work but has a 
very bad trigger time and now it has been in the field for weeks and we have yet 
to get a picture off it to post for its review. A number of our site visitors 
have told us about the STC-WD1 and wanted a review. The folks in the field have 
raved about this cam so I purchased one for about $170.00 from Cabelas . Out of the box it appeared to resemble 
several of the other Stealth cams that we have had. After I opened the case up 
it has a different look to the display and switches. I believe this cam is made 
for Stealth by another vender that is different from all the other stealth cams 
that I have operated. I was able to program this cam easy without using the 
manual. The manual is well written and easy to follow. This cam takes 6 C cells 
and has the external plug for an external 12 volt 
battery. The trigger time test averaged 2.25 seconds to 2.75 seconds or just under 3 seconds in a 20+ attempt test. The flash is 
good with an acceptable range of 40 feet. In shop test pictures at 1.3 MP 
setting (high 1280X1024) were sharp and clear. If this cam performs well it will 
be in direct competition with the Moultrie 3.1 
as far as price and trigger time. According to the users of this cam that have 
contacted us they have raved about the battery life 
also. We will be field testing this camera tomorrow as soon more flash range 
tests are performed this evening. When the cam is turned on after being 
programmed the LCD screen will come on for 30 seconds then shut down to conserve 
battery life. If no buttons are pressed the cam will then arm in 60 seconds. To 
make the display on the LCD to return you must press and hold the up or down 
button for 5 seconds. There are factory security brackets for this cam listed 
for $20.00 available on line from stealth or by toll free number. I will build 
my own this afternoon. 
 12-21-05 update : This camera appears to work very well , 
 with the exception of picture quality. It is doing very good on battery life 
 and it is sensing as well as the backup cams placed along side. The pictures 
 are a little fuzzy but readable. When the picture quality was put to other 
 field users on an outdoor forum we received the same remarks about the 
 picture quality. It is a pretty good camera for the price. 
  1-09-06 update: This cam has been running on its standard ( Duracell ) 
 batteries since early December. The past two weeks it has taken over 400 
 pictures with night temps in the high 20s and low 30s. We are starting 
 to like this camera very much and with only one drawback, that is 
 picture quality being a little fuzzy. We are getting ready to do the 
 movie mode tests soon. 
  
 
 Trigger time is under 3 seconds 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 
 
   
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-WD2 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
 
  
 This is the new 2006 Stealth Cam 
 STC-WD2. This camera is a mirror image of the WD1. The cost from 
 Cabelas was the same as the WD-1, in the $170 range and all features 
 are the same with the exception of the increased MP rating for this 
 camera from 1.3 MP on the WD-1 To 2.1 Mp on the WD-2. 

 

 If 
 this camera produces very sharp and clear pictures it is a definite 
 good bye to the Moultrie cameras that have occupied our 
 recommendation spot for the under $200 range. The trigger time is 
 just over 2 seconds which seems to beat most of the Moultrie cameras 
 and if the sensing is like the WD1 (which out performed the 
 Cuddeback 3.0) on our side by side tests, we will be pleased. 

 

 One of 
 the things that I do not like about this cam is that the cam is in 
 the door. It seems that several of the camera manufactures have 
 chosen to do this but it makes the cam clumsy to handle due to the 
 up front weight. I also noticed that the SD card slot is very close 
 to the frame which makes it difficult to remove the card if a person 
 has stubby fingers like mine. Being that I was familiar with the WD 
 1 programming I was able to program this camera in about 5 minutes 
 without the use of the manual. 

 

 The 
 flash tests proved to be the same as the WD 1 which proved to be 
 good out past 40 feet. Our tests were using the 1 min. delay and the 
 high 1600X1200 resolution setting. Being this camera has the 
 possibility to take the #1 spot in its price range I will take some 
 time to build a means to secure this camera and try to have pictures 
 of this soon. There is a factory bracket available for $20. This cam 
 will also adapt to the external 12 volt battery for folks who have 
 areas where they will be getting large numbers of pictures and have 
 a need to leave the camera out for extended periods of time. This 
 cam is in the field and as soon as I have the first set of pictures 
 we will post them. 
 3-11-06 Update : 

 We now have our first pictures after the camera being 
 out for three days. The clarity and sharpness is still in question but I 
 will delay judgment this time because of the gray rainy days it had to 
 operate in. To see if it is up to par with its older brother the WD 1 we 
 put the WD 2 and the Cuddeback 3.0 on the 
 same tree to test the sensing ability. The WD 1 beat out the Cuddeback in the same test so next week we 
 should know how this cam compares. I think that I an going to like this camera. 

 3-25-06 Update : 

 This week we checked the WD-2 that 
 was mounted on the same tree as the Cuddeback 3.0 and the results were that the Cuddeback took 31 pictures and the WD-2 took over 60. These two cams were set to 
 look at a corn feeder which also had one of our Buckeye wireless cameras 
 looking at the same area from the other side. The Buckeye also took over 
 60 pictures. The sensing ability of this camera is in line with its 
 early brother the WD-1 which outperformed the Cuddeback 3.0 under the same test. The day and night pictures are 
 very acceptable and as far as I am concerned this camera takes first 
 place for its price range thus pushing out the Moultrie cameras . 

 
 Trigger time is around 2 seconds 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 
 WD2 home 
 made Locking device made from a 8 1/2 inch X 1 1/2 inch X 
 1/8 inch piece of steel and 
 useing a 3/8 inch X 6 foot python cable.
Total cost was about $16. 
 
   
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-WD3 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
  
 STC-WD3MT ,  Factory purchase. 

 This camera is Stealth&apos;s attempt to be in competition with the 
 popular 3.0 Cuddeback . This company previously 
 had this model out less the MT in its number. The MT is moon and temperature 
 which is shown of the pictures similar to how Moultrie has it on theres. This is a 3.0 MP camera that 
 when compared to the Moultrie and Cuddeback , it 
 will easily hold its own. Out of the box it appears to be the same as the 
 WD1 and WD2. The case is the same dark OD color and latches and means to 
 hook it to the tree are the same. When you open the case most of the buttons 
 are the same with the addition of an adjustable sensing range dial. This 
 camera also has a 1.8 inch view screen for viewing pictures in the field. I 
 was able to power up this cam and do the programming in one step without 
 going to the manual. The programming is very easy and strait forward. The 
 manual is complete and easy to follow. After putting my hands on several of 
 these same styled cameras I found one thing that is a real bother to me. The 
 buttons are embossed with its task and unless you catch the light exactly 
 right it is very hard to determine what the button is for. Dealing with so 
 many different cameras, I have to be very careful before I hit a button to 
 keep from making a mistake in the programming. During my military days we 
 would swipe the buttons of our equipment with a dab of contrasting colored 
 paint to fill in the embossed printing which seemed to solve the problem. In 
 low light field conditions this can be a bother. The next dislike is the 
 same as the WD1 and WD2, and that is the heavy cam and batteries in the 
 door. This is minor but aggravating when mounting and handling this camera. 
 Resolution can be set all the way from VGA, 1.3, 2.0, to 3.0 MP. Our tests 
 will be at the 3.0 level. Settings to determine the picture per event can be 
 set from one to three or 10 second 320X240 10 fps movies. The CF card is the 
 manufactures choice for this camera, we used a Lexar 256 for our tests. A very nice feature is the lo battery indicator on the front of the 
 camera. We have tried to get the folks at Cudde to do the same but so far it has not appeared. Trigger time is 2 to 2.5 
 seconds and the flash range is good out past 40 feet. Initial picture 
 quality was judged to be sharp and clear. Below is a comparison to other 3.0 
 cameras.   

 Ease of programming : Moultrie 
 3.0 and Stealth 3.0 have it all over Cuddeback here.  

 Security : I would 
 have to give this to Cuddeback and Stealth over 
 the Moultrie. 

 Sensing :   Without 
 a doubt the Stealth is first followed by the Moultrie and then the Cuddeback . Our tests proved that both the Moultrie and the Stealths took right at twice the amount of pictures as the Cuddeback with identical exposure to the target animals.   

 Trigger time: Cuddeback is second to 1 second, Stealth 2.0 to 2.5 seconds and Moultrie 3 seconds. 
 All of which is very acceptable for most field uses.  

 Picture quality : All 
 three have very good pictures with the exception of the saucer eye problem Moultrie has with its flash pictures.   

 Flash range : Most 
 are equal with the Stealth maybe slightly stronger past 40 feet. 

 Field viewing : Only 
 Stealth has a view screen, Moultrie and Cudde have to have an external device to view images in the field.  

 Cost : Moultrie 
 is jammed with features for around $160, Stealth comes in with a cost of $380 and Cudde comes in at $400.   

 On off switch : Both 
 Stealth and Moultrie have this feature, Cudde does not.  

 Lo battery indicator : Moultrie has a LCD display viewable from the front and Stealth uses a small light to 
 tell you of a low battery condition. Cuddeback requires the user to go through some programming to gain this information.  

 Solar panel : Both 
 the Moultrie and the Stealth have this 
 feature the Cudde does not. We have adapted one 
 of our Cuddeback cameras to use a solar panel with success now for over a year.   

 External battery : Moultrie 
 and Stealth have this feature Cudde does not.   

 Door vs removable 
 panel : Most all cameras have doors with some 
 type of latch to close it tight for weather proofing. Moultrie and Stealth have done a very good job of this. 
 Though it is not a big deal the Cuddeback uses a 
 screw and detachable front panel with a small underneath place to use a 
 lock. This has proved to be a pain in some cases where the cam is on a tree 
 with brush close or mounted low.   

 Initial conclusion is that we really like the 
 WD3. Our wish would be that one of you manufacturers (or homebrewers ) would take the Cuddeback trigger speed along with the Stealth cams sensing and put it with the Moultrie price and the result would be 
 outstanding. The plan is that if weather permits we will be field testing 
 very shortly. 
 04-23-06 update : As with its WD1- WD2 predecessors the WD 3 MT has climbed its way up to a point where we are 
 going to have to give it, its due. Having only the trigger time and 
 flash range pictures to judge this camera showed that it was capable of 
 some pretty great pictures. This camera not only produced some really 
 great pictures it showed that its flash reaches out way past the average 
 target animal Having the benefit of a view screen and great sensing this 
 camera is an exceptional piece of work. The two second trigger time did 
 not hold this camera back from holding its own against one of the 
 competitors which has engineered some pretty exceptional trigger times 
 and picture qualities. I will say that not only do I like this camera, I really like it . 
 04-27-06 update :  During the second week 
 we gathered a couple hundred pictures and a few movies. The picture quality for both day and night were very 
 good and the movie quality was very much like most trail cam 
 examples, very readable but grainy. Battery life was not determined 
 due to our two week test was using the external battery. We are 
 looking to the field users to report back on our forum to determine 
 that information. The three camera sensing test that we are running 
 on our forum is putting three different manufactures to test side by 
 side. For a short period of time we set the WD 3 in on that test and 
 its performance was equal to its little brother the WD 2. With the 
 3.0 MP cameras presently on the market and I was given the task to chose between this cam and other 3.0 MP 
 cameras I would go with the WD 3 MT. Cameras with very good trigger 
 time have the advantage as far as how you place it in the field, but 
 if your sensing is weaker and the cam does not see the target 
 animal, the camera will not take the picture. Having really great 
 sensing is becoming a bit more important than the trigger time. 
 Knowing the limits of your cameras trigger time allows the user to 
 make his setup in a way to keep the animal in front of the camera 
 for that one second longer period of time. The new generation of 
 cameras that we will be receiving in the next couple months may 
 change all of this. 
  
 
 Trigger time is around 2 seconds 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 
 

 Movie samples
 
 
    
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-IR1 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
  
 STC-IR1 
 5.0MP , Factory purchase. 

 When this camera came out of the box I was 
 totally impressed with the appearance of this cam. From the views seen on 
 the manufactures site and outlets like Cabelas , 
 I was expecting a camera about the size of the WD1. This camera is about 11 
 inches tall and 9 inches wide and 4 inches thick. The camera is the typical 
 OD color as the others we tested with a large 4 inch square IR array behind 
 a smoked glass cover. This should provide a degree of camo for this large array. 

 When opened up there is the cam in the 
 door thing again with the typical set of hard to read buttons and LCD 
 display along with a view screen. The indicator sticker next to the CF card 
 slot was somewhat confusing until I found the picture of proper card installation in the manual. There is both a 
 solar panel and a 12 volt receptacle on the bottom of the camera. The TV out 
 and USB outlets are next to the CF card slot. On the inside back of the 
 camera is a small programming instruction sticker which has printing so 
 small that my old eyes could hardly read it. It seems that with a camera the 
 size of a normal piece of bond paper and room for a much larger instruction 
 sticker that manufacture would do just that. 

 There is a wide strap and a tree 
 screw with a bend in it to match a threaded hole in the bottom of the 
 camera. This proved to be not very stable or safe for a camera of this size. 
 We chose to use the strap. The metal bar with two holes that is shipped with 
 most Stealth cams for security is also part of the accessory package that 
 came in the box. This means of security is pretty good when used with the 
 Master Python cable. Care must be taken because the slot for the mounting 
 strap and security bar is located on the back of the camera, directly behind 
 the sensor and camera lens thus the cable has just a very narrow place to 
 cross the front of the camera. Another suggestion is to leave the cable with 
 enough slack to sag below the lens opening. 

 I went from the out of the box 
 programming of the WD-3 MT to out of the box programming of the IR-1. I was 
 stopped completely until I had a chance to review the manual. Even though the programming is 
 straight forward it is not nearly as intuitive as the WD-1, 2, and 3 but with 
 care can be accomplished. I attempted the trigger speed test about ten times 
 and could not get anything to record to the card nor could I get the IR 
 array to fire. I spent several hours going over every thing even to opening 
 up a new CF card to no avail. The camera will write to its internal memory 
 but not to the card. A quick call to their tech support and it was 
 determined that shipping may have caused a problem. I will have to get it 
 back to them to take a look at it so we can complete this review. Cabelas last catalog has the price on sale at 
 $599.99. 
 
 05-01-06 Update: The replacement cam arrived this afternoon 
 and I commenced the trigger time testing which turned out to be around 5 
 seconds. I had some difficulty measuring the delay time because 
 sometimes it would be about one minute and the next time it appeared to 
 be two minutes. I had it set on one minute but the actual time looks 
 more like 1.5 minutes to recover. The IR array was so bright that it 
 wiped out the clock so I ended up with a piece of 5X8 card with a hole 
 in it to select just one emitter taped over the array in order for me to 
 be able to read the clock. This time the cam did not have the manual in 
 the box so I had to rely on memory (bad idea) to do the programming. 
 Most of the process I was able to do but eventually I got the old 
 magnifier out and went to that door sticker and finished the task. IR 
 flash testing proved that this camera will take clear night pictures out 
 to 40+ feet. I have taken down some data so that when we get our hands 
 on the new WD 3 IR we can do some comparisons. Next step is get this camera to an area with some game for 
 some field testing. 

 05-12- 06 Update:  We have concluded the field test of this camera. 
 With the higher MP rating the night pictures were very sharp and clear. 
 The IR flash strength is overpowering on animals that came in close and 
 washed out the detail. Care must be taken when placing this camera to be 
 far enough away from the target area to insure that the flash does not 
 wipe out the pictures. The IR night time movies were sharp and clear. 
 Our daytime pictures showed that this camera had what appeared to be a 
 problem. All of the daytime pictures showed half the picture to be clear 
 and sharp with good color but the other half of the picture showed an 
 exposure problem. This will be explained to their tech support when we 
 send it back in. Being spoiled by the excellent sensing of the WD 1 ,2,3 cameras we expected this camera to perform the same but it did not. 
 Placed along side another IR camera that we knew of its sensing ability 
 the IR 1 did not do as well. This camera does work but having a 5 second 
 trigger time and a sensing ability that is lower than the WD series, 
 care must be taken when placing it in the field in order to insure that 
 the target animals will be directly in front and have a longer exposure 
 time to trigger. New owners of this camera should visit the Stealth Cam 
 site and view the excellent how to videos they have put together. 
 Programming this camera is somewhat difficult even with the manual but 
 their tutorial videos on the site makes it 
 much more understandable. Stealth&apos;s new WD 3 
 IR should correct most of the deficiencies we found on the IR1 and we 
 are looking forward to testing it. 
 
 
 
 Trigger time (around 5 
 secs) 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 

 Mechanical filter stuck between modes:
 
  Movie Samples Movie 1      Movie 2 
  
 
 Infra 
 Red Camera visual comparison 
 Pictorial Page 
 

 STEALTH CAM 

 I230 IR
(WD2 IR) 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
Stealth Universal Bracket:
This 
bracket also fits Bushnell and WildView.
 
 StealthCam I230IR Review 

 The 
 WD-1, 2, 3, and now the IR all come in the solid water tight OD green case. 
 In place of the standard flash is an IR array which contains 27 emitters 
 compared to the Bushnell which has only 12 and the Leaf river has 36 (both wide angle and standard) emitters. Flash range 
 tests proved that things were well lit up at 40 feet. Programming was the 
 same as previous models and was easy to do following instructions in the 
 manual. Trigger time proved to be 3 seconds which is the same as the Leaf river and Cudde IR 
 cameras. I still do not like the buttons in this camera because the 
 embossing is hard to read unless the light is just right. Disappointing also 
 was the absents of the lock bar that we had on 
 some other models and should be one of the items that a user should buy (now 
 as an accessory) $7 from Stealth. Cam security any more seems to be a big 
 issue with most new buyers of game cameras. Stealth chose to include a nice 
 wide strap for mounting and this along with the optional lock bar and Python 
 lock will make securing this cam easy. Our trigger time photos are out of 
 focus due to the clock was set inside the 5 food focal distance of this cam. 
 Every IR camera we have tested to date with the exception of the Stealth IR1 have fuzzy night time pictures. Even with this 
 degree of clarity found on all IR camera night pictures they are still sharp and clear enough to pick out enough good 
 detail for game animal evaluation. We had hoped to have several IR cams to 
 do a side by side test but due to the issues found on the Cudde , it had to be returned. Our Recon Extreme 
 ended up with a damaged PIR sensor lens and is on the way back to us with a 
 new lens. So, it looks like this test will be just the Leaf River IR and WD- 
 2 IR for right now. Putting the 1/4 th second trigger time 
 Bushnell IR up against these cams would not be fair. We did this with the Cudde IR and the Bushnell blew the Cudde out of the saddle. I played around with 
 the test mode just to see what it would do at 40 feet on a 76 degree 
 morning. I was quite impressed with the sensing range and width. With the 
 external battery and a 2 gig card (over 6000 pictures at the high rez setting) this camera should go a couple 
 months before it would have to be visited. I am judging the battery life 
 from our experience with the standard WD-2 which we ran over two months 
 without a change. Just like the Bushnell IR, it only took a few minuets to 
 figure out that I really like this camera. We have been extremely happy with 
 all of the WD series cameras from this company. Lets hope that the field tests dont disappoint us with some bad things. The cost 
 on this camera is $299.99 and if you choose to order the security bar it 
 lists for $7 plus a dollar shipping. Should you choose to make your own 
 security bar this can be done with a 9 inch piece of 1/8X1 X9 inch piece 
 of steel with two inch holes drilled in the ends to run the python lock through. A short note about this cameras burst 
 mode, it will take three pictures in less than a second for each triggering. 
 This is nice for that ole buck that is following 
 behind the doe and for certain security applications. 

 Our initial field test was a side by 
 side with a Leaf River IR camera and both cameras almost the same amount of 
 pictures. The 4 day test had 150 day and night pictures. We found that this 
 camera actually looks low compared to the Leaf river . 
 A good portion of the pictures were of just the lower half of the deer. We 
 re installed it in the burst mode and made the necessary corrections to have 
 the pictures centered and put it back out, this time in the burst mode. This 
 was done so that we could have some nice sample pictures. During this same 
 period of time we were running a parallel test using a couple of the 
 Moultrie cameras. Neither of the Moultries had 
 pictures. We have always been impressed by the sensing ability of the Leaf 
 River cams and for this camera to get equal amount of pictures under exact 
 conditions says a lot. Every one of the WD series Stealths have proved to be very good in the sensing department. Now lets talk picture quality. It is my impression 
 that no IR camera to date has produced what I would call really great night 
 pictures with the exception of the high MP Stealth IR1. All the IR cameras 
 tested to date had acceptable picture quality for scouting cam purposes. 
 Also most of these cams have a small difference in MP ratings which makes it 
 hard to do across the board comparison. Cudde IR 
 being the worst and the Bushnell IR being the best putting this cam and the 
 Leaf River in the middle. The cudde also has the 
 lowest MP rating and the Leaf River has the highest which says this type of 
 comparison is un fair. One thing that is very 
 noticeable is the strength of the IR array. This camera with its good 
 sensing and extremely strong array needs to be placed further away from the 
 target area 20 feet at least. The pictures of deer at 15 feet were nearly whited out in some cases. This solid and very functional camera is going to get my approval. 
 With its great sensing ability and having a cost that is a $150 cheaper that 
 a Cudde and $50 more than a Bushnell and the 
 same as the Leaf River this camera is directly out front. What makes it shine over the rest, is features like 
 being able to use external battery with solar panel, ease of programming, 
 and acceptable picture quality (no it does not have a view screen). I know 
 that I am going to hear it from the Leaf River fans about this because most 
 everything about both cams are pretty equal with the exception of the Leaf 
 Rivers softer array light which tends to make their night time pictures more 
 grainy and fuzzy. I do not like these quickie charts but we are going to 
 try to put together a page that has the pictures from each cam to show side 
 by side comparison. 

 We have concluded the review on this 
 cam and yes we do like this cam. We found that sensor on this 
 particular camera was not as far reaching as out WD 1 but it reached well 
 past the range of the IR flash.  
 
 
 Trigger time (around 3 secs) 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 
 Note: The following samples show improper cam 
 placement. We aimed it too low. This causes a flash circle 
 on the ground and over exposed subjects. These do 
 exemplify clarity and resolution for day and night however. 
 
 
 
 Infra 
 Red Camera visual comparison 
 Pictorial Page 
  
 STEALTH CAM 

 I-450
(WD4) 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
  5-30-2007             Camera Purchased from TrailCamPro.Com 
 
Stealth keeps things interesting each year with this barrage of new 
nomenclatures, in this case it is the I 450 which is to us a WD 4. Every thing 
has basically remained the same in appearance this year. Most all changes are 
internal with the upgrade to a full 4 MP and a better flash. The external 
battery port remains the same as the previous WD series cams and is one of our 
favorite features. This camera came to us sealed in a clear bubble pack as would 
be the case for any user. All dimensions remain the same as all the WD cameras 
and this camera did not come with the locking bar (now optional) that is 
required to secure this camera when deployed to the field. The memory is 32 
internal and up to 2 gig using the not included SD 
card. Flash is easily turned on and off with the up button and the burst mode 
has a selectable up to 9 images per PIR trigger. Video (320X240) can be set from 5 to 90 seconds. Resolution can be easily set 
to 0.4. 1.3, or 4.0 MP through programming . This is 
a very easy camera to setup and use. This company also has a very good history 
of folks dealing with their customer service. After a recent review on another 
brand camera which had a very narrow sensing angle, we were pleased to see that 
stealth has a full 45 degrees of sensing. First thing of interest will be to 
test the new flash and see how good it is, then move 
on to the ol trigger time testing. The sturdy OD 
green water proof case and with locking bar this camera will take to the 
elements just fine. My first flash test was inside and when I stepped in front 
of the camera and it went off at about ten feet it felt like my optic nerve had 
been toasted. It was a good half hour before the spots went away enough to get 
back on the computer and do a little more writing. With out any further testing 
I would say that they did jack up the flash just a tad.  

 05-31-2007 update:   Playing around with 
 this cam doing the trigger and flash range testing proves that this cam 
 works very well. The trigger time seems to be exactly the same as the WD-2 
 and WD-3 cams previously tested. This is in the 2 second range and is more 
 than adequate for both trail and feeder use when properly placed. The flash 
 range is all the way out to 65 feet and the sensing range for a 70 degree 
 morning proved to be a repeated 45 feet. Night time flash pictures taken 
 during the flash range testing were sharp and clear. We will stick this cam 
 on one of our test sites and see how it does with a few of the wild critters 
 we have paying us a visit.  
  
 06-09-2007 update : More time has allowed us to find a 
 potential issue for folks who select sites that are under heavy cover 
 and the morning and evening light has a hard time getting through to the 
 camera. Our test area is under a pretty full canopy of trees and because 
 of this we have seen not only on this cam, but two others tested this 
 year that about an hour in the morning and evening the camera cannot 
 tell if it should flash or not which is causing a few washout pictures. 
 Folks using this camera where it is good and bright most of the time 
 will probably not see this issue. We tried lowering the cam and aiming 
 it a little upward with the intent that it would gather more light in 
 the light sensor but this proved to be ineffective. When we get past 
 these two periods things start to happen very well with sharp and clear 
 pictures. Last year we also found that several of the cameras had the 
 same problem, and some of the folks tried drilling out the light sensor 
 hole but I do not think anyone came up with a workable solution other 
 than moving the camera to an area with more morning and evening light.

 06-17-2007 update:  With the cameras confusion between day 
 light and night came short periods of very light pictures that had some 
 folks worried. We have seen this whiteout thing with all makes of 
 cameras and it seems to be something that we camera users are going to 
 have to live with until all the manufacturers find a fix. (read about whiteout ).This 
 being a minor issue we found that this camera is one super performer. A 
 little slower trigger time than its Moultrie competitor but only by 
 second. Very good picture quality and overall performance was without 
 fault. This is a very good performer that is woods ready, and will 
 definitely get the job done in good fashion. 
 
 08-20-2007 update : We have approached 
 Stealth concerning the whiteout issue that some users have experienced. Stealth 
 engineers are working on a firmware upgrade and correction for this 
 issue which will be a web download. Owners can upgrade the 
 firmware in their cameras without sending them back to Stealth. When this firmware update is available we will make a note here. 
 
  
 
 Trigger time (right at 2 secs) (with flash)
 
(in sun light)
 
 Flash Tests Sample Photos
 high resolution Note: Time is 12 hours off. In this 
 first set we got some washouts in the day time but it was 
 raining heavily in a forested setting and the flash appeared to 
 be going off in day time hours. 
 
 
 
I lowered the camera and aimed it up a bit. The strong 
 flash reflects off the ground. Mount around 24&quot;or so. 
 low resolution
 
 
 
 The tree rats knocked the camera to the side 
 but I still managed to get this yearling doe. This is a 3+ 
 MB file so make sure you have high speed internet or your will 
 have a long wait:
 
 Video sample 1 
  
 
  
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-DVIR 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
 
  
 Stealth Prowler STC-DVIR Review 08-13-2007 

 I heard a noise of a box bouncing 
 off the recliner on the front porch and went to investigate. I opened the 
 box and it was obvious that there was something in the box but I could not 
 see it. We only wish that the new Stealth Prowler was that concealable but 
 it is the same OD color as all the previous WD series cameras. Scanning 
 through the catalogs a person gets the opinion that this should be a much 
 larger camera than the rest of the Stealth line but it is not. If you were 
 to take a WD-2 and slice off the excess plastic along the edges in a shape 
 similar to the aircraft that carries the same name then you would have a 
 prowler. It is a good looking camera and the water tests showed the case to 
 be tight though it still has the small weep holes along the bottom 
 preventing it from being totally water proof as with the rest of the Stealth 
 line of trail cameras. The case is solid and the latches pull things up 
 tight. This camera supports a two lens system so that the color day and the 
 IR night does not have to use that noisy 
 mechanical filter found on the single lens IR cameras. Programming is the 
 same as the WD series so there is nothing new here. Easy to program, solid 
 case, good documentation, dual lens, and with the Stealth locking bar it 
 will be easy to conceal. The 1 to 9 burst per IR trigger is also 
 incorporated which is a super feature. Video is adjustable from 5 to 90 
 seconds (640X480) Color day rez settings are 
 1.3, 3.0, and 5.0 and when switched to night IR operations the options are 
 .3, 1.3, and 2.0 MP settings. IR video night time pictures are also at the 
 640X480 setting. Battery condition is shown by the battery symbol as 
 standard on all previous cams. I installed 6 new Energizer C cells to start 
 with and we will run them until the cam shuts down. Similar to the Moultrie 
 cams the pictures will display the date time along with moon phase and 
 temperature. Spread across the front of the cam is an array that is 6 
 emitters tall and 7 wide (42 total) this should brighten up the night. Hope 
 that it is not over kill like the retina burning flash on the I-450. 
 Stealths previous IR-1 flagship cam turned out to be a banner boat because 
 of its mechanical filter which wanted to hang up all the time. The old IR-1 
 turned in some of the best IR pictures we have seen to date. Maybe we will 
 get lucky again with this sliced off box of a cam. Lens viewing angle of 52 
 degrees and PIR sensing out to 48 degrees would make us thing that if it is 
 out there this camera should see it and capture it. While standing by this 
 cam uses a small 2 mA drain which during capture 
 increases to 180 mA of drain. Internal memory is 
 32 MB and camera will except up to a 2 gig SD card .. The camera lenses are glass and not plastic. Looking this good makes me want 
 to just stay up and test this thing all night just to see how good it is. 
 Maybe I will try to sneak at least 8 hours before the 4 AM flash and sensing 
 rang testing starts. This morning it was another one of those 80 degree 
 mornings so I dont know how well the sensing is going to do in the morning. 
 
 08-14-2007 update:  Proceeded with the flash range tests and 
 found this cam has a very good flash that is a little overwhelming at 
 close range. Targets at 50+ feet were well illuminated. Sensing range 
 for this 80 degree morning was a consistent 30 to 35 feet. The 
 unofficial trigger time (judging from IR illumination) is a quick 1 to 2 
 seconds. This puts it much faster than the Cudde no flash. The camera 
 was set to the low rez setting for the flash range tests but the 
 pictures were still sharp and clear. It will be off to get the official 
 trigger time tests done and then the field and battery life testing will 
 follow. 
 

 08-18-2007 update:  It is not very often that we have a camera 
 that performs far out of standard. This new Stealth flag ship has turned 
 into a flag dud. Great flash, Great sensing, and lousy trigger time. The 
 trigger times with flash has been measured in excess of 9 seconds 
 repeatedly. When you watch the IR array illuminate after the cam has 
 been triggered it appears to be about one second. This illumination 
 lasts a long time and near the end of the illumination the picture is 
 shuttered. This kind of trigger time is unacceptable and because of this 
 we are going to suspend the review. We will try to get a couple sample 
 pictures before we send this cam back as being either poor quality or it 
 has a severe electrical malfunction causing this kind of poor 
 triggering. We are hoping that we can find some old slow doe that is 
 taking her time so we can get some sample pictures. 
 08-20-2007 update : We 
 have contacted Stealth management about our trigger times with flash and it 
 was determined that this camera has an electrical problem. We are 
 returning this camera to Stealth so that engineers can go through it and 
 determine the problem. We should receive a replacement camera very 
 soon and will repeat our tests and continue this review. Keep checking 
 back for updates on this camera. 
 

 08-23-2007 update:  As promised we now have our hands on a 
 replacement Prowler camera from the folks down in Texas. I jumped on all 
 the tests to see where I could find a difference between the old slow 
 poke and this cam. The flash range and operation is all the same. I 
 spent several hours playing with the flash trigger time (un official) 
 and feel strongly that this camera is going to perform much better than 
 its now departed partner. The IR array on this camera does not stay on 
 nearly as long as the last cam. This shows a definite change and is 
 welcome. There was some discussion on our forum that suggested that the 
 company would dope up a cam and send it to us to improve the review but 
 this is definitely not the case. Should I ever find out this kind of 
 action we would make a major note of this fact. With our schedule (the 
 real job) , it may take a little longer to get the first results out but 
 just be assured that we are working to get this data out due to this 
 camera&apos;s popularity. We feel at this time folks will not be to 
 disappointed. 
 08-25-2007 update : Another marathon trigger time episode and it shows that this replacement 
 camera has a full 5 second better trigger time with flash. The repeated 
 tests show a 4 second or a little less trigger time with flash. Daytime 
 without flash remained the same at 3.5 seconds. This is in line with some of 
 the recent cameras that we tested and we consider it acceptable. It is now 
 in 9 burst and we will see how it functions. We will run this cam on its 
 first set of batteries until it stops ticking to see how many pictures it 
 takes and how long they will last.

 09-01-2007 update:  The past six days this cam has been going 
 through its operations in high, low, and movie modes. We have literally 
 taken hundreds of pictures and hundreds of movies so far and I counted only 
 three blank pictures with nothing in them. There have been no whiteout 
 pictures, but what we do see is that slight blur in the pictures where the 
 deer are moving pretty fast. This blur is common in all IR cams we have 
 tested so far, with some like the cudde having a little more. We spent the 
 morning going over tons of pictures and hooked a couple hundred movies 
 together and viewed them. To put it mildly we are impressed. It appears 
 that the daytime movies that are in color have a slightly less frame rate 
 than the night IR AVIs. The sensing distance (guesstamate) was picking out 
 animals at around 60 feet on 72 degree mornings. We had tons of pictures of 
 deer crossing in front of the cam and were still center frame. The wide 
 angle of this PIR lens more than makes up for the 3.5 trigger. The folks at 
 Stealth have told us that the pre production samples that were presented to 
 them for acceptance were all in the 1.5 to 2 second range trigger time. Post 
 production samples pulled from the line are varying from 2 to 4 seconds. The 
 engineers are in the process of analyzing things so maybe if it is doable we 
 might get a fix. Could you imagine this cam with a 1 second trigger. That 
 would be pretty nice. Then do the same to the wildview 5.0 and lookout trail 
 cam manufacturers. The way it is working now I would not call it a slouch. 
 Over two weeks of operation and as of this morning the batteries still 
 showed full. We hung it back out this time in single capture basic mode for 
 another round off sample pictures. 
 09-23-2007 update:  This cam was started off 
 last month on the 18 th and has ran constantly until this morning. 
 The C cells kept it going 36 days and the camera took 3667 pictures during 
 that time. We had no whiteouts and the function has been very good. Two 
 things that we noticed about what this camera does is 1. during low light 
 conditions the pictures have very faint horizontal lines across them, and 2. 
 when the batteries became very low the flash became very weak for the last 
 few nighttime pictures. At the very end the pictures were black. The day 
 pictures at that time were the normal good color. From start to finish this 
 camera has functioned very good and has been a real pleasure to use. Stealth 
 can be proud of this one and if they ever get around to providing a fix to 
 lower the trigger time this will be one hell of a camera. Put this cam on a 
 good external SLA battery and I would expect two to three months of 
 continuous pictures. We have a few more tests to do before we hang up the 
 finished sign on this cam. 
  
 
 Trigger time (with flash around 9 seconds)
 Note: there appears to be an electrical problem 
 with the camera we have tested. We will test these times 
 again with a new camera as soon as possible. 
 
 
 Trigger times with the replacement camera:
(Trigger time with flash is 4 seconds) 

 
 

without flash is 3.5 seconds
 
  
 Flash Tests Sample Photos
 high resolution 
 
 
   Low Resolution
 
 
 
 Burst Mode 9
 
 
 

 Movies
 (high resolution 640x480) 
 
 
 
  
  
 Patroller 
STC-SLC2B 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 


 
 Stealth 
 Cam Patroller STC-SLC2B review 06-04-2008 

Over the past year while scanning all the outdoor forums looking for field 
 data on scouting cams, I noticed many threads where folks had their hunt 
 camp, shed, cabin, and barn broke into by some low life trespasser. The 
 solution has been that folks had to conceal a trail camera to watch the 
 property and this solution sometimes meant the loss of the trail camera 
 installed to catch a picture of the offender. Week before last I found on 
 the net while surfing for some camera data this new type of motion light and 
 camera combination. I had asked Stealth if they thought that this product 
 deserved a review but I got no response. Being this seems to be so closely 
 associated with hunting and scouting cameras I went ahead and purchased one 
 to test and report on.

Out of the box I noticed a number of things that I did not like. The first 
 thing was the instruction pamphlet and the way that the programming was 
 handled. Then there is no on off switch for the camera portion of this 
 device. The design is intended to be permanently installed as a motion 
 sensor light. When this is done, the camera is on the bottom and is 
 concealed very nicely. It takes a close look to actually pick out that there 
 is a camera tucked into this setup. With it being at the bottom of the lamp 
 it is nearly impossible to read the LCD and do the programming. The bracket 
 will allow the cam to be tipped up slightly and this helps a little but 
 standing on a ladder and trying to see under the camera proved problematic 
 for me. It requires that you have the instructions in hand to do the 
 programming because the procedure is outside the normal methods folks are 
 used to on trail cameras. Having to push two buttons at once and holding 
 others for 2 seconds and then re programming in another area once the first 
 portion was done. Being very familiar with every brand of trail camera, I 
 usually can just do the programming without ever looking at the 
 instructions. This is one of our tests to find out how intuitive the 
 programming is. It took me a good long time to finally accomplish the 
 programming and do some walk tests.

I shut the Patroller off to remove the card and found when I did this that I 
 lost the program and had to go through it again. Power failures would also 
 wipe out the programming. Drag the ladder out and stand on my head again for 
 another period of time so I could re install the program.

This device will take up to a 2 gig SD card and at its 2 MP rating set on 
 high it will capture 3328 pictures. Low setting will give you 5120 pictures 
 and on movie mode you can get 1024 ten second videos. The halogen lamp that 
 came with it was 500 watts which I swapped out for a 150 for these tests. 
 Program allows for single picture per trigger of a selectable burst mode can 
 be programmed in for multi shots while motion is present. The lamp can be 
 timed from 1 to 5 minutes per trigger. A 
 day light sensor will keep the lamp from coming on during the day but the 
 camera will still function. There is a 16MB internal memory that cam be used 
 if there is no card installed. The PIR sensor looks out to about 30+ feet 
 depending on the outside temperature and has a 48 degree sweep. I had been 
 using a scandisk 64 and I could not get any pictures, I swapped this out for 
 another brand and when I turned the light back on it kept the program 
 (?????). I will have to play with this a little more. As of now I still have 
 not got the thing to take pictures. I will leave it dormant for a while to 
 make sure that I am past any delay period and see if I can capture at least 
 one image before I finish pulling out the last few strands of hair I have. 
 This cam appears to be very card sensitive. The off brand card that used 
 worked fine and I was able to capture some very good color daytime pictures 
 that still had the time date stamp across the bottom. I will have to wait 
 for this evening to see how the night pictures come out. The night time 
 pictures proved to be only fair and this is partly due to the smaller sized 
 lamp which I installed for these shorter distances. The most disturbing 
 thing is that out of a multitude of triggers, it failed to catch me in any 
 of them . I was able to cross in front of the cam at 17 feet very slowly. 
 The lamp would come on but when I checked the card there was no pictures of 
 me. I then would stand in front of the cam and then it would catch me but 
 the trigger time is so slow that at a normal pace it would fail to catch a 
 person crossing in front of the camera. Pointed down a driveway where a auto or person was there for a longer period of 
 time it would probably work fine.

The conclusion is that a very well placed and concealed scouting camera with 
 IR flash and fast trigger would serve this situation better. Once installed 
 looking at an area where the target would be there for an extended period of 
 time this device would probably work fine and just leave it alone and turned 
 on until an obvious intrusion has been determined then check the card for 
 possible evidence. In this case when the card is full the oldest picture is 
 eliminated and the last picture is recorded. This review has been 
 concluded and this device is now in the recycle bin with some other refuse .

Sample pictures (I resized these from the originals - These are smaller)
 
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-V650 

WD6

 http://www.stealthcam.net 
 
 Stealth Cam 
 STC-V650 (WD-6) Review 06-25-2008 

 Camera arrived in a sealed bubble pack and through the plastic cover 
 it appeared to be a very good looking camera. Once out of the plastic you 
 can see that it is the same WD case with two plastic adhesive camo strips on each side of the face of the cam. 
 There was a big fingerprint smear on the main camera lens. When I opened the 
 cam the LCD display had part of the plastic removed and there were prints on 
 this screen also. The internal memory also showed use. Making a quick trip 
 through the instructions showed me that they have made some very nice 
 changes. The adjustable sensitivity knob and the solar panel switch. The 
 front of the cam has that great flash they have had in the past. Below that 
 is the LCD display for picture count and in the same panel there is the low 
 battery indicator and test indicator. The PIR sensor is the same wide angle 
 type that was seen on all the WD series cams. At the bottom is the external battery jack and now the new 
 solar panel jack that is used along with the switch inside. Latches and 
 water seal remain the same and very functional. The X 20 threaded socket 
 for tripod or tree screw remains also. Open the case and at the top is the 
 RFT LCD display. Below is the 6 C cell compartment with cover. The switch 
 panel includes the on off along with the standard programming buttons. These 
 are menu, up, down, and confirm. The new solar battery switch is just after 
 that. The only other things under the cover are the SD card slot, TV out, 
 and USB port. Going over the specifications I see that the image sensor is a 
 2.0 CMOS rated. The advertised max MP rating for this cam is 6.0 MP. Boy 
 that is one hell of an interpolation stretch. I think I would have to just 
 run this cam at 3.0 MP setting. The settings cam go from .3, 1.3, 3.0, to 6.0 MP which is pretty standard. The picture capture 
 is either single, burst, or AVI video at 320X240. The video is at 10 frames 
 per second but can be stretched out to 90 seconds. The PIR sensor looks out 
 at 48 degrees and the image sensor can se 52 degrees. I spent a considerable 
 length of time doing the basic (not official) trigger time test. The best 
 that I saw was 6 seconds. The settings were at 6.0 MP and single capture 
 with flash. If this holds true this will prove to be a very short review. 
 Moultrie I-40 slid to 3 seconds and the folks panicked when the seen what 
 had happened from 07 to the 08 models. The troubling things I see as of now 
 is the stretch from a 2.0 MP sensor to 6.0 and the slow trigger. Lets hope that when we really get into this thing 
 we start to see some better function. Flash range tests will happen sometime 
 after 4 AM tomorrow morning then off to the field for a few test pictures 
 and videos if we can get the deer to hang around long enough.
  
 06-26-2008 update:  Spent a lot of time re doing the unofficial 
 trigger time tests. With the better than 1 minute delay time, it took a 
 couple of hours to do a bunch of these to get a feel of what the earlier 
 tests had indicated. The tests revealed that the better tests were at 
 4.75 seconds and the slower tests were at 5.25 seconds. A good portion 
 of the tests were a solid 5 seconds. The flash range tests showed that 
 it is good out past 40 feet. This was a very warm morning at 72 degrees 
 (cam showed 78 degrees) and the sensing distance was past 25 feet. This 
 cam was endorsed by Jim Shockey and if we had a fast Eddie cam we would 
 have to call this camera the slow Jimmy cam. Previous WD series cams had 
 trigger times of 2 seconds. Something has happened this year for having 
 a 3 second slide in performance. Off to the woods to try to get some 
 sample pictures and Movies.
  
 06-29-2008 update:  Well it has been confirmed that the 
 trigger time is near 5 seconds which makes it a full 2 seconds 
 slower than the 2008 I-40 Moultrie which slipped a second and a half 
 this year to 3 second trigger time. Because of this we are just 
 going to try to grab a few test pictures and videos and call it 
 quits on this cam. It is a shame because we had high hopes and we 
 were looking forward to a long range battery test using the panel 
 setup with this cam. It is loaded with good features which now 
 become void because of the lousy trigger time. We have scheduled a 
 number of the 08 Stealth cams for testing and we will now have to 
 make the trigger time test the first thing out of the box before we 
 start the review. It makes me think that who ever the suppliers are 
 for these good companies feed them good cams to start with and then 
 things seem to slip down hill unless someone is monitoring the 
 cameras performance on a continuous basis. This is the third company 
 this year that has experienced this. Pre production verses post 
 production seems to be two different cameras. We had reports early 
 on that some from the first owners of the Sniper cameras that found 
 the trigger time was somewhere between one and two seconds. This is 
 the reason we were so hot to get our hands on this cam to test. This 
 has been a big let down for us because we are very much fans of all 
 the WD series of cams.

 07-01-2008 update:  Had the cam on the hill and was able 
 to gather some pictures in the 6.0 MP mode and like its little 
 brother the I-450 it takes some very good pictures. The day time 
 pictures are very natural in color and the night time examples with 
 flash proved to be very good also. One puzzling things was that none 
 of the pictures had any of the little critters in them and there 
 were a couple of the night pictures that had a rabbit but there was 
 also a deer in the background. Most every camera that we have tested 
 in that very same area had an overwhelming amount of tree rat 
 pictures of them stealing the corn. The day temperatures are high 
 but other cameras under the same conditions did manage to see the 
 smaller animals. We moved on to the movie mode and as soon as that 
 is finished we will try to do the rest of the rez settings prior to 
 retiring this cam.

We captured a deer video in good day light and the 320X240 rating 
 sure leaves a bit to be desired. There is a definite lack of clarity 
 with this cam in the movie mode. Where this cam shines is when it is 
 in still picture mode and then there is some good picture quality. 
 Having an approximate 9.5 frame rate is plenty to make the movies to 
 appear fluid. The graininess is what destroys the picture quality. 
 There was a slight tendency to slip a little toward the whiteout on 
 a very few pictures but with the light conditions in our testing 
 area this cam did very good. So far I think we only had a couple of 
 pictures that were a little washed out.
  
 07-02-2008 update:  Resetting to 
 3 MP setting and we did not get any pictures on the card. All 
 went to internal memory. We changed to a different card and then 
 it again started to take pictures to the card. The morning 
 transition times showed an extreme amount of whiteout pictures ( see 
 examples ) until it got very bright outside then it took 
 color pictures. The change from the higher MP ratting to the 
 three MP setting showed a definite quality drop in picture the 
 quality. In order to get good sharp and somewhat clear daytime 
 pictures this camera likes to have a good amount of light. Under 
 the forest canopy with dappled light this cam has a hard time. 
 To my surprise I picked up an I 540 IR today and when I was 
 going through the specifications and features the much cheaper 
 cam appeared to have a much better selection, plus it would take 
 night time videos. The lack of color in the night pictures just 
 doesnt seem to bother most folks who choose the red flash over 
 the white flash cameras. We see the trend to move toward more 
 folks liking cams that take the day/night videos. Well Jimmy 
 what do we do now?

 07-06-2008 update:  This cam has ran 12 days on a 
 new set of energizers and taken 1124 pictures and 3 movies and 
 the battery low lamp is on. This cam is looking very much like 
 the I-450 with its need for power. The external setup with panel 
 will probably be the only way to go with this cam. Well it is 
 time to say adios Jimmy and we must go on to the next 
 challenge. 
 
 09-04-2008 update:  After going through all the 
 settings and found the performance far less then its $100 little 
 brother the I-590 we have decided to conclude this review. 
   
 
 Trigger time without flash
 
with flash
 

  
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 6MP (2784x2088)
 
   3MP (2048x1536)
 
 
 Whiteouts 
 during transition hours: 
 1.3MP (1280x1024)
 
 
 
 Movie Sample
 
  
 
  
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 EPIC
 
 http://www.stealthcam.net 

 

 Camo version with hat mount clip 
 
 Stealth Cam 
 Epic review 06-25-2008           Camera Purchased from TrailCamPro.Com 

 Early in 08 the folks at Stealth let us know about this new device. 
 At that time Anthony had a ski trip planned out west. I tried to acquire one 
 for that trip but it has been a long wait and June is about over and it has 
 arrived. Trying to figure an angle how we could fit this device into the 
 scouting camera house is going to be a little hard. There is no motion 
 sensor, there is no flash, and there is no room for 6 C cells in the battery 
 compartment. Instead this is a tiny D cell battery sized camera that is 
 powered by two AAA cells and has a slot for a 4 gig SD card, and a USB 
 socket. This is all packed into a 3 inch long cylinder. Across the bottom is 
 a dove tail plate to match a series of different holders to connect to 
 handlebars and such. The specifications of the cam are a 2 MP image sensor 
 that can be boosted up through interpolation from VGA, 3.0 MP and on top is 
 the 5 MP rating. This cam can be set for single picture to 9 shot burst 
 mode. In the movie mode you can select 320X240 and 640X480. Movie mode is at 
 30 frames per second which is nice. The down side is the basic image sensor. 
 The potential for this type of camera is immense. From the deer stand and on 
 board on any type of transportation is where this cam should be used. The 
 still camera mode is just that. Care must be taken to ensure that you 
 do not move during the shutter time because it will blur every picture. My 
 initial tests in the still mode resulted in no pictures being without a 
 degree of blur. This tells me that when mounted on a gun or bow it would 
 probably have a lack of definition. Change over to movie mode and now you 
 have something that works fairly well as long as there is adequate light. 
 From the deer stand during early morning hours would be a stretch to get 
 usable pictures. Using this cam in your boat, bike, ATV, horse back, back 
 pack, or even hook it to your pet, the potential is enormous as long is the 
 movie mode is selected. To use this cam in still mode you must trigger it by 
 hitting a button. This makes its use limited in the still function because 
 in order to capture the action you would have to hit the trigger of the cam 
 and do what ever you wish to capture. From the deer stand this would work 
 when explaining what you did not want to shoot. I can only see where the 
 video mode is where this device will shine. During bad weather there is a 
 plastic weather proof case that can be used to protect the camera. This 
 enclosure has rubber buttons so you can operate the camera from the outside 
 without fearing the device getting wet. Putting this cam to work this 
 afternoon in the bright sun showed me that the picture quality on high rez is still limited. There seems to be a limit 
 as to how far interpolation can be pushed. It is still going to be fun to 
 play with at $170 cost and being able to get a couple of hundred minutes of 
 video on one 4 gig card will be nice for in house use. The sensing tests 
 will depend on how hot the operator is when he is operating. We are going to 
 do some basic tests during the next few days to see just what trouble we can 
 get into with this device. 
 
 06-28-2008 update:  Now that I have had some time with this 
 device I have came to one main conclusion. This cam does not have a very 
 good light gathering ability. Early evening and late morning when 
 visibility with the human eye is good this cam cannot see the target. 
 Day time and good light it really works well. The good frame rate and 
 color with sound makes it a pleasure to use. The low grade image 
 processor still leaves a lot to be desired as far as picture quality is 
 concerned. The video quality is good but far from being great. There is 
 a lack of contrast and definition. I am being pretty critical on this 
 because having good detail is very important in the scouting camera 
 business and this is not a scouting camera. For a record of a white 
 water experience or a trail ride on your cycle where detail would be 
 nice but is not needed this cam works very well. Today we are headed to 
 the country to check the cams and this will be going along with us and 
 it will get a ride on an ATV. I am going to have to get a little 
 creative in order to develop more things that will give this little cam 
 more jobs to do. This morning I began taking movies at 4AM and am going 
 to keep it up until I start to get enough light to be able to read the 
 videos on my computer. It is now just about 0630 and I can easily see 
 outside and walk around but this cam just shows a spec of light here and 
 there but no pictures of the silhouettes I was trying to capture. The 
 trip checking cams resulted in a few short clips on the ATV while 
 checking the cams. You can see just how the color is and when going off 
 into the shade how it slides down hill a little. The automatic cutoff 
 was a bit of a problem and caused a loss of some pretty good footage. 
 Back to my drawing board to gather some ideas for this little cam. 
 

  
 
 Whats in the box 
 
 Movie Samples
 
At 6:09am (low light condition) 
 

Ay 6:39am (low light condition) 
 

 The following movie samples utilize the hat 
 mounting clip pictured below: 
 

 Riding the 4-wheeler and checkin some 
 cameras: 
 
 
  
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-I540IR 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 

  
 Stealth 
 Cam STC-I540IR camera 07-03-2008 

 At $119 to $129 this cam is in the 
 neighborhood of our trusty old D-40 Moultrie. The outdoor forums started to 
 ring with a lot of noise about this camera. This definitely is not Stealths 
 signature cam but at first glance it appears to function better. It is a 
 full second faster on trigger than the slow Jimmy cam (Sniper) and is 
 quite a few dollars cheaper and does night movies. A 4 second trigger time 
 is just not acceptable any more but at the price and when the user has 
 feeders and salt licks this cam should work very well. It would also be a 
 nice cam to put on a scrape. One very troubling function of this can is just 
 prior to the IR going off when the cam is triggered it sounds like you just 
 dropped a pallet of bricks. A very loud clunk that even with my shell 
 shocked old ears could hear at 40 feet. We bad mouthed the I 40 for having a 3 second trigger time this year but that was 
 mainly because it gained a good reputation last year and now this year the 
 trigger time has slipped a full second and a half and it takes black and 
 white pictures long into the morning when it should have switched to color. 
 This cam in the catalog appeared to be in the same case as the old AD-3 but 
 this case is much flatter. The case is about ten inches tall and seven 
 inches wide with a thickness of about three inches. The case is flat black 
 and there are two pretty good latches to secure the door. There is a full 
 gasket in the door all the way around except for a small weep hole at the 
 very bottom. The front of the camera has the main lens at the top center and 
 it is nicely counter sunk so the rain should not hit the glass. Below that 
 is the IR array with 36 emitters. The picture count window is just above the 
 array and the low battery and test LEDs are next to that window. They are 
 still also holding with the same PIR sensor that has been used on all 
 previous models and we think in most cases has worked great. At the bottom 
 are the external battery port and the tripod socket 1/4X20 insert. As you 
 open the door there is the TV out and USB socket next to the SD card slot. 
 Then with the door all the way open there is a LCD screen for programming 
 and the right of that is the associated buttons. This is all pretty well 
 standard and programming is simple and easy. Below that is the off on test 
 switch and just to the right is the adjustable sensitivity slide switch. 
 This is a nice feature that Stealth has included on all the new stuff so 
 far. This is a five MP camera (both day/night) with the low setting being 
 two MP. This means that it is a two MP sensor interpolated to 5 to gain the 
 top number. There is also three quality settings 
 which is also a nice feature. The delay period is from one minute to sixty 
 minutes. The standard 9 burst is also being used in this cam where you need 
 a string of pictures to catch that buck following the do into the target 
 area. The picture ID across the bottom has the date time, moon phase, and 
 temperature. Like most cameras there is an internal memory for those who 
 choose to use the cam without a card. Here is the really nice feature that 
 drew my attention to this camera. It will record from 10 to 120 seconds of 
 video at 10 fps at 640X480. If this is 
 found to work well then I believe that this cam has found its nitch . The maximum SD card size is 2 gig so as long as the batteries hold this cam 
 could be left out a good long time. Judging from the specifications so far 
 and excluding the severe filter clunk I think that I would prefer this cam 
 over the slow Jimmy Sniper cam. With it all programmed up and the 
 unofficial trigger time clock set up I will get on with the testing. The 
 flash range testing will happen around 4 AM tomorrow morning.

 07-04-2008 update:  The flash range tests were done this morning 
 around 4 AM and I paid close attention to see if the filter clunk was loud 
 enough to wake up any of the neighbors. We had some fireworks in the area 
 last night so I think that they had settled in and the noise did not bother 
 them. The flash is very good past 40 feet. The sensing range at 72 degrees 
 was at 30 feet and the picture quality of the IR during this test was very 
 acceptable. We did a side by side analysis of this cams pictures with the 
 Moultrie I 40 and I 60s pictures and feel that the picture quality of this 
 cam is equal to the I 40 but not as good as the I 60s pictures. After 
 working with several cams that had a very short delay period, I felt a 
 little aggravated by having to wait through the delay period in order to 
 trigger the next test. One minute delay is a long time, but having a cam 
 that can be set to burst mode would get around this when having the next few 
 pictures taken in rapid succession is needed. With the degree of noise by 
 the filter, folks should not have any problem getting the animals to look at 
 the camera during the shutter period. I will get this cam to the hill for 
 some sample pictures and movies. We are currently only testing one white 
 flash cam so we can run this cam in the same area without having a conflict 
 of flashes. Next week we have more IR cameras coming in so there is a need 
 to try to get as much done on this cam as we can.

 07-04-2008 update : Trigger Time - The official trigger time is 
 now 4.5 seconds and some times we&apos;ve seen close to 5 seconds.  Daytime 
 without flash turned out to be a second shorter at 3.5 seconds.

 07-06-2008 update:  We took some time to observe the deer 
 reaction to the noise clunk being given off by this camera. The slow trigger 
 did not allow us to actually see the reaction of the deer in the pictures. 
 By carefully approaching the feeder area we were able to actually see the 
 camera shutter and watch the animals reaction. Each and every time the deer 
 would jump and move off a ways and turn and look at the camera. This time of 
 year and on into early scouting time the temperatures will require to have 
 this cam placed in the 20 to 25 foot range from the target area. In this 
 case this cam would probably run off some pretty good bucks that are a 
 little on the wary side. Later in the year when the daytime temperatures are 
 dropping into the 40 and 50s then this cam could be moved out away from the 
 target area to the point where maybe the noise to the animals would not be 
 so noticeable. The two areas that the company should be looking at are the 
 trigger time and this filter noise clunk. If those two areas were addressed 
 this camera with its features and acceptable pictures would be one hell of a 
 camera for the price. We are now going to see just how good the movie mode 
 is before we conclude this review.

 07-09-2008 update:  We moved through all the rez settings and 
 found the picture quality for this camera is above average. The low rez 
 pictures still were presentable and above the quality of some cameras high 
 setting. Even with the very terrible trigger time we found that the movie 
 (video) mode is something to talk about. This camera does a very good job at 
 this. It is not quite up the Scoutguard 550s quality but for a camera that 
 cost just over a hundred dollars it does a good job. The wide sensing area 
 and being properly placed this camera with a little luck could capture some 
 great footage when the opportunity is presented. Now that we have found the 
 slot that we can fit this camera we do have a job for it and it is going to 
 be a keeper. We have some great cameras that do a better job in the movie 
 mode but none in this price range having the degree of nighttime 
 illumination that is required to reach on out there. 

 
 
 
 Trigger time without flash 3.5+ seconds
 
with flash 4.5 - 5 seconds
 

  
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 5MP (2560x1920)
 
 
 
 3MP (1600x1200) 
 
  Movie Sample (high)
 Sample1 
 Sample2 
 Sample3 
 Sample4 
 Sample5 
 
  
  
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-I430IR 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 

  
 Stealth Cam STC-I430IR IR (red flash) 
 (WD-4IR) flash camera review 07-18-2008

 Camera Purchased from TrailCamPro.Com 

 After a bad start with all the Stealth cams 
 tested so far this year I put this camera on the trigger time bench first 
 and proceeded to see just where the trigger time is set. The unofficial 
 trigger time I got was just over four seconds. The white flash Sniper was a 
 little worse and the I-540IR came in about the same. I just finished putting 
 new Energizers in my old WD-2IR and was getting ready to take it back out. 
 This has been one of my main work horses in security. Its trigger time is a 
 couple seconds faster and is a couple years older also. I cannot figure out 
 what has happened with Stealth this year. Things have slowed down in their electronics.The I-430 comes in the standard green WD case with the good latches and seal. There are 
 still a couple of the small weep holes at the bottom of the case where if 
 you are not careful you could have some ant visitors. Weather is not a 
 problem though. The front of the case has the standard 27 emitter IR array 
 as used on other models. Below there is the LCD display, low battery 
 indicator and test indicator. The same wide angle PIT sensor is also used as 
 with all other models. Inside everything is the same as other WD models with 
 a black and white LCD display for programming and below is a set of switches 
 that include the on/off, up, down, confirm, and test buttons. Along the side 
 is the TV out and SD card slot along with the USB connector. This is a 
 single lens camera so there is a filter that moves for the IR operation. 
 This cam has only a slight thud when the filter moves and is not nearly as 
 loud as that of the I-540. At the bottom of the case is the 1/4X20 threaded 
 hole for tripod or tree screw mounting. The external 12 volt jack is next to 
 this threaded hole. The slow trigger is a real bummer but knowing this and 
 knowing how to position the camera because of this will still allow this 
 camera to be somewhat effective for scouting. This will be mainly on 
 feeders, crossings, and other areas where the target animal will be in front 
 of the camera for a number of seconds. I was told by one of the suppliers 
 that he regularly has visitors come by and purchase cameras to ship back 
 overseas to reverse engineer. I dont think they have asked for a single 
 Stealth yet this year. This camera comes with a 1.3 MP image sensor that 
 does color day and IR night pictures. This 1.3 is interpolated to 4 MP on 
 the top side. 

 Resolution settings are 0.3, 1.3, and 4.0 for 
 all the still captures and video is 320X240 at 10 fps. There is no fancy 
 stuff on the picture stamping which is just 
 time/date, moon phase and temperature. Missing is the adjustable sensing 
 knob found on the slow Jimmy cam. A quick test at high rez daytime pictures of some of the bosss flowers showed good color 
 contrast and acceptable pictures. The flash range tests went very well and 
 were out past 40 feet. The sensing was around 30 feet at 71 degrees this 
 morning. This was one of the cams that I had tests scheduled for along with 
 a Bushnell. This camera just works great compared to the other camera. The 
 low rez pictures with this camera are much 
 better than the high rez pictures of the 
 Bushnell. I just wish that Stealth had not played around with the trigger 
 times because if it was back to that 2 second area this would be one hell of 
 a good camera. It is in the box with the others to head for the hill for the 
 series of test sample pictures.

 07-24-2008 update : Well bad 
 news, we will have to pick through the hundred or so whiteout pictures in 
 order to find enough pictures for sample pictures. This is like looking at 
 the 450 all over again. We will try one more time after we replace the dead 
 batteries and see if by chance we can get enough good pictures to show. In 
 the scouting camera business, putting a camera on a tree under the canopy is 
 pretty standard as long as you maintain the orientation. This camera is more 
 like a full sun camera that should be dedicated to areas of bright sun and 
 not under a tree in the shade. One more quick try to catch some pictures and 
 if that fails we are going to have to pull this review. 
 
 
 Trigger time without flash 4.5 seconds
 
 
with flash 4.5 seconds
 

  
 Flash Tests Sample Photos 4MP (2304x1728)
 
 
 
 
  Low Res (640x480) 9 shot burst mode 
 
 


 
 
 
  Movie Samples
 note: if these do not play, right click and 
 choose&quot;save target as&quot;to your computer and then open those. 
 
 
  
  
 
 STEALTH CAM 

 STC-I590 

 http://www.stealthcam.net 

 
  
 Stealth Cam STC-I590 white flash 5MP digital 
 camera review 08-30-2008 

 They call this their digital video scout camera. What I see 
 that is different is the choice of 10 to 180 seconds when the video mode is 
 selected. This camera seems to have some of the same internal parts as some 
 of other cameras like the Moultrie D-40 and GS-200. The physical description 
 is the same as the Stealth I-540IR but where the IR array was located there 
 is a very nice white flash unit. It is advertised to be good to 90 feet and 
 if it is like one of the WD series cameras that I previously tested, it will 
 wipe out your optic nerve if you are to close. Refer to the I-540 IR review 
 for all the case and programming information because this cam shares all the 
 same data except the IR cameras will do the night time movies and this cam 
 will only do still shots at night up to the programmable 9 burst mode. The 2 
 mega-pixel image sensor is interpolated to 5 MP when selected in the 
 programming. The low setting is the 2MP and will probably be where we will 
 do the most of our testing but we will still show sample pictures at the 
 higher setting. There is still the normal 32 MB internal memory and USB and 
 TV out. Cam can be set up in the single capture with 1 minute delay or the 9 
 burst with minimum delay. Video mode is adjustable from 10 to 180 seconds 
 daytime only movies. The frame rate is 30 fps at the 640X480 resolution 
 fixed setting. Date/time is printed of the first frame of each video. As 
 with most cameras the exposure and white balance are automatic and not 
 adjustable. Flash on/off is selectable which is mandatory when using a 
 camera in some of the security situations. Pictures have a information strip showing the military time, moon phase, date, and 
 temperature. Stoked up with 8 new energizer batteries and the cover back on 
 I proceeded to try to see where the trigger times were going to fall. The 
 unofficial times were about 41/2 seconds average for a 20 series test. This 
 is pretty sorry and the only thing that will probably save this cam from 
 becoming a 100 yard target will be if it gives us some very good pictures 
 and the wide angle PIR sensor is like that of the I-540IR and will see the 
 animals coming in the peripheral giving the camera plenty of time to get 
 ready to trigger. The I -540IR almost matched some 
 pretty fast cameras when they both were looking at the same area. We will 
 see if our tests show this but right now it is not looking good. Sharing the 
 same case and having some of the same features does not say that what is in 
 the inside will work the same. The 540IR had a Boly camera in it and this cam has a Zoran Coach camera in it. PIR sensors should be 
 the same, but there again is an area that I am going to be looking strong 
 at. The Trail cam market needs a very good white flash camera since Cudde fell on its face with the Capture and 
 Bushnell lost its good trigger time. This leaves the trusty Moultrie D-40 to 
 take up the space. Moultrie M series has the great battery life but the 08 
 cams have a sorry trigger which has been leaving its users with lots of 
 empty pictures. Lets hope that this cam will 
 perform at least as good or not better than the more expensive Moultries. 
 Flash range tests in the morning then off to the hill for sample 
 movie/pictures. 
 08-31-2008 
 update : The flash range testing went off real easy this morning 
 and it was easy to see that their advertised 90 feet may be correct. I could 
 see things at 50 feet real clear when the camera would flash. I was pretty 
 surprised as to the picture quality. The pictures in the flash on the flash 
 range were not great but pretty good. The sensing distance was 30 feet and 
 the thermometer said 71 degrees this morning. It appears that this camera 
 may very well be equal to the 540IR when it comes to sensing. I will have to 
 see the daytime color before I make any final judgment on the full picture 
 quality. As soon as the sun comes up I will test that and get this cam off 
 to Anthony to put it on the hill. We now have a deep woods setup for 50 foot 
 flash range tests where it is open woods and not have the reflection of the 
 building. We will still do the same flash range tests but just adding one 
 more test to show open woods flash range at 50 feet. For those cameras that 
 are adjusting white balance all the time this will give a better idea of 
 just how good the flash is. 
 09-02-2008 update : Since we have had our hands on this cam we 
 have gained a small degree of respect. This is very strange. Our official 
 trigger times were ranging from a half second to five seconds. Sometimes the 
 camera will see our reflection off the clock and trigger at the wrong time 
 so on occasion we have to turn the clock a little sideways so this does not 
 happen. This camera was still doing the same thing. We finally figured out 
 that this camera has a very wide peripheral range and when we would get up 
 close to the side of the camera it would see us every time. We had to remain 
 in back of the camera for it not to see us. The times started to fall into a 
 pattern of around 5 seconds for both flash and non flash pictures. Well the 
 test will be whether or not it is sensing better than it is seeing. We 
 figure with this super sensing that it should be somewhat like the 540 IR 
 and still capture good pictures. It has been placed in a situation now to 
 test this and if successful we will stick this cam on the list of keepers. 
 We are also looking at a possible battery issue and if we can get the camera 
 to repeat the first case then we will report that. The pictures are pretty 
 impressive for a hundred dollar camera.   
 09-03-2008 update : Keeper?  YES Two 
 days on the hill and a ton of pictures both day night and high and low rez. 
 All pictures are very sharp and clear and with very good color. The night 
 time flash burns down trees at 65 feet, yet it does not seem to be over 
 powering on close animals. This setup was exactly the same as we had done on 
 the 08 Moultrie I series cameras. Both the Moultries had gazillion whiteout 
 and black out pictures during the transaction, then turn to good color mid 
 day. This camera has always had a critter of some kind in every picture. 
 There have not been any whiteout or blackout pictures taken so far. We had 
 several pictures of just part of the animal, but it was the head and not the 
 tail end we captured. The peripheral vision of the sensor is extreme and it 
 is a little concerning that maybe it might see a little out of view of the 
 camera. I can tell you for a 5 second trigger camera it sure does not miss 
 much that is going around the camera. That would not be the case if the 
 animal was at a full run rather than just walking in. This is one white 
 flash $100 camera that should do a fair job in most folks scouting needs. No 
 word on battery life yet but it looks promising and we will report as soon 
 as the data is gathered. We will gather some quick flicks (videos) and then 
 take it to the field after we get the deep woods flash testing done. 
 

 09-17-2008 update : We stuck this bugger in video mode and 
 began to capture some pretty good daytime footage. Then night came along 
 and not a thing. We did not get the stills that the company said we are 
 supposed to be getting. Yanked the batteries and gave it a new tank of 
 gas and put it back out. This time we did get some pretty impressive 
 night time color still pictures. We do like this camera very much once 
 we figure out some of the glitches that low battery will cause. We still 
 have this cam in the keeper list. 
  
 Trigger Tests 
without flash 4.5 seconds
 
with flash 5.5 seconds
 Flash Range
 Samples High Res 5MP
 
 
 
 
 Low Res
 
 
   Movie Sample
 
 
  
 

 

 
 Copyright 2005, 2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010 Chasingame.com 
Your Source for scouting camera reviews, performance ratings, sample photos and movies, performance and stress testing. 

 Please read our disclaimer: 
 As an independent consumer review site our goal is to 
 provide as accurately as possible, our experiences with the 
 cameras and equipment we test. Our findings are based 
 solely on the units we test as are the results. Our statements reflect only our opinions unless stated 
 otherwise. We take pride in being accurate and make 
 every attempt to communicate with manufacturers about our 
 findings. We do not sell cameras, accept kickbacks, or 
 own stock in any camera manufacturers.
Thank you for visiting Chasingame.com.
	</body>
</document>
