<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007156" url="http://thelivelykitchen.com/2012/04/12/vegan-carrot-raisin-pineapple-salad/" time="2012-07-13-00:08" support="2" score="0.0034875419291582723" bingtitle="Vegan Carrot Raisin Pineapple Salad « The Lively Kitchen" webtitle="Vegan Carrot Raisin Pineapple SaladThe Lively Kitchen">
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>... carrots (the finer the better – I used my food ... But, it’s clearly a fast food restaurant, so don’t set the ... have really clean bathrooms and changing tables.</description>
	<body>
		My kitchen may not always be clean, but it is always lively. 
Search
 The Lively Kitchen 
 About Links Contact Me Recipes 
 
Vegan Carrot Raisin Pineapple Salad
 12 Apr 
 It’s hard to do the mom circuit in the Texas suburbs without ending up at Chick Fil A at least once.  The chain is kid friendly, clean and has top-notch customer service.  And play areas (complete with hand sanitizer).  Actually, the husband I had our first meal together (a year and half before we actually started dating) at Chick-Fil-A about 15 years ago, so I’m a little partial to the chain.  Plus I ate many a chicken-biscuits for breakfast in high school before dance team practice.  Breakfast of champions, don’t you know? {insert sarcasm font} 

It’s not remotely a vegetarian restaurant, so I am usually stuck with sides for a meal these days.  I tend to order a side salad and a small carrot-raisin-salad.  And maybe fries if I’m feeling naughty–they do have delicious waffle fries.  The side salad is standard, but the carrot raisin salad is really good.  The carrot juice/dressing liquid that forms at the bottom of the bowl is a nasty bugger potent stain to get out of your clothes if you happen to spill the container ( which I do far too often, sometimes my kid’s fault, usually mine) , but the salad is refreshing and tasty.

Last week I decided to re-create the carrot raisin salad and, after googling a few versions of the Chick-Fil-A recipe and learning it contained mayo, veganizing it.  It worked!

 

 Vegan Carrot Raisin Pineapple Salad 

This salad is sweet, crunchy and refreshing.  It comes together quickly and keeps really well for 3-4 days in the fridge.

 
 Ingredients: 
 2 c shredded carrots (the finer the better–I used my food processor) 1/3 c raisins 2 tsp lemon juice 2 Tbsp vegan mayo–I like the soy-free veganaise. Could also use regular non-vegan mayo 3/4 c diced pineapple 2 Tbsp pineapple juice 1/2 tsp salt 

 Directions: 

1. Add all ingredients and mix until well combined.  Let sit in the fridge for a couple of hours for flavors to meld.
 
Share this:
 
 Facebook Print Pinterest 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Tags: carrots , salad 
 
 Comments 4 Comments Categories Recipes , Salad 
 ← Dusting Off The Ol’ Keyboard Photo Friday–good reads → 
4 Responses to“Vegan Carrot Raisin Pineapple Salad”

 Laura April 12, 2012 at 7:32 am # 
That sounds really good! I like the pineapple addition. I’ve actually never eaten at a CFA, can you believe it?!
 Reply 
 Michelle {The Lively Kitchen} April 12, 2012 at 8:59 am # 
I’d be surprised if you didn’t end up there with a playdate in the next few years. But, it’s clearly a fast food restaurant, so don’t set the bar too high. they are a great place to stop on Texas road trips, as they have really clean bathrooms and changing tables.

Michelle

Sent from my iPhone
 Reply 
 Emily Dingmann (@nutritionisteat) April 12, 2012 at 8:34 am # 
I don’t think my husband has ever been to Chick-Fil-A but people just rave about it! I’ve only had it because they served a limited menu at the U of M Union…I don’t remember a carrot salad though! It sounds great!
 Reply 
 
Trackbacks/Pingbacks

 Broccoli–Carrot–Raisin Salad«The Lively Kitchen - July 10, 2012 
[...] you like this recipe, you would probably like this carrot raisin pineapple salad [...]
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
Welcome to The Lively Kitchen!

 
I&apos;m Michelle, a stay at home mama to two very active kids and wife to one very patient man. I&apos;m a vegetarian raising mostly vegetarian kids. In my pre-housewife days I was a corporate food scientist and I still love to create food. Glad you stopped by!
 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 102 other followers

 

 
 
I’ve finally caved in….
 
The Lively Kitchen on Facebook
 The Lively Kitchen 
 
 Promote Your Page Too 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 
Search
 
Tags
 almonds apple avocado bananas beans carrots chickpeas chocolate cilantro cleanse coconut collard greens cookbook love Cooked Daily Eats Deep Thoughts dehydrator dessert feeding kids giveaway granola Greenling Green Smoothie husband friendly iPhone blogging kale kid friendly kombucha life linky love oatmeal pizza quinoa recipe Repeater Recipes Restaurant Review salad school lunches smoothies soup spinach Vitamix walt disney world workouts wrap 
 
 
 April 2012 M T W T F S S «Mar   May»   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30   
   
Top Posts&amp;Pages

 What I Ate on a Quiet Tuesday Broccoli - Carrot - Raisin Salad Natural Rainbow Smoothies - Daily Buzz Moms 9x9 Recipes Raw Carrot Avocado Soup 
 
Talk To Me

 Amy-Nutrition by Nat… on What I Ate on a Quiet Tue… Candy @ Healthy in C… on What I Ate on a Quiet Tue… Amber Shea @Almost V… on What I Ate on a Quiet Tue… Laura @ Mommy Run Fa… on What I Ate on a Quiet Tue… moderngirlnutrition on What I Ate on a Quiet Tue… 
 Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Bueno by WooThemes . Follow 
 Follow“The Lively Kitchen” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 102 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
