<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007825" url="http://www.mattbodnar.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:47" support="14" score="0.014980846418925614" bingtitle="Matt Bodnar" webtitle="Matt Bodnar">
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001253" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000877" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000031" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000635" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000656" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>Picking one great idea and going all ... like it was straight out of a fast food restaurant ... Near the counter or on an adjacent wall; Above the condiment station (Four Barrel ...</description>
	<body>
		Matt Bodnar Restaurants, Social Media, Entrepreneurship, Technology 
 Subscribe via RSS 
 Home Bio Book 
 19 Jun/12 0 
 Aspen Food&amp;Wine Classic–Day Two 

 
 This is the second part of my recap of Aspen Food&amp;Wine – read part one here . 
 

After a fantastic day one, the second day (and a half) of the “Classic” were packed with interesting insights, delicious wines, and lots of fun.

 Wisdom 

The Fresh crew got up bright and early to hit the continental breakfast at the Jerome Hotel (delicious granola by the way) and see the day’s first Trade Talk – “Homegrown: Sowing the Seeds for the Future” – a candid look at the local food movement featuring John Besh, Michel Nischan, Niki Leondakis, and southern favorite Sean Brock. Here are a few of my favorite quotes from the session. See the full video here .

 
 
&quot;Let&apos;s start thinking about dirt - let dirt be the center of the conversation.&quot; - Sean Brock

“Local food creates a sense of place, where you are, where you&apos;re from, and where you&apos;re going.&quot; - Michel

&quot;People are hungry for stories, people are hungry for connections... stories taste good, and connections taste good.&quot; - Sean Brock

&quot;We are sowing the seeds of responsibility for the future.&quot; - John Besh

“Local food helps chefs connect with the seasons.” - Niki

“Respect of the land is the trust form of inspiration.” - Sean Brock

“Local food inspires everyone at the restaurant.” -Niki

&quot;Before World War 2 people in Chicago and New York met their own needs twelve months a year, combined with modern technology there is even more potential to do the same&quot; - Rick Bayless (hiding in the audience)

&quot;Start small with local production, and then learn to scale it” - Sean Brock

“Everyone is always really excited about growing their own food… then the weeds come.” - Sean Brock

&quot;You can taste the intentions….&quot; - Michel

&quot;… and intentions taste good.&quot; - Sean Brock

&quot;Support people making the right decisions no matter where you are, we have to respect the dirt.&quot; - Sean Brock

&quot;Community canaries can help solve many local sustainability issues.&quot; - Sean Brock

&quot;Freezing local food picked when ripe and in season is better than shipping unripe blueberries sprayed with chemicals from 3000 miles away.&quot; Michel
 
The second Trade Talk on day two was “Restaurant Reset: Small Changes, Big Payoff” – an examination of what it takes to be a successful restaurant operator featuring Tom Colicchio, Anita Lo, John T. Bettin, and Grant Achatz. Catch the full video here , below are some of the highlights.
 
&quot;Focus first on every touchpoint that comes into contact with the guest.&quot; – John T. Bettin

&quot;Don&apos;t come to the table with a problem, come with a solution&quot; - Tom C.

&quot;Check your ego at the door&quot; - Tom C.

“The key to staying relevant is having a real connection with your guest.&quot; John Bettin

&quot;Every so often, do something outrageous to keep yourself in the conversation.&quot; John Bettin

&quot;Training and technology are the two most important things to invest in.&quot; Tom C.

&quot;Opening a new restaurant is like a drug.&quot; Tom C.

“The kiss of death is when a customer says ‘the food was fine.’” - John Bettin

&quot;Get information from your customers and your wait staff - they are on the front lines&quot; - Tom C.

“Regulars are your life blood.” - Tom C.
 
 Wine 

 

When we weren’t busy with industry Trade Talks, we also hit two awesome wine tastings. Saturday afternoon we attended a tasting lead by Danny Meyer titled “Swill for the Grill” – a tasting focused on what wines to pair with grilled meats (in the spirit of summer). The tasting started by giving everyone a 6x6 grid with six different wines and six different proteins, the proteins provided by legendary NYC meat purveyor “The Magician of Meat” Pat LaFrieda and grilled by Maialino executive chef Nick Anderer.

The great part about this tasting was that they encouraged everyone to try unique pairings and let your own palate decide what was best (of course – everyone in our group had wildly different preferences). Also, the &quot;scoring system&quot; included smiley faces.

 

A few fun quotes from the tasting.
 
&quot;There are no rules, wine tasting is about your taste.&quot; - Danny Meyer

&quot;Salt, pepper, and smoke - that&apos;s it.&quot; Nick Anderer

&quot;Don&apos;t be afraid of a little char&quot; - Nick Anderer
 
Sunday morning we also attended a wonderful tasting titled “Taste Like a Star Sommelier: an Intro to Blind Tasting.” The panel was led by Richard Betts, master sommelier and wine director at the Little Nell in Aspen and legendary sommelier Rajat Parr along with two other sommeliers. The tasting featured seven unlabeled wines and invited everyone to taste them in order and determine what type of wine it was.

 

While watching the panel of sommeliers absolutely crush every guess (literally within a mile or two of the actual vineyard almost every time) was astounding, the great part was learning a little more about how to taste wine and taking a few guesses myself at what I was drinking. The real gem of the tasting, however, was the amazing “map to your desires” as Betts called it – a guide for how to think about any wine that you taste.

 A few great quotes from the tasting. 
 
&quot;Wine is about fun, pleasure, and intellectual value&quot; - Richard Betts

&quot;There is no such thing as wine speak.&quot; – Richard Betts

“Your own pallet is like your own thumb print - you&apos;re always right” – Richard Betts
 
 Odds&amp;Ends 

Last but not least, a few more delicious wines I had over the weekend (remember I was focused primarily on Pinot Noir).

 Monterey Pinot Noir - Carmel Road 

 Maggy Hawk &quot;Alfred&quot; 

 Founders Reserve - ZD Wine 

 

And, I feel like Merlot really gets a lot of flack (thanks Sideways...) but seriously... we sampled some Shafer Merlot at &quot;Swill for the Grill&quot; and it was delicious .

 

Also, wanted to share this pic of my swag bag – especially excited about the Vinturi aerator .

 

Stay tuned on Twitter to follow my adventures.
 Tagged as: aspen , aspen food and wine , food and wine , local food aspen classic , wine No Comments 16 Jun/12 0 
 Aspen Food&amp;Wine Classic–Day One 

 

After the Big Apple BBQ last weekend (Great recap here ) – the Fresh Hospitality team didn’t skip a beat. We flew out of Nashville Thursday AM bound for the Aspen Food&amp;Wine Classic. This was my very first “Classic” as they call it – and I wanted to share a few thoughts, tips, insights and pics from day one.

 Wisdom 

Being fortune enough to have a “Trade” badge (here on business people!) that granted me access to the Amex Trade Talks – I was able to learn some fascinating stuff in the two talks I attended day one.

 

The first talk was a panel titled “Marketing To Today’s Diner” featuring big names Rick Bayless, Danny Meyer, Jose Andres, and Google’s head of Product Development Bernardo Hernandez. The panel moderator began with a discussion of traditional media, PR etc and how restaurant’s build a reputation – but within 10 minutes the entire panel had shifted to a conversation about how important Twitter is to restaurant marketing (by the way all 3 chefs do ALL their tweeting themselves). See the full video here. A couple awesome quotes from the panel.
 
&quot;Twitter is an extension of the dining room, giving guests opportunity to be engaged and involved in a conversation&quot; – Danny Meyer

“Technology only amplifies human needs, High Tech will never trump High Touch.” – Danny Meyer

“I always tweet pictures, a picture is worth 1000 words, and on Twitter you only get 140 characters.” – Rick Bayless

&quot;It’s not about databases its about communities&quot; - Bernardo Hernandez

“Everyone is media now.” – Jose Andres

“I use Twitter to show people an insider view – to get people to know me as a person.” – Rick Bayless

“It’s a mistake to write off Foursquare as an operator.” – Danny Meyer

“We don’t spend a dime on advertising.” – Jose Andres
 
The second Trade Talk – “Fame Game: The Realty of TV” was a candid insider discussion on the realities of the rise of celebrity chefs, what TV means today, and how to be successful. The panel featured Jacques Pepin, Tim Love, Spike Mendelsohn, and MingTsai. One of the most interesting messages from this panel was that TV in itself isn’t a way for chef’s to make money – it simply creates outside opportunities (restaurants, books etc) for creating wealth.  See the full video of the panel here .
 
“You cannot escape yourself, you are who you are.” Jacques Pepin

“Embracing your community is the key to success.” – Spike Mendelsohn

“The reality is with TV, you create opportunities.” –Tim Love

“Everyone’s a food critic now, that’s a pain in the ass.” – Ming Tsai

“The best thing Food TV has done for me…Now I can get a reservation at any restaurant in America.” – Ming Tsai

“Get a PR person, you can’t VIP yourself” – Ming Tsai
 
 Wine 

Wow! Wine – I mean I know it’s the Food and Wine Classic but the sheer amount of wine they have available is mind blowing. The Grand Tasting was a sight to see - three massive tents spanning a gorgeous park in downtown Aspen (the view is incredible) all jam packed with every kind of wine you could ever desire.

 

I’m not wine expert (I am currently plodding through Wine Bible and I really do want to learn more) but I wanted to share some of the best wine’s that I had. I tried to focus in and stick to one or two main grapes to have something to compare to and not get totally overwhelmed. My choice was to focus on Pinot Noir and branch into other reds as I saw fit.

The three best Pinot’s that I had were (in no particular order)

 Goldeneye by Duckhorn 

 

 Grand Detour Pinot Noir by Landmark 

 

 Santa Lucia Highlands Pinot Noir by Mac Murray Ranch 

 

Well, this post is a lot longer than I intended. Anyway – off to experience Day 2 of “The Classic.” Hit me up on Twitter and follow for updates all day!

  Tagged as: aspen , aspen classic , aspen food and wine , danny meyer , social media , twitter , wine No Comments 16 May/12 1 
 How Content Grabs Customer Attention 

 

So many restaurants struggle to use social media because they are communicating the wrong thing to their customers. People don’t tune in to social media sites – like YouTube – to watch salesy advertising materials. Even in TV – the bastion of old world mass media marketing – DVR has given customers the freedom to simply zoom by ads without even noticing them.

To get customers attention it doesn’t work anymore to blast them over and over again with mass marketing messages. You have to get people to come to you. The way you do that is by providing them something interesting. You create CONTENT that your customers want to see. Content is something that needs to be one (or more) of three things (1) Educational (2) Interesting or (3) Entertaining – period. If you aren’t providing content that is one of these three things customers have already tuned you out.

When you start churning out interesting and relevant content to your core audience – they will come back over and over for more. You’re already doing this in your daily life whether you realize it or not. That blog you read every day (don’t you wish they updated more often?) or that YouTube video series you watch every week (Epic Meal Time anyone?) or even your favorite author. These people have already become a “Trusted Resource” to you. They provide consistent content you know and trust and enjoy consuming – and because of that you are much more likely to listen when they do happen to have a product or service offering – because you already know and trust them and know that they provide quality content.

You know what people do with content they love? They naturally share it with their friends. That’s why social media is worth of mouth on steroids – because it allows you to create real and relevant content that your customers want to see and want to share with their friends. That builds trust and loyalty and turns them into brand ambassadors and raving fans. Tagged as: content , marketing , social media 1 Comment 9 May/12 0 
 Engage&amp;Integrate–Social Media Tactics For Restaurants [NRA 2012 Presentation] 

Enjoy our presentation on social media engagement from the 2012 National Restaurant Association Conference in Chicago
 
 
 
 Engage&amp;Integrate: Social Media Tactics For Restaurants on Prezi 
 Tagged as: giving , marketing , nra2012 , restaurats , social media No Comments 3 May/12 0 
 Four Things You Must Do in Chicago During The NRA Show 

 

So you&apos;re in Chicago for the NRA Show and you want to know all the cool spots to check out in your free time? I&apos;m not a local but I visit Chicago quite a bit on business and the below destinations come highly recommended. (click the restaurant names for a link to their site)

 Xoco 

Rick Bayless’s Xoco is shaping the future of the fast casual industry – and the food is just plain awesome. This is a mandatory stop every time I am in Chicago and I * highly * recommend checking it out.  What should you order?

 Ahogada – this torta – served sitting in a bowl of tomato broth, is one of the signature items on the menu.

 Caldos – the “soups” here – any of them are awesome but in particular I would get the Pork Belly (coming from a full blown pork addict).

 Churros w/ Chocolate dipping sauce…. Heavenly.

 

Also - check out the acqua frescas - I recommend the one with Hibiscus

 Sunda 

 Billy Dec and the Rockit Ranch crew (one of Chicago’s biggest restaurant players) really outdid themselves when they created Sunda (great video about Sunda’s creation here ). This beautifully designed Asian fusion restaurant sports a massive menu, including a full sushi bar, of delicious food.

 

Must order…

the Peared Sake – literally tastes like you are drinking a chilled pear – I get this every time.

The menu is so huge picking favorites is like picking children – but I would say the Cripsy Rice with Tuna is one of my favs, along with the Rock Shrimp Tempura. 

 The Doughnut Vault 

 

A well hidden food craze in Chicago. This entire restaurant is jam packed into literally a hallway in the back of a building. You won’t even see the building walking by, but you can’t miss the line of people pouring out the door. They tweet how long the line is and what doughnuts they are running out of so make sure to keep an eye on them @doughnutvault so they don’t run out!

If you want to hit these guys up, they are CLOSED on Sunday/Monday so keep that in mind. Well worth making the journey for their delicious and oversized doughnuts.

 Big Star 

An awesome bar and tex mex joint in Chicago’s Wicker Park. The food is great (you won’t believe how tiny their kitchen is) but you really go for the atmosphere. Great place to sit and have a drink and a few tacos for happy hour.

 

The thing to order here is a glass of Templeton Rye . A small batch rye native to Iowa and tough to find anywhere but the Midwest – one of the smoothest and most delicious rye whiskies you will ever drink. Templeton Rye was the choice drink for none other than Al Capone who actually bootlegged it for a number of years during prohibition.

Their food menu is short and sweet but their whiskey menu is deep.

Hope you enjoyed my suggestions! Let me know what you think in the comments and on Twitter and enjoy NRA 2012! Tagged as: chicago , chocolate churros , NRA 2012 , restaurants No Comments 26 Apr/12 1 
 Why Fast Casual Is Not The Future Of The Restaurant Business 

A new breed of restaurant is fast approaching on the horizon and starting to catch people’s attention. These concepts buck the traditional fast casual model in so many ways that it’s time to create a name for this new segment.

Who are the market leaders in Fast Casual? Despite all the up and comers, three stand apart as the dominant players in the space. Chipotle, Panera Bread, and Five Guys. These three goliaths dominate the market and the consumer’s mindshare when it comes to fast casual, the same way McDonald’s does for QSR.

I’ve heard people at restaurant industry conferences occasionally say things like “fast casual plus” or “premium fast casual” to try and describe this emerging market – but that doesn’t go far enough to capture it’s essence.

I’m officially drawing a line in the sand and calling this new segment FRESH CASUAL . Like Fast Casual before it, which sits definitively closer to the QSR side on the spectrum between QSR and Casual Dining, Fresh Casual sits on the same spectrum – but definitively closer to the casual or in some cases even fine dining side.

In essence, Fast Casual is casual dining quality food served in a QSR environment. Fresh Casual is a full casual dining experience with a limited (usually QSR) service model.

This may seem trivial at first, but the gulf between “Fast Casual” concepts and “Fresh Casual” competitors in the same exact space is so wide that it can no longer be ignored.

Here is how Fast Casual and Fresh Casual stack up on the MAJOR differences in market point (these are general categorizations and I realize that not every restaurant fits each definition perfectly ). 

 Menu 

 Fast Casual - Customer driven menu. Most commonly featuring a “build your own” style menu where customers choose their protein, starch and flavor.

 Fresh Casual – Chef driven menu. The menu is designed by a chef or culinary team to have specific dishes and flavor profiles. Often the menu is designed by a corporate chef and then executed by a kitchen staff in store.

 Service Model 

 Fast Casual – Fast Casual differs little from the QSR service model – having customers order at a counter  and pick their food up there.

 Fresh Casual – Fresh Casual retains counter ordering but then adds an additional layer of service -  running food to customers, refilling drinks, and bussing tables.  Once a customer orders at the counter, the rest of their service experience takes place at the table.

 Décor&amp;Design 

 Fast Casual – differs little from a traditional QSR design&amp;décor, very sparse clean interiors, often with promotional materials and posters on the walls.

 Fresh Casual – mimics a casual dining interior. Focus on higher quality furniture and fixtures as well as art and artifacts in store to create a relaxing and comfortable atmosphere.

 Food Quality 

 Fast Casual – delivers higher quality than QSR, but still sometimes reheating and using frozen product. Prep and cooking is usually as simplified as possible

 Fresh Casual – delivers food consistent with top quality casual or fine dining, often fresh and locally sourced and rarely frozen. More complex prep and cooking is required to deliver a higher quality of food

 Platewear 

 Fast Casual – served with traditional QSR paper and disposable service ware

 Fresh Casual – served on plateware and with glass (excluding to-go orders) similar to casual dining 

 Price Point 

The price point is the same for both market segments – $8-12 dollars per meal.

 Buildout 

The square footage, which obviously varies between concepts, is similar in both Fast and Fresh Casual. Between 1500 and 4000 sq ft in a shopping center.

Now that you’ve got a better sense of this distinction, I want to point out 6 specific examples of the restaurants with the same type of food – currently both considered “fast casual” that are a world apart.

 Mexican: Xoco vs. Chipotle 

 

 

If you want to see what the future of restaurants looks like – visit Rick Bayless’s Xoco in Chicago. This beast of a Mexican concept is the most stark example distinguishing Fresh Casual from Fast Casual. As soon as you walk in the door you will realize exactly what I’m talking about ( read here my site report on Xoco). Xoco is just on another level compared to Chipotle, Moe’s, or the other fast casual Mexican and burrito players.  The ambiance, the food quality, the service all fit perfectly into the fresh casual mold. The open kitchen showcases the handmade breads as well as the freshly prepared torta and soup. The ambiance is warm and cozy like a sit down restaurant – and after you order from the counter the service model is indistinguishable from top level casual dining.

 Asian: Pei Wei vs. Panda Express 

 

Pei Wei, one of the older players in the space, fits the Fresh Casual mold to a tee. It is a full blown casual dining restaurant that simply begins your order at a counter. The look, the feel, the service, the food quality etc all stand apart from a Panda Express (or even Chipotle’s new entry into the market Shop House) to such a degree that you can’t help but put Pei Wei in another category all to itself.

 Italian: Vapiano vs. Nooi Pasta 

 

 

Vapiano is a fresh casual Italian concept that hails from Europe. Despite their counter based service model, their food quality is astounding and the ambiance is very much that of casual dining. The cooks hand make pasta daily and boil it to order, pizzas are made from scratch before your eyes. The flavors are bold and delicious and so fresh.  While Fast Casual Italian is still a very young and under-served market, the fledging competitors in the space can’t hold a candle to Vapiano in terms of food quality or ambiance. (Learn more about fast casual Italian .)

 Burgers: Shake Shack vs. Five Guys 

 

 

I personal think the burger space is a huge bubble right now and there are too many concepts for all of them to survive. That said, one of the survivors will almost certainly be Danny Meyer’s Shake Shack. Meyer of Setting The Table fame is one of New York’s premier restaurateurs and arguably one of the guys who kicked off the entire “better burger” craze. After building a near empire in NYC’s restaurant scene Meyer finally decide to scale one of his concepts – and he chose Shake Shack. The chef driven deliciousness of Shake Shack is a fresh casual triumph over the build-your-own burgers of Five Guys. The freshness, quality , and flavor of Shake Shack’s food creates an unquestionable gulf between the plethora of fast casual burger joints and the big boys like Shake Shack.

 Bakery Cafe: Wildflower vs. Panera Bread 

 

 

Wildflower is a 10,000 ton missile aiming straight for Panera. I first ate here out in Phoenix for the RLC 2012. I had heard several people hyping Wildflower up and I was convinced that there was no way it could live up to the hype. Wrong. Wildflower is a Panera with great food, a full kitchen, a much sexier ambiance, and tremendous customer service. One spicy chipotle egg sandwich or order of pancakes (oh those fluffy, fluffy pancakes) at Wildflower and you will know the difference between Fresh Casual and Fast Casual.

 Mediterranean: Taziki’s vs. Garbanzo 

 

 

Ok ok I know,  I put Taziki’s on the list. But at Taziki’s we set out every day to define ourselves as Fresh Casual – to bring a new and better experience to our customers. Taziki’s food is all made completely fresh every day, no freezers and no fryers in the entire store. Our entire menu is designed by our team of chefs to craft delightful, different, and delicious flavor combinations. The décor is soft and inviting like a casual dining restaurant. The service model delivers much more to the customer than a traditional counter model, food is delivered to the customer’s table, drinks are refilled, and the table is bussed for the customer. Similar players in the Mediterranean space like Garbanzo and Roti are both focused on assembly line style build your own menus, with sparse metallic interior and counter only service (essentially replicating Chipotle’s model but replacing the proteins and starches with Mediterranean ones).

 See For Yourself 

Words can only do this distinction so much justice. Get out in the world and see these concepts for yourself. Eat at one and then the other and you will know exactly what I’m talking about when I say that Fresh Casual is here to stay. After travelling across the country week after week and personally visiting all of these concepts, I can say hands down that Fresh Casual is real and it’s a serious force to be reckoned with. Tagged as: Asian , fast casual , fast casual italian , fast casual research , FRESH Casual , garbanzo , healthy , interior design , lessons , restaurant report , tazikis , Vapiano , xoco 1 Comment 16 Apr/12 0 
 Nutrition Solution For Restaurant Chains 

A new video we put together featuring Fresh Tech&apos;s flagship product - Fresh Nutrition . This product was also nominated for a 2012 Operator Innovation Award by the National Restaurant Association.

 Tagged as: fresh tech , marketing , nutrition , technology , videos No Comments 3 Apr/12 0 
 The Best Burger Concept EVER. Period. 

 

 

“OMG You HAVE to try BUBBLE BURGER – its seriously the best burger ever – they are soo much better than Five Guys and Smashburger and Flip Burger and Mooyah Burger and Shake Shack and In&amp;Out Burger and Riff Burger and Culver’s and Better Burger and Fatburger and Elevation Burger and all the other burger joints I could list…”

At RLC a few weeks ago I had 4 separate people come up to me and tell me about this “amazing new fast casual burger concept” that was “hands down the best one” – all talking about four DIFFERENT burger joints none of which I have even listed above.

I hate to rain on everyone’s parade but the fast casual burger segment is over saturated. There is just no way the market can sustain all of these “better burger” concepts competing with one another. This is in a post Five Guys world (where you see one on literally every corner) and a world where McDonalds is STILL the single most successful restaurant business in the world. Who keeps eating all these burgers?

It’s going to be super challenging and a serious blood bath for someone to try and scale any one of these nation wide. As soon as they enter the market where another better burger concept is already dominating (have you seen the volumes In&amp;Out does?) they will start to eat away at each other’s margins.

I wish everyone who’s gung ho about the better burger segment the best of luck, but I personally am starting to get pretty skeptical about how many more better burgers the market can sustain. Tagged as: burger bubble , burgers , fast casual No Comments 26 Mar/12 1 
 Behind The Scenes With Little Donkey–Fresh Hospitality’s New Mexican Concept 

Check out this awesome video we put together for Little Donkey - our new Mexican flex casual concept . Little Donkey feature original Mexican food and spirits influenced by our Southern soul. Slow-smoked meats, fresh-pressed tortillas. Scratch-made everything.

 Tagged as: fast casual , flex casual , FRESH Casual , little donkey , mexican , xoco 1 Comment 10 Mar/12 0 
 Candied Bacon Infused Bourbon–Southern Decadence At Its Finest 

So you wanna make some Bourbon that will blow your mind? What’s awesome? Bourbon. What else is awesome. Bacon. What’s even better? Candied Bacon (or “dog treats for humans” as Epic Meal Time calls them). The Mother Of All Awesome? Candied Bacon Infused Bourbon.

The best part is its pretty easy to do. The hardest part is cooking the bacon! All it takes is time and a little bacon grease.

 Part One: Candy Thy Bacon 

Things you will need (aka ingredients)…

 Bacon Brown Sugar Real Maple Syrup Baking Sheet w/ Rim Optional – cinnamon 

 

Get some bacon. Benton’s if you want to class it up – if you want to keep it really simple just get some bacon at the store.

Preheat oven to 350 degrees

Lay the bacon flat on a baking sheet with a rim

Cover the bacon in brown sugar (but not too thick)

(Optional) Add a pinch of cinnamon

Drizzle very lightly with real maple syrup (otherwise the bacon gets too gooey)

Note: Do Not Use fake maple syrup or corn syrup – it burns in the oven and ruins the recipe!

Stick in the oven for 10-12 min

Watch it very closely! It goes from delicious to burned pretty quickly.

Enjoy a delicious candied bacon snack.

 Part Two: Use Your Infusion 

You can end up doing a bacon-infused bourbon with any bacon grease – but why do that when can you can be even more decadent and make candied bacon too?

 You will need…

 Bottle of Bourbon (we used Bulleit) 1-2 Bowls Fine / High Grade Coffee Filters (get a pack at least) Funnel Pitcher Liquid Bacon Grease 

 

Start by pouring off (or drinking) the first half of the Bourbon. Obviously you don’t need to throw it out – just move it to another container. You only want approximately a ½ full large bottle of bourbon.

Carefully pour the bacon grease from your baking sheet into a bowl or pitcher and then pour it carefully into the ½ full bourbon bottle (use the funnel if you need to).

Seal the bottle and shake the bourbon&amp;grease mix thoroughly. You will want to shake the bottle for a good 15 minutes to make sure the grease flavor really infuses into the bourbon.

Once you have shaken the mixture thoroughly you want to pour the entire mixture into a large bowl (or 2 smaller bowls) and let it settle. Simply leave the bowls out on the counter (do not refrigerate) This could take 1-2 hours.

Once the mixture has settled – all of the grease will rise to the top and the alcohol will all remain on the bottom. Carefully transfer the settled mixture to a freezer. Freeze for another 2-3 hours.

 

Now – pull out your bowl – the grease has hardened and frozen and the alcohol has not. Simply pour the alcohol mixture into a pitcher and leave the frozen grease in the bowl. (That stuff is really gross by the way!)

Using another bowl or bottle – pour the bourbon mixture from the pitcher through a fine coffee filter&amp;funnel – it will take some time as there are still big chunks of grease infused in the bacon. Once you’ve run the filtration through once, run the entire mixture through again to clear up any remaining grease particles.

Viola – you now have Candied Bacon Infused Bourbon. Sit back, relax, and enjoy the decadence as you sip on your delightful hand crafted cocktail.

Let me know what you think below and hit me up on Twitter .

 BONUS CLIP: How To Make Chocolate Covered Bacon 

  Tagged as: bacon , bacon infused bourbon , bourbon , candied bacon , candied bacon infused bourbon , recipe No Comments     Older Entries» 
Topics

 bacon (2) books (4) entrepreneurship (9) fast casual (11) poker (2) restaurant intelligence (11) restaurant research (11) restaurants (7) social media (4) technology (1) videos (7) 

Ideas
 Asian aspen aspen food and wine bacon BBQ books brewing business plan competition chicago coffee coffee roasting danny meyer denver entrepreneurship failure fast casual fast casual italian fast casual research fresh baked pita FRESH Casual garbanzo giving goldman sachs gourmet coffee healthy ideas in store marketing interior design lessons marketing micro-testing muses Octane poker recipe restaurant report restaurants roti social media Tokyo Joes Vapiano videos wall street wine xoco 
Good Reads

 Ben Casnocha Hacker News James Altucher Seth Godin Tim Ferriss 
 Copyright©2012 Matt Bodnar ·Powered by WordPress 
 Lightword Theme by Andrei Luca Go to top↑ 
 Matt Bodnar  is using WP-Gravatar
	</body>
</document>
