<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007442" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1415037" time="2012-07-13-00:24" support="1" score="0.0012130035113431632" bingtitle="Did you ever go to a drive in restaurant, wher the servers wore ..." webtitle="Did you ever go to a drive in restaurant, wher the servers wore roller skates? | Answerbag">
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>... about us not having windows to hang the trays on ... prefer the drive thru, or sitting down at a fast food restaurant? ... How many GameCube controllers can go in the Wii?</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Food And Dining / Fast Food / Fast Food (General) 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Did you ever go to a drive in restaurant, wher the servers wore
roller skates?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 17 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by xhepera on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes. A very long time ago. There was a drive-in restaurant in Hollywood, CA, called Tiny Naylor&apos;s, that had carhops on roller skates. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Anonymous on April 20th, 2009
 
 About twenty years ago in Texas - can&apos;t remember the name of the place but they were speeding around a large parking lot delivering fast food - it sure was a sight to see : ) 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Anonymous on April 20th, 2009
 
 God no. But that i gotta see!!!lol 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Gina A on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes at Sonic, they still wear them every now and them. Depends on whose workn. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by pyroco5 on April 20th, 2009
 
 I havent personally..but i seen on TV that one resteraunt is doing it again...i think its Jack in the Box but im not 100% sure.. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Teller of Truth on April 20th, 2009
 
 When I was a kid I use too see those types of restaurants everywhere, now they are as extinct as the dinosaur... 
 
Comments

 
they were great weren&apos;t they :) thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
They were great...As a kid it was a bonus to see this very attractive woman come out on skates and deliver food too our car...I would fall in love with her and then she would skate on out of my life, I fell in love with many skating waitresses at those types of places, of course I fell in love with just about any woman I found attractive, anyways...There are some of those restaurants in Nevada still, I believe Sonic is doing it these days...

 Report 
 
by Teller of Truth on April 20th, 2009
 
thanks again

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Element 99 on April 20th, 2009
 
 No...but if I go on Teusday I am Canadian and they wear ice skates. 
 
Comments

 
thanks

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by KayJ on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes, we have one of those in our small town 
 
Comments

 
they are so cool and i miss having them around. I haven&apos;t been to one since i was a kid. thank you Kay

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
You are welcome! They are pretty neat.

 Report 
 
by KayJ on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by kat on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes!Sonic but they don`t were skates anymore. 
 
Comments

 
thank you KAT

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by -NUNYA-- on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes at an A&amp;W Drive up restaurant in a small town near here. +5 
 
Comments

 
thank you Miss NUNYA

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by klkl on April 21st, 2009
 
 No I cannot say I have...but having been a waitress once...skates and trays of food, that takes good balance.. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 21st, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Ice man on April 20th, 2009
 
 Hahaha, yes. Many years ago a couple of my buddies and I would ride our motorcycles over to the A&amp;W, in the neighboring town, for teen burgers and to flirt with the carhops on skates. The girls would bring out the burgers and say something about us not having windows to hang the trays on, and we would talk them into hanging around to hold the trays, while we flirted with them. Man, those were the days !! :) 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 21st, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Pearls..loves diamonds too on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes, I did when I was a small child many years ago. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 21st, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by ChandaDiane - est. 1975 on April 20th, 2009
 
 You, and I used to work at one :D 
 
Comments

 
we did, when? :P thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
lol, I meant yes, It&apos;s been a long day.

 Report 
 
by ChandaDiane - est. 1975 on April 20th, 2009
 
i&apos;m sorry i was just teasing you a little bit , forgive me :(

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Nightwatchdog on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes, a couple of Sonic Drive Ins in Arkansas ans Missouri still do that - or did do that 6 - 8 years ago. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Simply99 -- Not a fan favorite. on April 20th, 2009
 
 Still do, every year when we take a trip up to Michigan. 
 
Comments

 
thank you

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by anddeb on April 20th, 2009
 
 Yes and I do miss them. 
 
Comments

 
thank you Deb invis +6

 Report 
 
by Jimmy on April 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 Do you think fast food is the cause of health problems personally or do you think that fast food industies should have certain regulations? 
by Jennifer_M1982 on April 17th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Which fast foods is better? Burger King or Carl&apos;s JR? 
by XT on April 15th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Do you agree with doctors who claim Pres. Obama should STOP eating HOT DOGS? 
by Scorpio7 on May 10th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 What fast food is really, really junkie? 
by HoboJoe on May 2nd, 2012
 
 | 3 people like this
 
 Do you like Rocky Rococo&apos;s? 
by Slipshod Wombat and Co. on May 31st, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 More Fast food (General) See only professionally researched Fast food (General) questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Did you ever go to a drive in restaurant, wher the servers wore roller skates?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 At a fast food restaurant, have you ever showed up to the drive thru window, fully naked? 
 
 Have you ever owned roller skates or ice skates? 
 
 Who invented four-wheel roller skates? 
 
 Do roller skates have a shoe brake on both? 
 
 Do you prefer the drive thru, or sitting down at a fast food restaurant? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 Who invented four-wheel roller skates? 
 
 Do roller skates have a shoe brake on both? 
 
 How do I buy restaurant gift cards online? 
 
 Is the front axle geared the same as the back axle on a 4-wheel-drive vehicle? 
 
 How many GameCube controllers can go in the Wii? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Revealing information about patient What is that ressturant called that serves food on roller skates When did drive in restaurants have waitresses skate around Did a w canada ever have waitresses on rollerskates at the driveins Did a w in canada ever use roller skates 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
