<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007866" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090901164008AAAtXnQ" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="1" score="0.000817109134970329" bingtitle="Hepatitis B and smoking ? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="Hepatitis B and smoking ? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001245" bing-rank="60"/>
	<description>You get it mostly through drinking cup in restaurant. That is why fast food restaurant use throw away food and drink container. I think you will get it that way.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Health &gt; Diseases&amp;Conditions &gt; Infectious Diseases &gt; Resolved Question 
 Larry Member since: May 28, 2007 Total points: 38 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Hepatitis B and smoking ?
 If you share a cigarette with someon who has heptaitis B can you get it. There was no blood involved, just saliva. Would I have to have an open cut for the saliva to touch ? 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by lost in a contraption Member since: September 01, 2009 Total points: 93 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 someones a risk taker..... 
Source(s):
 cancer and hep b 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (8)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Baby Romantic Maya Member since: January 14, 2009 Total points: 957 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Possible.because the virus of hepatitis B is different from the other hepa virus.sometimes we are not aware that are mouth has wound.so there is possible that u can get hepa B if that person is infected with hepatitis B.Hepa B virus can leave more than a month outside the human body what more if it is inside our body. so possible 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Member since: March 24, 2009 Total points: 2,057 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 hmm no because the immune system in the mouth is the strongest of the hole body. unless there was open cuts on both of ur mouths then there is some chance u can get it. 
Source(s):
 my brain 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Hammster Member since: June 14, 2007 Total points: 4,233 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Ok, what exactly is your question, you just answered it and you asked it again?
Answer:
 http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index;… 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Itikuo Member since: October 20, 2008 Total points: 291 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 YEAH MAYBE YOU SHOULDN&apos;T BE SMOKINGG

USE

 http://smoke51.com/591.html 

INSTEAD! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Seeker Member since: October 10, 2008 Total points: 9,535 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You get it mostly through drinking cup in restaurant. That is why fast food restaurant use throw away food and drink container.

I think you will get it that way. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by We are all screwed Member since: March 21, 2008 Total points: 4,654 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 you have probably had the vaccine for B and C is probably more of a concern 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Fantasie... Member since: December 02, 2008 Total points: 577 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No but you can get an even worse disease from smoking.....CANCER! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by peace(: Member since: March 02, 2009 Total points: 976 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 MAYBE YOU SHOULDNT BE SMOKING! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Infectious Diseases 

 Questions about a ruptured spleen? Really worried about the contraction of HIV!?!? Should I see a doctor? Is This A Sign That I Had Polio? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Health 
 Diseases&amp;Conditions 
 Allergies Cancer Diabetes Heart Diseases Infectious Diseases Other - Diseases Respiratory Diseases Skin Conditions STDs 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
