<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007394" url="http://kitchenware.goldaskitchen.com/cookware/Danesco" time="2012-07-13-00:22" support="1" score="0.0014295221608343178" bingtitle="Danesco on Golda&apos;s Kitchen" webtitle="Danesco on Golda&apos;s Kitchen">
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>... those from your favourite fast food restaurant ... Popsicle Moulds | Ice Pop Molds ... touch of elegance to your table or beside the stove with this stainless steel oil dispenser.</description>
	<body>
		Prices are in Canadian dollars
Taxes and shipping and handling fees are additional
We ship worldwide 
 

 
 
 [Popular searches] Only show sale items category Tools (75) 
 Tableware (21) 
 Patioware (18) 
 Storing&amp;Transporting (15) 
 Cookware (11) 
 Bakeware (9) 
 More[+] 
 brand Danesco (152) 
 
 price range Under $5 (25) 
 $5 - $10 (28) 
 $10 - $20 (47) 
 $20 - $30 (33) 
 $30 - $50 (17) 
 $50 - $100 (2) 
 
 size Mini (16) 
 10&quot; (5) 
 15&quot; (4) 
 1 L (3) 
 6&quot; (3) 
 8&quot; (3) 
 More[+] 
 colour Green (15) 
 Blue (13) 
 Red (7) 
 White (6) 
 Yellow (5) 
 Grey (4) 
 More[+] 
 material Stainless steel (44) 
 Silicone (22) 
 Melamine (13) 
 Steel (11) 
 Bamboo (6) 
 Stoneware (6) 
 More[+] 
 theme Mother&apos;s Day (2) 
 Thanksgiving (2) 
 Christmas (1) 
 Fall (1) 
 Father&apos;s Day (1) 
 Jewish Holidays (1) 
 More[+] 


 best sellers Wine Glass - Stainless steel Roasting Rack - Oval - 6×9 - Non-stick Pastry Mat - 18×24 
 
 
 1 - 36 of 152 search results for Danesco 
 Page  1   2   3   4   5  of 5 |  Next View: Grid | List View  12 24 32 64 128 300 results Sort by  relevance price: descending price: ascending product: ascending product: descending Tasting Spoon Set - Glass Tasting Spoon Set - Glass Tasting Spoon Set - Glass by Danesco These spoons are the perfect size for serving hors d&apos;oeuvres, tapas, appetizers, and more. Made of durable 2-layer fused glass, the spoons will add a splash of colour to your entertaining. Set of 6: one each of yellow, burgundy, red, green, blue, and orange 
  $12.00 Egg Poacher/Skillet - 4 eggs Egg Poacher/Skillet - 4 eggs Egg Poacher/Skillet - 4 eggs by Danesco Stainless steel skillet with 4 non-stick egg cups. The cups can also be used to gently melt small portions of butter or chocolate. The pan may be used separately as a skillet or saute pan. 7 piece set: skillet, poacher insert, 4 removable egg cups, and glass lid Capacity:  4 eggs 
 Related Searches: Egg Poacher | Poacher | Egg  $40.00 Popsicle Mould with Sippers Popsicle Mould with Sippers Popsicle Mould with Sippers by Danesco Create a variety of frosty treats with these flexible popsicle moulds. Finished popsicles can be removed from the mould one-at-a-time; the built in handles and deep drip guards help protect fingers from getting sticky. A built-in straw on the base of each holder allows for melted popsicle drippings… Set of 5: 4 handles/drip guards and 4-cavity mould stand 
 Related Searches: Popsicle Molds | Popsicle | Popsicle Moulds  $6.00 Baking Cups - Silicone - Mini - Green/Blue/Orange Baking Cups - Silicone - Mini - Green/Blue/Orange Baking Cups - Silicone - Mini - Green/Blue/Orange by Danesco Isn&apos;t it irritating when half your mini muffin or cupcake sticks to the paper baking cup and you are left trying to scrape the last bits off with your teeth without eating the paper as well? Here is the solution. Muffins and cupcakes will bake evenly with a moist, light texture in these silicone… Pack of 12 Size: Mini Colour/Pattern:  4 green, 4 blue, and 4 orange 
 Related Searches: Cupcake Liners | Silicone Baking Cups | Silicone Muffin  $8.00 Roasting Rack - Oval - 6×9 - Non-stick Roasting Rack - Oval - 6&amp;times; 9 - Non-stick Roasting Rack - Oval - 6×9 - Non-stick by Danesco This oval roasting rack will sit inside most roasting pans and raise meat above the juices and fat. Non-stick coated for easy clean-up. Size: 6×9 
 Related Searches: Roasting Rack  $8.00 Measuring Scoop -¼cup Measuring Scoop -&amp;frac14; cup Measuring Scoop -¼cup by Danesco This stainless steel measuring scoop is great for scooping flour, sugar, and other dry ingredients such as rice or oatmeal. The scoop provides an accurate measure and is perfect for leaving in a canister of flour, rice, or oatmeal for easy portion control. Or, use it together with other measuring… Capacity:  ¼cup/60 millilitres 
 Related Searches: Scoop | Measuring Cups | Measuring Spoons  $6.00 Bamboo Salad Bowl with Servers Bamboo Salad Bowl with Servers Bamboo Salad Bowl with Servers by Danesco  -  Natural Living Add a dash of style and a pinch of beauty to the tabletop with this salad bowl made of sleek and beautiful bamboo. The bowl includes a matching pair of salad hand servers. Set of 3: bowl and pair of salad hands Size: 10&quot; 
 Related Searches: Salad Bowl  $45.00 Molcajete - Granite Molcajete - Granite Molcajete - Granite by Danesco This rough-hewn Mexican-style molcajete (mortar and pestle) is sculpted from natural granite and is great for crushing the flavour out of fresh or dried herbs and spices. The premium quality mortar is heavy, well balanced, and suitable for rigorous pounding and grinding; the pestle&apos;s design allows… Size: 8&quot; Colour/Pattern:  Grey Capacity:  3 cups/750 millilitres 
 Related Searches: Mortar | Mortar And Pestle | Pestle  $30.00 Measuring Spoon Set - Small sizes Measuring Spoon Set - Small sizes Measuring Spoon Set - Small sizes by Danesco Rounded measuring spoons in the smallest of sizes. Set of 3: dash (1/8 tsp), pinch (1/16 tsp), and smidgen (1/32 tsp) capacities 
 Related Searches: Measuring Spoons  $3.50 Paella Pan - Non-stick Paella Pan - Non-stick Paella Pan - Non-stick by Danesco This traditional-style pan cooks delicious paellas in the oven or on the stovetop. The large, flat cooking surface promotes even cooking and maximum flavour distribution. The shallow design with sloping sides, helps rice cook evenly and develop intense flavour. The pan is constructed of carbon… Size: 15&quot; Capacity:  3¾quarts/3.5 litres 
 Related Searches: Paella Pan | Paella  $25.00 French Fry Pan French Fry Pan French Fry Pan by Danesco Frozen french fries baked on this non-stick pan taste like those from your favourite fast food restaurant. You don&apos;t even have to turn them and they come out crispy and delicious. 
 Related Searches: French Fry | Pizza Pan | Pizza  $15.00 Silicone Spatula - Stainless Steel Handle - Mini - Green Silicone Spatula - Stainless Steel Handle - Mini - Green Silicone Spatula - Stainless Steel Handle - Mini - Green by Danesco This small spatula has a flat stainless steel handle and a silicone head for scraping batter from bowls or the contents from jars. Size: Mini Colour/Pattern:  Green 
  $2.00 Basting Brush - Silicone - Mini - Red Basting Brush - Silicone - Mini - Red Basting Brush - Silicone - Mini - Red by Danesco This mini pastry or basting brush has a comfortable stainless steel handle and silicone bristles with which to apply sauces, dressings, and marinades. Size: Mini Colour/Pattern:  Red 
 Related Searches: Brush  $2.00 Turner - Silicone - Mini - Green Turner - Silicone - Mini - Green Turner - Silicone - Mini - Green by Danesco This small turner has a silicone-coated head which is the perfect size for handling small items. The turner is safe for use with non-stick cookware. Size: Mini Colour/Pattern:  Green 
 Related Searches: Mini Green  $2.00 Cheese Board Set - Slate - 6×6 Cheese Board Set - Slate - 6&amp;times; 6 Cheese Board Set - Slate - 6×6 by Danesco This cheese board set will bring rustic charm to your entertaining. Each plate has a handsome natural slate finish that offers a beautifully organic surface for serving salads, seafood, and other tasty entrées. The plate is shaped with natural, unfinished edges to reveal the beauty of this… Set of 4 Size: 6×6 Colour/Pattern:  Slate grey 
 Related Searches: Wine  $22.00 Water Bottle - Stainless steel Water Bottle - Stainless steel Water Bottle - Stainless steel by Danesco This water bottle is a safe and environmentally-friendly choice for reducing waste while staying healthy. The bottle is made of high-quality, food-grade stainless steel. This rust-resistant bottle has a flip-up spout with a leak-proof cap. A large removable clip makes it easy to attach the bottle… Size: 750 mL Colour/Pattern:  Stainless steel Capacity:  27 ounces/750 millilitres 
 Related Searches: Water Bottle  $8.00 Basting Brush - Silicone - 2&quot; - Red Basting Brush - Silicone - 2&quot;- Red Basting Brush - Silicone - 2&quot; - Red by Danesco This basting brush has flexible, heat resistant silicone bristles and a chromed wire handle. Use the brush to remove excess flour from dough, brush egg or water washes on pastry, grease cake pans, or baste foods. Size: 2&quot; Colour/Pattern:  Red 
 Related Searches: Cake Flour  $6.00 Thermal Flask - Stainless steel Thermal Flask - Stainless steel Thermal Flask - Stainless steel by Danesco This stainless steel thermal flask is ideal for carrying hot beverages to the stadium or on a picnic. The flask keeps coffee, tea, and hot chocolate hot or cold beverages cold. The flask&apos;s lid inverts to become a stainless steel mug, so you don&apos;t need to sip directly from the flask. Size: 500 mL Colour/Pattern:  Stainless steel Capacity:  18 ounces/500 millilitres 
 Related Searches: Travel Mug  $18.00 Pastry Mat - 18×24 Pastry Mat - 18&amp;times; 24 Pastry Mat - 18×24 by Danesco This pastry mat is great for rolling out dough, as well as for chopping, slicing, and dicing. The mat is marked with measurements on all four sides and circles for pies, tarts, and pizzas for easily rolling out dough to the proper dimensions. Size: 18×24 
 Related Searches: Pastry Mat | Mat | Pie  $9.00 Tasting Plate Set - Glass Tasting Plate Set - Glass Tasting Plate Set - Glass by Danesco These plates are ideal for serving hors d&apos;oeuvres, tapas, appetizers, and more. Made of durable 2-layer fused glass, the plates will add a splash of colour to your entertaining. Set of 6: one each of yellow, burgundy, red, green, blue, and orange 
 Related Searches: Green  $15.00 Teapot - Brown Teapot - Brown Teapot - Brown by Danesco  -  CHA Tea This matte-finished stoneware teapot has a charming round belly design which brews a lovely cup of tea. The teapot has a stainless steel infuser for holding and straining loose tea leaves. The lid is stainless steel to help keep contents warm longer. Size: 1 L Colour/Pattern:  Dark chocolate brown Capacity:  47 ounces/1.4 litres 
 Related Searches: Teapot  $30.00 Travel Mug with Infuser - Red Travel Mug with Infuser - Red Travel Mug with Infuser - Red by Danesco This travel mug is perfect for preparing great tea for the morning commute. The double wall plastic travel mug has a stainless steel infuser basket to hold tea leaves, or remove the infuser basket and fill with coffee, hot chocolate, or any other beverage. In addition to a travel top with sipping… Size: 340 mL Colour/Pattern:  Red Capacity:  12 ounces/340 millilitres 
 Related Searches: Tea | Tea Infuser | Coffee Mugs  $18.00 Oil Dispenser - Stainless steel Oil Dispenser - Stainless steel Oil Dispenser - Stainless steel by Danesco Bring a touch of elegance to your table or beside the stove with this stainless steel oil dispenser. The vintage-look dispenser is perfect for drizzling oil over salads or vegetables. The tapered spout is designed for to be virtually drip-free for less mess and easy clean ups. Capacity:  10 ounces/300 millilitres 
  $28.00 Flatware Set - Summer Fresh - 24 pcs Flatware Set - Summer Fresh - 24 pcs Flatware Set - Summer Fresh - 24 pcs by Danesco Add bold colour to your next gathering with this contemporary-style flatware set. The set is a must-have for the entertainer with an eye for vivid colours; it is perfect for picnics, garden parties, and outdoor dining. Set of 24: 6 each table forks, table knives, table spoons, and tea spoons. Colour/Pattern:  Blue, green, purple, and white stripe design 
 Related Searches: Danesco Summer Fresh  $35.00 Tumbler - Double-Wall - Blue/Green/Purple Tumbler - Double-Wall - Blue/Green/Purple Tumbler - Double-Wall - Blue/Green/Purple by Danesco This eco-friendly alternative to a disposable plastic cup is great for water, soft drinks, iced coffees, smoothies, and other cold drinks. Safer and more durable than glass, this tumbler is ideal for picnics, garden parties, and outdoor dining. The removable straw and a screw on lid reduce spillage. Size: 16 oz Colour/Pattern:  Clear with blue, green, and purple stripes Capacity:  16 ounces/475 millilitres 
  $6.00 Melamine Plate - 8&quot; - Summer Fresh Melamine Plate - 8&quot;- Summer Fresh Melamine Plate - 8&quot; - Summer Fresh by Danesco This food-safe melamine plate is perfect for use at outdoor barbeques or picnics. It is just the right size for individual servings of salad. The vibrant bands of colour will lend contemporary style to your outdoor event. Size: 8&quot; Colour/Pattern:  White with blue, green, and purple stripe design 
 Related Searches: Plates  $5.00 Melamine Bowl - Summer Fresh Melamine Bowl - Summer Fresh Melamine Bowl - Summer Fresh by Danesco This food-safe melamine bowl is perfect for use at outdoor barbeques or picnics. The vibrant bands of colour will lend contemporary style to your outdoor event. The bowl can be used for individual servings of salad or cereal, and is also suitable for serving also suitable for serving nuts or chips. Size: 5½&quot; Colour/Pattern:  White with blue, green, and purple stripe design 
  $3.00 Melamine Plate - 10&quot; - Summer Fresh Melamine Plate - 10&quot;- Summer Fresh Melamine Plate - 10&quot; - Summer Fresh by Danesco This food-safe melamine dinner plate is perfect for use at outdoor barbeques or picnics. The vibrant bands of colour will lend contemporary style to your outdoor event. Size: 10&quot; Colour/Pattern:  White with blue, green, and purple stripe design 
 Related Searches: Melamine Plate  $6.00 Cutlery Caddy - Purple Cutlery Caddy - Purple Cutlery Caddy - Purple by Danesco Keep all your kitchen utensils easily within reach on the countertop in this colourful and attractive galvanized steel caddy. The caddy features six removable compartments. The multi-purpose caddy can also be used to store pens and pencils in the office, art and craft supplies in the classroom, or… Colour/Pattern:  Bright purple 
  $15.00 Ice Bucket - w/Scoop - Purple Ice Bucket - w/Scoop - Purple Ice Bucket - w/Scoop - Purple by Danesco This charming galvanized steel ice bucket is perfect for outdoor entertaining. It features a removable plastic insert that helps keep melting to a minimum. Handles on either side of the bucket make for easy carrying; the lid also has a handle for easy access to contents. Set of 2: ice bucket and scoop Colour/Pattern:  Bright purple 
  $20.00 Serving Tray - Purple Serving Tray - Purple Serving Tray - Purple by Danesco This galvanized serving tray has a modern, outdoorsy look which makes it perfect for use at outdoor barbeques or picnics. The tray has two handles and a raised rim for safe and easy transport of food and drinks. Colour/Pattern:  Bright purple 
  $15.00 Poultry Thermometers Poultry Thermometers Poultry Thermometers by Danesco Take the guesswork out of grilling with these poultry thermometers. Simply insert the stainless steel probe into the thickest part of the meat for an accurate temperature read. The thermometers are ideal for chicken, turkey, duck and goose. Set of 2 
  $8.00 Melamine Platter - Oval - 17&quot; - Bubbly Melamine Platter - Oval - 17&quot;- Bubbly Melamine Platter - Oval - 17&quot; - Bubbly by Danesco This food-safe melamine serving platter is perfect for use at outdoor barbeques or picnics. The rimmed edge is designed to keep contents from spilling over the sides. The platter is ideal for serving appetizers and desserts, or use it to serve the barbecued chicken, ribs, or burgers. Size: 17&quot; Colour/Pattern:  White with blue and lime green bubbly pattern 
  $12.00 Melon Wedger Melon Wedger Melon Wedger by Danesco The serrated stainless steel blades of this melon wedger quickly and easily slide through fruit to deliver 12 equal segments in one motion. The wedger is ideal for slicing cantaloupe, honeydew melons, pineapples, and small watermelons. The soft-grip handles are comfortable to use and help prevent… Colour/Pattern:  White 
  $18.00 Rolling Pin - w/Measurements - Bamboo Rolling Pin - w/Measurements - Bamboo Rolling Pin - w/Measurements - Bamboo by Danesco This French-style rolling pin (without handles) is perfect for rolling out pizza, pie, pastry, cookie and fresh pasta dough. The rolling pin has a smooth rolling surface for maneuverability and precise control and is made from durable bamboo sourced from renewable resources. The rolling pin… Size: 15&quot; 
 Related Searches: Rolling Pin  $20.00 Herb&amp;Spice Infuser - Stainless steel Herb&amp;Spice Infuser - Stainless steel Herb&amp;Spice Infuser - Stainless steel by Danesco Add flavour to soups, sauces, stews and more with this herb and spice infuser. Use the stainless steel infuser to quickly infuse appetizing blends of fresh or dried herbs and spices into soups, stews, and sauces. Simply fill the container and hang from the chain hook onto the pot; when finished… 
 Related Searches: Pitcher | Tea Infuser  $12.00 Search Suggestions: Egg Poacher | Popsicle Molds | Popsicle | Popsicle Moulds | Roasting Rack | Ice Pop | Poacher | Ice Pop Molds Page  1   2   3   4   5  of 5 |  Next 

 
 Site Search  by  
 Home | Shop | Your Order | Your Account | Newsletter | About Golda&apos;s Kitchen | Contact Golda | Help 
 Terms of Use | Privacy Policy ©1999 - 2009 Golda&apos;s Kitchen Inc. All rights reserved.
 GOLDA&apos;S KITCHEN and the LADY DESIGN are registered trademarks of Golda&apos;s Kitchen Inc.
For our corporate information, click here .
 For more information about this website, contact golda@goldaskitchen.com 

Developed using iHTML Version 2.19 and iHTML Merchant Enterprise Version 2.02 
Portions©1996 - 2000 Inline Internet Systems, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
