<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007970" url="http://www.paperbackswap.com/Corinne-T-Netzer-Corinne-T-Netzer/book/0440236428/" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="2" score="0.0031249024707380607" bingtitle="The Corinne T Netzer 2001 Calorie Counter, Corinne T. Netzer ..." webtitle="The Corinne T Netzer 2001 Calorie Counter, Corinne T. Netzer. (Paperback 0440236428) Used Book available for Swap">
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>The Corinne T Netzer 2001 Calorie Counter Author: Corinne T. Netzer ... US Patent Number 7,877,315 | Copyright © 2004 - 2012 PaperBackSwap.com.</description>
	<body>
		What&apos;s New - Home - Login Member $ avings: $ 31,226,817.92 |
 Books Available: 5,057,794 |
 Members Online: 1,761 Your Source for Swapping&amp;Buying Books Online! How To Swap Books Sign Up Search All Books PBS Market (New Books)  Gift Buying Guide Book Browser Advanced Search Books Posted Today Member Book Reviews Award Winning Books NYT Best Sellers Most Traveled Copies Club Wish List Login Community Member Directory Discussion Forums Book Lists Club Lists My Book Lists My Watched Lists Create a List Blog Donations School Donation Program In Memory of... Military Donation Program Friends of PBS Live Chat (3) Box-O-Books Maps The Eclectic Pen Fun Stuff 20 Questions Sudoku Top 100 Wishes Requests Posts Swappers Referrers Pulse of PBS Spread The Word Tell A Friend Bookmarks Facebook Page Facebook App More Photo Gallery Recipes Club Tag Cloud Member Testimonials Help Center How To Swap Books? Browse Help Docs Ask the Librarian Live Help Kiosk PBS Market (New Books) Go Shopping Buy Credits Buy PBS Money Gift Certificates Transfer Credits   Need Help? Visit the Help Center - Close X 
Tell a friend about this book...

 Friend&apos;s Email:   
 Subject:   I have found a book that I think you would enjoy 

 

 
 Search - The Corinne T. Netzer 2001 Calorie Counter 
 
 
 
 The Corinne T Netzer 2001 Calorie Counter 
 Author: Corinne T. Netzer 
 Forget about deprivation! The secret to staying in shape is knowledge. And that&apos;s what you&apos;ll get in this newly revised edition of Corinne T. Netzer&apos;s bestselling classic. Pocket-size for easy portability, jam-packed with the latest, most accurate calorie counts for brand-name and common foods, here is an essential reference for today&apos;s health-c ...   more onscious consumer. Discover how easy it is to enjoy healthful, delicious meals with the guide that helps you make the best choices--wherever you are! Whether you&apos;re trying to lose weight, maintain, or just eat healthily, this handy pocket guide will help you stay on track. So indulge in a guilt-free treat...plan a sumptuous family meal...catch a bite at a fast-food restaurant...make on-the-spot dining decisions with confidence.... Remember, you&apos;re in charge--with the book that helps you take control of your eating!

Want to get in shape for the New Year? Anticipating a big vacation? Worried about the holidays, a wedding, a gala party? Relax! This handy pocket reference puts you in control! You know you&apos;re in good hands with Corinne T. Netzer, America&apos;s most trusted authority on the nutritional content of food. With her help, counting calories will become second nature. Discover the latest information about the newest foods, updated facts about old favorites, and so much more in the book that takes the guesswork out of eating healthy-at home or on the road. Whether you&apos;re cooking up a storm, trying one of the latest brand-name foods, or planning a night on the town, here&apos;s the perfect guide for people on the go.    less 
 Post This Book + Reminder Login | Register 
 ISBN-13: 9780440236429 
 ISBN-10: 0440236428 
 Publication Date: 10/10/2000
 Pages: 288 
 Rating: 
 Currently 0 /5 Stars. 
   ? 
 0 stars, based on 0 rating Publisher: Dell 
 Book Type: Paperback 
 Reviews: Amazon  |  Write a Review 
 
 
 

 Genres: 

 Health, Fitness&amp;Dieting &gt;&gt; Diets&amp;Weight Loss &gt;&gt; Diets &gt;&gt; General Health, Fitness&amp;Dieting &gt;&gt; Diets&amp;Weight Loss &gt;&gt; Food Counters 

 
 My Account 
 Post Books 
 Wish List 
 Bookshelf 
 Member Tools 
 Under the Hood 
 Newsletter Archive 
 Search for a Book 
 Browse My Favorite Genres 
 Advanced Book Search 
 Book Browser 
 Club Tag Cloud 
 NYT Best Sellers 
 Newbery Medal Winners 
 Pulitzer Prize Winners 
 Books Posted Today 
 Award Winning Books 
 Mobile / PDAs 
 Help Center 
 How to Swap Books 
 Ask the Librarian 
 Live Help 
 Browser Test 
 Feature List 
 Amazon Search 
 Community 
 Spread the Word 
 Widgets&amp;APIs 
 Feeds RSS/XML 
 Box-O-Books 
 Discussion Forums 
 Blog 
 Facebook 
 Twitter 
 Company 
 Press&amp;Media 
 Pulse of PBS 
 Contact Us 
 Careers 
 Privacy&amp;Security 

 Sister Sites 
 SwapaDVD.com 
 SwapaCD.com 







 Back to the Top ↑ By using this Web site, you confirm that you have read, understood, and agreed to be bound by the Terms of Use .
US Patent Number 7,877,315 | Copyright©2004 - 2012 PaperBackSwap.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
