<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007142" url="http://greentechnolog.com/carbon_footprint/" time="2012-07-13-00:07" support="2" score="0.0018721461679348647" bingtitle="Green Technology: Carbon Footprint Archives" webtitle="Green Technology: Carbon Footprint Archives">
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>... EV owners use their cars batteries as storage ... A typical coffee shop or fast food restaurant can use 1000 ... put it in a compost pile or even throw it in the trash where ...</description>
	<body>
		Green Technology 

Achieve a Sustainable Future with Green Technology. Create Innovation for New Energy.
 
 Main 

July 08, 2012
 
 Skyonic Sequesters CO2 By Turning it to Baking Soda 
 



 CO2 removal / sequestration is a big issue for power plants and industries. Skyonic has developed technology that can both remove CO2 and other pollutants from waste streams or flue gas and turn the recovered CO2 into a saleable product.

“Skyonic’s SkyMine® technology removes CO2 … through co-generation of saleable carbonate and/or bicarbonate materials…. cleans SOx and NO2 from the flue gas, and removes heavy metals such as mercury.”

“… SkyMiine® also produces green chemicals, such as hydrochloric acid, bleach, chlorine, and hydrogen, … [that] can replace less environmentally-friendly products in market.”

With investments from BP, ConocPhillips and others, Skyonics is planning to build a demonstration plant in San Antonio at a Capitol Aggregates cement plant that would come on-line in 2014.

This technology could be a key way to clean up the CO2 emitted by cement plants. Cement plants are considered a huge emitter of CO2 – by some estimates [Wikipedia] emitting 5% globally of man-made CO2 emissions.

 

The process is flexible and can take from 10 – 99 % of CO2 out of the waste stream – depending on requirements,

 

 

 Via: Skyonic LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 01:20 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 21, 2012
 
 GreenTouch 
 



 

GreenTouch’s mission is to …” deliver the architecture, specifications and roadmap to increase network energy efficiency by a factor of 1000 from current levels.”

One promising area is to reduce the energy used by fiber going to homes. Using new technology they plan to significantly lower “energy consumption in fiber-to-the-home (FTTH) networks, …” The technology is called Bit-Interleaved Passive Optical Network (Bi-PON).

The video below explains …
 GreenTouch 
 

 Via:  GreenTouch  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:44 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 03, 2012
 
 General Electric uses Cyclopentane to Reduce CO2 Footprint of Refrigerators 
 



 

General Electric is using cyclopentane as a foam blowing agent for insulation in refrigerators and freezers. Using cyclopentane in place of HFC such as HFC-134a or HFC-245fa (typically used by US refrigerator manufacturers) significantly reduces the CO2 footprint from foam blowing.

GE is using cyclopentane at two major facilities – Appliance Park, KY and Decatur, GA. - to lower toe CO2 footprint associated with prior HFC foam blowing agents.

 At Appliance Park – “ … reduce average annual CO2 emissions … by more than 99 percent, or 117,781 metric tons of CO2 annually …”

 At Decatur GA – “ .. reducing … by 400,000 metric tons of CO2 … a 99-percent reduction in GHG emissions ..”

This is equivalent to the “ … of 101,185 car” and the amount of CO2 “ … absorbed by 132,093 acres of Southeastern U.S. forest”.

 

 Via:  General Electric  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:12 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 28, 2012
 
 Hasbro Improves Product Packaging 
 



 

As part of Hasbro’s commitment to sustainability they are beginning to make changes in product packaging. One result is an increase of approx. 15% in the ration of product to packaging. In other words - less packaging for a given amount of product.

Other planned packaging changes include:

 plastic blister packages that use less material more efficient packaging removing PVC packaging no longer using wire ties increasing recycled content: “ … the 2013 MY LITTLE PONY assortment pack is expected to reduce the size of shipping containers by 20 percent …” 

Less and more efficient packing means less shipping costs and shipping emission and less material for the consumer throw away in the trash.

For more on Hasbro’s sustainability efforts follow this LINK 

 

 Via:  Hasbro  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:32 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 15, 2012
 
 Global Green Lighting Reduces Energy Costs and CO2 Emissions 
 


 
Green Lighting (GGL) reduces energy costs and lowers CO2 emissions using LED lights and lighting control technology.

“Low Energy lighting [using]… LED (Light Emitting Diodes) and Induction white light technologies … offer 50% to 70% lower energy consumption, 80% lower maintenance, significantly reduced CO2 emissions …”

See video below describing how Chattanooga, Tennessee is saving money – on maintenance and return on investment - and improving the city lighting at the same time. Technology from GGL allows the city to control individual lights, determine which bulbs need to be replaced and report energy usage back to a central data store for analysis.

 

 

 

 Via:  Global Green Lighting  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:18 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 04, 2012
 
 Zotos: One of US&apos;s Top 20 On-Site Wind Power Generators 
 


 
 

Zotos makes professional hair care products. They also are going green and have major initiatives under way for wind power, carbon offsetting and greener packaging.

“ … we must change the way we see our world. … Zotos is … implementing one of the largest private industrial sustainability programs in the nation.”

They have been recognized by the US-EPA as one of the Top 20 On-site Wind Generators. Two turbines at their Geneva NY plant that “ … generate approximately 6.5 million kWh of electricity … annually … provide more than 60 percent of Zotos’ energy requirements … expected to reduce overall CO 2 emissions by 50 percent in 2011.”

 

  Via: Zotos Internatinal LINK

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:23 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 21, 2012
 
 Earth Day 2012–April 22 
 



 

Get ready for earth day 2012.  Get ready to make your own positive impact on the planet …

Consider (if you are not already doing so) …


- recycling
- shopping with reusable shopping bags
- FreeCycling rather than landfilling
- composing certain kitchen scraps
- installing a programmable thermostat for a/c
- insulating your water heater
- using CFL or LED bulks
- buying energy efficient appliances

Take time to celebrate earth day 2012 …
 
 

 Via:  Earth Day Network Link 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:04 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 08, 2012
 
 Makani Airborne Wind Power 
 



 

Makani has an energy solution that harnesses the power of winds at elevations far beyond that available to ground based turbines. Their “tethered” wind turbine system uses far less material to construct that a typical turbine. The long term goal would be a system, that can autonomously launch when the wind conditions are right and land when the wind dies down.

“ …. autonomous wing fitted with onboard turbines … Flying at 1,000 ft, … mimics the motion, and speed, of a conventional turbine’s aerodynamically effective blade tips.”

 

 

 Via:  Makani LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:40 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 31, 2012
 
 Enlightened - Intelligent Energy Saving Lighting 
 



 

 

ENLIGHTED is an advanced lighting technology company. It’s lighting solutions advance lighting and energy savings to the next level.

They position themselves as offering the 4th generation of lighting management.

- 1st generation is no user feedback
- 2nd generation is occupancy and daylight detection
- 3rd generation is zones with central control).

See graphic for a detailed view of the 4 generations of lighting control  LINK 

 Using “ … an autonomous sensor and control system … deploys an addressable sensor and controller at every fixture in the building…” The sensors collect data in real time for presence / occupancy, temperature and ambient light to develop a profile for how each light fixture needs to operate.&quot;”
 
 

 Via:  Enlighted, Inc.  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:02 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 27, 2012
 
 Panasonic Technology for Hybrid Car Carrier 
 



 

 

Panasonic along with Mitsui O.S.K Lines, Ltd. and Mitsubishi Heavy Industries are working on technologies to reduce CO2 emissions from ocean going ships.

The test platform is the “EMERALD ACE”. The ship will be fitted with “ … solar panels (160kW planned) and lithium-ion rechargeable batteries (approximately 2.2MWh planned) … “

The solar panels charge batteries that provide power when in the harbor – in place of diesel generators reducing CO2 emissions. The batteries are used as ballast and do not impact the carrying capacity of the ship.

 

 Via: Panasonic  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:26 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 10, 2012
 
 SheaHomes and SolarCity Partner on ZERO Energy Homes 
 



 

SheaHomes and SolarCity are partnering to bring consumers the “No Electric Bill” home.

“ … expected to be one of the largest net-zero electric home projects in the U.S. when completed. …”

SheaXero homes have these green features … solar power, energy efficient windows, Energy Star appliances,CFL bulks, blown in wall insulation, programmable thermostats, motion sensors for lights, insulated garage doors and more. 

“SheaXero is a state-of-the-art package that combines a sleek, low profile solar power system with over 30 groundbreaking green features to completely eliminate your electric bill …”

The “No electric Bill” homes are expected to be available in SheaHome communicites in the states of Arizona, California, Florida, Nevada and Washington.

 Via:  SheaZero  LINK and SolarCity LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:24 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 21, 2012
 
 carpooling.com Links Rides and Riders Around the World 
 



 carpooling.com provides an easy way for rides and riders to connect. Ride sharers “… save gas and money, reduce auto emissions and meet new friends. …”

carpool.com is easy to use and can “ … be accessed from a computer, a mobile phone … or a social network … Solutions are also available for enterprises, communities and commuters.”

Check out this podcast for more details… PODCAST The World - BBC 

 

 Via:  carpooling.com  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:13 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Nectar Restaurant (Berwyn, PA) Goes Green with Solar Panels 
 



 Nectar – in Berwyn, PA – has 238 solar panels in the back of the parking lot that “ … will produce enough energy to run the entire restaurant. “ The expense was $300,000 and “ … the government will subsidize 30 percent … pay for itself in roughly seven years.” 

They are also trying to be sustainable by “ … building a restaurant garden, complete with fresh herbs and veggies …”

 

 

 Via:  Main Line Today LINK  

and Nectar  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 02:34 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 12, 2012
 
 Nike Recycles Old Sneakers 
 



 Nike collects and recycles old sneakers. You can drop sneakers off at Nike Stores ( LINK to find one near you). The sneakers are separated into 3 components … sole, foam and fabric. The soles are used to make tracks surfaces.

See video for more information on the process. 

 
 
 Via:  Nike LINK

 Posted by Green Dude at 12:35 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 28, 2012
 
 Exelon Turns Chicago Brownfield Site to Solar Farm 
 



 Exelon is repurposing a brownfield site in the Chicago area into a solar farm. The 41 acre site have 32,292 solar panels and generates 14,000 mWatt-hrs yearly.

“ … uses SunPower® solar tracking systems that tilt the panels toward the sun as it moves across the sky, increasing energy production by up to 25%.”

The energy generated by the solar panels offsets “ … more than 30 million pounds of greenhouse gas emissions per year …”

Exelon also remediated the site which had been vacant for more than 30 years.

 

 Via:  Excelon  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:16 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 24, 2012
 
 PSE&amp;G (NJ) Generates Heat from Sewage in Camden, NJ 
 



 

PSE&amp;G is using the thermal energy from a sewage plant in Camden, NJ to help heat the facility. The system is closed loop – meaning the sewage does not enter the building – but the heat energy is extracted and used to offset the need for electric to heat the facility.

The “ … $1.3 million project … is one of 18 funded by PSE&amp;G toward meeting a state requirement that utilities invest in improving energy efficiency …”

“ … project is believed to be the first of its kind in the United State …”

The waste heat system is expected to save “ … $80,000 a year on electricity bills, about a quarter of its heating costs.”

In addition to the energy / electric savings there is a positive environmental impact.

 

 

 

 Via:  Philly.com  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:38 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 18, 2012
 
 Solo Cup&apos;s BARE Sustainable Products: Bringing Alternative Resources to the Environment 
 



 

 

 

 

 

 

 

Bare® products, by Solo®., are made with recycled content, and are recyclable o compostable. Products lines are available for commercial or consumers and are both paper based (compostable) or plastic based (recyclable). 

Solo is “ … actively involved in developing large-scale applications to make foodservice in public venues greener. … partnership with The Chicago Cubs is a great example!” 

See the Real Fans Recycle” video&gt;&gt;&gt; LINK 

 

 

 

 

 Via: Solo Cup LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:17 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 14, 2012
 
 Certified Green Restaurant at Longwood Gardens (Kennet Sq, PA.) 
 



 

Longwood Garden’s casual dining spot, the Terrace, has achieved “Certified Green Restaurant® [from] … the Green Restaurant Association (GRA)”

I recently had dinner there (it had been a ling time since I had been there) and noticed that they replaced the china type pales and bowls with plastic and compostable tablewear.

My first reaction was “more junk for the landfill”. I then noticed that the table busing area had containers for:

- recyclables (plastics marked #1 or #2)
- compostables (foods)
- trash (all the rest)

The Green Restaurant Association’s mission “ … creating an ecologically sustainable restaurant industry, and … to make the process as simple and effective as possible.   “

Certification includes meeting certain criteria areas including … Water Efficiency, Waste Reduction and Recycling, and Sustainable Furnishings (and more).

 

 Via:  Longwood Gardens LINK and Green Restaurant Association  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:11 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 08, 2012
 
 Sears and Plugless Power™Partner on Home EV Chargers 
 



 

Plugless Power and Sears have partnered to offer installation of wireless (hence the name Plugless) EV car chargers for homeowners. “Aftermarket installations are available now for … Nissan Leaf or Chevrolet Volt electric vehicles, with retrofits for other electric vehicle makes and models coming soon.”

Plugless charging greatly simplifies EV car charging … see video below … the car is driven to the charging “pod” on the garage floor and there is no plug needed!

Sears will install and provide ongoing support services and maintenance. Sears will also provide these services commercial fleets.

“Sears installation network technicians will be trained and certified on the wireless charging systems … ”

See 

 Via:  Plugless Power™  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:28 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 AnmgloAmerican Turns Waste By-Product into Bricks for Homes 
 


 
South African mining company AngloAmerican is using a waste product of coal mining to make bricks for homes. Gypsum a by-product, is mixed with cement to make “ …‘low cement’ bricks for housing in the city of eMalahleni .” 

Operations recover about 200 tons / day of gypsum and at a rate of about 8 tons / house can be used to make close to 25 homes / day.

Estimates are that the low cement reduce 3 metric tons for each house build compared to houses made from traditional bricks.

See this CNN video for more information.

 

Via: SmartPlanet LINK

 Posted by Green Dude at 01:00 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 06, 2012
 
 Recycle Your Christmas Tree 
 



Happy New Year … as the Christmas Trees start to come down consider RECYCLIN G / MULCHING / COMPOSTING rather than landfilling your tree.

Check out their Treecycling Guide …

Check for locations to recycle your tree at Earth911 . Follow the link and enter “Christmas tree” and your ZIP code in the search boxes for locations near you.

 

 Via:  Earth911.org LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:24 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 02, 2012
 
 Southwest Windpower Partners with Home Depot for Home Wind Turbines 
 



 Some Home Depot stores in Texas and the western US will carry Southwest Windpower’s Skystream 3.7 home sized wind turbines. This makes wind power – 100 % renewable energy – readily available to consumers. 

The Skystream 3.7 is connected to the local power grid and ” … has a built in inverter, and produces up to 400 kWh of clean electricity per month … (assuming a 12 mph average annual wind speed). …”

Click here to see the Skystream turbine features.

This video gives more details ….
 
 Via:  Southwest Windpower  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:38 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 25 Easy Ways to Green your Life 
 



Follow the link below for some very easy ways to save energy, reduce your carbon footprint and green your lifestyle.

 Here are some …
- wash laundry in cold water
- turn down the temperature on your water heater
- insulate your water heater
- use reusable shopping bags
 - compost what you can 
 

 
 

 

 Via:  Wise Bread  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:59 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 01, 2012
 
 Green Planet Bottling Company - Bottles 100% Made from Plants 
 



 

Green Planet bottles are 100% made w/o petroleum – 100% from plant based materials. 

“ … bottles … that outperforms other biopolymer bottles … a bottle that can be reused as well as biodegradable in a commercial compost in under 85 days.”

The bottles are:

- free from BPA
- recyclable
- reusable when washed by hand

This bottle reduces reliance on petroleum products and since it is compostable can reduce landfill space … as well as just be recycled

It looks like a good deal for the planet ….

 

 Via:  Green Planet LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 12:32 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 27, 2011
 
 Could Data Centers Heat our Homes and Offices ? 
 



Data centers use a lot of energy to power servers and in doing so generate a lot of heat. Additional energy is then needed to keep the servers and other equipment from overheating (air conditioning or chiller systems). Could the heat from servers be repurposed instead of cooled ?

According to a research paper (link below) “ … “data furnaces” could offer a lower carbon footprint … [in] home offices or office buildings. … servers could … become a primary heating system for these buildings …”

There are obstacle to overcome but in theory it seems to make sense.

What do you think ? Will there ever be a server farm in your apartment building / complex or office tower?

&gt;&gt;&gt;To read the Microsoft research paper LINK 

&gt;&gt;&gt;Fujitsu is using a similar concept for heat reuse – using it to drive data center cooling systems LINK 

 

 Via: ZDNet   LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:25 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Wind Energy without Turbines from Cornell University Prof. 
 



Cornell professor Francis Moon (photo) has done some research on generating wind power wit hout turbine blades.

The research looks at “ … vibro-wind power: harvesting en ergy from the wind as it flows around commercial and residential buildings. …”

If scalable this would might be a source of power in many large cities bringing the generation source close to the point of use. Large citie4s with multi story buildings may have more power potential with vibro-wind than solar as the roof-print dwarfs the outside surface area.

 
 Via:  Cornell University  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 12:32 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 14, 2011
 
 OnionFlats To Design New Net Zero Homes in East Falls, Philadelphia 
 



 

 Design firm OnionWorks was selected to design new net-zero energy homes on a site in Philadelphia’s East Falls neighborhood.  

Plans call for 120 + housing units and retail space with sustainability and low energy use part of the plans as well as proximity to mass transit.

“ … energy for … heating, cooling, light and home hot water will be generated on site, with green roofs and a solar panel array. … indoor bike storage … electric vehicle charging ports and spaces for Zip Cars.”

While not a sure thing plans call for construction to start in 2013 with completion in 2014.

 

 Via:  NewsWorsks  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:24 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 05, 2011
 
 Seventh Generation&apos;s 4X Detergent - Packaged in a PAPER BOTTLE 
 



 Seventh Generation is known for its green products and low impact manufacturing. Their paper package for 4X detergent takes this to a new level.

Seventh Generation has developed a paper container for its 4x detergent. Made from “… 100% recycled fiber. The entire packaging system (fiber bottle, pouch, spout, cap) system uses 66% less plastic than a typical 100 oz 2X laundry bottle …”

A plastic pouch / liner provides a barrier for the detergent and allows the paper to still be fully recyclable.

For those wishing to minimize their environmental and carbon footprint this may be the way to go and make a positive impact.

 

 Via:  Seventh Generation  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:52 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 28, 2011
 
 Energy Hub&apos;s Home Energy Management System 
 



Energy Hub’s Energy Management System lets you understand and manage your home’s energy usage. Web and mobile phone access allow for remote viewing and control.

“ … Home Base … understand and manage the energy use from your major and smaller appliances—down to the last cell phone charger. …”

“… one-touch modes like “At Home,” “Goodnight” and “Away” let you control your home… “

Watch the video below for more information.
 
 

 Via:  Energy Hub  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:33 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 18, 2011
 
 Marriott and Constellation Partner on Energy Savings 
 


 
 

Marriott partnered with Constellation Energy to manage “load response” for over 250 properties including those in the mid-Atlantic area and New England. This manages electricity usage in response to prices and / availability – while keeping guests comfortable.

In effect this is a“Load response is the reduction of electrical consumption in response to high wholesale electricity prices, system resource capacity needs or system reliability events. “

This ties in with Marriott’s sustainability programs. &quot;… dramatically improve the energy efficiency of our hotels, saving an estimated 1.2 million kilowatt-hours of electricity annually.&quot; 

Marriott will use Constellation’s VitruWatt TM  to “ … track electricity usage, bid directly into demand response markets and automate load curtailment strategies.”

For more information on VitruWatt TM  LINK 

 

 Via:  Constellation Energy  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 12:14 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 10, 2011
 
 nest Self Learning Programmable Thermostat 
 



 

The nest self learning programmable thermostat solves an interesting problem. Programmable thermostats should be able to save lots of energy – but they are difficult to program. Thermostats no longer have the energy star rating as the energy savings did not materialize …. 

&gt;&gt;&gt;nest programs itself around they way you live … analyzing when you adjusts the thermostat and using sensors to see if there are people in the house so it can determine when to lower the thermostat

“10% of all U.S. energy is controlled by thermostats. That’s the equivalent of 1.7 billion barrels of oil per year.” … so there is a lot of money and energy at stake …

 

The YouTube video gives more information …

 

 

 Via:  nest LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:25 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 01, 2011
 
 Recycle Broken / Old Christmas Lights / Upgrade to LED 
 



 

HolidayLEDs will take your old / broken Christmas lights and safely recycle them. In return they will send you a coupon for 25% off new HolidayLED Christmas lights.

LED Christmas lights typically use only 10% of the energy of incandescent lights, are much cooler to the touch and last up to 25 times longer.

Follow the instructions on their website and mail the lights to the address on their Web Site for recycling. 

“ … a 3rd party recycling facility … puts the lights through a commercial shredder, which chops the lights up into little pieces. … processed and sorted into the various components that make up the lights (pvc, glass, copper.) …. materials are … transported to a region center for further processing. …”

Help the environment in two ways … (1) reduce landfill waste by reusing materials and (2) get new lights that use significantly less electricity than incandescent bulbs.

 

 

 Via:   HolidayLEDS  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:09 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 27, 2011
 
 GE Looks to Cut Cost and Weight of Rooftop Solar Systems 
 



 

GE recently received federal funding (from US-DOE) to find more cost effective ways to bring solar to homes.

One part of solar PV (photovoltaic) system that they are looking to improve is the inverters that convert DC to AC. Current inverters have drawbacks including “… higher cost, less than ideal efficiency. Research will focus on integrated inverters that are lower in cost and more efficient to help get the cost closer to retail electric prices. 

Another opportunity is to reduce the weight of systems. Systems today are 2 – 3 l bs / sq-ft with external (to the panels) wiring.  GE is looking to develop systems in then range of 1 lb / sq-ft. with connected wiring. These could unfold at the installation site and be ready to install – without the need for heavy racking systems.

 

 

 Via:  GE Global Research LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:44 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 19, 2011
 
 Facebook Energy App–Compete with your Friends 
 



Facebook is planning to launch an app that lets friends see who can use less energy at home. The app is from OPOWER and is expected to be available in early 2012.

 “OPOWER … is working with Facebook and the Natural Resources Defense Council to create an app that will let people share data about how much -- or little -- electricity they&apos;re using at home.”

“ … app essentially builds on how OPOWER already works. …” POWER can download data from smart energy meters to give people a very detailed picture of their energy use and how it compares with others.The app is expected to be available early next year, according to Facebook and OPOWER.

 

 

 Via:  CNN  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:35 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 17, 2011
 
 Infineon Raceway in California Greens Up the Racetrack 
 



 

Infineon Raceway has a number of green indicatives underway including solar power (over 1,600 panels), recycling and using sheep to cut the grass instead of gas powered equipment.

“Since 2004 … has recycled more than 141 tons (282,541 pounds) of materials … “ including 14,000 tires.

“ … partnership with Panasonic Corporation [on a] … major solar installation that accounts for 41-percent of the raceway’s overall energy usage …”

The video below gives more details on the sustainability efforts at Infineon Raceway.

 

 

 

 Via:  Smart Planet  LINK and Infineon Raceway LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:21 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 13, 2011
 
 Mike Biddle Video on Sustainably Recycling Plastics–from TED Global 2011 
 



The statistics on waster are amazing … “Less than 10% of plastic trash is recycled … because of the massively complicated problem of finding and sorting the different kinds. …” 

Mike Biddle has developed a solution to change that “ … developed a patented 30-step plastics recycling system … that takes less than a tenth of the energy required to make virgin plastic from crude oil. …” The process is sustainable, uses waste streams as a raw material, helps eliminate waste and reduces CO2 emissions … instead of oil.

See the fascinating TED video for details …on an efficient plant that can, and does, recycle any kind of plastic.

 

 Via:  TED LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:52 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 12, 2011
 
 Peninsula Packaging Uses Solar Power Greener Packaging 
 



 Peninsula Packaging uses recycled materials and green energy. I recently saw some apples packed in one of their clamshells that noted the plastic was 70 % recycled and made with 50% solar energy.

They own and operate “ … one of the largest privately funded renewable energy solar&quot;farm&quot;in North America. ”

Over the past 3 years their use of recycled plastics and green energy have resulted in some impressive results …

“ … 2.9 billion drink bottles recycled … ..enough electricity saved to power 20,600 homes … over 84,000 tons of green house gas … was NOT emitted in the atmosphere … “

 

 Via: Peninsula Packaging Company Link 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:29 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 10, 2011
 
 King of Prussia Mall (PA) Gets EV Chargers 
 



 The King of Prussia Mall, in King of Prussia PA is getting EV charging statins.

The first 2 in front of Nordstrom and are expected to be available for use in October. Two more are to follow in front of Bloomingdales. 

“ … chargers will be installed and operated by 350Green, an electric vehicle service provider … initially will be free … will partially charge customers&apos; vehicles in 60 to 120 minutes.”

The King of Prussia Mall is owned by Simon Properties Group – they have installed EV charges at some of their other malls.

 

 Via:  PhillyBurbs.com   LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:39 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
September 28, 2011
 
 University of Delaware Reaserch Using EVs as Power Grid Stabilizers 
 



 The University of Delaware is working on technology to enable EV owners use their cars batteries as storage / stabilizing capacity for the grid. 

 The University of Delaware is working with NRG Energy and eV2 on this project. EVs may be able to provide power to the grid to cover peak needs and serve as significant storage capacity for smoothing out peak needs. 

“…resulting in cost savings to electric vehicle fleet operators and eventually other electric vehicle owners and consumers,…“  

The technology works while the EV is plugged in to the charging system…and instead of drawing power would send power to the grid.

“…allow electric vehicle owners to sell battery storage back to the electric grid…at no risk or inconvenience to daily driving needs.“



 Via:  University of Delaware  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:29 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
September 15, 2011
 
 GE and Home Depot Partner on EPA’s Responsible Appliance Disposal (RAD) Program 
 



 

Many communities recycle glass, aluminum and paper … maybe even some plastics.

What about old appliances ? In addition to containing easy to recycle metals some appliance also contain harmful refrigerants. 9 million (+ / –) refrigerators are thrown out each year in the U.S. and most are shredded to reclaim the metal … the foam and other materials go to a landfill and may release GHG to the atmosphere. 

GE and Home Depot have a different approach that keeps an additional 47 lbs of a typical refrigerator out of landfills (resulting in 102 lbs not sent to landfill per refrigerator).

With Responsible Appliance Disposal a refrigerator’s refrigerant is safely removed and recycled / processed. Then any GHG from foam insulation is safely processed and the remaining material is separated for recycling.

“ … Refrigerants and recoverable components are removed … will reduce the weight of typical refrigerator landfill waste by approximately 85%.”

“ … Approximately 95% of the insulating foam is recovered, compressed and can be used as fuel”.

Many Home Depot locations will take the appliances for recycling. For locations see links below …

 

 Connecticut      Delaware      District of Columbia      Maryland       Massachusetts     
 New Jersey      New York      North Carolina      Pennsylvania      Rhode Island     
 Vermont      Virginia      West Virginia 

 

 Via:  GE  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:26 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
September 13, 2011
 
 PrintEco Paper Saving Software 
 



 

PrintEco saves paper when printing web pages. Using software to determine how to eliminate wasted space PrintEco can show you how many pages and pounds of CO2 were saved by “reformatting” a web page.

Saving paper can save money, reduce waste, save printer toner and reduce your carbon footprint. 

“ … track the financial and environmental impact of your printing habits through our web-based dashboard, PrintEco Analytics.”

See video below for details showing a web page before and after PrintEco …
 
 

 

 Via:  PrintEco  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:28 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
September 08, 2011
 
 EV Profiler 
 



 If you are looking to by an EV – electric vehicle – you can use EV Profiles to see how far you can drive b y using your current driving habits to model what you might expect with an EV.

. EV Profiler “ … evaluates your driving conditions as they are today, in your existing car, and predicts your battery needs for the same travel in different models of electric vehicles. …”

EV Profiler uses a sensor called a DDR – digital data recorder. After a week of typcial driving it can predict “ … your electric vehicle battery needs from your … real world driving.”

 

 Via:  EV Profiler LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:26 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
September 06, 2011
 
 GreenSwitch 
 



 

GreenSwitch has an interesting solution to saving energy by making it easy to turn off all power using devices when you leave you home with a single switch.

GreenSwitch allows a single switch to turn off selected energy sapping devices while allowing other devices to work --- like clocks.

A master switch ” sends “ … wireless signal is sent to all of the GreenSwitch™ slave components (wall plugs, light switches, and thermostat) …” This allows you to turn off TVs, printers, and other devices on standby mode at once easily and just as easily turn them baco on …

See the video with Ed Begley describing GreenSwitch …
 
 

 Via:  GreenSwitch  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:54 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
August 20, 2011
 
 GE Opens Platinum LEED Data Center in Kentucky 
 



 

GE’s recently announced Platinum LEED data center in Kentucky is a rare breed. It is GE’s first Platinum LEED data center and one of just a few in the world.

 Materials were over 50% locally sourced, approx. 30 % had recycled content and 80 plus % of construction waste was recycled and not landfilled. 

Approx. 6% of LEED facilities in the world meet Platinum certification.

Here are some key highlights:

“ … reducing water consumption inside the building by 42 percent …”

“ … offset 35 percent of the data center’s predicted annual energy consumption through the purchase of off-site renewable energy … “

“… Outside … reducing water consumption by 100 …”

 

 

 Via:  GE LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:16 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
August 14, 2011
 
 Suntrica&apos;s SolarStra™Solar Powered Charger for Small Electronics 
 



 

 

 

With Suntrica’s SolarStrap™you never have to worry about runnning out of batteries for your small electronic devices. 

Suntrica’s SolarStrap™combines a solar panel with an integrated battery pack to store power for charging small electronics such as cell phones, mp3 players and is“…compatible with most…devices utilizing 5 V charging voltage”

 

“SolarStrap™is…designed specifically for harsh outdoor use.…responce to the…charging challenge in developing markets having limited access to electricity.“

 

 Via:  Suntrica Ltd.  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:39 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 24, 2011
 
 Energy Saving Tips from LifeHacker 
 



Check out the “electric / Gas” section of the referenced LifeHacker post. There are all sorts of ideas for measuring and then reducing your energy bills. Some basic tips (using a programmable thermostat, turning off incandescent lights when leaving the room, raising the temp setting for the A/C and lowering the temp setting for the heat and replacing incandescent bulbs with CGL or LED bulbs. &gt;&gt;&gt; LINK .

 

For those determined to explore a little more and make a more serious energy reduction check this LINK for a post from Jason Chen LINK  He managed to cut 1/3 from his energy bill.  You might find some good tips there …

Remember; unless your energy is from a renewable source, reducing your energy use also lowers your carbon footprint and can save you some money.

 

 

 Via:  LifeHacker  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:34 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 What’s Your Carbon Footprint? See the Cool Climate is Carbon Calculator from UC Berkley for a View into your Carbon Footprint 
 



A typical US household uses 120 barrels of oil and generates about 50 tons of CO2 a year !

The CO2 estimator in the the video below allows, you to model your carbon footprint based on where you live … so it looks at your energy use and how power in your region is generated. You can also see how your compare it to others in your region. 

There are recommendations to to lower your carbon footprint if you want to give it a try.

Here is the link to the CO2 calculator …

 

 

 Via:  SmartPlanet  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:32 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 17, 2011
 
 Ditto Environmentally Friendly Hangers 
 



 

Ditto&apos;s goal&quot;... is to elevate your customer’s perception of your core brand, enriching the consumer experience through smart, ecological design.&quot; 

One of their products is an Environmentally Friendly Hanger made of paper. Retailers can use these in place of wire or plastic hangers and make a statement about their support of the environment and sustainability.

Ditto hangers are reusable and recyclable ...


Hangers are everywhere in the clothing business ... according to Ditto&apos;s website an estimated 8 BILLION hangers are landfilled each year ... companies using Ditto paper hangers can have a very positive impact on that number!

I saw Ditto paper hangers in a display window at a GAP in Ardmore, PA. 


 

 Via : DITTO Brand Solutions  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:11 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 14, 2011
 
 TV Series“The Good Wife”Sets a Green Example 
 



The CBS series “The Good Wife” is a green production. From the practices on the set to the scenes they film they are being green. 

The set has made significant reductions in waste … using soda fountains instead of cans of soda, mostly eliminating paper plates and plastic ware, using reusable water bottles and sending scene / script rewrites electronically rather than printing paper copies.

They even “lead by example” by modeling green behaviors … having characters carry reusable water bottles instead of single use plastic bottles. 

 

See the video for more information … two of the actors and the Executive Producer tell how they live green in real life. This is an impressive story.

 

 

 Via:  Smart Planet  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:46 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 11, 2011
 
 KPMG - Living Green for Sustainability 
 



 

Consultancy KPMG is committed to being green. With their Living Green program they have made significant progress in key areas such as reducing carbon footprint and waste between 2007 and 2010.

Notable achievements include&quot;...reduce ... carbon footprint by 25 percent... reduce waste by 10 percent ... Achieve ... (LEED) certification with 100 percent of new construction ...&quot;Increase alternative transportation by 5 percent

Click LINK to read KPMG&apos;s 2010 Living Green Report.
 
 

 Via:  KPMG  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:07 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 06, 2011
 
 Amazon carbon footprint not ready for transparency 
 



Amazon engages its employees in sustainability but encourages its shareholders to keep its carbon footprint confidential. …
 
…  “The program allows employees to suggest more ways in which the company can be environmentally conscious.”  …
 
Via Time: Carbon Footprint .

 Posted by Green Tech at 03:44 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
July 04, 2011
 
 Arizona State University Targets Net Zero Carbon Footprint by 2025 
 



 

Arizona State University wants to be&quot;Net Zero Carbon&quot;by 2025.

It will achieve this status by&quot;... balancing a measured amount of carbon released with an equivalent amount of renewable energy or offsetting by planting trees ...&quot;

Check out Arixzona State University&apos;s Carbon Neutrality Action Plan which gives details for reaching Net Zero Carbon. 


 

 Via:  Arizona State University  LINK 


 

 Posted by Green Dude at 08:55 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Penn State Research Develops Fracking Aid from Industrial Waste 
 



Fracking (hydraulic fracturing for oil in shale formations) is a contentious subject. But the demand for energy - including natural gas in shale formations is rising.


 

Researchers from Penn State has found a way to use waste from industry in place of sand. Currently sand for fracking comes from mines in the mid-west. 

The&quot;new material&quot;called PennProd would replace sand (lowering the carbon footprint of bringing in a non local raw material) and help eliminate industrial waste.

This process would treat industrial waste and use it in the fracking solution ... eliminating waste that would otherwise have to be landfilled. Since a typical Marcellus Shale well would take 25 rail-cars or 5 million lbs of sand this eliminates a good amount of industrial waste.

PennProd is&quot;...engineered to use waste from metabasalt mines. Heated to 3,000 degrees, the metabasalt forms into molten obsidian spheres. The glassy pellets are then heat-tempered into a hardened ceramic.&quot;
 
 Via:  Bellingham Herald  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 08:30 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 29, 2011
 
 Fisker and EVConnect Partner on Charging Infrastructure 
 



  

 EV Connect, provider of EV charging solutions and Fisker Automotive, maker of EV cars are partnering to bring the EV infrastructure to Fisker owners.

&quot;... EV Connect will install and service electric vehicle supply equipment (EVSE) for Kar

 

ma owners and 47 Fisker dealerships throughout the United States and Canada, ...&quot;

EVConnect will start the process of installing a EVConnect charger for Fisker buyers ... at home or at work. EV Connect is also will be&quot;... the turnkey infrastructure solution for Karma, ...&quot;handling the logistics and permitting and being the point of contact for the EVSE - including maintenance of the charging equipment..
 
 Via:  Fisker Automotive LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:54 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 28, 2011
 
 Airbus Sets Biofuel Goal for 2020 
 



 Airbus along with major European Airlines and producers are crating an initive called the‘ Biofuel Flightpath ’.

The goal is to bring 2 million tonnes of biofuels to the European market by the year 2020.
 The fuels will be make in Europe from local raw materials. Biofuel Flightpath&quot;... aims to establish appropriate financial mechanisms to support the construction of industrial‘first of a kind’advanced biofuel production plants.&quot;   
&quot;... create the first industrial venture ever introducing sustainable biofuel s for commercially competitive operations. ...&quot;
 
 

 Via:  European Commission SETIS  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:26 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 27, 2011
 
 The Dow Chemical Company gets a PHEV Fleet 
 



  

Dow Chemical Company is working with Quantum Fuel Systems Technologies Worldwide to produce PHEV (plug-in electric hybrids). This is a natural&quot;fit&quot;for Dow as they have a JV with Kokam to produce batteries for hybrids. 


The program converts Ford&apos;s F-150 to ...&quot;PHEV trucks powered by Dow Kokam lithium ion battery technology, which delivers the energy and power balance required for these vehicles.&quot; 

&quot;... create and deploy the first PHEV trucks–using leading battery technology ...&quot;

Plans call for the first trucks to be available in December 2011 ... with more than 100 PHEV trucks at Dow by 2012.

   

 Via:  Dow Chemical Company  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:26 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
June 26, 2011
 
 Novel Idea - Wind Tubines on Highway Signs 
 



  

An Arizona State University student has a novel design to mount HORIZONTAL wind turbines on overhead highway signposts. By modifying the existing signposts they can be become wind energy sources. See mocked up picture at RIGHT&gt;&gt;&gt;


&quot;... estimates ... on the highways outside of Phoenix, ... each turbine would produce enough energy annually to power a 700-square-foot apartment. ...&quot;

The idea is that the breeze from the moving cars and the wind can generate&quot;free energy&quot;for the grid - and not require any additional energy use by cars and trucks. In Arizona many of the highways have a 70 mph speed limit.

  
 Via:  DVICE LINK 
 
 Posted by Green Dude at 10:38 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 27, 2011
 
 Dow Chemical Opens Turbine Blade Adhesive Plant 
 



  

The Dow Chemical Company announced it has completed construction of a plant that makes epoxy for wind turbine blades. 

The facility is in Roberta, Ga and is expected to be fully on line July 1, 2011. Material is for both the US and export markets.

 &quot;“Epoxy adhesives play a critical role in the fabrication, performance and durability of wind turbine blades ... toughness and durability to withstand the extreme loads a wind turbine blade is subjected to throughout its service life.”&quot;


 

 

 Via:  Plastic News Link 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:12 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 26, 2011
 
 G.E. FlexEfficiency(TM) 50 Combined Cycle Power Plant 
 



 

General Electric&apos;s new FlexEfficiency power plants are designed to work well with renewable power sources.

Renewable renewable energy generation can be intermittent as it is dependent on wind or sun and can require augmentation quickly. The FlexEfficiency makes use of technology that let&apos;s it run at rates as low as 87% and still be 61 % efficient.  

The technology includes simplified design, construction and waste heat recovery.

The plant is fast starting, highly automated, highly efficient and a range of loads and low in emissions

&quot;... uses an integrated approach to reduce fuel costs, create additional revenue sources, improve dispatch capability and reduce carbon emissions compared to prior technologies.&quot;

See the video at LINK that provides more information. 
 
 

 Via:  General Electric LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:12 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 20, 2011
 
 EvoLucia Aimed LED Ligthing 
 



 

 

  EvoLucia Aimed LED Lighting is not only more energy-efficient and environmentally friendly than other light sources, it is also much more effective. Through our patented Aimed Optics™ technology, we have demonstrated that less overall light is needed if the light is correctly focused on the target area, which allows for more efficient lighting solutions. We have identified an immediate opportunity, particularly in the outdoor lighting market, to supply high quality energy-efficient lighting solutions through this patented technology. We continue to develop and refine our products to serve the market and are actively pursuing alliances that will allow us to drive down the cost of producing our “Aimed LED Lighting” products.

Simply put, “aimed LED lighting” is the method of providing exactly the light that’s needed, where it’s needed. Through our patent-pending Aimed Optics™ technology, EvoLucia optimizes utilization of LEDs to put the most foot-candles on the ground, in the pattern required, with the best uniformity, using the fewest LEDs and the least power consumed.

While traditional luminaires are utilize one single, omni-directional light source per fixture, such as a metal-halide light bulb, EvoLucia’s Aimed Optics™ lighting technology platform uses multiple LEDs. A reflector directs the light in the desired pattern and provides the requisite number of foot-candles exactly where they’re needed.

It is both cost advantageous and energy-efficient to minimize the number of LEDs used to achieve the required number and uniformity of foot-candles in the pattern desired. In order to do this, each LED (or small group of LEDs) must be aimed and focused optimally. The method for doing this is the basis for the Aimed Optics platform.

 
 

 Via:  EvoLucia Lighting LINK

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:15 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 18, 2011
 
 SPD Glass Controls Solar Gain and Heat Load 
 



 

Research Frontiers, Inc&apos;s SPD technology uses suspended particles in glass to react to a small voltage to change from clear to nearly blocked. With voltage is applied the glass is clear.


This would allow for large glass windows for light and letting the same windows block direct sun to reduce A/C load and reduce UV damage to fabrics.

&apos; ...provides exceptional control over solar energy...&quot; 

&quot;... ability of architectural smart glass to improve the energy efficiency of buildings by effectively controlling solar heat gain and harvesting daylight ...&quot;

   
 
 
 
   

 Via:   Research Frontiers, Inc.   LINK and LINK


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:41 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 17, 2011
 
 Dow&apos;s 2nd Zero Net Energy Home in Midland, Michican 
 



 

 

The Dow Chemical Company and Cobblestone Homes have collaborated on a second highly energy efficient home. This one is at 5018 Butterfield Dr. in Midland, Michigan - home to Dow.


The home was build for approx. the price of the average new home in the U.S. - $250,000 - bring ing energy efficiency closer to the mass market.

The home is called“InVision Zero”and is expected to&quot;... to save $2,441 in energy costs and avert 30,233 pounds of CO 2 annually ...&quot;. These figures are achieved using a number of Dow technologies and products resulting in a very&quot;tight&quot;home that is free of drafts (and the resulting heat / cooling losses).

The h ome has a DOE HERS (House energy rating) value of -4. Energy Star Homes have a rating of about 85 and Net Zero homes rate a 0. This home is very energy efficient.








 Via:  Dow Building Solutions  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:03 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 16, 2011
 
 United Airlines Eco-Skies Committment 
 



 United has a green sustainability program called eco-skies. Among the highlights of the program are ...

... over 300 planes with winglets that reduce emissions by up to 5% ... 3600+ service vehicles that are either electric or alternative fueled ... recycling over 3 millions lbs plastic and aluminum from flight service over a 5 year period ... 

&quot;First U.S. biofuel and synthetic fuel demonstration flights and signed letters of intent to advance cost-efficient and environmentally responsible alternative jet fuels derived from biomass feedstock ...&quot;
 
 Via:  United  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:03 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 13, 2011
 
 Dandelions Possible Route to Rubber 
 



 The rubber industry is looking for alternatives to petroleum based rubber as pricing for petroleum is going up fast.

Researchers at Ohio State University, The University of Akron, Oregon State University, Cooper and Bridgestone are looking to see if the Russian dandelion is a route to rubber. 

&quot;...&quot;Russian dandelion ... is being domesticated ... and produces high-quality natural rubber in its fleshy taproot. ... performance mirrors the natural rubber produced from ... Brazilian rubber tree ...&quot;

 
 

 Via: Ohio BioProducts Innovation Center (OBIC) LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 04:49 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 11, 2011
 
 Honda ECON Button Boosts Civic Fuel Economy 
 



 

Certain Honda Civics have an easy way to save fuel .... by pushing the ECON button. When pushed&quot;... the Civic&apos;s engine and other energy-consuming systems are automatically configured to operate more efficiently...&quot;

Better fuel economy at the push of a button ! 

 

 Via:  Honda  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:22 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 10, 2011
 
 Whole Foods Market Recycle Wine Bottle Corks 
 



 

Ever wonder what to do with corks after you finish that bottle of wine? How about recycling them ? Whole Foods and Cork ReHarvest has partnered to set up recycling boxes at Whole Foods MArkets.

&quot;... make it easy ... to properly dispose of cork at all of our 292 stores in the United States, Canada and the United Kingdom. ...&quot;

Did you know that cork production is environmentally friendly as trees are not cut but t he bark (cork) is harvested approx every 10 years from trees that can live for 300 years.

What about the environmental impact of cork recycling - the energy and cost to ship cork back for processing? The cork is returned on the same trucks that deliver so there is a close to ZERO net carbon footprint. So the cork recycling loop is close to impact free.

Depending on the location the corks are used to make floor tiles or other products.
 
 Via:  Whole Foods Market  LINK 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:11 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 09, 2011
 
 Super Energy Efficient Homes from Blu Homes 
 



 

With energy costs still climbing interest in energy efficient homes continues to grow. 

Blu Homes manufactures very energy efficient homes. &quot;...cost on average 50 to 70 percent less to operate on a monthly basis than conventional homes. Performing significantly beyond even Energy Star standards, ...&quot;. 

Lower energy costs translate to lower operating costs, lower energy use and a lower carbon footprint.

Check out the details on the Breezehouse (a green home with lots of natural light) - from BluHomes. Green features include passive solar, high efficiency heating / ventilating / AC systems, solar panels and tight insulated construction.

 
 
 

 Via:  Blu Homes LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:07 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Greenversations - Official Blog of the US EPA 
 



 

Greenversations is the official blog of the US EPA ! Check out the various sections including the Question of the Week&quot;.

A good source for green information you can use ...


 Via:  EPA  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:49 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 05, 2011
 
 EPA Funds Research on Reducing e-Waste 
 



 e-Waste is a growing problem - one significant issue is that it is often taken to other nations for handling and improper or unsafe disposal.


The EPA and the United Nations University (UNN) are partnering to reduce pollution and health effects from improperly disposed e-waste. The EPA gave a 5 year 2.5 million USD grant to the UNN to help develop programs to&quot;... help authorities track shipments of North American electronic waste and provide support to nations in both Africa and Asia coping with e-waste imports ...&quot;

&quot;... improper disposal can threaten the health of local people and the environment ...&quot;

Goals include better tracking of e-waste and better methods for refurbishment and safer disposal.


 Via:  EPA  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:14 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 03, 2011
 
 MIT Uses Virus&apos; to Improve Efficiency of PV Cells 
 



 MIT scientists have found a novel way to use virus&apos; to improve the efficiency of PV cells. The virus&apos;&quot;... perform detailed assembly work at the microscopic level ... based on findings that carbon nanotubes ... can enhance the efficiency of ... solar cell&apos;s surface.&quot;

The virus&apos; are used to&quot;... control the arrangement of the nanotubes ... so they can’t short out the circuits ...&quot; 

Improvements in power conversion efficiency are close to 1/3.

 

 

 

 Via:  MIT LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:14 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
May 01, 2011
 
 Corridor of the Future - Solar Highway in Oregon 
 



 

Oregon has a stretch of the Corridor of the Future - at interchange of I-5 and I-205 in Oregon. Ground mounted solar panels that provide power used at the interchange.

&quot;... 104 kilowatt ground-mounted solar array ... supplies about one-third of the energy needed for illumination at the site.
 
&quot;... energy ... feeds into the grid during the day ... At night ... energy flows back from the grid to light the interchange. ...&quot;

Too see the current energy stats click the LINK 



 

 Via: Oregon.gov  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 03:08 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 University of Nebraska - Roadway Wind/Solar Hybrid Power Generation and Distribution System 
 



 Street sgns and utility power poles are almost everywhere. A project at The University of Nebraska is looking into ways to use wind power and solar panels on signs to power roadway lights and traffic signals. Any excess power will go into the local energy grid.


The units combine solar and wind generators and feature batteries for storage. &quot;... Each unit consists of a wind turbine generator and one or more PV panels mounted on the top of the pole for electric power generation.&quot;

&quot;... overall system involves power generation, storage, distribution, grid operation, and demand-side management.
 
 Via:  University of Nebraska - Lincoln  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 02:40 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 28, 2011
 
 Macy&apos;s to Offer EV Charging Stations in California 
 



 
 Macy&apos;s is partnering with ECOtality to pilot self serve EV (electric vehicle) charging stations.&quot;... two electric vehicle charging stations this fall outside each of six Macy&apos;s stores in ... San Diego ...&quot; 

&quot;... will install ECOtality’s Blink Electric Vehicle (EV) Level 2 Commercial Pedestal Charging stations ...&quot;

 metropolitan area (locations are being identified). ...&quot; 

   

 

 Via:  Macy&apos;s  LINK and ECOtality  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:08 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Green-ness of UK Energy Grid - Live Stats 
 



 Ecotricity is a green UK energy supplier. 

They have been bundling wind turbines and selling the electricity produced since 1996. They are also educating and raising peoples awareness of the impact they can have on the environment by choosing a lower carbon generating supplier.
Changing electric suppliers&quot;... takes about five minutes but it&apos;s the biggest single step you can take to reduce your emissions and protect the environment.&quot;


Click HERE to see the current stats on the UK electric grid ... power generated by (in order) fossil fuels, nuclear, and renewable energy sources as well as the Grams of Co2 / KWh.

On 4/28/2011 ( Thu 28/04/11 @ 12:05 BST) the stats were:

Fossil:         72.4 %
Nuclear:      22.9 %
Renewable:   4.7 %


CO2 / KWh:  415 g CO2 / KWh

How other UK Energy Companies Compare LINK 


 

 Via: ecotricity LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:58 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 26, 2011
 
 TD Bank&apos;s Green Energy Powered Call Center 
 



 

TD Bank recently opened a call center in Auburn, Maine that is 100% powered by green energy sources. The center is designed for US LEED Gold certification. 

Among the green design elements / features are&quot;... plumbing fixtures that use 33 percent less water, drought tolerant plants ... a recycling system that will collect paper, glass, metal, plastic, cardboard, fluorescent lamps and batteries.&quot;

For more on the green features check out the link at the bottom of this post.

TD has also committed to going carbon neutral and is one of the largest US Banks to commit to being carbon neutral.
 
 Via:  Environmental Leader  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:10 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 24, 2011
 
 San Francisco Airport (SFO) Water Hydration Stations 
 



 

 

SFO offers travels free water refills as a way to help reduce the use of single use plastic water bottles and the associated waste / carbon footprint.

... innovative water bottle refill stations provide access to San Francisco&apos;s free high-quality, great tasting tap water. ... some of the purest, safest and best tasting water in the world.&quot;

 

The Hydration Stations are located throughout the SFO airport.

 

  

 

 Via:  SFO  LINK and San Francisco Public Utilities Commission LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 04:55 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 20, 2011
 
 San Francisco Airport (SFO) has USA&apos;s First LEED Terminal 
 



 San Francisco&apos;s new Terminal 2 was retrofitted to be green by design. It is the first Airport Terminal in the US to achieve GOLD LEED. 

Among the green features in the design were waste reduction (achieved by reusing or recycling all construction waste), reduced water use (achieved by a closed loop reclaimed water system for the toilets and urinals that is treated on site) and Greenhouse Gas - GHG - reductions (achieved by eliminating the need for airplane auxiliary power units by providing preconditioned air and power at the gate). 
In addition ...&quot;...food vendors will be required to use biodegradable tableware and source separate all food service wastes for direct transport to off-Airport composting facilities ...&quot;

 

 Via:  SFO  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 04:51 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 19, 2011
 
 Celebrate Earth Day (April 22nd 2011) at Starbucks 
 



Starbucks is celebrating EARTH DAY by giving a free cup of coffee if you skip the paper cup .... either bring in your own refillable cup or ask for your coffee in a&quot;for-here&quot;cup. Either way it is free. Last year Starbucks had 1.2 million participants !  


&quot;... on Earth Day ... inviting everyone to bring in a reusable mug or tumbler and get a free brewed coffee or tea ... hot or iced ... at participating stores in the United States and Canada.&quot;

&quot;... We recognize the impact one can make through careful, conscious choices ...&quot;

If you do not have a reusable mug and want to buy one you can get one for 20 % off and then get 10 cents off each time you use it at Starbucks.

Here is your chance to make a positive impact on the environment on Earth Day and every day !


 

 Via:  Starbucks  LINK 


 

 Posted by Green Dude at 03:36 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 12, 2011
 
 American University&apos;s New School of International Service expected to be LEED Gold 
 



 

American University new School of International Service is expected to receive LEED-GOLD certification.

The building is designed by architect Willam McConough, ...&quot;renown for sustainable design and his&quot;cradle-to cradle&quot;philosophy for recycling and reusing building materials....&quot;.

Some of the many green and environmentally friendly features include: a 33 KW solar energy system, rainwater collection (60,000 gallons) for flushing toilets, LED lighting in the car park, rain gardens, and much more.

Read more by follwing the link below.
 
  Via:  American University  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:27 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 07, 2011
 
 M.E. Heuck Co. (cookware) Achieves CarbonNeutral® Certification 
 



 

Cooks can now buy carbon neutral cookware from M.E. Heuck. 

M.E. Heuck partnered with FirstCarbon Solutions to get a CarbonNeutral ® Certification for its ZEROCA line of cookware. The certification comes from The CarbonNeutral Company.
&quot;... independent assessment of the CO2 emissions produced from manufacturing and distribution followed by an offset-inclusive carbon management program. ... every metric ton of CO2 that ZEROCA produc es is matched by an equivalent, guaranteed CO2 reduction through a carbon offset project.&quot;
M.E. Heuck is the first cookware to achieve CarbonNeutral ® Certification.

 

For more information about FirstCarbon Solutions LINK 


For more information about CarbonNeutral Company LINK 

 

 Via:  FirstCarbon Solutions LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:47 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 06, 2011
 
 Vestas V164-7.0 MW turbine launched (it&apos;s huge) 
 



 

Vestas announced their V164-7.0 - the rotor has a diameter of 164 meters and the turbine produces 7 MW of power. This huge turbine is&quot;... specifically designed for the roughest North Sea conditions ...&quot; 

&quot;... designed ... to provide the highest energy capture and the highest reliability in this rough and challenging environment.&quot;

Veatas has an installed base of 580 offshore turbines - equal to 43 % of all offshore turbines worldwide.

 

For a perspective on this huge turbine check out this video …

 



 Via: VESTAS  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:01 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 03, 2011
 
 Save Some Green - Green Things Store in Philadelphia, Pa 
 



 


Check out the Save Some Green at 2005 Chestnut Street in Philadelphia, Pa.v

&quot;ALL of our products are better for the environment ... Recycled, Recyclable, Biodegradable, Compostable, ... Sustainable, ... Less-wasteful, Local–or a combination.&quot;

 The store fixtures are reused or made from bamboo or recycled cardboard.  

&quot;.... carry products which are reasonably priced ...&quot;

They offer to recycle materials such as # 3 - # 7 plastics and even take food for composting !

Check out their website to learn more about what they do and what they offer LINK 

 

Don&apos;t live in Philadelphia - see their Amazon store !

 Via:  Save Some Green  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:45 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
April 01, 2011
 
 University of Vermont - Green Coach Research Program 
 



 The other day while walking in the city I noticed an interesting large green sticker on a intercity bus. It was from the Green Coach Initiative and promoted the bus line&apos;s&quot;support being and acting green.&quot;

What a great way to raise Green Awareness !


The University of Vermont with the American Bus Association and the United Motorcoach Association launched the Green Coach Certification Research initiative. Companies that meet the standards are able to&quot;Wear&quot;the appropriate certification; such as the&quot;Green Coach Energy Reduction CERTIFIED&quot;label below. 

There are a variety of stickers such as&quot;meeting or exceeding ... 148 passenger miles per gallon ... and ... Offsetting carbon emissions by 80 through an endorsed carbon-trading organization&quot;.

 

Is your bus Green Coach Certified ? 

 

  Via:  University of Vermont  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:41 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 28, 2011
 
 Seattle Mariners Supports Green Initiatives Joins Green Sports Alliance 
 



 
The Seattle Mariners have joined other professional sports teams to form the Green Sports Alliance, an organization that encourages professional sports teams to be greener and make reductions in their&quot;... impact on the environment....&quot;

Members are&quot;... urged to initiate strategies that reduce energy and carbon emissions, ... encouraged to promote their greening initiatives throughout their respective leagues and surrounding communities. ...&quot;
The Green Sports Alliance has its HQ in Portland, Oregon; founding members include teams from MLB, NFL, NHL, NBA, WNBA and MLS. For more on the Green Sports Alliance LINK.

For more information on the Green Sports Alliance visit www.greensportsalliance.org . 


 Via:  Seattle Mariners  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 07:13 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 25, 2011
 
 Beautiful Earth Group (BE) Donates EV Charging Station in Brooklyn Bridge Park 
 



 

85 acre Brooklyn Bridge Park was built with sustainability in mind ... from EV service vehicles to reused / recycled construction materials from prior buildings on the site.

&quot;... Designed and built by BE, ... the first solar-powered charging station in New York City and one of only a few in the world. ...&quot;

Over the projected 25 year life of the EV chargers will save&quot;... more than $200,000 in gasoline costs ... More than 530 tons of CO2 ...&quot;

The EV charging system has 24 PV panels with battery storage for 7 x 24 availability can produce 5.6 Kw. 


 

 Via:  Beautiful Earth Group  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:07 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 22, 2011
 
 BIC®ecolutionsTM 
 



 BIC®ecolutions TM product line is formulated to be green…from using recycled plastic for pen barrels to recycled paper for packaging to water based solutions for the Correction Aqua“white out”.

“…perform to the same high quality that you’ve come to expect from…BIC products…”

Check out their“tips for a greener office”link…

 Via:  Bic Ecolutions  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:30 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Portland, Maine Partners with Ameresco on Building Effeciency 
 



 

Portland, Maine has signed a deal with Ameresco to cut its carbon footprint. The project covers approx. 15 years and is to cost $9.4 million. The city expects to save $17 million over the life of the project.

What is unique about this engagement is that there is no upfront cost to Portland. &quot;Ameresco will guarantee ... cash flows ... will exceed the cash requirements for the project, offsetting the costs ...&quot; 

Per their website ... Ameresco&quot;delivers ... solutions on both sides of the meter ... leverage renewable energy and achieve ... sustainability goals for our ...customers.&quot;

Part of the improvements will be a 2,000 watt solar array at one of the schools.


The agreement covers 45 city buildings and 15 schools.

 

Ameresco is based in Framingham, Mass. 


 

 Via:  Ameresco  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:07 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 16, 2011
 
 These Come From Trees .... Promote Reduce, Reuse and Recycle. 
 



 

I saw this sticker on a paper towel dispenser and wanted to know more about it. It seems this was a grass roots effort that seems to work. From their website ...&quot;... From our field testing, each sticker deployed saves about a tree&apos;s worth of paper (~100 lbs.) a year. Crazy, isn&apos;t it? &quot;and saves about 29% per year in paper.


The idea is to use what you need but not more ... many folks grab lots of paper towels (same for napkins) and toss most unused into a trash can.

According to the blog site there are over 10,000 of these at Starbucks and 10,000 at McDondald. A typical coffee shop or fast food restaurant can use 1000 - 2000 lbs of paper towels a year. I saw&quot;mine&quot;at a local Starbucks (I ask for my coffee in a reusable ceramic mug or my reusable thermos !)

If you are looking for a way to green your office or work site consider buying a few ... !

 Be Green and make a difference.


 

 Via:  These Come From Trees Blog LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:13 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 11, 2011
 
 Joule Pioneers Biofuel Producion from CO2, Water and Sunlight 
 



 

&quot;Joule&apos;s Helioculture™ platform combines ... sunlight and waste CO 2 directly into clean, fungible diesel fuel, bypassing the limitations of biofuel production....&quot;

&quot;... SolarConverter ® ... scaling to desired output levels with no dependence on raw material feedstocks, agricultural land, fresh water or crops.&quot;

Joule&apos;s&quot;platform&quot;makes fuel from sun and CO2 w/o biomass or raw materials. Basically they have engineered organisms that take in CO2, water and sunlight and spit out bio-fuel - basically unlimited fuel.

Joule has it HQ in Cambridge, Massachusetts.

 

 Via:  Joule Unlimited, Inc.  LINK 



 Posted by Green Dude at 05:56 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 10, 2011
 
 Altaeros Energies Airborne Wind Turbine (AWT) 
 



 
Altaeros found a way to capture the wind energy available at higher altitudes. They use a helium filled&quot;ring-wing&quot;to bring a turbine to altitude and keep it stable.

They were a semi-finalist in the 2010 Clean Energy Contest sponsored by MIT.

&quot;... producing clean power at a cost that is competitive with non-renewable resources.&quot;

&quot;... allow Altaeros to reduce the levelized cost of offshore wind energy by 60 percent.&quot;

 

 Via:  Altaeros  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:19 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 07, 2011
 
 Sonoma Wine Company Solar Cogeneration Plant 
 


 
Sonoma Wine Company takes sustainability seriously and works to reduce the footprint of the winery operations. A cogeneration facility is a natural next step.

In this process the heat that passes through the solar cells (PV) is captured to heat water … so electricity and heat are produced from the sun.

Sonoma Wine Company and Cogena Solar have partnered to build the “ … first commercial scale solar cogeneration system to supply renewable heat and electricity …”.

When at full capacity the facility will “ … displace approximately 64,000 kilowatt-hours and 12,500 therms of natural gas annually….”

 
 
 Why Solar Cogeneration? from Stephen Harper on Vimeo .

 Via:  Sonoma Wine Co  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:41 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 06, 2011
 
 Vision Zero - Michigan&apos;s First Net Zero Home 
 



 The Dow Chemical Company and Cobblestone homes have collaborated to build Michigan&apos;s FIRST Net Zero Energy Home. The home uses techniques like &quot;...insulation, sealants, geothermal heating and solar generation.&quot;

The home is @ 3118 Summerhill, Bay City, Michigan LINK 


This home showcases some cutting edge technologies ... but all homeowners can make a positive energy impact on their homes but choosing CFL or LED for lighting, and making sure storm windows fit ... and of course using the right amount of insulation.

 

 Via:  Vision Zero Home LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 07:58 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 03, 2011
 
 All Electric VW Bulli (revamped microbus !) 
 



 

Google Translated from German ...

The VW microbus may come back as a 6 seat all-electric called&quot;Bulli&quot;. &quot;... maximum utilization of space ... driven ... by a powerful electric motor or alternatively efficient gasoline and diesel direct injection engines ...&quot;

 See picture of concept car at left ...

 

 Via:  Volkswagen  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:47 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
March 02, 2011
 
 National Renewable Energy Laboratory 
 



 

After building a very efficient building in Boulder, Colorado, the NERL is building an extension that is 17 % more efficient. How ? By looking at changes in available technology in the last year that can bring energy improvements.

One area for change was the windows. Those in Phase 1 are very efficient but still those on the southern exposure were cold ... changes made for Phase 2 included making them slightly smaller and increasing the thermal break to slow air infiltration that can cause temperature changes. When these savings are multiplied over 600 windows the energy efficiency is significant.
 Improvements were made in the Phase 2 thermal storage system ... they found they could simplify the design ... instead of&quot;... interlaced structural concrete grade beams for thermal transfer ....&quot;... there just now just a&quot;....a large open concrete crawl space.&quot; 
Lastly each occupant is put on an energy diet of 55 watts / workstation. This goes a long way to keeping electricxity bills under control.

Follow this LINK and at the bottom of the page are details on other technologies used in the building.

 

 Via:  National Renewable Energy Laboratory  LINK 
 
 Posted by Green Dude at 07:47 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 28, 2011
 
 Jordache Enterprises Uses Solar for Electricity and Hot Water 
 



 
Jordache Enterprises - owner of Jordache Jeans - uses solar panels at a factory in Jordan. 

They are&quot;... among the first garment manufacturers worldwide to have installed and use solar panels to heat water ...&quot;

A subsidiary owns the The Orchid hotel in Israel which was the first to install solar cells; these generate&quot;... electricity in excess of the resort’s consumption. ... hooked to the regional electric grid, selling excess capacity to the Electric Company...&quot;
 
 Via:  Jordache  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:58 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 24, 2011
 
 Volvo to Offer Diesel Plug In Hybrid V60 Wagon 
 



 Vovlo plans to introduce a V60 wagon that is the WORLD&apos;s FIRST Diesel Plug In Hybrid. 

&quot;... enables the driver to select from one of three modes of propulsion: Pure for electric drive, Hybrid for alternating propulsion and Power for an extra boost from both.”&quot;

The car is to be launched in Europe in 2012 ... no timing was announced for US import.
 
 Via:  US News  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:17 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 23, 2011
 
 Enerkem W2E Technology 
 



 

Enerkem turns waste to biofuels and chemicals ...&quot;converts residual materials, such as non-recyclable municipal solid waste, into clean transportation fuels, advanced chemicals and green electricity.&quot; 

Enerkem&apos;s technology eliminates waste products and turn otherwise unusable materials into useful products.


Enerkem has 2 facilities in Canada and is developing one on Mississippi with funds from the US DOE.

 CLICK to see a schematic of the process.
 
 

 Via:  Enerkem  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:23 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 19, 2011
 
 Envyrozone recycling stations 
 



 

 I saw these multi-stream recycling stations all over the Philadelphia International Airport.  
 

 In one easy to use spot you can recycle glass, cans and plastic (most commonly recycled materials). Very handy with nice appeal to help folks recycle whi le not at home or the office. If you make it easy folks will recycle.

&quot;.... solutions address the facilitation of collection, removal and reuse of recyclable materials as well as the integration of a collection program into a holistic corporate recycling program.&quot;

 &quot;Envyrozone ... believe in LOHAS, a Lifestyle of Health and Sustainability, ... a core principal that we bring to every customer relationship.&quot;

 

 Via:  Envyrozone  LINK 


 

 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:46 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 18, 2011
 
 SolarCity to Lease Solar Systems to Residential Customers 
 



 

Solar systems are becoming more popular as the cost of panels drops and their efficiencies increase. But solar systems are still EXPENSI VE.

While solar (PV and / or hot water) can help save money the upfront cost can be enough to make this a non-practical option for many customers.

SolarCity has a program called SolarLease that&quot;... can make it possible for homeowners and businesses to switch to clean, solar power for less money than they currently pay for electricity.&quot;


 

 Via: SolarCity  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:33 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 16, 2011
 
 Stanford Students Design Recyclable Laptop Prototype 
 



e-waste is a growing problem. When tossed into a landfill they can cause water and soil pollution. Several Stanford University students have tackled the problem by developing a prototype laptop that is modular so it is easily “de-manufactured”. The process is fast and can facilitate recycling the constituent components.

Theoretically manufacturers could use this in “green advertising” to differentiate their product from others.

Check out this video … 

 

 

 

 Via:  SmartPlanet  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:41 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 15, 2011
 
 Heat from Commuters in Stockholm’s Central Station Serves Nearby Office Block 
 



Here is a very interesting story from Sweden. Engineers in Sweden have found a way to recover the excess heat generated by commuters in Stockholm’s main train station.

 

The technology is really not that different from any other heat exchange process but is certainly unique. Certain factors help to make this application workable including the low winter temperatures in Sweden and their relatively high cost of energy. 

The energy created from businesses (like bakeries and restaurants that generate heat) and people is able to help a nearby office block reduce their heating costs by 20%. For a large office block this can really add up … this waste heat from the Central Station is a valuable energy for an office block nearby.

Check out this video of more details … 

 

 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:22 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 13, 2011
 
 Kigo Uses HOYO CYCLEPET for Shoe Fabrics 
 



 

Kigo uses CYCLEPET for some of its shoes ... CYCLEPET is made from Post Consumer PET (#1 PE).

&quot; PET ... most important raw material in the textile industry.&quot; 

Using recycled POST Consumer PET keep plastic out of landfills and reduces the need to use petroleum for new PET.

&quot; kigo footwear uppers, lining and packaging are all crafted from recycled elements. ... CYCLEPET–plastic jugs are [turned] into strong, soft fabric. ...&quot; 

 

  Via:  HOYO LINK and KIGO  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:10 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 12, 2011
 
 EcoCradle™ Green Packaging 
 



 

My son showed me this neat green packaging product ...

Companies are looking to reduce the environmental footprint of their packaging materials and are moving away from foamed PP and PS.

Using a green packaging material is a great differentiator and can minimize the downstream waste that is generated as part of the product life cycle.

&quot;EcoCradle™... made of agricultural byproducts ... from renewable sources. ... is just as reliable, easy to use,
and affordable ...&quot;

&quot;... literally grown , ... uses a filamentous fungi (mushroom roots) to bond this packaging into almost any shape. ...&quot;

When it comes time to dispose of this packaging material you can break it into small pices and add to your garden, put it in a compost pile or even throw it in the trash where it will decompose EVEN WITHOUT oxygen !

 Via:  ecovativedesign LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 07:43 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 08, 2011
 
 Kigo Shoes have Small Environmental Footprint 
 



Kigo embraces the reduce, reuse, recycle approach ...  

&quot;... aspires to be responsible throughout the entire lifecycle of our shoes so our team and all who wear our shoes can leave a positi ve...Footprint 

They support telecommuting (lowers carbon footprint and saves resources) ... use recycled packaging and plastic for shoe fabrics (reduce, reuse, recycle) and use ony enough packaging to protect their shows (reduce).



 Via:  Kigo  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:02 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 06, 2011
 
 Green Super Bowl Party Ideas 
 



What makes a Super Bowl (or any party) GREEN ?


Use technology to send invitations (no paper wasted). Buy local foods (minimize your carbon footprint). Buy foods that use alternative energy .

For invitations use&quot;... Evite or MyPunchBowl ...&quot;

For beer try New Belguim&quot;... brewery is wind powered ! ...&quot;and they are green in many other ways

For serving use real plates or at least real flatware / tableware ... to get a mix of easy to clean and minimize some trash.




 

 Via:  Fun Time Guide to Living Green LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:57 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
February 05, 2011
 
 Martifer Solar and North County Transit District Collaborate on Solar System 
 



 

Martifer Solar USA and North County Transit Distinct (NCTD) collaborating on 482 kW of solar arrays for the NCTD. A combination of roof and ground mounted panels will generate 482.52 kW of power. 

The solar panels are ” … anticipated to save … an estimated $86,000 dollars per year and … offset … approximately 1,141,488 pounds of CO2 annually….” This is equivalent to the energy needs of “ … approximately 104 average California homes per year.”

Martifer has previously installed solar systems for “ … public transit operations including the Antelope Valley Transit Authority in Lancaster, CA and the Big Blue Bus maintenance facility in Santa Monica, CA.”

 

 Via:  Martifer Solar  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 03:48 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Green Banking from First National Bank of Omaha 
 



 

 The First National Bank of Omaha (Nebraska) has as green focus. They have a fuel cell powered data center that is a GHG free power source. They also offer paperless / online banking which can reduce your impact on the environment.

 


Thinking of switching to paperless banking? Know what the environmental impact is…?

Did you know that by switching to paperless / electronic banking the average US household can ovoid using and wasting“…6.6 pounds of paper and avoid producing 171 pounds of greenhouse gas emissions…equivalent of not driving 169 miles, consuming 8.8 gallons of gas or preserving 24 square feet of forestland.”

 

 Via:  First National Bank Omaha  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:32 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 30, 2011
 
 Prysm Laser Phosphor Display (LPD) Technology - Low Energy Displays 
 


 
Prysm Laser Phosphor Display (LPD) technology uses significantly less energy than other large format displays.

&quot;... Unlike traditional technology that wastes light with filters and layers, LPD uses a patented Laser Engine to convert low-power, solid-state lasers into pure light.&quot;

&quot;... Fundamentally different from LED or LCD-based display technology ... the industry’s smallest environmental footprint. ...&quot; 


 Via:  PRYSM  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 07:34 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 25, 2011
 
 Naked Juice’s 100% Post Consumer Recycled PET (rPET) 
 



Check out this You Tube video from Naked Juice talking about their reNEWabottle – made from 100% post consumer recycled PET (rPET).

Made with recycled plastic and fully recyclable … helping to reduce energy and reduce landfill waste.

 
 


 

 Via:  Naked Juice LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:05 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 24, 2011
 
 Naked® Juice: First Nationally Dstributed Brand w/ 100% post-consumer recycled PET (rPET) bottle 
 


 

Naked®Juice is the first nationally distributed brand to have a&quot;...100% post-consumer recycled PET (rPET) bottle...&quot;

The new bottles are called the&quot;Naked reNEWabottle&quot;... and in addition to being made with recycled material are 100% recyclable PET (codes as #1).

The amount of virgin plastic replaced with the 32-oz bottle is 1 millions lbs / yr and when used across the product line will amount to 8.1 million lbs / yr.


 Via:  Naked Juice  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 10:12 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 22, 2011
 
 Sprint eco-criteria Standard for Cell Greener Phones 
 



 

Sprint is developing a standard for green phones called eco-criteria. Manufacturers who meet the standards will be able to use the eco-criteria symbol on the phone…scoring “points”for both Sprint and the manufacturer with the green community.

This is a natural extension of their other ongoing“green”initiatives.

The standard sets categories and as total point level required to be green. The categories are“Reduction of Environmentally Sensitive Materials (ROH), Energy Management, Lifecycle Management, Sustainable Packaging, Eco-Friendly Applications and Innovation.

Points are awared for&quot;...  RoHS Compliance, low levels of PVC, BFRs, Phthalates, Beryllium ... Energy Star qualification ... High recyclability rate, recycling envelop included in box, standardized connector, recycled plastic or renewably sourced plastic content  ...&quot;

 
 

There are 115 available points and 70 or more are required for the eco-criteria logo.





 Via:  Sprint LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 02:45 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 11, 2011
 
 US Army Evaluating Solar Tents 
 



 

The Army and its operations are energy intensive. Getting energy to remote or war ravaged areas is both expensive and dangerous.


The Army is looking into tents that incorporate PV solar panels that can be used to charge batteries and small electronics like computers. In addition to not having to bring in fuel they can travel lighter by not needing a generator (or a smaller one).


Using&quot;... Flexible Photovoltaics (PV), ... convert light energy into electricity ... ideal for charging up batteries, making sure your (communications), night vision goggles and computers are powered ...&quot;

The key is technology that makes PV&quot;panels&quot;flexible so they are lightweight and foldable / packable. While still in the testing phase they may be deployed soon.

 


 Via:  US Army LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 06:13 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 06, 2011
 
 Cracker Barrel to Install EV charging Stations at 24 Tennessee Restaurants 
 



 One key infrastructure item slowing the acceptance of pure electric vehicles is a lack if EV charging stations. Cracker Barrel is helping to build out the infrastructure using locations along highways

Cracker Barrel Restaurants will install EV chargers from ECOtality at 24 locations in Tennessee. Many of the locations are identified … see map below.

“ … will become a major participant in The EV Project, an initiative to increase the adoption of electric vehicles by creating a solid charging infrastructure across the country. ….” 

Dines and shoppers can get “ … an 80% charge … in just under a half hour at … locations which will have the DC Fast Charging stations. …”:

Plans are to start installation in the spring of ‘11 and be complete in several months. Check the Cracker Barrel web site for updates.

 

 

 Via:  Cracker Barrel  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:47 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 03, 2011
 
 Motorola Citrus is One Green Phone 
 



 The Motorola Citrus is one green cell phone. Showing that consumers want green items the phone advertises an“eco-friendly design that is carbon free and made in part with 25% recycled plastic” If you want / need a cell phone why not look for one that allows you to consider the individuals impact on the environment.

“carbon free through a partnership with carbonfund.org; eco-friendly packaging”are also noted.

Less waste in packaging, lower toxic materials add up to a more environmentally friendly product.

 

 Via:  Motorola  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 09:25 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Snyder&apos;s of Hanover&apos;s solar Farm 
 



 

Snyder&apos;s of Hanover (PA) announced construction of the largest solar energy system in PA in October 2010. Covering 26 acres across from their corporate HQ (in Hanover, PA) the&quot;farm&quot;will have more than 15,000 panels.


&quot;...reduce greenhouse gas emissions in excess of 230 m illion pounds of carbon dioxide over a 25 year period. ...energy created ... equals more than 111 million miles not driven by a medium sized car ... 11 million trees would need to be planted to equal the same level of carbon dioxide reduction.&quot;

Hanover is not new to green efforts and already has initiatives that include compostable packaging.


View the Webcam image ... LINK 


 

 Via:  Snyders of Hanover  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 04:28 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
January 02, 2011
 
 Alchemy Goods - Recycling anfd Upcycling 
 



 

Alchemy&apos;s mission&quot;is top turn useless into useful&quot; They reuse / recycle / up-cycle inner tubes and seat belts to make wallets, belts, bottle openers and messenger bags. 

They partner with REI and Trek to take back and recycle inner tubes. You can even take your used inner tubes to REI or a Trek store for recycling.


Each product has a small number to the left of and above the Alchemy Goods logo. That number indicates the % b y weight of up-cycled material in the product.


&quot;... Alchemy Goods bags are, ... recycled. ... we hope you’ll also appreciate our effort to work with recycled materials. Purchase Alchemy bags knowing that you’ve helped limit the consumption of Earth’s natural resources. ...&quot;

 

 Via:  Alchemy Goods LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:50 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 22, 2010
 
 Textile Sustainability with bluesign® 
 



 

bluesign® is a standard for the textile industry that provides a framework for all aspects of the textile process. This standard goes beyond what many companies had developed on their own … and is recognized as the “gold standard” for the textile business. Many outdoor / sporting goods manufactures are supporting this standard including North Face and REI. 

“ …exclude substances, which are potentially hazardous to the human health or the environment … independent standard … can be applied to the entire production chain and that delivers certainty at all levels … leading the way to a successful and healthy textile future …”

Check out this YouTube Video …
 
 

 Via:  bluesign  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 11:11 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 19, 2010
 
 3G Biofuels Power Military Green Strategy 
 



Military is on the brink of a green revolution as it shifts energy strategy to green technology and renewable sources. …
 
…  “The Navy is only testing fuels like camelina and algae that do not compete with food, that have a total end-to-end carbon footprint cleaner than fossil fuels … ”  …
 
Via New York Times Op-Ed: Green Strategy .

U.S. Navy MH-60S Sea Hawk helicopter tests a 50/50 Camelina seed-based biofuel blend at Naval Air Station Patuxent River, Md. …

 

 Posted by Green Tech at 11:09 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 Sustainable Waste Solutions - Waste to Energy 
 



I saw a trailer in a parking lot with the Sustainable Waste Solutions and knew there would be a blog post there. SWS is a local company with a Souderton, Pa address that turns waste to energy (W2E).

&quot;... a landfill-free alternative for recycling, waste transportation, and disposal to companies ... throughout Southeastern Pennsylvania, Lehigh Valley and Delaware. ... we generate enoug h electricity from waste to power tens of thousands of homes per day ...&quot;

W2E burns waste material to generate electric and results in waste that is only 10% by volume compared to the starting amount.

Until we run out of trash this is a renewable energy solution!

See SWS website for more details ... 

 

 Via:  Sustainable Waste Solutions  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 03:13 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 16, 2010
 
 Kristianstad Sweden Uses Biofuels Not Fossil Fuels for Heat and Electricity 
 



 Kristianstad Swede n uses no fossil fuels for heating. Instead they uses biomass from farming leftovers. 80,000 homes heated by biomass and not fossil fuels like coal, oil and gas! And this is an area of the world where it gets VERY COLD !


Since solar and wind would not be effective in Kristianstad they worked with biomass. &quot;... remains from farming ... manure, potato peels, pig intestines, and even cookies, .... to create biogas ... a certain type of   methane , ... heat of the entire city, and to provide electricity for the city as well.&quot;

The driving force for the move away from fossil fuels was to protect their environment and they did not want to import fossil fules from abroad.
 
 Via:  Metrolic  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:39 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 14, 2010
 
 Philadelphia to Get Solar Farm 
 



 

Philadelphia wants to get 20 % of its electricity from renewable sources by 2015.

&quot;... Solar City Partnership will develop a strategy through which 2.3 MW of solar electricity will be generated within the city of Philadelphia by 2011 and 57.8 MW by 2021...&quot;

The Solar City Partnership is a JV between the U.S. Department of Energy and the City of Philadelphia. 

Two Systems under consideration are ...

- a 900,000 kWh solar system at the Naval Yard.

- installations at city owned water treatment facilities (Philadelphia Water Department).
 
 Via: Phila.Gov LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 10:42 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 12, 2010
 
 Save Ink While Printing with Preton 
 



 

The computer has not eliminated paper and printing has a huge impact on the environment ... paper, ink / toner, electricity ... and then the waste once the printed item is no longer needed.


&quot;... tendency to print is not diminishing, ... solution should not try to change the printing increase trend, but suggests means to alleviate its impact on the environment.&quot;

 &quot;... PretonSaver™reduces the surplus consumables which are not required to produce high quality“fit for the purpose business documents”...&quot;

To see some details on the impact of printing on the environment in terms of GHG, waste sent to landfills and the like ... CLICK . 


 

 Via:  Preton  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 08:56 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 09, 2010
 
 Burt&apos;s Bees Sustainability Details 
 



 

Burt&apos;s Bees is known for their environmentally friendly products. They are also an environmentally friendly company.

&quot;... goal is to be the&quot;greenest personal care company on earth.&quot;... by 2020 ... be carbon free and operating on 100 percent renewable energy ... [no] waste to be deposited in landfills ... manufacturing facilities will have LEED certification. ...&quot;

They plan on having a Platinum LEED green building by 2020 ... and recycle recycle wood, shrink wrap, and even waste water.

In addition to the usual paper and aluminum they recycle wood, corrugated cardboard, shrink wrap chipboard and fiberboard. Break rooms are equipped with composting bins and reusable / compostable utensils.
 
 Via:  Burt&apos;s Bees  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 10:13 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
December 08, 2010
 
 Scott Naturals™ Tube-Free Saves Tons of Paper 
 



 According to the Scott&apos;s web site 17 billion toilet tissue tubes are thrown away each year ...&quot;That&apos;s enough to fill the Empire Sta Building. Twice&quot;. Or 20 747s.

That is a serious waste of a natural resource. Scott Naturals™Tube-Free are made without the cardboard core and are helping to reduce waste and save natural materials.

What a simple but great idea. Think of all the energy avoided by not manufactuing and then throwing away all those roll cores.

Something so simple can help individuals make an impact on the environment and save landfill space.

It is better to reduce than recycle or reuse!

 

 

 Via:  Scotts  LINK  


 Posted by Green Dude at 09:54 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 22, 2010
 
 Samsung Evergreen - Green Cell Phone 
 






 Samsung&apos;s Evergreen is one GREEN phone.

&quot;... built with recycled plastics, is hazardous substance free and comes with all sorts of eco-themed apps and tools ... packaging is green, made 80% of recycled paper and uses soy ink.&quot;

 Via:  Samsung  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 10:27 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 21, 2010
 
 Pepsico Dream Machine - Recycles Plastic Bottles 
 



 

PepsiCo and Waste Management are trying to increase the rate of plastic bottle recycling from the current 34 % to&quot;50 % by the year 2018.

A key tool may be the Dream Machine ... which has&quot;... a personal reward system that allows consumers to collect and redeem points for each bottle or can they recycle in the kiosk.&quot;

Currently about 12% of spaces have a recycling container. The Dream Machine will bring recycling to thousands of locatio ns and facilitate recycling away from home - who wants to carry bottles home for recycling?

In case you are asking what you can do ... the numbers are are compelling for individuals to make a change. If each household in the country recycled just 3 more plastic bottles a month the result would be over 23 millions pounds diverted from landfills !

Wow! 3 more bottles a month - that is not hard to do !

 
 

 Via:  PepsiCo  LINK 




 Posted by Green Dude at 07:59 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 15, 2010
 
 Supply Chain Sustainability Management Solution 
 



developed by IBM and McKesson to optimize efficiency and climate impact. …
 
…  “Now, McKesson is breaking new ground by using IBM&apos;s new Web-based analytics offering called the Supply Chain Sustainability Management Solution (SCSM) to simultaneously minimize both its carbon dioxide emissions and its distribution costs.”  …
 
Via IBM: Greenhouse Gas Reduction .

 

 Posted by Green Tech at 09:39 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 14, 2010
 
 GE Makes Committment to Electric Cars - to Purchase 25,000 EVs 
 



 

General Electric announced that they would purchase 25,000 EV by 2015. This is the largest EV purchase announced so far and will get GE closer towards their goal of having half their global fleet being EV by 2015. 
&quot;“By electrifying our own fleet, we will accelerate the adoption curve, drive scale, and move electric vehicles from anticipation to action.”&quot;
The plan is to buy 12,000 Chevy Volts (General Motors) starting in 2011 and then buy from other manufacturers as they are brfought to the market.

GE will initially purchase 12,000 GM vehicles, beginning with the Chevrolet Volt in 2011, and will add other vehicles as manufacturers bring them to market. By 2015 GE will convert at least half of its global fleet of 30,000 vehicles and will partner with its fleet customers to deploy a total of 25,000 EVs.

GE&apos;s Jeffery Immelt says ...&quot;Wide-scale adoption of electric vehicles will also drive clean energy innovation, strengthen energy security and deliver economic value.”&quot;

 

 Via:  GE  LINK 

 Posted by Green Dude at 03:46 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 13, 2010
 
 thinkeco modlet - help understand your electrical usage 
 



 

Thinkeco has a way to find the energy wasters in your house. Appliances are big power users and can even draw power when&quot;off&quot;. Some refer to this as vampire poser draws.

We sort of know that many electronic devises are drawing power all the time but also realize that it is not practical to unplug all you appliances when not in use; or even to be sure which are drawing the most power.

modlet solves this problem.


&quot;... plug the modlet into an existing electric outlet and plug your appliances into it. ... use your web browser to wirelessly monitor and manage your power consumption.&quot;

It is expected that the modlet can save 10 - 120% on your energy bill and pay for itself in 6 months. It is expected to be available for sale on-line and else where this year.

 
 Via:  thinkeco  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:28 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 11, 2010
 
 LEED Green Housing in Phila, Pa offers Electric Car Chargers 
 



 

Sheldon Crossing in Manayunk (Philadelphia) Pa offers the latest in GREEN LIVING. In addition to being LEED certified they offer a Coulomb Technologies electric car charging station.


&quot;... will earn a Platinum LEED certification ... homes will use less energy, water, and natural resources ...&quot; Features include&quot;... solar panels, vegetative green roofs, insulation, plumbing, HVAC, water purification and smart home automation ...&quot; 

The model home&apos;s Charging Station for electric vehicles is the first in the city of Philadelphia. Picture&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;




 

 Via:  Sheldon Crossing LINK and Philadelphia Inquirer LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 08:41 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 09, 2010
 
 Emerson Opens Green Data Center in Missouri 
 



 

Emerson&apos;s data center in Missouri is green ... boasting solar panels, design features to minimize wiring needed and reuse of construction waste.

&quot;... more than 550 solar panels can generate 100 kilowatts ... enough to power the average American home for more than three days ...&quot; 

&quot;... 80 percent of the construction waste ... diverted from landfills through recycling ... .&quot;

LEED Gold from USGBC is expected.


 

 Via : Emerson  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:22 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
November 03, 2010
 
 Save Water and Money with Scott Smart Flush™ 
 



  

Follow the simple directions on the bag and you could be on your way to saving 2000 gallons of water a year with Scott Smart Flush ™ . Smart Flush ™ is a bag that sits in the water tank of the toilet and reduces each flush by 1 liter. 

Currently available in 8 and 12 pack rolls of Scott Naturals.

This is a simple and for now free way to save water and money - and be GREEN.


 

 Via:  Scott  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 03:40 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 28, 2010
 
 GreenBuildExpo Conference: Nov 17-19 in Chicago 
 



 

GreenBuild 2010&quot;is in Chicago this Nov 17 - 19. It is a great chance to hear from industry experts about what is new in the greenspace for green buildings.

Did you know that Chicago was : ... one of the first cities to adopt LEED for public buildings and ... is home to more LEED-certified buildings than any other...

Check out the Video Link  to see what collect students are doing in the green space.  


 

 Via:  GreenBuild  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 06:30 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
 EcoBatt Natural Sustainable Insulation 
 



 

What&apos;s a quick easy way to save money .... year after year? 

Insulate !!

EcoBatt insulation is made from&quot;bio-based&quot;binders - not petroleum derived raw materials and is certified to GREENGUARD standards so it is safe for children and use in schools. 

 &quot;... reduces binder embodied energy by up to 70%, and does not contain phenol, formaldehyde, acrylics or artificial colors used to make traditional fiberglass insulation.&quot;
 
&quot;.... combines sand ... renewable resources, post-consumer recycled bottle glass ... to create ... sustainable insulation…&quot;


 

 Via: EcoBatt  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 04:57 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 27, 2010
 
 Smith Electric Trucks -The Value Proposition 
 



Smith Electric Trucks has approx. 80 years (in the UK) building electric vehicles and has US Operations that have delivered electric trucks to companies such as Staples, Frito-Lay and AT&amp;T.

 Electric Vehicles produce no smog in operation and are very low cost to operate. They have a range of up to 100 miles and are great for city use. 
Check out this video to see what it is like from the drivers side and the business owner’s perspective.  Smith Electric Vehicles on Fortune’s Web Site.
 

 

 Via:  Smith Electric Smith Electric Vehicles 

 Posted by Green Dude at 05:48 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 17, 2010
 
 Yusen Terminals Inc. - First Tenant-Installed Solar System at the Port of Los Angeles 
 



 

Yusen Terminals, Inc has installed solar panels at a facility in the Port of Los Angeles. The specifics:

96 panels
11,800 kWh/yr
emissions reductions = planting close to 6 acres of trees

Live stats of power generation are available at LINK  
 The installation uses&quot;CIS&quot;... cells, produced by Solar Frontier K.K. environment-friendly&quot;next-generation PV modules&quot;... highest photoelectric conversion efficiency of all thin-film modules ..&quot; 
 

 

 Via:  NYK Line LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 08:31 PM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 14, 2010
 
 Quick and Easy Energy Saving Tips for Winter 
 



 Here are 10 quick things you can do to get your house in better shape for winter. Total time to complete is estimate to b e a weekend and costs are in the order of $100 making for a great return on time and investment.

Here are some highlights -&quot;Change your furnace filters ... Insulate your pipes ... Caulk your windows ... Weather stripe your doors ... [get / install a] Programmable thermostat ...&quot;

Do the ones you can yourself and save some money - consider a contractor if some arel. beyond your skill level. Each will make a difference to the environment and your energy bills.

While not on the list - do not forget to use CFLs or LED bulbs ... in my area (SouthEastern PA) they are reasonably inexpensive as they are subsidized (at least at the Home Depot) by PECO (local utility). 

 

 

 Via:  SustainLane  LINK 


 Posted by Green Dude at 05:04 AM | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBacks (0) 
 
October 12, 2010
	</body>
</document>
