<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007136" url="http://beepdf.com/doc/30609/" time="2012-07-13-00:07" support="3" score="0.0017829563951718553" bingtitle="Circle Time Theme: Transportation - Upload and Share PDF ebook" webtitle="Circle Time Theme: Transportation">
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000515" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Materials ... with clear contact paper or laminate. Directions: 1. Ask children whether or not they have been to a fast food restaurant.&lt;br ... the car parts ...</description>
	<body>
		ex: html , ford , diagnostic tips Sign In or Register 
 Report 

Circle Time Theme: Transportation
 
To view this page ensure that Adobe Flash Player version
 9.0.124 or greater is installed.
 Please login or register to make a comment! 

1 Circle Time Theme: Transportation 1. Air, Land, Or Water Materials: Pictures of motorcycles, cars, trucks, bulldozers, feet, saddled horses, wagons, ferries, helicopters, airplanes, hot air balloons, sail boats, motor boats, ships, submarines, rafts, garbage trucks, ambulances, sea planes, unicycles, snowmobiles, dog sleds, sleighs, trains, race cars, paddle boats, canoes, rocket ships/space shuttles, motorcycle, four-wheelers, etc. (note these can be downloaded from the internet or found in magazines).

Green, and blue tablecloths from the Dollar Tree or LARGE pieces of paper in each color. Before this activity begins, cut the blue cloth in ½ creating a cwavy d edge (like water). Use the other half to create a sky complete with white, puffy clouds.

Assemble the cloths on the floor to create a cland, sea, and air d effect. Directions: 1. Begin by asking students about their own travel experiences ( cHas anyone ever flown in an airplane?

Ridden on a boat? A truck? d Etc.) Allow students to share their experiences. 2.

Explain that there are many ways to travel on the land, water, and in the air. Allow each student to choose a picture and ask them to tell the class about it. If necessary provide the name of the object and ... more. less. 
 
some details.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Ask the students where they think the object belongs (land, water, or air) and have them explain their answers. If needed, help them by calling attention to specific details ( cSnowmobiles have special skis on the bottom so they can drive on top of snow. d).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Then have the student place their picture where it belongs. When this activity is finished you will have a cland, sea, and air d mural.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage the students to clear it off and reassemble it during center time. VPK Standards Addressed: III. D.3 Participates in the group life of the class IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings 2 IV. C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions, and events VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (f). 2 Represents and analyzes data VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B. (a). 1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B. (a). 3 Makes comparisons among objects VII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (d). 1 Describes the location of things in the environment 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Favorite Way to Travel Graph Materials: Poster board, markers, pictures of an airplane, passenger train, boat, motorcycle, car, and bicycle. Using the pictures, create a graph titled cMy Favorite Way to Travel d. Be sure to have an cother d column so that everyone has the opportunity to list their favorite mode of transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Begin by discussing the different modes of transportation. Show students the pictures and ask how they are alike and different.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage students to discuss their own travel experiences. 2. Explain to students that they are going to choose their favorite way to travel.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It 9s o.k. if they have not traveled that way before as long as they think they may like it best. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Before collecting the data ask the students to guess which mode of transportation will be most popular. 4. Graph the data as each student chooses their favorite.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Be sure to ask them why they made that choice. 5. Assist the students in counting the names in each column and comparing the quantities to discover the classes 9 most popular way to travel.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Did they guess correctly? This activity can be extended into the art center where students may choose to paint a picture of their favorite way to travel. Be sure to ask them about their picture and write what they say across bottom of the paper.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: II. D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III. A.1 Demonstrates self-concept III.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.3 Participates in the group life of the class 3 IV. C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions, and events IV. E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predict outcomes, and solve problems V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression. VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 3 Shows understanding by participating in the comparison of quantities VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 4 Assigns and relates numerical representations among numerals (written), sets of objects, and number names (spoken) in the range of five to ten VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(f). 2 Represents and analyzes data VI. B.3 Makes comparisons among objects 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Guess the Mode of Transportation Materials: a large gift or paper bag, small transportation objects pictures (tractor, school bus, ambulance, bike, fire truck, sailboat, etc.) Directions: 1. Explain that you have filled the bag with different modes of transportation. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask students if they can remember some of the modes of transportation that you have already discussed and where they travel (land, water, air). 3. Begin by shaking the bag (this gets their attention) and choosing an object but not pulling it from the bag.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Before pulling it from the bag give the student 9s descriptive hints one at a time ( cThis travels on the water, it needs wind to move it, it has a giant sail, it begins with the /S/ sound d etc.) Continue to give hints until someone has guessed correctly and then pull it out of the bag and allow the students to see it. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask students thinking questions such as ( cHow did you know what the object was? d cWhat information helped decide what I was describing? d etc.) 6. Discuss who might drive such a vehicle ( cfirefighters drive/ride in fire trucks, pilots fly planes, captains drive boats, conductors drive trains, astronauts drive space shuttles d , etc. 4 Extension idea: place the bag on a table and allow students to play in small groups.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: II. Shows some planning and reflection III. D.3 Participates in the group life of the class IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings IV. E.3 Uses appropriate language and style for context V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.3 Shows alphabetic knowledge VII. A. (b).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2 Describes some people 9s jobs and what is required to perform them 4. Transportation Thumbs Up, Thumbs Down Materials : 8-10 sentence strips and markers, large cards labeled True with a picture of a thumb up and False with a picture of a thumb down. Before this activity write a statement on each sentence strip (Trains need must travel on tracks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Cars have two wheels. Some planes can land o water. Ambulances have sirens.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Submarines have sails. Etc). Be sure to include both true and false statements.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Begin by reviewing some transportation concepts ( cWhat do we know about transportation? d) and encourage student response. If necessary assist them with reminders such as cWe know that planes have wings and travel in the air.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;What else travels in the air? d 2. Explain that you are going to play a game that will require them to listen carefully and think hard . Tell the students that each time you make a true statement they will respond by giving the thumbs up signal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If your statement is false they will give the thumbs down signal (model thumbs up and thumbs down as you explain). Be sure to explain that false means not true. 5 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Practice a few times using statements about student 9s clothing ( cChase is wearing blue pants today. Thumbs up or thumbs down. d ). Once they seem to understand the rules hold up each sentence strip and read it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask the children cthumbs up or thumbs down d after each statement. Place the strip under the correct True or False card. 4.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When you have finished review the statements quickly. VPK Standards Addressed: I. A.3 Exhibits auditory ability to facilitate learning II.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III. B.1 Follows simple classroom rules and routines III. D.3 Participates in the group life of the class IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meaning. V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Shows motivation for reading VII. A. (c).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1 Demonstrates awareness of rules VIII. B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks 5. Driver, Driver, What do You See?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Materials: construction paper, pictures of different modes of transportation, (hand drawn, from magazines, or color copied from a book) Sharpie marker, Hole punch, 3 round book making rings or yarn, pictures from activity 1 Before this activity mount the pictures on construction paper and add words to each page following the concept of Brown Bear, Brown Bear ( cDriver, Driver, what do you see? d I see a blue race car looking at me. d Yellow submarine, green helicopter, red fire engine, purple bicycle, etc.). Create a title page, punch holes in each page and fasten together with rings or yarn. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Review some of the modes of transportation you have discussed (motorcycles, cars, trucks, bulldozers, feet, saddled horses, wagons, ferries, helicopters, airplanes, hot air balloons, sail boats, motor boats, ships, submarines, rafts, garbage trucks, ambulances, sea 6 planes, unicycles, snowmobiles, dog sleds, sleighs, trains, race cars, paddle boats, canoes, rocket ship/space shuttle, motorcycle, four-wheelers, etc.) Ask students what they know about each one. 2. Explain that you have created a new book about transportation especially for the class.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read the book through one time. 3. Ask students if the book reminds them of another book with which they are familiar.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If necessary help them to see the similarities between this book&amp;Brown Bear, Brown Bear . 4. Reread the book asking students to chelp d by creading d the names of the pictures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Extension Idea: Place the book in the book area so that students can cread d it throughout the day. Encourage students to create their own transportation picture and label it with their name (using books and pictures for ideas). Assemble pictures and add words to create a class book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I. A.2 Demonstrates visual ability to facilitate learning II. A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meaning IV. C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions, and events V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Shows motivation for reading V. A.4 Shows understanding of text read aloud V. B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;V. B.2 Uses letter like shapes, symbols, and letters to make words or parts of words VI. B.3 Makes comparisons among objects VIII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing, and art tools 7 Art Activities Theme: Transportation 1. Tire Track Art Materials: paper, paint, various wheeled vehicles (small&amp;medium sized), additional art supplies (crayons, markers, glue, buttons, etc.) Directions: 1. Begin by discussing tire tracks ( cTell me about a time you noticed tire tracks. d cWhat can tire tracks tell you about the vehicle that made them? d Etc.) 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow students to drive the vehicles through paint and on to the paper. 3. Assist students in making observations about the result ( cHow are the cars tracks different from the big trucks tracks? d cI notice these tracks are straight and these are wavy&amp;how did you make that happen? d etc.) 4.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Once the tracks have dried encourage students to create a vehicle (using art materials of choice) to go with them (on the same paper). Ask the student to cTell me about your vehicle. d (other thinking questions include: cWhere did you get the idea to create this vehicle? d cTell me about who drives this vehicle and where it is going. d Etc.) 5. Write what the student has said on his paper and read it back to him (be sure to write from left to right across the bottom of the page using quotation marks and correct punctuation.) Note: Finished products can be made into a class book entitled On The Road With Mrs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;____ 9s Class . VPK Standards Addressed: I. A.1 Shows characteristics of good health to facilitate learning II.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner II. C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness III. A.1 Shows some self-direction 8 IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaks clearly enough to be understood without contextual clues IV. C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions, and events IV. D.2 Connects phrases and sentences to build ideas V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B1. Shows motivation to engage in written expression VI. B.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VI. B.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 3 Makes comparisons among objects VII. B.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 1 Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experience and exploration VIII. B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing, and art tools 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Make Your Own Transportation Materials: Various art materials (small boxes, buttons, construction paper, empty spools, scissors, glue, popsicle sticks, aluminum foil, tag board, markers, paint, masking tape, pipe cleaners, etc.) Head bands or cbadges d with Vehicle Design Specialist printed on them. On a separate table; set out a collection of transportation books and pictures, clip boards, paper (graph paper adds an exciting element to this activity) and pencils. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to students that they will have the opportunity to design their own mode of transportation . Encourage them to put on an cOfficial Vehicle Design Specialist d headband or badge and use the books and pictures to inspire their imagination. They can draft their plans and ideas and move to the assembly table.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Review the available art materials so that students can plan what they will use. Allow students to create their own mode of transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Ask students to tell you about their creation or design. Be sure to ask thinking questions during and after assembly ( cHow did you decide on that design? d cTell me about your vehicle d cWhy did you choose to use foil for the___? d) 9 4.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Create a special place in the classroom to display finished products. You might print a sign that reads Gallery of Transportation Designs. Be sure to include an index card for each creation with the child 9s name and explanation of the design.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I. A.2 Demonstrates visual ability to facilitate learning II. C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness II.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III. A.2 Shows some self-direction III. B.2 Uses Classroom materials carefully IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B.1 Speaks clearly enough to be understood without contextual clues IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings V. B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression VII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B. (a). Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experience and exploration VIII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B.2 Uses eye-hand coordination to perform simple tasks VIII. B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing, and art tools 3. Geometric Transportation Materials: set of geometric cookie cutters (circle, square, rectangle, triangle, oval, diamond, etc.) play dough, rolling pins, plastic place mats, non-serrated plastic knives Note: This activity requires access to a great deal of play dough.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Please consider making a few batches of homemade dough (in 3-4 colors) before you begin. Here 9s a good recipe: Cooked Play Dough 3 cups flour 1 cup salt 6 teaspoons cream of tartar 3 cups water 3 tablespoons vegetable oil Food coloring Mix flour, salt, and cream of tartar in a large saucepan. Blend water and oil together in a bowl.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Add to the saucepan and cook over medium heat, stirring constantly until it 10 thickens. Add several drops of food coloring until you get the right color. Cook for about five minutes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Take the play dough out of the saucepan and put it on a cutting board or counter and knead for a few minutes. Add flour if it&apos;s too sticky. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Review some pictures of different modes of transportation with students. Ask questions such as: cDo you remember what this is called? d cWhere is this used or driven? d cWho drives this? d cHave you ever seen one of these? d 2. Show students the cookie cutters and review the names of the shapes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain that they can use the shapes to create vehicles. Show them an example or two. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage them to be creative and use different colors of dough. Ask them to c tell me about your creation d or cTell me which shape you made first, next, etc d. Make thoughtful comments and observations about the positions of the shapes ( cI see you placed two circles under the rectangle. d cOh look!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You placed a red triangle on top of the blue square. d). This activity can be extended by encouraging students to create repeating patterns of vehicles (car, train, car, or truck, truck, car, etc) VPK Standards Addressed: I. A.2 Demonstrates visual ability to facilitate learning II.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness II. D.1 Shows some planning and reflection IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (c). 1 Recognizes patterns and non-pattern VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (d). 1 Understands various two 3dimensional shapes, Including circle, square, triangle, rectangle, oval, and other less common shapes 11 VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (e). Shows understanding of and uses several positional words VII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B. (a). 1 Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experience and exploration VIII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks 4. Make Your Own Road Materials: white paint, black construction paper, rulers, a variety of small road vehicles Directions: 1. Begin with a discussion about roads ( cWhy do we need roads? d cWhat are the characteristics of roads? d cWhat can travel on a road? d cWhy do you think some roads have lines? d cHave you ever seen road workers building or fixing roads? d etc.) 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to students that they will have the opportunity to create roads and then drive vehicles on them. 3. Show students the materials and encourage them to make horizontal , diagonal , and vertical lines on the black paper.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Make rulers available. 4. As you comment on their roads use positional words and phrases such as: over , under , next to , etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Once the roads have dried ask students if they want to name the roads and assist them (if necessary) by using white chalk to write the names they have chosen. 6.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage students to drive small vehicles on their roads. 7. They may choose to place several pieces of paper together and create a huge highway.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;12 VPK Standards Addressed: II. C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness IV. C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings V.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.1 Shows motivation for reading V. B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(e). 1 Shows understanding of and uses several positional words VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(e). 3 Understands and can tell the difference between orientation terms such as horizontal, diagonal, and vertical VIII. B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing, and art tools 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Transportation Mural Materials: large bulletin board paper, crayons, markers, old magazines, glue sticks, scissors, construction paper, chart paper, etc. Directions: 1. Explain to students that a mural is a painting on a wall, ceiling, or other large permanent surface.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Further explain that the class will be creating a transportation mural. 2. Using the chart paper, create a list of ideas (what kind of surfaces, modes of transportation, etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;should be included). Help students plan and draw the scene. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage students to share specific jobs (one can draw train tracks while another draws a road, lake, traffic signs, houses or clouds). Discuss what surfaces will be needed for the vehicles they have chosen. Assist them in deciding upon details for the mural.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. On days to come encourage students to gradually fill up 13 the mural with vehicles (created with construction paper and/or cut from magazines). Some suggestions to include: cars, trucks, tractors, fire engines, trains, air planes, hot air balloons, bicycles, scooters, etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Ask thinking questions and make observations as students work on the mural (this project should last several days at very least). Students may wish to add to the mural as they learn about new modes of transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Note: Be sure to discuss the importance of traffic signs and their unique shapes (a STOP sign has eight sides and is called an octagon , a Yield sign is an upside down triangle , a speed limit sign has four sides and is a rectangle ). cWhy do we need traffic signs? d cWhat might happen if we didn 9t have any traffic signs or if people ignore them? d cWhat are some other ways to stay safe while traveling? d (Seat belts, life preservers, helmets, etc.) Extension: Take pictures of the mural process from the planning stage through completion and create a class book or poster. Review the stages with students and encourage them to comment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I. B.2 Follows basic health and safety rules II. C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness II.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III. A.2 Shows some self- direction III. D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children III.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.3 Participates in the group life of the class IV. C.1 Shows understanding of words and their meanings 14 IV. C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions, and events IV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predict outcomes, and solve problems VI. A. (d).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1 Understands various two-dimensional shapes, including circle, triangle, square, rectangle, oval, and other less common shapes VI. A. (d).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2 Shows understanding that two-dimensional shapes are equivalent in different orientations VII. A. (d).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1 Describes the location of things in the environment VIII. B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks Dramatic Play Theme: Transportation 1. Fast Food Restaurant Materials: Pencil, pads, paper bags, calculator, small riding toys, hat, tray, pictures of hamburgers, French fries, soft drinks, hotdogs, chicken&amp;x2 and a cardboard box.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Glue pictures of food on to cardboard box. Place box on top of a table or shelf. The box will be used as the drive thru menu.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Cover 2 nd set of food pictures with clear contact paper or laminate. Directions: 1. Ask children whether or not they have been to a fast food restaurant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Ask the children which fast food restaurant is their favorite and why. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Show and discuss with children the various types of foods that have been cut out for the menu. Based on the types of food offered allow children to create a name for the classroom drive thru restaurant. Ask children to explain how they decided on their name choice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;15 4. Have children cast their votes for their choice of names for the drive-thru. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Graph the results of the voting. 6. Count the votes and explain which name is has the most votes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;7. Write, paint or draw the name of the drive thru on the menu box. 8.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to the children that there will be drive thru employees and customers in this activity. 9. Discuss roles of employee 9s and customers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;10. Invite children to take turns driving (on the small riding toys) to drive thru window. 11.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Children will then place their order from the menu. 12. The restaurant employee will cwrite d down the order.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(remember that children will be using emergent writing and they will be making symbols and letter like forms for letters/words.) 13. After the order has been taken the restaurant employee will place the pictures (from the second set of pictures) of the ordered food on the tray or in the paper bag. 14.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Continue activity allowing children to take turns being restaurant employees and customers. VPK Standards Addressed: III.A.1 Demonstrates self-concepts III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.D.2 Connects phrases and sentences to build ideas V.A.1 Shows motivation for reading V.B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression V.B.2 Uses letter-like shapes, symbols and letters to convey meaning. VI.A(a)1 Demonstrates understanding of one to one correspondence VI.A.(a)3 Shows understanding by participating in comparisons of quantities VI.A.(f)2 Represents and analyzes data VII.A.(b)1 Describes some people 9s jobs and what is required to perform them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;16 2. Road Trip! Materials: Small suitcases, road map, keys, phone, camera, clothing items and other items for traveling, 3X5 cards, pens, four chairs and four belts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Before beginning this activity, arrange chairs to resemble a car, placing two chairs together for the front seat and two chairs behind them for the backseat. Place belts to be used as seatbelts on each chair. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to the children that during this activity they will be pretending to take a road trip. 2. Ask children whether or not they have ever traveled in the car on a trip.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children how they think a road trip differs from a trip to the grocery store or to school. 3. Talk with children about safety while traveling in the car.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stress the importance of the children wearing their seat belts even on short drives. 4. After these discussions invite children to take turns preparing for and taking a road trip.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Encourage language by asking children what they might need for their trip and why they think they would need those items. Ask childen where they will be traveling (their destination ) and whether or not they will be spending the night on their trip.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6. Remind them to cbuckle up d for safety. 7.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Invite children to write a postcard to a friend or relative from their chosen destination. Remind children that letters start with Dear ___. (Remember, children 9s writing maybe made by symbols, etc.) VPK Standards Addressed: IV.D.2 Connects phrases and sentences to build ideas IV.E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experience, predict outcomes and resolve problems IV.E.3 Uses appropriate language and style for content V.B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression V.B.2 Uses letter-like shapes, symbols and letters to convey meaning V.B.4 Shows knowledge of structure of written composition 17 VII.A.(d)1 Describes the location of things in the environment VIII.B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Air Travel Materials: Several chairs arranged in rows to resemble an airplane, hole punch, 3x5 cards, pilot hat ( sentence strip hat, with PILOT written on it) push cart and plastic cups. Directions: 1. Explain to children that in this activity they will be pretending travel in an airplane.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Ask the children if any of them have traveled in an airplane. If so, have them share their experience with their classmates.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Explain to children that during this activity there will be three types of characters/players. There will be a pilot (the person who flies the airplane) a flight attendant (the person who takes tickets and helps with food/drinks) and passengers (the people who are traveling on the airplane).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Explain to children that in order to board (get onto) the plane they will need to have a ticket. Have the passengers cwrite d their names on the 3x5 cards.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Explain that the flight attendant will be at the front of the plane and that he/she will hole punch their ticket, allowing them to board the plane. 6.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After the passengers are seated the pilot can let the passengers know that the plane is taking off. 7. The flight attendant may begin beverage service (delivering drinks to passengers).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The flight attendant may push the beverage cart down the aisle (in between the rows of seats) and ask the passengers what they would like to drink. This can be done with empty plastic cups. 8.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Continue activity allowing children to change roles. VPK Standards Addressed: II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.D.2 Initiates, asks questions and responds to adults and peers in a variety of settings 18 V.B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression V.B.3 Demonstrates age-appropriate ability to write letters VII.A.(b)2 Describes some people 9s jobs and what it takes to perform them VIII.B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing and art tools 4. Creating a Mode of Transportation Materials: Large boxes, paint, paintbrushes, markers, construction paper, glue and scissors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Children will use the materials to create a mode of transportation. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow children to use materials as they see fit. However, do ask them questions that encourage language and cognitive skills. For example: Tell me about your mode of transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Where does it travel? How does it work? How many wheels is it going to have?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children what they did first , second , etc. in creating their mode of transportation. Talk to children about the geometric shapes they used to create tires, wheels, steering wheels, doors, headlights, wings, license plate, etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Ask children to cname d or label their transportation. Allow them to cwrite d the name on a piece of paper or on the creation itself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. When the children 9s creations are dry, allow them to climb inside and pretend take their mode of transportation for a drive, flight or cruise. VPK Standards Addressed: II.C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.2 Shows some self-direction III.B.2 Uses classroom materials carefully IV.C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions and events IV.E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predict outcomes and resolve conflicts V.B.2 Uses letter-like shapes, symbols and letters to convey meaning VI.A(a)1 Demonstrates understanding of one to one correspondence VI.A.(a)6 Shows an understanding of and uses appropriate terms to describe ordinal positions VI.A(d)1 Understands various two-dimensional shapes, including circle, 19 triangle, square, rectangle and oval VII.B.(a)1 Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experience and exploration 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Building Structures for Transportation Bringing dramatic play into block area Micro-dramatic play Materials: Block center, paper, pencils/markers, small cars, trucks, tractors, bulldozers, motorcycles, boats, trains etc. Directions: 1. Begin this activity with a discussion of the structures used by different modes of transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For example: Bridges, tunnels, overpasses, highways, runways, tracks etc. Invite children to add their ideas for other structures. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In block center allow children time and materials to create structures for small cars, trucks, trains. 3. Encourage language development by asking children about the structures that they have built.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow children time to explain how and why they created their structure. If children are not using shapes, positional, ordinal and describing words, ask questions to facilitate that type of language development and cognitive skills. For example: Tell me about your structure?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Where does the car/truck travel? What made you decide to put that long rectangle block there? When did you add the small square blocks to the top?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Allow children to label their structures with the structure name and/or their name. VPK Standards Addressed: II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.2 Shows some self-direction III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions and events V.B.1 Shows motivation to engage in written expression V.B.2 Uses letter-like shapes, symbols and letters to convey meaning VI.A.(a)6 Shows an understanding of and uses appropriate terms to describe ordinal positions 20 VI.A.(d)1 understands various two-dimensional shapes including circle, triangle, square, rectangle and oval VI.A.(e)2 Describes relative positions from different perspectives VIII.B.2 Uses eye-hand coordination to perform tasks Sensory Activities Theme: Transportation 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Construction Site Materials: Sand/water table, sand, gravel, rocks, small trucks, tractors, bulldozers, paper and pencils/markers and small building blocks. Directions: 1. Ask children if they have ever seen a construction site (Where something is going to be built) 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Encourage language development by asking children questions about where they have seen construction sites, what was going at the construction sites, what modes of transportation were at the construction sites and how the construction site changes over time and what is the sites end result.(New store, new home etc.) 3. While children are engaged at the cconstruction site d observe how they are using materials. Ask children open ended questions about how they are using the modes of transportation and what is happening at their construction site.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Extended children 9s language by asking them to describe the different textures and weight of the gravel, rocks and sand etc. 4. After their site has been cleared/prepared invite children to build their structure on the construction site, 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow children to name or label their construction sites, writing their name or their sites name on paper with pencils/markers. VPK Standards Addressed: II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.1 Shows some self-concept III.A.2 Shows some self-direction 21 III.B.2 Uses classroom materials carefully IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV.C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meaning V.B.1 Uses letter-like shapes, symbols and letters to convey meaning VI.B.(a)1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore Materials and natural phenomena VI.B.(a)2 Uses simple tools and equipment for investigation VI.B.3 Makes comparisons among objects VII.A.(b)2 Describes some people 9s job and what is required to perform them VII.A.(d)2 Shows awareness of the environment VIII.B.2 Uses eye-hand coordination to perform tasks 2. Aluminum Foil Watercrafts Materials: Water table, blue food coloring (add to water) aluminum foil, markers, chart paper and small paper.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Begin this activity by discussing watercrafts with children. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Invite children to give examples of different types of watercrafts, reminding children that watercrafts are modes of transportation. 3. Explain to children that for this activity they will be creating watercrafts from aluminum foil.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Provide children with markers and paper in order to design their own aluminum foil watercraft. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children thinking questions about their designs. What made you decide to design this type of watercraft? What will this type of watercraft used for?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6. Allow children to create their watercraft out of aluminum foil and to launch (put the craft in the water) their watercraft in the water table. 7.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children to compare their drawn design to their created design. Ask children what caused them to them the changes 22 that they did. Remember that it is O.K.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;if drawn design and created design look different. VPK Standards Addressed: II.C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.2 Shows some self-direction IV.B.1 Speaks clearly enough to be understood without contextual clues. IV.E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predict outcomes and solve problems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VI.A.(e)2 Describes relative position from different perspectives VI.B.(a)3 Makes comparisons among objects VII.B.(a)1 Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experiences and exploration VIII.B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks VIII.B.3 Shows beginning control of writing, drawing and art tools 3. Tasty Trucks Materials: Oranges, bananas, graham crackers, cream cheese, paper plates, plastic bowls, plastic knives and food coloring (optional) Directions: 1. Invite children, two or three at a time, to come to snack table, Explain to children that they will be making a car or a truck snack.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Help children to slice the fruit into rounds (circles). Ask children how they might use these slices in their design.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Have children carefully break the graham crackers into squares and rectangles.. Ask children how they might use these shapes in their design.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Have children spread cream cheese onto crackers to use as paint and/or glue. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow children to create their own eatable car/truck using oranges and bananas as wheels, steering wheels etc. 6. After children 9s have completed their vehicle ask them to 23 recall their process for making their vehicle.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;What did they do first, second, etc ? Ask children if they can count the number of circles, squares and rectangles that they used. Ask children if they used more circles or more rectangles?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I.B.2 Follows basic health and safety rules I.B.4 Makes wise food choices I.B.5 Performs some self-care tasks independently II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection IV.A.2 Follows two and three step directions IV.B.1 Speaks clearly enough to be understood with contextual clues IV.D.1 Uses age appropriate grammar in conversations VI.A.(a)1 Demonstrates understanding of one to one correspondence VI.A.(a)3 Shows an understanding by participating in the comparisons of quantities VI.A.(a)6 Shows an understanding of and uses appropriate terms to describe ordinal positions VI.A.(d)1 Understands various two-dimensional shapes including circle, triangle, square and rectangle VI.A.(d)2 Shows an understanding that two-dimensional shapes are equivalent in different orientations VIII.B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks 4. Tracks a Tire Makes Materials: Small cars, trucks, paint, mud, shaving cream, silly putty and cookie sheets for each substance. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Introduce the substances that will be used in this activity. Ask children how substances are used and some of the characteristics of the substances. For example: Shaving cream- cMy Daddy uses it when he shaves. d cWe use it to clean the tables at school. d cIt smells good and it is white and fluffy. d 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Place one substance and car/truck per cookie sheet. 24 3. Allow children to roll the cars/trucks through the different substances.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Ask children to describe the differences in the tracks made by the different substances. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children thinking questions as to why they think why the tracks differ from one substance to another. VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.1 Demonstrates visual ability to facilitate learning II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner III.C.1 Interacts easily with familiar adults IV.B.1 Speaking clearly enough to be understood IV.C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many object, actions and events VI.B.(a)1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VII.A.(d)1 Describes the location of things in the environment VII.B.(a) Uses a variety of art materials for tactile experiences and exploration VIII.B.3 Shows eye-hand coordination 5. Water Table Car Wash Materials: Water table, scrub brushes, dishwashing liquid (or other type of soap), small cars and trucks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You can do this after the activity of tire track art . Directions: 1. Prepare water by adding dishwashing liquid/soap.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Allow children to place small cars and trucks into soapy water. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Invite children to use scrub brushes to clean the cars and trucks. 4. While children are scrubbing the cars and trucks, talk with them about the parts of the cars and trucks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For example: Roof, tires, wheels, hood, chrome, headlights, bumpers, bed etc. 5. Encourage children to indentify the car parts as they scrub them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.1 Shows characteristics of good health to facilitate learning 25 II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions and events VI.B.(a)1 Asks question and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VIII.B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks VIII.B.2 Uses eye-hand coordination to perform tasks Movement and Music/Gross Motor Theme: Transportation 1. I 9m a Little Airplane Materials: Chart paper, markers and words to song. Before beginning this activity, write song on chart paper using words and pictures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I 9m a Little Airplane (tune; I 9m a Little Teapot) I 9m a little airplane (raise arms at sides to shoulder height) Now watch me fly! ( spin one arm in front of them like a propeller) Here are my instruments From down low to up high (with arm reach from the ground to above their heads) First I get revved up (make engine noises) Then I can fly (raise arms to shoulder height and spin arms around) Lifting off the runway (start walking forward) Up to the sky! (walk on tiptoes around circle until back in original positions) Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read through song using the ccrisp pointing d technique. Crisp pointing is a technique where the teacher points to the first letter in each word as she reads. This technique allows children to see where each word begins and to realize that sentences are made up of different words.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stop to 26 explain words that may not be familiar to children. Also, explain movements that children will be doing. Instruments - Buttons and knobs that control the airplane Revved -Started up Runway - A long road where the plane goes fast enough to take off 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read through song again allowing you and children to engage in the movements. 3. Repeat as wanted VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.1 Shows characteristics of good health to facilitate learning I.B.1 Shows that basic physical needs are met III.D.3 Participates in group life of class IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV.A.2 Follows two and three step directions V.A.4 Shows understanding of text read aloud VI.A.(e)4 Uses directions to move through space and find places in space VII.A.(c)1 Shows an awareness of rules VII.B.(a)2 Participates in group music experiences VII.B(a)3 Participates in creative movement, dance and drama VII.A.1 Moves with balance and control VIII.A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Can Fly Can 9t Fly Materials: None needed Suggested items to name/say: Airplane, boat, canoe, motorcycle, bike, jet, helicopter, tractor, train, dump truck, sea plane, van, scooter, blimp, snowmobile, hot air balloon, car, space shuttle, truck etc. Directions: 1. Gather children and have them form a circle.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Discuss with children the modes of transportation that you will be using for this activity. Ensure that children are familiar with the different items and where they travel (land, water or air).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Explain to children that they will be cflying d around in a circle until you say the name of something that DOES NOT fly. 4.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When you say the name of something that DOES NOT fly the children will slow down and softly land on the ground. 27 5. When you say the name of something that DOES fly the children should begin to cfly d around the circle again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6. Continue as long as you and the children wish. VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.3 Exhibits auditory ability to facilitate learning I.B.3 Participates in physical fitness activities III.B.1 Follows simple classroom rules and routines III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings VI.A.(e)1 Shows understanding of and uses several positional words VI.B.3 Makes comparisons among objects VIII.A.1 Moves with balance and control VIII.A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We 9re Riding on the Bus Materials: Chart paper, markers. Song on written on chart paper using words and pictures. We 9re Riding On The Bus (Tune: If You 9re Happy and You Know It) Oh, we 9re riding on the bus, on the bus.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Oh, we 9re riding on the bus, on the bus. Oh, we 9re riding on the bus. Come ride along with us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Oh, we 9re riding on the bus, on the bus. Repeat substituting words such as: clapping, bouncing, steering, laughing, smiling, leaning etc. Directions: 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read through song one time using the ccrisp pointing d technique described in #1 of Music and Movement. 2. Ask children of the meanings of steering, bouncing and leaning, adding language when necessary.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With children 9s input decide how the substituted words will be performed. 3. Sing song and have children perform substituted movements as practiced.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children if they can recall what action they performed first, second&amp;28 4. Invite children to brainstorm for more actions and movements. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask class if they can think of other modes of transportation that could be substituted for bus in the song. Remind children that they will need to think a word to rhyme with their mode of transportation. For example: Oh, we 9re riding on a train&amp;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I hope it doesn 9t rain&amp;Oh, we 9re riding on a boat&amp;I know that it will float&amp;6. Invite children 9s ideas for movements for added modes of transportation. VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.1 Shows characteristics of good health I.B.3 Participates in physical fitness activities II.C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness III.C.1 Interacts easily with familiar adults IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV.C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings IV.C.2 Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions and events V.A.2 Shows age-appropriate phonological awareness VI.A.(a)6 Shows understanding of and uses appropriate terms to describe ordinal positions VII.B.(a)2 Participates in group music experiences VIII.A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks 4.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moving Like a Train Materials: Chart paper and markers Directions: 1. Ask children whether they have ever seen a train or ridden on a train. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children to describe how trains move, how trains sound, where trains travel (on tracks) and what trains might carry inside their cars etc. Ask children if they know the name of the first car of the train (engine). Then ask if they know the name of the last car of the train (caboose).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Also, introduce names of other cars of the train (coal car, box car, freight train, cattle car, tank car). 3. Create a list on chart paper of what the children know about trains.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Saying and spelling words as you write them. 29 4. Tell children that now the class will try to move and sound like a train.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Invite children make a line and then place their hands on the shoulders on the friend in front of them. 6.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Have children move with short sliding steps. 7. Next have children make the cchug, chug d sound and whistle like a train.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner III.D.1 interacts easily with one or more children IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV.C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meanings IV.E.2 Initiates, asks questions and responds to adults and peers in an variety of settings VI.A(a)6 Shows understanding of and uses appropriate terms to describe ordinal positions VI.A.(e)4 Uses directions to move through space and find places in space VII.B.(a)3 Participates in creative movement, dance and drama VIII.A.1 Moves with balance and control 5. Boat Movements Materials: Chart paper, markers and list of types of boats. Find pictures or draw pictures for as many types of boats as possible.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sailboat Motorboat Tugboat Tanker Barge Rowboat Canoe Directions: 1. Talk with children about various types of boats. Ask children what information they can give about the listed boats.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While you are discussing each boat, point to the word and to the picture. Ask children if they can think of any boats that 30 are not on the list. If so, add these boats to the list and spell out the words as you write them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Ask children to think about how the boats are the same and how they are different. For example: Same: Different: Are boats Sizes In water Shapes Float Made of different materials Leisure Work 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Invite children to give ideas of how they think the different types of boats might move and sound or the actions of the passengers on the boats. For example: Sailboat-Sway arms like a sail blowing in the breeze Motorboat-Make sound like a motor Tugboat-Push pull motion Tanker- Spread arms wide Barge-Arms straight out in front Rowboats-Rowing motion, both arms together Canoe-Paddling motion one side at a time 4. Point to the different types of boats on the list and have children make the sounds or motions agreed upon.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I.B.1 Shows that physical needs or met II.A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.1 Shows some self-concept IV.B.1 Speaks clearly enough be understood IV.C. Uses an expanded vocabulary to describe many objects, actions and events IV.E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predicts outcomes and solves problems IV.E.3 Uses appropriate language and style for context V.A.1 Shows motivation for reading VI.B.(a)3 Makes comparisons among objects VII.A.(d)1 Describes the location of things in the environment 31 Outdoor Activities Theme: Transportation 1. Flight Distance Materials: inexpensive balsa wood gliders (Dollar tree or WalMart) or teacher made paper airplanes, long unit blocks (all the same size), or 10-15 foot long pieces of yarn, clip board, paper, pencil.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If you are going to use paper airplanes allow students to decorate a piece of white paper and fold it into an airplane for them. Directions: 1. Explain to students that they are going to take the planes outside and measure how far they fly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Further explain that you will be using blocks or yarn to measure distance . 2. Before leaving for outside hold up one airplane and ask how many blocks or yarn lengths they think it will travel.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Write down their guesses. Fly the airplane across the room and use your non standard measuring tool (blocks or yarn) to measure the distance (remember that the measuring tools must all be the same length). Review the guesses and see if they were close.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. Take the class outside and allow students to fly their planes. Help them record their guesses, measure, and review their distances.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Compare the distances, c John 9s airplane flew a distance of 8 blocks and Brooke 9s flew a distance of 10 blocks. Who 9s plane flew farthest? d Use positional words to assist the students in making observations about where the plane landed ( cLook, your plane flew over the picnic table and landed under the tree d) .&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Allow students to experiment with the planes until they lose interest. 32 VPK Standards Addressed: I.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.2 Exhibits visual ability to facilitate learning. II. A.1 Shows eagerness and curiosity as a learner.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;II. D.1 Shows some planning and reflection. III.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children. III. D.3 Participates in the group life of the class.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VI. A. (e).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1 Shows understanding of and uses several positional words. VI. A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(f). 1 Compares continuous quantities using length, weight, and height. VI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;B. (a). 1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VI. B. (a).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2 Uses simple tools and equipment for investigation. VI. B.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(a). 3 Makes comparisons among objects. VII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A. (d). 1 Describes the location of things in the environment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VIII. A.1 Moves with balance and control. VIII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks. 33 2. Riding Toy Wash Materials: Riding toys, buckets, water, dishwashing liquid/soap, sponges, drying towels, chart paper and marker.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Explain to children that this activity is like washing a car. 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children if they have ever been to a carwash, if they have ever seen someone wash a car or if they have helped someone wash a car. 3. Explain to children that they will be using the riding toys for this activity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Ask children to help to create a list of materials/supplies needed to wash a car. Ask children name materials/supplies and write the items on a piece of chart paper.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children the beginning sound or letter of each item before you write it. 5. Allow children to drive to the carwash and then wash their riding toys.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6. After the children finish washing the riding toys, allow them finish the job by drying the riding toy with drying towel. VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.1 Shows characteristics of good health to facilitate learning II.D.1 Shows some planning and reflection III.A.1 Demonstrates self-concept V.A.2 Shows age-appropriate phonological awareness VI.B.(a)1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VII.A.(b)2 Describes some people 9s jobs and what is required to perform them VIII.A.1 Moves with balance and control 34 VIII.A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks VIII.B.1 Uses strength and control to perform simple tasks VIII.B.2 Uses eye-hand coordination to perform tasks 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Red Light Green Light 3Traffic Light Materials: Construction paper (red, yellow, green cut into circles), large craft sticks and glue. Glue circles onto craft sticks. (One circle per craft stick).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Before beginning this activity, talk with children about traffic signals/lights. Ask them if they have seen traffic signals.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask them where they have seen traffic signals and why they think traffic signals are necessary. 2. Ask children if they know what the different color lights stand for.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For example: green means GO, yellow means SLOW DOWN and red means STOP. 3. This game is played like cRed Light Green Light d except you will use the colored traffic lights to direct the children to GO, STOP and SLOW DOWN.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Have children line up, horizontally approximately 20 feet from where the teacher will be holding traffic signs. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The teacher will hold up traffic signs one at a time and have children either walk quickly (green light) slow down (yellow light) or stop (red light). 6. When the children reach the traffic signals the game is over and it can be repeated.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: I.A.12 Demonstrates visual ability to facilitate learning I.B.3 Participates in physical fitness activities III.A.1 Demonstrates self-concept 35 III.D.1 Interacts easily with one or more children IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening VI.A.(e)4 Uses directions to move through space and finds places in space VII.A.(c)1 Demonstrates awareness of rules VII.A.(d)1 Describes the location of things in the environment VIII.A.1 Moves with balance and control 4. Paper Plate Driving Materials: Sturdy paper plates, red, green and yellow paint of markers. Paint or color several paper plates red, yellow and green.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Directions: 1. Before beginning this activity place colored (red, yellow, green) paper plates around playground at children 9s eye level. These colored plates can be placed on fences, trees, buildings, easels etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Review the meanings of the red, yellow and green lights with children. 3.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children to explain the purpose of traffic signals. 4. Walk around playground with children pointing out the locations and colors of the traffic signals.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ask children whether or not the colors of the signals are placed in pattern. For example: Green, yellow, red, green, yellow, red etc. (They do not have to placed in a pattern, just ask children whether or not there is a pattern to the placement).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. Allow children to walk around playground using the plain paper plates as their steering wheels. 6.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When children cdrive d to the traffic signals they should obey rules of the road depending on the signals color. Red/Stop, Yellow/SLOW DOWN, Green/GO. 36 VPK Standards Addressed: I.B.2 Follows basic health and safety rules I.B.3 Participates in physical fitness activities III.A.2 Shows some self-direction IV.C.1 Shows an understanding of words and their meaning VI.A.(c)1 Recognizes patterns and non-patterns VI.A.(e)4 Uses directions to move through space and find places in space VI.B.3 Makes comparisons among objects VII.A.(c)1 Demonstrates awareness of rules VII.A.(d)1 Describes the location of things in the environment VIII.A.1 Moves with balance and control VIII.A.2 Coordinates movements to perform simple tasks 5 .&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ramps or Inclined Planes Materials: Small and medium cars and trucks, long rectangle unit blocks, long narrow boards and something to elevate one end of the ramp/incline (milk crate, bricks etc.) Create several ramps/inclines at different heights. Directions: 1. Introduce the concept of ramps/inclined planes to children.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to children that ramps are another name for inclined planes. An inclined plane or ramp is a simple machine. It is a flat surface whose endpoints are at different heights.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For example: a wheelchair ramp at school or a store. Moving an object up an inclined plane is much easily than moving the object vertically. 37 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explain to children that the steeper the incline the faster an object will move down the incline. 3. Set up several inclines at different heights and let children predict the incline that the objects will move down the fastest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. Place a small car or truck on various inclines to see if the children 9s predictions were correct. 5.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Continue the activity by allowing children to use inclines, cars, trucks and by creating inclines on their own. 6. Ask children to make their predictions for the new inclines that they created.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;VPK Standards Addressed: II.C.1 Approaches tasks with flexibility and inventiveness III.A.2 Shows some self-direction III.B.2 Uses classroom materials carefully IV.A.1 Gains meaning by listening IV.E.1 Uses language to express needs and feelings, share experiences, predict outcomes and solve problems. VI.B.(a)1 Asks questions and uses senses to observe and explore materials and natural phenomena VI.B.(a)2 Uses simple tools and equipment for investigation VI.B.(a)3 Makes comparisons among objects 38 Books About Transportation Big Book of Transportation 3 D.K. Publishing We All Go Traveling - Sheena Roberts&amp;Siobhan Bell Transportation (Around the World Series)- Margaret C.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hall How Will We Get to the Beach? - Brigitte Luciani&amp;Eve Tharlet Always Got My Feet: Poems About Transportation - Salas&amp;Laura Purdie From Kalamazoo to Timbuktu! - Harriet Ziefert&amp;Tanya Roitman Motorcycles- Darlene R.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stille Bulldozer- Darlene R. Stille Submarines - Darlene R. Stille Transportation in Many Cultures - Rustad&amp;Martha E.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;H. Trucks - John Hudson Tiner Race Cars - Darlene R. Stille Police Cars - Darlene R.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stille Shapes in Transportation - Jennifer Roy&amp;Gregory Roy Airplanes - Nancy Robinson Masters My First Highlight Book of Transportation - Early Start Editors&amp;Robert Salanitro Trains - Anne Rockwell Trains - Lee Sullivan Hill and Howard Ande Go! -DK Publishing Cars -John Hudson Tiner Ships&amp;Boats (Let 9s Investigate: Transportation) - John Hudson Tiner Farm Equipment -Calvert Gamwell&amp;Carrie Jordan School Buses (Wonder Books Level 1 Transportation) - Cynthia Fitterer Klingel&amp;Robert B. Noyed Emergency Vehicles (Transportation Around the World) - Chris Oxlade Tractor Trailers - Lola M.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Schaefer Fire Trucks - Darlene R. Stille 39 Big Book of Things that Go! 3 D.K.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Publishing Transportation Inventions: From Subways to Submarines (Which Came First) - Sandra Will Freight Train - Donald Crews The Little Engine that Could - Watty Piper If I Could Drive an Ambulance - Michael Teitelbaum Sheep in a Jeep 3 Nancy Shaw My Sister 9s Rusty Bike 3 Jim Aylesworth Mama Zooms 3 Jane Cowen- Fletcher Transportation Vocabulary Flight Road Captain Cruise Path Astronaut Destination Traffic Wheels Pavement Travel Directions Freight Conductors Distance Highway Ramp Bridge Runway Steer Passenger Tracks Helmet Pilot Soar Motor Launch Construction

 less 
 
 
 Username: fishero Name: Arago Subcategory: Home &gt; Aviation &gt; Aircraft Added: 05:02 ← 03 Aug 2010 Views: 868 Downloads: 0 File size: 392.2 KB Favourites: 0 | Add to favourites Status: Public Tags: circle , time , theme: , transportation 
 
 Embed URL Thumbnail 
 Latest documents 
 Otmane el rhazi fgc financial markets 
 
 Masimple otmane el rhazi 
 
 Headshoulders otmane el rhazi 
 
 Fibonacci otmane el rhazi 
 
 Candlestickbasics el rhazi otmane 
 
 Calloptions otmane el rhazi 
 
 Business insider otmane el rhazi 
 
 Bullcallspread otmane el rhazi 
 
 Gt reformas constitucionales 201244 
 
 Gt reformas constitucionales 2012 
 
 Lista de bodas 
 
 American Record Guide September / October 2006 
 
 Word Pro - findersfees 
 
 NASD OFFICE OF HEARING OFFICERS 
 
 SEC News Digest, 12-23-1971 
 
 IN THE SUPREME COURT OF CALIFORNIA 
 
 TOWN OF STUYVESANT 
 
 Upselling Strategies: Don’t Leave Money on the Table 
 
 Frequently Asked Questions 
 
 Matthew Sanderson Associate 
 
 The Food and Beverage Vending Environment in Health Care Facilities 
 
 Point-of-Sale Technology and Service Provider Relies on Kaseya for 
 
 BurgerKing CS US FRT.ai 
 
 Fast Food Industry Award - South-Eastern Division 2003 
 
 DRAFT #1 – July 11, 2005 – 4:45 PM Eastern 
 
 How to Make Fast-Foods Healthier for Students 
 
 STATE OF WASHINGTON DEPARTMENT OF FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS SECURITIES 
 
 Ban Junk Food in Public Schools, Say Arizonans 
 
 Responding to Complex Market Demands in Retail 
 
 Invention to Venture: About Us 
 
 Kahala?Cold Stone Key Facts 
 
 history growth product 
 
 Restaurant-Hospitality.com : Ready For The Gold Rush: San Francisco 
 
 For more information, contact: 
 
 A Feast of Franchises 
 
 CORPORATE FACT SHEET 
 
 STRATEGIC ACTION PLAN PUBLIC MEETING PHASE 1 Loyal Heights Community 
 
 FRANCHISE OPPORTUNITIES 
 
 Franchise Systems Using SBA Financing An Analysis of the Franchises 
 
 The 2009 Fast 55 companies are all over the map—find out which 
 
BeePDF is a dedicated pdf search engine for PDF ebooks, manual, catalogs, sheets and forms. We are available by webmaster@beepdf.com
 
 Account Join for Free Sign In 
 
 Browse Latest Uploads Most Viewed Categories Flymed 
 
 Help&amp;Info Privacy Notice DMCA Contact Us Terms Of Use 
 
 
 Copyright © 2010 beepdf.com .
 All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
