<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007338" url="http://www.syscowcf.com/Going%20Green.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:18" support="17" score="0.034783687172088414" bingtitle="Sysco West Coast Florida Going Green" webtitle="Sysco West Coast Florida Going Green">
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="162"/>
	<description>Clean the trays only as needed. Reuse water from steam tables to wash down the ... staff in the decision-making process and rewarding them for good ideas can pay ...</description>
	<body>
		What&apos;s Green at Sysco? 
 
                            As stewards of the Earth, it is our responsibility to protect, 

                      nurture and build upon the natural resources provided to us. We 

                     will continually seek out new ways to grow, harvest and distribute food 
 in a manner that not only preserves and protects the environment, but 
 strengthens our ability to deliver the best possible quality to our 
 customers. In this way, we ensure a healthy future not just for our 
 planet, but for our businesses and end users alike.         Click here to read more! 
 
 

     Going Green 
 
 
 
             Why Operators Should Go Green and Practical Steps for Doing It 

 Going green is not just the right thing to do; it can benefit 
 your bottom line. In fact, conserving natural resources and reducing 
 waste can reduce restaurant operating costs, which is critical 
 in these challenging times, and being environmentally friendly 
 can be a great way to bring more customers in your door. Sysco 
 has reviewed foodservice industry publications, articles, and 
 best practices in the area of sustainability. The collective 
 wisdom of these sources has been distilled to provide actionable 
 advice. 

 
                                  Whats the Fuss about the Environment? 

 Certainly every operator has heard something about 
 sustainability and going green. As operators are considering 
 environmentally related steps they might take, many operators are 
 asking, Why should we go green? What are the benefits? How do we do it? 
 What do we do? What resources are available to assist me? 

 

 Why Go Green? 

 There are many compelling reasons to become more 
 environmentally conscious and to make environmentally focused changes to 
 your operations. The key reasons to go green include: 

 
 Its the right thing to do. Our planet 
 has a finite amount of natural resources and many of them are being 
 rapidly consumed. The foodservice industry is a major user of these 
 resources. Just a few examples include: 
 
 Restaurants account for 33% of all U.S. 
 retail electricity used. 
 The average operation uses 300,000 gallons 
 of water a year. 
 Approximately 100 billion pounds of food 
 is wasted each year; food scraps alone make up almost 12% of all 
 the municipal solid waste generated in the country. 
 

 So, reducing the resources that are used is simply 
 the
right thing to do. 

 
 It can deliver significant cost savings. Reducing the amount of food, electricity, and water that are used 
 can decrease operating expenses. For example, an operator profiled 
 in a December article in the Boston Globe said that composting and 
 recycling costs him 30% less than traditional trash service and 
 replacing one conventional light bulb with a compact fluorescent one 
 can save $35-$45 per year. Because operations often have numerous 
 light bulbs, this savings can add up. 
 It can help attract customers. According to the National Restaurant Association, 62% of adults 
 surveyed say they are likely to choose a restaurant based on how 
 environmentally friendly it is. As a result, operators that go green 
 and that promote their environmental activities can leverage this as 
 a strategy to grow their traffic. 

 The bottom line is that going green can be good 
 for operators bottom line. It is not just a strategy for ardent 
 environmentalists; it is a strategy for savvy business people to 
 decrease operating expenses, increase traffic, and differentiate their 
 operation. As one operator said in a NRA publication, This is the new 
 way of business for restaurants. 

 
                                     How to Go GreenAreas of Focus 

 For new or renovated operations, it is possible to 
 build green. For existing operations, it is possible to become greener 
 through approaches that include conserving energy, reducing water usage, 
 and decreasing food
waste. 

 

 Build Green 

 If you are opening a new restaurant, thinking 
 about renovations, or just taking notes for future locations, there are 
 several creative ways to keep the environment in mind. 

 

 To conserve energy, use natural light whenever 
 possible. This will naturally warm the space and reduce electricity 
 consumption. Kitchens should be designed around energy-efficient 
 appliances and equipment. Rooftops can be painted to reflect sunlight 
 and lower air conditioning costs. An upfront investment in high quality, 
 efficient products will save significant cash down the road. 

 

 Also consider using products that contain recycled 
 materials. There are numerous tiles, dcors, centerpieces, and light 
 fixtures made from recycled glass. Old wooden doors make great tabletops 
 or hostess stands. Look for restaurant furniture auctions. These events 
 often showcase retro materials, hard-to find novelties, and even 
 antiques. 

 

 Finally, be sure to seek out sustainable building 
 materials. Bamboo is harder than most woods and is fast-growing and 
 rapidly renewable. Sisal fiber contains low or zero volatile organic 
 compounds (VOCs). This product safeguards indoor air quality by reducing 
 emissions from paints and adhesives, and minimizes sound transmission 
 within the building. Granite alternatives that are made from recycled 
 newsprint look great and make excellent countertops. 

 
 Conserve Energy 
Conserving energy is a great way to help the environment and reduce 
 costs. Virtually every restaurant can employ numerous free or 
 inexpensive techniques for cutting back on electricity use. A few 
 examples: 

 
 Unplug and turn off. When devices that 
 run on electricity are not in use, unplug them. This includes 
 computers, electronics, coffee machines, the POS system, and any 
 small appliance. Turn off lights and cooking hoods when they are not 
 in use. Consider installing motion detectors in storerooms, offices, 
 and restrooms, and set lights on timers. 
 Replace lighting. Replace incandescent 
 light bulbs with longer lasting CFL or LED lights. Dont forget exit 
 signstraditional signage can be replaced with LED exit lighting. 
 Clean and maintain. Clean equipment 
 uses energy more efficiently. Regularly dust all appliances, top to 
 bottom. Also perform routine preventive maintenance on HVAC, 
 plumbing, appliances, and major equipment. 

 Decrease Water Usage 
Water usage is another area where restaurants can do their part to help 
 the environment while saving money. Tips include only serving customers 
 water upon request and running dishwashers only when they are full. 
 Opportunities for water conservation exist in all areas of the 
 operation: 

 
 Kitchen. Turn off the continuous flow used to 
 clean drain trays of the beverage island. Clean the trays only as 
 needed. Reuse water from steam tables to wash down the cooking area. 
 Recycle water where feasible, consistent with state and county 
 requirements. For example, consider recirculating rinse water from 
 the dishwasher to the garbage disposal. 
 Bar. Dont use running water to melt ice in 
 the sink strainers. Investigate installing automatic shut-off 
 faucets for the bar sink. 
 Maintenance. Check for leaks and turn off any 
 unnecessary flows. Repair dripping faucets and leaking toilets. (A 
 leaky toilet can waste more than 50 gallons of water a day.) Reduce 
 the water used in toilet flushing by adjusting the vacuum flush 
 mechanism or installing toilet tank displacement devices. Switch 
 from wet or steam carpet cleaning methods to dry powder methods and 
 instruct the clean-up crew to use less water for mopping. 

 Reduce Waste 

 Today, food waste losses account for up to $30 to 
 $40 billion per year in restaurants and convenience stores. Less than 3% 
 of food waste is currently recovered. Other types of waste occur as 
 well, including waste in beverages, paper products, chemicals, and more. 
 Programs to reduce waste, particularly food waste, can result in both 
 economic and societal benefits. 

 
 Economic benefits. From an economic 
 perspective, developing a food waste reduction program candecrease 
 disposal fees, lower sewer treatment and electricity costs, and 
 decrease purchasing costs because the restaurant only buys what is 
 needed. The extra food that is present at the end of a shift 
 contributes greatly to the amount of food waste and affects an 
 operations food cost percentage. 

 Using prep sheets that base production on actual 
 sales history and projections, instead of well, weve always made this 
 much, will help decrease the amount of food leftover, thereby lowering 
 food costs. 

 
 Societal benefits. Donating food can 
 assist people and animals in need. It can also be used for 
 industrial purposes and composting. (In addition, donations can 
 result in tax deductions). 

 A good first step in developing a food waste 
 reduction program is conducting a food waste audit. Track and collect 
 data on the types and amounts of each food scrap item. The quality of 
 the food scraps and the estimated generation rate will help determine 
 how to reduce the amount of food waste and divert it for useful 
 purposes. 

 

 The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) has 
 created the Food Waste Recovery Hierarchy to prioritize different 
 methods for reducing surplus food. The levels of this hierarchy are: 

 
 Source reduction. Based on the outcome 
 of the food waste audit, operators can change their operations to 
 reduce unused food. Operators can also talk with their Sysco 
 Marketing Associate about products that are packaged in ways that 
 can reduce the amount of material being disposed. For example, 
 consider buying products in concentrate form, using refillable 
 condiment bottles, buying shelf-stable food in bulk, or purchasing 
 recycled paper products. 
 Feed people. Unsold or excess food that 
 meets quality and safety standards can be donated to food banks. 
 Many national and local food recovery programs offer free pickups 
 and containers. The Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act 
 (Public Law 104-210) protects food donors from legal liability. 
 Feed animals. Determine if local 
 farmers or zoos use food scraps as animal feed. There may also be 
 nearby companies that convert food scraps into animal food products. 
 Industrial uses. Waste oils, fat, and 
 grease can be rendered into a raw material to make biodiesel, soaps, 
 and cosmetics. 
 Composting. Food scraps can be 
 composted either at a composting facility or on-site. Contact your 
 local or state environmental agency to find out more about 
 composting options in your area. 

 Use of landfills and incineration, which is common 
 today, is the last resort for food, only after the other options have 
 been exhausted. 

 

 Become Certified Green 

 One way that operators can demonstrate their 
 environmental commitment is by becoming a Certified Green RestaurantTM. 
 This is a certification offered by the Green Restaurant Association (GRA), 
 a non-profit, national environmental organization. 

 

 The GRA has developed environmental standards for 
 restaurants, a points system where operations can earn points in 
 hundreds of different ways for reducing their environmental impact, and 
 a suggested process for becoming Certified Green. 

 

 A key step in this process is securing support for 
 going green from an operations key financial, marketing, and 
 operational stakeholders. Their support is based on understanding the 
 benefits of having a more environmentally friendly operation. 

 
 Financial . The key financial issue is 
 understanding the short- and long-term financial impact of operating 
 a more sustainable business. The GRA can help demonstrate how 
 restaurants are saving money through lower gas, oil, water, 
 electricity, and garbage costs. 
 Marketing . Becoming a Certified Green 
 RestaurantTM provides an opportunity for an operator to project a 
 positive image and to appeal to the large segment of society that 
 cares about the environment. 
 Operations and Purchasing. Those with 
 operational and purchasing responsibilities may be concerned that 
 going green will compromise quality or causes purchasing headaches. 
 But once the GRA explains its 18-year- old system of working with 
 vendors to create a smooth change process, fears of operational 
 concerns usually disappear. Those in operations and purchasing can 
 be confident that instead of being a burden to staff, the process of 
 environmental improvement will contribute to positive employee
morale and higher productivity. 

 Once a restaurant has the necessary buy-in and 
 support to proceed with becoming green certified, the next step is to 
 develop a strategy for certification. The GRA works with each restaurant 
 to conduct an environmental assessment, and then environmental 
 consulting, implementation, education, certification, and 
 communications. 

 
 Involve Employees 

 In implementing each of these environmental 
 strategies, operators should include their staff in the discussion of 
 what to do and the implementation plans. Ask for their input and 
 assistance in reducing waste and reducing consumption of electricity and 
 water. Involving staff in the decision-making process and rewarding them 
 for good ideas can pay dividends with higher productivity, better 
 morale, lower costs, and less waste. 

 

 
                                      Resources to Assist 
 You in Going Green 

 There is a wealth of information and resources to 
 assist operators in the efforts to become more environmentally friendly, 
 and to save money in doing so. 

 

 Sysco Can Help 
As you work to reduce your restaurants carbon footprint, Sysco can 
 provide valuable assistance. Sysco iCare partners offer solutions that 
 help environmentally minded business owners. These partners include: 

 
 Green Restaurant Association ( www.dinegreen.com ). 
 The Green Restaurant Association (GRA), which is described in more 
 detail in the previous section, uses environmental consulting, 
 education, certification, public relations, and marketing to help 
 restaurants implement credible environmental change. 
 Tradition Energy ( www.traditionenergy.com ) . 
 Tradition Energy offers Renewable Energy Certificates (RECs) and 
 Green Power to restaurants. RECs represent the environmental, 
 social, or other positive attributes of power generated by renewable 
 resources. RECs are purchased separately from, and in addition to, 
 conventional commodity energy supplies. Green Power is conventional 
 fossil fuel generated electricity bundled with RECs. 
 NorthWrite ( www.northwrite.com ). 
 NorthWrite energy monitoring solutions help create sustainability 
 through decreased energy use, reduced waste, and a streamlined flow 
 of information that helps an operator measure and manage energy 
 consumption. DegreeGuardTM monitors temperatures of coolers and 
 freezers, ensuring equipment is operating correctly, doors are 
 properly closed, and energy is not wasted. EnergyGuardTM helps 
 benchmark energy use to see if significant opportunities for savings 
 exist. 

 Another way that Sysco can help is through 
 electronic billing and payments. Sysco operating companies offer 
 customers the ability to receive their billing statements via email, and 
 in the first quarter of 2009 Sysco plans to roll out web payment 
 capabilities. Electronic billing and payment reduces mailing expenses 
 and administrative time while also decreasing the amount of paper used 
 and the energy required to deliver a piece of mail. The United States 
 Postal Service recently released a study which showed that every first 
 class piece of mail generates 87 grams of CO2. A Sysco customer 
 receiving bills and paying electronically can reduce its carbon 
 footprint by 22.5 pounds per year. If 50,000 customers use electronic 
 billing and payments, Sysco will eliminate about 1.3 million pounds of 
 CO2 each year. 

 

 Additional resources include: 

 
 The 
 National Restaurant Associations Conserve Solutions for 
 Sustainability Initiative ( www.conserve. 
 restaurant.org/index.cfm ) 
 The 
 California Integrated Waste Management Boards Restaurant Guide to 
 Waste Reduction and Recycling ( www.ciwmb.ca.gov/Publications/ 
 BizWaste/44198016.pdf ) 
 EPA 
 Sound Food Scraps Management Program ( www.epa.gov/epawaste/conserve/materials/ 
 organics/food/index.htm ) 
 U.S. Composting Council ( www.compostingcouncil.org) 
 EPA 
 WasteWise Program ( www.epa.gov/epawaste/ 
 partnerships/wastewise/index.htm ) 
 EPA 
 Green Building Program ( www.epa.gov/ 
 greenbuilding/ ) 
 The 
 National Hunger Clearinghouse ( www. 
 worldhungeryear.org/nhc_data/nhc_01.asp )
	</body>
</document>
