<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007712" url="http://www.denverpost.com/restaurants/ci_11437679" time="2012-07-13-00:40" support="1" score="0.0018732187337969035" bingtitle="Sometimes you just gotta do a drive-thru - The Denver Post" webtitle="Sometimes you just gotta do a drive-thru - The Denver Post">
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>... classic relic of later-middle 20th-century fast-food restaurant ... are, of course, a host of other things on the menu ... expected at Commerce City meeting on medical-waste ...</description>
	<body>
		Commenting: Sign In   |   Register 
 Home | Media Kit | Sign up for breaking news email alerts | Photo Galleries 
 
 

 
 weekly ad specials from the denver post Site Yahoo 
 

 

 
 
 Home &gt; Style &gt; Food &gt; Restaurants 
 
 
 
 Print    Email    Font Resize Eat Local | Griff&apos;s 
Sometimes you just gotta do a drive-thru
 Story and photo by Tucker Shaw 
 Denver Post Food Critic denverpost.com Posted: 01/14/2009 12:30:00 AM MST 
 (Tucker Shaw, The Denver Post) 
They tell us we shouldn&apos;t eat fast food. They tell us we shouldn&apos;t eat in the car. They tell this, and they tell us that. But one truth is unshakable:
There is no cure for a drive-through burger jones, other than a drive-through burger. And when the jones hits, you can resist it for only so long.
Enter Griff&apos;s.
Housed in a red-roofed A-frame all but directly underneath the Broadway/I-25 overpass, Griff&apos;s might one day end up considered a classic relic of later-middle 20th-century fast-food restaurant architecture, a well-populated and surprisingly artful subgenre that includes early McDonald&apos;s, A&amp;W and Der Weinerschnitzel.
But you don&apos;t pull into the Griff&apos;s lot to admire the architecture. You pull in to take care of that jones.
The best value is the No. 3 combo, a single patty, griddled, topped with fresh onion, lettuce and tomato, plus ketchup and mustard, on a devilishly buttery (and also griddled) bun, small side of fries, always hot (ask for extra salt if you swing that way) and a 16-ounce soda.
This classic, by-the-book example of a drive-through meal—served in a car-friendly waxy paper envelope—is one of the last in town that&apos;ll set you back less than $5.
$4.75, to be exact.
There are, of course, a host of other things on the menu, cheeseburgers and double cheeseburgers and the requisite chicken sandwich. And of course, shakes.
You&apos;d be smart to park it in the lot for a moment or two to wolf down that burger before hitting the road; the very last thing you need is a food-fueled fender-bender.
They&apos;re right: We shouldn&apos;t eat drive-through fast food.
But a jones-driven visit to Griff&apos;s, every now and again, just can&apos;t be helped.
 

Griff&apos;s

Burgers. Open seven days. 742 S. Broadway, 303-777-7290. Second location at 5770 Olde Wadsworth Blvd., Arvada, 303-422-2098.




 Copyright 2012 The Denver Post. All rights reserved. Print    Email    Font Resize Return to Top    
 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 Like this article? Recommend it ()  all reader-recommended news 

 Login | Sign Up | Email Support 
Article Comments

 Is your comment not appearing on the article? Read this .

 
 Note: Our article pages automatically refresh every ten minutes. We cannot change this. If you start writing your comment on this page, please refresh the page before you do so—this will reset the ten-minute counter .

 You must be registered to comment (your comment will be saved for you while you register). It&apos;s quick (it takes about 30 seconds) and we only require your email and name. Comments that include any offensive material are prohibited. By using our site you agree to our terms of use .
 
 
You have javascript turned off. To comment on this article from the article page, javascript must be turned on. Alternately, you can search for this topic thread in our forums .
 
 Comment: 

 Use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; link when necessary (you don&apos;t have to be a member, or be logged in) Keep it clean and respect others—don&apos;t use language you wouldn&apos;t use with your parents Read the Post&apos;s Article Commenting Ground Rules here (link will open in a new window) 

 
 
 More Restaurant Reviews MORE MORE RESTAURANT REVIEWS HEADLINES Restaurant review: The Ninth Door in LoDo offers a world of tasty tapas to Denver diners Udon Kaisha Japanese restaurant is a welcome addition to Lafayette Restaurant review: D&apos;Corazon in LoDo offers tasty Mexican comfort food Restaurant&amp;Bar: 3 Monkeys Cantina a welcome addition in Denver&apos;s Platt Park neighborhood Eat Local: Vail Valley&apos;s Northside Coffee&amp;Kitchen in Avon sells Blue Bottle coffee Denver-area restaurant guide June 17, 2012 New Now: Native Foods Cafe opens in Boulder with meatless menu Restaurant review: Riffs Urban Fare brings fresh flavors to Boulder Denver metro dining guide Eat Local: Korea House brings welcome wackiness to Boulder Dining Out: Boulder&apos;s popular The Kitchen eatery opens a sister restaurant in Denver Bar: With a tuneup, Gary Lee&apos;s Motor Club and Grub might just purr like a kitten A taco truck becomes a full-service restaurant at Longmont&apos;s Comida Cantina Restaurant review: Denver&apos;s Lucky Pie gets pizza right Eat Local: Pints Pub deserves its Denver love Lucy Restaurant opens in Comedy Works South for breakfast-lunch Restaurant review: Urban Italian cuisine at The Wooden Table in Greenwood Village Hapa Sushi closes location on Boulder&apos;s University Hill Nostalgic games keep Denver bar patrons occupied Syrup restaurant opens second location in downtown Denver New Denver restaurant: Sputino is savory, sweet, with a nod to Italy Restaurant review: Denver&apos;s Phat Thai restaurant delivers standout pan-Asian flavors New Now: Lucky Pie Pizza and Tap House Eat Local: North Denver favorite Lechuga&apos;s fame is well-deserved Restaurant review: Damascus Grill serves solid Middle Eastern fare in Littleton   
 
 
 
 Blogs Front Page Aurora | Boulder | Denver | Feeds | More 

 Denver&amp;the West 
 
 &apos;Waistline Bandit&apos; suspected in Aurora, Denver robberies Highlands Ranch, Denver dentist may have contaminated patients for 12 years ATF would consider aiding Denver to fight violent crime   
 
 Rockies | Avs | Nuggets | Preps | RSS | More 

 Sports 
 
 Broncos&apos; situation at linebacker looks murky Boulder&apos;s Laura Bennett attempts to medal in triathlon at London Games Mark Kiszla: NBA&apos;s joke of parity is on the Nuggets   
 
 Balance Sheet Blog | Techknow Bytes 

 Business 

 
 
 Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight day Colorado appeals court overturns Erik Osborn theft conviction Sun Microsystems co-founder Scott McNealy to keynote Demogala Denver tech conference   
 
 
 
 Movies | Music | TV | RSS | Video 

 Entertainment 
 
 Steven Tyler exiting as &apos;American Idol&apos; judge Bumped from Dish, AMC makes Breaking Bad available online Video: Christian Louboutin partners with Disney to create Cinderella shoe   
 
 Columnists | Letters | Cartoon | RSS 

 Opinion 
 
 Editorial: Penn State failed kids in favor of football Editorial: Hot shots earn health insurance Editorial: Richard B. Scudder, 99   
 
 Arcade | Crossword | Sudoku 

 Watercooler 
 
 Cop accused of stealing driver&apos;s iPhone from wreck Court: Ore. police can seize $1M lottery prize German town designates tricky parking &apos;men only&apos;   
 
 
 
 
 
 Top Food Stories Bistro Vendome chef Dana Rodriguez&apos;s American dream has a French twist Healthy eating is matter of survival for chef Seamus Mullen, author of &quot;Hero Food&quot; Mr. Beer: Sweet Action in Denver adds beer to its ice cream menu Squeaky Bean restaurant reopens in new LoDo location Kale comes in many varieties, all of them healthy and tasty - like this recipe Chef Jose Andres shares dance moves, caviar, gazpacho in Aspen   
 
 TOP STORIES MORE TOP STORIES HEADLINES Highlands Ranch, Denver dentist may have contaminated patients for 12 years &apos;Waistline Bandit&apos; suspected in Aurora, Denver robberies University of Colorado theater department receives $2 million   
 
 Jerry Sandusky report: Penn State could have stopped abuse in &apos;98 Denver ICE agents shut down 22 counterfeit shopping websites Loose food cart injures five during landing of Frontier flight in Phoenix Downed bicyclist hit, killed by Lakewood driver Unemployment hitting black middle class Task force assigned to Chris &quot;Birdman&quot; Andersen case awaiting forensic evidence Broncos&apos; situation at linebacker looks murky Strength coach Luke Richesson wants Broncos to finish strong   
 POPULAR TALKERS RECOMMENDED YEAR AGO 
 



 
FRESH DAILY. Subscribe to our
Afternoon Newsletter
 
Email Address
 
» See a sample afternoon newsletter here 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
All contents Copyright 2012 The Denver Post or other copyright holders. All rights reserved.
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed for any commercial purpose.

 Advertise / Media Kit | Archives | Careers | Contact Us | Ethics Policy | E-mail Alerts | Mobile | Privacy Policy | Web Feeds | RSS | My Yahoo | Repurposing Denver Post content - Guidelines | Site Map | Home Delivery | Terms of Use 

Our other sites: Viva Colorado | Boulder Daily Camera | Boulder&apos;s Colorado Daily | Broomfield Enterprise | Sterling Colorado Journal-Advocate 
 Estes Park Trail-Gazette | The Lamar Ledger | The Fort Morgan Times | Brush (Colorado) News-Tribune 
 Tweet 

 Privacy Policy   |   Terms of Use   |   MNG Corporate Site Map   |   Copyright
	</body>
</document>
