<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007268" url="http://www.asiarooms.com/en/indonesia/bintan_island/198942-bintan_cabana_beach_resort.html" time="2012-07-13-00:14" support="1" score="0.0014460318563389437" bingtitle="Bintan Cabana Beach Resort Bintan Island - Indonesia | Discount ..." webtitle="Bintan Cabana Beach Resort Bintan Island - Indonesia | Discount Hotel Deals - AsiaRooms.com">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>Bintan Cabana Beach Resort have a wide selection of ... lined up next to the beach and a sea view fast food restaurant. ... A credit card is required to secure your reservation ...</description>
	<body>
		Cheap Hotels&amp;Accommodation - ideal for booking last minute hotels 
 
 English Customer Support 

 Home Hotels Travel Guides My booking Reviews 
 
 View all hotels in Bintan Island Asia &gt; Indonesia &gt; Bintan Island &gt; Bintan Cabana Beach Resort
   
 Bintan Cabana Beach Resort, Bintan Island   
 Jalan Malang Rapat, Pantai Trikora Km 46 View this hotel&apos;s location on a map 
 Make a Booking Hotel Facilities Hotel Location Photo Gallery 9 Guest Reviews 13 
 
 
 More pictures in the gallery 
Hotel Description
 Bintan Cabana Beach Resort have a wide selection of private rooms at great prices. Rooms come equipped with 2 beds, air-conditioning, hot water, television, garden view, sea view. Great care has been taken in furnishing our rooms and lodges to the highest standard with quality beds. At our sister resort our guests can also have a meal, Spa treatment, sea sport activities and have Internet access. Guests can also make use of its swimming pool. The resort has it&apos;s own garden, small huts lined up next to the beach and a sea view fast food restaurant. On the beach there are sea sport activities, security and comfort for anyone wishing to stay in peaceful, homely surroundings.

Our goal is to offer you as our host a warm, satisfaction and familiar environment, with calm and homely that is reflected by the ‘‘Selamat Datang’’.
 read more Show less 
Average hotel rating
 5/6 
based on 13 reviews
 100% 
recommend this hotel
 100% 
would stay again
 Bintan Cabana Beach Resort, Bintan Island reviews     Check In: Check Out: Adults 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Children 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Updating Rates 
You can check in from 15:00. You need to check out by 12:00.

A credit card is required to secure your reservation at Bintan Cabana Beach Resort in Bintan Island. If the reservation is not cancelled outside of the 5 days cancellation notice period, your credit card will be charged with the full amount of the first night&apos;s stay unless otherwise stated in the room notes.

The AsiaRooms.com rates for Bintan Cabana Beach Resort in Bintan Island are the price of the room and not the &apos;per person&apos; rate.
   
&amp;COPY;2012 AsiaRooms.com - All Rights Reserved

 About us | Terms&amp;conditions | FAQ | Privacy | Customer Support | Add your hotel | Press | Affiliates 
 English en-gb | ไทย th-th | 简体中文 zh-cn | 繁體中文 zh-tw | Bahasa Malaysia ms-my | Bahasa Indonesia id-id 
 
 English ไทย 简体中文 繁體中文 Bahasa Malaysia Bahasa Indonesia
	</body>
</document>
