<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007633" url="http://www.franchise.com/franchise/fast-food-restaurant/ice-cream/Kona-Ice/owners-franchisees.cfm" time="2012-07-13-00:36" support="2" score="0.0012124181025355615" bingtitle="Kona Ice Franchisees &amp; Kona Ice Franchise Owners Testimonials" webtitle="Kona Ice Franchisees&amp;Kona Ice Franchise Owners Testimonials">
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>Receive franchise.com updates: ... - Bill &amp; Clint Lyons “Anytime we make a call to them ... Computer and Internet Education Financial Services Food ...</description>
	<body>
		Kona Ice Franchisees&amp;Kona Ice Franchise Owners Testimonials

 franchises 
 Subway Franchise For Sale 7-Eleven, Inc. Kona Ice Franchise For Sale Visiting Angels Coverall Health-Based Cleaning System Little Caesars Enterprises Nestlé Toll House Café by Chip West Sanitation Home Helpers Franchise For Sale Fast-Teks Franchise For Sale 
    |    franchises by state 
 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
    |    advertise with us    |    site map 
    |        Email Us Find Your Franchise: Select Category Automotive Franchises Beauty Franchises Beverages Franchises Business Opportunities Business Services Children Related Cleaning&amp;Maintenance Computer&amp;Internet Earth Friendly Education Franchises Financial Services Food Franchises Health&amp;Fitness Home Related Low Investment Master/Area Developers Minority Focused Pet Related Photo&amp;Video Printing Packing&amp;Shipping Retail Franchises SBA Approved Senior Services Sports and Recreation Travel Franchises Veterans Franchises Women&apos;s Franchises Work From Home Select Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington Washington DC West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Canada US Territories Not USA or Canada 
   Franchises by Category 
 Automotive Franchises 
 Beauty Franchises 
 Beverages Franchises 
 Business Opportunities 
 Business Services 
 Children Related 
 Cleaning&amp;Maintenance 
 Computer&amp;Internet 
 Earth Friendly 
 Education Franchises 
 Financial Services 
 Food Franchises 
 Health&amp;Fitness 
 Home Related 
 Low Investment 
 Master/Area Developers 
 Minority Focused 
 Pet Related 
 Photo&amp;Video 
 Printing Packing&amp;Shipping 
 Retail Franchises 
 SBA Approved 
 Senior Services 
 Sports and Recreation 
 Travel Franchises 
 Veterans Franchises 
 Women&apos;s Franchises 
 Work From Home 
 VIEW ALL 
 

 Franchise Directory 

 Top 25 Franchises 

 Big Opportunities 
 Home  &gt;  Franchise Categories  &gt;  Food Franchises  &gt;  Ice Cream/Frozen Yogurt  &gt; Kona Ice  Cash Required 
 
$20,000 - $30,000 Total Investment 
 
$96,600 Financing 
 
Pre-Arranged Lifestyle / Hours 
 
full time, part time, flexible HEAR FROM OWNERS COMPANY INFO INVESTMENT / TRAINING / SUPPORT HEAR FROM OWNERS PHOTOS / VIDEOS STEPS TO OWNERSHIP 
 Receive franchise.com updates:   
 



 Text size 
 Click on“PHOTOS/VIDEOS”(at left) to hear franchisees’testimonials in their own words. 

 “Thank you for dreaming this up, making it work, and offering it up to us lucky franchisees. Thank you for being there to solve problems, soothe fears, and encourage innovations. Thank you for being family - people you can count on no matter what. I know that I can present any issue or idea and be taken seriously and compassionately... You will dream with me until we get to the next level.”
 - Meredith Stevenson 

 “Our expectations have been more than met.” 
 - Eric Wright 

 “What we bring to children, and the experience, is completely different than anything that they’ve done before.” 
 - Eric Wright 

 “Kona was everything we were looking for. It was colorful, it was exciting.. people come up to the truck happy and go away happier.” 
 - Jim&amp;Sharon Sweeney 

  “I love the day in and day out joy of seeing the kids run to the truck.” 
 - Charlie Smoot 

 “The surprises with Kona is that it branded immediately. The kids were happy, the community is happy and, of course, being a franchise owner that makes you ecstatic.” 
 - Kelly Hunt 

 “We were looking for a company that had a good vision, that was exciting and it was fun, and Kona has met all those expectations and more.”
 - Bill&amp;Clint Lyons 

 “Anytime we make a call to them (Kona) we get immediate response and immediate help.”
 - Bill&amp;Clint Lyons 

 “It was a lot easier to sell than I had imagined it would be. I have hardly ever had anyone turn me down when I asked them for their business.” 
 - Charles Love 

 “I expected a lot of help from Kona but my dreams of that have been far surpassed.” 
  - Kim Brown 

 “We practically paid off our yearly royalty in a 5 hour Sunday afternoon event” 
 - Megan Stevenson 
 Note: At this time, Kona Ice is only accepting inquiries from within the USA and Canada. Please send me information on Kona Ice to the following address: 

 First Name:* 
 Email:*  
 Address:  
 State:*  - Please Select - Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Guam Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virgin Islands Virginia Washington Washington DC West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Alberta British Columbia Manitoba New Brunswick Newfoundland Nova Scotia Ontario Prince Edward Island Quebec Saskatchewan Not USA or Canada 
 Zip:  
 Last Name:*  
 Phone:*  
 City:  
 Country:  USA Canada United Kingdom Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antarctica Antigua&amp;Barbuda Argentina Armenia Aruba Ascension Islands Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia&amp;Herzegowina Botswana Bouvet Island Brazil British Indian Ocean Territory Brunei Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Cambodia Cameroon Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos (Keeling) Islands Colombia Comoros Congo, Dem. Rep. of the Congo, Rep. of the Cook Islands Costa Rica Côte d&apos;Ivoire Croatia Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic East Timor Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Falkland Islands (Malvinas) Faroe Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia French Southern Territories Gabon Gambia Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Guadeloupe Guam Guatemala Guernsey Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Heard&amp;Mc Donald Islands Honduras Hong Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iraq Ireland Isle of Man Israel Italy Jamaica Japan Jersey Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Korea, South Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libya Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mayotte Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Poland Portugal Puerto Rico Qatar Reunion Romania Russia Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts&amp;Nevis Saint Lucia Saint Pierre&amp;Miquelon Saint Vincent&amp;the Grenadines Samoa San Marino Sao Tome&amp;Principe Saudi Arabia Senegal Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia So. Georgia&amp;So. Sandwich Is. Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Svalbard&amp;Jan Mayen Islands Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad&amp;Tobago Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks&amp;Caicos Islands Tuvalu Uganda Ukraine United Arab Emirates Uruguay Uzbekistan Vanuatu Vatican City Venezuela Vietnam Virgin Islands Wallis&amp;Futuna Islands Western Sahara Yemen Yugoslavia Zambia Zimbabwe 
 Available Capital:  Please Select over $500,000 $250,000 - $500,000 $100,000 - $249,999 $75,000 - $99,999 $50,000 - $74,999 $25,000 - $49,999 up to $25,000 undisclosed 
 Start-up Timeframe:  within 3 months 3-6 months 6-12 months more than 1 year 
 Please send me Franchise News We value our relationship with you and are committed to protecting your personal information.

   LEARN ABOUT FRANCHISING 
 Franchise Business Glossary 
 Franchise Articles 
 Finance&amp;Start a Small Business 
 New Franchises For Sale TOOLS AND RESOURCES 
 Business&amp;Franchising Events 
 Franchisee Testimonials 
 Net Worth Calculator 
 Franchise FAQ&apos;s COMPANY INFORMATION 
 About Franchise.com 
 Advertise With Us 
 Privacy Statement 
 Franchise Blog Franchise.com Home    Disclaimer    Site Map    Contact Us Copyright 1995-2012 Franchise.com
	</body>
</document>
