<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007833" url="http://www.courierpress.com/news/2010/jul/05/filling-bellies-filling-a-need/?partner=RSS" time="2012-07-13-00:47" support="2" score="0.0015514131377066952" bingtitle="EVSC&apos;s free summer meal program expands to fill the need ..." webtitle="EVSC&apos;s free summer meal program expands to fill the needEvansville CourierPress">
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>Take the minimum wage job at the local fast food restaurant. ... As a daycare teacher, we receive a great deal of ... Heavy Trash. Dates for the fall heavy trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Login | Manage Account | Mobile | Contact | e-Edition&amp;Subscriber Services | Find a Business 
 User Name: 
 Password: Forgotten your password?  | Create an account Register or log in using your account on these websites. site web 
Web Search powered by Yahoo! SEARCH
 Evansville Courier&amp;Press 
 News 
 Today Local 
 Warrick News West Side News Public Records Stadium i69 
 State National World YourNews Obituaries Politics 
 Election 
 Education Columnists 
 John Lucas Len Wells Good Morning Tri-State 
 Local Databases The Gleaner 
 News Obituaries Sports Business Entertainment Columnists 
 Judy Jenkins Donna Stinnett David Dixon Frank Boyett Chuck Stinnett Steve Austin Kevin Patton Kathy Moore Mitchell Stinson Billy Edwards Ron Jenkins Mike Smith 
 
 
 Sports 
 Local High School College 
 UE USI IU 
 Professional 
 Indianapolis Colts 
 Otters Icemen Columnists 
 Dan Korb Randy Beard Tim Ethridge Steve Ford Gordon Engelhardt Phil Potter 
 Contest Zone 
 Business 
 Local National / International Technology Columnists 
 Morton Marcus Tom Lovett Justin Williams Andrea Eldridge 
 Business Directory 
 Opinion 
 Blogs Editorial Letters to the Editor Polls Columnists 
 Bonnie Erbe Dan Thomasson Dale McFeatters Cliff May Martin Schram Jay Ambrose Mizell Stewart III 
 
 Entertainment 
 Local Arts / Theater Books Dining 
 Bars&amp;Clubs 
 Food&amp;Drink Specials 
 Restaurants 
 Open Now Submit Restaurant 
 
 Events 
 Submit Event Upcoming Expos Evansville Venues 
 Games 
 Online Games Sudoku 
 Movies Music 
 Evansville Bands Evansville Venues mp3s Evansville Radio Studio Soundcheck 
 Contest Zone Columnists 
 On and About Town Check It Out Roger McBain Jacob Newkirk 
 LibraryGhost 
 Lifestyles 
 Faith&amp;Values Food 
 Recipes 
 Health&amp;Fitness 
 Movement The Diet Docs Dr. Mom Mental Health Your Family Doctor 
 Home&amp;Garden 
 Green Tips&amp;Ideas C. Dwight Barnett Larry Caplan 
 Family 
 Youth First Youth Resources 
 Pets Travel Wedding&amp;Prom Local Coupons Columnists 
 C. Dwight Barnett Sara Anne Corrigan Charlie Cross Julia Gregg Todd Linn Julie Mallory Hanns Pieper Sharon Sorenson Rev. Joseph L. Ziliak 
 
 Media 
 Today&apos;s Photos Photo Archive Photo Galleries Photo Galleries by Topic Videos Cams 
 Jaguar Cam Weather Cam Library Ghost Cams 
 Children&apos;s Room Basement Room Research Room 
 
 User Submitted 
 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classified 
 
EVSC&apos;s free summer meal program expands to fill the need

 By Jared Council Evansville Courier&amp;Press Posted July 5, 2010 at 11:37 p.m. 

 Discuss Print A A A 
 

 
Article Highlights

 The Evansville Vanderburgh School Corp.&apos;s Summer Food Service Program served 4,122 lunches in its first year Last summer it served nearly 57,000 
 
DENNY SIMMONS / Courier&amp;Press
Isaac Ruckriegel, 6, eats another french fry after eating two burgers to go with his two milks at Tekoppel Elementary School&apos;s cafeteria on June 29. The Evansville Vanderburgh School Corp.&apos;s summer lunch program at Tekoppel feeds more than 200 participants each day.
 
 EVANSVILLE —
Since its inception, the function of the Evansville Vanderburgh School Corp.&apos;s Summer Food Service Program has been consistent: Provide free, nutritious meals to anyone 18 and younger.
 
Zoe Williams, 7, is entertained by her brother, Simon, 5, as he blows bubbles in his chocolate milk in Tekoppel Elementary School&apos;s cafeteria on June 29.
 

 
 Summer lunch still available 

The Evansville Vanderburgh School Corp. invites community agencies, organizations and families to any of these sites between 11:30 a.m. and 12:30 p.m. until July 23:

 n Caze Elementary
	</body>
</document>
