<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007652" url="http://www.dailyspark.com/blog.asp?post=does_it_really_whats_the_deal_with_the_bodybugg" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="3" score="0.005446789366268976" bingtitle="Does It Really? What&apos;s the Deal with the bodybugg?" webtitle="Does It Really? What&apos;s the Deal with the bodybugg?">
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>Always seemed like a waste of my money. So- I was ... under $7 a month- you could spend that at a fast food restaurant ... Either way, I track my food in their tracker and I ...</description>
	<body>
		Psst, can you keep a secret? I have a confession ! 
 
 
 Stuff We Love Chef Meg Yoga Restaurants Habits Of Fit People Weight Loss News In The News Motivation Healthy Cooking 
 
 My Trackers 
 Start my Nutrition my Fitness Other Goals SparkStreaks Reports Planner SparkMail my SparkPoints Web Search 
 Healthy Lifestyle 
 Healthy Lifestyle Home Nutrition Fitness Motivation Wellness SparkDiet Lifestyle Centers Videos SparkRecipes.com 
 Health Conditions 
 Health Conditions Home Health A-Z Condition Centers Health News 
 Community 
 Community Home Message Boards SparkTeams SparkPages Blogs Success Stories SparkAmerica 
 
 
 About DailySpark Submit a Story Press Contact 
 
 Email RSS 
 
 
 
Does It Really? What&apos;s the Deal with the bodybugg?
 Tweet Pin It Share on Tumblr 
By: Dean Anderson : 1/29/2009 11:19 AM   227 comments Wouldnt it be great if there were an easy-to-use, moderately priced weight loss tool that told you exactly how many calories you burned each day, how many you ate, and what your real calorie surplus or deficit is?

That would sure take a lot of the mystery and confusion out of the business of losing or maintaining weight. Right now, all the numbers you get from exercise machines, online calculators, and even heart rate monitors come from general formulas based on statistical data from large numbers of people. Since no two people are exactly alike, these general estimates can be, and usually are, inaccuratesometimes by as much as 30-40%. And food trackers, of course, are only accurate if you record everything you eat.

Well, there is a device that claims to come pretty close to solving these problems. If you watch &quot;The Biggest Loser&quot; on NBC, youve probably seen it on the contestantsits called the bodybugg. The bodybugg is owned and sold by Apex Fitness, the same company that owns the chain of gyms called 24 Hour Fitness, which is also a major sponsor of &quot;The Biggest Loser&quot; show. For current pricing and information about what you get for your money, you can check the
	</body>
</document>
