<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007145" url="http://www.freshii.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:07" support="18" score="0.09502773607511703" bingtitle="Freshii - Home" webtitle="Freshii -   Home">
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000354" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000559" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>ORDER NOW ... Check Gift Card Balance</description>
	<body>
		FRESHII
 HOME ABOUT MENU CATERING LOCATIONS FRANCHISING PRESS LOCATION: USA 
 Canada USA Austria UAE 
 
 
 ORDER NOW 
MEET KALE.
 YOUR NEW
FRIEND WITH

BENEFITS.
 
LIMITED TIME OFFER!

SuperFoods
 Quinoa, Kale, Avocado, Dried Cranberries, Blueberries&amp;More! ORDER NOW 
ENERGY SOURCE
 They say you are what you eat, so learn more about our 40 nutritious ingredients! 
©2012 Freshii
 
 Privacy Terms Careers Media Blog Contact Check Gift Card Balance 
Select Your Location


 Canada USA Austria UAE 

 PLEASE SELECT A COUNTRY: PLEASE SELECT STORE: SELECT ONE 
 CHICAGO - 311 S WACKER CHICAGO - WATER TOWER PLACE CHICAGO - 200 WEST MONROE ST CHICAGO - 111 W JACKSON CHICAGO - 161 NORTH CLARK CHICAGO - 200 W RANDOLPH CHICAGO - PALMER HOUSE CHICAGO - OAK BROOK WASHINGTON - 2001 M ST. NW WASHINGTON - 11TH AND E STREET WASHINGTON - 15TH AND K STREET DENVER - REPUBLIC PLAZA LOS-ANGELES - BRENTWOOD LOS-ANGELES - FARMER&apos;S MARKET LOS-ANGELES - FRESHII DOWNTOWN LA NEWPORT-BEACH - THE BLUFFS SACRAMENTO - FOLSOM MARKETPLACE SAN-FRANCISCO - FINANCIAL DISTRICT SAN-FRANCISCO - 4 EMBARCADERO CTR HOUSTON - GALLERIA MALL HOUSTON - HOUSTON CENTER HOUSTON - TWO SHELL HOUSTON - CHASE TOWER NATIONAL-HARBOR - NATIONAL HARBOR PHILADELPHIA - PENN SQUARE PORTLAND - PIONEER SQUARE PORTLAND - FIRST AND MAIN BALTIMORE - CHARLES VILLAGE BALTIMORE - LIGHT STREET BOSTON - HIGH STREET CINCINNATI - 425 WALNUT ST TORONTO - YONGE AND BLOOR TORONTO - YONGE AND ST.CLAIR TORONTO - SPADINA&amp;RICHMOND TORONTO - TD CENTRE TORONTO - EXCHANGE TOWER TORONTO - EATON CENTRE TORONTO - YORKVILLE TORONTO - YONGE AND EGLINTON TORONTO - KING&amp;CHURCH TORONTO - YONGE&amp;COLLEGE TORONTO - YORKMILLS&amp;LESLIE TORONTO - HEARTLAND TOWN CTR TORONTO - YORK UNIVERSITY VANCOUVER - WEST CORDOVA ST VANCOUVER - BROADWAY&amp;CAMBIE VANCOUVER - GEORGIA OTTAWA - 50 LAURIER AVE. E OTTAWA - 98 SPARKS ST EDMONTON - WEST EDMONTON MALL WIEN - HERRENGASSE DUBAI - DUBAI IFC DUBAI - AL RAZI BUILDING
	</body>
</document>
