<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007961" url="http://job.donkiz.co.za/job/cashier-requirements.htm" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="7" score="0.014557024391671931" bingtitle="Cashier Requirements - Donkiz Job" webtitle="Cashier Requirements - Donkiz Job">
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="11"/>
	<description>Cashier position available in the Northern Suburbs at a fast food restaurant. ... Receive listings by email for : cashier requirements</description>
	<body>
		job 
 
 My Donkiz - Sign in 
   Real-Estate    Job    Car    Motorcycle    Miscellaneous   
 
 What... Where... Ex : cashier requirements Ex : Cape Town, Johannesburg, Pretoria 
 
  
 Cashier Requirements 
 1 - 12 of 170 jobs &quot; Cashier &quot; 
       List sorted by : Pertinence - Date 
 Filter 
 Hours work 
 
 Work johannesburg 
 
 Work stores 
 
 Sales 
 
     
   
CAREER TRAINING AND PLACEMENTS
 Cape Town Start your career with us.bank tellers, cashiers ,till operators,data captures, call center , receptionists ,bookkeeping, ship crew , barmen, waitresses.2-4weeks training + certificates + job placements. call now to sign up ..., or visit us at our office in Belliville 11 Modderdam Road.We make dreams come true. 2-8 weeks training + certificate and placements. Requirements grade 11 and above 
 08-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 Cashier 
 Johannesburg Cashiers required for Hirsch&apos;s Meadowdale and Strubensvalley branches. 
 06-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 Cashier Required for Shop in Sunninghill Sandton.
 Johannesburg Cashier required for shop in Sunninghill Sandton. Must speak good english. Must live in Sunninghill or Joburg. Please send CV. 
 07-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 Cashier 
 Durban - Experienced We require experienced Cashiers to 1) Accurately process orders paid by cash, credit card, bank guaranteed cheque and M-65 payments. 2) Receive monies due correctly. 3) Reconcile the daily float including payments received to Oracle Reconciliation Daily Report. 4) Monies collected to be handed over to the Cash Sales Team Leader at day end and/or prior to leaving. 5) In case of discrepancies, to investigate and provide an explanation for the discrepancy. 6) Portray a positive and professional disposition at all times. 7) When required , capture and process new applications received at the... 
 09-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 Cashiers Needed
 Requirements : 
 05-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 CASHIER REQUIRED FOR FULL TIME POSITION IN SHERWOOD
 Durban - Full time Full time cashier required for fuel station in sherwood. 
 03-07-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
Receptionist/ Cashier 
 Pretoria - Experienced - Full time Cars for Sale Business directory Chat&amp;Dating Classifieds Property Sign In Register -- Select Province -- Eastern Cape Free State Gauteng Kwazulu Natal Limpopo Mpumalanga North West Northern Cape Western Cape Advanced Home Job Seekers Post Your CV Search Jobs Advanced Search Jobs By Company Jobs By Category Employers Post A Job Search CV Database My Saved CVs Sign In or Register Receptionist/ Cashier Home » Jobs » Receptionist/ Cashier Please click here to apply online for this position Job Information Category Administration Location Gauteng ( Pretoria ) Contract Full Time Pay R4,500 per month... 
 24-05-2012  -  jobspace.co.za save Queries related to &quot; cashier requirements &quot; : jobs at gauteng train  -  receptionist training jobs 
 
   
 Cashier Temp
 Modderfontein We have a temporary opportunity for a Cashier who has at least 3 years experience in working with cash ( Cashier or teller)and on an accounting system. A knowledge of reconciliations is important. Computer literacy too. Candidates must be SA citizens and Must have clear credit&amp;criminal record. Must also have good contactable references. Please do not respond unless you meet ALL of the above requirements . 
 13-04-2011  -  bestjobs.co.za save 
 
   
 CASHIER 
 Part time SELLING OR RENDERIND OF SERVICES NB: Jobs that require an up-front payment are scams. Your discretion is advised. 
 04-03-2011  -  jobspace.co.za save 
 
   
Versatile 23year old looking for job in Northern Suburbs
 Cape Town - Full I am a well groomed 23year old female studying Civil Engineering at CPUT Bellville. I am looking for a temporary job from 3-20July 2012(preferably full days and weekends). I am trustworthy, honest and reliable. I work well with others and I&apos;m always willing to learn. Previously worked as a cashier , general admin clerk, secretary, promoter. All of which was temporary/contract work. I am fluent in english and afrikaans, have excellent telephone ethics and computer literate in MS word, MS excell, MS powerpoint and e-mail. I am very versatile and a fast learner. Please do not hesitate to call or... 
 25-06-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
   
 Cashiers and Packers
 Cape Town Cashiers and Packers Required Urgently, 
 21-06-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save Queries related to &quot; cashier requirements &quot; : packers cape town 
 
   
 Cashiers Required 
 Durban Cashiers required for service station. Good working environment, well situated, salary approx R 3500pm(excl o/t) 
 24-06-2012  -  gumtree.co.za save 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next »    
 cashier requirements 
 
   Create a free email alert for this search or     RSS flow for your search or     Send to a friend 
 Receive listings by email for :
 cashier requirements 
My email address : 
 Error: invalid email address
 You may cancel this alert at any time 
 Email from your friend : Error: invalid email address
 Your message : 
 
 
 What Where   
 
 About  |  Publish your Listings  |  Webmasters
	</body>
</document>
