<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007836" url="http://studentoffortune.com/question/1056875/PLEASE-HELP-WITH-STATISTICS-1Give" time="2012-07-13-00:47" support="4" score="0.004212196120463705" bingtitle="PLEASE HELP WITH STATISTICS. 1. Give - StudentOfFortune.com" webtitle="PLEASE HELP WITH STATISTICS. 1.	Give - StudentOfFortune.com">
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="205"/>
	<description>... had eaten the following number of times at a fast food restaurant ... Rank the following data in increasing order and ... The sample data is shown in Table B. Table A ...</description>
	<body>
		Question 
 $10.00 PLEASE HELP WITH STATISTICS. 1. Give 

 From Mathematics : Statistics Closed , but you can still post tutorials Due on May. 21, 2011 Asked on May 20, 2011 at 6:28:57PM 
 Asked by : madelyn101 
 Rating : No Rating 
 Questions Asked: 35
 Tutorials Posted : 0     Q: PLEASE HELP WITH STATISTICS. 

1. Given the following frequency distribution, find the mean, variance, and standard deviation. Please show all of your work.
 
Errors Frequency
71-73 17
74-76 8
77-79 12
80-82 7
83-85 16


2. Please show all of your work when answering the following:
 
I. Use Chebyshevs theorem to find what percent of the values will fall between 220 and 316 for a data set with a mean of 268 and standard deviation of 12.
 
II. Use the Empirical Rule to find what two values 99.7% of the data will fall between for a data set with a mean of 239 and standard deviation of 19.

3. Nine college students had eaten the following number of times at a fast food restaurant for dinner in the last ten days:
 
1, 5, 10, 6, 7, 8, 8, 6, 8
 
Find the mean, median, mode, range, and midrange for these data. Please show all of your work.

4. A Math test has a mean of 35 and standard deviation of 18.0. Find the corresponding z scores for: 
 
I. a test score of 34 
II. a test score of 71
 
Please show all of your work.

5. Rank the following data in increasing order and find the position and value of the 46th percentile. Please show all of your work.
 
2 2 8 8 3 0 7 2 9 5 2 3
 
6. The following data lists the average monthly snowfall for January in 15 cities around the US:
 
21 5 43 39 45 42 26 40
38 32 17 23 31 28 16
 
Find the mean, variance, and standard deviation. Please show all of your work.

7. Starting with the data values 70 and 100, add three data values to the sample so that the mean is 76, the median is 82, and the mode is 82. Please show all of your work

1. For a particular sample of 63 scores on a psychology exam, the following results were obtained.
First quartile = 57 Third quartile = 87 Standard deviation = 9 Range = 51
Mean = 72 Median = 72 Mode = 98 Midrange = 57
Answer each of the following:
I. What score was earned by more students than any other score? Why? 
II. What was the highest score earned on the exam? 
III. What was the lowest score earned on the exam?
IV. According to Chebyshev&apos;s Theorem, how many students scored between 45 and 99?
V. Assume that the distribution is normal. Based on the Empirical Rule, how many students scored between 45 and 99?
Please show all of your work. 

2. Find the range, standard deviation, and variance for the following sample data:
62, 84, 49, 68, 37, 92, 31, 55, 83, 37, 16, 96, 77, 85, 78, 34 

3. In terms of the mean and standard deviation:
- What does it mean to say that a particular value of x has a standard score of +1.2? 
- What does it mean to say that a particular value of x has a z-score of -2.1? 

4. A student scored 46 percent on a test, and was in the 27th percentile. Explain these two numbers.

5. An animal trainer obtained the following sample data (Table A) in a study of reaction times of dogs (in seconds) to a specific stimulus. He then selected another group of dogs that were much older than the first group and measured their reaction times to the same stimulus. The sample data is shown in Table B. 
Table A Table B 
Classes Frequency Classes Frequency
2.3-2.9 7 2.3-2.9 25
3.0-3.6 6 3.0-3.6 5
3.7-4.3 40 3.7-4.3 15
4.4-5.0 38 4.4-5.0 14
5.1-5.7 4 5.1-5.7 2
5.8-6.4 3 5.8-6.4 35

 
Find the variance and standard deviation for the two distributions above. Compare the variation of the data sets. Decide if one data set is more variable than the other.

6. In each of the four examples listed below, one of the given variables is independent (x) and one of the given variables is dependent (y). Indicate in each case which variable is independent and which variable is dependent.
I. Monthly sales; Monthly commission
II. Miles driven; Gas consumption
III. Blood alcohol level; Alcohol consumption
IV. Test score; Course grade 

7. A sample of purchases at the local convenience store has resulted in the following sample data, where x = the number of items purchased per customer and f = the number of customers. 
x 1 2 3 4 5
f 11 12 8 8 7What does the 12 stand for in the above table?
Find the midrange of items purchased.
How many items were purchased by the customers in this sample?

8. Suppose we have a set of blood pressures with a mean of 120 Systolic, and a sample standard deviation of 15 points. If we assume a normal distribution of Systolic blood pressures, then between what two values can we be assured 99.7% of all Systolic blood pressures will lie?

9. SAT I scores around the nation tend to have a mean scale score around 500, a standard deviation of about 100 points, and are approximately normally distributed. What SAT I score within the population would have a percentile rank of approximately 16? Show all work as to how this is obtained.   Attachments: 
 statistics W2.doc (52K) 
   
     
     
     
         
   
 Home 
   
 Get Tutoring 
   
 Get Paid 
 
   
 
 Home 
 | 
 Blog 
 | 
 Fees 
 | 
 FAQ 
 
 
 
 Ask a Question 
 | 
 How Does This Work? 
 | 
 Recent Tutorials 
 | 
 Topics 
 
 
 
 Upload a Tutorial 
 | 
 See Recent Questions 
 | 
 Browse Questions 
 | 
 Affiliate Program 
 
       Blog | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Press | Frequently Asked Questions | Contact Us | Affiliates | Sitemap | About Us 
 Cheap Textbooks | Chegg Coupon 
Copyright©Student Of Fortune, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
