<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007624" url="http://www.homewindpowerkits.net/i-need-help-ten-points-best-answers.php/" time="2012-07-13-00:35" support="1" score="0.000756447320744187" bingtitle="I need help ten points best answers.? :Home Wind Power Kits, Home ..." webtitle="I need help ten points best answers.? :Home Wind Power Kits, Home Wind Power, Wind Power Generators">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>... sample of 250 customers at a fast food restaurant ... are able to predict the total number of visitors that plan to return to the park. ... one of the eleven for a one car ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Wind Generated Power For The Home About Us Contact Us Home Wind Power Kits Privacy Policy 
 
 Home Wind Power Kits, Home Wind Power, Wind Power Generators 

Build a wind power generator and save money on your electric bills.
 
Subscribe via Email | RSS 
 
I need help ten points best answers.?
 Thursday, April 29th, 2010 at
1:36 am  

 


 

I did all 50 questions and i need help with these thank u.

8.
In a random sample of 250 customers at a fast food restaurant, 84 customers ordered a salad. If the restaurant typically has 1,000 customers in a day, how many customers will probably order a salad? (2 points)
• 386 customers
• 436 customers
• 336 customers
• 261 customers
9.
A survey showed that 56% of car owners prefer four-doors cars, 31% prefer two-door cars, and 13% have no preference. You ask 550 people. How many do you think will prefer four-door cars? (2 points)
• 358 people
• 208 people
• 308 people
• 373 people
10.
Gina has made 40% of her goal kicks in soccer. How could you simulate her next 14 goal kicks? (2 points)
• Flip 1 coin.
• Spin a spinner with 10 equal sections having 4 sections shaded.
• Flip 2 coins.
• Roll a number cube with 9 sides.

12.
A yogurt shop offers 6 different flavors of frozen yogurt and 9 different toppings. How many choices are possible for a single serving of frozen yogurt with one topping? (2 points)
• 54 choices
• 52 choices
• 15 choices
• 57 choices
13.
Jamestown Builders has a development of new homes. There are 5 different floor plans, 11 exterior colors, and an option of either a one-car or a two-car garage. How many choices are there for one home? (2 points)
• 18 choices
• 165 choices
• 110 choices
• 55 choices
14.
If no digit appears more than once, how many 5-digit numbers can be formed from the digits 2, 3, 4, 6, and 7? (2 points)
• 120 numbers
• 24 numbers
• 126 numbers
• 115 numbers
15.
Which events are independent? (2 points)
• You draw 2 colored cards at the same time and get one red and one green.
• You study English 20 minutes nightly, and then you get an A on the next test.
• You toss two coins and get one head, one tail.
• You choose two ice cream flavors.
Short Answer

22.
The owners of an amusement park have hired you to find out if visitors will return to their park. You find that 45,000 people visit the park during a given week. When you ask 1,000 people at random whether or not they will return, 750 say yes, 150 say no, and 100 say they are unsure.

a. Organize the results of your survey into a chart. Note: create a chart on a separate piece of paper.
b. Summarize your findings and explain to the owners how you are able to predict the total number of visitors that plan to return to the park.

 


 


 Filed under: Home Wind Turbines 

 Like this post? Subscribe to my RSS feed and get loads more!
 
 Comments RSS Feed TrackBack URI 
 
4 Comments

 KiwiKid loves you ;] says: April 29, 2010 at 1:36 am 
In a random sample of 250 customers at a fast food restaurant, 84 customers ordered a salad. If the restaurant typically has 1,000 customers in a day, how many customers will probably order a salad?
250 is a quarter of 1000, right. So 84/250 = 336/1000 = 336 customers.

A survey showed that 56% of car owners prefer four-doors cars, 31% prefer two-door cars, and 13% have no preference. You ask 550 people. How many do you think will prefer four-door cars? (2 points)
0.56 * 550 = 308 people

Gina has made 40% of her goal kicks in soccer. How could you simulate her next 14 goal kicks?
Spin a spinner with 10 equal sections having 4 sections shaded.

A yogurt shop offers 6 different flavors of frozen yogurt and 9 different toppings. How many choices are possible for a single serving of frozen yogurt with one topping?
I don’t know.

If no digit appears more than once, how many 5-digit numbers can be formed from the digits 2, 3, 4, 6, and 7? (2 points)
120

Which events are independent? (2 points)
You toss two coins and get one head, one tail.

Organize the results of your survey into a chart. Note: create a chart on a separate piece of paper.
This is easy.
Yes | No | Unsure | Total
750 | 150| 100 | 1000
 Jon says: April 29, 2010 at 1:36 am 
8:336/1000
12:54
the other ones are too complicated for me lol too much brainwork
 candid101 says: April 29, 2010 at 1:36 am 
 84 customers x customers
____________ = ____________
250 customers 1000 customers

cross multiply (84 times 1000) and divide by 250.
answer: 336 customers

9) 56 x
____ = _____
100 550

cross multiply (550 times 56) and divide by 100
answer: 308

10) spin a spinner. 4/10 is the simplified from 40/100

12) 54 [each of the six can have one of nine toppings]

13) 110. each of the five can have one of the eleven for a one car garage. which is fifty-five. each of the five can have one of the eleven for a two-car garage which is fifty five. added together, you get 110
 Just a person who enjoys answers says: April 29, 2010 at 1:36 am 
This site is not for getting other people to do your homework for you. Could you not try and answer those for yourself.
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 
 
 

 

 
 
Home Wind And Solar Power
 
Adding an additional power source to your home or even replacing a traditional gas or electric system with solar panels or wind turbines is an alternative for many homeowners today.
Installing Solar or Wind power units for your home can not only help save you dollars on your heating and electric bills, but help save the planet. As more and more people use greener solutions for energy production in the household, it is creating a more sustainable ecology for the world.
One of the options that many people are looking into is building your own windmill or wind power system. The DIY or do it yourself models have been big sellers and are quite popular, as they provide the means to getting your own home wind power but also can save on the cost significantly as well.
The range of the cost varies greatly and can be anywhere from several hundred dollars to over $20,000 for a particular system, depending on your needs.
It all depends on how much energy you are using and where your home is and the environment of your area in particular. In a very urban and crowded area it will not be as effective as it would in a rural and more open environment as the city and urban areas tend to limit the amount of energy that can be created by such windmill units.
Very rarely, if ever, do these home wind turbines generate enough power to eliminate the need for gas and oil, but they can reduce your bills and also lower your carbon footprint significantly, which is important to many as well as saving money.
 
 
Categories

 Home Solar Power Home Wind Power Kits Home Wind Turbines Photovoltaic Solar Panels Wind energy Wind Power 

Recent Posts

 FHA Loans and Green Homes? Do we save energy if we unplug our cable, phone, and computer bundle each night? Do you save more energy keeping your laptop plugged in all day or only charging when you have low battery? Which would be the best air filter for my truck? What is the point of wind farms/turbines? Is it worth it to save energy by shutting off water heaters when not taking showers? How do you change the air filter for a 2006 Scion tc? What are some expensive ways to save energy? Green Chillies: are they just unripe chillies? How can I acquire cheap land for living off grid/sustainably? When and where was the world&apos;s first SUCCESSFUL wind farm? What are two positive aspects and two negative aspects of wind power? Why is my central air not cooling my house? What companies want to lunch energy efficient business in China? Cervelli and Gardner back-to-back home runs? 

Recent Comments

 H ikram Sadiq on FHA Loans and Green Homes? Phantom of on Do we save energy if we unplug our cable, phone, and computer bundle each night? Jackie Sun on Do we save energy if we unplug our cable, phone, and computer bundle each night? Casey Stinnett on Do we save energy if we unplug our cable, phone, and computer bundle each night? Mike T on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? Chris D on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? belairjr on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? dalrker2003 on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? Anthony C on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? dewcoons on Do you save more energy keeping your laptop plugged in all day or only charging when you have low battery? fwendt72 on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? goodfella8243 on Which would be the best air filter for my truck? Jon M on Do you save more energy keeping your laptop plugged in all day or only charging when you have low battery? DR. DIRT on Is it worth it to save energy by shutting off water heaters when not taking showers? my3terrors on Is it worth it to save energy by shutting off water heaters when not taking showers? 

Resources

 Best News Politics Energy efficiency and renewable energy Homepower magazine Making Renewable Doable Products for Home Power Solar Power/Wind Power Technology Smooths the Way for Home Wind-Power Turbines Wind Turbines for Home Power 

Tags
 alternative energy alternative energy sources amp apartment appliances batteries cars clean energy coal earth electric guitar electricity furnace google green energy heating oil hot water insulation jobs js money natural gas quot renewable energy script type solar energy solar panel solar panels solar power solar wind sun text javascript thanks in advance thermostat turbine watts Wind energy wind farm Wind Farms wind generator windmill windmills Wind Power wind turbine wind turbines 
Archives

 December 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 February 2011 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 February 2009 January 2009 
 
This blog copyright© Home Wind Power Kits, Home Wind Power, Wind Power Generators
	</body>
</document>
