<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007535" url="http://www.afs.nonprofitoffice.com/index.asp?Type=B_BASIC&amp;SEC={F30DF060-29DD-4F62-A782-39C2576D2B65}&amp;DE={D3840634-5213-4043-A598-F7166ABE496E}" time="2012-07-13-00:30" support="1" score="0.0007625107063259392" bingtitle="David Morris, Vice President of Institute for Local Self Reliance ..." webtitle="David Morris, Vice President of Institute for Local Self Reliance -
		Recipients of the Second Annual Sustainability Awards - Alliance for Sustainability">
			<query id="000386" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Contrary to conventional wisdom, every time a fast food restaurant opened the number of jobs in the ... helped communities defeat or cancel over 150 large-scale waste ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content .
 
 
 
 2012 Sustainable Communities Conference - March 23&amp;24 Green-U Upcoming events Sustainability Awards Awards Sponsors Recipients of the Second Annual Sustainability Awards Previous Awards events Sponsors Past Events 
 


 
 
 Search 
 GO 
 Full Site 
 This Section 

 Search Tips 
 
 

 
 
 David Morris, Vice President of Institute for Local Self Reliance
 
 David Morris, Vice President, Institute for Local Self Reliance 

 Nominee: David Morris, Vice-President, Institute for Local Self-Reliance 

 1313 5th St. SE , Minneapolis , MN 55414 www.ilsr.org 

 Summary: 
For more than three decades David Morris has been one of the nation’s leading proponents for humanly-scaled, community-based economic and political systems as a prolific writer, speaker and advocate who has provided the basis for an extraordinary array of path-breaking policy initiatives. An economist by training with stellar academic credentials, David is a syndicated columnist and author of more than 200 books and articles on rural communities, energy and sustainability. He co-founded the Minneapolis and Washington, D.C.-based Institute for Local Self-Reliance in 1974 and currently serves as its Vice-President and director of its New Rules Project. The Institute’s mission is to identify public policies that promote strong, locally owned and environmentally sound economies and to assist communities to move in that direction. 

 Detailed Description: 
David is one of the most enlightened, energetic, and thoughtful speakers on the future of America . He has selflessly devoted his life to improving the quality of life for people living in both rural and urban communities throughout America . Bill Moyers calls him&quot;one of the nation&apos;s most innovative thinkers&quot;and US Senator Paul Wellstone of Minnesota described him as&quot;one of the nation&apos;s leading experts on sustainable development.&quot; 

Morris holds a PhD. from Union Graduate School (1976), an MA in Political Science / Latin American Studies from the University of Florida , and a BA in Industrial and Labor Relations from Cornell University . 

His writings range from an analysis of economic and political development in Chile to an evaluation of the potential for ecological and autonomous cities and neighborhoods, as well as a how-to-manual on electric power generation. His books include The New City States , Self-Reliant Cities , Ethanol Policy and Development :  1978-1992 (1992), The Carbohydrate Economy: Making Chemicals and Industrial Materials from Plant Matter (1993). His book, Seeing the Light: Regaining Control of Our Electricity System , argues for a more decentralized power system and cities assuming a more central role in energy planning. He is also the co-author of two peer-reviewed energy balance studies on ethanol and bio-diesel: How Much Energy Does It Take to Make a Gallon of Ethanol? (1995), and How Much Energy Does It Take to Make a Gallon of Soy-diesel? (1996) 

His articles have appeared in the Wall Street Journal , New York Times , Washington Post , Los Angeles Times and the Smithsonian magazine. He appears regularly on TV and radio, including All Things Considered, NBC’s TODAY Show, The O’Reilly Factor, and CNN Financial News. 

Among his areas of expertise is energy in the rural areas of America . David has been an advisor on Energy to four U.S. Presidents and is a nationally known expert on ethanol, wind-generated power, and electric vehicles. He has testified before numerous legislative committees at the state and federal level and currently serves on the Congressionally-created Biomass Advisory Committee to the U.S. Departments of Agriculture and Energy. 

David believes that rural America provides the economic backbone of the country, and that the very fabric of social culture is wrought in the countryside of our great country. His message is not only one of hope; but, of a path that will lead us there.

The Institute for Local Self Reliance (ILSR) is a small organization with a remarkable track record for breaking new ground in promoting sustainable communities. In 1978 RAIN magazine described ILSR as an organization that&quot;puts hard numbers on soft dreams&quot;. 

Ever since its founding ILSR has researched the feasibility of communities generating a significant amount of wealth from local resources and has worked with the increasing numbers of communities interested in moving in that direction. In its initial years it focused on its surrounding Washington , D.C. neighborhood, Adams Morgan. Its urban townhouse became a working model of its ideas, with rooftop hydroponic gardens and solar collectors and a commercial basement sprout operation and composting toilet. It researched the income flows and ownership patterns of the neighborhood and helped to build cooperative businesses. 

Later it widened its lens to examine cities, and then regions. It became a national organization and worked with state and national governments. Yet its work continued to be informed by its projects in communities and connections to grassroots organizations, small businesses, farmers and local governments. 

ILSR was the first to systematically apply the concept of local self-reliance to urban areas. In 1980 ILSR was the first to investigate the energy conservation and solar energy potential for a major city ( Baltimore ) and was one of the first groups to formally testify before a utility regulatory commission in favor of investing in energy conservation as a cheaper alternative to new energy supplies.   

ILSR also tracked the dollar flows of a neighborhood franchise--MacDonald&apos;s--in a study that remains a classic. It found that of the $750,000 spent there almost two-thirds left not only the neighborhood but the metropolitan area. Contrary to conventional wisdom, every time a fast food restaurant opened the number of jobs in the local economy actually declined.   

ILSR has always believed that with the proper public policies, communities could become far more productive places. In 1990,&quot;The $6 Billion Solution: Making Minnesota Energy Self-Reliant&quot;, provided Minnesota policymakers, business and citizen organizations the first assessment of the potential for substituting homegrown fuels for imported energy and offered strategies to achieve that goal. 

With regard to solid waste, ILSR has always argued that these are valuable resources that, if recovered, could strengthen local and regional economies. In the late 1970s and early 1980s ILSR was the primary national group providing assistance to grassroots organizations fighting garbage incinerators. By the mid-1980&apos;s ILSR&apos;s citizen training efforts helped communities defeat or cancel over 150 large-scale waste incinerators. It helped to stop more than 30 proposed incinerators with the dual argument that incinerators were expensive and polluting and that they foreclosed the more valuable option of recycling.   

To prove to policymakers that communities would recycle in 1986 it published the first case studies on the subject,&quot;Beyond 25 Percent&quot;. In 1988,&quot;Beyond 40 Percent&quot;became a bestseller among activists and policymakers. For the first time it offered concrete evidence that recycling and composting could become the primary waste handling strategy rather than playing only supplementary roles. 

ILSR&apos;s interest in local resources extends beyond used materials to new, renewable materials. In 1986, ILSR&apos;s&quot;Substituting Agricultural Materials for Petroleum-Based Industrial Products&quot;was the first state-based study of the potential for making agricultural materials into industrial products. In 1992, a broader and more comprehensive report,&quot;The Carbohydrate Economy: Making Chemical and Industrial Materials from Plant Matter&quot;, broke new ground by arguing that a new economy is emerging that could potentially satisfy three major objectives: environmental protection, rural development and the preservation of small farms. 

In October 1992 its work on plant-derived plastics led to co-hosting the first International Workshop on Biodegradability. Some forty scientists from around the world discussed the elements of a common definition and testing protocol for degradable materials. The proceedings were published in&quot;Toward Common Ground&quot;. 

In the 1990s, as&quot;sustainable development&quot;has grown, ILSR played a key role in integrating the concepts of human scale, community development and intra-generational equity into a concept that often was focused on natural resource protection. In early 1993 David delivered the keynote address to the opening session of Minnesota &apos;s Sustainable Development Initiative,&quot;Setting the Compass: Toward a Sustainable Minnesota,”which was the first time a local self-reliance framework had been applied to such a statewide initiative.   

ILSR&apos;s emphasis on the primacy of territorial communities--neighborhoods, cities, counties, regions--has led it to examine the role that transportation subsidies play in encouraging long distribution systems. In 1992,&quot;Getting from Here to There: Building a Rational Transportation System&quot;offered an analysis of a transportation pricing and financing framework that embraced two new economic principles: full cost pricing and least cost accounting. 

In 1987 ILSR was one of the first American groups to offer a critical analysis of the free trade issue in&quot;Free Trade: The Great Destroyer&quot;. Since then it has been actively involved in the debate about GATT and NAFTA. In keeping with its history, philosophy and experience, ILSR maintains that global rules that govern commerce are needed and that these rules should be designed to encourage sustainable communities rather than merely to encourage greater mobility. 

 Awards: David received the student athlete award on graduating from high school.  The Utne Reader listed him as one of the top 100 visionaries in America . President Clinton&apos;s Secretary of Energy appointed him to a congressionally created advisory committee to the DOE and USDA and President Bush&apos;s Secretary of Energy reappointed him. 
 
 
 
 
 

 1521 University Ave SE - Minneapolis, MN 55414 - 612-331-1099 - iasa@mtn.org 
 Home | Support Us | WHO WE ARE | Contact Us | GET INVOLVED! | The Natural Step | INSPIRING EVENTS | Register for events | LEARNING&amp;ACTION | Sustainable Schools | Green Neighborhoods&amp;Cities | Congregations | TIPPING POINTS | Sustainability Campaign | Pilot Communities | Media Room 
 powered by NonprofitOffice.com
	</body>
</document>
