<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007029" url="http://www.727area.com/restaurants/" time="2012-07-13-00:01" support="1" score="0.0004766772027062891" bingtitle="St Petersburg &amp; Clearwater Restaurants | Dining Guide &amp; Restaurant ..." webtitle="St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater Restaurants | Dining Guide&amp;Restaurant Reviews in Saint Petersburg Florida">
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>$6 for a single whiskey and coke in a plastic cup? Come on. ... ... Head out to Crabby Bill&apos;s and enjoy the beautiful sunset over the beach while you ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign Up Log In 
 
 Home Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Events Travel Recreation Shopping Jobs Real Estate Photos&amp;Video 
 
 Restaurants Home All Restaurants Seafood Pizza Delivery Daily Specials 
 
Upcoming Events in St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater
 12 Jul Tequila Tasting Thursday 
6:00 PM at Taps&amp;Tequila 12 Jul Tequila Tasting Thursday 
6:00 PM at Taps&amp;Tequila 13 Jul Tampa Bay Rays vs. Boston Red Sox 
TBA at Tropicana Field 14 Jul Tampa Bay Rays vs. Boston Red Sox 
TBA at Tropicana Field 15 Jul Tampa Bay Rays vs. Boston Red Sox 
TBA at Tropicana Field View All Events 
Recent Nightlife Photos

 Downtown Digital at Jannus Live 
2012-06-02 Bliss Cabaret with Nikki Delano 
2012-01-28 The Pirate Ship Royal Conquest 
2011-11-11 Bliss Cabaret Nightmoves Caravan of Star 
2011-10-06 Porn Star Road Trip at Bliss Cabaret 
2011-09-30 
 
 View All Photo Albums 
St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater Reviews
 
 Sean C reviewed Frenchy&apos;s Rockaway Grill 

 Pros: 
Location, food, location, views, location, prices. ...
 Cons: 
Service not always the best but it is the beach so you should not be in a hurry. Sometimes a long wait but that&apos;s the price to pay for ...
 Comments: 
Great location!! I love the Grouper sandwich and it is well worth the drive from Tampa. I make sure to stop through when I come to the beach ...
Overall Rating: 
 
Anonymous User reviewed Pilates in the Park 

 Pros: 
The core toning it provides. ...
 Cons: 
...
 Comments: 
I went this morning and it was fun, refreshing, beautiful outside, and a great workout. I could keep going with the pros but you guys should just come find out ...
Overall Rating: 
 
 Ozonaman reviewed Sawgrass Tiki Bar 

 Pros: 
none ...
 Cons: 
see above ...
 Comments: 
STAY AWAY! STAY AWAY! Worst hole near the sponge docks. I ordered a 50oz margarita and if it had alcohol, I didn&apos;t taste it nor did it have any effect. ...
Overall Rating: 
 
 St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater FL &gt;&gt; Business Directory &gt;&gt; St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater restaurants 
 
St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater Restaurants
 Find restaurants by Type, by Location or both by simply selecting from the following choices. Browse All Types American Asian Barbecue Breakfast Buffet Cajun Caribbean Carryout Catering Chinese Coffee House Cuban Deli Style Delivery French Greek Indian Italian Japanese Latin Mexican Pizza Seafood Southern Spanish Steakhouse Sushi Thai Vegetarian Browse All Locations St Petersburg Clearwater Largo Pinellas Park St Pete Beach Clearwater Beach Treasure Island Madeira Beach Indian Rocks Beach Dunedin New Port Richey Tarpon Springs Palm Harbor Gulfport 
 1 2 3 
 
 Best Grouper in Clearwater, FL 

Cleawater, Florida is known for their grouper. Whether you want a grouper sandwich, filet, taco, or however you like it, find the best places in Clearwater for grouper.
 
 Sushi in Saint Petersburg 

Is your mouth watering for the taste of sushi? Find a sushi restaurant in Saint Petersburg.
 
 Pizza Restaurants in Saint Petersburg 

Maybe New York style pizza is your favorite. Maybe Chicago deep dish. Find pizza restaurants in Saint Petersburg that fit your craving!
 
Restaurants

by Neighborhood

 St Petersburg Clearwater Largo Pinellas Park St Pete Beach 

by Type

 Seafood Mexican Pizza Restaurants Steakhouses Sushi Bars 
 
Popular Restaurants

 The V Caddy&apos;s on the Beach Cabanas American Bar and Grill Vue 19 Taps&amp;Tequila Acropolis Clearwater 13 Cafe and Lounge Arthur Treacher&apos;s Fish&amp;Chips Frenchy&apos;s Rockaway Grill Ceviche Tapas Bar and Restaurant 
 
Recently Reviewed
 Frenchy&apos;s Rockaway Grill Vue 19 The Garden Restaurant 
Before You Go Out

 Find the Nightlife Check out the Specials Book a Hotel Find an Event Go Shopping 
 
 Billy&apos;s Stone Crab, Seafood, and Steaks on St. Pete Beach 
The name says it all; Billy&apos;s, simply put, is one of the best places for some truly great stone crab, seafood, and steaks on St. Pete Beach.  Open since 1972, Billy&apos;s Stone Crab, Seafood, and Steaks has worked to perfect the art of cooking some truly great seafood and more in their...
 Green Iguana Closes in St. Petersburg, Opens Inside Airport 
Green Iguana, one of the biggest local bar and restaurant chains in the Tampa Bay area, has closed its St. Petersburg location at 8790 Bay Pines Boulevard in the Tyrone area.

Green Iguana officials decided not to renew the lease on the St. Petersburg Green Iguana, the franchise&apos;s...
 Willy&apos;s Burgers&amp;Booze, St. Pete Beach 
Burgers, booze, and the beach; an excessive, overindulgent, and admittedly awesome combination.  If you find yourself on St. Pete Beach, the prime destination for all of this is Willy&apos;s Burgers&amp;Booze, a year-old burger joint providing locals and visitors alike with the...
 Mo&apos; Ziki | Delicious, Fast, Affordable Greek Food in Largo 
Fresh, flavorful, fast, and affordable are the name of the game at Mo&apos; Ziki, Largo&apos;s newest destination for delectable, Greek-inspired cuisine.  Opened just under a year ago at the Promenade Bardmoor Center, Mo&apos; Ziki aims to provide Largo residents and visitors alike with fast-casual...
 Slyce Pizza Bar, Indian Rocks Beach | Stone Fired Pizza and More! 
Nothing beats a great slice of pizza.  Gooey cheese, heavenly crust, delectable toppings; they can all come together to make a seriously delicious meal.  All throughout the 727 area there are tons of places to grab a slice or pie that will definitely satisfy.  Slyce Pizza...
 
 
Most Popular Restaurants in St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater

 The Most Popular Restaurants in St Petersburg&amp;Clearwater FL are determined by our users Favorite Places

 Arigato Japanese Steak House 

 
8.4 Located off US 19 in Clearwater, Arigato Japanese Steak House features an extensive menu of Japanese cuisine. Choose from a variety of steak and ... Crabby Bill&apos;s 

 
7.3 Located right in the heart of Clearwater Beach near Pier 60, Crabby Bill&apos;s is quite popular for their seafood and drink specials. ... Guppy&apos;s 

 
8.9 Seafood restaurant which is very popular for sunset dinners and outside dining. The menu includes everything from a Grouper sandwich to the Guppy&apos;s Seafood ... Captain Kosmakos Seafood House 

 
0.0 ... A Bit of Germany 

 
0.0 ... 
 

Sections
 Nightlife Restaurants Events Travel Recreation Business Directory Jobs Real Estate The Loop 


About
 About 727area.com Contact Us Partners FAQ Terms of Use Privacy Policy Careers Sitemap 


Business Toolbox
 Add Your Business Post Your Event Advertise with Us 


Connect
 Sign Up Now Find Us on Facebook Follow Us on Twitter RSS Feeds 


Popular Areas
 St Petersburg Clearwater Largo Pinellas Park St Pete Beach Clearwater Beach Treasure Island Madeira Beach Indian Rocks Beach Dunedin New Port Richey Tarpon Springs Palm Harbor Gulfport 
 All logos and trademarks in this site are property of their respective owner.
The comments and listings are property of their posters.
All the rest Copyright©2012 by 813area.com .
All Rights Reserved.
 Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
