<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007069" url="http://inquietnessandconfidence.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="1" score="0.0006258313147386382" bingtitle="In quietness and confidence - Home" webtitle="In quietness and confidence - Home">
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Just a quiet day to reflect, and count ... gooey caramel at the bottom of the cup. Jalapeno bites at the local fast food restaurant ... is not just to lose weight, but to change ...</description>
	<body>
		In quietness and confidence 
 Home About Me My Family Resources Blogroll Disclosure 
 
 More counting... 10/03/2011 0 Comments   
 It&apos;s raining outside today. I guess it wouldn&apos;t be raining inside, huh? Unless the roof was leaking! But oh, how refreshing after months of dry heat. Cool, crisp, moist air. 

 The leaves are starting to turn, the dormant time of winter is coming.  A time to curl up beneath a blanket on the couch with a good book. Watch a movie with the kids, and eat popcorn. 

 Just a quiet day to reflect, and count those blessings... 

 11 - aahhh, rain. 

 12 - a little girl copying bible stories from her bible

 13 - a toddler clinging to Mom, because she just needed to be held 

 14 - almost all As on a boy&apos;s school work 

 15 - reading to my kids 

 16 - notes for Mama written by a five year old 

 17 - learning 

 18 - grace 

 19 - forgiveness 

 20 - &quot; He who began a good work in you will carry it on to completion until the day of Christ Jesus .&quot;  
 
 Add Comment   John 10 09/29/2011 0 Comments   The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy;
 I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full. 
 John 10:10 
 
 Add Comment   Seeing Jesus Through Her Eyes 09/27/2011 0 Comments   Did you ever want to see Jesus through the eyes of someone who followed him? Who walked the path he walked, and knew him intimately? How about through the eyes of a woman who followed him?
 
 I came across an encouraging resource recently at Magdalena Today . You can order a free DVD called &quot; Magdalena: Through Her Eyes &quot;, or watch the movie instantly on their site here . This movie was made by women for women, and focuses specifically on encounters Jesus had with women and how he responded to them. From the woman at the well to the woman caught in adultery.  A woman filled with demons to a little girl who was dead. 
 (taken from their site )
 &quot;The film, &quot; Magdalena: Through Her Eyes &quot;, is the true story of Jesus seen through the eyes of Mary Magdalene–a story of tenderness, freedom and purpose. &quot;Magdalena&quot; reveals what can happen when women refuse to live in defeat and choose to discover their real value.&quot;
 The site also includes a bible study with downloadable video clips for group or personal studies, and other books to encourage women in their walk with the Lord. 
 
 Add Comment   Counting One Thousand Gifts 09/26/2011 0 Comments   
 I&apos;ve been following Ann Voskamp at A Holy Experience for the last 18 months or so. She is by far one of my most favorite bloggers and I read her posts almost daily. Her poetic writing leaves much to contemplate. Her main theme - all is grace . All. Is. Grace. Think about that for a moment. Everything we have, every moment we are given, is just grace showered down from Heaven, from a loving Father who gave us all He had on the cross, who gives us every good thing for our benefit and His glory.  

 Ann wrote a book, too, called One Thousand Gifts, which I&apos;m still digesting after only one read. She presents an outlook on life that we all need - to count our blessings, even in the midst of heartache and turmoil, to see how God is working in our lives moment by moment, day by day. An attitude of gratitude. A habit of purposefully seeing, eyes wide open, heart open even wider to receive all as gift.  
 
 Every Monday, Ann leads a community in counting one thousand gifts (and many more). I will be joining her and others in counting my own gifts given by the One who made all, is in all, from Whom all blessings flow. Will you join me?
 
 1 ~ A two year old girl doing her happy dance with a smile that brightens any room
 
 2 ~ A five year old girl teaching herself how to read
 
 3 ~ Five little ones sitting around the living room all quiet with books in laps
 
 4 ~ Rain
 
 5 ~ Home school
 
 6 ~ The sweet smell of early morning dew
     
 7 ~ A 13 year old disabled boy doing his own happy dance when the bus shows up for school
 
 8 ~ Bookcases full of books
 
 9 ~ The availability of almost anything in the world through the internet. If I need it, I can buy it. If I want
               to know something, I can find out. If I want to reach someone, they&apos;re right there.
 
 10 ~ Bible-teaching podcasts   
 
 Add Comment   Isaiah 43 09/21/2011 0 Comments   
 Do not fear, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name; you are Mine!
 When you pass through the waters, I will be with you; 
 and through the rivers, they will not overflow you. 
 When you walk through the fire, you will not be scorched, nor will the flame burn you. 
 For I am the Lord your God, the Holy One of Israel, your Savior. 

 Isaiah 43:1-3 
 
 
 Add Comment   Losing Weight - Week 1 09/21/2011 0 Comments   I&apos;ve been complacent, gluttonous, an addict. A food addict. Yep, there I said it. Over the last few years, well, all my life really, I&apos;ve turned to food for comfort, solace, joy, a reward, even mindless eating to appease my mouth&apos;s desire for texture. You know, the crunch of M&amp;Ms and the smooth, chocolatey middle. The crunch of the ice in my favorite milky way blended coffee, and the gooey caramel at the bottom of the cup. Jalapeno bites at the local fast food restaurant because life is moving faster than I can keep up sometimes, and I just enjoy that warm cream cheese middle and the sweet berry sauce. Yum!

 I&apos;ve gone through phases of weight loss in my life, some larger amounts of weight than others. I&apos;ve exercised regularly, eaten healthy meals, and watched my body take on that curvy shape while my pants size got smaller. The last three and a half years, I&apos;ve given in to &quot; just getting through the moment&quot; when life overwhelms with seizure disorders and job layoffs and home remodels and... life. Five pounds here and ten pounds there slowly adds up to (gulp!) 75 pounds . I don&apos;t own a full size mirror, so it wasn&apos;t that obvious to me. I simply bought bigger clothes. But now when I catch a glimpse of myself in the reflection of a window, or I&apos;m brave enough to stand on a chair in front of the mirror over the bathroom sink, I gasp. What have I done?!

 If there&apos;s anything I have learned this last year in my walk with the Lord, it is to choose each day whom I will serve, and that I have a choice and it is mine to make. No one can or will make it for me - not even God, unless our souls depend on it, and then He&apos;ll move Heaven and earth to accomplish what He must, whether we like it or not. But really, every day, every moment is a choice, and the other thing I started learning years ago (and have been slow to catch on, ahem) is that God asks us to follow right now . No going back to get something you forgot. Just follow right now. So, on September 9, I chose to quit eating all the &quot;bad stuff&quot; and chose a diet plan I felt I could live with. My goal is not just to lose weight, but to change how I eat for the rest of my life. Still, it&apos;s daily choices, built one on top of another, and daily I must lean on God for strength to make those right choices. To date I have lost 9 lbs, just by changing what I eat. In the coming weeks, I will share what diet plan I chose, how my weight loss is and why.    Add Comment   

 Welcome! 
 My name is Bridgett.  
 I write here about life as a child of God, completely flawed, but saved by His amazing grace. You&apos;ll find info and observations here about children of divorce, frugal living, homeschooling, widowhood, disabilities, homemaking, motherhood, marriage, and learning to trust God in every area of life. 

 
 What I&apos;m reading... 
 The Ryrie Study Bible KJV
	</body>
</document>
