<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007418" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/how-much-money-spend-fast-food-310183.html" time="2012-07-13-00:23" support="12" score="0.051427285243849846" bingtitle="How Much Money Do You Spend on Fast Food? - Yahoo! Voices - voices ..." webtitle="How Much Money Do You Spend on Fast Food? - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="39"/>
	<description>If you order fast food for lunch and dinner, 5 days a week, this turns into $200-$250 a ... you are paying about $10 a pound for the beef alone when you go to a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
How Much Money Do You Spend on Fast Food?
 Keith Riffle , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Apr 27, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food Food Spending Worst Fast Food 
 Flag Close The fast food industry makes lots of money. If you are looking for ways to save money, you need to ask yourself how much money you spend on fast food. You would think the amount is rather insignificant, but the reality is that most people spend more money on fast food than they realize.
How much do you spend on fast food each week? The answer depends on how much you eat at fast food restaurants, and what you eat when you are there.

On the one hand, there are certain items on fast food menus which are rather inexpensive, such as the items you find on the &quot;value menu&quot;. Most of these items cost less then $1, and help you stretch the dollar. So, if you stick to the value menu when you eat at fast food extablishments, you aren&apos;t going to be spending a very large amount of money. However, when you order items that are not from the value menu, things can get costly.

For example, suppose you eat fast food once a day for lunch, 5 days a week, and you always order a &quot;combo meal&quot;, consisting of a burger, french fries, and a drink. Depending on where you order your fast food, this is going to cost you $4-5 a meal. Multiply that times 5 days a week and you get $20-25 a week or $100-125 a month, just on fast food, for only one meal a day. If you order fast food for lunch and dinner, 5 days a week, this turns into $200-$250 a month, and this is only for two meals a day.

Now, eating fast food is not exactly the healthiest thing to do, but for comparison purposes, how does the cost of fast food stack up against the cost of food at a grocery store? The results may astound you.

For starters, compare the cost of beverages at fast food extablishements to the cost of beverages at the grocery store. For example, you are usually charged about $1 (and in many cases more) for a medium sized fountain beverage, about a third of which is ice. Yet, if you go to the grocery, you can usually get a 12 pack of the same beverage for under $4. So, that same 12 pack of soda pop at the grocery store is going to cost you $12 at the fast food establishment!

But that is just soda pop, what about beef? Well, you can get a hamburger by itself for about $3 at a fast food establishment, which usually has 1/4 pound of beef. If you deduct a little for the price of the bun, you are paying about $10 a pound for the beef alone when you go to a fast food restaurant. Since you can buy 1 pound of beef for $2 at the grocery store, you are spending about 5 times as much for the same amount of beef at the fast food establishment compared to the grocery store.

If you want to save money, stop spending so much money at the fast food establishment, and start spending more at the grocery store!
 
Published by Keith Riffle 

Keith works part time as an internet marketer, and resides in Omaha, NE.  View profile 
 
 What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? Ever notice that the fast food places used to have really good food in the beginning Fast Food Failures What if someone put together a list of all the really bad fast food restaurants? What if that someone was me? Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Many fast food restaurants are now offering healthy choices. This means Americans can get their instant satisfaction without receiving a side order of thunder thighs. But, how... How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants Most of us have eaten inside a fast food restaurant at least once in our lives, if only to drop in for a quick lunch while traveling cross-country with the family. Staying safe... Kick the Fast Food Habit Addicted to fast food?&quot; Here are some ideas to help you beat your addiction. 

 Product Review: Ore Ida Fast Foo... Make Your Own Fast Food with No... Consumer Saving Tips- Saving Mon... 
 
 Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Save Money: How to Lower Your Next Grocery Bill Is Fast Food Becoming Slow? Fast Food Vs. Your Budget: &quot;Cheap&quot; Convenience Food Isn&apos;t All that Inexpensive! Breaking the Fast Food Habit Fast Food is Everywhere in CA Healthy Fast Food Choices 
 
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Health and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
