<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007424" url="http://jamaica-gleaner.com/gleaner/20120314/health/health3.html" time="2012-07-13-00:23" support="10" score="0.03192884152657718" bingtitle="Adding up fast-food calories - Health - Jamaica Gleaner ..." webtitle="Adding up fast-food calories - Health - Jamaica Gleaner - Wednesday | March 14, 2012">
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000850" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>OK, so your favourite fast-food restaurant now posts the calorie count of your ... bucket of chicken was listed as having 3,240 to 12,360 calories, but the menu board ...</description>
	<body>
		Wednesday | March 14, 2012 
 
 
 Kingston           
 
 Home Lead Stories News Sports Entertainment Business Letters Commentary Flair Health 
 
 World News Lifestyle In Focus Auto Social Outlook Food Art&amp;Leisure 

 Classifieds Jobs Photos Radio 
 Mobile Version 
 Subscribe to this feed 
 Join us on Facebook 
 Follow us on Twitter 
 
Adding up fast-food calories
 Published: Wednesday | March 14, 2012 Comments 0 
 Charlyn Fargo, Contributor 
 OK, so your favourite fast-food restaurant now posts the calorie count of your favourite sandwich. That&apos;s a good thing. However, a new study finds that nutritional information can be confusing to diners if they don&apos;t read the fine print when making healthy meal choices. 

In the study, the scientists examined the calorie listings for 200 food items on menu boards from 12 restaurant chains in the New York City neighbourhood of Harlem. Too often, calorie counts were listed for combo meals or meals intended to serve multiple people or had wide ranges in what the calorie count might be.

For example, a bucket of chicken was listed as having 3,240 to 12,360 calories, but the menu board did not provide enough information for consumers to determine the number of pieces of chicken in a serving size. A listing for a sandwich combo meal said it ranged from 500 to 2,080 calories. However, no information was provided on how to order within the lower range of this menu item.

Under federal law, restaurants with 20 or more locations must provide calorie data and additional nutritional information for menu items and self-serve foods. Although the calorie information complied with US labelling rules, consumers may have a tough time making sense of much of it, the study found.

&quot;Menu postings for individual servings are easily understood, but complex math skills are needed to interpret meals designed to serve more than one person,&quot; wrote study author Elizabeth Gross Cohn, an assistant professor at the Columbia University School of Nursing, and colleagues. &quot;In some items, calories doubled depending on flavour, and the calorie posting did not give enough information to make healthier selections.&quot;

 &apos;Math literacy&apos; 

Researchers suggested that calorie listings should do more than merely comply; they should also take into account what level of &apos;math literacy&apos; is needed to make use of the information. In a revised system, a breakfast sandwich, for example, would be listed as &apos;Egg with ham/bacon/sausage: 350/550/750&apos;, so consumers could know exactly how many calories various options would add.

&quot;In low-income communities with a high density of chain restaurants and where educational attainment of consumers may be low, simplifying calorie postings and minimising the math required to calculate calories would increase menu-board utility,&quot; the researchers wrote.

Information courtesy of the Journal of Urban Health and Columbia University Medical Center.

 Energy slump and weight loss 

 Q: I&apos;m trying to lose weight, but each afternoon around 4 p.m., my energy hits a slump and I end up eating junk food. How will I ever lose weight? 

 A: It sounds like you&apos;re running out of fuel. Eating enough and choosing the right foods are two keys to maintaining energy while you&apos;re trying to lose weight. If your lunch is too light because you&apos;re either skipping it or trying too hard to cut back, it won&apos;t provide enough energy to get you through the afternoon.

Many people find that getting about a quarter to a third of total daily calorie needs at lunch works well. Calorie needs vary, but as an example, someone keeping calories to 1,600 a day for weight loss might aim for 400 to 500 calories at lunch (depending on how much snacking they prefer to do and how they spread out meal times). That&apos;s why a diet frozen meal, plain cup of soup, or energy bar usually won&apos;t suffice.

 Information courtesy the American Institute for Cancer Research. 

Charlyn Fargo is a registered dietitian at Creators Syndicate writers and cartoonists, at website at www.creators.com.


 Share | 
 
 The comments on this page do not necessarily reflect the views of The Gleaner.
The Gleaner reserves the right not to publish comments that may be deemed libelous, derogatory or indecent. 
 Please keep comments short and precise. A maximum of 8 sentences should be the target. 
 Longer responses/comments should be sent to &quot;Letters of the Editor&quot; using the feedback form provided. View the discussion thread. blog comments powered by Disqus 
 More Health Print this Page E-mail the Editor 
 smaller | larger 
Ads by Google
 
More Stories

 Strength training is number one for 2012 Combining drugs, alcohol Spinning your way to fitness Health trends 
 
 In The Blogs 
 
 Latest 
 

 
 
 The Gleaner Your Way Mobile: Get the Gleaner on your mobile RSS Feeds: Get content updates daily Newsletter: Get Headline News 
 
 The Gleaner Archives Digital Archives: Gleaner online editions 2006-2012 Print Archives: Print Editions 1834 - Present Library: Research&amp;Assistance 
 
 
 Gleaner Company Websites Jamaica Gleaner The Star Go Jamaica Hospitality Jamaica Gleaner Extra (NA) Youthlink Voice UK 

 Gleaner Company Websites Business Directory Gleaner Classifieds Restaurant Week Discover Jamaica Go Jamaica hosting Go Local Sports Jamaica 

 Gleaner Links RSS Feed About Us Contact Us Privacy Policy Suggestion Subscription Terms and Conditions 
 Copyright©2012 Gleaner Company Ltd. All Rights Reserved. A Gleaner Company Website. Designed by GoJamaica.
	</body>
</document>
