<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007863" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2019104/McDonalds-includes-free-fruit-Happy-Meal-health-campaign-pressure.html?ITO=1490" time="2012-07-13-00:49" support="1" score="0.0008692940812029687" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s includes free fruit with every Happy Meal after health ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s includes free fruit with every Happy Meal after health campaign pressure  | Mail Online">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="59"/>
	<description>... bringing their children to a fast food restaurant. ... healthy options in its meals so it was ‘automatic’ that children would eat them. ... of the food ended up in the trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Home     News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 News Home Arts Headlines Pictures Most read News Board 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 12AM  10°C 3AM 11°C 5-Day Forecast 
Free fruit with every Happy Meal: McDonald&apos;s bows to pressure from health campaigners
 
By Daniel Bates 
 UPDATED: 11:59 GMT, 22 September 2011 

 
 Comments ( 97 ) Share 
 
 
 

 With its combination of fast food and a free toy, the formula has proved irresistible to children for more than 30 years. 


 But McDonald’s has bowed to pressure from health campaigners and is revamping its Happy Meals. 


 From April next year, all 14,000 of its U.S. outlets will provide fruit or vegetables with every child’s meal. 
 
Happier meal: Apple slices will now be included alongside burgers, chicken nuggets, fizzy drinks, and a small helping of chips
 
 Portions of fries will also be reduced in an attempt to make parents feel less guilty about bringing their children to a fast food restaurant.   
More...

 SARAH IVENS: Does breastfeeding really burn 500 calories per day? 
 

 And if the changes are considered a success, they are likely to be replicated in the UK. 

 
Revamped: Portions of fries also shrink
 
 McDonald’s said it had tried offering a 
portion of fruit or vegetables as a replacement for fries, but customers
did not like it.
 

 Instead, apple slices will now be 
included alongside burgers, chicken nuggets, fizzy drinks, a small 
helping of chips–and free toys. 

 Other healthy options will include carrots, raisins, pineapple slices or mandarin oranges, depending on the time of year and location. 


 McDonald’s claims the changes will lead to a 20 per cent decrease in the meal’s calories, a 15 per cent decrease in sodium and a 20 per cent reduction in saturated fat .

 But that still leaves Happy Meals among the unhealthiest options for children. 

 A study by Yale University has found that they contain up to 700 calories and 755mg of sodium per meal. 

 
McDonald&apos;s President: Jan Fields said it was a &apos;great time&apos; for the company to introduce the changes
 
 For a typical five-year-old who does little exercise, that equates to more than half of the 1,200 calories they need each day. 
 

 McDonald’s has long been the largest and
most profitable fast food chain in the world but has been repeatedly 
criticised by health campaigners. 

 Earlier this year, 550 U.S. health professionals called on the company to stop marketing targeted at children and retire its clown mascot Ronald McDonald. 


 Company president Jan Fields said McDonald’s was including healthy options in its meals so it was‘automatic’that children would eat them. 


 A spokesman for McDonald’s in the UK said:‘Looking ahead we will learn from the moves made by our business in the U.S. and continue to listen to our own customers to inform any future changes that we may make.’ 

 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 4 Next 
 
 Police hunt dealer who sold Tetra Pak wife Eva Rausing the... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Two hotel workers found NOT GUILTY of murdering a honeymoon... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... What a difference a trim makes! Neighbours breathe sigh of... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it... &apos;Mini Monet&apos;: Nine-year-old artist set to become a... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 97 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
Do kids even finish all the food in these meals? Mine were always so preoccupied with the toy that a great deal of the food ended up in the trash bin.

- Betsy, Sioux City, IA USA, 28/7/2011 07:30
 Click to rate     Rating   2 
 Report abuse 
 
Anyone who eats at McDonalds often enough for it to matter for their health, is hardly likely to eat a piece of fruit. Not that the fruit is necessarily likely to be of much nutritional value anyway, it will no doubt be prcoessed in such a way as to reduce it to a bit of fructose and some fiber.

- Steve, Perth, Western Australia, 28/7/2011 06:17
 Click to rate     Rating   3 
 Report abuse 
 
Too little, too late. Ban the company from the UK. Until the UK government bans this odious outfit we risk bankrupting the NHS through obesity treatments alone.
- Karen, Littlehampton, 27/7/2011 7:24&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;Riiiight - because if everyone went back to traditional British fare like fish and chips, curry, shepard&apos;s pie and full English breakfasts they&apos;d be thin in no time. No one is forced to eat at McDonalds - you all have free will. You can sip seaweed shakes with Gwyneth Paltrow and Madonna instead of stuffing your face with big macs. I don&apos;t eat at McDonald&apos;s often, but when I do I like to get a happy meal because it&apos;s the right size for me. If I want to eat an apple, I&apos;ll go to a farmer&apos;s market - when I eat at McDonald&apos;s I want french fries.

- Anon, Anon, 28/7/2011 01:41
 Click to rate     Rating   6 
 Report abuse 
 
Free fruit with every Happy Meal: - Sure, probably served up as a deep fried fritter !

- Things&apos;aint what they used to be, Birmingham, 27/7/2011 16:00
 Click to rate     Rating   2 
 Report abuse 
 
Noticeably the AFFECTED are out and about pressing red buttons,or,is it the McDonalds&apos;staff in denial ??

- Greg, W.Yorkshire, 27/7/2011 15:56
 Click to rate     Rating   4 
 Report abuse 
 
All that will happen is they will take out the fruit from the Happy Meal and dump it. McDonalds isn&apos;t that bad if you only eat it once in a while - it&apos;s the people who buy it 4 - 5 times a week are the ones at risk. Maybe they government should reintroduce domestic science or home tech as it used to be called and teach children how to cook themselves healthy food.

- julie, essex, 27/7/2011 15:55
 Click to rate     Rating   7 
 Report abuse 
 
Too little, too late. Ban the company from the UK. Until the UK government bans this odious outfit we risk bankrupting the NHS through obesity treatments alone.

- Karen, Littlehampton, 27/7/2011 13:24
 Click to rate     Rating   14 
 Report abuse 
 
Companies trading overseas should have to maintain the same standards they maintain in their home country and if foreign standards are more stringent, those standards should be met at home. The practice where companies can for example sell salt-laden goods abroad which they couldn&apos;t sell at home is wrong and we all know it. The same applies to advertising standards - allowing cigarette companies for example to advertise in say Indonesia in a way that would be prohibited in the US is outrageous. Those companies employing double standards are clearly just exploiting loopholes in local law for profit and they should be named and shamed.

- Tracey, Greenwich, London, 27/7/2011 12:20
 Click to rate     Rating   1 
 Report abuse 
 
I eat a quarterpounder with cheese about once every two months. I don&apos;t eat the chips because I fine them too fatty. I bring the burger home and eat it with Microchips. Other than that my diet is balanced and mostly vegetarian. I resent anyone telling me what to eat.

- Rusty, Surrey, 27/7/2011 11:59
 Click to rate     Rating   18 
 Report abuse 
 
Disappointed McD is bowing down to pressure from do-gooders.
Everyone knows what they are getting when they order a happy meal, fruit is already available from McD so why make a change. Its just to appease vocal meddling minority of health nazis.
This makes me so angry.

- James, West midlands, 27/7/2011 11:37
 Click to rate     Rating   9 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using M&amp;S;virtual technology Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Kim and Kanye as you&apos;ve never seen them before! Couple pile on the pounds in frumpy portrait... with the help of a little trickery &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; Playful by night: Kelly Brook nearly pops out of her dress as she dances at dinner Thom&apos;s eyes almost popped out too at restaurant in Italy Divorce leaves Tom feeling flushed: Cruise visits loos THREE times in 20 minutes on Oblivion set Filming in Iceland &apos;Still shocked and saddened&apos;: Tom Cruise plans to see Suri &apos;very soon&apos; as he struggles to get to grip with being dumped by Katie Holmes Former Scientology chief claims church &apos;brainwashed Tom Cruise&apos;s children and turned them against Nicole Kidman&apos; Marty Rathbun left in &apos;04 Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Doppelgangers! Joey Essex appears to be taking after Tom Cruise&apos;s style Uncannily similar jacket and shades to Top Gun star Lifting the summer spirit: Miranda Kerr sizzles as she debuts latest Victoria&apos;s Secret Cotton Lingerie range in sensual video No nudity, no sex, just cuddles: How one woman is making a living from snuggling - but for 38 an hour, would you pay to hug a stranger? Why This Morning&apos;s penis enlargement feature brought a tear to my eyes (for all the right reasons) PETER LLOYD found him brave Halle Berry steps out with shorter hair after chopping her curly locks Actress has had long curly tresses for several months The holiday that just keeps rolling on: George Clooney and Stacy Keibler continue Italian sojourn with scenic scooter ride Loving &apos;la dolce vita&apos; &apos;We know God&apos;s in control&apos;: Family of Usher&apos;s stepson ask for prayers as they hold vigil after tragic jet ski accident &apos;From far away it&apos;s okay&apos;: Kim Kardashian gives Harper&apos;s Bazaar editor makeover with her bronzer ... but forgets she&apos;s fair-skinned Always ready for her close-up! Celebrity chef Cat Cora looks picture perfect in mug shot for DUI arrest 44-year-old looking sleek It&apos;s Only Rock &apos;n Roll (But They Like It): Rolling Stones reunite for 50th anniversary at photo exhibition launch as they hint at tour comeback Another holiday, ladies? Tamara and Petra Ecclestone play tourists in their mother&apos;s native Croatia Family are on luxury boat &apos;I was mental patient level of crying!&apos; Anne Hathaway reveals trauma of cutting hair - as she learns to soften her crop in floral dress FINALLY acting like a couple! Giggly Kristen Stewart and Robert Pattinson behave like the only two in the room at Comic Con First look: Rihanna teams up with Nicola Roberts and Henry Holland in new fashion series Styled To Rock Singer is in short trailer I quit! Steven Tyler confirms departure from American Idol after two seasons Says he will now focus on music Her bundle of joy! Alyson Hannigan cradles new daughter Keeva Jane on an outing with husband Alexis Denisof They were spotted in LA &apos;We&apos;re being unfairly accused&apos;: Teen Vogue dismisses 14-year-old girls during meeting after anti-Photoshop protest Andrej Pejic, the TV star? Androgynous model gets own reality show as his mum joins him in New York to commence filming Whittle-d down: Ricky becomes a one woman man again as he holds hands with new girlfriend while baring his chest (of course!) Year since Carley Stenson split That&apos;s no demure maxi! Miranda Kerr sexes up her floor-length dress with a plunging neckline and hip-high slit Two maxi dresses in row The devil wears gym gear: Emily Blunt looks ready for the Olympics as she works up a sweat during gruelling work out session Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! Katy Perry in a spin as insurers try to ban her from wearing trademark rotating bra Experts are concerned about the resulting strain on her neck Paralympian rower bares all for ESPN&apos;s Body Issue and reveals &apos;for me, eating is one of the hardest things&apos; Inspiring Oksana Masters Mother in heart-breaking plea for return of son, three, &apos;missing&apos; in Corfu with Greek father amid tug-of-love custody battle Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Friends again: Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox enjoy reunite on night out after rift rumours They hadn&apos;t been seen together for months The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics It&apos;s Posh-er and hips! Made In Chelsea&apos;s Hugo Taylor and Natalie Joel sport matching outfits... but hers is cut a little lower Robert Blake launches into bizarre tirade at Piers Morgan in first interview since being sensationally acquitted of wife&apos;s murder Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; All by myself: Pregnant Camila Alves does some solo sightseeing in Berlin while her husband Matthew McConaughey promotes his new film She&apos;s learned her lesson! Lydia Bright teams up with Zoe Hardman to encourage the public to stay safe in the sun Been burnt before Getting down and dirty! British women&apos;s football team enjoy muddy bonding session as they prepare to open the Olympic Games Soldiering on: Bikini girl Rihanna lights up a suspicious roll-up cigarette as she unwinds in Barbados after family drama Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Curse of the Vera Wang wedding gown? How eight celebrities who married wearing her designs have ended up divorced After her own divorce Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Fleetwood Mac reuniting for tour next year, reveals Stevie Nicks Play their first shows since 2009, Stevie confirmed Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites What were you inking! The embarrassing matching tattoos that brand couples for life They take saying &apos;I love you&apos;, to a whole new level It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? 
 
CREDIT CARDS: OUR TOP PICKS

   Best balance transfer credit card rates   Best credit cards for cashback and rewards   Best credit cards for overseas use   Best credit cards for spending
	</body>
</document>
