<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007605" url="http://www.e-propertylinks.com/search_listings.php?sort=&amp;showNum=500&amp;btnSubmit=Go&amp;pg=8" time="2012-07-13-00:34" support="4" score="0.007431141495704222" bingtitle="Search Listings" webtitle="Search Listings">
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>ZONED HD RESIDENTIAL BUT SELLER APPLIED FOR A CHANGE ... it is just across the road from the Calaveras County ... Sit Down Diner, Fast Food Restaurant, Motel (60 Units) with ...</description>
	<body>
		Email Password 
 
 Forgot Password? | 
 
 
 Home | Search Listings 

 Commercial Commercial Wants Residential Residential Wants Business Opportunities Funds Seeking Projects Projects Seeking Funds 
 | Post Listings | Find an Agent | Find a Service Provider | Resources 

 About Us Contact Us Key Interest Rates Resources and Affiliates Advertise With Us 
 | About Us 
 
 
 Property Types 
 Select the property type(s) that most closely match your search. 
 Acreage/Farm/Agricultural Automotive Development Land Gas Stations / C-stores Hospitality Industrial Medical Mixed Use Mobile Home Parks Multifamily Office Other/General Commerical Restaurant/Bar Retail Senior Housing Tenants in Common Opportunities  WANTs 
 Cancel Location 

 
 Country:   -Select- United States ---------------------------------- All International ---------------------------------- Afghanistan Aland Islands Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antarctica Antigua&amp;Barbuda Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia&amp;Herzegovina Botswana Bouvet Island Brazil British Indian Ocean Territory Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Rep Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos (Keeling) Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Costa Rica C?te d&apos;Ivoire Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Dem Rep of Congo (Zaire) Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Falkland Islands (Malvinas) Faeroe Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia/Tahiti French Southern Territories Gabon Gambia Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Guadeloupe Guam Guatemala Guernsey Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Heard Island&amp;McDonald Islands Holy See (Vatican City State) Honduras Hong Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Isle of Man Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jersey Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Korea, Democratic Republic of Korea, Republic of Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libya Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Palestinian Territory Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Poland Portugal Puerto Rico Qatar Reunion Is. Romania Russia Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts&amp;Nevis Saint Lucia Saint Pierre&amp;Miquelon Saint Vincent&amp;Grenadines Samoa (Amer.) Samoa (Western) San Marino Sao Tome&amp;Principe Saudi Arabia Senegal Serbia&amp;Montenegro Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands South Africa South Georgia&amp;S. Sandwich Islands Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Svalbard&amp;Jan Mayen Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syria Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Timor-Leste Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad&amp;Tobago Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks&amp;Caicos Islands Tuvalu Uganda Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States United States Minor Outlying Islands Uruguay Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Vietnam Virgin Islands, British Virgin Islands, US Wallis&amp;Futuna Isle Western Sahara Yemen Zambia Zimbabwe   State: County: -Select Country First- -Select State First- City:   To search multiple cities, separate cities by comma. Or Search By: Postal Code: To search multiple zipcodes, separate cities by comma. 
 
 Property Criteria 

 
 Both For Sale For Lease

 Price Range: to 

 Building Size (Square Feet): From to 

 Lot Size (acres): From to 

 
 
 Display only Auctions:     Cap Rate (%): From to 

 Year Built: From to 

 Keywords: 
 Please seperate keywords with a comma. 
 
 
 
 

 
 Total Listings: 8497           Page 8 of 17  Sort: -Sort- City Date Posted Price (Low to High) Price (High to Low) State Show: 20 50 100 250 500 
 

 4.49 Acres of commercial property in Show Low , Arizona Commercial
Development Land
 Located between Sleep Inn, and an office complex. Could be split 2 1/2 acres in the back for townhouses, or offices and the front 2.0 is just screaming for a restaurant. Next to high end residential developments, IE: Sierra Pines and Torreon. At the appro... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arizona 
 Marce Wildman 
 
 60 acres in Peoria, AZ Commercial
Development Land
 60 acres of land in Peoria, AZ in the entitlement process for 179 lots of approx 60’x120’. The master plan development is called Vistancia. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arizona 
 Steven N Vale 
 
 Hot Springs Corner Commercial
Development Land
 Nine acres on very busy corner of Highway 70W and Pittman Rd. in Hot Springs. Heavy traffic area ideal for strip center, apartments (Lake Hamilton School District), storage buildings, doctors offices, fast food etc. One brick 4 bedroom, 2 bath home, plus ... 
 $630,000 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Wayne Thomason 
 
 CORNER COMMERCIAL LOT Commercial
Development Land
 EXCELLENT LOCATION, GENTRY, AR (WEST OF BENTONVILLE, AR * HOME OF WAL-MART GENERAL OFFICES) ZONED C-2, NEXT TO US POST OFFICE AND ACROSS THE STREET FROM A CONVENIENCE STORE, LOOKING FOR LAND TO BUILD A BANK, LAUNDROMAT, STRIP CENTER, WAL-GREENS? GREAT PRI... 
 $110,000 
 For Sale 
Gentry, Arkansas 
 Kim Rutledge Griffin Company Realtors 
 
 COMMERCIAL LOTS Commercial
Development Land
 EXCELLENT NORTH SPRINGDALE, ARKANSAS LOCATION, CLOSE TO NEW 5 LANE WAGON WHEEL ROAD, 2006 TRAFFIC COUT 27,900 VEHICLES PER DAY, ACROSS THOMPSON STREET FROM SCHMIEDING CENTER, NEXT TO NEW C-STORE, ZONED C-5. 5 LOTS AVAILABLE, PRICES FROM $173,400 - 471,500... 
 $173,400 
 For Sale 
Springdale, Arkansas 
 Kim Rutledge Griffin Company Realtors 
 
 600 Acres Independence County Commercial
Development Land
 FANTASTIC RETREAT FOR ALL KINDS OF OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES. FROM DEER HUNTING TO HIKING AND CAMPING. PROPERTY HAS THE YEAR ROUND CURIA CREEK THAT RUNS THROUGH IT WITH BLUFFS AND LOTS OF LIMESTONE ROCKS. THIS IS 600 AC MORE OR LESS OF GETTING BACK TO NATURE. of... 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Larry Brinkley 
 
 Prime Land Commercial
Development Land
 44+ Acres Land ready for high end retail/office/mixed use development. West of this land is a newly developed 300+ Acres 18 Hole Golf Course development and on the North is multi-million Dollar City Center development starting end of 2007. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Jerry Bajaj 
 
 18.47 acres in booming Rogers, Arkansas Commercial
Development Land
 I have six commercial lots totaling 18.47 acres in booming Rogers, Arkansas for sale. Lots range in size from 1.4 to 5.55 acres. Zoning of C-2, C-3, and R-O. Planned for 680,000 sq. ft. of office, hotel, condo, and retail uses. Lots appraised at $16 per f... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Paul E. Myer 
 
 1.59 acres at Dodson Rd Rogers, AR. $692,604 Commercial
Development Land
 Myers Ranch, mixed use development with infrastructure included. ? block from Walton Blvd&amp;J St and ? mile from I-540. Will Subdivide. This project has covenants and restrictions. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Jerry Horton 
 
 1.4 acres at Dodson Rd Rogers, AR. $731,808 Commercial
Development Land
 Myers Ranch, mixed use development with infrastructure included. Zoned C-2. ? block from Walton Blvd&amp;J St and ? mile from I-540. Will Subdivide. This project has covenants and restrictions. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Jerry Horton 
 
 6 acres in one of the fastest growing areas Commercial
Development Land
 In the nation, North West Arkansas home of Wal-Mart. currently zoned AG but perfect for commercial development. Corner of Hwy 412 and 303. http://findhomes.nwa.mlxchange.com/?r=1870309507 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Arkansas 
 Steve Glakeler 
 
 2/3 Acre Commerial (GC) Land, Corner lot, +Traffic Commercial
Development Land
 3 APNS INCLUDING 419-071-009&amp;419-060-021. CORNER PROPERTY! EXCELLENT VISIBILITY! HOUSES ALL BEHIND, COMMERCIAL MAIN Rd IN FRONT. REDEVELOPMENT AREA! GUTTER,ROAD&amp;CURB COMPLETE. UNLIMITED POTENTIAL. ZONED C2. PERFECT FOR RESTAURANT,FAST FOOD,GAS... 
 $399,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 Small lot in Loma Linda Commercial
Development Land
 GROWING AREA OF LOMA LINDA, CLOSE TO BARTON ROAD (VISIBLE FROM BARTON RD) COMMERCIAL PROPERTY NEXT TO NEW LLBN OFFICE. ZONED IN THE CITY OF LOMA LINDA. CREDIT UNION IS BEING BUILT NEXT DOOR!GREAT OPPORTUNITY! BUYER&amp;/OR BUYER&apos;S AGENT TO VERIFY ALL INF... 
 $79,000 
 For Sale 
LOMA LINDA, California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 1 Acre-IL LAND-FLAT-w/ 2200 sqft home Commercial
Development Land
 LIGHT INDUSTRIAL COMMERCIAL LAND! HUGE LOT-1.03 ACRES! LEASE, LEASE TO OWN OR SALE!CLOSE TO THE 10 FRWY, WATERMAN AND REDLANDS BLVD. COMMERCIAL or RESIDENTIAL USE. EASY ACCESS, NON-THROUGH STREET, LLU CAN BE SEEN FROM BACKYARD. LEVEL, FENCED LOT, NEW APPL... 
 $349,000 
 For Sale 
SAN BERNARDINO, California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 80 acres-MIXED USE-ON HWY 62 Commercial
Development Land
 PRIME LOCATION! ZONED HD RESIDENTIAL BUT SELLER APPLIED FOR A CHANGE OF ZONE- POSSIBLY MAKING IT MIXED USE. 80 ACRES RIGHT ON THE 62 (29 PALMS HWY)-IN A FAST DEVELOPING AREA. Submitted rezone for Mixed use. (POSSIBLE COMMERCIAL AND RESIDENTIAL) TESTS COMP... 
 $699,000 
 For Sale 
JOSHUA TREE, California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 39,000 sqft land-RETAIL-EXISTING SHOPPING CENTER Commercial
Retail
 Great location with unlimited commercial potential! Located in existing Shopping center Anchored by Ralph&apos;s food store. Surrounded by retail this is a prime commercial location for retail, fast food, strip center, etc. Zoned in the City of Moreno Valley w... 
 $375,000 
 For Sale 
MORENO VALLEY, California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 Commercial/Residential Subdivision Development Commercial
Development Land
 Beautiful development opportunity with a mix of commercial,residential, multi-family use within the growth development area adjacent to and east of St. Ignatius, MT. This land holds the key to further development to the east through town. Unobstructed vie... 
 $750,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Douglas Martin 
 
 5002 Warner Ave, Huntington Beach Commercial
Development Land
 Subject property is a 8,924 SF square shape land located on a busy corner of Warner Ave and Bolsa Chica Rd. It is zoned commercial and can be used for service station, retail store, etc. It is situated just 1 block west of busy Warner Plaza, which include... 
 $950,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Michael Pourmirza 
 
 1450 W. Artesia Blvd. Commercial
Development Land
 362 feet of Artesia Blvd. frontage. Part of the new Artesia Blvd. Specific Plan. Traffic counts Artesia Blvd. 47,600 ADT. Normandie Blvd. 21,300 ADT. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Peter Steigleder 
 
 Commercial Development Lot on Ski Run Blvd Commercial
Development Land
 Prime commercial development lot in Ski Run Village. Plans nearing approval for a 4,004 sq/ft multi-use building w/ elevator, 16 parking spaces, 5,763 sq/ft of verified coverage, and CFA in place. Two existing homes on the lot can be removed and banked as... 
 $785,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Brian Des Rochers 
 
 OCEAN FRONT Visitor-Serving Development Project Commercial
Development Land
 CA Hwy 1 is the main tourist route between San Francisco and the Monterey / Pebble Beach area. For a stretch of nearly 50 miles of this scenic highway, this is the ONLY COMMERCIAL PROPERTY west of the highway. It has direct Hwy 1 access, and direct beach ... 
 $6,900,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 David Worden 
 
 Stockton Center Commercial
Development Land
 Three contiguous lots totaling 11+/- Acres on Stockton Boulevard near Fruitridge in Sacramento. All cash offer for a fast sale $5,650,000 Each lot could be sold individually - 1.87 Ac $1,150,000; 1.75 Ac $1,070,000; 7.25 Ac $4,430,000 Commerical zoned pro... 
 $6,650,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Dennis Griffin The Griffin Company 
 
 12+ Acres with Approved Map Commercial
Development Land
 There are over 12 acres in three legal parcels, a .55 acre piece, a 7.62 acre piece and a 4.12 acre piece. There are currently 2 undeveloped encroachments onto the highway. There are 2 existing wells that can be used for landscaping. There is an older hom... 
 $4,499,500 
 For Sale 
California 
 John Reed 
 
 4601 W. Slauson Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90043 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Commercial land for sale or lease. Ideal for auto sales, car rentals, retail, church, school or contractor&apos;s yard. Major retailers in area include CVS, Home Depot and McDonalds. Owner will consider long term ground lease. Over 17... 
 $12 
 For Sale 
California 
 Anthony Behar Major Properties 
 
 524 Washington Bl., Montebello, CA 90640 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Commercial paved land for sale. Corner exposure with great visibility. Currently includes 2 small buildings totaling 807 sq.ft. Possible development site. Great potential! Many possible uses. Zoned MN C2. Location Description: Northe... 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Rene Mexia 
 
 1281 S. Eastman Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90023 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Industrial zoned land for sale. Multi-use property with great potential. Fenced. Zoned LC M1. Includes 288 sq.ft. office building used as a residence. Property delivered vacant. Location Description: Northwest corner of Union Pacific... 
 $343,440 
 For Sale 
California 
 James Bond 
 
 1604 W. 11th St., Los Angeles, CA 90015 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Fenced vacant land. Potential development site. Zoned LA C1. Pico/Union area just west of Downtown Los Angeles. Location Description: Located just west of Union Ave. Walking distance to LA Live, Staples Center and Los Angeles Convent... 
 $625,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Ira Flusberg Major Properties 
 
 1111 S. Central Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90021 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Investor or developer opportunity. Includes 7,404 sq.ft. warehouse. Earn income from warehouse while waiting to develop property. Major redevelopment happening in immediate area. Fantastic future potential! Corner property with high ... 
 $7,830,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Ira Flusberg Major Properties 
 
 1820 S. Flower St., Los Angeles, CA 90015 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Paved and fenced parking lot for sale. Zoned M2. Great for owner/user or investor. Possible development site. Location Description: Downtown Los Angeles. Half block north of Washington Bl. corridor. Easy access to 10&amp;110 freeways. ... 
 $560,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Ira Flusberg Major Properties 
 
 209 W. 11th St., Los Angeles, CA 90015 Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: Prime Downtown Los Angeles Development Site. 0.11 acres of paved land with 884 sq.ft. building. Zoned R5. Fantastic loft location -- heavy redevelopment in immediate area. Location Description: NW corner of 11th&amp;Hill Streets. Walki... 
 $1,750,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Ira Flusberg Major Properties 
 
 10452 Macarthur Blvd Commercial
Development Land
 2300 sq. ft. lot for mixed use development.Great opportunity for the right developer. Property is fenced with lockbox. Seller is motivated. We have an appraisal with and without entitlements done in&apos;07. 
 $1,400,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Kenneth/Rhona Harris 
 
 4.2 acre, zoned multi-family Commercial
Development Land
 4.2 acres, level, undeveloped (formerly a single family ranchette)...can accomodate 48-62 units. 
 $1,095,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Frank Damrell 
 
 Industrial Land Commercial
Development Land
 103 acres of of industrial land strategically located to meet quick distribution needs throughout Southern California, Western U.S. and International travel. 30 Mi from SCLA So. Cal Logistics Airport, 120 mi to Los Angeles. Property is ready to build with... 
 $3 
 For Sale 
California 
 Velma Hall 
 
 286 ac. for Resort/Commercial/Rural Homesites Commercial
Development Land
 The propety is conveniently located in the heart of the Mother Lode below the snow and above the fog. It has Hwy 49 frontage and it is just across the road from the Calaveras County Airport. In addition to Commercial/Planned development/Resort opportuniti... 
 $5,250,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Joseph Welch 
 
 64 Acre Historic Gold Mine/Rock Quarry w/pond Commercial
Development Land
 64 acres - The Historic Gleeson Diggins in the Sugar Pine Lake Recreation Area between Foresthill&amp;Colfax off of hwy 80. This property had a working gold mine and rock quarry years ago. There was a blacksmith shop there in the 1800&apos;s and a working go... 
 $199,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Susan Kelly 
 
 RARE DEVELOPMENT/INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITY Commercial
Development Land
 Asking Price: $9,395,000. Rare development/investment opportunity. Located in the most central spot of West Los Angeles. Site lies along future corridor of mass transit: Intersection of 10 FWY, Venice Boulevard, and the Exposition Boulevard Light Rail Lin... 
 $9,395,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Floyd Fouquette Fouquette Commercial Real Estate Services 
 
 74+ Acres Near Airport on Highway 10 Commercial
Development Land
 Great Investment Opportunity! This vacant land parcel is just 3 miles west of the Blythe Airport with frontage on Highway 10. Great opportunity to purchase land near Blythe which is staged for a great development potential! Blythe is strategically located... 
 $349,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Gina Lee Keller Williams Realty 
 
 Stunning Hercules Condo Commercial
Development Land
 Beautifully stunning and best price in Bravo complex. This two bedroom, two bathroom unit backs up to open space - peaceful and quiet setting. Inside find new carpet and freshly painted interior. Master bedroom features oversized tub to soak away the stre... 
 $315,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Michael Hughey 
 
 Gateway to Playa Vista Commercial
Development Land
 Corner Property surrounded by streets and alley. Excellent Freeway Visibility. Adjacent to Playa Vista Mixed Use Project by Rick Caruso, the Developer for The Grove Mall in Los Angeles. Across from the LA Clippers Training Center. M2 Zoning (Light Industr... 
 $5,950,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 W. Antonio Hachem 
 
 Premium Development Opportunity In Swanzey, NH. Commercial
Development Land
 LAND AVAILABLE Development Opportunity in Swanzey, NH. One of the most visible tracts of land in a newly developed area. Highly visible multi-use land available for $5.53per sq. ft. or $2,600,000 for the entire parcel. 10.79+/- acres zoned commercial-indu... 
 $2,600,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Greg Johnson H.G. Johnson Real Estate 
 
 NANDINA ST.-VACANT LAND Commercial
Development Land
 5 ACRES LOCATED IN THE HOTTEST DISTRIBUTION AREA OF THE INLAND EMPIRE. CLOSE TO MARCH ARB/DHL BASE, AND THE 215 FREEWAY. DISTRIBUTION CENTERS ALREADY INCLUDE LOWES, ROSS, WALGREENS, MORE. ADJACENT 5 ACRES ALSO AVAILABLE. SELLERS MOTIVATED! 
 $2,100,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 JOHN SCHWAB 
 
 Proposed Travel Center Commercial
Development Land
 I have a mixed use, general commercial shopping and service project. The proposed uses for the center are an Auto Fueling Facility, Mini-Mart and an Auto/Truck related retail store. Sit Down Diner, Fast Food Restaurant, Motel (60 Units) with General Retai... 
 $1,000,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Yvette Lotz 
 
 Prime Commercial Land Commercial
Development Land
 Private, 2.69 acre commercail site located in prime Monterey Peninsula location. Zoned C-O-D-2, ideal for office, professional or religious assembly development space. Active use permit with City of Monterey. 
 $895,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Craig Boswell 
 
 Ramsey St, Banning 92220 Commercial
Development Land
 Features: Lot 20-39,999 Sqft, Redevelopment Area, Sewer, Trees Description: 3 Apns Including 419-071-009/419-060-021. Corner Property! Excellent Visability! Houses Behind, Fwy&amp;Main Rd In Front. Unlimited Potential. Gutter Curb Done.Redevel Area. Gre... 
 $689,000 
 For Sale 
California 
 Debbie Hanna REMAX 
 
 Prime Land For Investment!! Commercial
Development Land
 Over 37 acres of flat vacant land less than 2 miles away from highway 14. This corner property fronts both Avenue A and 35th Street. Avenue A is a wide paved street that has homes on the street. This is a great area with the highway nearby and homes in th... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Gina Lee Keller Williams Realty 
 
 5.78 Acres - $2,990,900 Commercial
Development Land
 44 Home residential subdivision with final map. Interested parties must go view property in San Jacinto otherwise owner is not interested in talking with them. Located San Jacinto TG page = 811(a1) Tracrt # 31253 Apn # 434-110-024-(4.83acs) , 434-110-023-... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 
 
 40 Cypress Street, Vallejo CA Commercial
Development Land
 Stunning Cypress Street! Sale Price $189,900. Industrial area zoned IU, 14,985 SF Fenced lot, Great for equipment or Vehicle storage. You could build a shop here and still have storage space. This is on county land, not actually in the City of Vallejo. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Paul R. Winders 
 
 1545 Broadway Street, Vallejo, CA Commercial
Development Land
 Sale Price $749,900. High density area zoned residential. 38,333 SF Fenced lot, approved plans for 18 units. Soil report in and lot is ready to build. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Paul R. Winders 
 
 Vacant Land - Arcadia (ARCD) Commercial
Development Land
 (605) Arcadia 91008 Price: $5,200,000 Have: 5.3 Acres Vacant Residential Zoning Res Cross Streets: Whispering Pines&amp;Torrey Pines Builder Tract: Custom SqFt: 13.02 Acres TGNO 567E2 AP # 5771-001-007 Easements? N Fee? Y Zoned: ARRM; Residential-Vacant Lan... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Mario A. Navarrete, Jr., Realtor? 
 
 700 Broadway St., Vallejo, CA 94590 Commercial
Development Land
 Located at the corner of Broadway&amp;Nebraska. Great location for fast food or taco trucks, to feed lots of hungry students. Smog check business for sale for $149,900 or seller will move business. Sale Price $699,900 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Paul R. Winders 
 
 Land 0.42 Acres Malibu CA $3,000,000 Commercial
Development Land
 Rare Development Site in Malibu Frontage On High Traffic Pacific Coast Highway Many Retail Uses Possible Prime Location Near The Malibu Pier Land Assemblage Possibility With Adjacent Property 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Thomas McBride 
 
 Complete Development Project For Sale: $12,888,000 Commercial
Development Land
 IL VILLAGGI 306-310 First Ave., Arcadia, CA. 91007 The Construction to be Completed in December, 2006. This is the first Mixed Use development project approved by Arcadia. Total building size: 27,124 Sq. Ft. It provides 8 Residential Condos, 8 Retail Stor... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 George Liang GVA DAUM 
 
 13191 Crossroads Parkway N. Suite 175 City of Industry, CA. 91746 Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial Land at Excellent Location. Mixed use development plan in process. Total Building Size: 15,061 Sq. Ft. Approx. Commercial Portion: 9,853 Sq. Ft., plus 4 Senior Condo 4,764 Sq. Ft., 70 Parking. Land with Mixed use Plan for Sale 823 S. San Gabrie... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 George Liang GVA DAUM 
 
 Development Project - Historic Templeton, CA Commercial
Development Land
 Northern San Luis Obispo County, City of Templeton Just off Highway 101 btw. Atascadero&amp;Paso Robles Asking $4,300,000 5.5 acres of pristine, secluded land just off Main Street! Currently Zoned &quot;Commercial&quot; Rezone to Multi-Family Residential underway Ide... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Mike Barriere 
 
 For Sale Or Exchange: Approved Tentative Parcel Map Commercial
Development Land
 for 16 single family lots in the City of San Diego Property is near Qualcomm Stadium and San Diego State University, Asking price is $260,000/lot, or $4,160,000. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 Barry Collins 
 
 823 S. San Gabriel Blvd. San Gabriel, CA 91776 Commercial
Development Land
 $2,700,000 15,365 Sq. Ft. (Lot Size) Commercial land, submitting plan for mixed use development. Building Size: 15,061 Sq. Ft.: Commercial Area: 9,853 Sq. Ft., 4 Senior Condos: 4,764 Sq. Ft. Subterraneous 70 parking spaces. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
California 
 George Liang GVA DAUM 
 
 RIDGEVIEW LAND Commercial
Development Land
 The property represents the last phase for development in the new and very successful Ridgeview Marketplace Shopping Center. The Anchor, King Soopers Grocer (Kroger), is Colorado&apos;s Market leader and is the best anchor you can have for your shopping ce... 
 $1,995,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Michael Pourmirza 
 
 50 cents on the dollar Commercial
Development Land
 Appraised at $1,875,000. on current appraisal. 10 acres (+/-)We still owe the bank $900,000. and would rather sell for the debt rather than let bank have . we can still save our credit 970-225-4043 
 $900,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Rick Archibald 
 
 SLATE RIVER REAL ESTATE Commercial
Development Land
 374 ACRES 3 MILES FROM THE HEART OF DOWN TOWN MONTROSE COLORADRO. 
 $13,500,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 MELISSA WINNAMAN 
 
 741 PITKIN AVE Commercial
Development Land
 Great location,in downtown Grand Junction. Taps in and paid, ready to build. Call Rob Burnett 970-250-2929 or Mike Burkhard 970-640-4655 
 $35,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Rob Burnett 
 
 *Limited Only By Your Imagination* Commercial
Development Land
 *3350 Acres Plus Access To 1000 Acre Lake, 45 Minutes From Denver International Airport*Create Your Own Resort City* 
 $25,000,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Miles Lane 
 
 Montrose Gateway Mixed Used Development Commercial
Development Land
 Price has just been lowered to facilitate a sale on this commercial /residential 108 acres. Right on Highway 50, this piece is in the path of growth and will accomodate 40-60 acres for future retail and the rest in residential. Homebuildiers are making of... 
 $6,900,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Candace Seaton Grubb&amp;Ellis | Quantum Commercial Group 
 
 Denver Industrial Land in Path of Growth Commercial
Development Land
 320 Acre Parcel Annexed and Zoned (Northeast Plains District--a light industrial zoning) on 56th Ave (paved two lane) with approved plans to be the major six lane arterial from I-25 to Front Range Airport. Located just south of Denver International Airpor... 
 $2,880,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Max Walker 
 
 Lafayette - 1 Acre available for sale Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial site available with frontage along S. Public Road in Lafayette, Colorado. This prime site is suitable for office, retail, daycare, medical, veterinarian, commercial etc. Site offers great visibility and access from S. Boulder Road and S. Highwa... 
 $435,600 
 For Sale 
Lafayette, Colorado 
 Thomas Niewohner LandCorp 
 
 Colorado Springs, CO Commercial
Development Land
 6.4 acres for sale at $7.75/SF $2.16 Million. Will design build-to-suit. 2-story, 75,000-SF build-to-suit office/R&amp;D;building possible. Site is situated in an advanced technological, ideal business and employee environment. InterQuest is Colorado Springs&amp;... 
 $2,160,000 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Wayne P.E. 
 
 Historic 186-acre property Commercial
Development Land
 Nestled at the base of Colorado&apos;s tallest and longest mountain range, the Sangre de Cristo Mountains, this historic 186-acre property has operated as a guest ranch for over 100 years and is the ideal location for comfortable and spacious family living... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Richard Peterson 
 
 Lookout Mountain Ranch Commercial
Development Land
 Lookout Mountain Ranch features approximately 894 acres on Missouri Heights overlooking the entire Roaring Fork Valley with fabulous Sopris Mountain views. The ranch is divided into twenty-five 35-acre parcels plus one 20-acre parcel. Some utilities and w... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Billy Long 
 
 Dancing Bear Ranch Commercial
Development Land
 Nestled in the heart of the Rocky Mountains, this 503-acre property defines comfortable elegance. The stone, timber and wood accented home, replete with cathedral ceilings and generous windows, offers panoramic views from over 6,700 sq. Ft. Of heated livi... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Billy Long 
 
 Durango Colorado Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Wanted BUYER - Investors / Developers / Builders for 2,000 Acre Development Opportunity in Durango, Colorado! - This 2,000 acres are adjacent to the City of Durango, Colorado: I am partnered with another agent to find the perfect fit for this unique, once... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Michael Schmidt 
 
 Grand Junction/Palisade Colorado 640 Acres Commercial
Development Land
 5 minutes from Palisade Co the Peach and Wine region of the Western slope. Beautiful views of the Bookclifts 5 minutes from I-70. Very rare parcel so close to Palisade and Grand Junction Colorado $1,950,000.00 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Elizabeth Birmingham 
 
 Colorado 29,700+ Acres Commercial
Development Land
 Fee simple, Aggregate Mining / Development Property $125 Million Well over $2 Billion Dollar, wholesale value, of Limestone, gravel, and decorative rock on the property. This is a proven reserve based on engineers report Active Mining Permits to extract L... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Craig Ginter, CCIM, ALC, Broker Associate 
 
 Completed residential subdivision in Montrose Commercial
Development Land
 12 residential Lots $56,000 each. 10,000 SF to 12,500 SF lots. 1 Commercial Lot, 1/2 acre Residential lot price includes all utilities installed and paid for. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Chuck Trice 
 
 1 Acre Commercial zoned (B-2) Lot in Montrose. $169,000 Commercial
Development Land
 High traffic count, across the street from a new 180 lot residential subdivision. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Chuck Trice 
 
 Montrose Colorado 81401 Commercial
Development Land
 Completed residential subdivision 12 residential Lots $56,000 each 10,000 square ft to 12,500 square foot lots 1 Commercial Lot, 1/2 acre Residential lot price includes all utilities installed and paid for 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Chuck Trice 
 
 One acre commercial zoned (B-2) Lot in the City limits Commercial
Development Land
 $169,000 High traffic count, across the street from a new 180 lot residential subdivision 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Chuck Trice 
 
 For sale: 460ft. of road frontage consisting of 3.384 ac. Commercial
Development Land
 On Aspen/Maiden Hwy. /Hwy. 321 at the intersection of Elizabeth Av. in Lincolnton, NC. With traffic count of app. 14,000 cars per day. Zoned N B (Neighborhood Business), gas, elect. water, and sewer on the property. RE/MAX at the Lake-Commercial, 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 RE/MAX at the Lake-Commercial 
 
 10.77 acres +/- Watkins, Colorado Commercial
Development Land
 Location: Property is located 7 miles East of Aurora, CO on I-70 just East of Exit 295 along the South Frontage Road (Colfax Service Rd), directly adjacent to the Thunder Ranch Subdivision. Property is well located East of Aurora, CO, South of DIA and the... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Colorado 
 Richard Case 
 
 Muti-family vacant land- 2201 Knights Trail Road Commercial
Development Land
 29.89 acres of developable multi-family land. Plans for 240 town homes, club house, pool&amp;gym. Land cost per unit is $28,541.67. Requirements for storm detention&amp;wet land buffers are met. Architecture is in accordance with city of Venice Venetian Gatew... 
 $2,100,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Robert Novack 
 
 Commercial Land for Sale Commercial
Development Land
 Affordable Small Site on Busy SR 434
 Less than 1/8 of a mile from the major intersection of Hwy 17-92 on SR 434
 Major New Development at the intersection
 Ideal for Automotive Car Lot or small retail use
 Easy Access to Hwy 17-92, ... 
 $249,000 
 For Sale 
Winter Springs, Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 Automotive/Car Lot for Lease - Orlando, Florida Commercial
Automotive
 1,500 SF +/- of Office/Warehouse Space
 Recently Renovated
 Grade Level Warehouse with (2) 10&apos; X 10&apos; DOORS
 Parking for 20 Cars +/- Great for a Small Car Lot or Auto-Related Uses 
 Direct Access from both Directions o... 
 $3,000 
 For Lease 
Orlando, Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 Waterford Park Commercial
Development Land
 PRE-APPROVED DEVELOPMENT OPPORTUNITY; Zoned PD Approved for 290,000 SF Mixed-Use Development (150,000 SF Office/Retail) (140,000 SF Flex Space); Usable Land Area 29.48 Acres; 1300 +/- Frontage on Lake Underhill Rd and 1300 +/- Deep; $8,000,000 ($275,000/A... 
 $8,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 Commercial Land Development Commercial
Development Land
 Near SR 415, 427, Hwy 17-92, SR 46&amp;Toll Road 417. 
 $3,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 Mohawk Commercial Commercial
Development Land
 Fenced 1/2 of an acre in Sanford. Good outside storage site.
 Owner will consider a build to suit
 Privacy fence surrounding the property
 Cleared of all trees
 1,500 SF structure in place  
 $1,500 
 For Sale 
Sanford, Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 E. Colonial Land Commercial
Development Land
 26 acres on East Colonial with over 1700 FT of frontage in the direct path of development. Great Land Bank! 
 $5,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 9.89 Industrial Acres Commercial
Development Land
 Approximately 9.89 Industrial Acres
 Zoned Light Industrial (I-1)
 Frontage Maguire Road - 459&apos;, Kissimmee Avenue - 226&apos;
 Property backs up to two major roads: Kissimmee Avenue and Maguire Road with drive through access
 Over o... 
 $2,500,000 
 For Sale 
Ocoee, Florida 
 Vincent Wolle Results Real Estate Partners, LLC 
 
 Vacant Land Available Commercial
Development Land
 $275,000 per acre. Zoned heavy manufacturing. Sewer&amp;water close to property. 880 +/- frontage / 645 depth. Excellent signage&amp;curb exposure. Survey available. Possibility of railroad siding. Located in flood zone C (not in 100 yr flood zone). 
 $3,484,500 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 James Barnett 
 
 LAKEWOOD RANCH - 1.4 Acre PAD for Office or Retail in LAKEWOOD RANCH Commercial
Development Land
 Richland Plaza includes two pads (one just sold to Exxon-Mobil, the other FOR SALE) &amp;a 17,300 SF TBB strip center. It onnects to Regions Bank&amp;CVS on corner of SR 64&amp;Lakewood Ranch Blvd. It is pproved for 8,000 SF of office or r... 
 $1,100,000 
 For Sale 
Lakewood Ranch-Bradenton, Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 38+/- acres ( 5 commercial&amp;32.44 residential) Commercial
Development Land
 Front 5 acres approximately 650 feet on Highway 20 has recently been cleared Location Description: North side of Highway 20 Just west of the Interlachen Police station 26 miles East of Gainesville 11 miles West of Palatka 39 miles from Historic Saint Augu... 
 $499,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 David Ritchie 
 
 1.75 ACRE +/- in Palm Bay Commercial
Development Land
 1.75 acres +/- on Malabar and Emerson, one of the highest traffic areas in Palm Bay. currently there are 4 model homes 2 vacant lots and an older existing home. Keep the homes or tear them down, this is a unique opportunity to get one of the best corners ... 
 $1,950,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jack Gove 
 
 Are you tired of Paying the Landlord&apos;s Mortgage? Commercial
Development Land
 19 parcels for sale ranging from 1-3 acres for commercial, industrial, office and warehouse construction. No concurrency issues. Off SR 27/41 in Newberry Florida. 
 $184,500 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Joyce Dorval 
 
 Emerson Model Park Commercial
Development Land
 The property is zoned RC Restricted Commercial District and consists of 7 residential lots with single family homes on 5 of them. The property has been a model center for the last 15 years. It is located on the corner of Emerson and Malabar Rd. and is one... 
 $1,950,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jack Gove 
 
 15 Acres - PRIME LOCATION Commercial
Development Land
 Frontage of 181 +/- feet on Narcoossee Road
Widening of Narcoossee recently approved by City
Income producing cell tower at rear 
Easy access to SR 528 and to the airport
Nearby shopping Home Depot, Kohl&apos;s, Walgreens, CVS, Publix, Wal-Mart, Taco Bell,... 
 $2,995,000 
 For Sale 
Orlando, Florida 
 Al Clark Southeastern Realty 
 
 2.71 Ac. Retail/Commercial Site, Riverview Commercial
Development Land
 Property located at SEC US 301&amp;Bloomingdale Ridge Dr. in Riverview. It has 200&apos;of frontage along U.S. 301 and has excellent visibility. It is zoned PD-MU. The site is approved for 27,000 SF of BPO uses, including office, bank, child care or small d... 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Ron Sparks 
 
 .49 Ac. Site at MLK Jr. Blvd.&amp;Pine St., Seffner Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent site at signalized intersection of MLK Jr. Blvd. (SR 574) and Pine St. in Seffner. Good location for retail uses, such as coffee shop, fast food, liquor store, sports store, self-service car wash, general&amp;medical office, daycare, auto supply a... 
 $225,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 40,299 SF Corner Site in Ruskin Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent 40,299 SF retail and/or office site with 186&apos;of frontage on US 41 and 206&apos;on 7th St. SW in Ruskin. Zoned CG (Commercial General) and Land Use is OC (Office Commercial). All utilities are available. There are 11,709 existing/planned hou... 
 $499,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 Corner 2.04 Ac. Development Site, Tampa Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent 2.04 acre development site at a signalized intersection at the SEC of Temple Terrace Hwy.&amp;78th St. (9127 N. 78th St.) in Tampa. Zoned PDMU; approved for 44,600 SF of self-storage and 92 multifamily units. Other possibilities with zoning change... 
 $950,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 4.336 Acres MOL (2 Parcels) Commercial
Development Land
 Two sites (Lot 1 - 1.83 ac., Lot 2 - 2.50 ac.) in front of the Interstate Business Park on Kathleen Road in Lakeland. Lot 1 - $850,000; Lot 2 - $1,198,000. Zoned I-1, Industrial and Small Lot Commercial. Opportunity for retail, office, restaurant, persona... 
 $850,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 3.2 Acres MOL Corner Development Site Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent retail/office development located at the southeast corner of US 19&amp;Bourassa Blvd. in Weeki Wachee. Located in a high growth area, including Shoppes at Glen Lakes with a Publix Center under construction 1/2 mile south, Crystal Waters Subdivisio... 
 $1,350,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 29,035 SF MOL corner site on SR 54 Commercial
Development Land
 Corner site near signalized intersection at the entrance to Saddlebrook Resort. Excellent site for professional office uses, business and financial services. Retail uses if rezoned to C-1. 
 $650,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Chamblee 
 
 +/- 20 Acres at US Hwy 98 North, Lakeland, Florida Commercial
Development Land
 LOCATED BETWEEN DUFF AND MANN ROADS, THIS PROPERTY IS IN THE HEART OF THE NORTH LAKELAND RETAIL MARKET. SURROUNDING RETAILERS INCLUDE PUBLIX, TACO BELL, AND WALGREENS. THE ENTIRE 20 ACRES IS ZONED C-2. 
 $4,250,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Cory Petcoff 
 
 1816 Kathleen Road Commercial
Development Land
 PERFECT SITE FOR GAS STATION/CONVENIENCE STORE, FAST FOOD OR FULL SERVICE RESTAURANT. CITY UTILITIES AVAILABLE TO THE SITE. APPROXIMATELY 1.25 ACRES OFFERED AT $800,000.00. 
 $800,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Cory Petcoff 
 
 Retail Storefront for Lease in Prime Location Commercial
Retail
 Location, Location, Location..Retail Storefront...Was Sucessful
Pizzaria...Available For Rent!!! Great Opportunity!!!!! 
 $3,800 
 For Lease 
LONG BEACH, New York 
 Maria Aramanda Gull Realty Inc 
 
 Lake Lapin Estates Commercial
Development Land
 188 acres of mostly high and dry land except for several large spring fed lakes bounding the proprty. The property is situated by two lakes, Lake Lapin and Lake Dae. The adjacent property is currently under development with single family residential const... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Dean Vanderpool 
 
 Vacant Corner Lot Frontage Hghway 17-92 Sanford Commercial
Development Land
 Vacant Corner Lot at SW corner of busy intersection of W 5th St and Highway 17-92 in Sanford FL Zoned General Commercial-2 Wide vartiey of permitted uses. Drive-thru permitted. Lot surrounded by paved city roads on 3 sides. Frontage on Hwy 17-92 which is ... 
 $575,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Laura Gray 
 
 Development Ready Project - Estero, Florida Commercial
Development Land
 Development Ready Project with approved DO and Building Plans for 57,069 sf fronting Estero Parkway and Cypress View Drive. Approved uses include retail, office, medical office, restaurant, place of worship and more. Easy access to Southwest Florida Inter... 
 $3,750,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 MaryAnn Spence Select Real Estate by Stephanie Miller, Inc. 
 
 BRADENTON - Manatee Ave E Retail or Office Pad Commercial
Development Land
 FABULOUS CORNER LOT at Manatee Ave. E&amp;18th St.zoned for office, professional office&amp;retail. High traffic, 6 lane highway with access directly off Manatee Ave (US 64)&amp;off 18th Street. Turning lanes allowing for left in&amp;out. VERY FLE... 
 $1,300,000 
 For Sale 
Bradenton, Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 22.55 Acre Commercial Parcel -St. Johns County, FL Commercial
Development Land
 1/2 mile west of I- 95 on SR 207. PUD allows for up to 240,000 SF of Commercial General (CG) space. Zoning allows most retail&amp;office uses. &quot;Big box&quot; would require a zoning change. Priced to sell at only $3.58 PSF. Contact Ed Herbert @ 904.637.9271 
 $3,516,555 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Edward Herbert 
 
 Development Site near Niagara Falls, NY Commercial
Development Land
 This 3-acre commercial parcel is located at a heavily traveled intersection in the Town of Wheatfield NY. A high visibility location on one of the primary routes for tourists traveling to see Niagara Falls. The property currently houses a well-appointed r... 
 $850,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jane Munro Hunt Commercial Real Estate 
 
 3.38 acres Clarkston, GA Commercial
Development Land
 Comprised of 4 buildings totaling over 30,858 square feet this 3.38 acre site has multiple possible uses including the ability to be redeveloped. The site has excellent visibility from Stone Mountain Freeway (Hwy 78) with over 110,510 cars passing that lo... 
 $1,550,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Mitesh Patel 
 
 Residental Lakefront Lots Commercial
Development Land
 2.22 acres of lake front, level property. Preliminary layout has 9 lots for residential use. Beautiful lakefront with access to three total lakes with the use of the canals. 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Angela Hibbard 
 
 Gulf Front Propety Panama City Beach Commercial
Development Land
 133 feet on the Gulf of Mexico and 250 feet Deep (parcel outlined in red). Zoned Seasonal Resort 2 allowing high rise condo development, mixed use, retail and restaurants. Adjacent parcels (highlighted in blue on map) can possibly be combined as an assemb... 
 $16,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Panama City Beach Pkwy Development Opportunities Commercial
Development Land
 Numerous parcels available on Panama City Beach Parkway ranging in price from $450,000 to $2,450,000. Email for specific information. 
 $450 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Jackson County Florida Commercial
Development Land
 Ideal for Residential Subdivision Approximately 239 +/- Acres. Entrance from State Hwy 77&amp;College Drive. Pond on Property&amp;Borders Creek in NW Corner. 30,000 sq ft metal building with possible use for S/D Community Building. Gentle Rolling Terrain. Par... 
 $2,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Washington County Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Approximately 236&apos;x 325&apos;and 1.81 Acres. 236&apos;of Highway 90 Frontage. Ideal for Shopping Center, Office Building or Industrial. Additional parcel 239&apos;x 325&apos;, approximately 1.71 Acres also available for $120,000. 
 $130,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 West End Panama City Beach Commercial
Development Land
 10 Acre Parcel Zoned Commercial Adjacent to New Retail Center 
 $10,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Thomas Drive Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Panama City Beach. Premium Land Available Zoned SR-1A Can accommodate Hotels, Condos, Apartments&amp;Retail. Minutes from New Proposed International Airport Preliminary Plans&amp;Engineering for Condo Development Available. 
 $2,300,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Fannin Bayou Commercial
Development Land
 4 Parcels totaling Approximately 56 Acres. Zoned Residential. Property could possibly be a Marina with Residential Development. Parcels can be bought separately. 
 $14,600,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Oyster Point Commercial
Development Land
 16 Acre Parcel. Zoned Residential with potential for waterfront Residential Community. Located off of Cutchens Road&amp;Hilliard Street. 
 $5,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Marina Property Commercial
Development Land
 Parcel A = 8.26 Acres with 4.6 acres of uplands with Marina Area. Parcel B = 17 with 8-9 acres of uplands. Parcels can be bought separately. Possible Uses for Property would be a Marina with Residential Development. 
 $8,700,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Escambia Bay Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Gated Waterfront Community on Beautiful Escambia Bay in Santa Rosa County. 11.8 Acres with Unobstructed Bay View. 460&apos;on Escambia Bay. All permits and approvals in place for 47 lot subdivision. 
 $3,250,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Gulf Drive&amp;Thomas;Drive Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 South side of Gulf Dr is approximately 350&apos;on the Gulf of Mexico and 250&apos;deep. North side of Gulf Dr is approximately 400&apos;on Gulf Dr and 230&apos;deep with 300&apos;on Thomas Dr. Zoned Seasonal Resort 2 (SR-2), allowing high rise condos, mi... 
 $39,925,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Front Beach Road Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 108 Feet on North Side of Front Beach Road-Zoned C-2 Plaza Commercial, .54 acres. 250 Feet on the Gulf of Mexico on the Most Pristine Beaches in Panama City Beach, Florida. Zone Seasonal Resort Commercial 
 $25,950,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Panama City Beach Front Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 C2 Plaza Commercial DO in Place for Gated Community Gulf Views Across from Deeded&amp;Dedicated Beach Access 
 $3,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Grace Bay - Journeys End Commercial
Development Land
 Approximately 14.5 Acres with approximately 774&apos;of Bay Frontage and Approximately 870&apos;Deep. THE FORGOTTEN COAST IN THE FLORIDA PANHANDLE. 
 $12,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Marina Development Opportunity in Panama City Bch Commercial
Development Land
 Secure Private Gated Entry Private Deep-Water Marina Dry Boat Storage Facility 
 $16,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Marina Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 750&apos;Deep Water Approximately 5 Acres Private Deep-Water Marina Dry Boat Storage Facility 
 $14,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Gulf Front Luxury Resort Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 786&apos;Highway Frontage on Gulf Approximately 5 Acres with Approximately 900&apos;of frontage in 10 Acre Parcel on North Side of Highway, including Portion of Lake. 
 $89,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Front Beach Road - Gulf Highlands Commercial
Development Land
 Features 578&apos;Frontage on The Gulf of Mexico. Additional Lots on the North Side of Street. Located on the Premier East End of Panama City Beach. Approximately 4.11 Acres of Exceptional Real Estate. 
 $62,895,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 Paradise Beach - Thomas Drive Commercial
Development Land
 Development Order In Place 170&apos;of Gulf Frontage Upscale Beach Condominium Resort Planned Ultimate Luxury Superior Location 1.45 Acres 
 $20,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Kenny Whatley 
 
 SR 80 Commercial Property Commercial
Development Land
 At the NW corner of SR 80 (Palm Beach Blvd.) and SR 31 Fort Myers, FL 33905 Available For Sale - 24.66+/- Acres - 2.25 miles East of I-75 on Palm Beach Boulevard. Across from Bonita Bay Group&apos;s Verandah Development and just a few miles south of Babcoc... 
 $10,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jim Tamblyn Colliers Arnold 
 
 9 acres South Florida Ave Lakeland, Fl Commercial
Development Land
 So. Florida ave.@ Oak Lane, Lakeland Fl. 9 acres (5 usable)... North of Home Depot, So of Outback Steak House etc.&amp;across street from Post Office. Owner broker ready to sell and would consider trading down. 
 $750,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jerry Herring 
 
 Light Industrial vacant land near I-4 Lakeland, Fl Commercial
Development Land
 Light industrial land in Enterprise Zone 1 mile so. of Interstate 4. Located on 4 lane and adjacent to RAIL. Owner broker ready to sell...will consider trading down. 
 $3 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jerry Herring 
 
 Forest City Road&amp;Pembrook Drive Commercial
Development Land
 32,232 square feet of vacant land available. Developed lot, offsite retention and shared offsite parking. 100% usable property with all utilities at site.  Located next to new church building, would be a great location for child day care, adult ... 
 $498,000 
 For Sale 
Orlando, Florida 
 Al Clark Southeastern Realty 
 
 7+/- Acres - 3108 W. Vine Street Commercial
Development Land
 Orlando tourist district. Close to disney area accommodations, restaurants and shopping centers. 325&apos;+/- frontage on Highway 192, 460&apos;+/- on Plantation Drive. Zoned H-C. Additional parcel available for access to red light on Dyer Blvd. Traffic co... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Ron Cole Southeastern Realty 
 
 Anglers Escape Commercial
Development Land
 21.7 acres with access to St. Andrews Bay. Developer wants to build 140 detached units with metal roof and boat slip for each unit. A old Florida Fishing Village concept. Needs investors. Panama City Beach Location. 
 $8,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Stephen Gilliam 
 
 LAND FOR SALE NEAR NEW DESTINATION DAYTONA Commercial
Development Land
 36,5000 sf in ideal motorcycle related retail location. Property is located among the hottest biker bars in the Daytona Beach area. 100&apos;frontage on US-1. Zoned central business. Property includes 1216 sf house and 576 sf garage. 800 Amp electric serv... 
 $595,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Buddy Buddiansky 
 
 Ft Lauderdale Land; Entitled for 20 Condo/Twnhomes Commercial
Development Land
 All entitlements and Permits Completed, ready to build today. The subject property is a rectangular shaped, 48,825 square foot (SF) or 1.12 acre (AC) vacant parcel of RMM-25 (Residential Multifamily Mid Rise/Medium High Density District) zoned land on the... 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 William Kedersha 
 
 Cement plant with waterfront land Commercial
Development Land
 Cement Plant&amp;constructionbusiness with 150 acres waterfront property that includes 70 acres high and dry with the rest beeing bay bottom. Business is doing $20MM a year. Land is zoned commercial 
 $80,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jean Kruger 
 
 Tampa-Carrollwood Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 A Wonderful development opportunity close to the heart of Carrollwood. For sale are 2 continuous properties being sold together, the first approx 3.8 acres and the other approx .75 acres totaling approximately 4.6 acres. A long standing plant nursery and ... 
 $2,500,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 John Pestalozzi Jr 
 
 I-75 FRONTAGE - FORT MYERS Commercial
Development Land
 2055 ft of frontage on I-75. Located on SR 82. Zoned I-2 in City of Fort Myers. Billboard lease. Water&amp;sewer available. 
 $13 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 MaryAnn Spence Select Real Estate by Stephanie Miller, Inc. 
 
 30 +/- Acres in Mount Dora, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Located in the fastest growing area of Lake County in Central Florida. Daytime population of 65,366 within 5 miles. Trip count of 42,000 cars daily. Just 2 miles away from the new Florida Hospital Waterman. Located 3.2 miles from the proposed beltway inte... 
 $12,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Marnie Connor 
 
 Seacrest Blvd Commercial Land, Boynton Beach, FL Commercial
Development Land
 30,000 +- sq ft - Approved for 5,000 sq ft restaurant with parking by Palm Beach County; 200 ft frontage on Seacrest Blvd., just off of I-95&amp;Hypoluxo Blvd., next to Sam&apos;s Club, Comfort Inn, Taco Bell, Mobile Gas; Across from mixed use Windsor Center... 
 $750,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Bonnie Anthony 
 
 Investors! Commercial Lot in Fort Walton Beach! Commercial
Development Land
 JUST REDUCED!!! A RARE FIND.....9/10 OF AN ACRE IN CENTRAL FORT WALTON BEACH ZONED URBAN MIXED USE FOR FUTURE LAND DEVELOPMENT. COUNTY SHOWS THE 3 LOTS AS 2 IN THE TAX RECORDS. YEARLY RENTAL INCOME IS $36540. LOT 6 IS 187&apos;X 75&apos;AND HAS 2 TRAILERS... 
 $359,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Robert Olson 
 
 Commercial Property Available in Fort Walton Beach Commercial
Development Land
 PROPERTY IS CURRENTLY BEING RENTED TO LAMBERTS CABLE SPLICING ON A MONTH TO MONTH BASIS. 
 $179,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Robert Olson 
 
 Knuth PCD Commercial
Development Land
 Boynton Beach, Florida, Palm Beach County Property Description: 12.5064 acres of entitled high and dry land approved for 120,000 sf P.C.D. shopping center. Has Boynton Beach Blvd and Knuth Rd frontage. This location is in the very fast growing region of w... 
 $25,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Joan Kippert 
 
 Commercial Land on Biscayne Boulevard in Miami Commercial
Development Land
 2 Lots available - one is 10,400 sq ft and the other is 8,200 sq ft. Both front Biscayne Blvd with 210 feet of frontage. Zoned C-1 Commercial with clean environmental audit. Zoned to build up to 12 stories high. Best price! 
 $1,700,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Mike Mason 
 
 Commercial Land High Traffic Count! Commercial
Development Land
 301&apos;Road Frontage, 1.3 Acres+/- Zoned C-3, General Commercial and all residential uses) 230&apos;Height Limit,High Traffic Counts just south of Busy Hwy 98 Fly Over. Prime piece for visibility. Just across the Street from Navel Station. Would be a gre... 
 $1,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Donna Stokes 
 
 West Waters Avenue - Tampa, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Five Parcels totaling 3.11 Acres (MOL). Located on a corner with median cut. Located between Dale Mabry Highway and the Veternas Expressway. Currently there are multiple buildings on the site including a 12,000 SF office/warehouse building. Four parcels a... 
 $2,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chris Bowers 
 
 Central&amp;49th - St. Petersburg Commercial
Development Land
 - Located on the Corner of Central Ave&amp;49th St N in St. Petersburg, FL - 1,917 SF building could be used as office / retail / re-development Two parcels totaling 11,000 SF - Zoned CG - Frontage on Central Ave, 49th St N,&amp;1st Ave S 
 $425,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chris Bowers 
 
 Pine Lake Land Commercial
Development Land
 - 1.8 Acre lot - Zoned Heavy Commercial - 300 ft of frontage on 66th St - Located on the corner of 66th St N&amp;121st Ave N. - Median Cut for easy access - AVALIABLE AS LAND LEASE OR BUILD-TO-SUIT 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chris Bowers 
 
 St. Pete Land - Central Avenue Commercial
Development Land
 * Five parcels totaling 29,000 SF (MOL) * UV-1 zoning allows for mixed use of Retail, Office or Residential * Close to Downtown St. Petersburg, Tropicana Field&amp;I-275 * Frontage on Central Ave, 28th St&amp;1st Ave S * Owner has drawings for 36,000 SF+ with... 
 $1,250,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chris Bowers 
 
 12285 U S HWY 301 N Parrish Commercial
Development Land
 Prime 4.29+/- acres located in the heart of the village of Parrish, Fl. 350+/- feet road frontage on US Highway 301. side road frontage, adjacent to rural health center. Unlimited development potential. currently zoned A1 Village. 100 year old homestead a... 
 $1,275,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Croom Bilbrey 
 
 Highland Avenue-Sunny Hills Commercial
Development Land
 Prime commercial district property in fast growing Sunny Hills, Florida. Sunny Hills Subdivision has 24,000 residential lots platted, with National Recreational Properties, Inc., ready to launch marketing for 7,800 lots. Other proposed developments in and... 
 $499,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Gary Hartman 
 
 South Beach Land Development for Hotel or.... Commercial
Development Land
 This unique Development Opportunity in South of Fifth at South Beach is an ideal location for a Boutique Hotel or Luxurious condos. Perfectly nested on Collins Ave just 1/2 block from the ocean and a short distance to South Beach famous nightlife and rest... 
 $12,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 David Degen 
 
 Willow Run Quarry Commercial
Development Land
 560 +/- Excavation Rock Mine in one of Collier County&apos;s highest growth areas just minutes from I-75 and U.S. 41. The subject property is surrounded by luxury golf courses and communities. Outstanding Opportunity for a private community. 
 $65,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Dan Guoan Premier Commercial Properties 
 
 Wilham Pavilion Commercial
Development Land
 5.01 acre parcel with 3.34 usable acres. Direct frontage on Six Mile Cypress. B-1 Zoning(General Commercial) currently approved for a one story multi-tennant retail/office center that is 27,274 sf in size. Located on the east side of Six Mile Cypress Park... 
 $2,400,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Dan Guoan Premier Commercial Properties 
 
 Hawks Preserve Commercial
Development Land
 Opportunity to purchase pre-construction flex space in the heart of an enormous growth area. Units starting at 1,200 sf but can be designed to suit a multitude of needs. Located just off Alico Road in the Alico Commercial Park. Minutes from Miromar Outlet... 
 $2,100,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Dan Guoan Premier Commercial Properties 
 
 St Lucie Farm Commercial
Development Land
 Farm is located about 5 miles west of I95. It is an 82 acres citrus grove with aproximately 35 acres of the citrus removed on the East side of the property. This land is in a fast developing area and is one of the few large tracts that is available for de... 
 $1,100,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jean Kruger 
 
 Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Fully approved development opportunity in fast growing Doral. Across from world-class golf resort, close to schools, places of worship, retail and brand new Doral City Center. Quick and easy access to major highways, business parks, warehouse district and... 
 $36,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Ivan Amayo 
 
 Oceanfront Multi-family Commercial
Development Land
 11.7 acre site, fully entitled for 104 units, clean with 531&apos;of oceanfront and 125&apos;height limit. All plans, designs and additional information available on completion of confidentiality.. 
 $26,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Bob Haynie 
 
 Fountainview Commons Commercial
Development Land
 Address: I-95 and St. Lucie West Boulevard Description: Imagine your business location (and signage) being along I-95 with unobstructed exposure to hundreds of thousands of vehicles! We have site plan approval to build two 8,000 sf single story buildings ... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Ross Realty 
 
 Top Of The Hill Commercial
Development Land
 Over 11 acres sandwiched between industrial and residential use. City will zone it for anything that makes sense. Ideal for Warehouse condos, ACLF, small apartment complex, storage, etc. Save an acre for a retail outlet. In 3 years that acre will cover th... 
 $995,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 bob Zegota 
 
 National Builders Private Land Sales Commercial
Development Land
 We have pocket private listings for two National builders entitled properties from 5mil to 100mil range. All are entitled and some with up to 200mil in infrastruture already in. serious inquiries only call for details. a non-circumvent and non- disclosure... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Charles Harris 
 
 Rockridge Road Commercial
Development Land
 2.44 acres located on the Southwest corner of Hwy 98&amp;Rockridge Road. This prime parcel is located at a traffic light and across the street from a service station. This piece also backs up to Cypress Lakes Golf Course. 
 $185,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Casey Herring 
 
 Pipkin Creek Commercial
Development Land
 Total of 21.48 acres located at 4175 Pipkin Creek Road. 10 Acres zoned BPC-1. Additional 11 acres are zoned Residential Suburban. Minutes from Polk Parkways and I-4. 
 $2,900,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Casey Herring 
 
 Redevlopment Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Property consist of a 3-parcel 4.67 acres improved by a self-storage operation on US 301 just north of two shopping plazas, each anchored by a a Sweet Bay and a Publix Market with a &quot;power center&quot; under development; major housing development now taking pl... 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Matthew Aronson 
 
 Alico Industrial/commercial Airpark Commercial
Development Land
 241 ACRES WITH 1,608 FRONT FEET ON ALICO ROAD, CONTIGUOUS TO SW FL INT&apos;L AIRPORT ZONED MIXED USE PLANNED DEVELOPMENT ALLOWS HEAVY INDUSTRIAL USES IN ADDITION TO COMMERCIAL AND RETAIL COMMERCIAL. PROPERTY LOCATED APPROX. 1 MILE EAST OF ALICO/TREELINE I... 
 $24,600,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 JESSICA RUSSO 
 
 Land Zoned For Retail&amp;Office Commercial
Development Land
 4.81 Acres ; Land zoned for office building or Hotel 300 Feet height with retail on the bottom.Located on Hallandale Beach ,East of Us-1 , 1 Mile North of Aventura FL ,2 miles East of 1-95 and 4 miles South of Fort Lauderdale airport and 3/4 mile West of ... 
 $25,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Luis Roman 
 
 Half Acre For Condominium Development Commercial
Development Land
 Appx. acre for 8 unit condominium development situated waterfront in Perdido Key, Florida. Located at the gateway of the red hot Florida/Alabama Intracoastal Waterway. Zoned for up To 10 stories. 
 $2,800,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Mitchell 
 
 100 Waterfront Acres In Florida - Jv Opp!! Commercial
Development Land
 101 WATERFRONT acres valued 2005 at $9.1 -10 mil. Fire sale for quick action 55% discount...only $4.25 mil. Gulf access Intracoastal Waterway, Port St. Joe, FL. Pre-approved 157 units. Price includes survey and closing costs...will provide title/insurance... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chester Novak 
 
 Office/Flex/Warehouse 180,000 Sf Office/flex/ind. Commercial
Office
 NOW UNDER CONSTRUCTION. OFFICE&amp;OFFICE/FLEX OPPORTUNITY!! SRQ TechPARK! .Amazing 27-Acre gorgeous LEED certified business park now UNDER CONSTRUCTION. Total of 180,000 SF of Office/ &amp;Office/Flex/Industrial space. From 1,800 SF to full buil... 
 $315,000 
 For Sale 
Sarasota, Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 87 MOL Residential Development acre Commercial
Development Land
 87 MOL Residential Development acres in NW Orange County, Fl Located within the City of Apopka Near Major Highways, Water and Sewer available at adjacent subdivisions City of Apopka changing zoning for 5 du per acre $7,400,000-Price For more info: 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Gayle Brewer 
 
 Commercial Site Commercial
Development Land
 4 acres located on Highway 40 in Ocala. Property is zoned M-1, and has 220 feet of road frontage. City water and sewer at site. Four-laning of highway near completion. Property is near city airport and close to proposed retail/hotel site. Owner financing ... 
 $697,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Broward Sanchez 
 
 Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Development opportunities for two class A mixed use buildings with a minimum of 300,000 square feet each with indoor parking. Properties are entitled for retail, office and residential use. Both situated in busy downtown Gulf Coast Florida locations, one ... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Emma Catalini 
 
 Florida Development Land Commercial
Development Land
 Florida Development Land available for residential, single and multifamily units. Some on waterfront location. 5 to 500 acre parcels. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Emma Catalini 
 
 Prime Commercial Panama City Fl. Commercial
Development Land
 INFO FROM TAX ROLLS- PLEASE VERIFY. PRIME COMMERCIAL LOCATION ON THE CORNER OF TYNDALL PKWY AND TRAM RD. TRAM ROAD WILL BE UNDER GOING PRELIMINARY ENGINEERING IN 2008 BY THE FLORIDA DOT FOR USE AS PART OF THE GULF COAST PARKWAY. ONE PACEL IS 260&apos;FRON... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 ANTHONY JENSEN 
 
 52 Acres Mixed Use Development Land Commercial
Development Land
 Zoned MX, PDP-GHC,PDP-MF,PDP-SF Brooksville, FL This property has an excellent location fronting on State Road for approximately 1,650 feet. Prime for mixed use development. As per the owner, the front approximately 12 acres is zoned commercial, the cente... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nancy Haynes 
 
 200 Acres in St. Augustine, Florida Commercial
Development Land
 PUD fully permitted for 632 units. An exceptional property located 3 miles from the Ocean.&apos;Fully Entitled&apos;!!! Currently approved for a 632-Unit Mixed-Use residential development. For a complete listing brochure please click on the following link.... 
 $17,000,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jeff Klotz 
 
 Las Olas - 10 Unit Condo Project in Jacksonville Beach, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Rare opportunity to own and develop the last permitted property for 10 Units, exceeding the 35&apos;height restriction in Jacksonville Beach. Special Financing. Pay Sellers Interest Only. Close 1 year from Today. For a complete listing brochure, please cl... 
 $3 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jeff Klotz 
 
 Costa Del Mar, 10-14 Unit Project in Jacksonville Beach, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Rare opportunity to own and develop one of the last oceanview condominium sites in Jacksonville Beach. Special Financing. Pay Sellers Interest Only. Close 1 year from Today. For a complete listing brochure, please click on the following link: http://www.d... 
 $2 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Jeff Klotz 
 
 Hotel Pad Site-2.14 Acres Commercial
Development Land
 For 125 room hotel. Offering at $1,375,000. Part of 27 Acre LEED certified office&amp;office/flex/warehouse park. In University District&amp;nearly adjacent to SRQ Airport. HIgh traffic, 4-lane, with turning lanes &amp;two 4-way intersect... 
 $1,375,000 
 For Sale 
Sarasota, Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 SARASOTA RETAIL Pad Site Commercial
Development Land
 1.29 Acres on U.S. 301. Offering at $1,025,000. Part of 27- Acre TBB Business Park. 
 $1,150,000 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 AUTO DEALERSHIP - VACANT Commercial
Automotive
 VACANT AUTO DEALERSHIP Buick&amp;Suzuki.. FABULOPUS location. 3 Showroom&amp;Service buildings.In the hub of literally dozens of auto dealerships&amp;feeder services. Within 1.5 miles of 2 major Tampa Regional Malls. Go to web link: http://sale... 
 $8,550,000 
 For Sale 
Brandon, Florida 
 Cynthia Bishop Sperry Van Ness - Blackpoint REalty 
 
 1/2 Acre For 8 Unit Condominium Development Commercial
Development Land
 Appx. acre for 8 unit condominium development situated waterfront in Perdido Key, Florida. Located at the gateway of the red hot Florida/Alabama Intracoastal Waterway. Zoned for up To 10 stories. $2,800,000. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Tom Mitchell 
 
 6 Acres zoned commercial Commercial
Development Land
 700&apos;on hwy 27 Clermont, near turnpike exit, also fronts turnpike, about 270&apos;deep. Visit our latest project at www.BellaCasaResort.com 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Frank A. Werner Broker 
 
 VACANT LAND: Wildwood, Fl, I-75 and SR 44, 1.3 Acres. Commercial
Development Land
 High visavality location, great for has, fast food, hotel and more....asking $2,000,000...motivated seller 
 $2 
 For Sale 
WildWood, Florida 
 John Thomas Bosshardt Realty Services, Inc. 
 
 Commercial Land, 3601 Hwy 98 W, Panama City, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Corner Lot available in a busy retail business corridor. The property originally was a service repair station (owner states tanks have been removed). It is centrally located on 15th Street, Panama City. There is 140.0&apos;of Frontage with an existing ser... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 JESSIE COCHRAN 
 
 Commercial Land, 19102 Panama City Beach PKWY, Panama City, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Nice Level High&amp;Dry 2.11 Acre Tract of Land. Currently there is 88 storage units with room to build more or a great parcel for another commercial use. The owner is willing to finance-Call listing agent for details. Owner states rental potential @ 100% o... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 JESSIE COCHRAN 
 
 Hwy 60 Lake Wales Commercial
Development Land
 3900 block bldg with 2 other parcels. Approximately 1 acre of land with highway exposure. Property has a 2 bed/2 bath frame home and 100&apos;x200&apos;parking lot. Total of 200&apos;of highway frontage. All zoned for commercial use. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Linda Gauntt, Realtor 
 
 Commerical Land / Lot 15 Hwy 90, Defuniak Springs, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Zoning Industrial Land, 9.50 acres, oned forr Industrial use,Hwy 90, Defuniak Springs, FL oning Residential Single Family, iak Springs. em consisting of Lot 15 of Gillis Heights recorded lot. Survey complete, with frontage on CSX Railroad tracks, Property... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Brandon Jordan 
 
 Commercial Land - Industrial, Defuniak Springs, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Lot 14 Hwy 90, Defuniak Springs, FL. 18.2 acres, Bank Owned , Zoned for Industrial use, consisting of Lot 14 of Gillis Heights recorded lot. Survey complete, with frontage on CSX Railroad tracks, Property has over 18+ Acres and is priced at under 80k per ... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Brandon Jordan 
 
 Commercial Land - Industrial, Defuniak Springs, FL Commercial
Development Land
 Lot 13 Hwy 90, Defuniak Springs, FL. 22.07 acres, building SF 1428, built 1985, Bank Owned, Zoned for Industrial use, consisting of Lot 13 of Gillis Heights recorded lot. Survey complete, with frontage on CSX Railroad tracks, Property has a 1400+ square f... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Brandon Jordan 
 
 Multi Family Commercial Land, Crestview FL Commercial
Development Land
 1.13 Acres, Bay St. Crestview FL. Zoned Multi Family, These four lots, all adjacent and totaling 1.13 acres, are on the west side of Bay street between Blakely Ave and Springhill Court. The three other Parcel IDs are 20-3n-23-0000-0043-0000, 20-3n-23-0000... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Brandon Jordan 
 
 323.6 acres HIGH AND DRY with lake Commercial
Development Land
 near - Archer/Gainesville Florida View aerials and information at www.archerhighlands.com $18,500 per acre - developers dream - Ready for a PUD or rezoning 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Chere R Roane, Broker 
 
 290 Acre Waterfront Development Site Commercial
Development Land
 Florida&apos;s Panhandle. 2.5 Miles of Deep Water frontage, 1.5 miles of potential commercial Perfect site for Mixed Use Resort/Gated community with Marina. Density = 5/acre $75M JV possibilities 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nan Gile, Broker 
 
 638 Acre Development site Commercial
Development Land
 lake, river and pond, perfect for lifestyle community and close to the Gulf. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nan Gile, Broker 
 
 312 acre site Commercial
Development Land
 at interconnector of major interstate and southern route highway which will be main access to the countries newest International Airport 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nan Gile, Broker 
 
 10 Acres Commercial Land Commercial
Development Land
 on High Traffic Road in Destination Beach Community 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nan Gile, Broker 
 
 243 acres currently used for horses Commercial
Development Land
 contiguous to Audubon Land 3 ponds 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Nan Gile, Broker 
 
 Land 0.68 Acres West Palm Beach FL $4,729,504 Commercial
Development Land
 Center of Redevelopment Area of WPB 4 Blocks from the Intercostals 5 Blocks from the Convention Center Minutes from the Island of Palm Beach One block from proposed City Hall and Library 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Duane Bennett, CCIM 
 
 Land 40.00 Acres Punta Gorda FL $1,600,000 Commercial
Development Land
 40 acres on Huffmaster Road close to Babcock Ranch 40,000 resident town planned for Babcock Ranch Only minutes away from I-75 In Charlotte County just north of Lee County line Owner owns 101 contiguous acres - invites offers 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 Matthew Brannen 
 
 7871 SR 207, Hastings, FL $399,000 Commercial
Development Land
 Great property, multiple uses. Would make a great RV Park or a wonderful estate with a river running through it. Irregular lot, approximately 49 Acres in 2 parcels. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 James W. Smith 
 
 COMMERCIAL LAND - 815 MLK BLVD - $39,000 Commercial
Development Land
 815 MARTIN LUTHER KING BLVD, panama City, FL Zip 32401 This parcel is compact in size, but the very low price and central location makes this a smart investment. PC Planning&amp;Zoning confirmed that there is not a minimum sq footage requirement for build o... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 CHARLES HANCOCK 
 
 4.30 Acres Near Ybor City and I - 4 and 50th - $975,000 Commercial
Development Land
 4 acres of Commercial Intensive, Cleared, Fenced Land. Price for Quick Sale. Assessed value of $702K, per Hillsborough Records. 22 Acres next to it sold for $10MM. Zoning: Commercial Class 4.- - Commercial Intensive - Many Uses Clean Ground, NO Phase 2 ne... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Florida 
 The Stewart, Jones&amp;Levin Team 
 
 One level acre for Commercial Development Commercial
Development Land
 Where is the HOT SPOT in booming Barrow County so far as commercial developmment is concerned? Yes, that&apos;s right! It is the area surrounding Highway 316&amp;Highway 81. Already open is Home Depot. Under construction is Target, Belks, and Publix. Already... 
 $125,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Anthony Evans 
 
 This is the Hot Spot in Barrow County! Commercial
Development Land
 The area surrounding the intersection of Highway 316&amp;Highway 81 in booming Barrow County is truly the HOT SPOT for commercial development. Home Depot is already open, with Target, Belks, and Publix under construction. Wachovia, Best Buy, PetsSmart, Stap... 
 $325,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Anthony Evans 
 
 28.5 Acres located in Austell, GA Commercial
Development Land
 28.5 Acres located on Factory Shoals road with over 270 ft of road frontage. Property is on the corner of Hartman Road and runs to White Rd with 680 ft of road frontage. Property is currently zoned residential, but Cobb County has it marked as industrial ... 
 $2,990,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Charda Bishop 
 
 HWY 515 FRONTAGE AT BALLGROUND, GA! Commercial
Development Land
 Very visible 13.06 AC hilltop tract at Old Howell Bridge Rd., Exit 27 just 1 hr. No. of Atlanta, 10 miles So. of Jasper, GA. Area is exploding with growth, zoned Hwy Commercial. Beautiful mountain view, paved access utilities available. Excellent for comm... 
 $1,746,775 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Susan Shedd 
 
 5.18 Acres on Sugarloaf Pkwy Adjacent to 2 Schools Commercial
Development Land
 Community: This acreage is located on Sugarloaf Pkwy between Five Forks and Hwy 29 (Lawrenceville Hwy). The parcel is adjacent to two Gwinnett Schools and is neighbored by WalMart, Publix, Salvation Army, and several smaller retail outlets and restaurants... 
 $1,554,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Kenny Everson 
 
 Waterfront Development with 96 lots ready to build Commercial
Development Land
 Attention Builders and Developers . Once in a lifetime opportunity. Completed 96 lot subdivision. Appraised at 9.5 million in July. Will sell for 6.2 million. Just completed riverfront subdivision for sale by owner. 96 lots 17 being on the river with ocea... 
 $6,200,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Jim Thalmann 
 
 5.75 acres Locust Grove, GA Commercial
Development Land
 Subject property includes Two parcels totaling 5.75 acres with over 821 feet of frontage on I-75 Northbound and 224 feet of frontage on Tanger Blvd. at exit 212 in Locust Grove. Location is ideal for a Multifamily development as the site is supported by r... 
 $1,725,750 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Mitesh Patel 
 
 2.16 acres McDonough, GA Commercial
Development Land
 Subject property includes 2.16 acres with over 395 feet of frontage on I-75 Northbound off Industrial Blvd an access road between exit 218 and 216 in McDonough. Location is ideal for a Hotel/Motel or Restaurant as the site is surrounded by retail and indu... 
 $1,404,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Mitesh Patel 
 
 30 acres Mt. Zion Circle, Clayton County, GA Commercial
Development Land
 Subject property includes 30 acres with over 606 feet of frontage on Mt. Zion Circle directly behind AMC Southlake Theater. Location is ideal for a mixed use development with retail and multifamily residential. The property can be combined with another 20... 
 $6,450,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Mitesh Patel 
 
 9 ACRE, 831&apos;Road Frontage, Near Mall of GA, BUSY Commercial
Development Land
 This awesome location features over 9 acres of buildable land with 831&apos;of Road Frontage. Old Fountain Road (aka Jim Moore Road) is very busy with several thousand cars passing it daily. Within viewing distance of HWY 324 (Auburn Road). Sellers are mo... 
 $3,195,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Joshua Jarvis 
 
 10 Acres in Dacula City Limits, 549&apos;Road Frontage Commercial
Development Land
 Property Description: 10 Commercial Acres almost square in shape with 549 feet of road frontage. Near Dacula High School, Library, busy interesection, and less than 5 miles from new Walmart. This area has been slated to receive sewer in the next 3 years. ... 
 $1,600,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Joshua Jarvis 
 
 Lake Oconee Ga - Development Tract 128 acs. Commercial
Development Land
 Large acreage tract on Hwy 44, Lake Oconee&apos;s main corridor. About a quarter mile south of the New Home Depot Site - also featuring resturants and hotels. Currently zoned ag but adjacent to commercial property. Potential for commercial and residential ... 
 $4,250,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Ed Okenica 
 
 42.6 Acre Townhome Property Commercial
Development Land
 42.6 Acre tract within walking distance to mall, movie theater, restaurants, shopping, and Georgia Southern University. Prime piece of property already has all utilities and a deeded 6 acre tract for a walking trail connecting downtown adjacent to this pr... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Jay Saxon Saxon Design Builders 
 
 Against National Forest- RARE Commercial
Development Land
 Seclusion- and a rare find- right up against National Forest. Property lays well. Wildlife abounds and the mountain laurel is prolific. A true &quot;outdoor lover&apos;s Paradise!&quot; 
 $350,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Harriet Carter 
 
 Overlooking Alpine Helen Georgia- Commercial
Development Land
 ONE OF IT&apos;S KIND- LAST OF IT&apos;S KIND! 4.60 + - ACRES OF HELEN MOUNTAIN TOP WITH EXTREME VIEWS OF THE BEAUTIFUL ALPINE VILLAGE. BREATH TAKING VIEWS OF CHIMNEY AND TRAY MOUNTAINS- TO NAME JUST 2 ! PROPERTY WOULD BE IDEAL LOCATION FOR MANY TYPES OF EN... 
 $500,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Harriet Carter 
 
 9 ac. com. tract on corner of busy intersection Commercial
Development Land
 Land is on the corner of very busy intersection on 575/515 in Blue Ridge,GA. City water and sewer are on property. Would make very nice spot for a motel chain. Blue Ridge is nestled at the base of the Blue Ridge Mountains. We are mainly a 2nd home/resort ... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Laura Sisson 
 
 10.5 ac commercial land Commercial
Development Land
 Almost 11 acres in the city limits of Blue Ridge, GA. Blue Ridge is a growing community with mainly 2nd home (cabin) ownership. This tract is leveled and has city water/sewer and 3 phase power. Great visibility from main road 575/515, with DOT accell/dece... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Laura Sisson 
 
 200 ac. surrounded by National Forest Commercial
Development Land
 Wildlife is abundant on this pristine 200 acre tract completely surrounded by The Cohutta Wilderness Wildlife Mgt Agency. Property would make a great development or would be even nicer for a family retreat. Creek, waterfalls, pasture, year round mtn views... 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Laura Sisson 
 
 Land Perfect for Shopping Center Near Athens GA Commercial
Development Land
 Incredible opportunity! 9.075 Flat Acres, Backs up to new sewage plant, just off major thoroughfare between Atlanta&amp;Athens. This pristine piece of land is close to the prestigious GA Club that will have over 1000 homes when completed. It is less than 1/... 
 $1,361,250 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Heather Swint 
 
 13.97 Acres of MH&amp;RA-200 Zoning Commercial
Development Land
 This property has great potential for development. Right off Hwy 316 in Gwinnett County, GA, this property is zoned partially for Mobile Home and partially RA-200. Would be great for townhomes or other commercial development. Huge &quot;big box&quot; store is looki... 
 $1,606,550 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Terry 
 
 Commercial Land Commercial
Development Land
 Corner lot, .62 ac Perry Ga. has had a huge residental boom and the commerical end is just starting to take off the retail spaces are playing catch up with all the new homes and families that have moved into the county and that are going to move in. Call ... 
 $110,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Daniel Brown 
 
 White Cliff Road Commercial
Development Land
 This is an unbelievable oportunity to own 200 acres right in the middle of the U.S. National Forest! This propety is bordered by Cohutta WMA on 4 sides, and features waterfalls, mountain views, pastures, creeks, and it&apos;s all&apos;unspoiled&apos;acreag... 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Laura Sisson 
 
 124 South Professional Suites Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent Location! 7.4 Acres of O&amp;I, Ready for development. Gwinnett County Approved for 66,000 Square Feet. Perfect for Office/Medical Suites. 3.5 Miles from Emory Eastside Hosp. Owner will consider developing. 1031 Exchange Available. 
 $1,350,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Andrea Fielden 
 
 2.8 Acres Commercial
Development Land
 Right off Exit 111 (Lawrenceville-Suwanee Rd.) at I-85. 180,000 vehicles/day Zoned C2-A The corner where 2.8 acre piece is currently located will have a traffic signal (first one off of the interstate) and will become even more visible, possibly from the ... 
 $350 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Michael Wendt 
 
 70+ Acres Joins Usfs With Views Commercial
Development Land
 Joined on three sides by the USFS, this tract is one of the last large tracts for sale in all of Towns County. Priced at $22k per acre, this parcel can be developed into 5 acre tracts or for one large homestead. 
 $1,550,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Stan Raymond 
 
 Sportsmans Paradise, Laurens County, Ga Commercial
Development Land
 THIS 38 + ACRE TRACT OFFERS A 8 +/_ACRE STOCKED POND. STOCKED WITH BASS AND BREAM. EXCELLENT POTENTIAL FOR MULTIPLE HOMESITES OR MAKE THIS SITE FOR YOUR DREAM HOME OVERLOOKING THE LAKE. CALL MARK LEE 478-609-0464 OR EMAIL marklee@ccmi1.com 
 $450,000 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 MARK LEE 
 
 53 Acre Development, N. Of Atlanta 45 Miles Commercial
Development Land
 I have a 53 acre development located north of Atlanta, approx. 45 miles, with utilities in place, paved roads, community pavilion&amp;pool. It is located within White County &quot;Mountain Protection&quot; area but has been grand- fathered in. **There will be no more... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Leroy Payne 
 
 Thomasville, GA 45 acre. Commercial
Development Land
 Will divide into two parcels, Paved road on front side and dirt road on back and side. Has been in cultivation and is now ready for development. $8500 per acre. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Richard Kaley 
 
 1 Acre located in Downtown Hiawassee in the NE Georgia Mountains Commercial
Development Land
 Property is located next to two major hotel chains and overlooks beautiful Lake Chatuge and the downtown area. Lot has all utilities in place. Frontage on two streets. Ideal for patio homes or fast food restaurant. Easy access from main highway. $239,000.... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Candace Lee 
 
 Dalton GA - Garmley&apos;s Mobile Home Rentals Commercial
Mobile Home Parks
  57 UNIT MOBILE HOME REMTALS (31 MOBILEHOMES, 24 MINI-WHSES, 1 APARTMENT, 1 HOUSE) SITUATED ON THE BANKS OF THE OOSTANuLA RIVER IN THE SHADOWS OF FORT MOUNTIAN IN NW GEORGIA WITH A CENTRAL LOCATION, CONVENIENT TO SHOPPING, I... 
 $1,675,000 
 For Sale 
DALTON, Georgia 
 Ted Thompson Landmark Realty of GA., Inc. 
 
 9.5 acres, zoned commercial, Columbia County, Georgia Commercial
Development Land
 Hottest suburban market in Georgia! Double road frontage. Perfect for banks, gas station/fast food, daycare, lifestyle retail center.. Will sell all are part. $250,000 per acre. Sewer, water, and all utilities on site. VIP REALTY SERVICES, INC. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 JOHN H. CAPES 
 
 Land Mableton GA Commercial
Development Land
 Land 8.69+/- acres Mableton . GA 30126 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Charles E.Collins 
 
 Augusta Richmond County Georgia on Ft Gordon Highway at I-520 Commercial
Development Land
 4.4 acres of commercial land all utilities ideal for Motel, Restaurant, Automotive, Mobile Home Sales Price at $80,000 per acre 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Jim Reeves 
 
 Industrial for sale: 38 acres zoned Heavy Industrial Commercial
Development Land
 16,000 square foot building equipped with 1, 2, 6 Ton overhead cranes, includes 15 acres for further development, located at 1661 Dixon Airline RD in Augusta GA 30906 Priced at $490,000 recent appraisal of $560,000 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Georgia 
 Jim Reeves 
 
 Development Property -Hilo Town on the Big Island Commercial
Development Land
 Just above historic downtown Hilo, 4 blocks above the bayfront this 46,000 square foot lot is zoned RM-1 allowing for a multi-residential unit for every 1000 square feet of land. Condominium, apartment complex, care facility...lots of possibilities. Locat... 
 $890,000 
 For Sale 
Hawaii 
 Donna Duryea R (S) 
 
 Hawaii Multi-Family Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 One of 3 multifamily zoned parcels offered by same owner individually (or together for $21,512,950) aggregating approximately 64.256 acres. Parcel 29 (4.6 acres) and Parcel 37 (2.301 acres) and a roughly 27.746 acre portion of parcel 32 (57.355 acres tota... 
 $2,070,000 
 For Sale 
Hawaii 
 Lee Pappernow 
 
 Hawaii Multi-Family Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 One of 3 multifamily zoned parcels offered by same owner individually (or together for $21,512,950) aggregating approximately 64.256 acres. Parcel 29 (4.6 acres) and Parcel 37 (2.301 acres) and a roughly 27.746 acre portion of parcel 32 (57.355 acres tota... 
 $18,407,050 
 For Sale 
Hawaii 
 Lee Pappernow 
 
 Hawaii Multi-Family Development Opportunity Commercial
Development Land
 Very rare, inexpensive multi-family development opportunity in Waikoloa Village. RM-1.5 zoning allows for approximately 29 units per acre. Seller says sell IMMEDIATELY so price reduced by over 60% - now only $250k per acre (a steal as the last comparable ... 
 $819,000 
 For Sale 
Hawaii 
 Lee Pappernow 
 
 3000 acre mixed use land w/ geothermal acquifer Commercial
Development Land
 Currently the land is being used a ranch with more than 500 head of cattle, the possibilities are endless. For starters the land is ideally suited for an all &quot;green&quot; planned community with a golf course and year round water park. In addition, the geotherm... 
 $90,000,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 David Dina 
 
 Perfect Commercial Corner Commercial
Development Land
 Price Reduced from $725,000 New price is $2.00/SFC Close to new YMCA, Schools and Walmart center. Perfect location for C-Store, or retail center. Have plans drawn up for a 30,000 sq.ft. retail center. Has a Development agreement in place for 4 commercial ... 
 $495,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Amanda Alvaro The Real Estate Group 
 
 37 Acres **EXIT LOCATION** Commercial
Development Land
 This extraordinary development property is located right off the North side of Interstate 84 in Hammett, Idaho, Elmore County, 62 miles southeast of Boise, and 19 miles southeast of Mountain Home. The property consists of a total 37 acres of which 25 acre... 
 $925,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Ross Farris 
 
 Ind/Comm Development Land in Sandpoint Id. Commercial
Development Land
 Vacant land zoned light Industrial with city sewer/water, 3phase power, natural gas available. This property features over 1000 feet of frontage on City paved street and contains 3.32 acres with 2.65 acres net buildable. Located adjacent to BN R/W. This i... 
 $599,900 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Carl White 
 
 NOW Opportunity. Commercial
Development Land
 PRIME location for Winery&amp;Vineyard development on &quot;Cool Road&quot; in Idaho! Land offers rich farming soil and resides in an existing Wine producing area. 60 acres w/Water Rights, near proposed &quot;Scenic By-Way&quot;&amp;Winery Tour. Area wineries are; &quot;Hells Canyon,... 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Paul Greenfield 
 
 Mini-Storage Development LAND Commercial
Development Land
 Priced below market, this &quot;Industrial&quot; property offers PRICE and LOCATION. Potential Mini-Storage development, near the I-84 interchange and within city limits. Conceptual site plans avaliable. Other possible uses; &quot;RV Park&quot; or &quot;Mixed Use&quot; project. Call o... 
 $299,500 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Paul Greenfield 
 
 Potential Commercial Corner-Meridian HWY Commercial
Development Land
 This corner has many possibilities for the right buyer. Zoned RR, currently Ada County, but in Kuna City Future Comp Plan. 7.92 acres corner of Columbia and Meridian HWY. Sale subject to pending easement to be recorded allowing future access through W bor... 
 $1,250,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Laree Goodman The Real Estate Group 
 
 AUCTION Nov 8: Pre-Plat Approved Sub-Meridian, ID Commercial
Development Land
 $1.9M Minimum bid at Auction Thursday November 8, 2007 11:15 AM MST on site and online. Approved pre-plat status means two and a half years of work has been done for you! The next steps are to have a construction meeting and start digging. 20 acres = 61 L... 
 $1,900,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Chris Knight 
 
 COMMERCIAL LOT IN PRIME OSBURN LOCATION Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial lot in PRIME location on Mullan Avenue in Osburn. Ideally situated across from the gas station with drive-in access from two streets, this would be ideal for an espresso stand or a commercial building. City sewer and water available. 
 $59,000 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Jill Dorsey 
 
 Bonneville County commercial land Commercial
Development Land
 +-100 total acres, 32.85 parcel including a 5000+ square foot executive home, fully landscaped, 3 car garage with a 2000 s.f. detached shop. Abundant water rights on all five parcels. Large pond. First right of refusal on two additional contiguous parcels... 
 $8,624,880 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Sharon Schindler Market Real Estate 
 
 Acres In Coeur D Alene Id Commercial
Development Land
 3.124 acres, SE corner 5 lane Prairie Ave and Atlas Rd Coeur d Alene Secondary 4.6 acres available also $ 1,700,000Chuck Taylor, GRI 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Chuck Taylor 
 
 40 Acres In Chilco Id Commercial
Development Land
 Chilco 40 acres 7 miles north of Hayden on Old Hwy 95 with H2O main on south boundary, timber exemption $450,000 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Chuck Taylor 
 
 34.7 Acre Neighborhood Center Commercial
Development Land
 The property is: 34.7 acres within the City of Nampa, Idaho impact area. It is zoned as one of 7 Neighborhood Centers in the city. Neighborhood Centers allow for medium to high density residential mixed with some commercial. It is priced at $2,800,000.00.... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Tom Betzold 
 
 Lot 4 Blk 1 Thayer St, Rathdrum, ID 83858 Commercial
Development Land
 List #06-13120 Prime Light Industrial location in Rathdrum. Huge 90 x 308 (.64 acre)lot with all utilities available. Open and level. Great location to start or move your business. Potential Unlimited! All City utilities available in the street. Final pla... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Sally Deucher 
 
 Booming Boise, ID opportunity! $7,837,500 ($95,000/acre) Commercial
Development Land
 82.5 acres with commercial and residential development possibilities. Over 2200&apos;of frontage on major East-West arterial. Potential to double or more in value in 1-3 years. Best Places to Live, Boise #8 - Money Magazine, 7/2006, Best Places for Busine... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Trina Cummins Baum 
 
 Nampa, Idaho 3.8 acres would be great for an assisted living facility, apartments or town homes Commercial
Development Land
 On the edge of town but within a couple miles of hospital, shopping and adjacent to a 10 acre commercial retail project on the corner that will be a large strip mall. Seller could rezone for commercial use and would be good for medical or business offices... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Idaho 
 Kecia Mortenson 
 
 Bloomington Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 The site contains 23 acres. The subject is near to Highway I-57, I-74. I-72, and US-150 and adjacent to Corporate Park Centre a professional office centre that includes amenities such as a landscaped lake with fountain, and state-of-the-art OCB broadband ... 
 $2,504,700 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Alex Ruggieri 
 
 International Parkway Commercial
Development Land
 The subject property is located on the side of the I-72 interchange furthest from the bulk of the city. It has frontage on the I-72 access ramp, Wabash, and frontage with access on Rising Moon Road The site contains an estimated 11.98 acres and is irregul... 
 $2,495,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Alex Ruggieri 
 
 Development site for sale in Algonquin Commercial
Development Land
 Approx. .25 acre zoned B-1&amp;ready to develop. Agent has interest. MLS #06135469 
 $85,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Michael Markowitz Paramount Commercial Properties 
 
 Excellent Location for a Car Wash Commercial
Development Land
 Everyone loves a clean car and this is the ideal location for your very own Express Style Car Wash. Currently the .8 acre parcel is wooded and fronts Grand Ave. in Lindenhurst, Il. Grand Ave. is the main E. to W. roadway connecting the I94 tool way on the... 
 $426,500 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Matkovich 
 
 3 Acres of Prime Commercial Development Land Commercial
Development Land
 2 individual parcels side by side owned and operated by the same owner and currently zoned R3, the first parcel is 1.96 acres in size and has a single family home built in 1900, the adjoining parcel is 1.04 acres in size and has a Montessori school which ... 
 $1,725,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Matkovich 
 
 Redevlopment opportunity for sale Commercial
Development Land
 This property is ready to develop. Lot is zoned C-2 in the city of Mundelein. New Lake County sewer line across Rt. 83 from property. Agent has interest. 
 $420,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Michael Markowitz Paramount Commercial Properties 
 
 Development land for sale Commercial
Development Land
 B-1 zoned and ready for you to develop. Drawings on file for a proposed mixed use commercial building for this lot. Agent has interst. 
 $85,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Michael Markowitz Paramount Commercial Properties 
 
 Sites/BTS&apos;s in NEW Heavy Ind&apos;l Park near Rockford Commercial
Development Land
 3-70 ac. CN rail-served heavy ind&apos;l sites for sale/BTS to users/operators in new 145-ac. (expandable) Mill Race Ind&apos;l Park. Part of 5,000-ac. TIF District. Located 25 min. west of Rockford. I-39 Logistics Corridor location w/quick access to inters... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Sandra Griggs 
 
 2 Acre pad - Costco development Commercial
Development Land
 2 acres zoned B-2. Directly adjacent to Costco. Lowes in same development. Neighbors to numerous banks and restaurants. Near corner of Randall Rd&amp;Algonquin Rd. Randall Rd has 40,000+ VPD. Algonquin Rd has 30,000+ VPD. Village was enthusiastic for office... 
 $1,450,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Michael Fisher 
 
 Commercial land Route 64 Eastside Commercial
Development Land
 1.25 Ac on Rt64 zoned BL(very open)Buildings on site but value in the Development Potential. Great for Restaurant,strip center,auto repair/oil/detailing,etc.,Room for parking. Huge traffic count Features: Price: $749900 Status: Active Property Type: Comme... 
 $749,900 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 John Hoshaw 
 
 Commercial Corner at Major Intersection Commercial
Development Land
 1.26 acres B-1 Commercial land on the SW corner of IL Rt. 47 and IL Rt. 64. Land is improved by an operating, 840 SF restaurant building that seats 35. High traffic counts. Site is Appx. half way between I-90 and I-88 and is popular with locals, commuters... 
 $995,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Paul Miessler 
 
 160 Acres, 369Single Family Lots Commercial
Development Land
 369 lots at $21,000 per site. Zoned, Annexed with prelimninary plat approved. Sewer coonection per site $4,200. Possible buy in phases. No impact fees. Possible 50% financing to right buyer. See other listings for multi-family, residential&amp;commercial. T... 
 $21,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Koreba 
 
 21 Acres, 10.5 Multi-Family&amp;10+ Acres Commercial Commercial
Development Land
 21 Acres, 84 multi-family sites on 10.5 acres. $9,000 per site. Zoned, Annexed, Preliminary Plat approved. Buyer to complete final platting&amp;construction of sites. Sewer connection $4,200 per unit. 10.7 Commercial acreage. 10 minutes North of I-90&amp;Rt 2... 
 $9,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Koreba 
 
 200 Acres, 293 Single Family sites, 134 Multi-fam Commercial
Development Land
 293 Single Family residential sites, at $16,000 per site. 134 multi-Family sites at $7,000 per unit. 18.8 acres Commercial at $2.00 per sq/ft. Sewer fees $2,244 per residential unit. Very hot area of the I-39 Corridor, just West of the I-39&amp;Baxter Rd. I... 
 $16,000 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Koreba 
 
 10.7 Acres zoned C-3 Commercial Commercial
Development Land
 $2.00 per sq/ft. 10.7 acres Zoned&amp;Annexed, C-3 Commercial. Sewer&amp;water. Buyer to complete final platting&amp;improvements, or buy just &quot;minimum&quot; acre possible. Hot expanding area of Poplar Grove. 10 minutes North of I-90&amp;Rt. 20, Belvidere. See other l... 
 $2 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Ken Koreba 
 
 11.9 Acre Retail Development Parcel Commercial
Development Land
 *High-identity CORNER Sheridan Rd. (at Russell) location. *598&apos;of Sheridan Rd. Frontage. *Zoned retail; might support mixed-used. *Excellent demographics. *Motivated seller. 
 $2,979,500 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Sandra Griggs 
 
 Commercial Lot In Chicago Commercial
Development Land
 9 Consecutive lots on high traffic area. In the heart of Halsted redevelopment area. Great location for business. Lot is 225x106. Seller will look at all offers!!! 
 $499,900 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Irena Manojlovic 
 
 18.51 Acres B-3 Commercial Land, Yorkville Il Commercial
Development Land
 18.51 acres of raw, but level, Commercial land. Incorporated into City of Yorkville and zoned B3. Located on the west side of Rt 47, just south of the Rt 71 intersection. Situated between I-88 and I-80. Kendall Co. Is listed as being the third fastest gro... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Paul Miessler 
 
 Vacant Commercial Lot Commercial
Development Land
 1.15 Ac, 51000 sf zoned B3. This is zoning for office or retail and allows for a 30000 sf building. ( lot line setbacks must be met). All utilities at the lot line, Adjacent to developed strip mall. This lot sold 15 years ago for $325,000 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Gus Monahu 
 
 Commercial Lot, Sparta IL Commercial
Development Land
 2.34 acre commercially zoned lot on highway frontage of northtown Sparta, IL just minutes from World Shooting Complex. All utilities available at property.Next door to local airport. Great location for hotel/motel, restaurant, stripmall, office complex, e... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Geri Birkner 
 
 Vacant Land. Great opportunity to build Commercial
Development Land
 $210,000. Can be developed into a 4-Story mixed use building with 1,250 sq ft Retail/Commercial space and 4 apartments or condominiums. For more information please call L.A.! CALL TODAY! 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Illinois 
 Jasper Mangiaracina 
 
 0 Main St. Commercial
Development Land
 Unique wooded building site near Westside Park. The lower part of the property is in the flood plain. The boundary survey shows 4.07 acres and runs to the center of the creek. 
 $99,800 
 For Sale 
Greenwood, Indiana 
 Jimmy Johnson REALTY WORLD-Harbert Company, Inc. 
 
 Acreage - Southern, Indiana Commercial
Development Land
 (High Traffic commercial area up and coming in Newburgh Indiana, within 5 miles of Evansville IN) Price: $525,000 Description: Fantastic property with 860&apos;+/- road frontage on Hwy 66 less than 1 mile East on 261. This property is zoned R-3 and is eli... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Indiana 
 Charlie Butler 
 
 Land 11.98 Acres Springfield IL $2,495,000 Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent Commercial Development Opportunity 11.98 Acres Fully Buildable No Additional Detention Required Zoned I-1 Light Industrial All Utilities Available 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Indiana 
 Alex Ruggieri 
 
 ATTENTION: INVESTORS&amp;DEVELOPERS Commercial
Development Land
 PRE-MLS OPPORTUNITY 250&apos;x 300&apos;in Downers Grove Location- 3 ? blocks to train station/downtown 5532 Main Street 5540 Main Street 2 large lots with a potential for a 4 lot split, guaranteed 3 lot split. Lot 1 - Approx: 120 x 300 Lot 2 - Approx: 13... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Indiana 
 Andrew J Horn 
 
 Roughly 5 Acres of General Commercial zoned property Commercial
Development Land
 East Alton/ Bethalto/ Woodriver IL access area. It is located at the new 255 Interchange area across from Civic Memorial Airport. Has road frontage on Wesley Ave which recently was built as access to area new super Wal-Mart Center. Some suggestions from t... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Indiana 
 Marge Haworth 
 
 Aurora IL Major development opportunity! Commercial
Development Land
 Property is located in the middle of many major developments. Build 6+ story residential and commercial project in a TIFF district. Other projects have foundations in and sales centers open! River St. in Aurora is undergoing a major redevelopment with mul... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Indiana 
 Richard Hartian 
 
 DES MOINES IOWA COMMERCIAL SITES - Various Pricing Commercial
Development Land
 Multiple Commercial Sites in Des Moines, Iowa. From under 1 acre to over 3 acres. Excellant exposure and access. Unique locational features with Great Traffic Flow. These sites are zoned for, Retail, Office, and/or Multi-Family. One retail parcel with new... 
 $800,000 
 For Sale 
Iowa 
 Kevin J. McRoberts 
 
 New Store Site Commercial
Development Land
 Excellant Exposure and Access. Across from Regional Mall. Across from High School, Middle School, Elementary, New Walgreens. 4-Lane with full in-out both directions. Any size up to 3.7 acres. Buy all or part. $5 - $10 / s.f. Contact: Kevin J. McRoberts, B... 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Iowa 
 Kevin J. McRoberts 
 
 1399109 Commercial
Development Land
 Would make a great place for a strip mall or convience store. 
 $870,000 
 For Sale 
Kansas 
 Jerry Wesley Jerry Wesley Real Estate 
 
 Prime Land Commercial
Development Land
 44+ Acres Land ready for high end retail/office/mixed use development. West of this land is a newly developed 300+ Acres 18 Hole Golf Course development and on the North is multi-million Dollar City Center development starting end of 2007. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Kansas 
 Jerry Bajaj 
 
 Commercial ~ High Traffic Location Commercial
Development Land
 If you need a high traffic location, then this is it! Busy Commercial site offering approx. 1acre +/- with 156&apos;frontage on one of the most traveled streets in thecity of Ashland. Offering a 3 car garage&amp;small office building, with plenty of parking... 
 $154,900 
 For Sale 
Kentucky 
 Cindy Conley-Jones 
 
 Downtown Corner Lot ~ High Traffic Location Commercial
Development Land
 Approx.6 blocks from Kings Daughters Medical Center Hospital. LOCATION, LOCATION, LOCATION!!! Very high traffic corner lot. &quot;BUILD IT&amp;THEY WILL COME&quot;....Make this your next Great Business Opportunity! Offering an excellent CORNER LOT in a very desirable... 
 $249,900 
 For Sale 
Kentucky 
 Cindy Conley-Jones 
 
 I-64&amp;Rt. 180 9-Acres Prime Commercial Property Commercial
Development Land
 LOCATION...LOCATION...LOCATION!!! This property has great potential for business development. Location says it all, within 0.1 mile from I-64/KY 180 exchange&amp;Flying J&apos;s. Directly across the street is a recently built McDonalds&amp;Chevron Gas Station!... 
 $650,000 
 For Sale 
Kentucky 
 Cindy Conley-Jones 
 
 Indian Mountain Commercial
Development Land
 800 + or - acres with 7 coal seams including Blue Gem. Located in KY&amp;TN. Great for ranch, farm, lot development or coal mines. Recreational use such as 4 wheeler trails, walking trails, horse trails. Many uses 
 $1,850,000 
 For Sale 
Kentucky 
 Kent Sears 
 
 Land 4.62 Acres Hopkinsville KY $1,386,000 Commercial
Development Land
 Frontage on New Breathitt Parkway Heart of Hopkinsville Retail Area +/- 700 feet of Frontage 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Kentucky 
 Jeff Yeary, CCIM, SIOR 
 
 Covington LA, 9 acres Residential Commercial
Development Land
 Fronting on Military Rd with Little Bogua Falaya River in rear - Ideal for estate or could be development. 15 minutes from Causeway to New Orleans. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Louisiana 
 Bill McNeil 
 
 For Sale - About 2.14 acre corner lot Commercial
Development Land
 Busy intersection, 2 blocks from interstate exits, a couple of miles from the New Orleans International Airport. For more information 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Louisiana 
 Arvindkumar Parikh RE/MAX Affiliates 
 
 222 Acres for development, Sebago, Maine Commercial
Development Land
 Rolling hills and pastures. Timber $$$. Perfect for housing development or divide and sell off large or small tracts. Property contains an 1850&apos;s farm house and barn. Call or e-mail: 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Maine 
 Perri Lawler-KRE 
 
 R-3 zoned property near Aberdeen Proving Grounds Commercial
Development Land
 Beautiful,level land 4.2 acres near the back gate of APG.It has rare,desirable R-3 zoing. Approved for 5 units per acre by Harford county.This area is expecting 35,000 new jobs due to BRAC transfer in the next 3 years and 75,000 jobs in 10 years. GREAT IN... 
 $895,000 
 For Sale 
Maryland 
 Kay Macnew 
 
 Located only 1/10 mi from Walmart on RT 9 Commercial
Development Land
 Perfect place on very busy Route 9. Only 1/10 of a mile from the new Walmart. With over 30,000 cars great for a Strip Mall. Lot has 232&apos;frontage and 4.33 acres, Can be combined with # 70676814 to give you 464&apos;frontage and 8.66 Acres. Call today!... 
 $1,000,000 
 For Sale 
Massachusetts 
 Bob Wentworth RE/MAX Property Promotions 
 
 Possible Commercial Vacant Land Commercial
Development Land
 Possible commercial land. Also great for hunting, camping, recreational vehicles, and could possible harvest wood. Great location between South Haven and Kalamazoo on Old M43. 
 $86,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 David Rife 
 
 Rawsonville Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 Topography Flat. Rail access possible. Just south of Blackmore Rd. 
 $450,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 Pontiac Trail&amp;Wixom Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 Adjacent to Naccarato Industrial Park; all utilities on-site and railroad accessible; easy asccess to I-96 expressway;zoned Light Industrial. 
 $1,950,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 2570 Zam Parkway Commercial
Development Land
 Vacant Land. 5.50 acres zoned heavy industrial; flat topography; close to Pontiac Trail, Wixom Rd.&amp;I-96. $575,000. 
 $575,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 Gr. River&amp;Inkster Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 Office/Retail development opportunity; 11,710 Sq. Ft. Lot with 105 ft. frontage on Gr. River, zoned C-2. 
 $100,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 3rd&amp;Southfield - Land for Sale Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial Land. Main street exposure. High Traffic. Sewer, Electricity, Gas to sight. Approximately 3/4 acres @ $280,000.00 
 $280,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 1010 Rig Rd. - Harrison Acres Commercial
Development Land
 .63 acress @ $100,000. Main street exposure;corner lot of vacant land; will build to suit up to 5,000 sq. ft. Zoned Lt. Industrial; all utilities to site;joining 2 new industrial parks in the area. 
 $100,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 6.52 Acres - Michigan Ave&amp;Morton Taylor Rd Commercial
Development Land
 Price Reduced. 6.52 Acres. Commercial land for sale zoned G1; high-traffic location, lot size is 405x701. 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Michael Rose Coldwell Banker Commercial Ventura Properties 
 
 Lansing-Holt-Delhi Township Commercial
Development Land
 Prime piece of Commercial development land. Zoning is already in place. Delhi Township would welcome a big box user or any type of high quality commercial development. Ideal for Grocery store, pharmacy and other neighborhood service style stores. All util... 
 $13,000,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Mike Bone L.D. Clark Companies 
 
 Lansing, MI Apartment Land Commercial
Development Land
 We have 26+ acres of prime apartment land. Water, sanitary sewer and storm sewer available. Zoning is in place for multi family development. Land is actually located in Delhi Township, Holt, MI. Holt is growing bedroom community. 
 $1,000,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Mike Bone L.D. Clark Companies 
 
 PENTWATER, MI - 3.5A, Vacant Land, MultiFamily Commercial
Development Land
 Condo&apos;s, Apartments, or your own personal cottage. This property has already been re-zoned for MultiFamily use, recent survey, close to the Pentwater School. Utilities available at the road. 
 $125,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Sandy Bailey-Bristol 
 
 Residential or Commercial Bargain Commercial
Development Land
 In NE portion of Reed City, this .88 acre parcel abuts the rails-to-trails, on the SW corner of Sears and North Streets. Could be residential, multifamily, or commercial/light industrial per City approval. Nice high and dry setting with a few large trees.... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 David Ver Sluis 
 
 US31 N between Ludington and Manistee Commercial
Development Land
 Historical community &quot;hub&quot; property -1 acre on great corner with longtime history as gas/convenience/market. Tanks were removed, lot cleared and environmental work done by current owner in 97. Traffic count ~6000 cars per day. Zoning reverted to recreatio... 
 $45 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 David Ver Sluis 
 
 COMMERCIAL/RES INVESTMENT Commercial
Development Land
 FABULOUS LOCATION! JUST BLOCKS TO THE BEACH AND ALL OF HARBOR COUNTRY&apos;S AMENITIES.COMMERCIAL/RES ZONED-LARGE PARCEL 1.38 ACRES WITH POSSIBILITIES OF 3- RES-HOME SITES OR COMMERCIAL/BUSINESS LOTS. CURRENTLY THERE IS A SMALL COTTAGE ON THIS PARCEL THAT ... 
 $349,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Charlotte Lear 
 
 Ypsilanti, MICHIGAN-Restaurant/Hotel Pad sites Commercial
Development Land
 3 great commercial lots located off I-94 on the Whitaker Rd exit. There is a McDonalds on site, a Buffalo Wild Wings now under construction. perfect spot for a Bob Evans, or I-Hop or Applebees...Also great location for a Hotel like a Holdiay Inn Express o... 
 $525,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Mike Bone L.D. Clark Companies 
 
 2923 Coleman Road Commercial
Development Land
 High growth development area of East Lansing. Near Eastwood Towne center mall. Just south of the new Michigan State University Credit Union headquarters and Mercantile Bank. Zoned for office and mixed use development. Near two available parcels zoned for ... 
 $1,698,000 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Jim Caster Caster and Associates 
 
 30501 Orchard Lake Rd Commercial
Development Land
 ATTENTION INVESTORS&amp;DEVELOPERS! MAKE NO OFFERS UNTIL YOU CHECK OUT THIS UNIQUE OPPORTUNITY TO BUILD APARTMENTS OR CONDOS IN A VERY POPULAR FARMINGTON HILLS AREA! WALKING DISTANCE TO SHOPPING, DINING&amp;ENTERTAINMENT! CLOSE TO SCHOOLS&amp;X-WAYS! ZONED RC-2... 
 $339,900 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 GEORGE MICULICI 
 
 20 Acres, Shepherd, MI Commercial
Development Land
 Just listed 20 acres at the Shepherd exit off US 127 Highway on Blanchard Rd. Shepherd, MI. Easy off-on highway. Well and septic. Asking $300,000. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Patrick Frasco, MBA 
 
 1.3 acre corner parcel with 5340 SF operating restaurant. Commercial
Development Land
 NW corner or Mission&amp;Pickard, Mt. Pleasant MI. Over 30,000 cars/day; 80 parking spaces; F, F&amp;E negotiable. Owner may carry land contract or land lease. Asking $1,150,000. Contact agent for details: 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Patrick Frasco, MBA 
 
 20 acres of development property Commercial
Development Land
 at the Highway 127 Shepherd, MI exit. Great highway visibility. Potential rezoning - well and septic Asking $300,000. Contact agent for details. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Michigan 
 Patrick Frasco, MBA 
 
 103 Acres in Hanover MN Commercial
Development Land
 This could be where you build your dream home or development. Plat for 66+ sites has been pre-approved by city council. Site is 103.46 acres filled with rolling hills, wooded area, majestic views and lush natural landscaping. For more pics and information... 
 $1,800,000 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Sheila Sabas 
 
 Auction! 50+ Acres in Corcoran, MN Commercial
Development Land
 On-Line Only Real Estate Auction Bidding Ends on June 20th at 5P.M. XXX County Road 50, Corcoran, MN Please Feel Free to Inspect the Property at Your Own Convenience Directions to Property: County Road 50 just east of Eagle Ridge Road on the North Side of... 
 $1 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 RICK BERENS 
 
 Auction! 50+ Acres in Corcoran, MN Commercial
Development Land
 On-Line Only Real Estate Auction Bidding Ends on June 20th at 5P.M. XXX County Road 50, Corcoran, MN Please Feel Free to Inspect the Property at Your Own Convenience Directions to Property: County Road 50 just east of Eagle Ridge Road on the North Side of... 
 $1 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 RICK BERENS 
 
 NW State Hwy 371 (Prime Commercial Location) Commercial
Development Land
 PRIME COMMERCIAL LOCATION on east side of State Hwy 371, 4 miles south of Walker, MN near casino. 700&apos;of road frontage, 11.24 acres +/-, rolling to flat topography, some trees. Additional 12.04 acres adjoining property and 24.98 acres across highway.... 
 $399,900 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Helen Mankenberg 
 
 NW State Hwy 371 (Prime Commercial Location) Commercial
Development Land
 PRIME COMMERCIAL LOCATION on east side of State Hwy 371, 4 miles south of Walker, MN near casino. 650&apos;of road frontage, 12.04 acres +/- rolling to flat topograhy, some trees. Additional 11.14 acres available adjoining property and 24.98 acres across ... 
 $449,900 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Helen Mankenberg 
 
 NW State Hwy 371 (Prime Commercial Location) Commercial
Development Land
 PRIME COMMERCIAL LOCATION at Intersection 200&amp;371-Walker, Mn. 24.98 Acres on corner of busy intersection across from the Casino on Hwy 200. 591&apos;of frontage on Hwy 200 and 1255&apos;of frontage on Hwy 371. Walker needs a truck stop. Topography is wo... 
 $699,900 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Helen Mankenberg 
 
 Land For Sale Commercial
Development Land
 9.78 acres, site adjacent to Aldi&apos;s new 500,000 sq. Foot distribution center; regional access to I-35, I-94, and I-90; 20 minutes to Lakeville. Currently zoned Urban Reserve 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Jean Orhn 
 
 20 acres with great visibility! Commercial
Development Land
 Located just off US 127 at the North bound exit at Shepherd, MI. Possible commercial/industrial use subject to zoning change. Well&amp;septic. Asking $229,000. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Minnesota 
 Patrick Frasco, MBA 
 
 16 ac I-20 Frontage, Pearl (Jackson) Ms Commercial
Development Land
 16 acres, can divide, fronting I-20 frontage road, 103,000 traffic count, all utilities, across from Bass Pro, Sams, Atlanta Braves Farm Club Stadium, utilities at site; 2 minutes from intersection I-55 and I-20; zoned commercial 
 $4 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Bennett Chotard 
 
 Downtown Baldwyn Lot Commercial
Development Land
 Downtown Baldwyn Lot w/endless possibilities. .73 acre w/paved road frontage on 2 sides. Zoned Commercial. Doctor&apos;s office across the street. Surrounded by booming retail, 2 blocks to Hwy 45 exit road. One of few remaining Main St. &apos;Hwy 145&apos; buildable lot... 
 $22,500 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Hwy 45 property offering 38.83 ac of prime com. Commercial
Development Land
 Hwy 45 property offering 38.83 ac of prime commercial property. Baldwyn, Business Data: 34.9% Manufacturing, 100 miles from Memphis, 511 miles from Chicago. This location could be a perfect hub for distribution to the Southern region. Baldwyn offers media... 
 $1,941,500 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Developers! Investors! 72.5 ac. Commercial
Development Land
 Developers! Investors! Here is a once in a lifetime opportunity to continue the Gun Club Subdivision. We are offering 72.5 prime buildable acreage located at the end of Gun Club Rd, Tupelo. Make your move now! The Toyota Gold rush will need an abundance o... 
 $1,700,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Hwy 45 property offers 20 ac of prime commercial Commercial
Development Land
 Hwy 45 property offers 20 ac of prime commercial property. Baldwyn,MS, Business Data: 34.9 manufacturing,100 mi from Memphis,511 mi from Chicago. Could be perfect hub for distribution to Southern region. Baldwyn offers median resident age 35.5 yr, median ... 
 $1,000,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Hwy 45 property offers 10.8 ac of prime commercial Commercial
Development Land
 Hwy 45 property offers 10.8 ac of prime commercial property. Baldwyn, MS, Business Data: 34.9% Manufactring, 100 mi from Memphis, 511 mi from Chicago. Location could be perfect hub for distribution to Southern region. Baldwyn offers median resident age 35... 
 $540,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Commercial Opportunity! Hwy 45 Baldwyn, 5 acres Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial Opportunity! Hwy 45 Baldwyn, 5 acres with road frontage on Hwy 45 and Clearview Dr. Baldwyn home of Toyota&apos;s Auto Body was named one of NE MS fastest growing cities. MS 51st downtown beautification projects. Looking for a location with high... 
 $225,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Prime 3.99 commerical acres Commercial
Development Land
 Prime 3.99 commerical acres located in the heart of Baldwyn on busy Hwy 145 N.&apos;New Home of Toyota Auto Parts Manufacturing&apos;. 84 feet of road frontage on Hwy 145 and 284 ft on N. 2nd St. Baldwyn offers small town charm with all the city convenienc... 
 $180,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 1.89 acre Commercial Lot in Baldwyn Commercial
Development Land
 1.89 acre Commercial Lot in Baldwyn. Located of Hwy 45 N next to Baldwyn&apos;s Vistor&apos;s Center is a PRIME location for any type of business. This lot is located directly behind the Country Inn on a paved road. Baldwyn Community offers Level 5 schools.... 
 $166,800 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 Baldwyn Lot w/endless possibilities. .73 acre Commercial
Development Land
 Downtown Baldwyn Lot w/endless possibilities. .73 acre w/paved road frontage on 2 sides. Zoned Commercial. Doctor&apos;s office across the street. Surrounded by booming retail, 2 blocks to Hwy 45 exit road. One of few remaining Main St.&apos;Hwy 145&apos;b... 
 $30,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Ann Myers Cotland Realty LLC 
 
 438 acre casino resort Commercial
Development Land
 438 acres water front St Louis Bay zoned C-3 Resort Commercial District - marinas, condos, hotel, casino gaming,co-developer participation welcomed. 100+ aces uplands for master plan mixed use - approx 2 mls bay frontage with deep water access and close t... 
 $75,000,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 John C. Ellis, III 
 
 203 Lot Residential Development Commercial
Development Land
 342 acres all usable. Water, sewage, gas, electric, phone at property.Abundant water, minimum size lots 1/4 acre, phase 1 environmental done. Two industrial parks under development, ski resort, Painted Desert, Petrified Forest approx 1 hour away, 5600 foo... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Jerre Snider 
 
 Town Center in Pearl Mississippi 4.2 acres for sale Commercial
Development Land
 $ 1,200,000.Across the street from City Hall and Community bank. Additional property +-3 acres for sale. Bass pro Shop and Trustmark Park (AA Braves Baseball) opened last year and The Mississippi Head Hunters (arena Football Team) have made pearl their ho... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Frank Yekaitis 
 
 16 Acres Prime Commercial Property Commercial
Development Land
 16 Acres next to Wal Mart in growing community in East Central Mississippi. Sits directly across from largest and only public high school in Wayne County. Waynesboro is at the cross roads of Highways 45 and 84. Town needs entrepeneur to help develop with ... 
 $3,000,000 
 For Sale 
Mississippi 
 Barbara Sauls 
 
 Restaurant Sites for Sale in New Development Commercial
Development Land
 Lot #3I Restaurant of the Glaser Commons is a pad ready site located on the proposed (unnamed) public roadway which access is gained from State Highway 109 and leads to the new St. Louis Community College and the Wildwood YMCA. This approximately +/-28,85... 
 $1,010,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 Great Bank Site Location in Wildwood, MO Commercial
Development Land
 Lot #4F Bank of the Glaser Commons is a pad ready site located on the proposed (unnamed) public roadway which access is gained from State Highway 109 and leads to the new St. Louis Community College and the Wildwood YMCA. This +/-33,775 square foot lot ha... 
 $1,150,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 Restaurant Site for Sale in Wildwood Commercial
Development Land
 This 1.76 acre site features a &quot;Workplace&quot; zoning within the Wildwood Town Center. This zoning would accommodate retail, fast food or fast casual restaurant sites along with a wide array of other commercial uses. 
 $1,250,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 The Glaser Commons Retail Development Commercial
Development Land
 The Glaser Commons is a new proposed retail development located at the southwest corner of State Route 109 and Manchester Road in Wildwood Missouri. The site is located directly in front of the proposed St. Louis Community College and will feature over si... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 Retail Development Site For Sale Commercial
Development Land
 The Glaser Commons is a new proposed retail development located at the southwest corner of State Route 109 and Manchester Road in Wildwood Missouri. The site is located directly in front of the proposed St. Louis Community College and will feature over si... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 505 Acres in Branson Missouri Commercial
Development Land
 505 acres across from new 42M theater. Lake, beautiful creek, utilities. Development plan in place to include business association. 
 $10,000,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Stephen Lind 
 
 Development Land-Fastest Growing City in Missouri Commercial
Development Land
 Four acres of prime development ground for sale in Raymore, MO. Raymore is the fastest growing city in Missouri and 52nd fastest growing city in the United States. The ground is in between a brand new Lowe&apos;s and a new grocery store development. Owner ... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jeff Boyle Prudential CRES Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Hwy 40&amp;Hwy N Commercial
Development Land
 * 11 acres available * Excellent development site * Shadow anchored by Target, Shop N Save, JC Penny and Wehernberg Theaters * Located in exploding St. Charles County at I-64/40 and Hwy N in Dardenne Prairie * Easy access from new Hwy N interchange * Util... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jill DeLauter NAI Desco 
 
 86X Veterans Memorial Parkway (S. Outer 70) Commercial
Development Land
 * 1.2 acres planned commercial * Highly visible from I-70 with 319&apos;of frontage * Utilities to site * Graded * Easy access from I-70 * Sale price: $392,040.00 ($7.50 psf) 
 $392,040 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jill DeLauter NAI Desco 
 
 8.56 Acres at Progress Point Commercial
Development Land
 * Progress Point is St. Charles County&apos;s premier office park strategically located on I-64 at the convergence of Hwy K and Hwy 94 * Great opportunity for an office user * Home to CitiMortage&apos;s 5,000 employee regional headquarters, BJC&apos;s 72 bed... 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jill DeLauter NAI Desco 
 
 Maryland Heights Golf Course Commercial
Development Land
 New Golf Course in super great, central location at Westport Plaza, Maryland Heights/ super super location: Walking distance to PuJols Restaurant, Ozzies Sports Bar, Diedorf&amp;Harts Restaurant, Funny Bone Comedy Club and Many restaurants, Bally&apos;s and ... 
 $2,900,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Daryl Miller 
 
 For Sale 2 Acres Wentzville MO Commercial
Development Land
 2 acres located in very high growth area of Wentzville MO. Currently zoned agricultural with a home on site. Ideal for institutional, church, contractor supply and more. 
 $298,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Dolora Beckerle 
 
 Truman Road Commercial
Development Land
 This 3.15 acre is situated to obtain excellent visibility from eastbound or westbound Manchester Road. Priced very competitively at $10.95/ft with surrounding commercial land opportunities, this site affords great accessibility as well as a signalized int... 
 $1,502,493 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Charles Onge St. Onge Management&amp;Exchange Corp. 
 
 Broker/Member Commercial
Development Land
 Have For Sale .50 acres of commercial land located at a signalized intersection in St. Peters, Missouri and is adjacent to Midrivers Mall, Maytag Store, Circuit City and many National retailers and restaurants! Ideal freestanding retail or office uses in ... 
 $395,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Scott Sacco 
 
 Broker/Member Commercial
Development Land
 Have For Sale, 1.87 ac outlot to a shopping center fronting on I-70 South Service Rd. at Exit 208 in Wentzville, MO. This site is zoned Highway Commercial and has all utilities available and can be subdivided. Ideal site for a sit-down restaurant, retail ... 
 $569,900 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Scott Sacco 
 
 Owner Commercial
Development Land
 HAVE FOR SALE: 47.60 ac of multi-family development land ideal for senior housing, apartments, townhomes, cottage homes or villas. This ground has been zoned and the site plan has been preliminary approved by the City of Kansas City, Missouri for 338 unit... 
 $2,700,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Scott Sacco 
 
 Commerical Developemnt Land Commercial
Development Land
 1.5 ACRES M/L ON BUSY U.S. HWY. GREAT LOCATION FOR MCDONALDS, C-STORE, STRIP CENTER 
 $829,900 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 WILLIAM M MEEK 
 
 Commerical Developement Land Commercial
Development Land
 9 ACRES, WITH UTILTIES, HIGH TRAFFIC AREA, IN THE FASTEST GROWING COUNTY IN MIDWEST. ROAD ACCESS TWO SIDES. 22000 CARS PASS THIS WAY EACH DAY 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 WILLIAM M MEEK 
 
 Lake View Building Lots Commercial
Development Land
 14 different building lots with a great view overlooking Table Rock Lake near Branson Missouri. Prices ranging from $80,000 to $200,000. All utilities underground, plaved and curbed streets, ready for builder. Restricted to nicer high end homes. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jim Robertson 
 
 Branson Missouri Commercial Properties Commercial
Development Land
 8 lots zoned commercial with frontage on State Hwy 176 Suitable for medical clinic, auto services, deli, or other. Buy all 8 for $120,000 cash. This property and other great opportunities in a booming area. Unprecedented growth in this tourism driven econ... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Jim Robertson 
 
 800&apos;+ Frontage on Interstate 40, St Charles, MO Commercial
Development Land
 .25 mile to Target/Wal-Mart, 1 mile to Winghaven Interchange. Easy ground w/all utilities available. Great visibility. Strong demographics. Surrounded by retail, technology and housing. Growth minded municipality. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Missouri 
 Brenda Lowder 
 
 I-90 FRONTAGE DEVELOPMENT POTENTIAL $6.97/SF Commercial
Development Land
 DEVELOPMENT HIGHLIGHTS: Price Reduced to $649,995 ($6.97/SF) 2.137 Acres Located at I-90 Interchange&amp;North 19th Street Highest and Best Visibility in Bozeman Ideal Site for Retail, Restaurant&amp;Office Pad Site Option to Annex into City Prime location ne... 
 $649,995 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 JOE COBB Grubb&amp;Ellis | Montana Commerical LLC 
 
 17.5 acres Commercial land Commercial
Development Land
 1/4 mile of lighted Hwy 93 frontage with turn lanes on each end.17.5 acres in two trscts can be divided to accomodate several businesses. Priced at $2.33 per square foot here is an opertunity to invest in the future of a growing community on Flathead Lake... 
 $1,775,000 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dick Matejovsky 
 
 Gold Mine Commercial
Development Land
 5 patented placer gold claims located inside National Forest, water rights on 3 streams, gated access, 340 acres of trees and meadows. This is an excelent location for a hunting lodge, dude ranch or corporate retreat. The bulk of this property is situated... 
 $2,750,000 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dick Matejovsky 
 
 2.2 +/- acres mixed use corner lot with exposure Commercial
Development Land
 Go see this corner 2.166 acres that can be used for commercial purposes or build a home or up to 4 units. Perhaps build home and open up shop both. It has I90 and Hwy 10Exposure. Great for Mechanics, Storefront, or shop. Only access is off Collins. 
 $285,000 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Chase Natalie Prudential Montana Real Estate 
 
 2.61 Acres Valley Center Commercial
Development Land
 Price $18/SF + SID&apos;s and assessments. Pad sites for two restaurants with drive-ins or building up to 9,000 SF. Includes 120+- parking spaces. Located on I-90 and Valley Center5 lane, next to 5 new motels and Outback Steakhouse. Last lots available on ... 
 $18 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dennis Hardin Hardin&amp;Company, LTD 
 
 3 Acres North 27th Ave Commercial
Development Land
 ONE OF 3 LOTS AVAILABLE ON N 27TH AVE CLOSE TO I-90 INTERSTATE, NEAR MAJOR SHOPPING CENTER AND 5 NEW HOTELS AND OUTBACK STEAK HOUSE. Seller is a licensed Real Estate agent. Commission paid after referal fee deducted. 
 $977,365 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dennis Hardin Hardin&amp;Company, LTD 
 
 9 Acres North 27th Ave. Commercial
Development Land
 ONE OF 3 LOTS AVAILABLE ON N 27TH AVE CLOSE TO I-90 INTERSTATE, NEAR MAJOR SHOPPING CENTER AND 5 NEW HOTELS AND OUTBACK STEAK HOUSE. Seller is a licensed Real Estate agent. Commission paid after referal fee deducted. 
 $3,260,433 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dennis Hardin Hardin&amp;Company, LTD 
 
 N 27th Ave Commercial
Development Land
 ONE OF 3 LOTS AVAILABLE ON N 27TH AVE CLOSE TO I-90 INTERSTATE, NEAR MAJOR SHOPPING CENTER INCLUDING COSTCO, TARGET, ROSS, STAPES, PETSMART, BOB WARDS AND 5 NEW HOTELS AND OUTBACK STEAK HOUSE. LOT 1 IS MLS#142743. LOT 2 IS MLS # 142749. LOTS MAY BE PURCHA... 
 $1,155,609 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Dennis Hardin Hardin&amp;Company, LTD 
 
 Vacant Commercial Land Commercial
Development Land
 4.83 acres of commercial property with Hwy 2 frontage and Valley of the Moon. Great location for a commercial adventure. 
 $96,600 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Jan Sorenson Molly Montana Real Estate 
 
 Light Industrial Lots Next To Super Wal Mart Commercial
Development Land
 4.5 ACRES NEXT TO SUPERWAL MART IN RESERVE STEET AREA OF MISSOULA MONTANA. DIVIDED INTO FOUR PARCELS. REONTING ON 2 CITY STREETS CONTIGUOUS TO WAL MART IN HIGH TRAFFIC AREA. GREAT OPPORTUNITY TO BUILD AND DEVELOP LIGHT INDUSTRIAL PROJECT. 
 $1,250,000 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 TEX CATES 
 
 Commercial location of 18 acres prime development property Commercial
Development Land
 at $2.00 sq. ft. 800 feet hwy 93 frontage 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Lee Foss 
 
 Preliminary plat approval for 40 half acre lots Commercial
Development Land
 located 5 minutes from downtown Bozeman Montana on the desirable south side of town. $4,000,000.00 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Frederick M. Richards 
 
 Preliminary plat approval for 365 city lots Commercial
Development Land
 located in Manhattan Montana These are large city lots, 10K - 15K Sq. Ft. Property abuts high school grounds, location, location, location $11,500,000.00 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Frederick M. Richards 
 
 373 deeded acres with two spring creeks Commercial
Development Land
 two ponds and two irrigation ditches plus trees, wildlife and privacy All within 20 minutes of Bozeman Montana. $4,900,000.00 http://www.richardslandco.com/ 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Montana 
 Frederick M. Richards 
 
 Vacant Land Available- 2 acres-Niagara Falls Blvd. Commercial
Development Land
 3070 Niagara Falls Boulevard. TWO ACRES OF VACANT LAND, GAS LINES, SEWER ACCESS, ELECTRICAL ACCESS 319 feet of frontage on the Boulevard. 20,500 (2002) cars drive by every day. 239 feet of frontage on Mavis Drive. 
 $200,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Joe Giusiana Hunt Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Shopping Center Land Commercial
Development Land
 Great 25+- acres adjacent to US 395 in north Reno includes water rights 
 $10 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Ken Mattison 
 
 38.45 Acres Industrial/Commercial in N. Nevada Commercial
Development Land
 This parcel is zoned Industrial/Commercial with a level topography in a beautiful and Fast Growing Northern Nevada market. The property sits adjacent to the regional airport which has commercial expansion designs. The recently built 340 acre Carson Valley... 
 $4,187 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Josh Selleck 
 
 Pahrump Land - 68 Acres Commercial
Development Land
 Ideally located near Mountain Falls at the NEC of Golden Valley and Thousandaire Blvd. Zoned Mixed-Use.Parcel #45-101-05. T21S, R54E, Section 8 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Mark Schnippel 
 
 Providence Commercial
Development Land
 Intitled Multi family site within a Master Plan community. 
 $11,763,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Mark Schnippel 
 
 35.73 Acres General Commercial Land Commercial
Development Land
 This site offers users, developers and investors the unique opportunity to acquire a 35.73 acre retail development site in one of Northern Nevadas most vastly underserved markets. The property is strategically located between Reno and Carson City on U.S. ... 
 $9,180,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 7.3 Acres Commercial Zoned Land Commercial
Development Land
 Tremendous development opportunity strategically positioned at the convergence of U.S. Highway 395 and U.S. Highway 50 West in South Carson City. Site has an existing well occupied 346-unit mini-storage facility, and 94 Boat and RV storage sites. The site... 
 $7,936,435 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 1.57 Acres Tourist Commercial-Zoned Land Commercial
Development Land
 Terrific development opportunity strategically positioned off the newly constructed U.S. Highway 395 Bypass in North Carson City. The property is approximately 41.92 acres and zoned &quot;tourist commercial.&quot; The property is vacant with a significant amount of... 
 $895,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 41.92 Acres of Land for Sale Commercial
Development Land
 Terrific development opportunity strategically positioned off the newly constructed U.S. Highway 395 Bypass in North Carson City. The property is approximately 41.92 acres and zoned &quot;tourist commercial.&quot; The property is vacant with a significant amount of... 
 $8,995,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 1.46 Acres Commercial-Zoned Land Commercial
Development Land
 The offering provides a unique opportunity to acquire a mixed-use level land site located in downtown Reno. The land site is in a well established and redeveloping sub-market. The Reno Gazette Journal headquarters is to the east of the property across Sut... 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 1.47 Acres Mixed Use Land - north Reno Commercial
Development Land
 The 1.47 acre subject property is located just off of North Virginia Street, less than a mile north of the Bonanza Casino and approximately 2 miles north of the University of Nevada, Reno. Great location for and approved for: warehouse; outdoor storage; s... 
 $199,500 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Aiman Noursoultanova 
 
 Prime Downtown Henderson Land Commercial
Development Land
 This property is a 1.41 acre site with alley vacated and fully approved by the City of Henderson for the construction of a +/- 40,000sf office building with COH Redevelopment Owner Participation agreement in place. All utility approvals are in place and b... 
 $4,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Judy Henkens 
 
 TROP 42 Commercial
Development Land
 TROP 42 is a Casino/Hotel development and Resort Condo Hotel site. The site has County Use Approval for a 1500 Casino/Hotel on 21 acres of the site and up to 5000 Resort Condo Hotel units on the remaining 21 acres. FAA and McCarran airport height approval... 
 $498,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Flavio Ostolaza 
 
 Lake Mead Parkway Land for Development Commercial
Development Land
 13056sf Office/,1200sf residential temporary lease income of approximately $160,000 with NOI of approximately $90,000. Sale includes 7 parcels totaling 2.97. There is a possible contiguous 5.33 Acre with .28 City owned. Henderson Redevelopment funds may b... 
 $5,999,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Judy Henkens 
 
 46 W. Pacific Commercial
Development Land
 .13 acre on arterial street in the heart of Downtown Henderson Water Street District. Utilities on the property. Possible redevelopment funds with Henderson Redevelopement Agency. 
 $250,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Judy Henkens 
 
 27 Nevada Way Commercial
Development Land
 .27 acre on Boulder Highway frontage near the corner of Lake Mead&amp;Boulder Highway. More acreage possible. Currently has habitable residence on Nevada Way side of property. Includes 2 parcels of land 179-18-611-002&amp;179-18-612-001. Package available upo... 
 $650,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Judy Henkens 
 
 Parcel #179-18-310-140 Commercial
Development Land
 .33 acrea vacant lot located on the corner of Marine&amp;Atlantic in the heart of the downtown Henderson Water Street District Redevelopment core area. Zoned downtown core commercial and ready for your project. Redevelopment funds may be available for appro... 
 $350,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Judy Henkens 
 
 Prime Assisted/Independent Living Development Opp. Commercial
Development Land
 Prime opportunity to develop high-end assisted / independent living facility in Northern Nevada. Six acres, mixed use zoning, beautiful views, walking distance to shopping, medical, etc. Contact for more information. 
 $7,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Re&apos; 
 
 Master Planned Commercial Lot with Sahara Frontage Commercial
Development Land
 Approximately 4000 Sq. Ft. 50x80, Great potential, Sahara frontage, vacant land in both sides to make larger parcel, buyer&apos;s agent to verify all information. Property is located on Sahara Ave. between Frank and Lamont going W. on Sahara from Nellis Bl... 
 $96,900 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Eberth Mendez 
 
 Nellis and Vegas Valley Commercial
Development Land
 Exact Acreage To Be Determined by Survey Zoned C-2 (General Commercial) Property is part of a commercial subdivision and access easements are provided for from Vegas Valley Dr. and Nellis Blvd. Will build to suit or ground lease 
 $5,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato Amato Commercial Group 
 
 Tenaya and Azure Commercial
Development Land
 Acres: +/- 1.12 Zoned: T-C Average Daily Traffic Counts: 40,000 Projected Located near the 215 and 95 freeways Approved C-Store/Gas/Gaming/Beer&amp;Wine Excellent Design Opportunity Azure fast becoming New Commercial Corridor 
 $2,000,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato Amato Commercial Group 
 
 Palm and Olive Commercial
Development Land
 Lot Size: +/- .35 Acres Zoned: C-1, Approved for Convenience Store with Gas Pumps. 
 $650,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato Amato Commercial Group 
 
 Centennial and Commerce Commercial
Development Land
 Land Size: +/- 2.79 Acres Net May Sell all or part Build-to-suit available as well as Leasing options. Zoned: C-1 Neighborhood Commercial Approved for: -Convenience Food Store w/ Gas -Convenience Food Store w/ Drive Thru -Automated Car Wash -Automobile Se... 
 $4,600,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato Amato Commercial Group 
 
 .81 Acres- PRICED TO SELL - OUTSIDE OF QUANTICO MB Commercial
Development Land
 ATTENTION INVESTORS- GREAT LOT OUTSIDE QUANTICO MARINE BASE ON MAIN STREET IN THE TOWN OF DUMFRIES- GROWING AREA- NO AUTOMOTIVE SALES OR REPAIR NO GAS STATIONS- PERMITTED USES INCLUDE RETAIL, OFFICES, RESTAURANT, MIXED USED COMMERCIAL/RETAIL ALSO PERMITTE... 
 $475,000 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 MICHELLE MEYER 
 
 Land For Sale or Lease Commercial
Development Land
 Acres: +/- 1.12, Zoned: T-C Average Daily Traffic Counts: 40,000 Projected Located near the 215 and 95 freeways Lease Information: Lease Price: T.B.D. Lease Terms: 10 year, NNN Build-to-su Site Information: Approved C-Store/Gas/Gaming/Beer&amp;Wine Excellen... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato 
 
 Land For Sale Or Lease Commercial
Development Land
 Located on the Corner of Azure and Tenaya, 89130 Average Daily Traffic Counts: 40,000 Projected . Located near the 215 and 95 freeways Lease Information: . Lease Price: T.B.D. . Lease Terms: 10 year, NNN . Build-to-suit Site Information: . Approved C-Stor... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato 
 
 Land for Sale or Lease Commercial
Development Land
 4535 W. Russell Rd. Las Vegas, Nevada 89118 Suite 14 70 702.796.6519 Fax Sales Information: . Sales Price: $2,000,000 . Acres: +/- 1.12 . Zoned: T-C . Average Daily Traffic Counts: 40,000 Projected . Located near the 215 and 95 freeways Lease Information:... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato 
 
 Land for Sale or Ground Lease Commercial
Development Land
 Sales Information: . Sales Price: $2,000,000 . Ground Lease: $16,667 per month . Acres: +/- 1.24 . Zoned: C-1 approved for Gas Station/C-Store with Car Wash . Traffic Counts: 34,500 per day on Martin L King and 7,100 per day on Alexander . Contiguous to G... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato 
 
 Land For Sale Commercial
Development Land
 Sales Price: $675,000.00 NWC Palm&amp;Olive Las Vegas, NV 89104 . Lot Size: +/- .35 Acres . Zoned: C-1, Approved for Convenience Store with Gas Pumps. 2006 Popula- tion Estimate 24,583 249,671 Average HH Income $41,546 $48,624 Demographics Radius 1 Mile 3 M... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Nevada 
 Tony Amato 
 
 Londonderry, NH - 23 Acres on Route 102 Commercial
Development Land
 23 +/- acres on Route 102 - Much of land already cleared and flat. There are currently 2 tenants (month-to-month) that bring in $51,484 per year. Superb location near intersection of Route 128&amp;Route 102 (Nashua Road) as well as less than 2 miles fro... 
 $1,950,000 
 For Sale 
Londonderry, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 750 Acres Sand, Gravel and water w rail access Commercial
Development Land
 Rare unique property 3 parcels one with Rail access. Large deep water acquifer, 80,000,000-150,000,000 cu. yds of high quality sand and gravel deposits. Over 2 1/2 miles river frontage on the Ammonoosuc river. Long term reserves for sand and gravel operat... 
 $50,000,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Arthur Berlin 
 
 Hot Develoment area Commercial
Development Land
 12 acres - Located on New Hampshire Highway 11, just over town line from very busy Rochester, NH. - regional mega Wal-Mart approx. one mile - Has approved State of NH highway curb cut, plus long side frontage on private road. Lightly sloping upwards to re... 
 $600,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Andy Sullivan 
 
 Donovan Industrial Park - Two Lots Left Commercial
Development Land
 Donovan Park is a newly designed Commercial / Industrial park located just off of Exit 5, I-93. Public Water and Sewer are available at sites. Natural Gas and PSNH electric are available at street. Exit 5 is thriving with new developments and investments.... 
 $250,000 
 For Sale 
Londonderry, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 11.91 Acres on Londonderry/Manchester NH Line Commercial
Development Land
 11.91 +/- acres on Route 28 in Londonderry and South Willow in Manchester, NH. High traffic counts&amp;in dramatically growing commercial area. Property consists of 4 lots from 1 acre to 4.11 acres. Structures on some of the 4 lots, but value is in Route 28... 
 $2,950,000 
 For Sale 
Londonderry, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 Land Development Opportunity Southern NH Commercial
Development Land
 Bring your development to Swanzey. Perfect for warehouses, furniture stores and the list goes on. Excellent exposure on a state highway. 10.79+/- acres of commercial/industrial land. 3 pahse power at the street. Located on Rt. 10 within close proximity to... 
 $2,500,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Greg Johnson H.G. Johnson Real Estate 
 
 LAND FOR SALE Commercial
Development Land
 Located in the south westernly quadriant of exit 5, I-93. Perfect location for any operation that needs a high exposure commercial. Zoned properly for hotels, restaurants, car sales, retail and professional office uses. Visible from I-93 and Route 28. 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Giovanni Verani 
 
 Nashua, NH - Commercial Lot on Route 111 Commercial
Development Land
 Corner lot on Route 111 (East Hollis Road) in Nashua. Lot is next to McDonalds&amp;across street from Wendy&apos;s. 1.38 acres with very flexible zoning. Lot fully engineered as a new 104 unit residential facility is approved next door. Very high traffic cou... 
 $749,900 
 For Sale 
Nashua, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 Londonderry, NH - 5.34 Acres on Two Busy Roads Commercial
Development Land
 Great corner location. Located at Route 128 / Route 28. Lot is engineered for a two story 26,160 +/- SF retail/office facility. 5.34 acres of land on two state highways has many options for development. Located just off of I-93, Exit 5 and south of main t... 
 $999,000 
 For Sale 
Londonderry, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 Derry, NH - RARE 1 Acre Lot on Busy Route 28 Commercial
Development Land
 RARE 1 acre lot on Route 28 located at intersection of Route 28 and Bedard Ave. Affordable lots of this size are hard to come by on this heavily traveled road. Good topography and many uses make this lot an exceptional location for a new commercial buildi... 
 $211,000 
 For Sale 
Derry, New Hampshire 
 Scott Reiff Prudential Verani Realty 
 
 Premium Development Opportunity in Swanzey, NH. Commercial
Development Land
 LAND AVAILABLE Development Opportunity in Swanzey, NH. One of the most visible tracts of land in a newly developed area. Highly visible multi-use land available for $5.53per sq. ft. or $2,600,000 for the entire parcel. 10.79+/- acres zoned commercial-indu... 
 $2,600,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Greg Johnson H.G. Johnson Real Estate 
 
 Premium Development Opportunity In Swanzey, NH. Commercial
Development Land
 LAND AVAILABLE Development Opportunity in Swanzey, NH. One of the most visible tracts of land in a newly developed area. Highly visible multi-use land available for $5.53per sq. ft. or $2,600,000 for the entire parcel. 10.79+/- acres zoned commercial-indu... 
 $2,600,000 
 For Sale 
New Hampshire 
 Greg Johnson H.G. Johnson Real Estate 
 
 Commercial Lot near Pine Hill Golf Course Commercial
Development Land
 Great Location for building - across from the Pine Hill Golf Course and two major apartment complexes, The Mansions and Chalet! Great spot to start a laundry or food business to take advantage of clientele in the immediate area. Lot recently appraised for... 
 $250,000 
 For Sale 
New Jersey 
 Javier Rodriguez 
 
 Morristown NJ 1 BR Condo Commercial
Development Land
 FOR SALE - in town location - blocks to NYC direct train, shopping&amp;restaurants. This sunny condo has gleaming hardwoods and upgraded lighting. Kitchen has new stainless steel appliances&amp;countertop. W/D included. Move in condition. For more details con... 
 $269,500 
 For Sale 
New Jersey 
 Jamie Bracken 
 
 Highly Visible Location Commercial
Development Land
 This property has Excellent Frontage Visibility of 300 ft on Valley Drive with 1.4 acres. There are many possibilities for this site. Currently zoned M-2 with an application pending for C-3. This would include Restaurants, Retail Shops, Banks, Auto Servic... 
 $398,500 
 For Sale 
Las Cruces, New Mexico 
 Frank Paz DR Horton 
 
 Vacant Native American Lands Commercial
Development Land
 Various lots from 1 acre to 28 acres. A total of 66+ acres bordering Native lands in New Mexico. Can sell all or as little as 1 acre. Will carry REC with 20% down most any terms on balance. 
 $5 
 For Sale 
New Mexico 
 Andres Ramos 
 
 66 acres some on State Road 6 (old route 66) Commercial
Development Land
 Various parcels ie: 15/1.84acre lots located on highway frontage, 1/3.21acre lot located on highway frontage, 10/1.03 acre parcels w/road access,various 1+acre residential parcels, 1/3.31acre residential or comercial parcel, 2/2.5acre residential parcels.... 
 $8 
 For Sale 
New Mexico 
 Andres Ramos 
 
 land for development Commercial
Development Land
 30000 sq ft build able on major street in Riverdale Bronx. R6 Zoning with commercial overlay Call Broker for more details 
 $2,650,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Linda Lebowitz 
 
 6.2 Acres of Vacant Land- 2525 River Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 6.2 acre site for sale. Potential as a development site. Currently mixed use property. Frontage on the Niagara River with riparian rights. Great views of Niagara River and Grand Island. 
 $389,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Jane Munro Hunt Commercial Real Estate 
 
 2349 Goshen Turnpike Commercial
Development Land
 Prime property in the Medical area. It is close to the Orange Regional&apos;s $335M dream Hospital. The property has water and sewer and is close to the major highways. It is zoned for Office/Research and may be receiving approvals for a Senior overlay dis... 
 $7,000,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Jay Fienberg Century 21 Grand 
 
 3125 Niagara Falls Boulevard Commercial
Development Land
 19.97 acres zoned commercial. 468 frontage 1,600 depth. Flat terrain with some trees. Utilities located at street. NYS DOT- 20,570 cars daily. 
 $3,994,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Karl Puzio 
 
 171 Main Street Commercial
Development Land
 Currently there are three buildings on the property (used cars&amp;auto repair facility, liquor store and fast food restaurant) Excellent redevelopment parcel at key signalized intersection in Allegany, New York Ideal for drugstore, fast food, bank, etc. Up... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Robert Roller CB Richard Ellis Buffalo 
 
 1.2 Acre Development Site Commercial
Development Land
 2186-2202 Niagara Falls Blvd. 1.2 acre development site in very active commercial area. 245 ft. frontage by 209 ft. depth. 3 Parcels zoned commercial. Located less than 1/4 mile North of Interstate 290. Close proximity to 970,000 SF Boulevard Mall. Averag... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Derrick Pressley 
 
 Route 17M Commercial
Development Land
 A fully approved mixed use project consisting of 160 residential condo or apt. units with a clubhouse and 33,000 sq. ft. of commercial space on the ground level. Also included are two commercial pads, one at a hard corner light suitable for a Gas/Convenie... 
 $8,200,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Jay Fienberg Century 21 Grand 
 
 5542 Camp Road Commercial
Development Land
 .75 acres of vacant land for sale. Ideal Development lot for, medical, office, auto or any franchise fast food. This is an up and coming retail development area (Walmart). High traffic count on Camp Road: NYS DOT 27,378. All utilities on property. 
 $150,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Fred Occhino Hunt Commercial Real Estate 
 
 K-Mart Plaza Commercial
Development Land
 Highly Visible Hotel/Retail Site...3 to 5 acres at $60,000 per acre land lease per year. Traffic Count exceeds 120,000 cars daily. Located between the Syracuse Airport and Carousel Center/Destiny 
 $60,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 William Evertz 
 
 Commercial lot for sale. Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial lot for sale. Old Approval for 11,000 sq. ft building. Municiple Water, Sewer and Gas Available. 
 $525,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Heather Shields Century 21 Maxum Realty 
 
 0Corner lot on a dead end street Commercial
Development Land
 Corner Lot on quiet dead end street - nice neighborhood - Property needs engineering and may need some fill, bring all offers. 
 $80,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Olga 
 
 Million Dollar lake view, part 2 Commercial
Development Land
 Million Dollar lake view. Perfect for storage units. also being sold with the lot next door. 
 $62,500 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Heather Shields 
 
 Million Dollar lake view Commercial
Development Land
 Million Dollar Lake View, Perfect location for storage units...................many possibilities. Bring all offers..........Also being sold with MLS # 391670 
 $62,500 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Heather Shields 
 
 0 William Street near Transit Rd. Commercial
Development Land
 1.67 acres of vacant land. 220 of frontage. Excellent development opportunity for retail / medical complex. Located in a density populated residential area directly in front of Woodland Place Apartments. .5 miles east of Transit Road. All utilities at str... 
 $123,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Karl Puzio 
 
 0 Maple Street Commercial
Development Land
 Gorgeous 4.09 acre development parcel, just one block west of the Maple Street Exit of the Aurora Expressway/State Hwy. 400. Ideal site for an office user interested in a beautiful setting with immediate Thruway access. Located on a cul-de-sac directly ad... 
 $107,500 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Kristin Badger-Bach 
 
 K-Mart Plaza Commercial
Development Land
 3 to 5 acres available for Hotel/Motel/Rest/Retail Land lease or Build to suit, over 115,000 AADT located on exit to Rt81 in between the Airport and Destiny. $60,000 per acre on a land lease. 
 $0 
 For Sale 
New York 
 William Evertz 
 
 70 unit apartment site Commercial
Development Land
 Will sell with all approvals a 70 unit apartment site in Middletown, N.Y. Near shopping and major interstate.Excellent opportunity for developer. 
 $1,700,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 joel dropkin 
 
 Approved 184 unit multi-family site Commercial
Development Land
 25 acre site, fully approved for 184 rental units. All utilities to the site, asking 15,000 per unit. 
 $2,700,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 joel dropkin 
 
 104-110 Main Street, Macedon,NY -Developement Site Commercial
Development Land
 The property consists of 2.2 acres located on Rt. 31&amp;Rt. 350 in the Village of Macedon. Route 31 is a heavily traveled road between Rochester and Newark. The entire site includes 5 parcels, 4 of which are privately owned and 1 parcel that is owned by th... 
 $1,040,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Gregory Oehler 
 
 Commercial Development Project Near JFK Airport! Commercial
Development Land
 The site is a three-sided block front located at the intersection of 177the place, Farmer&apos;s Blvd&amp;Guy R Brewer Blvd. The development site has approximately 180 feet of frontage on Farmer&apos;s Blvd, 212 feet of frontage on 177th Pl and approx. 115 ft... 
 $5 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Sal Vinti 
 
 224 Acres Of Land To Develop Commercial
Development Land
 Development opportunities like this don&apos;t come along very often! 224 rolling acres of GORGEOUS land in Skaneateles, perfect for the right developer/homebuilder to create a new subdivision or golf course! Property has road frontage on 2 roads totalling... 
 $699,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Jon Alvarez 
 
 I-87 Exit 36 Plattsburgh New York Commercial
Development Land
 5.3 Acres Prime Commercial Development Site with Municipal Water/Sewer. Newly installed fiber-optic infrastructure. Busy interchange from I-87 Northway. North/South Trade Corridor for Montreal to NYC. Heavy traffic flow. Exit for airport, college, commerc... 
 $2,200,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Lewis Sanders 
 
 4 Commercial Lots For Sale - Watertown, NY Commercial
Development Land
 Arsenal St. is the place to run your business in Watertown City, NY. Build new at this graet location at the bridge! Entrance from Arsenal St. or Exchange St. under bridge. All utilities are already there! .64 of an acre - prime signage visibility! Restau... 
 $132,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 karen carson 
 
 Busy Tourist Corridor Vacant Lot Commercial
Development Land
 A 1.3 Acre Parcel located on busy Rt 28 between Oneonta and Cooperstown, New York. The lot is graded, has a curved driveway, drilled well. Perfect for convenience store, retail location, car lot, professional use. The area is a seasonal tourist route to t... 
 $69,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Patricia Wingate 
 
 30 Development Acres - Fort Drum Area, Ny Commercial
Development Land
 30 acres, mostly meadow, some trees, off Rte 37. One mile from Interstate 81. Zoned for housing and some business. Exit is Fort Drum Exit #48. Contact me for more info, pictures, tax map, etc. 
 $425,000 
 For Sale 
New York 
 karen carson 
 
 Zoned R7 / 40x100 Commercial
Development Land
 Zoned R7, Lot size 40x100 second to corner street. 2 Blks to &quot;7&quot; train. 
 $2 
 For Sale 
New York 
 RAy Aguilar 
 
 Watertown, Ny - Major Development Potential Commercial
Development Land
 Major Development Potential! 115.50 acres on high-traffic NYS Rt. 3 which runs between the Watertown Salmon Run Mall and new retail centers, (Kohls, Target, Petco, Bed Bath, Old Navy,and Beyond and more) new restaurants, Texas Road House,TGIF, Ruby Tuesda... 
 $749,900 
 For Sale 
New York 
 Cheryl Beecher-Zeldin 
 
 Catawba Valley Blvd. Commercial
Development Land
 1.76 acres near mall and community college.Additional acreage available joining this tract.Good location for many uses.$616,000.00 
 $616,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Dal Benfield Valley Properties LLC 
 
 Belhaven waterfront acreage Commercial
Development Land
 8 acres of in the coastal village of Belhaven,NC roadfrontage on main street. 800+ feet of deep water shoreline on Pantego Creek (Belhaven Harbor). Great location for marina/shops and multi-family development. Sellers looking for Quick sale. Zoned commerc... 
 $549,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Tim Powell 
 
 Land Available in Northlite Commons Commercial
Development Land
 5.5 acres available for $9.50/SF. Located at exit 60 on I-85 between Dale Earnhardt Blvd and Hwy 3. Anchors include Wal-Mart Supercenter, Kohl&apos;s, Sam&apos;s Club and Hobby Lobby. 
 $10 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Raquel Bliss 
 
 Prime 4.66 Acres on I-95 in Selma Commercial
Development Land
 EXPOSURE TO THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE 24 HOURS A DAY! OWNER MAY FINANCE! Land is located in Selma, Johnston County, NC. ATTENTION LAND DEVELOPERS: Are you looking for PRIME Interstate Land to develop a highly profitable Hotel, Gas Station, Factory or Auto Deale... 
 $1,300,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Dael Sidney 
 
 7589 Market St Wilmington, NC (Porters Neck Area) Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent development opportunity of a unique 3 acre tract in the middle of the high growth area of Porters Neck and Ogden. Approximately 290ft of highly visible frontage on Market St (Hwy 17) 
 $2,550,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Cody Cress 
 
 River Rd.&amp;Hwy. 321 Commercial
Development Land
 Out Parcels on Hwy. 321, at River Road exit. Excellent site for Convenience store, truck stop,fast food, or other. 
 $200,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Dal Benfield Valley Properties LLC 
 
 I-40&amp;Hwy 11 Wallace, Nc Commercial
Development Land
 Two tracts make up this 43.91+/- acre site at the inter-section of I-40 and NC Hwy 11 in Wallace, NC. City water and sewer are on the street. Voluntary annexation is require to tap into these utilities. Zoning is Highway Business (HB) from the Town of Wal... 
 $2,144,850 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Oscar Williamson 
 
 Commercial Acreage Commercial
Development Land
 Excellent development parcel for commercial or residential project. 5.35 acres in growing corridor off Interstate 26 near Asheville, NC. 
 $1,499,900 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Carol Kistler 
 
 6.0 Acres - Walkertown/guthrie Road Commercial
Development Land
 6.9 ACRES, ZONED FOR 144 UNIT MINI STORAGE FACILITY. PERMANENT EASEMENT ALONG RAILROAD FROM WALKERTOWN/GUTHRIE ROAD. 
 $285,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 CHRIS FRANTZ 
 
 2.84 Acres - 3201-05 Sandy Ridge Road Commercial
Development Land
 2.84 ACRES FRONTING ON MAJOR INTERSECTION IN FAST GROWING PIEDMONT TRIAD LOCATION. 400&apos;&amp;300&apos;ROAD FRONTAGE ON TWO SIDES OF THE CORNER WITH STOP LIGHT AND MULTIPLE CURB CUTS. ALREADY ZONED BUSINESS. AREA SURROUNDED BY INDUSTRIAL PARK AND GROWING ... 
 $850,000 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 CHRIS FRANTZ 
 
 North Carolina-between Murphy And Andrew, 144 acres Commercial
Development Land
 144+ acres with mountain views, rushing noisy creek, waterfalls, pasture. Main roads Cut in, electric already on property. Reduced to $10,500 per acre. On Main Highway, Surrounded by EBCI (Eastern Band Cherokee Indians) land on 2 sides. NEG 140000 Judy As... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Judy Aselton 
 
 Land 4.01 Acres Hickory NC $1,733,000 Commercial
Development Land
 4.01 acres retail entitled land Main&amp;Main location with stop light Entitlements and site plan already in place McDonald Parkway opened July 31, 06 Additional assemblage possible 
 $0 
 For Sale 
North Carolina 
 Jeffrey Mullis, CCIM 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Nice industrial lot with 2.21 acres. Zoned I-1 Industrial and located in Southeast Industrial Park Subdivision. Just minutes from downtown Bismarck. Uses include retail, service groups, truck terminal, utility groups, office, banks and much more. 
 $96,385 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Good commerical lot with 2.53 acres zoned I-1 Industrial. Level lot easy to build on. Lots of possibilities. 
 $110,152 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Nice commercial lot with 2.22 acres zoned I-1 Industrial. Located just minutes from downtown Bismarck. Uses include retail, truck terminal, service groups, utility groups, truck shops, storage,warehoue and more. Call Listing Agent for maps and more inform... 
 $96,753 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial land with Highway frontage. 2.22 acres in an excellent location for a convenience store. Zoned I-1 Industrial with uses such as retail, service groups, utility groups, truck terminal, office and banks and more. 
 $193,508 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Nice 3.3 acre Industrial lot zoned I-1. Located within minutes of downtown Bismarck. Uses include retail, service groups, convenience store, truck terminal, utility groups, office or banks, and more. Call Listing Agent for maps and more information. 
 $143,831 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Commercial lot in Industrial Park. 2.81 acres zoned I-1 with uses such as retail, gas station, service groups, utility groups, truck terminal, truck shops, storage, warehouse, office and banks. 
 $122,586 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Nice commercial lot in Industrial Park. 2.66 acres zoned I-1. Uses include retail, service groups, truck terminal, utility service groups, office or banks. 
 $135,935 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Good building lot in Industrial Park zoned I-1. Uses include retail, service groups, truck terminal, utility service groups, office or banks. 
 $105,073 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Commercial / Industrial lot Commercial
Development Land
 Nice level lot in industrial subdivision. Highway frontage just a few minutes from downtown Bismarck and on the edge of Lincoln, ND. Perfect for truck shops, warehouse and storage or convenience store. Call for maps and more information 
 $195,208 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Industrial Lots Commercial
Development Land
 Large 5.174 acre Industrial lot with good highway visibility. Located in growing area SE of Bismarck, North Dakota. 
 $169,026 
 For Sale 
North Dakota 
 Dennis Kaiser 
 
 Ashland, Ohio Land Commercial
Development Land
 30 +/- acres US Rte.250 at I-71 Interchange zoned Highway Commercial to 500 feet depth 
 $200,000 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 John Bourne 
 
 COMPUTERIZED DISPLAY SIGN +2.3 ACRES, I-75 Commercial
Development Land
 Location, Visibility and Accessibility with 110,000 traffic count. Shelby County, Ohio location at Exit 99. Contact Grover Rutter of Phil Cole Real Estate&amp;Auctions. 419-427-1564 
 $599,000 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 Grover Rutter 
 
 102 acres currently 9 hole golf course, Lodi, Ohio Commercial
Development Land
 102 Acres of land located just five miles from I-71 and I-76 interchange with 1/2 mile of frontage along route 224. Ideal opportunity for 1031/Development opportunity for mixed use opportunity. Contact Pete Hamo , Coldwell Banker Commercial, 330-414-7688 ... 
 $1,500,000 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 Peter Hamo 
 
 Maumee, Ohio - 3.93 acres Commercial
Development Land
 1600+ frontage on Alt 20 in the heart of arrowhead I-475 growth area. Beautiful private residence with over 4300 sq ft, pool, tennis courts, 8 stall horse barn. Maintain 1.5 acres for yourself and sell off 2+ acres frontage for professional offices. In ar... 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 Barb Lloyd 
 
 45 acres of land zoned for muti housing, St. Mary&apos;s, Ohio Commercial
Development Land
 Have 45 acres of land zoned for muti-housing..we are looking for high end active adult living developers! This property sits on Grand Lake St. Mary&apos;s in St. Mary&apos;s Ohio..... there is nothing like this in the area! Great need and desire for this ty... 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 Sheila Hirschfeld 
 
 Land 124.70 Acres Lima OH $1,495,000 Commercial
Development Land
 124.7 acres of newly platted single family lots Adjacent to Golf at Sugar Creek Area employment growth with Ford, P&amp;G;, Hospitals 
 $0 
 For Sale 
Ohio 
 Michael Leaventon 
 
 97 Acres Norman Commercial
Development Land
 97 Acres of prime developmental Property within Norman City Limits Neighboring corporate campuses include: Hitachi Computer Products, Yamanouchi Pharmaceutical Technologies, Shaklee Corporation, U.S. National Center for Employee Development, Saxon Publish... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Oklahoma 
 Debby Clark 
 
 Land for Sale Commercial
Development Land
 Close to Hotels. Current Zoning Residential, can be zoned Commercial, All utilities available 
 $135,000 
 For Sale 
Oklahoma 
 Kamlesh Aggarwal 
 
 82nd Avenue Redevelopment Land Commercial
Development Land
 2 acres Zoned C1&amp;EG2 land. Two locations:6302&amp;7227 SE 82nd Ave, Portland, Oregon. Currently leased $10k per month. Have site plan and preliminary design for office/retail and office/industrial. 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 mark zoller 
 
 Eugene, Oregon 3.22 Acres Subdividable Commercial
Development Land
 This level property is located in the rapidly expanding north Coburg Road area. North Coburg Road is increasingly attractive due to the easy access to the new River Bend Hospital and downtown Eugene. Two tax lots totaling 3.22 acres have been incorporated... 
 $1,400,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Vince Puleo 
 
 Prime Commercial Development Land Commercial
Development Land
 Freeway oriented commercial development project. 4.11 acres zoned to accommodate a mixture of retail services, restaurants, wholesale, lodging, RV park and light industrial. Property is located next to the Phoenix interchanges, Home Depot and La-Z-Boy hom... 
 $3,500,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Bob Methvin 
 
 OREGON NURSERY AND BUSINESS Commercial
Development Land
 SOUTHERN OREGON NURSERY: Rapidly expanding business in Klamath County Oregon on 205 acres with 340 acre private BLM lease. Plenty of room for trail rides. There are 2 homes, barn with tack room, machinery barn, work shop, KOI ponds, green houses and much ... 
 $1,922,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Burt Swingle 
 
 Oregon Coast Investment Property Commercial
Development Land
 A total of 14 acres with 4 acres ready to build, the balance is a nature area, suitable for dry camping, Yurts, nature trails etc. Was an old motel/restaurant torn down years ago, so the sewer permits have been maintained. Maximum permits approx. 44 for R... 
 $1,000,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Mark Smith 
 
 Hermiston Retail Development Land Commercial
Development Land
 Retail land in newly developing retail area; Three parcels are for sale, ranging from $887,796 - $3,305,000; Strong traffic counts and demographics; Serves entire Umatilla County market area; Immediately adjacent to Home Depot&amp;Super Wal-Mart; Outstandin... 
 $887,796 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Steve Mack Norris&amp;Stevens 
 
 Hermiston Apartment Land Commercial
Development Land
 1.60 Acres of Land in the 3800 block of N. Marine Drive; Zoned Heavy Industrial: City of Portland; Adjacent to two popular floating home communities; Located 1.2 miles west of I-5 interchange; all utilities to property. 
 $1,878,400 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Steve Mack Norris&amp;Stevens 
 
 1.60 Acres Industrial Land, N. Marine Drive Commercial
Development Land
 1.60 Acres of Land in the 3800 block of N. Marine Drive; Zoned Heavy Industrial: City of Portland; Adjacent to two popular floating home communities; Located 1.2 miles west of I-5 interchange; all utilities to property. 
 $750,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Steve Mack Norris&amp;Stevens 
 
 1.33 Acres of Office Land in Medical Complex Commercial
Development Land
 1.33 Acres of building-ready land zoned Outlying Commercial: City of Hermiston; Across from the Good Shepherd Medical Center in the Columbia Professional Plaza; Sidewalks and parking lot completed; All utilities to site. 
 $579,350 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Steve Mack Norris&amp;Stevens 
 
 80 acres w/Mixed Use - Cml, Ind, Res UGB w/Airport Commercial
Development Land
 6 tax lots in center of City of Sheridan totals 80.24 acres of mixed use. PRIVATE OREGON AIRPORT TOO! Mixed use is commercial, industrial and residential and portion is in City UGB boundary. Buyer to verify uses and potential with City of Sheridan and Yam... 
 $1,700,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Connie Knittel 
 
 Hood River Development Property Commercial
Development Land
 The last large (27 Acres) commercially zoned property inside the city limits of Hood River. Previously used as an RV/Trailer Park, this parcel was legally closedin 2003. Zoned C2. Dividable 27 acre commercial, residential, or mixed use. 
 $5,900,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Lynn Guenther 
 
 1/3 acre commercial land with concrete parking Commercial
Development Land
 1/3 acre commercial with concrete parking and some lighting installed. nearly ready to build your storefront or office building(s) seller may do a 1031 exchange 
 $269,900 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Jack Davis oregon realty 
 
 NICE 3 ACRE COMMERCIAL PROPERTY Commercial
Development Land
 Nice 3 acre commercial property. Sewer, water, power to property line. Buyer to assume LID. Property located across the street from proposed BI MART SHOPPING CENTER 
 $600,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Brian Vick 
 
 Land for sale in SW Portland Commercial
Development Land
 .34 ACRE OF PRIME COMMERCIAL PROPERTY, DO YOUR DUE DILIGENCE WITH WASHINGTON COUNTY, VERY HARD TO FIND THIS TYPE PROPERTY IN PRIME AREA, LARGE FLAT CORNER LOT. &quot;Please call Zhou(Joe)503-866-7675.&quot; E-mail zhou@realpronw.com for more info about this propert... 
 $530,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Ray Rabin 
 
 4 tax lots in Oregon City 595,000/each Commercial
Development Land
 PRIVATE RIVER FRONT LOTS IN CARVER, GATED COMMUNITY,THIS IS PRIVATE &quot;OUTSIDE LOT,&quot; COUNTRY ESTATE LIVING, MIN TO 1-205, MIN FROM PDX, OREGON CITY, CLACKAMAS, 5+ ACRE VIEW LOT IN BEAUTIFUL SETTING ON THE CLACKAMAS RIVER, &quot;LOTS FOR SALE OR OWNER WILL BUILD ... 
 $595,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Ray Rabin 
 
 Land In-City SE Portland Commercial
Development Land
 GREAT LOCATION, 1.32 ACRES, POSSIBLE 90 APT UNITS, HARD TO FIND PROPERTY OF THIS SIZE IN THIS AREA THAT IS READY FOR DEVELOPMENT. DO YOUR DUE DILIGENCE WITH CITY OF PORTLAND. &quot;Please call Zhou(Joe)503-866-7675.&quot; E-mail zhou@realpronw.com for more info abo... 
 $4,400,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Ray Rabin 
 
 2 tax lots (9.31 Acres) together SE Portland Commercial
Development Land
 9.31 ACRES INDUSTRIAL/COMMERCIAL PROPERTY, VERY DIFFICULT TO FIND THIS SIZE PARCEL IN THIS AREA OF PORTLAND, 2 TAX LOTS SOLD TOGETHER, 1 LOT .74 ACRE, 1 LOT 8.57 ACRES, SPRINGWATER TRAIL PASSES VERY NEAR THIS PROPERTY&amp;JOHNSON CREEK FLOWS AROUND PROPERTY... 
 $3,200,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Ray Rabin 
 
 Lake Owego Great Find- 2 Level lots with Potential Commercial
Development Land
 Fabulous opportunity to own almost an acre in Lake Oswego, level land. Currently 2 lots with newer 3 bedroom, 2 bath manufactured home&amp;large shop rented. Potential for developing about 5 lots. New high end homes being built nearby. 
 $875,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Edward Petrossian 
 
 LAKE CHELAN ZONED TOURIST ACCOMODATION! Commercial
Development Land
 Zoned Tourist Accomodation! Fantastic Lake Chelan, mountain, city and territorial views. Good level building site. City zoning indicates up to 17 units possible. Located next to Paradise View Condos and Lakeside Park on Lake Chelan. 
 $995,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Dan Folsom 
 
 R3 MULTI FAMLY LAND Commercial
Development Land
 INVESTORS! R3 Multi Family apartment land up to 200 units. Centrally located. 8.5 acres of R3 for sale inc. 2 acres RH. Seller willing to divide further. Located in expanding town of Myrtle creek. Easy land to build on. RMLS# 7066103 
 $1,200,000 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 JENNIFER MALONE 
 
 .92 Acre Ground Lease Commercial
Development Land
 High traffic area, zoned CG.Airport height restriction. Owner wants long term renewable lease for 20/ft. Mixed use. 85% buildout says city. 
 $20 
 For Sale 
Oregon 
 Janis Sandstrom 
 
 

 
 Total Listings: 8497           Page 8 of 17  Sort: -Sort- City Date Posted Price (Low to High) Price (High to Low) State Show: 20 50 100 250 500 
 
 
List your Commercial Real Estate Property for Sale.
Residential Real Estate Property for Sale, Business Listings for Sale, Real Estate Property for Lease. You can search for Commercial Real Estate, Residential Real Estate, Business listings for Sale, Real Estate for Lease, Joint Venture Project Opportunities, on e-PropertyLinks. The Fastest Growing online marketplace for Real Estate Investors, Real Estate Agents and Real Estate Buyers looking for Real Estate for sale or lease and Businesses for Sale.
Create a Professional Real Estate Business Profile.
Expand your marketing to our Real Estate community with e-PropertyLinks. Market your Commercial Real Estate Property listings, your Residential Real Estate Property listings, Your Real Estate Properties for Lease, your Business Listings for sale online to our Real Estate Investors, Real Estate Agents and Real Estate Buyers.
Service Provider Listings.
Create your Business Service Provider Profile on e-PropertyLinks to market your services to our Real Estate Investors, Real Estate Buyers, Commercial Real Estate Agents, Residential Real Estate Agents so they can contact you.
Search Commercial Residential Business Listings.
Search for Commercial Real Estate Listings, Residential Real Estate Listings and Business For Sale Listings, Real Estate Properties for Lease to find that perfect Commercial Real Estate Property, Residential Real Estate Property, Business listing for Sale, Real Estate Property for Lease for your Real Estate Buyer or Real Estate Investor with e-PropertyLinks. HOME | SEARCH LISTINGS | POST LISTINGS | FIND AN AGENT | FINANCING OPTIONS | ADVERTISE WITH US | PRIVACY/LEGAL 
 
Copyright©2012 e-PropertyLinks.com
 
 Website Designed by Blue Sky Web Design, LLC
	</body>
</document>
