<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007345" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Commercial-Property---Closed-Banks-and-Closed-Coffee-Shops&amp;id=2540154" time="2012-07-13-00:18" support="3" score="0.0018949248700822993" bingtitle="Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops" webtitle="Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops">
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>... have an adequate number of anchor tenants. They often look for grocery stores ... difficult when they leave ... Will the fast food restaurant merely use this to store paper cups?</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Real Estate » Commercial Property Lance Winslow 
 Diamond Author |   26,747 Articles 
 Joined: March 23, 2005 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops

 By Lance Winslow 
 
Every commercial property owner and property management company wants to make sure that their large properties have an adequate number of anchor tenants. They often look for grocery stores and retail department stores, but they also need high-traffic businesses like hair salons, travel agencies, instant printing, and fast food. To round out a good shopping center you need a bank and a good coffee shop.

Of course, this becomes quite a problem, as many of the banks are consolidating, many have been taken over by the Fed, and many are merely closing branches and locations to stay in business and cut costs during the recession. Having a bank on the property can be difficult when they leave, as the shell of that type of a business building is hard to convert into something else.

It is hard to do the tenant improvements on a closed bank and make it into a fast food restaurant. After all, what are you going to do with a giant walking and safe, which is surrounded by concrete and steel? Will the fast food restaurant merely use this to store paper cups? It&apos;s not as if you&apos;re going to dig out 2 feet of concrete reinforced steel and a giant fault with high tech stainless steel.

When a coffee shop goes out of business, it can be converted into something else for instance a Chinese restaurant, but generally the kitchen area is very small so it will require a lot of tenant improvement work, which makes it more difficult to get a tenant to replace them due to the cost of the TI work. This means that the commercial property owner will have to make an extremely good deal to get that building leased.

Often, they will opt for either another bank or another coffee shop in the same building and give a discount to the new tenant while they try to collect money from the old tenant that still owes money on the lease. These are all considerations when it comes to commercial property and management, and making it through the recession. Please consider this.
 
Lance Winslow - Lance Winslow&apos;s Bio . Lance Winslow is also Founder of the Car Wash Guys, a cool little Franchise Company; http://www.carwashguys.com/history/founder.html/ .
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Lance_Winslow 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article Download a PDF E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Real Estate: Commercial-Property 
 Lance Winslow 
 Email Address: Subscribe Commercial Property Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Recent Articles

 Hiring A Real Estate Attorney or Tenant Broker Office Leasing: The Smart Tenant&apos;s Tip Sheet 10 Essential Office Leasing Tips Commercial Property Broker - 8 Factors That Drive Better Listings and Commissions How To Choose The Right Industrial Property Broking And Management Company The Benefits of Commercial Real Estate Becoming a Commercial Real Estate Broker Why Your Landlord Offers Different Rental Rates to Tenants in Your Building Smart Investment in Commercial Real Estate It Is Time to Move Your Business to Redwood City? 
 
Submitted On June 29, 2009. Viewed 149 times. Word count: 351.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Winslow, Lance &quot;Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops.&quot; Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops .
 29 Jun. 2009 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Commercial-­Property-­-­-­Closed-­Banks-­and-­Closed-­Coffee-­Shops&amp;id=2540154 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Winslow, L. (2009, June 29). Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Commercial-­Property-­-­-­Closed-­Banks-­and-­Closed-­Coffee-­Shops&amp;id=2540154 Chicago Style Citation: 
Winslow, Lance &quot;Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops.&quot; Commercial Property - Closed Banks and Closed Coffee Shops EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Commercial-­Property-­-­-­Closed-­Banks-­and-­Closed-­Coffee-­Shops&amp;id=2540154 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
