<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007768" url="https://litigation-essentials.lexisnexis.com/webcd/app?action=DocumentDisplay&amp;crawlid=1&amp;doctype=cite&amp;docid=26+Stetson+L.+Rev.+901&amp;srctype=smi&amp;srcid=3B15&amp;key=7afdd7bc00c1f8e580dcf03588980380" time="2012-07-13-00:43" support="7" score="0.00589682513806797" bingtitle="CREATING MEANING WITHIN A GRAY AREA: REDEFINING LIKELIHOOD OF ..." webtitle="STETSON LAW REVIEW: NOTE: CREATING MEANING WITHIN A GRAY AREA: REDEFINING LIKELIHOOD OF CONFUSION IN LIBMAN CO. v. VINING INDUSTRIES, INC.">
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000979" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>86 Arbitrary or fanciful marks receive the broadest ... Two Pesos opened a Mexican fast food restaurant in ... to labels, signs, prints, packages, wrappers, receptacles ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip over navigation Browse Law Reviews and Treatises Skip over navigation Sign in with your lexis.com® ID to access the full text of this article.   -OR- Order the full text of this article if you do not have a lexis.com® ID.   Price:  US $15.00 (+ tax) Yahoo!®Currency Converter     Subject to Terms&amp;Conditions 
Copyright (c) 1997 Stetson University College of Law
Stetson Law Review

STETSON LAW REVIEW: NOTE: CREATING MEANING WITHIN A GRAY AREA: REDEFINING LIKELIHOOD OF CONFUSION IN LIBMAN CO. v. VINING INDUSTRIES, INC.

Spring, 1997

26 Stetson L. Rev. 901

Author
 Lee Ann Tranford* 
Excerpt
 

The trademarking of a product&apos;s color is the latest adaptation of the ever-evolving Lanham Trade-Mark Act. 1 Companies use a distinctive color or colors to set their product apart from others, for example, coloring fiberglass pink. 2 By using a distinctive color which consumers would not normally associate with that product, companies ensure that their product will stand apart from others, thus creating a distinctive identity for the product. 3 Therefore, this product distinction allows consumers to identify the item from many other goods available. 4 However, when a competing company markets a suspiciously similar, or nearly identical, color within a trademark, confusion can result for the consumer. 5 The resulting likelihood of confusion created by the similar use of color in a household item is the basis for the case of Libman Co. v. Vining Industries, Inc. 6 

I. FACTUAL AND PROCEDURAL DEVELOPMENT OF LIBMAN CO. v. VINING INDUSTRIES, INC.

In 1990, the Libman Company 7 created a broom with a contrasting-color bristle pattern and an off-centered handle called the Libman 201 model. 8 Libman used a vertical color band on bristles of the broom; this band contrasted with different colors used for the remaining bristles. 9 Libman used the colors red, green, or black as the band color with the rest of the bristles being dark gray (for red) or light gray (for green or black). 10 

Libman filed for federal trademark registration on March 12, 1990 and first marketed this off-centered, contrasting-color ...     If you are interested in obtaining a lexis.com® ID and Password, please contact us at 1-(800)-227-4908 or visit us at http://www.lexisnexis.com/ . Search Documents   eg., Environmental Insurance Coverage Under the Comprehensive General Liability Policy See Related Content   Lexis®Web - Beta       
Lexis®Web - The only search engine that delivers free web content specifically from legal sites validated by LexisNexis®attorney editors and includes tools for faster research and more relevant results.
   
 
 
 
   LexisNexis®Products   
 LexisNexis®Services at www.lexis.com LexisNexis®Store LexisNexis®Web Communities 
     Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | Copyright ©2012 LexisNexis, a division of Reed Elsevier, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
