<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007679" url="http://shine.yahoo.com/shine-food/best-worst-fast-food-meal-choices-173500043.html" time="2012-07-13-00:38" support="28" score="0.09875730666472886" bingtitle="The Best and Worst Fast Food Meal Choices | Jumpstart 2012 - Yahoo ..." webtitle="The Best and Worst Fast Food Meal Choices | Jumpstart 2012 - Yahoo! Shine">
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="001058" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Read our tips for making your fast-food choices both fast and healthy. McDonald&apos;s ... Nasty drag car crash from scary angle</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Shine from Yahoo! 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Today 
 The Thread The Ellen Show financially fit Moments of Motherhood Anderson Cooper Secrets to Your Success Team Mom 
 News 
 Daily Shot with Ali Wentworth Election 2012 Discover Britain Shine Latina 
 Style 
 Fashion Beauty The Thread Video Style Studio The Shine Summer Beauty Hair Guide 
 Healthy Living 
 Green Video Reluctantly Healthy The Dr. Oz Checkup Summer Shape-up Life Made Easy The Shine 
 Parenting 
 Moments of Motherhood Daily Shot with Ali Wentworth Video Team Mom The Shine 
 Love + Sex 
 Video Weddings Let&apos;s Talk About Love Ultimate Proposal The Shine 
 Food Work + Money 
 Financially Fit Secrets to Your Success Video 
 Pets 
 Animal Nation Video 
 At Home 
 Green Video Decorating Guide The Shine Book Club 
 Horoscope 
 Horoscope Chinese Astrology 2012 Annual Horoscope 
 My Shine 
 Create blog post Create slideshow Manage blog posts Manage slideshows Contributor Network 
 
 
 What&apos;s For Dinner Shine Supper Club Video Saveur Chow Ciao! Blue Ribbon Hunter Life Made Easy 
 Search 
 Keyword Search Shine 
 
Trending Now
 » 
 Paulina Gretzky Zsa Zsa Gabor Vera Wang split Kate Upton Nicole Kidman Bill Cosby Pluto&apos;s new moon Foreclosures Insurance rebates Chevy buy-back 
 
The Best and Worst Fast Food Meal Choices
 
By Glamour Magazine 
 
 Posts 
 By Glamour Magazine | Jumpstart 2012  –  Wed, Jan 11, 2012 7:28 PM EST 
 Courtesy of McDonald&apos;s Jenna Williams, Glamour 

When you&apos;re in a rush, it can be hard to judge the nutritional value of your favorite value meal. Read our tips for making your fast-food choices both fast and healthy.

 McDonald&apos;s: Bad and Better Food Choices 
We know it&apos;s tough to resist the lure of the golden arches, but DO pay attention to portion size when ordering from McDonald&apos;s.

 Breakfast 
 BAD Deluxe Breakfast, with a large biscuit and no syrup or margarine (1,150 calories , 60 grams of fat)
 BETTER Bacon, Egg&amp;Cheese Biscuit, made with a regular-size biscuit (430 calories, 24 grams of fat)

 Burger 
 BAD Double Quarter Pounder With Cheese (740 calories, 42 grams of fat)
 BETTER Cheeseburger (300 calories, 12 grams of fat)
*Leave off the cheese and you&apos;ll save 50 calories and 3 grams of fat!

 Salad 
 BAD Premium Southwest Salad With Crispy Chicken (430 calories, 20 grams of fat)
 BETTER Premium Caesar Salad With Grilled Chicken (220 calories, 6 grams of fat)
*Totals are without dressing. Remember, Caesar dressing is very high in fat and calories.

 Related: 12 Secret Signs He&apos;s Into You 
 
 Courtesy of Burger King Burger King : Bad and Better Food Choices 
When ordering a burger (and, hey, it is Burger King), DON&apos;T double (or triple!) up on patties. One extra piles on extra calories.

 Burger 
 BAD Triple Whopper Sandwich With Cheese (1,250 calories, 84 grams of fat)
 BETTER Hamburger (290 calories, 12 grams of fat)

 Side 
 BAD Large Salted French Fries (580 calories, 28 grams of fat)
 BETTER BK Fresh Apple Fries With Caramel Sauce (70 calories, 0.5 grams of fat)



 Courtesy of Wendy&apos;s Wendy&apos;s: Bad and Better Food Choices 
DO eliminate unnecessary calories in your salad without sacrificing taste by avoiding words like creamy or crispy. And always opt for grilled (not fried) chicken.

 Salad 
 BAD Chicken BLT Salad (470 calories, 27 grams of fat)
 BETTER Mandarin Chicken Salad (180 calories, 2 grams of fat)
*Totals do not include dressing.

 Sandwich 
 BAD Triple With Cheese (960 calories, 60 grams of fat)
 BETTER Jr. Hamburger (220 calories, 8 grams of fat)

 Conde Nast Digital Studio Five Guys: Bad and Better Food Choices 
DON&apos;T be fooled by names. At this patty palace, the&quot;little burger&quot;is anything but small. Cut calories by topping your burger with mustard or hot sauce instead of mayo and cheese.

 Burger 
 BAD Bacon Cheeseburger (920 calories, 62 grams of fat)
 BETTER Little Hamburger (480 calories, 26 grams of fat)

 Condiment 
 BAD Mayonnaise (100 calories, 11 grams of fat-in 14 grams)
 BETTER Mustard or hot sauce (0 calories, 0 grams of fat)



 Courtesy of Jack in the Box Jack in the Box: Bad and Better Food Choices 
We usually recommend skipping dessert if you&apos;re gorging on fast food, but if you&apos;re going to give in to your sweet tooth, DO skip the milk shake.

 Dessert 
 BAD Oreo Cookie Ice Cream Shake (1,454.5 calories, 75.1 grams of fat)
 BETTER Chocolate Overload Cake (300 calories, 7 grams of fat)

 Burger 
 BAD Sirloin Bacon&amp;Cheese Burger (1,136.8 calories, 74.9 grams of fat)
 BETTER Hamburger (281 .1 calories, 11.7 grams of fat)

 Entrée 
 BAD Large Fish&amp;Chips (1,153.2 calories, 72.6 grams of fat)
 BETTER Chicken Fajita Pita Made With Whole Grain (306.8 calories, 9.4 grams of fat)

 Courtesy of Blimpie&apos;s Blimpie: Bad and Better Food Choices 
We usually recommend skipping dessert if you&apos;re gorging on fast food, but if you&apos;re going to give in to your sweet tooth, DO skip the milk shake.
 
Dessert 
 BAD Oreo Cookie Ice Cream Shake (1,454.5 calories, 75.1 grams of fat)
 BETTER Chocolate Overload Cake (300 calories, 7 grams of fat)

 Burger 
 BAD Sirloin Bacon&amp;Cheese Burger (1,136.8 calories, 74.9 grams of fat)
 BETTER Hamburger (281 .1 calories, 11.7 grams of fat)

 Entrée 
 BAD Large Fish&amp;Chips (1,153.2 calories, 72.6 grams of fat)
 BETTER Chicken Fajita Pita Made With Whole Grain (306.8 calories, 9.4 grams of fat)

 Related: The Top 10 Ways to Wake Up Prettier 

 Courtesy of Subway Subway: Bad and Better Food Choices 
DO choose lean turkey meat. It&apos;s lower in fat than most other meats and has a subtle enough flavor to be paired with just about any topping.

 Sandwich 
 BAD 6-inch Double Meatball Marinara With Cheese (860 calories, 42 grams of fat)
 BETTER Jared Sandwich: 6-inch Turkey Breast (280 calories, 4.5 grams of fat)

 Salad 
 BAD Sweet Onion Chicken Teriyaki (210 calories , 3 grams of fat)
 BETTER Oven-Roasted Chicken Breast With Fat-Free Italian Dressing (175 calories, 2.5 grams of fat)

 Courtesy of Arby&apos;s Arby&apos;s: Bad and Better Food Choices 
Whether it&apos;s paired with a burger or sprinkled on a potato, DO watch out for calorie-laden bacon.

 Sandwich 
 BAD Roast Turkey, Ranch&amp;Bacon (818 calories, 38 grams of fat)
 BETTER Ham&amp;Swiss Melt (268 calories, 5 grams of fat)

 Side 
 BAD Large Mozzarella Sticks (426 calories, 28 grams of fat)
 BETTER 4-piece Southwest Eggrolls (225 calories, 7 grams of fat)
*Totals are without dipping sauces. The Chile Lime sauce that comes with the eggrolls adds 190 calories and 19 grams of fat. Yikes!


 More from Glamour:
 

 19 Cute Celebrity Haircuts to Consider 36 Cute Fall Dresses Under $100 21 Gorgeous Wedding Dresses Under $1,000 Exactly What to Eat to Lose Weight 












   
 All Comments 
   Top Locations Atlanta Chicago Tampa Phoenix New York Sacramento Irvine Los Angeles Houston Washington 
2,420 comments
 
 Popular Now Newest Oldest Most Replied 
 
 M Kat  •  6 months ago Bad: Lard.
Better: Water.

I hope I was as enlightening as this article. 
 Michael
	</body>
</document>
