<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007007" url="http://www.fastfoodsource.com/burgers-and-sandwiches/carls-jr" time="2012-07-12-23:59" support="4" score="0.014712684626746126" bingtitle="Carl&apos;s Jr. - Burgers and Sandwiches - Fast Food at Fast Food ..." webtitle="Carl&apos;s Jr. - Burgers and Sandwiches - Fast Food at Fast Food Source:  Your independent guide to fast food restaurants, menus, nutrition, locations, and fast food news!">
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Fast Food at Fast Food Source: Your independent ... the best chicken sandwich I have ever had at a fast food ... I am particular to a balanced condiment:meat ratio and so ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Skip to main navigation Skip to first column Skip to second column 
   
 Fast Food at Fast Food Source: Your independent guide to fast food restaurants, menus, nutrition, locations, and fast food news! 
 
Carl&apos;s Jr.
 Monday, 20 October 2008 22:48 
 

 About: Founded in 1941, Los Angeles, CA. 900 locations in the U.S., Mexico&amp;Pacific Rim

 Contact: 800-758-2275

 Author Recommends: Chicken Club, Famous Star, Western Bacon Cheeseburger

Unlike most reviews for Carl&apos;s Jr. and sister chain Hardee&apos;s, I am going to skip the obvious fawning over their tasty and substantial burgers and point out something that I think is underrated. Carl&apos;s Jr.&apos;s Charbroiled Chicken Club is the best chicken sandwich I have ever had at a fast food restaurant. Bar none. This beats, hands down, the previous champion Chicken Club at Burger King.

Now as to the burgers. I am particular to a balanced condiment:meat ratio and so I tend to avoid the giant patty burgers (Six Dollar Burgers or Thickburgers) in favor of the thinner patties of the classic Western Bacon Cheeseburger and Famous Star. That&apos;s not to say the bigger burgers are bad. You can&apos;t go wrong - they&apos;re delicious. But my aforementioned desire to balance out meat and condiments/accessories in every bite always brings me back to the traditional favorites. -RB
 Tags:
 carls jr 
 Joomla Templates and Joomla Extensions by ZooTemplate.Com   
 SEO by AceSEF 
 
 
 Find Your Local Restaurants . . . 
 
 Home Search By City List All Restaurants Fast Food Blogs Restaurant Inspections Nutrition Industry Links Mobile Access Awards&amp;Recognition Contact Fast Food Source 
 
Most Popular Tags
 big mac burger burger king carls jr checkers chicken del taco europe fast food fast food source fries hardees jack in the box locations mcdonalds menu news nutrition opinion review steak n shake taco bell tommys update wendys 
 [Back] 
 Carl&apos;s Jr. Find A Location Get Nutrition Info Carl&apos;s Jr. Website Contact Form 
 
 


© 2000-2012 FastFoodSource.com. Use subject to the Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
