<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007941" url="http://www.nihilismandcupcakes.com/2010/12/20/should-we-demand-fast-food-restaurants-to-be-healthier/" time="2012-07-13-00:55" support="5" score="0.014181057719496043" bingtitle="Should we demand fast food restaurants to be healthier ..." webtitle="Should we demand fast food restaurants to be healthier?Nihilism and Cupcakes">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>... and ask everyone, “okay, you ordered the number 3. ... You can’t force the fast food restaurant to be everything you ... no. am i well aware of my food decisions? yes.</description>
	<body>
		Nihilism and Cupcakes Just another WordPress site 
 Main FAQ My Story Controversy My Plan About Me Resources 
 
 Yes, I’m on about the food diaries again Shorter lifespans for those who are overweight? NO WAY! 
 
 Should we demand fast food restaurants to be healthier? 
 Health , Nutrition , Overall Health Dec 20 2010 
Let me ask you this question: how frequently does it happen in your life that you are trapped into going to McDonalds with no other options, forced to eat from their menu?

Yeah, I’m already showing my bias as a former fast food manager. Bear with me here.

A recent study showed that fast food was still unhealthy. Apparently, some folks at Yale were unaware that Burger King had not changed their menu completely to salads and tofu. I don’t know, seriously, this was news?
 
Fast Food: the cause of all of our problems, more on page 3
 
Let’s recap: about ten billion years ago, it was brought to the forefront just how unhealthy fast food is. Most chains started offering some options like salads, veggie burgers, fruit, or some other items that would allow them to keep some of their clientele that was now horrified yet didn’t want to kick their fast food habit. While the most recent changes included an option for swapping out the fries in kids’meals for fruit, beyond that, there haven’t been any radical overhauls in years. In fact, most fast food chains are more focused on stealing the coffee market at this point.

Yet, somehow, these researchers were absolutely amazed at what they found in what we see every day.
 
Harris and her colleagues did find that most of the fast food restaurants had healthy options as well, but they were hard to find.

“More than 80 percent of the time our mystery shoppers went into fast food restaurants, they were automatically given the french fries on the side,”she said,“and more than half the time, they were automatically given a cup for soda. So, even though they have the healthy options, they aren’t even asking people if they want them.”
 
OH MY GOD NO. NOT THAT.

And wait a second here—if you order a meal that comes with a soda, you’re going to get a cup for a soda. What other options are there? Coffee? Milk? If you want something other than the default, you have to ask for it. No restaurant should make assumptions that you want something special. These places have time quotas to meet, actually. They’re not going to stop and ask everyone,“okay, you ordered the number 3. Do you want everything that normally comes with that?”People know what their options are (or can ask), and it’s their responsibility to speak up if they want them.

 

Let’s also add that the healthier options often have a higher food cost. If you think a manager is going to encourage their employees to sell something that makes them lose more profit, you’d be out of your mind.

Is it so much to ask people to take personal responsibility for their nutrition?

Okay, so maybe you don’t know what your healthy options would be. Eventually, chain restaurants will have calorie contents listed on the menus in the US. Until then, you can search the Internet for about ten million recommendations, or take a short list from this CNN article for some quick no-brainers.
 
1. Arby’s Melt
Add on a chopped side salad with balsamic vinaigrette dressing and you’ve got a 570-calorie meal.

2. Chick-Fil-A Chargrilled Chicken Sandwich
With barbecue sauce and a large fruit cup, this meal is 425 calories.

3. McDonalds Asian Salad
Get the low-fat balsamic vinaigrette and it’s 340 calories.

4. Taco Bell Fresco Bean Burrito
Along with a side of Mexican Rice Fresco, it’s 460 calories.

5. Wendy’s Jr. Hamburger
It’s 320 calories if you add on a side of mandarin oranges.
 
There are indeed some healthy items on these menus. If they don’t appeal to you, don’t go to those restaurants . It’s that simple. Is it fair to demand that the junkier options be taken away just because you don’t want to eat them? Is it fair to badger the responsible splurger about having an occasional burger‘n’fries simply because that meal isn’t nutritionally optimum?

You’re at a FAST FOOD RESTAURANT. You’re not at Chez Greenfuck’s Organic Emporium. You know where you can get what. You can’t force the fast food restaurant to be everything you want it to be. They’ve already made some options available, which is more than they ever had to do in the first place. Educating people about nutrition will allow them to make better decisions should they choose to make them; but if they want french fries, they’re gonna order french fries. Let it go.

Now I’m gonna be over here ordering some Wendy’s chili and a baked potato. And I’m going to do my hardest to not get angry when they don’t ask me if I’d like milk or fruit with that.
 Add comments 
2 Responses to“Should we demand fast food restaurants to be healthier?”
 Comments (2) 
 Johnny M says: December 20, 2010 at 7:25 PM 
The thing with most healthier version of fast food is that it’s still fast food. It’s going to be over-processed and full of chemicals, preservatives, and other sub-standard stuff. I’m pretty sure that when I worked at Taco Bell, the meat that was used for tacos and burritos said“Grade D”on the box. But yes, if you’re like me and don’t like all that stuff, then simply don’t choose to eat fast food. It’s not that hard. I’ve eaten McDonald’s only once in the past 6 or 7 years, and that was one of those times when there were no other options (parents and I on a road trip through Kansas on our way back from Texas).
 Log in to Reply Rachael says: December 20, 2010 at 7:43 PM 
maybe i’m not the typical fast food client, but when i want a double decker taco from taco bell, i want it EXACTLY AS IT IS. same goes for my wendy’s spicy chicken sandwich, no mayo no tomato. and i do not consume fast food often, but when i do it’s because it’s either a necessity (you know, the whole *fast* part in front of the food part of the phrase) or because i actually have a craving for it.

like the mcrib. i never eat mcdonalds. i don’t like mcdonalds. but when that thing comes back around once a decade or however often it does, i have to have one. just one. that’s it. is the thing healthy? fuck no. do i care? no. am i well aware of my food decisions? yes. i am making my choices and i’m not an idiot and i blame nobody but myself for stuffing my face with some sort of processes pork product mushed into a flattened rib shape thing slathered in bbq sauce and put into a sammich.

i don’t understand why sonic should be punished for serving tater tots when i choose to eat tater tots because they are salted morsels of fried potato heaven.
 Log in to Reply 
 
Leave a Reply

 You must be logged in to post a comment. 
 
RSS
 Subscribe via RSS 
Archives

 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 
 
Categories

 Exercise 
 Cardio Strength Training 
 General Anger 
 Complete Idiots Misinformation Quacks 
 Health 
 Mental Health Organic/Natural Overall Health 
 Humor Motivation My Progress News Nutrition 
 Calories Carbs Fat Protein Vegetarian Vitamins 
 Products 
 Drugs/Supplements Equipment 
 Recipes Site News Studies Uncategorized Weight Loss 
 Diets Genetics Lifestyle Surgery 
 
 
Friends of NAC

 * NAC group on Fitocracy! * Eat, Drink, and Be Meiri Fat Diva in Motion Jorah&apos;s 80% Fat Free Blog SweatyGirl Weightloss-a-rama 
 
Helpful Links

 * My personal resources * Couch to 5k FitDay LiveStrong Mayo Clinic Fitness One Hundred Pushups SparkPeople Ten Thousand Steps 
 
More Friends of NAC

 Art of Wore Culinary Cat Eastern Skies Bodywork GamePron Inside Pulse Kandeart My Life Married to the Music Okaystupids Review-o-Matic S**t-Flix 
 
Follow Me
 
 
 
 ©2012 Nihilism and Cupcakes Suffusion WordPress theme by Sayontan Sinha
	</body>
</document>
