<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007205" url="http://www.job-applications.com/carnival-cruise-lines-job-interview-tips/" time="2012-07-13-00:10" support="1" score="0.0017209704580935462" bingtitle="Carnival Cruise Lines Interview Questions &amp; Tips, Employer ..." webtitle="Carnival Cruise Lines Interview QuestionsTips, Employer Questions - Job Application Help Online">
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>A Carnival Cruise Lines job interview may take several weeks to schedule, depending on position ... i would like to offer my services to the cruise lines as a number of my ...</description>
	<body>
		The #1 Independent Online Job Application Resource Website 
 
 
 
 
 Home » Interview Tips »Carnival Cruise Lines Interview Questions&amp;Tips

Carnival Cruise Lines Interview Questions
 
 
 
 
 

Hiring process information for an interview at Carnival Cruise Lines

A Carnival Cruise Lines job interview may take several weeks to schedule, depending on position and location. Before attending the Carnival Cruise Lines job interview, do some research on the company. Learn about company history and different jobs available. Dress professionally for the Carnival Cruise Lines job interview and prepare to talk about employment history.

Taking a job with Carnival Cruise Lines requires a great deal of customer service and communication skill. Some typical questions asked during a Carnival Cruise Lines interview include: “Do you get sea sickness, and how do you handle it?”, “Can you share small quarters with another person?”, and “Can you work with a diverse crew of associates from many nationalities?”

Positions:

 Carnival Cruise Lines typically hires for the following positions :
Accountant, Administrative Assistant/Support Services, Advertising/Marketing Manager, Casino Associate, Crew Member, Customer Service/Call Center Representative, Destination Shopping Specialist, Entertainer, Financial Analyst, Gift Shop Sales Associate, Human Resources Associate, Photographer, Spa/Beauty/Fitness Attendant

Application:

View the Carnival Cruise Lines Application and apply for the Carnival Cruise Lines job you want.

Possible Carnival Cruise Lines Interview Questions:

Prepare for your interview by reviewing the questions below. Think about how you would answer these types of questions.

 What about time off at port? Sea sickness–do you get it, how do you handle it? Can I choose the ship I work on? Can you share small quarters with another person? Can you work with a diverse crew from many nationalities?

Common Cruise Job Interview Questions:

Dont go unprepared. Review these often used interview questions and answers .

Have you done a job interview with Carnival Cruise Lines before?

Tell us about it! Your feedback helps our users prepare for the interview process. General tips, questions, and helpful information are appreciated. Feel free to leave a comment . Thanks!

For example, useful information includes:

 Should I bring anything to the Carnival Cruise Lines interview? What education level (high school or college) is required for the job? What other questions do they ask? How should you answer certain questions? What should I wear, or how should I dress for an interview at Carnival Cruise Lines? How much do they pay? Will they ask about salary expectations, if so what should I say? Does Carnival Cruise Lines drug test? What about second interviews? When should you expect a call after the interview?

 10 comments: 
 bla: 





i will have job interview for floor supervisor position.
do you know what questions will they ask me ?


 
 ozumbu: 





Hey Bla
I would like to apply for F&amp;B department,do you know how can I apply for Carnival Cruise Line?thank you for your help


 
 constantin: 





hello
how can apply online at carnival cl for head waiter position
thank you


 
 Winifred Blanchard: 





I operate an employment agency in my country where I screen workers for various positions and place them in establishments. i would like to offer my services to the cruise lines as a number of my clients have expressed interest in working on the cruise shipe. How do I proceed. Please respond.

I would like to offer assistance


 
 Ernesto Espinoza: 





Does Carnival hire seasonal workers? i would like a summer job. I’m a teacher and would like to work in the summer from about June to middle end of July.


 
 i gede yanda kartika: 





hi…my name is gede,,,i have experience on cruise ship for 3 years as a bar waiter,,now i would like to apply for carnival cruise line,,how can i apply online for carnival CL?

thanks


 
 Meheret: 





Hi, I just want to know how i could get a visa entry to be in Australia,


 
 Ajit: 





Sir, i have completed 3yrs hotel management course from lbiihm delhi n presently working in 5 star hotel as a cdp n plz guide me how can i apply online for carnival cruise line.?


 
 Ajaz: 





Hi i want to apply for a cruise ship job. I have experience of 2 yrs in a 5 star property…How do i apply?


 
 Michel Reginald: 





How can someone in Haiti apply for a Carnival Cruise Lines job??


 
 
 Most Popular Jobs Retail Store Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Career Research Employee Benefits 
 En Espanol 
 Interview Tips 
 Interview Questions 
 Job Descriptions 
 Job Finding Tips 
 Salary Info 
 Job Newsletter We&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name: Email: Zip Code: Select Category: Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery 

 Sign Up Job Categories Airline Jobs 
 Amusement Park Jobs 
 Armed Forces Jobs 
 Automotive Store Jobs 
 Banking Jobs 
 Book Store Jobs 
 Casino Jobs 
 Childcare Daycare Jobs 
 Coffee Shop Jobs 
 Computer Store Jobs 
 Cruise Ship Jobs 
 Delivery Driver Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Fashion Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Fitness Health Jobs 
 Furniture Store Jobs 
 Gas Station Jobs 
 Grocery Store Jobs 
 Hardware Store Jobs 
 Healthcare Jobs 
 Home Decor Jobs 
 Hospital Jobs 
 Hotel Jobs 
 Ice Cream Shop Jobs 
 Insurance Jobs 
 Mechanic Jobs 
 Movie Theater Jobs 
 Office Supply Jobs 
 Pet Store Jobs 
 Pharmacy Tech Jobs 
 Pharmacist Jobs 
 Pizza Delivery Jobs 
 Rental Truck Jobs 
 Rental Car Jobs 
 Restaurant Jobs 
 Retail Management Jobs 
 Retail Store Jobs 
 Shoe Store Jobs 
 Smoothie Maker Jobs 
 Specialty Foods Jobs 
 Sporting Goods Jobs 
 Telecommunications Jobs 
 Temp Agency Jobs 
 Tools Jobs 
 Tutoring Jobs 

 All Job Categories 
 
   

 
 Sign up - we&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name:
 Email:
 Zip:
 Select Category:
 Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery Sign Up 
 
 disclaimer 

 privacy policy 

 terms of use 
 
 
Copyright © 2011, 2012 Job-Applications.com
	</body>
</document>
