<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007111" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080118161259AAy4QXm" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="2" score="0.004134307627160476" bingtitle="Valentine for every sign? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="Valentine for every sign? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>Aries: You&apos;re determined to receive the most cards ... dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food ... Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Entertainment&amp;Music &gt; Horoscopes &gt; Resolved Question 
 eee Member since: January 14, 2008 Total points: 1,786 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Valentine for every sign?
 Does February 14 fill you with feelings of cheer or fear? Each Sun Sign has a different way of responding to this romantic holiday. Find out how your Sign handles this much-anticipated day of flowery poems, chocolate hearts and red roses.

Aries: You&apos;re determined to receive the most cards, candy and flowers. Who says sending roses to yourself doesn&apos;t count?

Taurus: A bouquet of dandelions, dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food restaurant? Relax, it was just a bad dream!

Gemini: You make two dates for the night -- and then backup plans with your friends in case you decide to flake on your original plans.

Cancer: Ooh, there&apos;s nothing like candy heart art and lace doilies to get you going! Martha Stewart&apos;s got nothing on you.

Leo: You are displeased by the single red rose some admirer left on your windshield. Clearly you are worth at least a dozen!

Virgo: You refuse to share the box of chocolates you receive -- what if someone fingers them? What if someone sneezes on your roses?

Libra: You send valentines to everyone you know: your hairdresser, your fourth grade teacher, your manicurist, your manicurist&apos;s cousin … You don&apos;t want anyone to feel left out.

Scorpio: Why go out for a fancy dinner when you already have dessert waiting at home? Who knew that a Cupid costume could be so sexy?

Sagittarius: You can&apos;t commit to sending a card -- what if the recipient reads too much into it? You fake temporary amnesia to avoid acknowledging the holiday.

Capricorn: Lacy hearts and syrupy sentiments make you sneeze -- besides, nothing says love like a new electronic organizer!

Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of decaffeinated herbal tea, but consuming a few vegan chocolates doesn&apos;t make you a conformist, does it?

Pisces: You live for this stuff! The world would be such a better place if we could all just hold hands and share heart-shaped cookies every day. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 http://www.astrology.com/fun/valentines.… 
 5 years ago 
 by shanayca... Member since: September 09, 2006 Total points: 316 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Cute....very cute indeed.....Sagittarius&apos;s rocks the house, i do fake amnesia on that day, and I just prefer Every other holiday all together, people get all emotional and feely touchy on Valentines Day

Hey Its Just like any other day!!!!
Boyfriends/girlfriends and husbands/wife&apos;s can make everyday Valentines day with the one/ONES you LOVE!!

Hooray to the suckers on Valentines Day.....
LOVE is in the air so ENJOY!!! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: yup........to all, enjoy everyday 
 Action Bar: 2 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Johnny Rocker 89 Member since: May 21, 2007 Total points: 37,380 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 As a Pisces, I must say I&apos;m not fond of Valentines Day anymore. Ever since every girl I liked dumped me to talk to other guys that had nothing going on, it is just another day. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by xoxo neon Member since: January 04, 2008 Total points: 1,280 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yay im scorpio and i get a different kind of dessert lol 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by sarah ♥ Member since: July 19, 2007 Total points: 492 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i am a taurus... and yes that was a bad dream 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Cassandra * Member since: October 29, 2007 Total points: 1,118 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It must be wrong.... 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by ? Member since: December 17, 2007 Total points: 773 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Very funny!!! Im gonna fake amnesia to avoid Valentine days! OK that is very funny. Even though I love Valentine days. But still these are entertaining to read. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Horoscopes 

 How come other signs won&apos;t admit Fire Signs are the strongest? Question for geminis? Which sign is the scariest to you, Aries or Scorpio? Who would win a fight, Gemini or Sagittarius? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Entertainment&amp;Music 
 Celebrities Comics&amp;Animation Horoscopes Jokes&amp;Riddles Magazines Movies Music Other - Entertainment Polls&amp;Surveys Radio Television 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 ? middnightangel… 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
