<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007563" url="http://www.democraticunderground.com/discuss/duboard.php?az=view_all&amp;address=439x2182163" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.0005436381494701597" bingtitle="Republicans going after sick and family leave benefits. Another ..." webtitle="Republicans going after sick and family leave benefits. Another example for why we need to VOTE!! - Democratic Underground">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="36"/>
	<description>Republicans going after sick and family leave benefits. ... council passed a second version of a paid sick leave bill ... Home | Discussion Forums | Journals | Store | ...</description>
	<body>
		Latest 
 Greatest 
 Lobby 
 Journals 
 Search 
 Options 
 Help 
 Login 
 Site 
search Web search 

 Republicans going after sick and family leave benefits. Another example for why we need to VOTE!! 

 Printer-friendly format 
 Email this thread to a friend 
 Bookmark this thread This topic is archived. 
 

 Home » Discuss  » General Discussion 
   
 Liberal_Stalwart71 (1000+ posts) Tue Oct-25-11 12:30 PM
Original message 

 Republicans going after sick and family leave benefits. Another example for why we need to VOTE!! 

 Thirty-eight of the fifty state legislatures are not in the hands of the Republicans. We all know that the American Legislative Exchange Council (ALEC) has been drafting legislation for the GOP that attacks public workers and unions, implements draconian voter registration laws, attacks abortion/reproductive rights, and strict immigration laws.

Here&apos;s another reason why it is critically important that we all VOTE, not just in general elections, but also in midterms.

Republicans are drunk on power...

------------
&lt;snip&gt;

Corporate Front Group ALEC Pushing For Repeal Of Paid Sick Day Laws Nationwide

By Zaid Jilani posted from ThinkProgress Economy on Oct 19, 2011 at 2:50 pm

Recently, a string of cities and states have passed new ordinances that would require paid sick days for employees at certain employers. Just last week, Philadelphias city council passed a second version of a paid sick leave bill after the mayor vetoed the earlier one. Earlier this year, Seattle approved paid sick days legislation, while Connecticut became the first state with a state-wide requirement.

Now, the Center for Media and Democracys PR Watch has published an expose of how the American Legislative Exchange Council (ALEC) a corporate front group that farms out legislation to almost a third of state legislators nationwide is drafting legislation on behalf of its wealthy conglomerate funders to repeal these ordinances.

PR Watch obtained documents from ALECs 2011 Annual Meeting showing that one of the groups committees the Labor and Business Regulation Subcommittee of the Commerce, Insurance and Economic Development Task Force focused its entire meeting on the issue of paid sick leave. Task force members, who are legislators, were given copies of a bill that enables state legislatures to override municipal paid sick days laws. The same bill was used in Wisconsin to override Milwaukees paid sick days requirement.

PR Watch notes that ALECs Labor and Business Regulation subcommittee is co-chaired by a company that owns many of the nations fast food companies, major opponents of paid sick leave:
Meeting attendees were given complete copies of Wisconsins 2011 Senate Bill 23 (now Wisconsin Act 16), as a model for state override. They were also handed a target list and map of state and local paid sick leave policies prepared by ALEC member, the National Restaurant Association.

In Wisconsin, the Wisconsin Restaurant Association lobbied for SB 23 to repeal the sick leave ordinance, as did the the Metropolitan Milwaukee Association of Commerce (MMAC), the local branch of the the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, an ALEC member). Not surprisingly, ALECs Labor and Business Regulation Subcommittee is co-chaired by YUM! Brands, Inc., which owns Kentucky Fried Chicken, Pizza Hut and Taco Bell. Fast food companies have fought paid sick leave across the country.

&lt;/snip&gt; 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
    Replies to this thread 

    maybe if we all started lodging complaints at these  EC   Oct-25-11 12:49 PM   #1     We also don&apos;t want sick employees spreading bacterial diseases,  kestrel91316   Oct-25-11 01:22 PM   #2         You ruining the&quot;fun.&quot;  nadinbrzezinski   Oct-25-11 04:36 PM   #5     Agreed!! n/t  Liberal_Stalwart71   Oct-25-11 04:21 PM   #3     Let me tell you about a fast-food...  CoffeeCat   Oct-25-11 04:35 PM   #4     Link?  salin   Oct-25-11 04:39 PM   #6     +1  usregimechange   Oct-25-11 06:21 PM   #9     These guys fought hard against the Connecticut Law  NutmegYankee   Oct-25-11 04:54 PM   #7     This is important.  surrealAmerican   Oct-25-11 05:43 PM   #8     sociopaths attacking poor Americans  fascisthunter   Oct-25-11 06:23 PM   #10     Link here...  Liberal_Stalwart71   Oct-26-11 12:55 PM   #11  
 
 EC (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 12:49 PM
Response to Original message 

 1. maybe if we all started lodging complaints at these 

 fast-food places that are complaining, about sick employees handing out food and how we&apos;ll never eat there again. Maybe the point will get through their thick skulls. The reason sick people should stay home is not to spread viral illnesses. And they should be paid sick days, since they don&apos;t pay enough for someone to voluntarily stay home. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 kestrel91316 (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 01:22 PM
Response to Reply #1 

 2. We also don&apos;t want sick employees spreading bacterial diseases, 

 like Salmonella and Campylobacter and Shigella.

Just my 2c worth. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 nadinbrzezinski (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 04:36 PM
Response to Reply #2 

 5. You ruining the&quot;fun.&quot; 

 Party pooper!!!! 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 Liberal_Stalwart71 (1000+ posts) Tue Oct-25-11 04:21 PM
Response to Original message 

 3. Agreed!! n/t 

 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 CoffeeCat (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 04:35 PM
Response to Original message 

 4. Let me tell you about a fast-food... 

 restaurant owner...my father.

He was against ANY kind of legislation that cost him one cent, and helped the
workers in ANY way.

He hated that there was a minimum wage. He detested the fact that he had to
pay sick leave.

We have a very liberal Senator, Tom Harkin. Harkin spearheaded the Americans
With Disabilities Act and was instrumental in this important legislation
becoming law. Harkin happened to be in the vicinity of my father&apos;s restaurants
and my father sought him out. My father told me that he had to give Harkin
a piece of his mind, for passing the ADA.

Because of the ADA, my father was forced to spend money to make the bathrooms
handicap accessible. This outraged my father. Why should HE have to spend
money because someone had a problem getting into the bathroom?

Yeah. That&apos;s what Republicans are like. Until you&apos;ve lived with one of these
psychopaths--you have absolutely no idea how sick they are. They will fight
to the death, to tear down any legislation that costs them any money. They
don&apos;t care if it&apos;s unfair or callous. It&apos;s all about the bottom line for them.

Nothing else matters. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 salin (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 04:39 PM
Response to Original message 

 6. Link? 

 looks like a good article to fully read.
 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 usregimechange (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 06:21 PM
Response to Reply #6 

 9. +1 

 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 NutmegYankee (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 04:54 PM
Response to Original message 

 7. These guys fought hard against the Connecticut Law 

 The &quot;this is anti-business&quot; mantra went on for months, but We The People still won in the end. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 surrealAmerican (1000+ posts) Tue Oct-25-11 05:43 PM
Response to Original message 

 8. This is important. 

 I don&apos;t usually recommend posts without a link, but ...


Sick leave and family leave should probably be nationally mandated - not left up to the states (or cities), but, given this congress, I&apos;m not holding my breath. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 fascisthunter (1000+ posts)  Tue Oct-25-11 06:23 PM
Response to Original message 

 10. sociopaths attacking poor Americans 

 oh soon... oh how soon it will be when we watch these motherfuckers beg for forgiveness, before we throw their asses in jail. They are playing for keeps. Well then, we up the ante and take all their freedoms away by locking them up. 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 Liberal_Stalwart71 (1000+ posts) Wed Oct-26-11 12:55 PM
Response to Original message 

 11. Link here... 

 Sorry. I thought I had added it:

 http://thinkprogress.org/economy/2011/10/19/347793/alec... 

 Printer Friendly  |  Permalink  |  |  Top 
 
 DU 
AdBot (1000+ posts) Thu Jul 12th 2012, 05:32 PM
Response to Original message 

 Advertisements [ ? ] 

 

   Top 
 
 Big Forums   |-- Latest Breaking News   |-- Editorials&amp;Other Articles   |-- Political Videos   |-- General Discussion   |-- General Discussion: Presidency   |-- The DU Lounge   |-- Ask the Administrators Forum Categories   |-- Topic Forums   |-- Places   |-- DU Groups   |-- Archives My Forums 
 
 Home » Discuss  » General Discussion 

Powered by DCForum+ Version 1.1 Copyright 1997-2002 DCScripts.com
Software has been extensively modified by the DU administrators
 
 Important Notices: By participating on this discussion 
 board, visitors agree to abide by the rules outlined on our Rules page. Messages posted on the Democratic Underground Discussion Forums are the 
 opinions of the individuals who post them, and do not necessarily represent 
 the opinions of Democratic Underground, LLC.

 Home  |  Discussion 
 Forums  |  Journals  |  Store  |  Donate 

 About DU  |  Contact Us  |  Privacy Policy 

Got a message for Democratic Underground? Click 
 here to send us a message.

©2001 - 2011 Democratic Underground, 
 LLC
	</body>
</document>
