<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007122" url="http://www.uihealthcare.com/topics/nutrition/nutr3176.html" time="2012-07-13-00:06" support="2" score="0.0016628846495359841" bingtitle="Calories: How Many Do You Need??: Health Topics: University of ..." webtitle="Calories:  How Many Do You Need??: Health Topics: University of Iowa Health Care">
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>When the number of calories consumed is less than the number of calories used ... To determine the fat in the food you eat in terms of fat grams, read the food package ...</description>
	<body>
		Health Topics Category Index 
 Health Topics for Nutrition 



     
 


Calories: How many do you need?
 
Calories measure the amount of energy that is supplied by carbohydrates, fats, and proteins in food. The energy supplied by food is needed for vital body functions like growth, movement, and thought.

A weight gain results when the number of calories consumed is greater than the number of calories used. When the number of calories consumed is less than the number of calories used, there is weight loss. There is no weight change when calories consumed equals calories used. Each person&apos;s energy balance is directly related to a combination of their behaviors, environment, and genetics.

Food labels identify the amount of calories and nutrients per serving. But how many calories do you need to fuel your daily activities? The National Academy of Sciences makes the following daily calorie recommendations:

 1,600 calories is about right for many sedentary women and some older adults 2,200 calories is about right for most children, teenage girls, active women, and many sedentary men (Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding may need somewhat more.) 2,800 calories is about right for teenage boys, many active men, and some very active women 

Excess calorie consumption plays a major role in being overweight. The convenience of fast food restaurants, pre-packaged foods, and soft drinks affect our food choices. These are likely to be high in fat and calories. Large portion servings also increase caloric consumption. People who do not know the basics about nutrition or understand food labels are less likely to make healthy food choices. Carbohydrates, proteins, and fats are the major nutrient components of the diet. Carbohydrates and proteins provide 4 calories per gram, while fats contribute 9 calories per gram. Food choices and food preparation effect the amount of calories we consume. Most Americans follow meal plans that are much too high in fat. A diet low in fat will reduce the risk for getting certain diseases and help maintain a healthy weight. To lower fat intake, choose plenty of whole grain products, vegetables, and fruits that provide needed vitamins, minerals, fiber, and complex carbohydrates.

Keep the fat content of your foods to 30 percent or less. The total grams of fat for a 1,600 calorie diet would be 53, for a 2,200 calorie diet the total would be 73, and for a 2,800 calorie diet the total would be 93. Therefore, for a 30 percent fat diet, 837 calories of a 2,200 calorie diet may be fat calories. Counting fat grams has become popular. To determine the fat in the food you eat in terms of fat grams, read the food package label. It will tell you how many grams of fat and what kinds of fats are in each serving.

If there is a balance between your caloric intake and your activity level, you should maintain your weight. If your caloric intake increases and your activity level does not, you will probably gain weight. If you eat fewer calories and increase your activity level, you should lose weight.

 Last Reviewed 2005 

Disclaimer: This content is reviewed periodically and is subject to change as new health information becomes available. The information provided is intended to be informative and educational and is not a replacement for professional medical evaluation, advice, diagnosis or treatment by a healthcare professional.

HIL File NUTR3176.rf2 VRS# 7416 Data Version 7.0 Copyright 1999, 2003 McKesson Health Solutions LLC. All rights reserved.
 
 Email this Page | We Welcome Your Comments | Site Index A-Z 
 The University of Iowa | Copyright&amp;Disclaimer Statements 
 Printer Friendly page 

University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics
200 Hawkins Drive
Iowa City, Iowa 52242

 Last modification date:
 Thu Oct 19 14:47:38 2006 
 URL: http://www.uihealthcare.com
 /topics/nutrition/nutr3176.html
	</body>
</document>
