<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007234" url="http://www.lawknowledge.org/employment-labor-law/56638/" time="2012-07-13-00:12" support="14" score="0.01441047108308894" bingtitle="Employment &amp; Labor Law: Paying Employees less if they want medical ..." webtitle="Employment&amp;Labor Law: Paying Employees less if they want medical benefits Michigan - lawknowledge.org">
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000203" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>... legal to pay an employee less if they want to receive ... The next line states that if 16 consecutive hours ... I just started working at a drive-in fast food restaurant, working ...</description>
	<body>
		Home » LAW »
 Employment&amp;Labor Law (Employment,Labor Law) »Paying Employees less if they want medical benefits Michigan

 Employment&amp;Labor Family Law Real Estate Immigration Criminal Bankruptcy&amp;Credit Traffic Lawyers Accidents 
 LAW Category Accidents&amp;Personal Injury Law Additional Legal Subjects BANKRUPTCY&amp;CONSUMER CREDIT BUSINESS&amp;FINANCIAL&amp;Corporate LAW Consumer Law&amp;Fraud COURTS, LAWYERS&amp;LITIGATION CRIMINAL LAW&amp;PROCEDURE Employment&amp;Labor Law Family Law Government&amp;Administrative Law Immigration Law Insurance Law Intellectual Property Real Estate&amp;Property Law Tax Law Traffic Law Wills&amp;Trusts 

 Reference 
 
Paying Employees less if they want medical benefits Michigan
 Tags: benefits , company , dental , employee , employees , employer , employment , labor , law , legal , medical , michigan , pay , paying , receive Is it legal to pay an employee less if they want to receive medical and dental benefits from their employer? My company is thinking about giving the option to new hires to take a reduced hourly wage if they want to be eligible for medical and dental benefits, and, in the alternative, paying those who choose to waive their benefits more. Are there any laws or regulations that would prevent them from giving new hires this option? 10 Comments under it. 
 &quot; 
Employment&amp;Labor Law
 &quot; Open Questions Paying Doubletime in excess of 12hr days New Jersey We are a union shop and the contract states that hours worked in excess of 12 during a workday is paid at doubletime. The next line states that if 16 consecutive hours of work is performed - you are guaranteed doubletime for atleast 4 hours. My question is: If a 3rd shift employee whose normal...... Paying Company&apos;s Losses as a bartender i dealt with all the restaurant&apos;s money.
i was contacted by my boss 3 days after i worked to be 
told the draw was short $98. other people have access to 
the draw. i told him there was no way i could have been short. i refused to pay. we agreed on my leaving after 3 years at...... Paying commission to sales staff after termination Florida I am aware that the FL DOL is virtually non-existent, but I have a question about the law. We presently do not have a policy stating how commission is handled once a sales team member leaves our employ. We need to put something in our handbook. Do we have to have the same policy if the employee...... Paying children less for the same work? Hello Everyone,
Let me preface my question with my background. I am 17 years old, 18 this coming June. I have been working at my place of employment since I was 15 years old. I live in the state of Massachusetts.
When I was hired at my job, there is 3 weeks of technical support and customer...... Paying back wages What is the name of your state? Nebraska
I am a seasonal business, and when my employees were let go at the end of the season, I had yet to pay one of them, because of some slow paying recievables. He was very accomdating, and after sometime I got funding by factoring the accounts, so I could...... Paying back unemployment New Jersey I was working a job for 2 yrs,quit due to lack of income.Worked at another job off the books(owner never put me on)worked for her for 4 mo.I got fired from the last job for something insignificant.File UE,go through all the details etc.. with the examiner.He determines that I was fired for no...... Paying back Unemployment benefits California Back when I got fired from my job in January I filed for unemployment and collected it until I got a new job. However my weekend job was not too happy about it, and filed a claim and claimed that I could have worked full time with them. But I needed a&quot;better paying job&quot;and the reason...... Paying Back Tuition Assistance I voluntarily left my company. I had taken about $2400 in Tuition assistance - TA (something I considered a benefit.) On the company TA for it does state that after receiving the TA, a commitment to the company for 1 year would be necessary or the TA would have to be repaid. 
My question is, how...... paying back the draw What is the name of your state? Maine. I recently quit my job, and was told by my&quot;X&quot;employers that I have an outstanding draw. My last sale commission should cover the draw. the question is: can they NOT pay me my last commision, and still tell me I owe on the draw !?! Is this legal ?... paying back sign on bonus when i joined my current employer in late august 2000, i was given a substantial sign on bonus. i signed an agreement that stated that i would repay the bonus in the event of voluntary termination.
as it turns out, neither the company nor the position was as it had been represented and i choose...... 
 
 Post a Comment Now. Comments Wed, 09 Jul 2008 14:50:00 GMT (1) Aren&apos;t there problems with paying people to opt out of a health plan?

I know the new TriCare law is just a recent example of where that would be illegal. Fri, 11 Jul 2008 02:19:00 GMT (2) No sarcasm. A little silliness, maybe, but no sarcasm. :)

Thanks. Silliness is not necessarily a bad thing. ;)

Hey, when they were in machines in New York, they were called automats. Which was before even MY time. :D Wed, 09 Jul 2008 14:54:00 GMT (3) This would only be an option for new hires. The company wouldnt be compensating current employees for opting out of the health / dental plan they already have. Just for those coming in. Thu, 10 Jul 2008 16:08:00 GMT (4) I know the way it worked where I was once, was like this:

Insurance premiums cost $X per month, so they put it like this:

Benefits include $x per month. We can put it in as your insurance premium, or we can pay it to you directly.

I don&apos;t know how they worked it on the accounting side, but basically if we didn&apos;t need or want the insurance, they just gave us the premium they paid (supposedly) instead of paying it to the health insurance company. :)

That&apos;s the basic definition of a cafeteria plan. Wed, 09 Jul 2008 14:48:00 GMT (5) None at all. Fri, 11 Jul 2008 11:23:00 GMT (6) Is it legal to pay an employee less if they want to receive medical and dental benefits from their employer? My company is thinking about giving the option to new hires to take a reduced hourly wage if they want to be eligible for medical and dental benefits, and, in the alternative, paying those who choose to waive their benefits more. Are there any laws or regulations that would prevent them from giving new hires this option?

I cannot think of any law that prohibits this, but you can (should) encourage the use of the plans (I will not get on a soap box right now).

&quot;If you opt out of our insurance, you will be paid $X, if you opt in, you will be paid $Y.&quot;Their choice. The exact structure of the two options could be cost neutral for the company. Probably should be. Thu, 10 Jul 2008 16:23:00 GMT (7) Patty, has anyone ever told you you&apos;re full of helpful information? :D

I thought it might have been called that, but was thinking &apos;why would they call something related to insurance&quot;cafeteria&quot;, that would be silly.&apos; Apparently the only silly thing about it was me. LOL

If you weren&apos;t being sarcastic, thanks. :D

It&apos;s called a&quot;cafeteria&quot;plan, I figure, because there are a list of benefits and the employee can pick and choose which ones they want, or none of them.

Are there even cafeterias any more? Now I guess they call them&quot;buffets&quot;, except the cafeterias I remember, all the food items were already plated up separately and you just added a gazillion little plates to your tray. :) Thu, 10 Jul 2008 17:01:00 GMT (8) If you weren&apos;t being sarcastic, thanks. :D

It&apos;s called a&quot;cafeteria&quot;plan, I figure, because there are a list of benefits and the employee can pick and choose which ones they want, or none of them.

Are there even cafeterias any more? Now I guess they call them&quot;buffets&quot;, except the cafeterias I remember, all the food items were already plated up separately and you just added a gazillion little plates to your tray. :)

No sarcasm. A little silliness, maybe, but no sarcasm. :)

Colleges have cafeterias, and schools, from what I know, but no cafeteria style restaurants that I know of. :)

Edit: I think, maybe, they called them cafeteria because maybe &apos;ala-carte&apos; hadn&apos;t been, I dunno, coined yet? Thu, 10 Jul 2008 15:49:00 GMT (9) This would only be an option for new hires. The company wouldnt be compensating current employees for opting out of the health / dental plan they already have. Just for those coming in.

I know the way it worked where I was once, was like this:

Insurance premiums cost $X per month, so they put it like this:

Benefits include $x per month. We can put it in as your insurance premium, or we can pay it to you directly.

I don&apos;t know how they worked it on the accounting side, but basically if we didn&apos;t need or want the insurance, they just gave us the premium they paid (supposedly) instead of paying it to the health insurance company. :) Thu, 10 Jul 2008 16:12:00 GMT (10) That&apos;s the basic definition of a cafeteria plan.

Patty, has anyone ever told you you&apos;re full of helpful information? :D

I thought it might have been called that, but was thinking &apos;why would they call something related to insurance&quot;cafeteria&quot;, that would be silly.&apos; Apparently the only silly thing about it was me. LOL Post a Comment Now. 

 Maybe you&apos;re interest in these... Deceptive use of POA before&amp;after death [ Wills&amp;Trusts ] What is the name of your state? Alabama 
My father&apos;s widow used his power of attorney after his death to cash checks that were made payable to him only. She also used his POA while he was still living to manipulate funds against his wishes. We (his two kids and executors of his estate) did not......... credit card harassment ? [ BANKRUPTCY&amp;CONSUMER CREDIT ] What is the name of your state? nj
i have a credit card with sears, i&apos;ve had it for several years. i have a balance of 10k , and i fell behind on 1 payment, and i am getting hit with late fees every month and a very high interest rate. i pay the $300 every month and just because i fell behind on......... Company went bankrupt, now trying to get $ from us?!?! [ BANKRUPTCY&amp;CONSUMER CREDIT ] We are from CA, but lived in AZ for a year, now working in Kuwait since DEC. (Complicated I know).
Well here is the story:
My husband went to a pilot school located in Avondale, AZ for about 2 or so months called Makarion(sp?). Well it was one of those flight schools that was&quot;go at you......... consequences [ Real Estate&amp;Property Law ] I have 3 months left on my lease contract here in TX. A few months ago I was going to buy a house but decided not to since I was told that if I will still be responsible for the remainder of the lease however if I fulfill half the term of my lease I will only be charged the reletting fee. 
Since......... Andy is an Idiot [ Tax Law ]&quot;AK&quot;&lt;ak-in-nc.lawknowledge.org.mchsi.com&gt;wrote That&apos;s an old worn out tactic....... Wanting IRS to act like a professional organization is hardly a&quot;psychological&quot;problem, but a good smear is always a perfect stooge response from a vile excuse of a being. Let&apos;s see, you smeared me......... Divorce Lawyer Info [ Additional Legal Subjects ] http://wagnerlegal.blogspot.com/...... leaving state [ Family Law ] What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? Minnesota
Heres the situation. I have 9 mo. old twins and left the father while I was pregnant due to abuse issues. We were not married. Now that child support contacted him we had to go to court to establish paternity. So of course he wants them......... Expo Facto Law [ Government&amp;Administrative Law ] How would expo facto law apply to the below case: City brings homeowner to court on violation of an ordinance for a nonconforming use. Judge issues specific direction during court proceedings that are in the transcript regarding the nonconforming use to the homeowner and dismisses the case.......... Navy Question [ Government&amp;Administrative Law ] Im sure you all read my previous post. Sorry to post again, Is an admin sep from the navy reserve (less than 180 days) considered a discharge? (Like I said I just want out) If so what type is it. I work for the gov in civilian life and don&apos;t want to mess anything up....... Is a Post Traumatic Syndrome a disability? [ Government&amp;Administrative Law ] Is a Post Traumatic Syndrome a disability?...... 
 
 &quot;Employment&amp;Labor Law&quot; Headlines Paying Employees 1 day late New Jersey Paying company back for draws against commission upon termination in North Dakota paying cash in ca California Paying by Shift? Michigan Paying bonus pay Indiana Paying Back workmans comp? Paying Back Vacation When Terminated Minnesota Paying Back Unemployment Insurance&amp;Lump Sum Severance Payment - Michigan Paying back STD paying back sick time 

 LAW Blogs Tax Types and Numeric Tax Codes (Virginia Department of Taxation) OVERTIME IS THE LAW! The Fiduciary Exception to the Attorney-Client Privilege -- Physician Sentenced for Private Health Insurance Fraud New Court Ruling Renders U.S. Anti-Subsidy Law Inapplicable to China Purchasing Workers&apos;Compensation Insurance (Pennsylvania) Workers&apos;Compensation&amp;the Injured Worker (Commonwealth of Pennsylvania) 2011 in Review: The Year Secrecy Jumped the Shark Israeli Firm Allot Communications Ltd Under Fire for Selling Spyware to Iran Election Law 

 &quot; Employment&amp;Labor Law &quot; Related Questions Paying back short till out of pocket Idaho I just started working at a drive-in fast food restaurant, working as a carhop. My first day exchanging money, I was short on my till, and the manager made me pay back the amount out of my tip money. It was not much, but it seems like an unethical behavior activity for an employer to do. My...... Paying Back Relocation Expenses to Ex-Employer My ex-employer has sued me in the Hamilton court in Cincinnati, Ohio to recover a relocation package that was given to me in February 2005. (I live in Calif now).. I was living in Cincinnati then and was working for the company in Northern Kentucky, across the river. The package of $5000.00 was...... Paying back overpayment of wages Alabama Heres the situation......recently we found out that several police and firefighters were put into the wrong step in the pay scale and after complaing about it our city went back and are now in the process of paying backpay to around 18 people as well as giving them a pay raise to where they were...... Paying back over payment after employment terminated New Jersey Hi, I work in NJ and have viewed previous responses about overpayment, which I have no problem with repaying, but I have questions to what rights I have . I resigned with two week notice and worked my agreed time, but received three extra paychecks (six weeks). I contacted my former employer and...... paying back moving allowance What is the name of your state?What is the name of your state? California
Hi, I&apos;m not sure if I&apos;m in the right forum, but here goes...
I am from overseas and have been working in the USA on an L-1 visa since Feb 1 2005. I was provided a moving allowance to get here, and signed a contract that...... Paying back moving $ What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? MI
If you got laid off or fired (not for cause) just days before you were to fulfill a moving allowance commitment have you seen a company actually try to collect? I&apos;d find it hard to believe a jury wouldn&apos;t see right through the employer&apos;s...... Paying back mistakes We&apos;re in Georgia,
My Wife was working for a small loan finance company. During the course of a day&apos;s business money was brought in for payments and paid out for small loans. If at the end of the day, the&quot;Drawer&quot;came up short, she was required to pay the money back, now if the drawer...... Paying back employer What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? Hawaii
I work for a university. I am a temporary employee. I submit my timesheet only for the record-keeper to keep in case of audit, and I am on salary style pay, so the timesheet is not necessarily a requirement for me to get paid. My boss, who...... paying back a hiring bonus What is the name of your state? CA
I signed a 12-month contract to work for the federal government. This included a hiring bonus, and it was stipulated in the contract that if I left before 12 months, I would have to pay back the bonus on a pro-rated rate. The bonus was paid to me in a lump sum,...... Paying back a cash shortage I work for a not for profit in the state of NJ and am required to settle my cash at the end of the day. I was told during training that I would be required to pay back any shortfalls in my receipts. I have been lucky so far, but other co-workers have had to pay back cash. Is this legal in NJ?... Paying An Employee for a Wife&apos;s volunteer work Missouri Can a company increase the wage of an employee to account for his wife volunteering for the company? Doesn&apos;t that violate&quot;wage and hour&quot;or at least social security laws?... Paying 100% Commission Utah Hello, I am a fairly new company, and am looking to hire some sales people. I want to pay them 100% commission. Can a W-2 employee be paid strictly on commission, or does it have to be a 1099 at that point? I would like to have them considered more of an employee then an independent contractor,...... paying $1.00 a minute to be late What is the name of your state? Tennessee
I work at an agency that is subcontracted to the state of Tn, we provide care for adults with mental disabilities. Many of us are called companions, we live in our service recipiants (SR) home. we provide for all their immediate needs, and assist them in...... payed wrong due to comp program Washington Our company implemented a computerized payroll system about 10 months ago. About 6 months ago people started having BIG problems with their pay. Some people had large amounts deducted from their checks with no understanding of why. When payroll was questioned about this, often times they could...... Payed to Drive? Florida Hi all, Hope someone can answer my question or either direct me to a link that can. Sometimes we require our employees to travel out of town to install cabinets at a jobsite - using our vehicles. Are we required to pay them for their drive time to the jobsite? My husband says yes, I say I&apos;m not...... Payed Time Off after Resignation New Jersey I resigned from my employer as an exempt employee after about 8 years with the company. Being it is&quot;at will&quot;employment at the company, in short, I pretty much sent an e-mail saying I resigned now and won&apos;t be coming to work anymore. I was wondering if there are any laws in New Jersey...... 
 
 lawknowledge.org is one of your best friends, we&apos;ll greah appreciate if you tell us what&apos;s you want to know and pinpoint the weakness of us. Function Links: Content Directory Latest Questions Popular Tags Free to Join us Map.XML Find To us: About us Advertise Contact DMCA Help/Faqs Links Privacy Terms of Use ©2001-2012 lawknowledge.org, LLC. All rights reserved. lawknowledge.org does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Application: 375.00 ms
	</body>
</document>
