<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007493" url="http://preferredmerchantservices.net/wireless.html" time="2012-07-13-00:28" support="12" score="0.031145997246583543" bingtitle="Preferred Merchant Services - Payment Processing Made Simple" webtitle="Preferred Merchant Services - Payment Processing Made Simple">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>The fact is, cash and checks can get lost and credit card information, if not put in a secure place, can get into the wrong hands between the time the information was ...</description>
	<body>
		Agent Login Merchant Login Give us a Call 1(877) 767-2500 
 Products Select any one of our products below Credit Card Processing Debit Card Processing EBT Processing Gift Cards MOTO Processing Wireless Processing Industry Solutions We service a wide range of industries Retail Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant Hospitality Petroleum Cash Advance Equipment Browse our catalog of various machines and solutions Our Firm Our Firm About Us Careers Contact Us PCI Compliance Apply Now Privacy Policy 
 
We carry a wide range of SOLUTIONS for accepting any form of ELECTRONIC payments. Preferred Merchant services does more than what any other merchant will or can do for you. We are the leaders in this industry.
 
 See what we can do for you Talk to our specialist about your needs, we will then find a solution to meet your business 
 
Wireless Processing

Wireless Credit Card Processing

Society has acquired a new mind set that things should be done instantly. As this mind set continues to grow, the demand for accessibility and instant satisfaction grows as well. Instead of using carbon machines to pay for items, more people are using telephones and computers. Everything is faster in today&apos;s world. A wireless transaction will take 2.5 seconds of a consumer&apos;s time, as compared to 12-20 seconds for dial-up terminals.
 
Accept Payments Anywhere

Whether you have a service business that works at your customer&apos;s location, or if you take your retail business on the road, wireless processing is an easy and cost-effective way to accept credit cards wherever your customers happen to be.Before m-commerce solutions became available, collecting funds for orders done &quot;on the road&quot; required people to either pay by cash, check, or write down their credit card information so you could process the transaction later back at your office.
 
Benefits

The fact is, cash and checks can get lost and credit card information, if not put in a secure place, can get into the wrong hands between the time the information was taken down and the customers card was charged. m-commerce solutions have taken a lot of the hassles out of doing business &quot;on the run.&quot; Improved cash flow Secure credit and debit card authorizations within a matter of seconds Reduced instances of credit card fraud and charge backs Ability to conduct business where phone line connections don&apos;t exist 
 
 Our other services and products All Retail Solutions Restaurant&amp;Cafe Solutions Quick Serve Restaurant (QSR) Any Hospitality Solutions Petroleum Solutions (Gas Stations) Cash Advance 
 Preferred Merchant Services LLC is a registered ISO/MSP of Wells Fargo Bank, N.A., Walnut Creek, CA About Us PCI Compliance
	</body>
</document>
