<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007074" url="http://ipohchai.com/teppanyaki-fast-food-restaurant-ipoh-greentown.php" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="34" score="0.0960261064983695" bingtitle="Teppanyaki fast food restaurant ipoh greentown - Ipoh Chai" webtitle="Teppanyaki fast food restaurant ipoh greentown - Ipoh Chai">
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001472" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>It is said that this is a fast food restaurant but I didn’t count how fast the food arrive upon my ... With so much issue in the line which never seems to come to an end ...</description>
	<body>
		Recent Topics Ipoh Food Welcome to IpohChai.com Recent Comments Take a break to Kuala Lumpur 
 Bukit Tambun Seafood @ HoHo Food World 
 Bird Photography at Kinta Bird Sanctuary Batu Gajah 
 The Melaka River Cruise 
 Trip to Melaka A Farmosa Water World 
 Fireworks at Station 18 
 Paintball Game In Ipoh 
 Sungkai Choy Kee Braised Pork Knuckle 
 The LimeStone Fine Dining Restaurant 
 Qiu Ji Restaurant Pengkalan 
 Buffet Dinner at Old Generation Seri Botani 
 Wasabe Japanese Restaurant Buffet 
 Onix Jun Korean Restaurant Ipoh Garden 
 andrew ~ these stall have already move 
 kompius ~ is unique seafood restaurant i 
 Lester Leong ~ You all right all are cheater 
 Lester Leong ~ Any address , please ? 
 Lester Leong ~ That&apos;s no good at all dont ge 
Foods lover. ~ Most famous laksa owner and mo 
 11 Feb 
Teppanyaki Fast Food Restaurant Ipoh Greentown
 Comments Ipoh Food This recently opened Tepanyaki restaurant serve a varieties of Japanese Tepanyaki dishes in a very simple manner at a very affordable price. 

When you talk about Japanese food, the first thing in mind would be the hefty price it came along with, especially when you enter a restaurant which is specializes in the Japanese food. You certainly not going off without paying more than RM30 per person for a moderate order. Japanese foods are expensive for good reason. The ingredients are mostly imported and there aren&apos;t many good chef which could made good authentic Japanese food around.

And one thing which bears in my mind about Japanese food is its presentation. Japanese culinary is a fine art which takes a good long time to master. From a simple plate of Sushi to a everything-in-one plate of Teppanyaki, you could see everything is very well arranged and looks very nice when served. Taste good or not, that is the next thing you need to discover.
 
Enough talk about this authentic Japanese foodstuff here. Just today, I came across this self claim fast food restaurant serving Teppanyaki dishes in Greentown, Ipoh. If Im not mistaken, this place was formerly the Kimberly Cafe which I reviewed before.

Here, you will find some less authentic Tepanyaki dishes at a very affordable price.
 
You wont find a Teppanyaki bar in the restaurant where you could see the chef prepares the Teppanyaki food right in front of the customers. It is all prepared in the kitchen and god-know-how-it-was-cooked.

It is said that this is a fast food restaurant but I didnt count how fast the food arrive upon my order but it is rather fast since we are the only customer there at the time, lol.

Looking at the menu, I could see their Teppanyaki dishes is served in several way such as Teppanyaki in tin foil, serve with either plain rice or fried rice or even Teppanyaki with Udon noodle. Price starting from RM6.90 which is really cheap.
 
I had a cup of Champagne milk shake and wifey had the guava juice. In addition, we get treated with some pineapple tart cookies. Yummy.
 
I had this Garupa Fillet Teppanyaki served with rice. Well, it was rather plain simple though. Just a bunch of bean sprout and then a few slices of fish fillet with a cup of plain rice. And the fish fillet was like baked in the oven instead of grilled on the Tepanyaki pan. If you wanted to know how this thing tastes, well, it was just so-so only lah.
You get what you pay for and it is really true in this case.
 
This is the Teppanyaki Fried Udon Cuttle Fish . There are ample of Udon noodle and cuttle fish too making it a very filling dish. The taste is rather mild and Im sure it would taste much better with a few more drops of Teriyaki and Soy sauce on it.

Serve along with the dishes is some Sambal Chilli which is kicking hot. Sambal chilli is certainly Japanese and I aint sure how they had this idea but I guess they just try to create another fusion between Japanese cuisines to our local favor.
 
Here is our local kind of Wasabi, our infamous Kampung Koh chilli sauce, hahaha! Ask you die or not.
 
The bill sum up to RM31.00 and the cashier didnt mind treating us another 2 pieces of Cloud9 Lemon Tea candy. So sweet.

Overall, the food here is just normal. Though it is below my expectation of what a Teppanyaki should be but the price explain everything.

This is a place for those who want a taste of Teppanyaki-like dishes at a less throat-cutting price.
Also Note*
Unlimited refill of hot / cold Green Tea
No Pork
No Service Charge

 Teppanyaki Fast Food Restaurant 
27, Persiaran Greentown 7,
Pusat Perdagangan Greentown,
30450 Ipoh, Perak.
Located next to Yeolde English

Tel 05-2548136

GPS Location: 435&apos;57&quot;N 1015&apos;47&quot;E 

 




 Read Also 
 Sungkai Choy Kee Braised Pork Knuckle 
 The LimeStone Fine Dining Restaurant 
 Qiu Ji Restaurant Pengkalan 
 Buffet Dinner at Old Generation Seri Botani 
 Wasabe Japanese Restaurant Buffet 



 Comments 
 #1 Jonath Lee (2010-02-13)
Tried this restaurant last year, overall consider okay, price weren&apos;t expensive. But they really need to gives more choices in their menu. Please Comment
 *Name
 Homepage
*Your Comment Here
 
Cheap Earrings, Bracelet, Necklace and Accessories at www.MyQQHouse.com Subscribe Feed Get Updates by Email 
Enter your email:
 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 Friendly Links 
 + iCalvyn.com 
+ Reanaclaire 
+ Ipoh Mali 
+ Paid Banner 
+ kimikoculinary 
+ Ontechnews 
+ RawPotato 
+ Teng2Teng 
+ MyloveMyfood 
+ Mecha Fans 
+ Celine&apos;s Blog 
+ Mushiemoshiu 
+ Steven&apos;s expression 
+ Jonath Lee 
+ Just Me N Us 
+ Weng Kit Journal 
+ SembangNTalk 
+ Johnny Ong 
+ Tekkaus 
+ Ipoh Motormouth 
 
 Popular Post 
 Arcade games of the past 
Some of the well known arcade games which I enjoyed during my teenage time

 Weekend at Sungai Klah Hot Spring Park 
It has been a tiring working week. With so much issue in the line which never seems to come to an end and tonnes of assignments which never seems would finish. So much headache and I really wanted to set free and relax my mind.

 Big Apple Donut Kinta City 
While Krispe Kreme and J.Co is being well known for their delicious donut, Big Apple is another new face in the donut maket and it is available at Kinta City, Ipoh.

 Nasi Ganja - Addictive as Marijuana 
The infamous addictive curry rice of Ipoh. What makes this food so addictive as it was like Marijuana!

 My Brother In Laws Nursery 
This is the story about my brother in law&apos;s nursery and farm in Ringlet, Cameron Highlands.

 Kizuna Japanese Restaurant 
There has been quite an amount of Japanese Restaurant operating around the Medan Ipoh lately and the Kizuna was one of the good one.

 Fo Guang Shan Dong Zen Temple 
The beauty of Fo Guang Shan Dong Zen Temple Flora Festival 2007.

 The Lost World of Tambun at Sunway City Ipoh 
Just spent another day at Ipoh&apos;s premier water park.

 Navigation 
 Archive 
 Sitemap 
 Contact Me 
 RSS Post 
 RSS Comment 
 Categories 
 About . Blogging . Cameron Highlands . Crap . Events . Funny . Ipoh Food . Ipohchai Kids . Me . Out of Ipoh . Places of Ipoh . Review . Tech Gadget . Travel Blog . Whats Cooking . Whats Up . Template design by IpohChai IpohChai 2008 All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
