<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007662" url="http://www.holidaywatchdog.com/4947-Altea-SH_Melia_Villa_Gadea_Beach_Hotel-Holiday-Review.html" time="2012-07-13-00:37" support="67" score="0.14464200334089566" bingtitle="SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel Reviews - Altea, Costa Blanca ..." webtitle="SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel Reviews - Altea, Costa Blanca - Holiday Watchdog™">
			<query id="001384" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001410" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000058" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000299" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001522" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001517" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001391" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001036" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000048" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001455" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000494" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001406" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000295" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001061" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001401" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001463" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000490" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000493" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000352" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001382" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001465" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000469" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000485" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001056" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001046" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000848" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000291" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001454" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001532" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000863" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001397" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000033" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000309" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000858" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000356" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000346" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001507" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001392" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001051" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000361" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000043" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001460" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000371" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000857" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000873" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001470" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001445" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000285" bing-rank="7"/>
	<description>... experience was similar to eating in a fast food restaurant ... was cold with poor choice, nowhere near 5 ... Security laws are strict and it does take some time for reception ...</description>
	<body>
		Join us on: Facebook Twitter Sign in  /  Register Holiday Reviews 
 Holidays&amp;Hotels Beach Holidays Cruise Forums Package Holidays Add Photos Write A Review 
 Home &gt; Europe &gt; Spain &gt; Costa Blanca &gt; Altea Holidays &gt; SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel 
SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel
 , Altea 5 star Partida Villa Gadea

03590,
 Altea,
 Spain More hotel photos Find great package holiday deals in Altea 
SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel reviews
 Sort by Date | Rating Although the building was superb the... 1 / 10 Oct 2007 , Mrs Jen Wright 
 Although the building was superb the rest was disappointing. The staff were very off-hand and uninterested. The hotel was full of very young children, making a lot of noise around the pool and in the dining room. For a 5 star hotel, this was not acceptable. Our evening meal... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 Whilst the bulding and accomodation... 3 / 10 Oct 2007 , Mr A S  Pace 
 Whilst the bulding and accomodation appear 5 star, the service, food and quailty could only be rated at 3 star at best. The dining experience was similar to eating in a fast food restaurant and the pool area was more like a children&apos;s playground. Nowhere in the hotel could... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 After having returned from Altea last... 9 / 10 Sep 2007 , Ms M McMonagle 
 1 reader found this review helpful

 After having returned from Altea last week I felt I should input an updated customer view of the Melia Villa Gadea. We have spent a week at the hotel with 70 friends and family as we decided to have our wedding reception there under good advise from a friend. The wedding... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 The building is very grand and the... 3 / 10 Aug 2007 , Mr W Wright 
 The building is very grand and the rooms are 5 star. The first meal that we had was dreadful. The cafeteria was full of small children screaming and crying. The food was cold with poor choice, nowhere near 5 stars. The hotel seemed to be offering a cheap deal for families... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 I would agree with the last reviewer.... 9 / 10 Jan 2006 , Mrs S Elwood 
 I would agree with the last reviewer. We stayed at this hotel in Dec 2005 and found it to be excellent. The hotel was clearly new, but there were no ongoing building works. The room was spacious, clean and comfortable. The staff were generally friendly and helpful. The... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 I do not believe that the previous... 9 / 10 Sep 2005 , Not Specified 
 I do not believe that the previous report refers to the Villa Gadea Hotel in Altea and if it does I can quite categorically state that is is absolute nonsense. POSSIBLE SOUR GRAPES FROM THE LOCAL COMPETITION! I could never imagine their own reservation manager suggesting... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 We arrived in July after being told... 1 / 10 Jul 2005 , Mrs W Wicks 
 We arrived in July after being told it was complete to find it was half finished its like a 3star hotel And the worst holiday i have ever had. The reservation manager at the hotel agreed that it wasn’t worthy of the 5star rating and also informed us that it wouldn’t be... more 
 Show Prices 
Was this review helpful? Yes 
 Read 50 additional reviews of SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel Stayed at SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel? Share your insight. Write A Review Add Photos 
More Traveller reviews of SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel
 Apartments from Pj Like an earlier reviewer we stayed in a private apartment on the Villa Gadea development. We share his comments about the quality of the apartments and the development - which is beautifully landscaped and where each relatively small block shares its own private pool and garden. However two things to note. The adjacent Melia hotel has had a clampdown on apartment renters using their facilities - apparently claiming that this benefit is for apartment owners only (this personally didn&apos;t bother us but maybe if you have younger children it... more Great Location, Grea Rooms, Weird Atmosphere from AlyP I have been going to Altea for ovr 10 years and know the area very well and have stayed at the Altea Hills Melia Resort several times and was very impressed. Couldn&apos;t wait to sample to Villa Gadea, especially as the location is so good, right on the beach. Overall we were impressed, the room was excellent, very big with a beautiful bathroom. Lovely sea view balcony, cleanliness tip-top. Breakfast was a banquet and the staff are very courteous and helpful. Our only critism, and this is the second time we stayed, first was in April 2006... more Great Stay from holidayreviews Great stay in the height of a very busy Spanish holiday season Staff courteous, helpful and great with my children. We had a junior suite that had two bathrooms and a double interconnecting door that was most welcome and enabled my husband and I to some much needed privacy at the end of busy days. Both the children’s area and ours lead through french doors onto a superb large balcony with an outdoor jacuzzi overlooking the stunning Muscarat Bay (for those of you who know the area). On one occasion when we were all very tired... more Stay in the Hotel - but not quite. from A2MCH Some local people we know advised us to stay within the hotel complex, but not actually in the hotel - and boy what good advice they gave. As you enter the hotel grounds if you look to your left you will see a series of reasonably high rise apartments. These are privately owned apartments who enjoy the full run of the 5 star facilities of the hotel. The very spacious apartments are stunning and have every mod con you could think of. Heated flooring? check. Jackuzzi on your balcony? check. minimalist modern furniture? check.... more Best Melia of the Costa Blanca from JWETS I stayed in the Villa Gadea for 5 days and can only confirm the previous comments- exellent service - beautiful and spacious rooms - outstanding breakfast buffet with lots of attention to details and service. Only take care the hotel is about 2,5 km from the town centre. The spa centre is exceptional well equipped although not cheap but worth every penny. Would recommend this hotel to people looking for quality and good service. Nice Hotel, Pity About The Service from LeanneDelaney They say first impressions are important and it was certainly the case when we met the 1st member of staff who just so happened to be the Reception Manager! However, lets go back a little. Parking facilities - check, impressive lobby - check, chic minimal decoration - check.... Checking in experience - horrific. As probably many of us have experienced, when using an online booker, for some reason there is sometimes a black hole in the communication between hotel and booker whereby your confirmed reservation gets lost in the... more Lovely Hotel and Staff - a few demerits.. from AcesGlasgow_UK My wife and I have just returned from an excellent, seven nights holiday in Altea. This hotel is a top standard accommodation which we paid 105 euros a night - booking direct using the Sol Melia website. This rate is off-peak, however there was no mention of which features would be unavailable on the website. Check in was very efficient (use the tip in the review below). The room was very good, although the TV reception was dire. There is marble everywhere you look in this hotel, so no expense was spared. The beach front is still... more best hotel in altea from A TripAdvisor Member we stayed in the melia villa gadea in the middle of october, bargain promotion price of 50euros a night for two. fantastic room with seaview and the old town of altea in the distance. I must say the service in reception was excellent [tip]become a member of melia hotels, not only post e -mails for special offers like we had but check in is less than 5 mins as they already have your details on file. We stayed last july05 in the melia altea hills hotel, so checked out the villa gadea for the day, loved the hotel, pools and facilities on offer,... more Superb New (June 2005) Altea Hotel from devaney10 SH Hotels have spared very little expense in constructing the more than worthy 5 star Villa Gadea Hotel. It is a superb example of contemporary meets Spanish design. First impressions on arrival were excellent and when we entered the hotels welcoming reception area we were not disappointed. Reception was not busy and we were looked after quickly and efficiently. Security laws are strict and it does take some time for reception to complete the necessary documentation to provide to the local police on a daily basis. This is not the hotel... more Brand new hotel with LOTS of teething problems from travelbug2 The hotel is final part of the Villa Gadea complex to be built just outside of Altea. Residence Villa Gadea is apartment buildings and villas grouped around many pools and gorgeous gardens on a small cliff top overlooking sea - very quiet and peaceful and lovely views (beach lovers please bear in mind that although the sea is beautifully crystal clear, the beaches here are shingle/pebbles). The hotel opened in June 2005 (still some construction work going on) and as I was staying in one of the apartments for a week I wanted to try out... more Click here for best prices on SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel, Altea Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Buchen Sie online! 
 Hotels.com Karten&amp;Bewertungen zu mehr als 140.000 Hotels weltweit! Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Top-Angebote inkl. Flug 
 weg.de Testsieger der STIFTUNG WARENTEST Jetzt sicher online buchen und sparen! Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Deutschlands bester Preis 
 Travel24.com 50 Euro Urlaubsgeld gratis dazu! TÜV geprüft - Jetzt hier buchen! Hotel SH Villa Gadea: von Holidaytest geprüft 
 Reisen.de Mehr als 200.000 echte Bewertungen 50 Euro Geld-zurück-Gutschein Sponsored links 
SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel also called

 SH Altea Beach Hotel sh melia hotel gadea beach Address: Partida Villa Gadea

03590, Altea, Spain 
 
Traveller Ratings
 Write a review Overall 7.5  /  10 72 reviews Brilliant 33 Good 16 Average 6 Poor 10 Awful 7 Room 8.5/10 Service 7.5/10 Value 7/10 Cleanliness 8.5/10 Location 8/10 Hotel Amenities Hotel Description 
 Bar/lounge Fitness Centre Restaurant Room Service Suites Swimming Pool Wheelchair Access 
 Rooms: 206 — More Amenities Click here for best prices on SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel, Altea Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Hier zum Bestpreis buchen 
 ab-in-den-urlaub.de Jetzt günstig&amp;bequem buchen bei Deutschlands Reise-Plattform Nr.1! Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Jetzt buchen und sparen! 
 Booking.com Hervorragende Wahl. Niedrige Preise! Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Sparen Sie jetzt! 
 Expedia.de Unglaubliche Angebote für über 120.000 Hotels in der ganzen Welt. Hotel SH Villa Gadea: Inklusive Frühstück 
 Olotels.com Finden sie hier die besten preise Sponsored links Share your opinion with other travellers. Write a review. 
View Map of SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel
 
Similar Hotels around Altea
 
 Villaitana Wellness Golf&amp;Business Sun Resort 5 star 7.5 / 10 54 reviews Gran Hotel Bali 4 star 6.5 / 10 932 reviews Belroy Hotel 4 star 7.5 / 10 35 reviews Dynastic Park Hotel 4 star 7 / 10 540 reviews Flamingo Oasis Benidorm Hotel 4 star 8 / 10 1,453 reviews 
 
Hotels Near SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel
 distance (miles) rating 
 Melia Altea Hills Resort Melia Altea Hills Resort Check Availability 1.4 8/10 Hotel Kaktus Albir Hotel Kaktus Albir Check Availability 3.8 7.5/10 Albir Playa Hotel Albir Playa Hotel Check Availability 4 8.5/10 Venus Albir Hotel Venus Albir Hotel Check Availability 4.2 7.5/10 Albir Garden Apartments Albir Garden Apartments Check Availability 4.4 6.5/10 
 Looking for a beach holiday? Get ideas here 
Explore Altea
 Altea Holidays Costa Blanca Holidays Altea Forum Nearby Airports Alicante (ALC) 37.4 miles Popular Holiday Destinations Benalmadena Holidays Canary Islands Holidays Crete Holidays Puerto Del Carmen Holidays San Antonio Bay Holidays Other Featured Hotels BelleVue Club Puerto Alcudia Dunas Mirador Maspalomas Hotel Maspalomas Eden Apartments Puerto Rico Grand Aquarium Apartments Icmeler Grand Hotel Central Barcelona Iberostar Epidaurus Hotel Cavtat Ionis Art Hotel Laganas Palmeramar Apartments Puerto Rico Radisson SAS Baypoint Hotel St Julians San Valentine Hotel Son Bou 
Do you own SH Melia Villa Gadea Beach Hotel?

 Promote your business with Holiday Watchdog content To respond to a review, use the Management Response Form 
 
 
The Holiday Reviews and other views posted on Holiday Watchdog are that of the visitors that have submitted them and are NOT the opinion of Holiday Watchdog.
 Holiday Watchdog Hotel&amp;Holiday Reviews, Vacation Reviews&amp;Independent Travel Review and Travel Advice. 
 Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Statement About / Contact Owners 
 ©Copyright 2012 TripAdvisor Ltd Registered in England and Wales No. 5612751 All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
