<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007665" url="http://eating-out.knoji.com/10-restaurant-salads-you-should-avoid/" time="2012-07-13-00:38" support="5" score="0.006948739152120149" bingtitle="10 Restaurant Salads You Should Avoid — Knoji" webtitle="10 Restaurant Salads You Should Avoid">
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Choosing a taco salad at a fast food restaurant is usually a ... We&apos;ve sent a confirmation link to your email address. ... members can ask on Knoji each day in order to ...</description>
	<body>
		Companies Coupons Reviews Q&amp;A; Articles Sign in Join Consumer 
 Knowledge ASK A QUESTION WRITE AN ARTICLE About Knoji Contact Help Forum Facebook Twitter Google+ Top Summer Deals on Hotels Follow @knojinetwork Babies&amp;Kids Baby Products Child Safety Childcare&amp;Nannies Clothing&amp;Fashion Contests Furniture Reading&amp;Education Toys Video, Games, Apps&amp;Websites Business&amp;Office Books, Certifications&amp;Reference Branding, Design&amp;Promotion Business Software&amp;IT Conferences&amp;Events Customer, Salesforce&amp;CRM Freelance Hiring Loans, Financing&amp;Insurance Market Research Tools Marketing Services Office Equipment&amp;Supply Payment Processing Payroll, Accounting&amp;Invoicing Productivity Tools Recruiting, Hiring&amp;Training Retail&amp;Restaurant Telephone&amp;Voice Department Stores Department Stores Electronics Books, DVD, Music&amp;Games Camera&amp;Photo Computer Accessories Computers&amp;Laptops Consumer Electronics Electronics, Parts&amp;Repair Internet Access, Voice&amp;Video PC Tuneup, Repair&amp;Recovery Phones, Tablets&amp;Mobile Software Fashion Customized Fashion Fashion Memberships&amp;Clubs Handbags&amp;Accessories Jewelry&amp;Watches Kid&amp;Teen Fashion Materials, Fabrics&amp;DIY Men&apos;s Clothing Personal Shoppers Shoes Specialty Fashion Underwear&amp;Sleepwear Women&apos;s Clothing Health&amp;Beauty Beauty Supply Cosmetics&amp;Makeup Dental Care Dieting&amp;Weight Loss Eye Care&amp;Vision Hair Care Health Experts&amp;Advice Massage&amp;Spa Nail Care Pharmacy&amp;Drugs Sexual Health Skin Care Sleep, Memory&amp;Aging Smoking Cessation Supplements&amp;Vitamins Home Appliances Automotive Bedding Emergency Preparedness Energy&amp;Utilities Food, Cooking&amp;Grocery Furniture Gardening Gifts, Crafts&amp;Hobbies Home Accessories Home Cleaning Home Improvement Home Security Interior Decor&amp;Accessories Kitchen Patio, Yards&amp;Grills Pets Pools&amp;Hot Tubs Senior Products Weddings, Events&amp;Parties Online Business Data Backup&amp;Sync E-Commerce Tools&amp;Services Internet Security Mobile Marketing&amp;Advertising Online Advertising Online Marketing Online Meeting Tools Online Printing Payment Processing Productivity Tools Publishing Tools SEO, PR&amp;Visibility Voice, Fax&amp;Telephone Web Hosting&amp;Domains Website Development Website Performance&amp;Optimization Personal Services Charity&amp;Fundraising Classifieds, Listings&amp;Auctions College, Textbooks&amp;Test Prep Coupons, Deals&amp;Rewards Gaming, Entertainment&amp;Video Insurance Investing&amp;Retirement Job Search Learning, Language&amp;Reference Legal Services Loans, Banking&amp;Credit Music Online Dating Online Education&amp;Training People Search&amp;Geneology Personal Productivity Tools Photo-Related Services Real Estate&amp;Moving Spirituality, Motivation&amp;Religion Taxes, Budgeting&amp;Accounting Sports&amp;Fitness Athletic Wear&amp;Shoes Baseball Boating&amp;Watercraft Camping, Outdoors&amp;Hunting Climbing Cycling&amp;Mountain Biking Dance Fan, Team Gear&amp;Accessories Golf Hockey Home Fitness&amp;Gyms Indoor Sports&amp;Games Martial Arts&amp;MMA Military&amp;Police Gear Muscle Development Paintball&amp;Air Guns Scuba Skateboards Ski&amp;Snowboard Soccer Sporting Goods Sports Injury Products Surf Swimming Tennis Yoga Travel&amp;Tickets Airfare Comparison&amp;Booking Budget Motels&amp;Hostels Bus Service Car Rental Destinations&amp;Attractions Hotel Reservations Luggage&amp;Travel Gear Parking, Taxi&amp;Shuttles Tickets&amp;Events Travel Clubs&amp;Memberships Travel Guides&amp;Advice Travel Insurance&amp;Services Vacation Home Listings Vacation Packages&amp;Tours Find coupons, reviews&amp;forums for thousands of companies Popular searches: Web Hosting , Photo Scanning , Shopbop , Textbook Rentals , Green Geeks , School Supply , Online Dating , Ticket Solutions 
10 Restaurant Salads You Should Avoid
 Mark Feldt — Ranked #1 in Eating Out FOLLOW Here are 10 of the unhealthiest restaurant salads that you will ever find on the menu. 
Ordering a salad when dining out can be a healthy alternative to most dishes that are offered on the menu. Salads are a good way to get the vegetables you need for a balanced diet. Unfortunately, there are some salads that can be worse than eating a burger and fries. Here are 10 unhealthy restaurant salads that you should avoid.

 Olive Garden 

 Grilled Chicken Caesar Salad 

 850 calories 

 64g fat 

 1880mg sodium 

 This salad has grilled chicken over romaine in a creamy Caesar dressing with parmesan cheese and croutons. The creamy Caesar dressing is what raises the fat content to 64g. Skipping the dressing would lower the fat and sodium content significantly.

 Del Taco 

  Deluxe Taco Salad 

 845 calories 

 47g fat 

 2470mg sodium 

Choosing a taco salad at a fast food restaurant is usually a bad idea. Most taco salads have a generous amount of refried beans in them and that is what elevates the level of sodium. This one has enough sodium for an entire day for the average adult.

 Chili’s 

 Quesadilla Explosion Salad 

 1300 calories 

 87g fat 

 2050mg sodium 

There are many items on the Chili’s menu that can wreck your diet. If you think that choosing a salad over the other offerings will help you, then you are wrong. This salad has grilled chicken with cheese, corn relish, tomatoes, cilantro, cheese quesadilla wedges, tortilla strips, and citrus-balsamic dressing. There is almost a day and a half worth of fat in this salad.
 
  Cheesecake Factory 

 Caesar Salad With Chicken 

 1510 calories 

 1453mg sodium 

Cheesecake Factory makes it difficult to find out the nutritional content of their food and this is one of the reasons. Almost every one of their menu items is high in calories and it boggles the mind that a single restaurant salad could have over 1500 calories.

 Macaroni Grill 

 Market Chop Salad 

 1020 calories 

 2400mg sodium 

Macaroni Grill has many items that are contains rich sauces and high sodium contents. This salad contains roasted turkey, pepperoni, artichoke, provolone, balsamic vinaigrette, and pumpkin seeds. This is a combination that creates a lot of calories and high sodium content.

 On The Border 

 Grande Taco Salad w/ground beef 

 1280 calories 

 85g fat 

 2250mg sodium 

Any item that has“Grande”in the title should be a red flag. It has all the typical ingredients that you would find in a taco salad. The problem is that they increase the portion to a real gut-buster.

 IHOP 

 Crispy Chicken Salad 

 1460 calories 

 95g fat 

 2090mg sodium 

IHOP is famous for their breakfast menu but they also serve lunch and dinner. This salad packs in 95g of fat. If you think the grilled chicken would be a better way to go, it has 2420mg of sodium.

 California Pizza Kitchen 

 Waldorf Chicken Salad with Blue Cheese dressing 

 1347 calories 

 1994mg sodium 

California Pizza Kitchen may be famous for their pizzas but they also serve a large variety of salads. This one contains chicken, grapes, apples, candied walnuts, celery, and lettuce. All of these are acceptable choices for a salad, it is the blue cheese dressing that racks up the calories.

 Applebees 

 Bruschetta Chicken Salad 

 1110 calories 

 66g fat 

 3120mg sodium  

The Bruschetta Chicken Salad contains grilled chicken breast, romaine lettuce, tomatoes, red onions, champagne vinaigrette, red peppers, Kalamata olives, Asiago cheese, fried mozzarella, and balsamic glaze. That is a lot of ingredients to pile into a salad. The cheese really adds to the high sodium count on this one.

 Chevys Fresh Mex 

 Steak Tostada Salad 

 1560 calories 

 100g fat 

 2550mg sodium 

This is one of the unhealthiest salads that you can find at a restaurant. It does not contain anything that you don’t normally find in a taco salad, but the way it is prepared has turned this into a culinary nightmare. It is hard to imagine that one salad could contain 1560 calories and 100g of fat.

 Tweet Need an answer? Get insightful answers from community-recommended
experts in Eating Out on Knoji. ASK A QUESTION Would you recommend this author as an expert in Eating Out? I would recommend Mark Feldt to friends and associates as an expert in Eating Out RECOMMEND You have 0 recommendations remaining to grant today. This article has +9 recommendations . It&apos;s been recommended by: Kathleen Murphy Mark Cruz Peter Bilton Yovita Siswati amy russell Donata L. Jerry Walch deep blue P. Guims Mark Feldt has +109 recommendations in the topic and is ranked #1 out of 18 experts in this topic. Comments (5) POST COMMENT Sign in to Knoji x Email address Password New user? Register with Knoji. Forgot password? Recover your password. Register with Knoji x First name: Last name: Email address: Password: Already have an account? Sign in. P. Guims 
Noted and shared.
 Posted 6 months ago Jerry Walch Ranked #4 in Eating Out 
No will ever be able to accuse me of eating healthy and I am
healthy, especially for my age. Still, this was an excellent list
of salads to avoid for those who are concerned about eating
healthy.
 Posted 6 months ago Donata L. 
Valuable, informative, and well-written share. Thanks for
posting this information...voted
 Posted 6 months ago Yovita Siswati 
I thought all salad menu has low calories. This is an eye
opener. Thanks for sharing.
 Posted 6 months ago Kathleen Murphy 
1500 calories in a salad? Eeek! 
 Posted 3 months ago ARTICLE DETAILS Topic: Dieting&amp;Weight Loss Sub-Topic: Eating Out 647 views— 5 comments— +9 recommendations Published on Jan 20, 2012 Last updated on Jul 12, 2012 POPULAR COUPONS View all The Flex Belt Get Free Priority Shipping Vitalicious 50% Off Shipping on Cyber Monday Only Official HCG Diet Plan Free Shipping Verseo 25% Off Select Items POPULAR ARTICLES The Benefits Of Cucumber Water Diet And The Types Of Cucumber Water Therapy and Dieting Techniques for Weight Loss Lesofat for Weight Loss 5 Simple Ways to Change Unhealthy Eating Habits and Lose Weight Tuning Up Your Diet with High Protein Vegan Recipes Interview with an Inspiration: Zumba Instructor Loses Over 100 Pounds Best Low-fat and Low-calorie Food at Tim Hortons 9 people are discussing Eating Out on Knoji Answers. ASK A QUESTION ARTICLE KEYWORDS chilis ihop olive garden restaurant nutrition restaurant salads salads to avoid salads with most fat salds with most calories unhealthiest salads unhealthy salads worst salads About Knoji - Terms of Use - Privacy Policy - Contact Us - Join Knoji - Facebook - Twitter - Google+ Copyright©2012 Knoji.com. All rights reserved. Ask a Question on Knoji x Get answers from experts on Knoji. For the best response, be clear in your wording, include all necessary details and avoid spelling and punctuation errors. Your Question: Details (optional): All questions are moderated. Ask a question x will be notified of your question. Your question will also be posted as a public question in the Knoji forums , so be sure to phrase it as a general question that anyone could answer. Personal questions and private messages should be sent using the Message Me feature instead. Your question: Details (optional): All questions are moderated. Confirm your recommendation x By making this recommendation, you are confirming that you would recommend Mark Feldt to people you know as an expert in the topic Eating Out . Confirm and recommend Cancel You have used your question credit for today. Please wait until midnight today for your question credits to renew. x To maintain a high standard for new discussions started, each Knoji member is limited to a certain number of questions each day. Use your questions wisely, ask quality questions and you&apos;ll get quality answers. Credits refresh at midnight US Central time, at which time you&apos;ll receive your next day&apos;s allotment of credits. Oops, you haven&apos;t confirmed your email yet x We&apos;ve sent an email to your registration email address. You&apos;ll need to click the link in that email before you can post stuff on Knoji. Didn&apos;t get the email? First, try checking your spam inbox. If you can&apos;t find it, click here and we&apos;ll resend your confirmation link. Thanks for registering! x We&apos;ve sent a confirmation link to your email address. Go to your email and click the link to confirm. Your postings on Knoji will be hidden from public view until you do so. Didn&apos;t get the email? First, try checking your spam inbox. If you can&apos;t find it, click here and we&apos;ll resend your confirmation link. Great! Here&apos;s a preview of your question. x We&apos;ve sent a confirmation link to your registration email address. Please click this link to confirm your email. Your question will not be posted publicly until you confirm your email. Didn&apos;t get the email? First, try checking your spam inbox. If you can&apos;t find it, click here and we&apos;ll resend your confirmation link. Your confirmation email has been resent x Please check your email (check your spam inbox too) and click on the link provided to confirm your account with Knoji. You have received 0 answer votes on Knoji x When people like the answers you provide, they make a public acknowledgement by placing a vote for your answer. The more votes you accumulate on Knoji, the higher you move up in rank. Increased rank gives you increased capabilities, more perks and more expert cred around the site. Answer questions now Learn more about user levels Oops, you&apos;re out of question credits for today! x We limit the number of questions members can ask on Knoji each day in order to improve the quality of questions and answers. Your question credits will reset each day at midnight US Central time, so come back then to ask more questions! User Levels on Knoji x Contributors on Knoji are awarded Levels as they establish themselves as experts within the community. There are three ways in which users can increase their level, via writing articles or via answering questions , or both . Level Article Track Answer Track Combined Track Abilities Member - - - Can publish articles, ask and answer questions Contributor Successfully publish first article Must earn +50 votes Publish first article OR +50 answer votes Eligible for revenue sharing. Access to Dashboard. Expert Must publish 10 consecutive articles Must earn +200 votes 10 articles OR +200 answer votes Self-publish and edit past articles. Increased compensation rate. Guide Must earn +500 recommendations Must earn +1,000 votes +250 article recommendations AND +500 answer votes Increased earnings rate. Greater number of votes. Authority Must earn +1,000 recommendations Must earn +5,000 votes +500 article recommendations AND +2,500 answer votes Increased earnings rate. Greater number of votes&amp;question credits. Pro Must earn +5,000 recommendations Must earn +10,000 votes +2,500 article recommendations AND +5,000 answer votes Increased earnings rate. Greater number of votes. Master Must earn +10,000 recommendations Must earn +50,000 votes +5,000 article recommendations AND +25,000 answer votes Increased earnings rate. Greater number of votes. What&apos;s a working, unique coupon? x To qualify as a working coupon, the link or code must provide a discount above and beyond what&apos;s freely available by default on the vendor&apos;s site. To check this, first click the link and check that the coupon can be applied and does provide the discount described. Then, in a different browser, open the vendor&apos;s site (without using the Knoji link) and check whether that same discount is available to any user by default. If it&apos;s not, and the coupon works, then you&apos;ve found a qualified coupon and can verify it and get your earnings. If not, you can verify that it does not work (explain why this is) and you&apos;ll earn a smaller credit.
	</body>
</document>
