<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007821" url="http://www.ofm.gov.on.ca/en/Legislation%20Directives%20and%20Technical%20Guidelines/Fire%20Code/Archived%20Documents/Fire%20Code%20Index.asp" time="2012-07-13-00:46" support="1" score="0.00047858720282569194" bingtitle="Index to the Fire Code (1997 edition) - Office of the Fire Marshal ..." webtitle="Ministry of Community Safety and Correctional Services :: OFM Home page">
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>fire hazards near, 5.5.5. fire protection of, 5.5.6. ... receptacles for, 2.4.1.9., 2.4.1.10. storage and removal of ... Exit signs, 9.5.3.5., 9.6.3.6. Exit stairs, numbering ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Ontario.ca Français 
 
 Search 
 
 Home NewsRoom About the Ministry Contact Us 
 You are here &gt; Home &gt; Office of the Fire Marshal &gt; OFM Home page 
Ministry of Community Safety and Correctional Services :: OFM Home page
 
 
 News 
 
 See the current Fire News 
 
 More 
 Fire and Life Safety Educators&apos;Conference&quot;Return to the Grapevine: The Perfect Blend&quot; 
July 10 - Mark your calendar for this year’s Fire and Life Safety Educators’Conference, scheduled for November 7-9, 2012 in St. Catharines. This year’s conference is presented by the OFM and St. Catharines Fire and Emergency Services, along with the Fire Marshal’s Public Fire Safety Council. More... 

 

 July 3 - The Fire Code Consultation period ended June 30, 2012. Thank you for your interest.
 
 

 A Message from the Fire Marshal of Ontario 

 June 18 - Protect your family from fire: install working smoke alarms on every storey of your home and practice a home fire escape plan with everyone in your household.

 248 East Boundary Road Fire Investigation Complete 

 April 27 - After a comprehensive fire investigation, the Office of the Fire Marshal (OFM) has determined that the cause of the fire that began at 248 East Boundary Road in Alexandria on August 12, 2011 was an improperly discarded cigarette. Four people tragically perished as a result of this fire.  More... 
 
 

 February 14 - Guelph Fire Department Teams Up With Co-operators to Demonstrate Benefits of Sprinklers 

 Keep Fire Safety in Mind as Temperatures Drop 

 Risk and Safety Management Plans (RSMP) for Propane Facilities 

 Canadian Fallen Firefighters Foundation (CFFF) Scholarships and Bursaries 



 

 Operational Planning: An Official Guide to Matching Resource Deployment and Risk 
 
External Links
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


   
 
Features
 
 

 Get to know us! 
Visit About the OFM and take the OFM Quiz .



 

Find out who is in the Staff Spotlight .



 

Feature video: 
Cacophony 

 
 
 

   

 Did You Know? 

   

 Careless cooking 
is the 
#1 cause of
fire-related injuries 
in Ontario . 






 
 
   
 Office of the Fire Marshal 
 
 OFM Home page About the Office of the Fire Marshal 
 Welcome Mission Statement Legislation and Administration OFM&amp;Fire Departments: Common Goals, Different Roles Offices Organizational Structure Programs&amp;Activities Service Regions Service Standards Features Job Opportunities 
 Ontario Fire College 
 Overview Fire Safety Train-the-Trainer Industrial Firefighter Training 
 Education Testing&amp;Certification 
 Overview Education&amp;Training Provincial Testing Certification&amp;Accreditation 
 Fire Safety&amp;Public Education 
 Overview Fire Prevention Week Public Fire Safety Information Safety Issues, Product Recalls and Warnings Resource Guide for Child Welfare Professionals Risk Watch Public Education Resources Public Education Resources Materials Order Form Smoke Alarm Information Subscribe to Public Education Matters e-Notice 
 Media Relations&amp;Resources 
 Overview Fire Marshal&apos;s News Releases Fire Statistics 
 Fire Service Programs 
 Overview Community Safety Enhancements Emergency Planning&amp;Strategic Development Fire Services Long Service Medals Municipal Fire Protection Information Performance Measurement and Benchmarking Plan Review Program 
 Fire Service Resources 
 Overview Announcements Communiqués Comprehensive Fire Safety Effectiveness Model Ontario Fire Service Messenger Protocol for the Ontario Fire Service (Manual) Public Fire Safety Guidelines Risk&amp;Safety Management Plans for Propane Facilities 
 Legislation, Directives&amp;Technical Guidelines 
 Overview Fire Protection and Prevention Act, 1997 Fire Code Hotel Fire Safety Requirements Enforcement Fire Marshal&apos;s Directives Technical Guidelines and Reports OFM e-Bulletin 
 Library 
 Welcome About Us Library Services Collections Fire News New Resources Fire Protection&amp;Emergency Management Links 
 Multi-Agency Emergency Preparedness/Response 
 Overview Terrorism/Hazardous Materials Course Breaking Down Barriers Emergency Response Teams 
 Fire Investigations 
 Overview After Hours Calls Contact Information Security 
 Emergency Building Measures 
 1. Purpose&amp;Scope 2. Background 3. Building Vulnerability Assessment 4. Security Measures 5. Developing an Emergency Plan 6. Emergencies Due to Human Activity 7. Emergencies Due to Natural Disasters Appendix A: Threatening Phone Calls Appendix B: Business Continuity Planning Appendix C: Committee to Develop Emergency Guide Appendix D: Abbreviations Library Resources Audio Visual Resources Sample Emergency Procedures 
 Make it Stop! 
 Install Smoke Alarms - It&apos;s the Law! Use the Hush Feature Move the Alarm Try a different type of smoke alarm Maintaining your Alarm Plan&amp;Practice Your Escape Public Service Announcements 
 FAQ 
 All Questions Barbecues Borrowing Resources Fire Department Telephone Numbers Fire Safety Information General Inspections Investigations Offices and Hours Outdoor Burning Purchasing or Viewing Legislation Radioactive Materials Notification Card Smoke Alarms Training and Education 
 Forms 
   
 Explore Government 
   
 Contacts 
 
 Telephone Directory Service Ontario MPPs Have a Question? 
   
 Additional Resources 
 
 Ontario Civilian Police Commission Ontario Police Arbitration Commission Ontario Parole Board     
 
Site Help

 Contact Us Accessibility Privacy Site Map 

Notices

 ©Queen&apos;s Printer for Ontario, Important Notices 

- Last Modified: July 12, 2012
	</body>
</document>
