<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007370" url="http://www.king5.com/health/McDonalds-adds-apples-to-every-Happy-Meal-reduces-fries-126223278.html" time="2012-07-13-00:20" support="1" score="0.0008929483419159747" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s adds apples to Happy Meals, reduces fries | KING5.com ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s adds apples to Happy Meals, reduces fries | 
                KING5.com Seattle">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="47"/>
	<description>But when you put it in a Happy Meal, it might help ... and fries is more likely to change customers&apos; eating ... the decision to feed them on the go at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip Navigation. Jump to Side Bar. 
 Return to the homepage 
 Search 
 
 Seattle, WA Today&apos;s Forecast 7-day Live Cams 

74°

Scattered Clouds
 
 Home News Weather Traffic Sports HealthLink Video Entertainment Food Travel Marketplace Community Your News On TV Login 

 Cancer Children&apos;s HealthLink 
 Business: Location: 
 Auto Dealers Auto Repair Bar Carpet Cleaning Child Care Chocolate Coffee Dentist Doctor Florists Furniture Golf Course Gym Hair Salon Hotels Insurance Jewelry Landscaping Locksmith Movers Pizza Plumbing Realtor Remodeling Storage Browse all» 
 by MojoPages 
 
 HealthLink 
 
Print
 
 print 

Email

 Email this article 

Share

 Tweet Share 

Share!
 X Digg Delicious MySpace LinkedIn StumbleUpon Newsvine Reddit 
 
 
McDonald&apos;s adds apples to Happy Meals, reduces fries
 
McDonald&apos;s adds apples to Happy Meals, reduces fries
 
KING5.com
 
Posted on July 26, 2011 at 6:08 PM

Updated
 Tuesday, Jul 26 at 6:08 PM
 

NEW YORK—An apple a day may keep the doctor away. But when you put it in a Happy Meal, it might help keep regulators at bay too.

McDonald&apos;s on Tuesday said that it would add apple slices and reduce the portion of French fries in its children&apos;s meal boxes beginning this fall, effectively taking away consumers&apos; current choice between either having apples with caramel dip or fries as a Happy Meal side.

The move by McDonald&apos;s, which has become a leader in moving from just burgers and fries to more nutritious fare like oatmeal and salads, comes as fast food chains face intense scrutiny from health officials and others who blame the industry for childhood obesity and other health-related problems. Some municipalities, including San Francisco, have even banned fast food restaurants from selling kids&apos; meals with toys.

Critics wasted no time complaining that McDonald&apos;s changes don&apos;t go far enough. Kelle Louaillier, executive director of a group called Corporate Accountability International, said McDonald&apos;s is just trying to get ahead of impending regulations that will restrict the marketing of junk food to children and require restaurants to post nutrition information on menus, among other changes.

&quot;McDonald&apos;s is taking steps in the right direction,&quot;says Louaillier, whose group has pushed for McDonald&apos;s to retire Ronald McDonald.&quot;But we should be careful in heaping praise on corporations for simply reducing the scope of the problem they continue to create.&quot;

Cindy Goody, McDonald&apos;s senior director of nutrition, said that the new directives are&quot;absolutely not&quot;related to new regulations. Rather, she said, they&apos;re a response to customers asking for healthier choices.

But apparently, customers aren&apos;t making those choices in practice. Indeed, only about 11 percent of customers were ordering apples with their Happy Meals, even though 88 percent were aware they had the option, the restaurant said.

McDonald&apos;s says the change will reduce calories in its&quot;most popular&quot;Happy Meals by as much as 20 percent. The new apple slices will not be served with caramel dipping sauce.

Currently, the lightest Happy Meal is the four-piece chicken nugget meal served with apples and apple juice. It has 380 calories and 12 grams of fat. The Happy Meal with the most fat and calories is a cheeseburger served with fries and 1 percent chocolate milk. It weighs in at 700 calories and 27 grams of fat.

&quot;McDonald&apos;s agrees with leading food and nutrition experts that making incremental lifestyle modifications with food consumption may lead to improvements in an individual&apos;s well-being,&quot;Goody said, adding that McDonald&apos;s didn&apos;t eliminate fries from Happy Meals because&quot;all foods fit when consumed in moderation.&quot;

Adding a half portion of apples and fries is more likely to change customers&apos; eating habits than simply offering apples as an alternative, said Jonathan Marek, a senior vice president at Applied Predictive Technologies. It should also be a good public relations move, he said, and more importantly, could help drive sales.

&quot;The key is, will this get parents to go to McDonald&apos;s one more time each month than they would have otherwise?&quot;said Marek, whose company helps restaurants forecast whether new programs will drive sales. He was not involved in the McDonald&apos;s program.

LaMonte Riker, a New York carpenter eating a chicken salad at a McDonald&apos;s on Tuesday, doesn&apos;t have kids but thinks the Happy Meal changes can&apos;t hurt. He also said he doesn&apos;t think it&apos;s fair for people to blame McDonald&apos;s for their health problems.

&quot;It&apos;s not McDonald&apos;s that&apos;s making your kids fat; you&apos;re making your kids fat by taking them to McDonald&apos;s,&quot;said Riker, 44.&quot;And I don&apos;t think McDonald&apos;s is that fattening if you don&apos;t eat it on a daily basis.&quot;

This isn&apos;t the first time the world&apos;s largest burger chain has tried to paint itself as an emissary of nutrition.

In the &apos;80s, it created a fitness program for middle school children featuring gymnast Mary Lou Retton. A decade ago, McDonald&apos;s used Ronald McDonald to encourage parents to get their children immunized and to tell kids to drink milk. In 2003, it added salad entrees to the menu. And around 2004, McDonald&apos;s christened Ronald a&quot;balanced, active lifestyles ambassador.&quot;

More recently, McDonald&apos;s has worked to portray itself as a healthy, hip place to eat, offering wireless access in restaurants and introducing smoothies, oatmeal and yogurt parfaits, moves that other fast-food companies are now trying to replicate.

&quot;We&apos;ve been in the nutrition game for over 30 years in providing nutrition information to our customers,&quot;said Goody, the McDonald&apos;s nutrition director.&quot;Now what we&apos;re doing is we&apos;re adding more food groups and ... creating nutritional awareness.&quot;

McDonald&apos;s ability to adjust to customers&apos; demands has helped bring already-loyal customers through the doors more often, but it&apos;s also attracting&quot;people who hadn&apos;t traditionally visited us in the past,&quot;said spokeswoman Danya Proud.

In 2010, McDonald&apos;s accounted for 9 percent of U.S. restaurant sales, according to Technomic. Last year, its U.S. revenue rose 4.4 percent, while U.S. revenue fell at Burger King, Wendy&apos;s, Kentucky Fried Chicken, Arby&apos;s, Sonic and Jack in the Box, Technomic said.

 
Print

 print 

Email

 Email this article 

Share

 Tweet Share 

Share!
 X Digg Delicious MySpace LinkedIn StumbleUpon Newsvine Reddit 
 
 
 
 Next article Virus therapy holds hope for brain cancer patients 
 
   
HealthLink Video

 
 HealthLink 

 Virus therapy holds hope for brain cancer patients add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Gene helps destroy life-threatening tumors add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Push for electronic health records creates new class of jobs -- scribes add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Family planning conference kicks off in London with Gates Foundation backing add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 New technology helping prevent sponges left behind in patients add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Doctors fighting diabetic limb amputations with patients&apos; own cells add to reading list   
 
 Food&amp;Recipes 

 Healthy Dish Apple salad with chives and blue cheese add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 New at-home test helps catch colon cancer add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Electrical stimulation helping combat foot drop add to reading list   
 
 More Video 
To add a comment, please register or login .
 Add another comment 

 1000 characters remaining 
 Submit 
 
We welcome your comments on this story&apos;s topic. Off-topic comments, personal
 attacks, and inappropriate language may be flagged and removed, and comment
 privileges blocked, per our Terms of Service. Thanks for keeping the
 comments space respectful.
 Privacy Policy 

 Showing: Newest first Oldest first None 
You have indicated this comment should be removed.
 Please select a reason why this comment should be removed: Select One Comment is offensive Comment contains profanity/racial slur Comment is off-topic/spam Personal Attack Copyright/Plagiarism Other Please explain why you are flagging this comment (10 characters or more required.) Close 
The comment has been submitted for review. Thank you .
 
 Comments: Displaying 1-13 of 13 
 
 doug276614834154 said on July 28, 2011 at 2:07 AM

The article says one group wants to do away with Ronald McDonald. How stupid can these groups get! We should ban fried Twinkies, fried Snickers, Fried Kool Aid from county fairs! This country is getting ridiculous! No toys in Happy meals in San Francisco? Is this all California has to think about? I think they have bigger problems. I think they think they need to show they are doing something.
As for the Happy Meals....maybe the whole reasoning is people will buy a side of fries to go along with the Happy Meals to increase their revenue. If you want fries you can still get fries..just tell them to not put the apples in since they will be thrown away (unless you want the apple).
 71413656 Flag this comment 
 s10maniac said on July 27, 2011 at 5:40 PM

This must be because of government regulations. Why?? Because McDonalds already offered a healthier option, apples instead of fries in a happy meal. No one bought it so now they are making apples manditory. Why would they take away peoples options if they still have to stock the same food? Because regulators want them too. Everyone knows these apples will just end up in the trash. Hasn&apos;t anyone ever seen cafiteria. The vegies get thrown away it is just a waste. Parents need to do something not McDonalds.
 71398084 Flag this comment 
 zosfrosty said on July 27, 2011 at 10:22 AM

There is nothing happy about the government taking away people&apos;s right to make decisions for themselves because some people will make a bad decision. But hell, the&quot;War on Drugs&quot;has been doing it for years, so I guess this is the status quo.

Parents need to stop taking their kids to get fast food every day, and then complaining when they get fat. A kids nutrition, health and weight is their parent&apos;s responsibility until they are 18, and then it becomes their own responsibility. Saying fatty food is to blame is like burning yourself on a hot stove, and then blaming the stove for existing.
 71374079 Flag this comment 
 scott_bellevue said on July 27, 2011 at 8:46 AM

Just stop going there. If enough people stop going then they&apos;ll change their menu. I haven&apos;t set foot in a McDonalds in 10 years and I haven&apos;t missed it one bit. For fast food there are plenty of other options - Pho noodles, chicken teriyaki places, subway, and other options. There are options...
 71367779 Flag this comment 
 bazwest said on July 27, 2011 at 8:03 AM

I don&apos;t have a problem with a company making changes to a product. I do have a problem with government regulators forcing it to happen (which it doesn&apos;t quite appear was the case here). A company is subject to market forces and if they change a popular item and people don&apos;t like the change they won&apos;t buy it and thats ok. Let the consumer decided if they like the new change. I happen to think that apples are a good idea. But perhaps a better way to go would have been to offer two happy meal choices, the old way with the full amount of greasy fries and the new apple version.
 71364988 Flag this comment 
 chevelle70ss said on July 27, 2011 at 7:56 AM

@ab211, they arent making it healthier it has always been healthier. They have always offered the option between apples and fries its the parents fault for letting the kid have the fries instead. All they did was take away our right to choose. And guess what poor people can&quot;choose&quot;apples instead of fries too it doesnt cost any more than fries.
 71364564 Flag this comment 
 slr728 said on July 27, 2011 at 7:43 AM

McDonalds apples have a bad after taste!
 71363648 Flag this comment 
 BaliBoy said on July 26, 2011 at 11:34 PM

I and my family, and I&apos;m thankful, are not&quot;in poverty&quot;. For a family of 3, for basic meals at McDonalds cost nearly 20 bucks...for I just spent it tonight. 20 dollars at any grocery store, can buy you alot more food than what I just shelled out at McDonalds. If your point is about&quot;poor people only have the option to McDonalds&quot;...please review your: facts, reason and logic. Your&quot;emotional&quot;argument has no merit.
 71347248 Flag this comment 
 zb211 said on July 26, 2011 at 11:13 PM

Fast food like McDonalds is, for some families living in poverty, the cheapest way to feed themselves and their kids, and sometimes the only option they can afford. I think its great that McDonalds is making these meals a little healthier. Also, nutrition in the home isn&apos;t happening for some families, regardless of the fact that it should. Taking this initiative is a good way to do a little more for the health of children whose parents are making the decision to feed them on the go at a fast food restaurant. Often times young children aren&apos;t even deciding what they get at such restaurants, their parents are, and its sad that children suffer in health from their parents poor choices. Sometimes, changing the way things are done through regulations is the best way to maintain the health of innocent people, such as children.
 71346832 Flag this comment 
 couchbull said on July 26, 2011 at 9:34 PM

I find this so bizarre that people in this country talk about all the&quot;freedom&quot;we have - but then it&apos;s not considered strange that regulators are allowed to say what McDonalds can put in their Happy Meals? How about putting some of the regulatory energy into actual corporate corruption and large corporations not paying taxes and scamming government contracts?

Really people, how hard is it for parents to step up and be parents. If you don&apos;t want your kids to eat at McDonalds just DON&apos;T BUY IT FOR THEM! Having the government come in and tell a private company what they can and can not sell - but then letting other companies get away with all sorts of stuff that is actually a crime is ridiculous. 

Myself and my daughter like Happy Meals just the way they are - toy and all. Don&apos;t take that away just because we live in a country full of parents who are too lazy to be parents and then want to whine and blame everyone else.
 71344512 Flag this comment 
 whatsyurbeef said on July 26, 2011 at 8:57 PM

If you don&apos;t want the food they sell or anyone else sells don&apos;t buy it. No one is being forced to eat fatty fast foods. If you don&apos;t like it stay home and cook your own food the way you like it. Freedom of choice ? you already have it, and have always had it. Prepare your own food or go out and eat. There are 500,000 dollar to 5000,000 dollar homes with state of the art kitchens 10,000 dollar stove tops for crying out loud that people have today, and never use their kitchens for cooking, just for looking at and showing off to their friends. Get off your B___ts and learn to cook.
 71343269 Flag this comment 
 lilredcv said on July 26, 2011 at 8:33 PM

Parents are more responsible for their child&apos;s nutritional intake than McD&apos;s or any other fast food chain. It starts IN THE HOME. Make good choices there, then when you&apos;re out and about you&apos;re child will make mostly decent choices while at a restaurant. But it shouldn&apos;t be up to the government to make these choices for it&apos;s people. They need to stay out of private affairs &apos;cuz if they don&apos;t and you continue to accept their interference into your private lives? Well, you&apos;re just asking for a communist state of affairs.
 71342374 Flag this comment 
 riverman said on July 26, 2011 at 7:43 PM

gimme a break. you want apples? go to the grocery store!!!
 71339703 Flag this comment 
 Sign Out Profile 
 
 Mobile RSS Feeds Special Offers Newsletters Twitter Facebook TEXT ALERTS: Closings, News, more... 
 
HealthLink Video

 
 HealthLink 

 Virus therapy holds hope for brain cancer patients add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Gene helps destroy life-threatening tumors add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Push for electronic health records creates new class of jobs -- scribes add to reading list   
 
 HealthLink 

 Family planning conference kicks off in London with Gates Foundation backing add to reading list   
 
 More Video 
Most Popular

 Most Viewed Most Emailed 
 
 Bristle from barbecue brush nearly kills Tacoma man Gene helps destroy life-threatening tumors New guidelines on obesity treatment herald changes in coverage Push for electronic health records creates new class of jobs -- scribes Children may help unlock mystery of multiple sclerosis. 
 
 Gene helps destroy life-threatening tumors Bristle from barbecue brush nearly kills Tacoma man New guidelines on obesity treatment herald changes in coverage Healthy Dish Cook up a Monster Energy Bar Healthy Dish Apple salad with chives and blue cheese 
 More&gt;&gt; 
 Home News Weather Traffic Sports HealthLink Video Entertainment Food Travel Marketplace Community Your News On TV 
 KING5.com (206) 448-5555 (phone) (206) 448-4525 (fax) newstips@king5.com 
 Search 
 
 Contact Us Employment Advertising Terms Of Service Privacy Policy UPDATED: Privacy Policy 
 
© 2009-2012 King Broadcasting Company, a subsidiary of Belo Corp. All Rights Reserved.

Powered by Broadcast Interactive Media .
	</body>
</document>
