<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007991" url="http://www.elpasotimes.com/living/ci_18886902" time="2012-07-13-01:04" support="1" score="0.0009244873561999825" bingtitle="Slow food movement takes on &apos;value meal&apos; with $5 challenge - El ..." webtitle="Slow food movement takes on &apos;value meal&apos; with $5 challenge - El Paso Times">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>Can you eat well without being wealthy? That s the focus of a $5 meal challenge being ... comparison to eating at a fast-food restaurant. For that ... Trash truck catches fire in ...</description>
	<body>
		Mobile e-Edition Today’s Print Ads Newsletters Customer Service Subscribe 

 
 
 This Site Web Search powered by YAHOO! 
 
 
 Home News New&amp;Updated Weather Juarez Nation / World Traffic Live chats Politics Election Weird News Public corruption EPISD Video Photo galleries Upload your photos Contact us Opinion Columnists Letters to the editor Blogs Nachotoons Sports UTEP Miners UTEP Video Highlights High schools Boxing Dallas Cowboys Soccer Sports Extra Sign-ups Hyundai Sun Bowl ››Blog: Knight Court ››Blog: The Mine Shaft ››Blog: Joe On Utepia ››Blog: Meet The Preps Business Gas Prices Marketwire Business Wire PR News Wire Entertainment Entertainment blog Events calendar Comics Puzzles&amp;games Horoscopes TV&amp;movies Tiempo Restaurants&amp;dining Movie trailers Communities West side / Central East side Northeast Fort Bliss&amp;Military Lower valley Texas Education NIE Living Pets Celebrations Travel Home&amp;garden Health Outdoors&amp;youth sports New Testament Spanish Obits Search obits Submit obituary ad Real Estate Find a home Apartments Farms / Ranch Cars Jobs Find a job Post a job Tools and advice Advertising Advertise with us Today&apos;s print ads Classifieds Coupons Real Estate Press Shopping Local Shopping 
 

 

 

 

 
 
 
 Tweet 
 
 
Slow food movement takes on &apos;value meal&apos; with $5 challenge
 By Michelle Locke \ Associated Press Associated Press Posted: 09/14/2011 12:00:00 AM MDT 
 Click photo to enlarge Associated Press file photo
Benina Burroughs of Merced, Calif., looks over a display of cherry tomatoes by Farmers with ALBA from Salinas, Calif., at a farmers&apos; market during Slow Food Nation in San Francisco. 
 « 1 » 
 
Can you eat well without being wealthy? That&apos;s the focus of a $5 meal challenge being launched this month by Slow Food USA.
The object is to get people to commit to making a slow food meal -- in other words, using whole ingredients rather than processed foods -- for $5 per person or less.
&quot;This challenge is about taking back the &apos;value meal,&apos;&quot; says Josh Viertel, president of Slow Food USA, a group that advocates a return to less processed foods.
The $5 Challenge launches Saturday with a Day of Action with hundreds of slow food gatherings planned across the country. Participation is free-form -- you can attend a local event, sign up online with a pledge to cook a slow food meal for $5 or less per person, or take part in various potlucks being organized.
People who take the challenge are encouraged to register their events and share stories at the website SlowFoodUSA.org/5Challenge.
Organizers say the challenge is in response to first lady Michelle Obama&apos;s challenge to the nation to end the childhood obesity epidemic in a generation. On a local level, the campaign is intended to bring attention to the difficulties some people face in trying to prepare healthy meals, from not having access to fresh produce to the rising prices of fruit and vegetables compared with cheap soda and junk food.
&quot;The opportunity here is to find the solutions that are already out there and at the same time identify what needs to change,&quot; says Viertel. &quot;It&apos;s going to take each of us Advertisement as everyday people rolling up our sleeves and pushing for big change.&quot;
The $5 target was picked as a reasonable comparison to eating at a fast-food restaurant.
For that much money, you can cook a &quot;really delicious, fresh, healthy meal and you can even have leftovers,&quot; says Viertel. But you have to have access to the ingredients and know how to prepare them.
So how do you fill a plate for five bucks or less?
Katherine Deumling, who runs a small cooking school in Portland, Ore., is ready to spill the beans on that one. Literally.
&quot;I&apos;m the bean queen,&quot; Deumling says with a laugh. So, she might start the week by cooking two pots, one of black beans and the other chickpeas, using dried beans -- which works out to just pennies per person -- and garlic and salt as flavorings. If you have additional spices such as cumin and access to fresh produce like chopped cilantro, all the better. Throughout the week, the beans can star in tortillas or serve as a side to rice, which also is cheap, and perhaps a small amount of meat.
And if you don&apos;t feel like cooking beans from scratch -- though she promises it&apos;s not hard -- then use canned. &quot;Eat beans however you can find them,&quot; says Deumling.
Another idea: kale pesto made by whirling blanched kale in a food processor with olive oil, a little garlic and almonds. Or, you can try a modified salade nicoise, using that old staple, canned tuna. &quot;A little bit goes a long way.&quot;
Deumling, a mom and a Slow Food USA board member, is enthusiastic about getting the message of slow food -- cooking fresh, wholesome food -- out to more people.
What&apos;s she&apos;s not interested in is creating a lot of rules or anxiety.
&quot;I want you to eat what you like. I want you to learn a few basic things. Just eat and have fun with it and cook. You will be so much happier.&quot;
Information: Deumling&apos;s site is cookwithwhatyouhave.com
To share a recipe or to find or host a meal, visit SlowFoodUSA.org/5Challenge. Creative event ideas and recipes will also be available at Twitter.com/SlowFoodUSA and Facebook.com/SlowFoodUSA.



 Copyright 2012 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Print    Email    Font Resize Return to Top    
 
   

 ››Learn more about our new commenting system: FAQ: Article commenting 

 
 
 
 
   
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 More headlines MORE MORE HEADLINES HEADLINES Bowed over: El Paso archery club sees interest rise Wayne Thornton: Swim clubs have made a splash in El Paso Take 5: Five ways to get out this weekend Action shot Area sign-ups Comic-Con to celebrate history, heritage Jane Steele: For Dona, there was always one more party Tidbits: Food and wine news Casasola Photo of the Week Mayor&apos;s 100 Teens: Amanda Pledger and Olivia Ashley Pulley   
 
 Most Viewed Most E-Mailed 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 Police: 81-year-old man admits killing wife in Northeast El Paso 3 to plead guilty to public corruption charges 14-year-old gets 20-year term for killing Texas teacher Man assaulted outside Central El Paso bar dies Ruidoso&apos;s Bonito Lake &apos;ruined&apos; Man seriously hurt in assault at bar last week YISD superintendent mum on job talks in Dallas Ex-state Sen. Shapleigh calls for action: Hundreds urged to help... Cooling rain floods streets, &apos;a blessing&apos; for El Paso Department of Defense confirms identities of Fort Bliss soldiers... 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 Report challenges Mexico&apos;s choices in drug war YISD superintendent mum on job talks in Dallas Mexican army: Killings in Juarez down 42 percent Police: 81-year-old man admits killing wife in Northeast El Paso 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   Jobs     Homes   
 
   Automotive EXPERIENCED...   (Jobs) GeneralGrill Ca...   (Jobs) Drivers Safe...   (Jobs) Legal Legal...   (Jobs) Acccounting KFOX...   (Jobs) All Listings 
 
   3200 GREENOCK ...   (Homes) 1937 SEAGULL DR...   (Homes) All Listings 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
 Copyright©by the El Paso Times and MediaNews Group and/or wire services and suppliers.
None of the content on this site may be republished or reused in any way without the written permission of the copyright holder. About our Ads | Advertise with Us | Customer Service | e-Edition | Facebook | Mobile | My Yahoo | Newsletters | RSS | Site Map | Twitter | YouTube Media Partners :    SomosFrontera.com | KFOX TV | Univision 26 | La Región Digital | El Paso Hispanic Chamber of Commerce News Partners :    Alamogordo Daily News | Carlsbad Current-Argus | Deming Headlight | Farmington Daily Times | Las Cruces Sun-News | Ruidoso News | Silver City Sun-News 
 
 Texas/New Mexico News Group- 

 Privacy Policy   |   Terms of Use   |   MNG Corporate Site Map   |   Copyright
	</body>
</document>
