<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007314" url="http://www.journalgazette.net/article/20120325/FEAT/303259992/1011/FEAT" time="2012-07-13-00:17" support="1" score="0.0016720383041763512" bingtitle="Augusta plays home to two types of golf | The Journal Gazette" webtitle="Augusta plays home to two types of golf | The Journal Gazette">
			<query id="001252" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... slogan for what well-known fast-food restaurant? 2. What is the name of the green rooster on boxes ... was required now: a short throw by ... needed a jolt of energy to counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement
 The Journal Gazette, 600 W. Main St., Fort Wayne IN 
91

Local weather 

National Weather Service 
 
 Local Blogs AP News Sports Business Features Food Ent Opinion Multimedia Contact Calendar Data 
 
 Subscribe Jobs Cars Homes Apartments Classifieds Shopping Celebrations Obituaries 
 
 Home « Features 
 Mobile | RSS Search archive You choose, we deliver If you are interested in this story, you might be interested in others from The Journal Gazette. Go to www.journalgazette.net/newsletter and pick the subjects you care most about. We&apos;ll deliver your customized daily news report at 3 a.m. Fort Wayne time, right to your email. 
Features

 Keeping em cool Summer is here, and weve shed our coats. Dogs and cats dont have that luxury, but their fur, which keeps them warm in winter, also protects them in the summer by preventing them from taking on too much heat. Today 3:00 am Summer sessions With constant pressure to have kids do more in school, and do it sooner, parents who spent their own summers playing outside until the streetlights came on might feel compelled to push academics over free play. Good news: Today 3:00 am Creativity shows with pendants Show off your DIY fashion skills with a collage pendant necklace. They are simple to make and the results are perfect every time. Today 3:00 am 
 Advertisement If you go What to do: 
Augusta Canal National Heritage Area, 1450 Greene St.; 888-659-8926 or www.augustacanal.com. Learn about the canal at the interpretive center ($6; 9:30 a.m. to 5:30 p.m. Monday to Saturday, 1 to 5:30 p.m. Sunday) or on a Petersburg boat tour ($12.50).
Morris Museum of Art, 1 10th St.; 706-724-7501 or www.themorris.org . 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Tuesday to Saturday, noon to 5 p.m. Sunday, $5; Sundays free.
Pendleton King Park, 1600 Troupe St.; 706-796-5025 or www.pendletonkingpark.com. Bird sanctuary with 18-hole disc golf course. Free.
Professional Disc Golf Association International Disc Golf Center, 3828 Dogwood Lane, Appling, Ga.; 706-261-6342 or www.pdga.com/IDGC. Free museum about 25 miles from Augusta. 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Monday to Saturday. Three public courses open daily dusk to dawn. Entry fee $5.
 Information : www.augustaga.org For walking tour : www.historicaugusta.org/tour/index.html
 Washington Post Disc golf is big in Augusta, Ga., where the International Disc Golf Center is the sports headquarters. Published: March 25, 2012 3:00 a.m. 
Augusta plays home to two types of golf
 Andrea Sachs | Washington Post 
Thats a good-lookinrip,Matt Flynn called out to his competitor from the 18th hole at the Pendleton King Park course in Augusta, Ga.



Ten eyeballs followed the plastic projectile as it flew through the air like a turbo-charged UFO, covering nearly 220 yards and landing near a metal basket with a chain-link fringe. All that was required now: a short throw by a steady hand into the baskets maw. Then off to the next hole and the next rip.



In Augusta, drop such athletic terms asgreens,putterandneeds more mustard,and everyone assumes that youre talking about the Masters, the legendary golf tournament held each April at Augusta National Golf Club. But on a recent Sunday morning, the players were neither sporting fancy pants nor wielding gleaming irons. Instead, they wore crumpled T-shirts and dusty sneakers and toted colorful discs as small as dessert plates.

These men, and a few women, represented the every-Augustan sport of disc golf.



We have eight courses within a 20-minute drive and a good variety with lakes, tightly wooded holes and elevation changes,Flynn said.You can show up at any park and see other people playing.



This last fact is significant, because only the privileged can view a round at Augusta National, a private club that hides behind towering hedges, intimidating gates and barking guards. If you want to watch the Masters, youll have better luck pressing your nose to the TV screen. But if you want to attend a disc golf game, simply show up at a course (for free or a nominal charge) and look for the folks chasing rainbow-colored saucers through the trees.



The Masters only impacts us one week a year,Flynn said. The other 51 weeks,Augusta is just a sweet Southern town.



Fortunately, I visited during one of the sweet weeks–the off-week this year is April 2 to 8–though the odds were in my favor. As was the weather in this year-round destination.



This afternoon, sunny, in the lower 60s, with southeast winds of five miles per hour,announced the robo-voice from the National Weather Service station on the Savannah River promenade.



Georgias second-oldest and second-largest city has been recording meteorological changes since 1870, the year President Ulysses S. Grant authorized the formation of a National Weather Service. The NWS information streams nonstop on the corner of 11th Street and the Riverwalk. I sat through four cycles of weather, including the forecast for the mountains and beaches of neighboring states, not leaving until I knew for certain how to dress the next day.



The five-block, multilevel walk is as languid as the river, which separates Georgia and South Carolina. Ducking into an alcove with benches, I watched tiny birds swoop through the trees and over the heads of children romping on a jungle gym in Oglethorpe Park.



The esplanade fronts a number of attractions, such as the Morris Museum of Art, which celebrates Southern artists. At the front desk, the docent directed me not to the exhibit titledFore!: Images in Golf,but to the hyper-realist watercolors of Mary Whyte. The Charleston, S.C., painter documents the blue-collar jobs that once flourished here: shrimping, spinning, cotton picking. According to my watch, I had 35 minutes to view 50 pieces. The employee, noting my predicament, invited me back for free. He didnt want me to rush, a concept thats anathema in Augusta.



Speed is not required on the self-guided walking tour of four main thoroughfares, either.It is not expected that anyone will take the entire downtown walking tour at one time during one visit,advised the Historic Augusta planners.



I decided to focus on local personalities honored with statues, such as Gen. James Edward Oglethorpe, who established the town in 1736 as a British colonial outpost, and James Brown, the Godfather of Soul who crowed and funky-chickened his way to stardom. Woodrow Wilson, who resided here from 1860 to 1870, earned more than a simple rendering: The 28th presidents entire boyhood home is enshrined.



Surprisingly, Henry Harford Cumming appears neither as a sculpture nor a brick house nor a water fountain. I know! Poor Henry. But I finally tracked him down inside the Augusta Canal National Heritage Area Interpretive Center, his black-and-white image still dapper after all these years.



Cumming was the idea guy and cheerleader behind the canal, which was built in 1845 and gave Augusta a much-needed shot of B12. Once a thriving trade center, the agriculture-based community needed a jolt of energy to counter the ill effects of a depression, the railroad and rising competition. The canal allowed the city to harness the energy from the river to power mills and factories that produced an array of products, including gunpowder during the Civil War. (The 153-foot-tall Confederate Powder Works chimney still stands as a memorial to wartime industriousness.) In the late 19th century, about a dozen mills lined the banks. Today, only three plants are in operation.



But theres still a lot of life along the 13-mile route. On an electric-powered Petersburg boat, a replica of the mule-drawn cargo vessels that once plied these waters, I waved to fishermen sitting half-alert on lawn chairs, their lines awaiting a bite from a catfish or a bass. Turtles sprawled on logs, and a blue heron skimmed the still surface like a giant paper airplane.



At the same early hour as a halfmarathon that diced up the town, about 60 disc golf players had congregated at Pendleton King Park, a 64-acre bird sanctuary with an 18-hole course. I was caddying for Flynn, one of the more expert competitors, carrying his gear, which resembled a small camera bag full of discs.



For two hours, I tailed my foursome, the bag bouncing against my back as I hoofed it up hills and along forested paths and around a goose pond. At the 17th hole, I watched with dread as Flynns disc rolled toward the parking lot, a one-stroke penalty. On the sixth hole, we paused to search the woods for his red disc. And on the seventh hole, I resigned.



This happens to me with organized sports; I sometimes drift away from the action. But to be honest, I lasted much longer with disc golf than I ever have with golf-golf, including the Masters.
 ©Copyright 2012 The Journal Gazette. All rights reserved. Neither this material nor its presentation may be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Share 
 E-mail Printer friendly 
 Advertisement 






   Stock Sponsor
 Click here for full stock listings 
 

 
 
Advertisement
 Copyright©2012, www.journalgazette.net | Terms of use/privacy policy
	</body>
</document>
