<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007908" url="http://www.supercheats.com/gamecube/walkthroughs/sonicadventuredxdirectorscut-walkthrough03.txt" time="2012-07-13-00:53" support="1" score="0.0017045682322731673" bingtitle="Walkthrough for Sonic Adventure DX: Directors Cut" webtitle="Walkthrough for Sonic Adventure DX: Directors Cut">
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>... Drive to the 32X (which was designed on a napkin in ... to the other part of SS and try finding a Fast Food restaurant. ... uses this attack, Spin Attack him to counter. 4.</description>
	<body>
		Walkthrough by KeroroG 
 Sonic Adventure DX: Directors Cut on SuperCheats.com 
 *************************
FAQ/Walkthrough
Sonic Adventure DX
Version 0.2
By KeroroG
ryuk66@yahoo.com/
g66ryu@yahoo.com
*************************

Copyright 2006~2008 Steven Ryu

This may not be reproduced under any circumstances except for personal, 
private use. It may not be placed on any web site or otherwise distributed 
publicly without advance written permission. Use of this guide on any other
web site or as a part of any public display is strictly prohibited, and a 
violation of copyright.

The following sites may use my guide:

Gamefaqs
NeoSeeker
SuperCheats

If you want this guide on your site, just e-mail me.

If you have a suggestion, comment, complaint, request, or if you just want 
some help, just E-mail me.

E-mail g66ryu@yahoo.com because I don&apos;t really check my e-mail. Thanks.

******************
Table of Contents
******************

1. Introduction

2. a. Characters
 b. Basic Controls

3. Walkthrough

Sonic The Hedgehog

BOSS - Chaos 0 
 -Emerald Coast
BOSS - Egg Hornet 
 -Windy Valley
 -Casinopolis
 -Ice Cap
BOSS - Knuckles
BOSS - Chaos 4
 -Sky Chase: Act I
 -Twinkle Park
 -Speed Highway
 -Red Mountain
 -Sky Chase: Act II
 -Sky Deck
BOSS - E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;
BOSS - Chaos 6
 -Lost World
 -Final Egg
BOSS - Egg Viper
 
Miles &quot;Tails&quot; Prower

BOSS - Egg Hornet
 -Windy Valley
 -Casinopolis
 -Ice Cap
BOSS - Knuckles
BOSS - Chaos 4
 -Sky Chase: Act I
 -Sand Hill
 -Sky Chase: Act II
 -Sky Deck
BOSS - E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;
 -Speed Highway
BOSS - Egg Walker

Knuckles the Echidna

 -Speed Highway
BOSS - Chaos 2
 -Casinopolis
BOSS - Sonic
 -Red Mountain
BOSS - Chaos 4
 -Lost World
BOSS - Chaos 6
 -Sky Deck

Amy Rose

 -Twinkle Park
 -Hedgehog Hammer
 -Hot Shelter
 -Final Egg
BOSS - Zero
 
Big the Cat

 -Twinkle Park
 -Ice Cap
 -Emerald Coast
BOSS - Chaos 6
 -Hot Shelter

E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;

 -Final Egg
BOSS - E-101 &quot;Beta
 -Emerald Coast
BOSS - Sonic
 -Windy Valley
BOSS - E-103 &quot;Delta&quot;
 -Red Mountain
BOSS - E-104 &quot;Epsilon&quot;
 -Hot Shelter
BOSS - E-105 &quot;Zeta&quot;
BOSS - E-101 &quot;Kai&quot;

Super Sonic

BOSS - Perfect Chaos

4. Emblem Checklist
 a. Action Stage Emblems
 b. Sub Game Emblems
 c. Adventure Field Emblems

5. Mini Games
 a. Sky Chase ACT 1
 b. Sky Chase ACT 2
 c. Sand Hill
 d. Twinkle Circuit
 e. Hedgehog Hammer
 f. Slot Pinball
 g. Card Pinball
 
6. Mission Mode

7. Mini Game Collection/Game Gear

8. Chao FAQ
 a. Chao Garden Locations 
 b. Hatching a Chao
 c. Raising a Chao
 d. Entering Races
 e. SA2B Connection
 f. Black Market
 g. The legendary Light Chao (Chaos Chao)

9. Version History

10.Thanks/Credits


==============================================================================
1. Introduction
==============================================================================

Welcome to my guide for Sonic Adventure Director&apos;s Cut. Lets skip this intro
and move on to some Sonic History. Read it though, Please =] Especially if
you&apos;re new to Sonic or to those who didn&apos;t really know how it all started.

A lot of this is from the words of Dave Halverson. Some are mine too. I just
wanted to give credits to those who made Sonic a great success.

The Sonic Saga

Sonic debuted at the 1990 CES in Las Vegas. Sonic was anticipated in the 
U.S. that SEGA rushed it out a month before Japan to begin their assault on
Nintendo who had seemingly insurmountable lead at the time. The first shot
fired in the real system wars was a blue varmint. Nintendo&apos;s SNES (Super
Nintendo Entertaining System) had Mario, (I hate him) an independent Sony 
sound chip, Mode-7 3D, and 256 colors onscreen, but SEGA had a character so
instantly lovable in a game so revolutionary they passed Nintendo like they
were standing still, with no sound chip (sound ate up space on the CPU-ouch)
and a measly 64 colors onscreen. Sonic the Hedgehog had single-handedly 
taken down the giant on his way to becoming more reconizable than Mickey 
Mouse.

*Applause* That is AMAZING. One of SEGA&apos;s great achievements *sniff* *sniff*

After Sonic the Hedgehog&apos;s release, SEGA and Sonic Team followed a suit with
a great sequal, Sonic 2. In September of 1993, Sonic CD was out. That 
following month, Sonic Spinball was introduced. In the 1994&apos;s, Sonic 3, 
Sonic and Knuckles, and Sonic 3D Blast was released. Sonic 3 made a landfall
in January of &apos;94, Sonic and Knuckles thrived but, Sonic 3D Blast fell flat
=( But that was ok because SEGA was evolving. SEGA jumped from the Mega 
Drive to the 32X (which was designed on a napkin in a bar; true story) to 
the Saturn, the oft-delayed game (set for Christmas &apos;96) was to be the first
fully 3D Sonic, but after numerous set backs it was scrapped in 1997. It
wouldn&apos;t be until later that year that Naka and company would finally enter
the world of polygonal 3D with Sonic R, the Sonic racing game. SEGA of 
America questionable distribution of wealth which included the founding of 
the SEGA Technical Institute coupled with an abhorrent disregard for their 
loyal fan base, and botching the 32X by nixing the sound chip, sapped 
Sonic&apos;s good will and set in motion a downward spiral capped-off by the 
decision to beat Sony&apos;s Playstation to market with an inferior 3D machine: 
the SEGA Saturn. But the Playstation was clearly the better polygon cruncher
but the Saturn was far the better 2D machine, at a time when 2D was king and
ripe to evolve. Had SEGA innovated 2D instead of killing it, the world would
be a different place. One only needs to look at... drum roll please...one of
SEGA&apos;s mascot&apos;s NIGHTS! SEGA&apos;s Nights: Into Dreams. But for some reason SEGA
never went forward with a Nights sequel. That all changes this year as SEGA 
releases Nights: Journey of Dreams on the Nintendo Wii. 
(I&apos;m a get that game) =D

Anyways, that should get some sense of what SEGA achieved with the Saturn. 
But we never got a side-scrolling 128-bit 3D Sonic...In factthere would 
never be a Sonic the Hedgehog sequel for the SEGA Saturn. Those were dark 
times. SEGA ostensibly killed 2D and lost the battle against Sony in one 
fell swoop. =(

But then something great happened... Cigar Man (Bernie Stohler) was out and
Peter Moore was in, taking the reigns for his shot at a SEGA resurgence, and
Peter had the right stuff. It didn&apos;t take long for him to return SEGA to 
it&apos;s former glory. He listened to the fans, has great respect for the 
Japanese, (You too should have great respect towards the Japanese because 
they made your cars, T.V.&apos;s, games ,etc. =D) signed up more third parties 
than anyone ever imagined and against all oddslaunched the Dreamcast like a 
new Paris Hilton video, (well maybe not her) orchstrating arguably the most 
exciting launch in console history. And he did it with Sonic. The true 3D 
Sonic had finally arrived. It took until 1998 to finally get it doneand it 
wasn&apos;t perfect, but it was revolutionaryin many wayswith its interactive 
open-world design, and multiple character scenarios. We ran from whales, we 
fished, we had fun.

That was the the original Sonic Adventure. Later games like Sonic Adventure
2 Battle was a perfect game in my opinion. But I didn&apos;t like Sonic Heroes or
Shadow the Hedgehog. Sonic the Hedgehog for the 360 was a fantastic game
except for the loading. Sonic and the Secret Rings was an awsome game. Thank
you for reading this and most of the words are from Dave Halverson.

The Sonic Era:

&apos;91
Genisis/Mega Drive Era
Sonic began life as a bulbous hedgehog with Nicole Richi legs

&apos;98
Dreamcast Era
Super stylized. Sonic ready for his 3D Dreamcast debut

&apos;06
Current Era (kinda)
Sonic after his extreme makeover... taller, leaner, faster, and ready for 15 
more years

==============================================================================
2. b. Characters
==============================================================================

Main Characters

Sonic the Hedgehog: Worlds fastest Hedgehog. Some people call him the blue
speed demon =D

Miles &quot;Tails&quot; Prower: He has two tails. Thats weird for a fox but he can fly.
He has his own workshop in the Mystic Ruins.

Knuckles the Echidna: Guardian of the Master Emerald. He can glide, dig, and
find pieces or shards of the Master Emerald. He&apos;s also short tempered and
usually fooled by Eggman.

Amy Rose: An energetic girl who loves Sonic. You shouldn&apos;t underestimate her
when she&apos;s carrying her Piko Piko Hammer.

Big the Cat: He loves fishing with his best friend Froggy.

E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;: Created by Eggman but he&apos;s different from other robots.

Sub Characters

Tikal: The light that helps you throughout the game. That light is like her
soul. (Hintball)

Pachacamac: He&apos;s like the village chief or leader

Echidna Tribe: They all look like Knuckles and they love fighting.

Froggy: Bigs best friend. He ate? a Choas Emerald and grew a tail.

Bad Characters

Eggman: He&apos;s a scientist with an IQ of 300. Up to no good once again.

Chaos: A mysterious liquefied life-form that had been trapped in the Master 
Emerald and was released by Eggman to do his evil bidding.

==============================================================================
2. c. Basic Controls
==============================================================================

Basic Controls

Game Start
Start/Pause

Item Selection
Select with Control Stick
A button

Cancel/Return to the privious screen
B button

Actions Common to all Characters

Walk and Run
Control Stick
Press the the control stick to the direction you want

Jump
A button
Jump height varies

Panning the Camera
L/R button
If it&apos;s on AutoCamera, you can&apos;t use the L/R button to change the camera view.
In some situaton, you can&apos;t change the camera view when you&apos;re near a wall.

Carrying Items
B or X button
Stand in front of the item to pick it up. You can&apos;t perform an action while
holding an item. (Spindash, flying, digging, etc.)

Shaking or Waving Items
B or X button and Control Stick
Shake items. Also used to cuddle chao&apos;s.

Throwing or Setting Items Down
B or X button and Control Stick
To throw, press B or X while moving. To set items down, press B or X while 
stopped

==============================================================================
3. Walkthrough
==============================================================================

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------Sonic the Hedgehog------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Sonic&apos;s Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

SA - Jump to perform a Spin Attack.

HA - Sonic&apos;s common attack to destroy enemies.

SD - A faster way of moving from places. SD + SA will lets you jump higher and
move farther. Use a SD and immediatly press the A button.

Light Speed Dash - You need the Light Shoes. Charge and release a Light Speed
Dash in front of a trail of rings to dash through the rings at light speed.

Light Spin Attack - You need the Ancient Light. Go to a group of enemies and
hold B. Release it to HA the enemies over and over.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Choas 0

When you first begin, press the A button once to jump. When you&apos;re in 
mid-air, press the A button again to perform a Homing Attack (HA) Try 
hitting him right away when you begin. You probably noticed the purple thing
on his head. It looks like a brain but whatever, all you do is hit that 
purple area with your HA 3 times.

Attack Pattern:
1. Punch
He&apos;s going to stretch his hand and try punching you. To counter this, simply
move and attack him with a HA.

2. Swing Attack
When you hit him 2 times, he&apos;s going to start swinging both of his hands. To
counter this attack, simply jump high and do a HA. Don&apos;t try hiiting him
directly or he&apos;ll punch you or maybe swing at you.

3. Jump on poll and punch
Simply run around and collect the 8 rings scattered around this boss fight. 
When he comes down, there&apos;s your chance to strike to finish him&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Ok lets go save Tails! You can talk to the people around you if you want. 
When you&apos;re finished, go to your first level.

**************
Emerald Coast
**************

Mission C: Rescue Tails
Start by going back and HA the 3 capsules. Now SD (Spindash) forward a few
times till you see an orange monkey known as a Kiki. You can HA and kill it 
if you want to but anyways, hit the spring. Jump off the platform you&apos;re on 
and land on the platform below you. Ignore the spinning spikes and hit the 
spring thats somewhere around you. Go through the loop and go through the 
checkpoint. SD your way through the hill and hit the board thing. Once you 
get to the next checkpoint, hit the dash panel. You run a short distance and
run up a hill. Move cautiously here because there&apos;s a bar of spikes that 
comes down. Go through the loop and get to the next checkpoint. Hold up when
you start running from the whale and when you jump to the next platform, 
hold down. When you get to the next checkpoint, go around the bar of spikes 
and start climbing the hill and hit the springs. Work your way through this 
area till you see a light house. Run across and go into the small opening 
behind the light house.

ACT 2
Hit the next checkpoint and start SD and start running on the walls. Go
through the small opening and go through the shortcut. You should reach the 
next checkpoint now so keep running till you see about 3 dash panels. Jump 
off the wall and HA your way through the water. Hit the board thing and go 
up the hill. If this is your first time playing, just go through the 
pathway. If this is not your first time playing, go on the fence thing and 
SD and jump. This is like a shortcut so be sure to make it or it won&apos;t be a 
shortcut at all. From here on out, you just have to follow the path and 
you&apos;ll find Tails (Goal)

Mission C completed. You should&apos;ve gottten your first emblem =D&gt;Cutscene&lt;Now you can play as Tails!

Anyways, head to the Mystic Ruins. Use the train. If you don&apos;t know how to 
get there, use the map. Go inside the hotel and take a right to get out of 
the hotel. The train station should be on the left so go in and enter the 
train.

Jump off the train station and take a right. If you see a lot of stairs, 
thats where you&apos;re supposed to go. Again, use the map if you can&apos;t find it.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Hornet

Grab a few rings and avoid the missles he shoots. This place is big so run 
around a lot. When he gets the sharp thing out run around a bit more and 
when the sharp thing gets stuck on the ground, HA the cockpit to damage Egg
Hornet. Hit him 3 times to defeat him.

Attack Pattern:
1. Homing Missles
Each time you hit him, the missles grow in numbers so just run around to avoid
getting hit

2. Take Down
He gets 2 sharp things and try&apos;s to crush you with it. Simply run back when he
attacks you with it.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the entrance to the workshop and grab the Wind Stone. Go downstairs 
and find a guy. There should be an entrance to a cave near him so when you 
find it, enter and set the Wind Stone on the pedestal. Use the map if you
can&apos;t find it. It&apos;s near the waterfall.

*************
Windy Valley
*************

Mission C: Get the Chaos Emerald
When you begin, take the top route and HA your way through to get the 
Magnetic Barrier. Hit the spring and get to the checkpoint. You can hit the 
hintball for help. There&apos;s an invisible path so just hold the control stick 
up and run through the invisible path. Use the spring thing to get up to the
platform above you and keep moving forward till you get sucked in a tornado.

Here, all you have to do is to get out. How? Work your way out of the 
tornado. Pretty easy. When you get to the number panels, rapidly press the A
button. You should get to a checkpoint afterwards. Go on the spring thing 
again to go on the bridge. Keep moving forward and hit the spring and land 
on the next platform. Hit the next spring and you&apos;re out of the tornado!

When you&apos;re out, run through the pathway and SD the wall thing. Get the High
Speed capsule and run or SD through this area. When you&apos;re back on a 
platform, you&apos;ll see that there&apos;s a path a rings and a rocket. Take the 
rocket, ignore the rings for now. Get to the checkpoint and run. There&apos;s 
also another invisible path but you&apos;ll be okay right? Go through it and hit 
the springs. Try going on the higher platform and hit the spring at the end.
You could get another magnetic Barrier if you lost yours somewhere. But 
anyways go on the hole thing and you should fly on a spring and get to 
another checkpoint. Run through this one and you should start running down 
when you get to a point where sonic starts running up. (He hits a dash panel
so he&apos;ll run down) You should be going through a loop and an invisible path.
Afterwards, you&apos;re finished. Just hit the Chaos Emerald =D

Mission C completed

When you come out, you should hear an enouncement that the train is going to
leave for SS. (Station Square) So go on the train.

Head to the other part of SS and try finding a Fast Food restaurant. There
should be a hole somewhere near the restaurant so enter it.

You should be in the sewers. Jump on a platform which should be behind Sonic
I think. Get your first upgrade! The Light Shoes lets you power up energy 
and dash through trails of rings in Light Speed. Hit the switch and try out 
your new power. (Takes too long to charge it up?) No worries, you&apos;ll be 
getting another upgrade so get out of here and go back to the hotel.

Go up the stairs (Sonic&apos;s left) and hit the switches. Charge up for your 
Light Speed Dash so hit the left switch and try going in the room. Get your 
2nd upgrade, the Crystal Ring! This shortens the time for the charge.

Anyways, go to the opposite of the pool area to go to the Casino.

Charge your Light Speed Dash and hit the switch. Light Speed Dash on the 
trail of rings and open the casino!

************
Casinopolis
************

Mission C: Get the Chaos Emerald
Start going to the Nights Table and purposly lose. You should fall down to 
an area with lots of rings, well, not yet. There&apos;s a lot of 10 ring 
containers here so do you best to get a lot of rings.

When you&apos;re out, you should be in the shower room. Go to the shower with a 
ring, stand there for a while and Sonic will start taking a shower! Anyways,
get out and head back to the Nights Table and start playing.

Card Pinball: Slot Pinball
This is like poker. 
One Pair +10 Rings SpeedStar +50 Rings
Two Pair +20 Rings T-Kickback +15 Rings
Three Card +30 Rings Shining &quot;K&quot; +30 Rings
Four Card +70 Rings BlueRose +50 Rings
Full House +50 Rings Rink3K +15 Rings
Straight +100 Rings FinalEggman -50 Rings

You can get additional rings for Three, Four Card, Full House, SpeedStar,
T-Kickback, Shining &quot;K&quot;, BlueRose, and Ring3K,

Anyways when you get 400 or more rings, go to the place where it has the 
Chaos Emerald and give the 400 rings to beat the level

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;When you begin, you could see Cream flying. Get the Ice Stone though. It&apos;s
across from the Train Staion entrance. Go to the Mystic Ruins afterwards.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the cave and go on the wind. There should be another pedestal around
here where you set the Ice Stone so do that. Enter the area and climb the
ladder.

********
Ice Cap
********

Mission C: Get the Chaos Emerald
Grab the rings and go outside. Go down and charge for a Light Spin Dash and 
go on the number panel and press A rapidly.

ACT 2
Jump on the big ice rock and land on a platform. Jump across to land next to
2 springs. Hit the right spring and HA the 3 capsules. Go back and hit the 
left spring and continue. When you&apos;re on the ice, use the control stick to
move and the A button to jump. Start jumping from ice to ice and when you 
get to the spring, hit it and hit the switch as well. HA to get some speed 
and run. continue moving forward till you get to the number panel . When you
finish jumping, the ice on the ceiling will fall and you&apos;ll be able to move 
to ACT 3.

ACT 3
Hit the wooden sign thing and...&gt;Cutscene&lt;Use the control stick to move the snowboard (Sonic) and A to jump. To 
perform a trick, you have to be near the tip of a ramp and press A. When 
you see planes (probably Eggman&apos;s) avoid the bombardment. After this big
area, you should see a much smaller area. Go to the left and enter a small 
shortcut. (There&apos;s an ice barrier but you can go through it) After that, go
through the cave. When you get out, there&apos;s going to be a ramp in the 
middle. Perform a trick and there&apos;s 2 more to come. When you get through the
ramps, the Chaos Emerald should be close. It&apos;s at the end of this area so
you can&apos;t miss it. Grab it to complete the level.

Mission C completed

Now go back outside and go to the waterfall area where you&apos;ll fight 2 
bosses. That sucks doesn&apos;t it?&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Knuckles

He&apos;s not that hard. Just HA attck him. When he starts gliding, jump to knock
him out for a short time (you too) Hit him 3 times to defeat him.

Attack Pattern:
1. Punch
Not like Chaos 0&apos;s punch. He does 2 jabs then a thrust. To counter this, 
simply HA attack him

2. Tackle while Gliding
He jumps in the air and glides towards you. HA him to bounce eachother back.
Or, SD until he lands. Then quickly HA him.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 4

We just lost our Chaos Emeralds =( 
When the fight begins, jump around the battlefield. This is like the battle 
with Chaos 0. Hit the brain area to inflict damage when it&apos;s glowing. 5 hits
and he&apos;ll go down.

Attack Pattern:
1. Sonic Boom
He&apos;s going to send some wide spreading attacks so jump over this attack when
he starts using it. When you inflict some damage, he&apos;s going to start 
throwing in some extra Sonic Booms so jump over them.

2. Punch
He&apos;s going to stretch his arms or whatever and swing it. Not much to say...

3. Split up Attack
He splits in 4&apos;s and starts to tackle you. Simply run around using the HA to
avoid getting hit

4. Lillypad sinking Hits
This attack won&apos;t hurt you but he basically sinks the lillypads that are in
sight and the one you&apos;re on.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;You can now play with Knuckles

Head to Tails&apos;s Workshop.&gt;Cutscene&lt;****************
Sky Chase ACT 1
****************

Press B or A to shoot
Hold B or A to lock on. Release it to shoot homing lasers.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the casino area&gt;Cutscene&lt;You can now play as Amy

When you come out of the Hotel, go right across the hotel area to Twinkle 
Park.&gt;Cutscene&lt;*************
Twinkle Park
*************

Mission C: Destroy the capsule and rescue the animals
Start by grabbing the rings that are behind the floating computer thing.
Now read what the floating computer says:

&quot;Bumper Car Controls
Accelerator: A Button
Brakes/ Reverse: Bor X Button
Collecting the rings increase bumper car acceleration&quot;

Kill the Kiki&apos;s and get on a bumper car. The gate will open so collect a lot
of rings throughout the track. 
NOTE: You can use the L/R Button to drift right or left

When you get off your bumper car, go in the hole.

ACT 2
Yay a rollar coaster ride! After you finish riding it, hit the first 
checkpoint and go on the small things that are moving. You&apos;ll automatically
be forced to SD. This is like bowling so try knocking all the pins down. You
get rings as a reward. Ignore the liquid enemy and get to the next 
checkpoint. Ignore the next liquid enemies and bowl again. Avoid the 
spinning spikes and get to the next checkpoint. Take the path that leads to 
a set of springs. Go on that and get to where you could jump on the 
platforms but some of them moves. If you don&apos;t fall, you can go through a 
shortcut. Get to the last checkpoint and hit the spring. You can go to the 
number pnels (The platforms leads you) or or you can take a shortcut. Go to 
where a black fence is and jump around it and hit the spring. Climb the 
stairs and avoid the enemies. jump on the capsule to beat the level.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go straight. Don&apos;t go back to Twinkle Park or Twinkle Circuit.&gt;Cutscene&lt;The card is in between the hotel and Twinkle Park. There&apos;s a light post if
you need another hint. Grab the employee Card and go to the floating 
computer thing and show the I.D. to get in. It&apos;s next to Twinkle Park. 
Enter the elevator.

**************
Speed Highway
**************

Mission C: Destroy the capsule and rescue the animals
Run till you start going down. At that point, jump and go to the left 2 
times to get the Magnetic Barrier. Go on the road thing and run till you get
on a red platform. This moves automatically when you go on it so wait till 
it stops. Hit the checkpoint and when you start running on the wall, go up 
to take a shortcut. All you got to do is keep moving forward from here and 
you&apos;ll be okay. When you get to a chopper, grab onto it and get to the next 
checkpoint. There&apos;s going to be cops (Kiki&apos;s) so kill them if you have to.
There&apos;s also a rocket that you need to go on so get on that. Run forward a 
bit and when you jump up in the air, try landing on the small platform. Then
HA your way through on another small platform. Underneath you (big platform)
is a rocket you need to go on so get on that and head to ACT 2.

ACT 2
Basically you run down a tall building collecting rings and all. This parts
pretty short.

ACT 3
Go on the dash panel on the right to run on the wall. Get to where you&apos;re on
a glass ceiling. HA the enemy and hit the spring. Run on the wall again and 
try making it on the higher platform above the rings. Grab the containers 
and SD and jump to the right building. Run forward and down the stairs. Go 
to the left and grab more containers. SD and jump towards the building with 
the giant bell. If you couldn&apos;t, go to the fountain or the spring on the 
left. The capsule should be a bit behind the giant bell.

Mission C completed

Go to the casino area.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to the Mystic Ruins.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go after Amy. Go to where Ice Cap is. (the entrance)
There was another path beyond where Ice Cap is. (again the entrance) But
it was locked but now it&apos;s open so go in there. Go to the bridge. You should
see an upgrade for Sonic so get it.

Alright! You got Ancient Light! With this, charge a Light Speed Dash towards
an enemy to do a Light Speed Attack

Now to test your upgrade. Use the Light Speed Attack on the guard monkey and
you&apos;ll be able to enter Red Mountain.

*************
Red Mountain
*************&gt;Cutscene&lt;Mission C: Chase the Egg Carrier!
Get on the rocket ahead of you and get to the spring. Hit it and you&apos;ll be 
in front of your first checkpoint. Go behind the giant spike and press the 
switch to activate the rocket. Hit the spring here and reach the next 
checkpoint. Run across the bridge and be careful not to hit the giant 
spikes. Get the life and hit the spring. Go on the little rope machine and 
hit the next checkpoint. Carefully jump from platform to platform and hit 
the spring. Run across the path and HA the 2 enemies and life. Get on the 
number panel and take the shortcut. HA the enemies and work your way up the 
mountain to reach the next checkpoint. When you&apos;re done crossing the bridge,
fall down where there&apos;s a fence thing. This is another shortcut, so hit the 
switch without getting smashed and get on the rocket. There&apos;s another rope 
machine when you get to the end. Jump down to enter ACT 2.

ACT 2
Hit the checkpoint and run forward till you see a trail of rings going up. 
Follow it and HA the High Speed container and run. Stop at the spring and 
hit it. There&apos;s a shield up ahead that should help so get that. HA the 
enemies and run till you get to the checkpoint. Hit the checkpoint and the 
spring. If you lost the barrier, there&apos;s another barrier so get that. Just 
jump and run through the level. When you see the fugitives hit the spring 
and wait for the rocks or whatever to fall. HA the enemies and charge for 
the Light Speed Dash. Hit the spring then the dash panel. Get to the final 
checkpoint and cautiously go through the area till you get to a rocket. Get 
on that and jump on the capsule.&gt;Cutscene&lt;****************
Sky Chase Act 2
****************

This level is pratically the same as ACT 1 but more enemies. Lock-on and 
keep shooting and you&apos;ll be okay.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Carrier

The front of the ship&apos;s going to open so thats the time to start shooting. 
But the Egg Carriers going to shoot a powerful beam so dodge it. When it 
finishes its attack, continue shooting it. This should be an easy fight as 
long as you don&apos;t get hit.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Hit the spring and...&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the entrance of Sky Deck.&gt;Cutscene&lt;*****************
Sky Deck
*****************

Mission C: Destroy the capsule and rescue the animals
Cautiously jump towards the opposite and hit the checkpoint. Cannons are 
going to be fired so keep running and jump over the obstacles. When you 
reach the next checkpoint, HA the enemies and land on the platform ahead. 
Wait for a crain to come and jump to grab on it. Get on the rocket and hit 
the Explosion capsule to kill the enemies around you. HA the Magnetic 
Barrier as well as the Invincibility, Life, and High Speed capsules. Go 
through the giant spikes if you wish but you can jump from the point where 
you are to the lower platforms. Be careful not to fall or you&apos;ll instantly 
die. There&apos;s going to be some annoying enemies as you go so I suggest 
killing them. There&apos;s going to be a big cannon that shoots over and over 
after you get to this last area so SD your way through but try not to rush 
or you&apos;ll probably die. When you get to a dead end with a rocket, shoot it 
when the cannon faces you.

ACT 2
Hit the checkpoint and grab the rings here. I suggest taking the left path 
but it&apos;s your choice. Work your way through this hell hole and go up some 
stairs and hit the checkpoint. When you hit the checkpoint, immediately SD 
forward. The platforms are going to periodically fall so you want to get to 
the otherside quickly as possible. There&apos;s another big cannon so fire the 
rockets that are setted in the area. 1 shot will destroy it so you don&apos;t 
have to rush. But there&apos;s a lot of mini cannons that shoots fast or slow so 
be careful here.

ACT 3
When you begin hit the checkpoint and go to the right. If you see a path of
rings and a elevator looking machine, thats where you&apos;re suppossed to go. 
Avoid the enemies here and hit the dash panel. When Sonic stops running, 
climb the ladder thing and there&apos;s going to be another crain so grab that. 
Land on the higher platform and take a right. You should be on a much higher
platform. Jump on the cargo and stay on the right. Don&apos;t go to the left or 
you&apos;ll have go through the longer route. Anyways, hit the spring and get to 
the top area. The camera should start changing and the haches will start 
opening so be careful. You have to climb the ladder thing and get to the 
checkpoint. When you reach the checkpoint, just keep following the path and 
hit the switch at the bottom to open the gate. Jump on the capsule to 
complete the level.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on the yellow transporter thing.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;

You want to finish him off before he can even attack so take him down. Hit 
him 3 times to defeat him

Attack Pattern:
1. Lock-on Attack
He targets on you and shoots you. Pretty easy to avoid.&gt;Cutscene&lt;You can now play as E-102

Head straight from where amy is.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the room. Hit the switch on the floor and use the Light Speed Dash on 
the trails of rings. Sit on the seat and the chair should start moving. 
Go back and hit the switch.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Get out and head back to where the Tornado 2 is.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 6

He has 6 Chaos Emeralds but Chaos 6 isn&apos;t that challenging. Eggman throws
these weird frozen enemies so you have to HA. When you HA it, it sort of
hardens up or something. Grab it and throw it into his mouth or let Chaos 6 
suck it up. He freezes and thats when you&apos;re supposed to HA him. Do this 4
times and he breaks apart.

Attack Pattern:
1. Inhale/ Suck In
Basically he tries to suck you in his body. Use the enemies that Eggman 
throws to freeze him up. Run the opposite direction if there&apos;s no enemy.

2. Homing Tail
He&apos;s going to stretch part of his body into small thin pieces to trap you.
Then he&apos;s going to get his tail out and swing at you. Try jumping through 
some of the stretched area. But it&apos;s hard to avoid getting hit from this 
attack.

3. Tail Whip
When you get too close to him, he&apos;s going to use this attack. Pretty hard 
to dodge. Best strategy is to stay far from him or stay an average distance
away from him.

4. Shockwave
It&apos;s like Chaos 4&apos;s Sonic Boom. A beefed up version. Jump to avoid getting 
hit.

5. Frozen Gas
Eggman&apos;s robot uses this kind of attack. If you&apos;re too close, the robots 
going to use this so HA them before they can get you. You could also Spin 
Attack them before they attack or SD away from them if they&apos;re too close.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;You can now play as BIG

Go in the snakes mouth.

***********
Lost World
***********

Mission C: Go to the center of the Ruin
Follow the rings at the beginning and enter the cave or whatever you like to
call it. After you come out of this area, you&apos;re going see fires and the 
ground moving. SD your way out and enter another cave. But this one&apos;s short 
so hold up. Get to the checkpoint and keep moving forward. The snakes mouth
is going to open so enter it. Here we need to press the 3 switches to go to 
ACT 2. There&apos;s a switch on the right but you can&apos;t get to it. So take a left
and run almost around this place. Once you get on the platform, jump on the 
blue switch.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the next platform and jump on the big switch. This raises the water 
level. Go on the snake and wait till you see the next switch. When you 
see it, jump off the snake onto a platform. Press the green switch.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Then go on the platform above you. SD and jump to go on the platform next 
to you. Press the big switch to raise the water level again. SD and jump or 
go on the snake and press the red switch.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Wait till the snake comes and ride on it. Jump off when you get to
the gate entrance and go in.

ACT 2
Run and follow the rings until you get to the Mirror room. This place is 
dark so use the light and reflect it on the mirror. Continue forward and 
use the light on the mirror again. There should also be a shield so get 
that. There&apos;s some traps here so jump from platform to platform. When you 
get to the next light and mirror, there&apos;s 2 paths. The left path is 
dangerous but quicker. The straight path is longer but safer. When you get 
to the next light and mirror, charge for your Light Spin Dash and jump from 
platform to platform till you see fire arrows and a trail of rings. Use your
Light Spin Dash to get across. There should be a checkpoint near here so hit
that and go in the water which is a waterfall. When you&apos;re out, hit the 
spring and SD through the next area. Hit the checkpoint and SD down the 
slope. Hit the checkpoint and continue. You should be seing a small ancient 
tower thing. Jump on top of it to get a barrier. You will need this barrier 
so go to the next area. When you get in, take a right and hit the switch 2 
times. Climb up and take a right. There should be a dead end so go on top of
the magic block thing. Jump on top of the spike and jump again to reach a 
platform. Charge a Light Speed Dash and hit the switch. Dash through the 
rings and run through the rest to get to the center of the ruin. 
(This is a short cut)&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Run towards the temple. Scan around the area to find a person on the ground.
Go to her.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to where Eggman went. Enter his base and how did he make all of this?
Light all lights to open the last stage for Sonic.

1. Jump on the 2nd light from the left.
2. Jump on the 3rd light from the left.
3. Jump on the 5th light from the left.

**********
Final Egg
**********

Mission C: Go to the center of the base
This part of the level isn&apos;t hard. HA the SparkUnit (the one that has purple
lasers shooting out) and get the Life and Magnetic Barrier on a higher 
platform. Run and SD through the level until you reach the 2nd checkpoint. 
Time your jumps carefully and get through this place. SD your way through 
the rest of this ACT.

ACT 2
When you begin, you&apos;ll be running but you&apos;ll land on a platform. Jump or HA 
your way down until you find a switch on the ground. (Do NOT fall down or 
you&apos;ll lose a life) Hit it and the platform rises! HA the enemies and land on
another platform. There should be a hammer swinging so time your jump (HA) and
get on the next platform. After you got through the platform obsticles, enter 
the elevator to go down to the lower level. Head forward and start going down 
more. You&apos;ll eventually come to a big platform and a big elevator. You could 
grab the rings but enter the elevator afterwards.

ACT 3
Get the 2 lives and the magnetic barrier when you begin. If you need more 
rings, there should be some in this room. When you enter a room with a ton 
of purple machines jump over them and climb the ladder. Hit the checkpoint 
and use the fans to continue. Don&apos;t fall or you&apos;ll die. When you get to the 
next checkpoint, you&apos;ll be jumping down. There&apos;s going to be a platform at 
the bottom but a small one. Use the fans and enter the next room. Run across
and ignore the enemies in this room. Jump over the 3 robots and a Sonic, 
Tails, and a Knuckles doll comes out. Ignore them and hit the last 
checkpoint. Charge a Light Speed Dash and head up stairs. Use your Light 
Speed Attack to get rid of the last enemies. Charge another Light Speed Dash
and go through the trail of rings. Run forward a bit and you&apos;re now at the 
center of the base!&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Viper

When the battle begins, go to far left or right to collect some rings.
Eggman&apos;s going to shoot some laser&apos;s (1) so run to avoid getting hit. He&apos;s
going to give you the chance to attack while he&apos;s dancing or mocking you so
HA him. When the Egg Viper starts aiming at you, run in one direction and come
back. When he shoots, it should make a wide spread explosion (Laser 2). When
you hit the Egg Viper 5 times, he destroys the other side of the platforms. 
And when he loses all of his HP, he crashes the Egg Viper on one of the 
platforms so do your best to not get hit. Hit him 7 times to defeat him.

Be patient.

Attack Pattern:
1. Laser Beam Attack 1
He shoots 3 lasers at you. Run or SD to avoid

2. Laser Beam Attack 2
Aims a wide spread laser at you. 

3. Laser Beam Attack 3
Rapidly shoots lasers. Run at him and while he&apos;s coming towards you and turn
left or right before he&apos;s going to hit you.

4. Energy Attack
When you HA 3 green spots and Eggman there&apos;s 3 blue round things around that
are charging. If you couldn&apos;t hit Eggman in time, he shoots a powerful 
energy attack. To avoid it, simply keep hammering Eggman with HA&apos;s.

5. Rotating Needle Attack
When Eggman releases the spikes on the Egg Viper, he shoots one at you, it 
stops but keeps turning. Jump on it and it should go back in front of the
Egg Viper. HA Eggman when you have a chance of hitting him.&gt;Cutscene&lt;CREDITS
FIN :D

You should have 12 Emblems so far...

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-------------------------Miles &quot;Tails&quot; Prower-------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Tails&apos;s Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

SA - Same as Sonic&apos;s

Tail Spin - Press the B button to spin your tail 360 degrees.

Consecutive Tail Spin - If you have the Rythem Badge, hold B to spin your tail
360 degrees over and over.

Fly - Press and hold A to fly. If you have the Jet Anklet, you&apos;ll fly faster.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;First, go behind Twinkle Park to enter some sewer. When you get to a dead
end, there should be a hole big eneough for you to enter. Fly up there and
enter the next room. Get your first upgrade, the Jet Anklet. This lets you
fly faster so this should really help.

Go to the Mystic Ruins. 

Go to his workshop when you get to the Mystic Ruins.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Hornet

Grab a few rings and avoid the missles he shoots. This place is big so fly
around. To attack him, wait until Eggman drives the sharp things on the
floor. Spin Attack him 3 times.

Attack Pattern:
1. Homing Missles
Each time you hit him, the missles grow in numbers so just run around to avoid
getting hit

2. Take Down
He gets 2 sharp things and try&apos;s to crush you with it. Simply run back when 
he attacks you with it.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Grab the Wind Stone in front of the workshop and go to Windy Valley. A 
persons near a cave. Thats the entrance. Set the Wind Stone on the pedestal
and go on the wind. It&apos;s near a waterfall.

*************
Windy Valley
*************

Mission C: Find the Chaos Emerald before Sonic!
You can run through the normal path or you can just fly platform to 
platform. When you start seing green and black circle things, thats a Dash
Ring. Fly through it to get a quick boost. Do this every time you see one.
This level should be an easy one. At the end, there&apos;s an invisible path so
be sure to hold up. Hit the Chaos Emerald before Sonic to win.

Mission C completed.

When you come back, take the train to Station Square. Go back in the hotel
and take a right to go to the casino area. Fly and hit the round object 
above CASINO to open the casino door.

************
Casinopolis
************

Mission C: Find the Chaos Emerald before Sonic!
Start by flying up and hit the Explosion capsule. Fly through this area 
until you reach the big room with a giant fan. Go to where a path of rings
that go up. Avoid the spikes and grab the capsules if you want. When you
reach another room with the giant fan, do the same thing. When you get to 
a room with groups of rings, fly over the spikes and get the barrier. Hit 
the Chaos Emerald before Sonic to win.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go get the Ice Stone. Take the train to the Mystic Ruins.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the cave and go on the wind. Search for a frozen door and a pedestal.
Put the Ice Stone in the pedestal and enter. Climb the ladder afterwards.

********
Ice Cap
********

Mission C: Find to the Choas Emerald before Sonic!
Sonic&apos;s ACT 3! Same thing, just perform tricks on the ramps and hit the dash
panel and you&apos;ll be alright. You get off your board at the end so you can&apos;t
miss the Chaos Emerald.

Mission C completed.

Go back outside and head to the waterfall.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Knuckles

Use your Tail (B) to attack Knuckles. Fly and tackle Knuckles when he starts
gliding. 3 hits will end the fight

Attack Pattern:
1. Punch
Not like Chaos 0&apos;s punch. He does 2 jabs then a thrust. To counter this, 
simply fly.

2. Tackle while Gliding
He jumps in the air and glides towards you. Fly and tackle him to knock both
characters down. Swiftly use your tail or jump on him to inflict damage.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 4

Collect some rings if you need to, then fly around and wait until the purple
thing glows. Hit him with a Spin Attack. Hit 4 times to defeat Chaos 4.

Attack Pattern:
1. Sonic Boom
He&apos;s going to send some wide spreading attacks so fly over this attack when
he starts using it. When you inflict some damage, he&apos;s going to start 
throwing in some extra Sonic Booms so fly over them.

2. Punch
He&apos;s going to stretch his arms or whatever and swing it. Not much to say...

3. Split up Attack
He splits in 4&apos;s and starts to tackle you. Simply fly around to avoid 
getting hit.

4. Lillypad sinking hits
This attack won&apos;t hurt you but he basically sinks the lillypads that are in
sight and the one you&apos;re on.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Tails&apos;s workshop and get on the Tornado!&gt;Cutscene&lt;****************
Sky Chase ACT 1
****************

Hold B or A to lock on target and release to shoot homing lasers.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Get on the trolley near the water fall. 

Fly towards the ancient temple&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the cave and fly up on the platform. Jump on the switch to move the 
sand. Enter

**********
Sand Hill
**********

Use the control stick to move. Go through the soccer goal looking thing to 
get points. Get to the end of the area to complete the level.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;First take a left and fly over the stairs. Run towards the right. If you 
see an upgrade, get it. If you can&apos;t, fly to look for it. You got the Rhythm
Badge. With this, you can continuously use the Tail Attack. Hold the B 
button to use it.

Go to the front of the big temple.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the workshop&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;****************
Sky Chase ACT 2
****************

Same as ACT 1 but a lot more enemies.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Carrier

The front of the ship&apos;s going to open so thats the time to start shooting. 
But the Egg Carriers going to shoot a powerful beam so dodge it. When it 
finishes its attack, continue shooting it. This should be an easy fight as 
long as you don&apos;t get hit.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Hit the spring and...&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the entrance of Sky Deck&gt;Cutscene&lt;*********
Sky Deck
*********

Mission C: Beat Sonic to the capsule and destroy it!
After you hit the first checkpoint, start running and jump over the 
obstacles. Fly on the platform and hit the spring. Time your jump and 
continue. Fly towards the crain area and fly through the Dash Ring. Fly
towards the the building with the stairs that goes up. (Not stairs but 
something like that)Get the magnetic barrier and fly. When you get to the 
next checkpoint, fly on top of the platform and fly across the whole level.
There are many platforms to fly from so use the Dash Rings to get some
capsules. Then fly towards the big capsule and jump on it to win.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on the yellow transporter thing.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;

You want to finish him off before he can even attack so take him down. Hit 
him with 3 Spin Attacks to end the fight.

Attack Pattern:
1. Lock-on Attack
He targets on you and shoots you. Pretty easy to avoid&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;**************
Speed Highway
**************

Mission C: Find the missle before Robotnik
There&apos;s a whole bunch of Dash Rings so use them as your advantage. Eggman
shouldn&apos;t be able to catch up if you keep moving. Ignore enemies and 
capsules and focus on flying and the goal. If there isn&apos;t any Dash Rings 
around you, just keep flying from platform to platform. If you see the 
rocket, the goal should be next to the rocket. Go in the opening before
Eggman to beat the level.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Egg Walker

If you have the Rythem Badge, this battle should be easy. First, grab a 
couple of rings, avoid Eggman&apos;s attacks, and go under the Egg Walker. Wait
until the Egg Walker starts to stomp the ground. It&apos;ll make some vibration 
so jump over that. When it finishes, hit the green/blue thing with your 
tail. When the legs collapse, hit the cockpit. Do this 5 times to defeat 
him.

Attack Pattern:
1. Bomb Attack 1
His opening attack. Grab a couple of rings and avoid getting hit. But it has
a decent spread ability so It&apos;ll be hard to dodge. Eggman uses this attack 
when you&apos;re far from him.
 
2. Bomb Attack 2
He uses this attack when he jumps. The location of the bombs falling are 
random.

3. Bomb Attack 3
Eggman launches small bombs from underneath the cockpit while the Egg Walker
moves. 

4. Flamethrower
He uses this attack when you&apos;re in the air. It doesn&apos;t really reach you if
you&apos;re kinda away from him.

5. Vibration/Shock Attack
He uses this attack when you&apos;re under the cockpit. Jump to avoidand use your
tail to cause some damage on the leg. Unbalance the legs to make the legs
collapse.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 20 Emblems now.

&quot;SONIC THE HEDGEHOG&quot;
was added to the list

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------Knuckles the Echidna-----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Knuckles Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

SA - Same as Sonic and Tails&apos;s

Punch - Press B repeatedly 3 times to do a jab&gt;jab&gt;thrust

Glide - Jump and hold A. Use the control stick to move Knuckles.

Wall Climb - Jump or glide onto a wall. Use the control stick to move.

Dig - Press A and B together to dig. You need a Shovel Claw to dig.

Maximum Heat Knuckles - You need the Fighters Glove to use this attack. Hold B
and release it to a group of enemies to perform this homing attack. 

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Start by going to the City Hall. (Where you first fought Chaos 0 with Sonic)
Punch the gate thing and enter the door.

**************
Speed Highway
**************

Mission C: Find the 3 Emeralds!
Use the radar and check where the Hintball flies. (Tikal) The Master Emerald
pieces can be in the open, inside an enemy, or buried underground (dig). The
radar changes from blue&gt;green&gt;yellow&gt;red.

Get the 3 pieces to beat the level.

Mission C completed

Now go to the casino area. As you know the casino&apos;s closed. Find a ring near
the casino. Climb the theater and glide towards the button that opens the
casino. Enter.

************
Casinopolis
************

Mission C: Find the 3 Emeralds!
Use the radar and hintball to find the 3 pieces. There&apos;s a Sonic statue in
the center. If the radar or the hintball tells you that it&apos;s in it, go on
the statue and punch the shoe area. Most of pieces are in the open so this 
level shouldn&apos;t be that hard.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Talk to the people if you want but go to the opposite side of where you 
started.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Now go back to the hotel.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the right elevator&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 2

Chaos was given 2 Chaos Emeralds but he&apos;s still pretty weak. Hit him 4 
times to defeat him.

Attack Pattern:
1. 2 Level Punch
His hand glows when he&apos;s about to use this attack. When he tries to punch
you move around the battlefield. His hand kinda bends. Counter attack when
he misses.

2. Instant Liquified
Chaos 2 liquifies it&apos;s body and creates a wide spreading attack. Jump and
glide to avoid getting hit. You&apos;ll know when he turns into a liquid and 
starts to glow.

3. Giant Ball Attack
He turns into a giant ball and tries to crush you. When Chaos 2 uses this
attack, Spin Attack him to counter.

4. Ball Split Attack
When Chaos 2&apos;s loses a lot of health, he spits into small blue balls.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the East Cave. If you don&apos;t know where it is, It&apos;s near Tails&apos;s
workshop. Use the map if you can&apos;t find it.

Instead of taking the trolley, enter the other room. When you enter this 
room, you&apos;re going be trapped. Get your first upgrade, the Shovel Claw. 
Press B and A together to dig. Go to the next room with an Eggman sign going
up and down. Dig to get the Monkey Destruction Switch. Throw it at the guard 
monkey to break through. Take the Monkey Destruction Switch with you to Red 
Moutain. Throw the switch at the guard monkey again to open the gate. Enter 
Red Mountain.

*************
Red Mountain
*************

Mission C: Find the 3 Emeralds!
Use the radar, the hintball, and now your shovel claw. If you know the 
radars red and you can&apos;t find the piece, try digging. Use the hintball if
you see one.

Mission C completed.

Now go to the waterfall area.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Sonic

If you lose your rings, you can dig for some. Hit Sonic with your fists.
3 hits should end the fight.

Attack Pattern:
1. Spin Attack
He&apos;s going to jump around so don&apos;t be too close to Sonic. Hit him with your 
fists

2. Homing Atack (Home Attack)
When you hit him 2 times, he&apos;s going to start HA you so spin attack to 
counter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 4

When the fight begins, glide around the battlefield. This is like the battle 
with Chaos 0 and 2. Hit the brain area to inflict damage when it&apos;s glowing. 
5 hits and he&apos;ll go down.

Attack Pattern:
1. Sonic Boom
He&apos;s going to send some wide spreading attacks so jump over this attack when
he starts using it. When you inflict some damage, he&apos;s going to start 
throwing in some extra Sonic Booms so jump over them.

2. Punch
He&apos;s going to stretch his arms or whatever and swing it. Not much to say...

3. Split up Attack
He splits in 4&apos;s and starts to tackle you. Simply glide around to avoid 
getting hit.

4. Lillypad sinking hits
This attack won&apos;t hurt you but he basically sinks the lillypads that are in
sight and the one you&apos;re on.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on the trolley behind you.

Your objective is to bring the 2 statues to the temple. But right now, glide
to the right. You should see some sort of tree right? Thats Big&apos;s house.
Go above that onto a platform. Get the upgrade known as the Fighting Glove.
Hold B to store power and release it to use the Maximum Heat Knuckles 
Attack. It&apos;s good for taking out a group of enemies at once.

Now go back and grab the Gold statue and set on the gold pedestal. Use your
map and locate a fork on the left side. It should be close to the temple.
Dig on the Eggman sign and grab the Silver statue. Set it on the silver
pedestal and go in the shiny opening.

***********
Lost World
***********

Mission C: Find the 3 Emeralds!
Use the hintball to locate the Emeralds and the radar to find it. Dig if you
know the Emeralds in the ground.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to the alter. Run up the stairs.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go back to the giant temple. You should notice a base? How did that get 
there? It wasn&apos;t there when you were getting the key&apos;s. Anyways, get closer.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Move a little closer to the place where Sonic fought Chaos 6. The bridge
area.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the pool room. The water should be empty so go to the bottom.&gt;Cutscene&lt;*********
Sky Deck
*********

Mission C: Find the 3 Emeralds!
Tilt the ship by pushing a lever up, down, left, or right. There&apos;s going to be
Emeralds in the hach so you need to tilt the lever. There&apos;s an Emerald in one 
of the Spinners (flying enemies) so use your Maximum Heat Knuckles Attack to 
get rid of them. There are 4 places to dig so use the hintball effectivly.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Run towards the alter. You should see Tikal on the floor so go to her.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to where you fought Chaos 6 with Sonic.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 6
Grab a few rings behind you and punch the ice robots with your fists. Throw
1 at Chaos 6 and freeze it. Spin Attack or hit Chaos 6 with your fist. Hit
him 4 times. there&apos;s some destroyed platforms so move by gliding or running
from the black and yellow tiles to the other side. 

Attack Pattern:
1. Inhale/ Suck In
Basically he tries to suck you in his body. Throw the ice robots to freeze
him. Run the opposite direction if you don&apos;t have an enemy to throw or
letting Chaos 6 suck one of those ice robots.

2. Homing Tail
He&apos;s going to stretch part of his body into small thin pieces to trap you.
Then he&apos;s going to get his tail out and swing at you. Try jumping through 
some of the stretched area but it&apos;s hard to evade.

3. Tail Whip
When you get too close to him, he&apos;s going to use this attack. Pretty hard to 
dodge. Best strategy is to stay far from him or stay an average distance 
away from him.

4. Shockwave
It&apos;s like Chaos 4&apos;s Sonic Boom. A beefed up version. Jump or glide to avoid 
getting hit.

5. Frozen Gas
Eggman&apos;s robot uses this kind of attack. If you&apos;re too close, the robots 
going to use this so Spin Attack them before they get you.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 26 Emblems now.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Amy Rose----------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Amy&apos;s Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Hammer - Press the B button to attack an enemy in front of you.

Hammer Jump - Press B while running to jump high momentarily.

Mid-air Hammer - Jump and press B to attack enemies in the air.

Hammer Swing - You need the Warrior Feather. Hold B and rotate your control
stick.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the casino area.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Twinkle Park&gt;Cutscene&lt;*************
Twinkle Park
*************

Mission C: Evade Zero and grab the balloon!
Start by taking a right and go around the pool. Tere are 3 switches that you
need to press. Ignore the enemies and continue forward. If you&apos;re too slow,
Zero will come out so hit the switches fast and enter the big door.

ACT 2
If you go to the next room, you&apos;ll be in the Mirror Room. Try jumping over or
dash through the spikes. Zero will probably come out so hit him to knock him
out if he gets too close. When you get to a checkpoint, there&apos;s another
Mirror Room. But your movements get a little hectic. Do your best to avoid
getting hit by the spikes and Zero. When you get to he next Mirror Room, there
are trap floors set but there easy to notice. Get out of the Mirror Room and
avoid the enemies. When you see a brown door, ACT 2 will be over so get 
through the door.

ACT 3
You&apos;ll hit a checkpoint when you enter ACT 3. If you go near the Hintball,
It&apos;ll tell you that you can use the drum can to fool Zero. Ignore it and start
going towards the right side. You should see a Kiki. Ignore him and jump over
the explosive barrels. Get up the hill and there should be a yellow balloon.
Get on that to beat the level.

Mission C completed

Go outside.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the next room.&gt;Cutscene&lt;****************
Hedgehog Hammer
****************

The doors locked so get on the stage and start swinging!

Blue Sonic +100
Yellow Sonic +500
Robotnik -200

Beat 2000 points to get the Warrior Feather.&gt;Cutscene&lt;With the Warrior Feather you can use the Spin Hammer attack. Hold B and rotate
your control stick 360 degree&apos;s.

Get out and hammer the switch on your left. Go in the middle door.

************
Hot Shelter
************

Mission C: Evade Zero and grab the balloon!
When you get off the elevator continue forward. You should see a hintball.
Go to the handle and hold it with B and turn it left. Open the gate and get
the barrier. When you see another hintball and 2 containers, Zero&apos;s going to 
come out so dash forward. Jump on the small platform and try not to fall in
the water. Climb the ladder if you fall. Hit the checkpoint and the Explosion
capsule. Go to the hintball and hit the switch. Go across and hit the next
hintball. Go to the handle and move it left once to get a green light. Now
move it right 3 times to open the gate. Hit the checkpoint and continue. Go up
the ladder thing into the air vent. When you come out, Zero&apos;s going to pop-up
from behind so run away. You can push the ladder or jump from the ladder to
the air vent. 

ACT 2
Hit the checkpoint and leave the girls restroom. Grab the shield and go to
the handle and quickly open the gate. Hit Zero if you need to. Jump down
and continue. Jump over the moving machines and hit the switch. Jump on the
moving machines again and hit the checkpoint. Grab the containers and go on 
the machine to the right. Let it take you to a higher platform. Hit the switch
and go on the other machine. Grab the High Speed and Invicibility capsules and
go to the Eggman sign. It should start opening so wait. Get inside and hit the
switch but be careful not to fall. Get to the other end.

ACT 3

Go up the ladder, ignore Zero, and grab the barrier. Go to the handle and go 
up. Jump down and hit the spring. Hit the checkpoint now and go in the Moniter
Room. Place the box or cubes in the color displayed and Zero should come out.
Run through the next area until you get to a checkpoint. Go to the right and
grab the Shield, High Speed, and Invincibility capsules. Head to the top area
after. Put the box or cubes in the color displayed. Go on the spring and get
on the thin platform next to you. Get the blue cube and get to the balloon. 

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go back. Run to the alter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Get out of the pool room.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go under the station. 

Use the boat? 

Once you&apos;re at the Egg Carrier, go to the opposite of where you are. Go on one
of the green swtces to call the monorail. Go in and It&apos;ll take you to the 1st
floor. Hit the switch with your hammer and go in the Hedgehog Hammer room.

Score over 3000 points to get the Long Hammer.&gt;Cutscene&lt;With the Long Hammer, the attack radius increases. Now go all the way back to 
the Mystic Ruins.

Go on the trolley. (Near the waterfall)

Go to the entrance of the base.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go in the base.

Light all lights to open the door.

1. Jump on the 2nd light from the left.
2. Jump on the 3rd light from the left.
3. Jump on the 5th light from the left.

Enter.

**********
Final Egg
**********&gt;Cutscene&lt;Mission C: Evade Zero and grab the balloon!
Go around the SparkUnits and stay away from the spinning spikes. When you get
to the checkpoint, jump in between the lasers and hammer jump the next one.
When you get to a switch, hit it and go behind some of the barricades. Wait
for the elevator to come and go on it when it opens. Jump throgh this area
and ignore the Spinners if you can. When you see the hintball, it tells you
that one of the 5 is the correct path. But it&apos;s random so hit Zero if he&apos;s
about to attack. When you find the right path, hit the checkpoint and get some
speed. Jump over to the higher platform to the left. Get on the balloon to
escape from him.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go back to the Egg Carrier.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Zero

Hit him with your hammer towards the electric wall. Hit the blue thing on his
head when it comes out to damage him. Don&apos;t hit him when he starts attacking
because the hammer won&apos;t push him. 3 hits to defeat him. Pretty easy huh? 

Attack Pattern:
1. Arm Punch
Locks on you and throws a punch. Easy to avoid.

2. Shockwave
Zero jumps and sends a shockwave around him. He jumps towards Amy and hitting
him while jumping won&apos;t send him back. So it&apos;s best if you jump to avoid the
shockwaves.

3. Electric Current Arm
Shoots out both of his hands and turns. Jump to dodge.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 30 Emblems now.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-------------------------------Big the Cat----------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Big&apos;s Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Strong Arm - Hold, throw, pull, and push objects.

Swim - If you have the lifebelt, hold A to sink. Use the control stick to
move Big.

Rod - Press B to attack enemies.

Cast - Hold B to use the cast console to target enemy. Release to attack the
enemy with the lure.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to where you got the Jet Anklet with Tails. Get the upgrade. You get a lure
upgrade.

Head to the City Hall area.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go through the tunnel and get to an elevator. Go on it and head to Twinkle 
Park.

*************
Twinkle Park
*************

Mission C: Fish for and catch Froggy!
I suggest going into the pool and find Froggy. Kill the Kiki&apos;s that can get
in the way and fish out Froggy to beat the level.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Grab the Ice Stone and head to the Mystic Ruins.

Put the Ice Stone on the pedestal and enter. You should see an upgrade on the
left. Get the Lifebelt! Press A in the water to sink. You&apos;ll stay afloat when
nothing&apos;s pressed.

Clmb the ladder.

********
Ice Cap
********

Mission C: Fish for and catch Froggy!
Start by going on the spring. Keep moving up until you find water under a
platform. Go through it and make it to the other end. Hit the spring and make
it back on land. Go down and look for a rock. Jump on the cracked ice around
this area. Go down and get a lure upgrade. Froggy should be near the area
you started so go back and catch Froggy.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on trolly and go to Big&apos;s house. Use the map if you can&apos;t find it. Push the
bed to get the Power Rod. You get a longer casting rod. *Yay*

Use your map to locate a round area near Big&apos;s house. Go there to get a lure
upgrade.

Go back to Station Square. Leave the station.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Emerald Coast

**************
Emerald Coast
**************

Mission C: Fish for and catch Froggy!
Froggy&apos;s near the Lighthouse so search him and catch him. Kill the enemies
just in case so they don&apos;t get in the way.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the prison cell area. Get another lure upgrade here and go to Hot 
Shelter.

************
Hot Shelter
************

Mission C: Fish for and catch Froggy!
Go to the Water Drainage Switch and hit it.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Froggy&apos;s near the stairs so fish him out.

Mission C completed&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to the alter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on the monorail.

Head to the Center Dome.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Chaos 6

Aim your rod at the red marker and try getting Froggy out of Chaos 6. Real
simple. Let Sonic take care of fighting Chaos 6.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the Tornado 2.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 35 Emblems now.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/------------------------------E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;---------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Gamma&apos;s Action/Attacks
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Change Mode - If you walk or run a few seconds, you&apos;ll change mode to a more
suited mode for the terrain. If you&apos;re on water, you change mode to a water
hovering mode. 

Hover - You need the Jet Booster. Jump and hold the A button.

Lock-on - Hold the B button to lock-on. Release to shoot.

------------------------
Lock-on | Bonus Time |
 x1 | +1 Seconds |
 x2 | +3 Seconds |
 x3 | +6 Seconds |
 x4 | +10 Seconds |
 x5 | +15 Seconds |
 x6 | +20 Seconds |
 x7 | +25 Seconds |
 x8 | +30 Seconds |
 x9&amp;| 30 + x5 |
 up | Seconds |
------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------------------&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Eggman.

**********
Final Egg
**********

Mission C: Destroy the Sonic Doll!
Destoying a Sonic doll is simple so practice locking on targets on this level.

Mission C completed

Go to Eggman. He&apos;s on the lower level.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-101 &quot;Beta&quot;

Attack Pattern:
1. Guidance Missle
The missle&apos;s slow so you can calmly lock-on the missle and Beta. 3 shots and
he&apos;ll go down.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Emerald Coast.

**************
Emerald Coast
**************

Mission C: Catch &quot;Froggy&quot;!
Lock-on and keep shooting enemies from a distance and you&apos;ll be okay. This
level&apos;s pretty short so you shouldn&apos;t have trouble.

Mission C completed.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to the alter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the prison cell.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go back.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the Ammunition Room and get the Jet Booster. You can now hover. Get out.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the rear of the ship. Take the transporter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Sonic

Attack Pattern:
1. Spin Attack
Sonic might try jumping at you or jump away. You can damage Sonic when he&apos;s
curled up in a ball.

2. Spin Dash
Charges up speed and try&apos;s hitting you. Jump or shoot him.

3. Homing Attack
When you hit Sonic 2 times, he&apos;s going to start HA you.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Grab the Wind Stone near Tails&apos;s workshop and enter Windy Valley.

*************
Windy Valley
*************

Mission C: Destroy &quot;E-103&quot;!
Lock on the enemies and gain time. There&apos;s sometimes enemies on the bridge.
If you shoot them, the bridge should collapse so be careful.

Mission C completed

BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-103 &quot;Delta&quot;

Shoot Delta 5 times to defeat him. He has a hovering upgrade so he hovers
around a few times.

Attack Pattern:
1. Guidance Missle
This missle lasts for 5 seconds when shot.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Red Mountain


*************
Red Mountain
*************

Mission C: Destroy &quot;E-104&quot;!
Lock-on and shoot the enemies. The magma can easily hurt you so be careful.
The hammer&apos;s pretty easy to go through you should have no problem.

BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-104 &quot;Epsilon&quot;

He shoots 2 missles at a time so lock-on both missles and Epsilon. 5 hits
and he&apos;ll go down.

Attack Pattern:
1. Guidance Missle
Epsilon shoots 2 missles. This missle lasts for 7 seconds when shot.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the Egg Carrier. Use the boat thing to get there.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go on the transporter again and go to the otherside where you got the Jet 
Booster. Get the Laser Blaster and head to Hot Shelter.

************
Hot Shelter
************

Mission C: Destroy &quot;E-105&quot;!
There&apos;s a lot of enemies here so lock-on and shoot. There&apos;s also a lot of
rings so get them as well. Move at your own pace and keep shooting the 
enemies.

BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-105 &quot;Zeta&quot;

He has 8 batteries that support the missles. Take &apos;em out and you&apos;ll be 
okay.

Attack Pattern:
1. Guidance Missle
The E series fastest missle. Shoot them down before they hit you.

&quot;SONIC DRIFTRACING&quot;
was added to the list

Go to the rear of the ship.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to where Beta went.

BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;E-101 Mk II &quot;Kai&quot;

A customized E-101. He floats and has 2 plates of big armor next to his 
arms. He got really fast so keep up with him. His back area isn&apos;t that well 
protected. Shoot that area when he uses the dash attack. 3 shots and you win.

Attack Pattern:
1. Guidance Missle
Not the same missle from the other E series. He shoots a couple of them.

2. Particle Beam
Charges up energy between his hands and shoots you a few times. He charges the
last one a bit longer. Don&apos;t get caught in the explosion.

3. Dash Attack
He focus&apos;s energy onto his arm and lunges towards you. He&apos;s vulnerable to
attacks from the back when he uses this attack.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 41 Emblems now.

************
Super Sonic
************&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Angel Island. When you get there, go to where Knuckles and Eggman are.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Head to the alter.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to Tikal.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the Master Emerald.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;Go to the trolley.&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;&gt;Cutscene&lt;BOSS&gt;&gt;&gt;Perfect Chaos
You need speed to hurt him so start by collecting some rings and hitting the
dash panels. When you see him, dodge his attacks and hit him. If you had
enough speed, you should&apos;ve been able to hit him. Do this 3 times.

His atacks get severe so watch out. Hit him 3 times again to defeat him. Thats
6 hits. Good luck :D

Attack Pattern:
1. Tenticle Attack
Splits the tenticle and shoots them like missles. If you move at a zig-zag
pattern, you&apos;ll probably not get hit.

2. Breath Attack
When you start getting close to him, he&apos;s going to shoot a powerful beam. The
beam that shot down the Egg Carrier 2. It&apos;s a direct attck so it&apos;s pretty easy
to dodge.

3. Tornado Attack
When you get really close to him, he starts shooting out tornado&apos;s. They move
at a zig-zag pattern.&gt;Cutscene&lt;Credits
FIN

You should have 42 emblems now

Congratulations! You beat the Story Mode!

==============================================================================
4. Emblem Checklist
==============================================================================

Aim for the 130 Emblem!
I arranged the emblems in segments so this should help :D

Action Stage:
Sonic 10 stages x 3 = 30
Tails 5 stages x 3 = 15
Knuckles 5 stages x 3 = 15
Amy 3 stages x 3 = 9
Big 4 stages x 3 = 12
Gamma 5 stages x 3 = 15

Mini Game:
Sky Chase ACT 1 2 each
Sky Chase ACT 2 = 10
Sand Hill
Twinkle Circuit
Hedgehog Hammer

Ending: 1 each
Sonic = 7
Tails
Knuckles
Amy
Gamma
Big

Chao Race: 1 each
Pearl = 5
Ruby
Amethyst
Sapphire
Emerald

Adventure Field: 4 each 
SS, MR, and EC = 12

Total = 130 Emblems

Alright lets get started!
Go to Trial Mode and start completing the Mission B and A.
You can also go to the Adventure Field but Trial Mode is faster.

==============================================================================
4. a. Action Stage Emblems
==============================================================================

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/------------------------------Sonic the Hedgehog----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Emerald Coast-------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 01**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
50 rings is simple. Don&apos;t get hit and take your time. Don&apos;t rush through the
level and you&apos;ll be fine.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 2 minutes
SD through the level and take shortcuts. If you get hit, thats a time loss so
don&apos;t let that happen.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Windy Valley-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 02*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s a lot of rings so you should do just fine. Don&apos;t rush.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 3 minutes
SD and don&apos;t get hit. Ignore the enemies and you&apos;ll be okay.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Casinopolis--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 03**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
Collect 400 rings and deposit them. Collect 50 more rings and hit the capsule.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 5 minutes
Good luck, you&apos;ll need it. Collect rings at a fast pace.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-----------------------------------Ice Cap----------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 04**********************************/

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
You can get like over 100 rings when you&apos;re on the snowboard. But collect some
rings just in case.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 4 minutes
On ACT, get on the number panel. On ACT 2, rush through it but try not to 
fall. On ACT 3, perform tricks on the ramp.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Twinkle Park-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 05*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s plenty of rings so you&apos;ll do fine as long as you don&apos;t get hit.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 3 minutes
This can be hard. Go on the umper car fast and avoid the other bumper cars.
The roller coaster ride takes about 15 seconds so when you get out, start
Spin Dashing through the level. When you get out of the spinning spikes, SD
forward and hit the spring. Try getting to the higher platform to save about
40 seconds. Go around the fence and hit the spring.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Speed Highway-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 06*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s a lot of rings in this level too. Avoid getting hit and take your 
time.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 2 minutes and 30 seconds
You want to run through the little road that the red block runs on to save
time. You don&apos;t want to get hit and keep falling platform to platform. SD and
take shortcuts to get through this level.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Red Mountain-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 07*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s a couple 5 and 10 ring containers so get them with additional rings.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 3 minutes
There&apos;s a lot of shortcuts in this level. After checkpoint 4, there&apos;s a
shortcut that can get you to ACT 2 instantly. Cross the bridge and start
going down the path. Jump off and try locating a platform (which leads you to
ACT 2) so good luck.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-----------------------------------Sky Deck---------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 08*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s a couple magnetic barriers in this level so get them to have rings
go to you intead of you going to them. There&apos;s also ring containers so get
them too.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 5 minutes
Collect minumum rings and avoid time loss. Keep running and don&apos;t stop. Try
taking shortcuts and do your best.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Lost World--------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 09*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
There&apos;s a lot of rings in this level so you shouldn&apos;t worry too much. Just
worry about avoiding enemy attacks and falling.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 4 minutes and 30 seconds
Use the shortcut to get through the level quicker than the regular route.
Hit the switch on the right 2 times. Climb up and take a right. Go on the 
block and jump on top of the spike. Jump on the platform above, charge your
Light Speed Dash, and hit the switch. Go through the trail of rings.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Final Egg---------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 10**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the capsule!
Get the magnetic barrier and and have the rings come to you. Get some ring
containers and don&apos;t get hit.

Mission A: Destroy the capsule within 4 minutes and 30 seconds
SD through ACT 1. In ACT 2, go at your own pace and try not to rush through
this ACT. SD ACT 3 and don&apos;t have the magnetic barrier at the end or you&apos;ll
have trouble with the Light Spin Dash.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------Miles &quot;Tails&quot; Prower----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Windy Valley-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 01*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and beat Sonic!
Not that hard. Go on the dash rings, and collect rings while running through
the thin road and you&apos;ll have enough rings to beat the level.

Mission A: Beat an even faster Sonic!
Go on the dash rings and you&apos;ll beat him in no time.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Casinopolis--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and beat Sonic!
There&apos;s a lot of rings in this level so you shouldn&apos;t have trouble collecting
them. Don&apos;t hit the spikes.

Mission A: Beat an even faster Sonic! 
Memorize the route and avoid the containers.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-----------------------------------Ice Cap----------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 03**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and beat Sonic!
Sonic tends to crash into the ice a lot so it shold be easy to beat him.
Memorize where the rings are and you&apos;ll do fine.

Mission A: Beat an even faster Sonic! 
Take the shortcut after the bombardment. Perform tricks and try not to crash
into the wall.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-----------------------------------Sky Deck---------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 04*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and beat Sonic!
There&apos;s a lot of rings and a magnetic barrier so getting 50 rings is easy.
Fly a lot. 

Mission A: Beat an even faster Sonic! 
Fly through the level and run through area&apos;s you have to cover with running.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Speed Highway-------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 05**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and beat Dr. Robotnik!
There&apos;s a couple containers in this level. Grab the magnetic barrier near the
beginning of the level to ease the pain of collecting rings.

Mission A: Beat an even faster Dr. Robotnik!
Memorize the shortcuts and go through the dash rings. The Jet Anklet can help
you a lot so have that.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------Knuckles the Echidna----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Speed Highway-------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 01**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////


Mission B: Find the Emeralds without using any HintBalls!
There&apos;s no time limit so take your time.

Mission A: Find the Emeralds within 1 minute!
Find the 3 Emeralds but don&apos;t get them. Restart and get them real quick to
beat the level.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Casinopolis--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Find the Emeralds without using any HintBalls!
Take your time to beat this level. Some Emeralds are in the shower room, the
lion&apos;s mouth and enemies.

Mission A: Find the Emeralds within 1 minute!
Find the 3 Emeralds but don&apos;t get them. Restart and get them real quick to
beat the level.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Red Mountain-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 03*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Find the Emeralds without using any HintBalls!
The Emeralds are in the open, in a enemy, or you have to dig. Use your radar
and hunt them down.

Mission A: Find the Emeralds within 1 minute!
Find the 3 Emeralds but don&apos;t get them. Restart and get them real quick to
beat the level.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Lost World--------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 04*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Find the Emeralds without using any HintBalls!
The Emeralds are in dangerous area&apos;s so take caution when trying to get them.
When the radar&apos;s red, try digging.

Mission A: Find the Emeralds within 1 minute!
Find the 3 Emeralds but don&apos;t get them. Restart and get them real quick to
beat the level.

&quot;SONIC SPINBALL&quot;
was added to he list

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Sky Deck----------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 05**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Find the Emeralds without using any HintBalls!

Tilt the ship by pushing a lever up, down, left, and right. There&apos;s going to 
be Emeralds in the hach so you need to tilt the lever. There&apos;s an Emerald in 
one of the Spinners (flying enemies) so use your Maximum Heat Knuckles Attack 
to get rid of them. There are 4 places to dig so use your radar.

Mission A: Find the Emeralds within 2 minute!
Find the 3 Emeralds but don&apos;t get them. Restart and get them real quick to
beat the level.


//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Amy Rose----------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Twinkle Park-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 01*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and grab the balloon!
Don&apos;t get hit and attack Zero when he starts to follow you around outside the
park. The spikes can easily hurt you so get the barrier at the pool area.

Mission A: Grab the balloon within 2 min.!
Jumping is faster than running so I suggest jumping instead. Avoid getting hit
over and over.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Hot Shelter--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and grab the balloon!
Take your time and collect the containers. There&apos;s a lot of 5&apos;s and 10&apos;s in
ACT 2.

Mission A: Grab the balloon within 6 min. 30 sec.!
Ignore the enemies and quickly turn the handles. Jump through ACT 2 and 3.
Put in the blocks fast and hit Zero. 

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Final Egg---------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 03**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and grab the balloon!
There&apos;s 4 random containers behind the balloon if you don&apos;t have enough rings.

Mission A: Grab the balloon within 2 min. 30 sec.!
Jump through the level and open 2 doors at once when you get to the 5 way 
room.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Big the Cat---------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Twinkle Park-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 01*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Catch a 1000g. fish and Froggy!
Catch a fish with over a 1000 grams. Then catch Froggy. Take your time and
jump in the water to look for a big fish.

Mission A: Catch a 2000g. fish and Froggy!
Find a big fish, the size of Big and catch it. Probably a Mecha Fish. A giant
one should weigh around 2000 or more. Catch it and fish out Froggy afterwards.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-----------------------------------Ice Cap----------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Catch a 1000g. fish and Froggy!
Catch a fish with over a 1000 grams. Then catch Froggy. Take your time and
jump in the water to look for a big fish.

Mission A: Catch a 2000g. fish and Froggy!
Find the blue shark. When you get a hit, try scanning the body size with the
camera. If it taes at least half the screen, it might be near 2000 grams. If
it&apos;s about 2/3 of the screen, it&apos;s about 2200 or so.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Emerald Coast-------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 03**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Catch a 1000g. fish and Froggy!
Catch a fish with over a 1000 grams. Then catch Froggy. Take your time and
jump in the water to look for a big fish.

Mission A: Catch a 2000g. fish and Froggy!
Look for a big swordfish, a hammerhead, or the blue shark. They probably have
the most weight in this level.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Hot Shelter--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Catch a 1000g. fish and Froggy!
Catch a fish with over a 1000 grams. Then catch Froggy. Take your time and
jump in the water to look for a big fish.

Mission A: Catch a 2000g. fish and Froggy!
Catch the blue shark or the Hammer head. 

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;-------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Final Egg---------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 01**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy the &quot;Sonic Doll&quot;!
When you go up the hill, look back and you should find containers with 10&apos;s.

Mission A: Destory the &quot;Sonic Doll&quot; with more than 150 seconds remaining!
Lock-on the Tails and Knuckles doll to get time. 3 shots will destroy the
Sonic Doll.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Emerald Coast-------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 02**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and catch &quot;Froggy&quot;!
There&apos;s a lot of containers. Just lock-on the enemies from a range.

Mission A: Catch &quot;Froggy&quot; with more than 180 seconds remaining!
Thats 3 minutes. This level can be difficult so it may take several times.
Lock-on enemies so keep trying if you can&apos;t get the right time.

&quot;SONIC LABYRINTH&quot;
was added to the list

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Windy Valley-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 03*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy &quot;E-103&quot;!
Shoot enemies from a distance and shoot Delta over and over. Don&apos;t let him
attack you or hover away.

Mission A: Destroy &quot;E-103&quot; with more than 150 seconds remaining!
Lock-on the BoaBoa (The purple floating enemy) for 10 shots. That gives you
40 seconds. There&apos;s a couple of them so you&apos;ll have enough time to defeat
Delta if you manage to get 40 seconds each time.


//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Red Mountain-------------------------------/
/***********************************Stage 04*********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy &quot;E-104&quot;!
Lock-on enemies from a distance and keep shooting whatever you need to shoot.
Don&apos;t fall in the magma or you&apos;ll lose your barrier or rings.

Mission A: Destroy &quot;E-104&quot; with more than 180 seconds remaining!
Lock-on enemies and don&apos;t get hit. When you fight Epsilon, try hitting him 
over and over so he won&apos;t be able to attack. 

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/---------------------------------Hot Shelter--------------------------------/
/**********************************Stage 05**********************************/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

Mission B: Collect 50 rings and destroy &quot;E-105&quot;!
Destroy anything that can hurt you. Shoot enemies from a distance and ignore
the chameleons because they come out and suddenly dissapear. Get the magnetic
barrier and the invincibility before the fight with Zeta for protection.

Mission A: Destroy &quot;E-105&quot; with more than 120 seconds remaining!
There&apos;s a lot of Kiki&apos;s so lock-on to a bunch of them to get lots of time.
At the end, hit the magnetic barrier and the invincibility before the fight.
You can calmly attack Zeta before the invincibility runs out.

==============================================================================
4. c. Sub Game Emblems
==============================================================================

You should of gotten 1 Emblem for both the Sky Chase ACT&apos;s and Sand Hill.
Break the records for the score and time to get an Emblem. 

****************
Sky Chase ACT 1
****************

I think it was 8000 points. Locking on and shooting is very important. This
ACT can be difficult.

****************
Sky Chase ACT 2
****************

Get over 20000 points. Go through the level locking on and shooting. When you
get to the Egg Carrier, shoot the missle things coming at you. Get enough
points and beat the level afterwards.

**********
Sand Hill
**********

Beat it with over 10000 points. Not that difficult. Try going through the
level smoothly to get 5000 points on the time bonus.

****************
Twinkle Circuit
****************

Go through 3 laps to beat the level. You get an Emblem each time you beat it
so this shouldn&apos;t be hard.

****************
Hedgehog Hammer
****************

Break the record. Aim for the Yellow Sonic (500 points) Don&apos;t get hasty or
you might hit Eggman.

==============================================================================
4. b. Adventure Field Emblems
==============================================================================

SS (Station Square)

1. In the Burger restaurant. You can get it with any character.

2. The SS station. Go in and go up the stairs. Look behind and there should be
an Emblem. Get it with Sonic, Tails, or Knuckles.

3. The space above where the Ice Stone first appeared. The one near
Casinopolis. Get it with Tails.

4. Between the 4 trees near the City Hall. USe Knuckles to get it.

MR (Mystic Ruins)

1. Near Big&apos;s house. You can get it with anyone.

2. Behind Tails&apos;s workshop. Get it with Sonic, Tails, or Knuckles.

3. Inside a tree right next to Big&apos;s house. Get it with Knuckles.

4. In mid-air near Angel Island. Get it with Knuckles.

EC (Egg Carrier)

1. Above the pool. Get it with Knuckles.

2. Private room. Hit the switch to open the door. Hit the switch near you to
open the bed. Get it with Sonic.

3. On top of the antenna thing. Get this with Sonic. Charge a Light Speed
Dash and go in the rocket thing near the pool area. Not inside. Have the
rocket shoots you and use your Light Speed Dash to land on top. The Emblem
should be in the center of the antenna thing.

4. In a box in front of the rocket. Extend the wings on the Egg Carrier. Go
on the transporter and go on the monorail. Go to the center with the rockets.
Go in one and it&apos;ll shoot towards a box. Hit the right one to get the Emblem.

==============================================================================
5. Mini Games
==============================================================================

==============================================================================
5. a. Sky Chase ACT 1
==============================================================================

A shooting mini game. The Tornado has 2 main attacks, the machine gun and the
homing missles (lasers) The homing missles are more reliable so use them.
Target enemies from a distance before they come and don&apos;t get hit a lot. The
homing missle won&apos;t hit targets that you pass so be sure to hit all targets.

==============================================================================
5. b. Sky Chase ACT 2
==============================================================================

There&apos;s going to be a lot of missles shooting at you from those red cannons.
Use the machine gun and shoot enemies with the missles. The Tornado 2 should
be able to lock-on more targets so start locking on and shoot. Don&apos;t get hit
by the Egg Carrier or you&apos;ll suffer a lot of damage.

==============================================================================
5. c. Sand Hill
==============================================================================

Jump over dash panels or you&apos;ll get too much speed and jump if you start 
getting a lot of speed. You want a normal speed level. Try getting the 5000
points at the end. (Go through the level smoothly)

==============================================================================
5. d. Twinkle Circuit
==============================================================================

The record&apos;s 10 minutes so this should be a piece of cake.

==============================================================================
5. e. Hedgehog Hammer
==============================================================================

Blue Sonic +100
Yellow Sonic +500
Robotnik -200

Super Sonic (yellow) gives you 500 points so be sure to hit a lot of them.

==============================================================================
5. f. Slot Pinball
==============================================================================

Slot Pinball:

SpeedStar +50 Rings

T-Kickback +15 Rings

Shining &quot;K&quot; +30 Rings

BlueRose +50 Rings

Rink3K +15 Rings

FinalEggman -50 Rings

I don&apos;t know much about the Slot Pinball so some help would be great.

==============================================================================
5. g. Card Pinball
==============================================================================

Card Pinball:

One Pair +10 Rings

Two Pair +20 Rings

Three Card +30 Rings

Four Card +70 Rings

Full House +50 Rings

Straight +100 Rings

If you go to the Nightmaren table, you can get cards more easily. If you go
through the loop, you can get an ideya. If you collect them all, you get 300
rings!

The cards that are in play are:
Elliot - the blue haired
Claris - the pink haired
NiGHTS - The purple jester
Nightopian - The fairy looking
Blue Chip - The blue card
Wizeman - The 2 hands sticking out and a blue curtain
Gilwing - The shark. The cards mostly blue. It has some green.
Puffy - The fat purple one.
Jackle - It&apos;s red and it looks like a rabbit.
Reala - The red haired puppet looking.

============================================================================
6. Mission Mode
============================================================================

The objective is to find the &quot;mission object&quot; in the adventure field. Use 
the hint that is displayed and complete the mission. Touch the &quot;mission 
object&quot; to display a hint. Use the hint to figure out how to clear the
mission. There are a total of 60 missions with 6 characters (Sonic, Tails,
Knuckles, Amy, E-102, and Big.

///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/-------------------------Sonic the Hedgehog------------------------------/
///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 1: &quot;Bring the man who is standing in front of the hamburger shop!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: It&apos;s in front of the station. Just go a bit forward to find it.

Stage: N/A

Grab the guy in front of the hamburber shop and place him on the circle.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 2: &quot;Get the balloon in the skies of Mystic Ruins!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: The top of the stairs at the Mystic Ruins station

Stage: N/A

Go to the waterfall area. HA the spinners and grab the balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 3: &quot;Collect 100 rings, and go to Sonic&apos;s billboard by the pool!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Right next to the pool entry. (Between the hotel and Emerald Coast)

Stage: N/A

The casino area is the best place to get rings. Hit the switch and use the
Light Speed Dash on the trail of rings over and over until you get a 100
rings. Go to the billboard to complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 9: &quot;Get the balloon floating behind the waterfall at emerald sea.&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Behind the elevator to Twinkle Park

Stage: Emerald Coast

Go to Emerald Coast. When you reach ACT 2, there&apos;s a group of spinners you
need to HA. Get to the spring and hit the balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 11: &quot;Destroy the windmill and proceed. Find the balloon in orbit!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Under the waterfall. Where the water starts leaving the waterfall
area.

Stage: Windy Valley

HA the floating windmill to get to the balloon. It&apos;s at the beginning

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 13: &quot;I can&apos;t take a shower like this! Do something!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Under Casino Ken

Stage: Casinopolis

Go to the shower room and destroy all the spinners.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 15: &quot;My medallions got swept away by the tornado! Somebody help me
get them back!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Location: Below the Mystic Ruins station. Between the bridge and the station.

Stage: Windy Valley

Get the 5 medallions. They&apos;re not in hidden area&apos;s so you could get them
while going through the tornado.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 17: &quot;Aim and shoot all the medallions with a Sonic Ball&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Next to the gold egg. The gift shop antique whatever.

Stage: Casinopolis

Get the 5 medallions in the Slot Pinball.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 20: &quot;Get all the medallions within the time limit! It&apos;s really
slippery, so be careful!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: On the left side of the water. Before the entry to Ice Cap.

Stage: Ice Cap

When you get to ACT 2, hit the switch and start collecting the medallions
that are in between the icicles. You have to get 13 medallions in 1 minute.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 23: &quot;Go around the wooden horse and collect 10 balloons!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Next to the entrance/exit to Twinkle Park/Circuit.

Stage: Twinkle Park

Not that hard. Go to the marry-go-round and get the balloons

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 27: &quot;Collect 100 rings and head to the heliport!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: In the hamburger shop

Stage: Speed Highway

Get 100 rings or more and go to the heliport. Go on the blue circle to
complete this mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 28: &quot;During the morning trafic, use the fountain to get the
balloon.&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: On the left side of the hotel. It&apos;s on top of it so jump to get it.

Stage: Speed Highway

Use the fountain to hit a spring and get the balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 30: &quot;A fugitive have escaped from the jail of burning hell! Find
the fugitive!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Between the silver and gold pedestals

Stage: Red Mountain

Go through the level until you get to the fugitive area. Instead of taking
the shortcut, go through the level untill you see a large group of Spinners.
HA your way to the top platform to reach the fugitive. Hit him to complete
the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 33: &quot;Shoot yourself out of the cannon and get the balloon!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: In the pool room. Between the 2 stairs.

Stage: N/A

Go to the left cannon outside the pool room to get the balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 34: &quot;Can you get the balloon that is hidden on the ships bridge?&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: On the bridge near the rockets on the Egg Carrier.

Stage: N/A

Charge a Light Spin Dash and hit the spring. Use your L.S.D. to get the 
balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 36: &quot;Fighter aircraft are flying everywhere. Somebody get me out
of here!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Location: Above the entrance to Hot Shelter

Stage: Sky Deck

The guy from the hamburger shop is back. In the beginning of ACT 2, the guy&apos;s
just ahead the checkpoint so grab him and go to the circle. (Behind the next
checkpoint)

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 40: &quot;What is hidden in the area that the giant snake is staring
at?&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: In Tails&apos;s workshop

Stage: Lost World

When you get the gate open, charge a Light Speed Dash and go on the snake.
Wait for a trail of rings. Light Speed Dash through the rings and you&apos;ll
complete the mission by touching the balloon.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 41: &quot;Look real carefully just as you fall from the waterfall&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: The entrance to Lost World. On the stairs.

Stage: Lost World

Do you remember the waterfall? Go on that and stay on the right side till
you fall. You shoud&apos;ve hit the balloon and completed the mission. If not,
restart and try again.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 45: &quot;Go to a place where the rings are laid in the shape of
Sonic&apos;s face!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: The entrance to Sand Hill

Stage: Final Egg

Go all the way to ACT 3. Go through the level until you get to the room where
the ground is bumpy. If you reconize this room, this is where Gamma shoots
the Sonic Doll. Go to where the Sonic Doll is and hit the sporing on the side.
Hold the control stick up and land on the 2nd level. Touch the flag and 
complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 46: &quot;A secret base thats full of mechanical traps. Pay attention,
and you might see...&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Location: In the Ruins. It&apos;s where you get the lure upgrade with Big.

Stage: Final Egg

When you get to ACT 3, go to the next checkpoint. Fall down and go to the
wall across from you. Hit the balloon to complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 49: &quot;Scorch through the track, and get all the flags!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Across the switch where you got your Light shoes

Stage: Twinkle Park

Very difficult if you go too fast. Go through the circuit slowly and
collect the 31 flags.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 53: &quot;Pass the line of rings with 3 Super High Jumps on the ski
slope!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Where you got the Ancient Light

Stage: Ice Cap

The most difficult mission. You&apos;ll probably get bored of this game and I swear
this mission will make you go crazy. Go through the 3 ramps and go through
the line of rings. I started with about 95 lives and spent about 85 trying to
beat it. Good luck &apos;cuz you&apos;ll need it.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 55: &quot;Run down the building to get all the balloons!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Next to the elevator. Go on the elevator to Twinkle Park but take
the opposite route.

Stage: Speed Highway

In Speed Highway go to ACT 2 and get the 8 balloons. If you couldn&apos;t get
them, restart.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 57: &quot;Peak of the volcanic mountain! Watch out for the lava!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Behind a rock on Angel Island. On the opposite side of the stairs 
that leads to the Master Emerald.

Stage: Red Mountain

When you get to the 2nd rope machine, look behind you. You should see a
container and a spring. You want to get on the spring so HA the container,
then the spring. This spring won&apos;t guide you through so you have to control
where Sonic goes. Hit another spring and touch the balloon to complete the
mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 58: &quot;The big rock will start rolling after you! Try to get all
the flags!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Behind the ladder in the Ruins.

Stage: Lost World

When you get to the boulder part, start going down slowly and run back when
the boulder starts coming down. There are 36 flags so take your time
collecting them afterwards. 

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------Miles &quot;Tails&quot; Prower----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 4 &quot;Weeds are growing all over my place! I must get rid of them!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: In front of the station. (MR)

Stage: N/A

Go to Tails&apos;s workshop. You&apos;ll notice the green weeds. Use you tail (Hold B)
to cut the weeds. There&apos;s 48 outside the workshop and 3 in the water so don&apos;t
miss them.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 10 &quot;What is that sparkling in the water?&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Right in front of the right elevator. (Before the boss fight with
Chaos 2)

Stage: Go to the Chao Garden and go behind the fountain. Grab the medallion
to complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 16 &quot;Get the flags from the floating islands!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Near the East Cave. It&apos;s close to the yellow fence.

Stage: Windy Valley

There&apos;s 8 flags. There&apos;s one on each platform thats shaped like a circle.
There&apos;s 2 circles and one narrow path. On one of the circle, there&apos;s a flag.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 24 &quot;I hate this dark and filthy place! Can you find it?&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Where the Ice Stone was in the casino area.

Stage: Casinopolis

Stop when you see the 3 spike balls. On the left, fly up and you should see
a sign with Cream and Cheese. Hit it to complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 31 &quot;Get the balloon as you float in the air along with the trash!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: SS Central Station. Between the 2 staircases. 

Stage: Casinopolis

When you get to the 2nd fan area go all the way to the top. But the fan will
stop running so you have to land somewhere. Hit the balloon to complete the
mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 37 &quot;Fly over the jungle, and get all the balloons!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Go on the trolley to the jungle. The mission objective should be
behind you.

Stage: N/A

5 balloons pop out of nowhere. Touch them to complete the mission.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 47 &quot;Get 10 balloons on the field under the time limit!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: On top of Tails&apos;s workshop.

Stage: N/A

Hit the switch that suddenly appeared to make balloons pop out of nowhere
once again. You have 2:30:00 to touch 10 balloons

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 54 Slide downhill in a blizzard and get all the flags!E
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Location: Between the ladder to Ice Cap and the pool.

Stage: Ice Cap

Another difficult mission. On the same level too! At the end, you have to hit
the flags. There&apos;s 13 of them. Ignore the ramps this time.

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------Knuckles the Echidna----------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 5 &quot;I lost my balloon! It&apos;s a way up there now!&quot;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 12 gWho is Chao a good friend with? And what is hidden underneath
it?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 25 gWhat is hidden under the lionfs right hand?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 26 gWhat is that on top of the shipfs mast that the pirates are
protecting?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 32 gCan you get the balloon that is hidden under the bridge?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 38 gA message from an ancient people: In the direction where 
the burning arrow is point, you will see...h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 48 gCan you get the medallion that the giant Sonic is staring 
at?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 56 gRelentless eruptions occur in the flaming canyon. What 
could be hidden in the area shefs staring at?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 59 gWatch out for the barrels, and find the hidden flag inside 
the container!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/----------------------------------Amy Rose----------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 6 gHe is going to drown! Help the man in the water!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 18 gDuring the night, at the amusement park, place your jumps on 
top of one of the tables.h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 19 gWhat is that behind the mirror?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 43 gFortress of steel. High jump on 3 narrow paths. Be careful
not to fall.h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 50 gSelect a road that splits into 5 paths before time runs out!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------Big the Cat---------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 8 gThe medallion fell under there! No illegal parking please!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 14 gI am the keeper of this hotel! Catch me if you can!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 22 gFind the flag hidden in the secret passage under the 
emerald ocean!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 29 gI am the keeper of this canal! Catch me if you can!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 35 gI am the keeper of this icy lake! Catch me if you can!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 44 gI am the keeper of this ship! Catch me if you can!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 52 gGet 3 flags in the jungle under the time limit!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 60 gSomething is hidden inside the dinosaurfs mouth. Can you 
find it?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
/--------------------------------E-102 &quot;Gamma&quot;-------------------------------/
//////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 7 gLonely Metal Sonic needs a friend... Look carefully.h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 21 gProtect the Sonic doll from the Spinners surrounding it!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 39 gTreasure hunt at the beach! Find all the medallions under 
a time limit!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 42 gI canft get into the bathroom. How could Ifve let 
something like this happen to me?h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Mission 51 gGunman of the Windy Valley! Destroy all the Spinners 
under a time limit!h
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

============================================================================
7. Mini Game Collection/Game Gear
============================================================================

SONIC THE HEDGEHOG 20 Emblems

SONIC DRIFTRACING 40 Emblems

SONIC CHAOS 60 Emblems

SONIC SPINBALL 80 Emblems

SONIC LABYRINTH 100 Emblems

SONIC THE HEDGEHOG 2 110 Emblems

Dr. ROBOTNIK&apos;s MeanBeanMachine 120 Emblems

SONIC DRIFT 2 130 Emblems

Now you can play as Metal Sonic
in trial mode

SONIC THE HEDGEHOG TRIPLE TROUBLE 20 Missions






=============================================================================
8. Chao
=============================================================================

Chao&apos;s are cute mysterious creatures :) You can go to the computer thing in
the chao garden to learn more about chao&apos;s.

=============================================================================
8. a. Chao Garden Locations
=============================================================================

The locations to the Chao Garden are:

the left elevator in SS. (In the hotel)
The cart in the East Cave (MR)
The transporter in the Egg Carrier (EGGMAN is the answer to go in the room
with the transporter)

=============================================================================
8. b. Hatching a Chao
=============================================================================

Simply grab it with B or X and move the control stick. You can throw it to
a wall, or wait till it hatches by itself. Real simple.

=============================================================================
8. c. Raising a Chao
=============================================================================

Giving it fruits will increase stamina and keeps your chao happy. Giving
chao&apos;s animals and love will make your chao much more happier.

If you take away fruits, not feeding chao&apos;s, and abusing chao&apos;s, they will
hate you. You&apos;ll also decrease their life span I think so don&apos;t do anything
that might make your chao hate you or anything.

I might make a animal chart/list&lt;whatever you like to call it...but not
now.

=============================================================================
8. d. Entering Races
=============================================================================

Winning races in this game are much harder so if you transport stronger 
chao&apos;s from SA2B, the races should get a bit easier.

Pearl - A race that tests your chao&apos;s strength ability.
Amythyst - A race that tests your chao&apos;s flying ability.
Sapphire - A race that tests your chao&apos;s strength and running ability.
Ruby - A race that tests your chao&apos;s swimming ability.
Emerald - A race that tests your chao at it&apos;s best.

This game doesn&apos;t let you see any abilities. (S, A, B, C, D, E) So you have
to rely on luck if you don&apos;t have SA2B. If you do have a cable, GBA, and
SA2B, you can transport chao&apos;s to both games. The doctor (SA2B) will let you
see the chao&apos;s abilities. You can do the animal glitch but I&apos;m not sure if it
works in SA. This will speed up things a lot. Good luck =)

=============================================================================
8. e. SA2B Connection
=============================================================================

If you have a GBA (Gameboy Advance) and a link cable, you can transport
chao&apos;s from Sonic Adventure 2 Battle and Sonic Adventure DX. This can really
help if you are having trouble beating the races in SA.

=============================================================================
8. f. Black Market
=============================================================================

The black market sells goods for rings as a trade. The black market sells
eggs, fruits, hats, etc. Save rings and collect a lot more emblems to get
rare or more products.

I&apos;m not going to list every item.

=============================================================================
8. g. The legendary Light Chao (Chaos Chao)
=============================================================================

I don&apos;t know how to make a Chaos Chao in SA but I think it&apos;s the same with
SA2B. Reincarnate a chao twice, give all animals and wait for it to evolve.

I think you can make a Angel Chaos Chao or a Devil Chaos Chao too in DX.

The Light Chao (Neutral Chaos Chao) closly resembles Chaos 0.
The Angel and Devil are...I don&apos;t know. Google it or something :D

To people who play SA2B:
Don&apos;t give Chaos Drives to your chao. Only give the animals.

=============================================================================
9. Version History
=============================================================================

Version 0.2(04/29/08) - I added the copyright information at the beginning.
Version 0.19 (09/1/07)- Did some info on chao&apos;s. Mission mode is going to
 take a while.
Version 0.18(08/15/07)- Skipped 53 and started Tails&apos;s mission. Stuck on 52
 now. :(
Version 0.17(08/14/07)- Went through most of the missions with Sonic. Can&apos;t
 beat Mission 53. Fucken hard.
Version 0.16(08/13/07)- Finished Mini game section. Added some chao FAQ.
 Started Mission mode.
Version 0.15(08/12/07)- Finished the Emblem Checklist. 
Version 0.14(08/11/07)- Finished Gamma and Super Sonic&apos;s story mode. Started
 Emblem Checklist. On Sky Deck, game kinda broke
 down.
Version 0.13(08/10/07)- Finished Amy and Big&apos;s story mode. Started Gamma&apos;s.
 Added some things in the Mini Game, Chao, and
 Emblem Checklist.
Version 0.12 (08/9/07)- Finished Tails and Knuckles story mode.
Version 0.11 (08/8/07)- Finished Sonic&apos;s story mode. Going to start Tails&apos;s
 story mode tomorrow.
Version 0.1 (08/7/07)- Started the guide. Finished introduction, 
 characters, and almost Controls. Before Emerald 
 Coast on guide.

==============================================================================
10. Thanks/Credits
==============================================================================

Shinobu Toyoda - Original producer of Sonic the Hedgehog
Yuji Naka - Chief programmer

SEGA Team, Dave Halverson, myself for typing the guide...
I think thats it...

Written by: Steven Ryu (KeroroG)
E-mail: ryuk66@yahoo.com
E-mail: g66ryu@yahoo.com
	</body>
</document>
