<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007684" url="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=6479568" time="2012-07-13-00:39" support="2" score="0.0040688647498375915" bingtitle="Fast-Food Chains Push to Increase Speed : NPR" webtitle="Fast-Food Chains Push to Increase Speed : NPR">
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Also heard on NPR stations: ... HORSLEY: Jack in the Box&apos;s new credit card readers may also lead to bigger orders.</description>
	<body>
		NPR Shop | NPR Social Media | Login | Register 
 
 Find a Station 
 Search close   
 home news arts&amp;life music programs listen 
 
news

 Morning Edition All Things Considered Fresh Air The Diane Rehm Show On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation 

 Talk of the Nation Science Friday Tell Me More Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday Also heard on NPR stations: Marketplace APM 
 
arts&amp;life

 Ask Me Another Car Talk Radiolab Snap Judgment TED Radio Hour Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Also heard on NPR stations: This American Life PRI A Prairie Home Companion APM 
 
music

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino Favorite Sessions First Listen From The Top Live In Concert 

 Mountain Stage NPR Music Essentials Piano Jazz Song Travels The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
special series

 StoryCorps Planet Money Picture Show Krulwich Wonders... Cabinet of Wonders 
 PUBLIC RADIO PROGRAMS A-Z | close 
hear continuous streams
 
 24-Hour Program Stream 

NPR News and Shows
 View Schedule 
 Find Stations | Music Streams 
 
hear the latest news
 
 Hourly News Summary 
 [4 min 45 sec] 
Latest NPR Newscast
 Public Radio Programs A-Z | close 
 News &gt; Business 
 
 Twitter (0) Facebook (0) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
Fast-Food Chains Push to Increase Speed
 
by Scott Horsley 
 
November 13, 2006
 
 Listen 

 Morning Edition 
 
 Add to Playlist Download 
   text size A A A November 13, 2006 
Most customers at fast-food restaurants order from their vehicles. The faster the drive-through line moves, the more money the restaurant makes. So, fast-food chains are experimenting with new ways to speed up their service.
 
Copyright©2006 National Public Radio. For personal, noncommercial use only. See Terms of Use. For other uses, prior permission required.

STEVE INSKEEP, host:

Technology is making fast food come to you a little faster. Restaurant chains across the country are adopting high tech tools like no-touch credit card readers to speed up the drive-thru. NPR&apos;s Scott Horsley reports.

SCOTT HORSLEY: So it&apos;s lunchtime and you&apos;ve just placed your order for a cheeseburger and large curly fries, and as you inch towards the pickup window you dig through your pockets and maybe the ashtray, looking for enough coins and crumbled bills to cover your meal.

Unidentified Woman (Restaurant Employee): Hi. Three-fifty-three. You want some ketchup?

HORSLEY: Before long, customers at Jack in the Box won&apos;t have to fumble for cash. Spokesman Cason Lane says the San Diego-based chain is installing new credit card readers that allow customers to pay simply by holding a credit card embedded with a special radio chip nearby.

Mr. CASON LANE (Spokesman, Jack in the Box): Speed and convenience are two of the most critical factors in fast food. So we&apos;re always looking for ways to get food to customers faster and to just improve their overall experience.

HORSLEY: Jack in the Box is not alone. According to the trade journal QSR, more than 80 percent of fast food restaurants launched programs in the last year to improve their drive-thru speed. Industry consultant Dennis Lombardi of WD Partners says it&apos;s no wonder, since for every dollar in fast food sales, 50 to 80 cents comes through the drive-thru window.

Mr. DENNIS LOMBARDI (WD Partners): A lot of these restaurants have to make the bulk of their sales in about a 90-minute period around lunchtime. So if you can go from servicing 60 cars in an hour to 80 cars in an hour, that&apos;s 20 more transactions.

HORSLEY: Some restaurants are now routing drive-thru orders to remote call centers. Lombardi says remote operators are not only faster in many cases but often better at selling additional items to a customer than a harried restaurant worker who&apos;s also pouring drinks and making change.

Mr. LOMBARDI: It&apos;s easier to execute for the person who is only doing the order taking in a call center than it is for someone who&apos;s also got three other major things to do.

HORSLEY: Jack in the Box&apos;s new credit card readers may also lead to bigger orders. Tests show fast food customers tend to spend more when they&apos;re paying with plastic.

Scott Horsley, NPR News, San Diego.

Copyright©2006 National Public Radio. All rights reserved. No quotes from the materials contained herein may be used in any media without attribution to National Public Radio. This transcript is provided for personal, noncommercial use only, pursuant to our Terms of Use. Any other use requires NPR&apos;s prior permission. Visit our permissions page for further information.

NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPR&apos;s programming is the audio.
   
 Twitter (0) Facebook (0) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
 More Business 
 
Podcast + RSS Feeds
 
 Podcast RSS 

 Business 
Subscribe to Business podcast via:

 

Or use this URL:

 

 close 
     Morning Edition –   
   
 Planet Money 

 Waiting For JPMorgan And The Whale 

JPMorgan executives must face investors on Friday to offer more information on big trading losses.
 
 Business 

 Lobster Glut, Low Prices Leave Boats High And Dry 

Prices are plummeting, and the lobstermen are staying away from their traps to save extra expenses.
 
 Poverty In America: The Struggle To Get Ahead 

 Turning Trash Into Cash To Help Nation&apos;s Poor 

A nonprofit in Eugene, Ore., recycles mattresses to help fund services for low-income families.
     
Comments





 Discussions for this story are now closed. Please see the Community FAQ for more information.
   Recent First Oldest First Most Recommended 
 View all comments » 
 
NPR thanks our sponsors

 Become an NPR Sponsor 
 
most popular 
 
 Viewed Recommended Commented 

 Three Secrets To Crispy Pickles, And A &apos;Lost Recipe&apos; Found How Stereotypes Can Drive Women To Quit Science Studies Tie Human Bladder Infections To Antibiotics In Chicken A Nation Of Meat Eaters: See How It All Adds Up 
 
 @nprbusiness On Twitter 


 
Follow @nprbusiness on Twitter.
   Planet Money Headlines: Planet Money 
 Waiting For JPMorgan And The Whale How To Define Your Terms In 300 Pages Watch: Planet Money Live At The 92nd Street Y 

 more 
 
 NPR Double Take - Two Views On The Same News 

 The Mandate Upheld 
 


 other recent cartoons 
 
 Business Headlines 

From the Associated Press
 
 Yahoo Confirms Theft Of 450,000 Users&apos; Passwords Senator Questions Findings In Toyota Investigation Yahoo&apos;s Interim CEO Faces Off With Shareholders 

 View More Last updated: 
 5:56 pm
 ET 
 
From The Opinion Pages
 
 Weekly Standard: Obamacare Cost Estimates Rise 

 The Weekly Standard&apos;s Daniel Halper decries the costs of the Affordable Care Act.
 
 New Republic: Obamacare Means Higher Employment 

 The New Republic&apos;s Jonathan Gruber says the Affordable Care Act is a job-creator.
 
 The Weekly Standard: The Economy And The Courts 

 The Weekly Standard&apos;s Irwin M. Stelzer examines the judicial system&apos;s impact on the economy.
 
 podcast 
 
 Planet Money Podcast 

Meet high rollers, brainy economists and regular folks -- all trying to make sense of our rapidly changing global economy.

 Subscribe 
 
 podcast 
 
 NPR Business Story of the Day Podcast 

The top business story of the day from Morning Edition , All Things Considered and other award-winning NPR programs.

 Subscribe 
   
 npr always on 

 Newsletters Podcasts Mobile RSS Feeds Widgets API Radio 
 
 news 

 U.S. World Opinion Politics Business Technology Science Health Sports 
 
 arts&amp;life 

 Books Movies Pop Culture Food Performing Arts Games&amp;Humor 
 
 music 

 Music Articles Music Videos NPR Music Radio Browse Genres Browse Artists A-Z 

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino First Listen Live In Concert NPR Music Essentials Marian McPartland&apos;s Piano Jazz The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
 programs a-z 

 All Things Considered Ask Me Another Cabinet of Wonders Car Talk The Diane Rehm Show Fresh Air Morning Edition On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation TED Radio Hour Tell Me More Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday 
 
listen

 Hourly News NPR Program Stream Schedule Find Station Streams 
 
more

 Multimedia Columns Blogs Analysis Commentary NPR Ombudsman StateImpact 

 about 

 This Is NPR Support and Sponsor Press Room Careers NPR Shop Contact Us 
 
 Copyright NPR Terms of Use Privacy Policy Permissions Corrections Text-Only Site Help Contact Us Donate Our partner in public broadcasting
	</body>
</document>
