<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007632" url="http://www.deseretnews.com/article/700204532/Santa-finds-kids-giving-shorter-lists-in-recession.html" time="2012-07-13-00:36" support="2" score="0.0014339414559533376" bingtitle="Santa finds kids giving shorter lists in recession | Deseret News" webtitle="Santa finds kids giving shorter lists in recession | Deseret News">
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="39"/>
	<description>Obituaries; Classifieds; Cars; Jobs; Deals ... paper because his mother was taking napkins and paper towels from a fast food restaurant ... school this semester and can&apos;t get ...</description>
	<body>
		Salt Lake City: Scattered Clouds 102° 
 Home 
 

 About the new design Login/Register 
 Mobile Mobile Site Text Version Mobile Apps 
 
 Deseret News Archives: 1850-1987 Web: powered by Yahoo Powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 News Sports Business Opinion Faith Family Life Obituaries 
 Classifieds Cars Jobs Deals 
 
 
 Utah World&amp;Nation Politics More News 
 Education Salt Lake County Utah County Davis County Police/Courts Legislature Weather Immigration News Wire 
 

 Census Fire Watch 
 About this ad 
Santa finds kids giving shorter lists in recession
 
 Print Font [+] [-] Leave a comment» 
 

By Martha Waggoner

Associated Press

 
 Tweet 
 
Published: Tuesday, Dec. 6 2011 12:46 p.m. MST
 
 View 4 photos» 

In this Wednesday, Nov. 30, 2011 photo, Santa, Cliff Snider, talks with Adeline Adams, 3, about her Christmas list during a photo shoot at the &quot;Beach Shack&quot; in Emerald Isle, N.C. When Snider, who&apos;s been playing Santa since he was a teenager, gets a big-ticket request, he typically answers: &quot;There&apos;s an awful lot of children asking for that this year. What else do you want?&quot;

Tom Copeland, Associated Press
 Summary 
A job for their mom or dad. Money for the heating bill. Food or a place to live. Maybe gloves or boots.
 You might also like 
 
 Stories of Japanese internment camp recovered 

Jan. 18, 2012
 
 Santa trackers having record holiday 

Dec. 24, 2011
 
 Santa Claus passes new poll 

Dec. 23, 2011
 
 
 “ Connaghan recalled the night he and other Santas took some needy children shopping. One boy wanted to buy toilet paper because his mother was taking napkins and paper towels from a fast food restaurant for toilet paper.”
 
RALEIGH, N.C.—A job for their mom or dad. Money for the heating bill. Food or a place to live. Maybe gloves or boots.

More and more, Santas say the children on their laps are asking for less—and Santa is promising less as well.

With unemployment stubbornly high, more homes in foreclosure and the economic outlook dim, many children who visit Santa are all too aware of the struggle to make ends meet.

&quot;These children understand the conditions around the home when they ask for stuff. They understand when there are other children in the family, they need to be cautious or thoughtful of them as well and not ask for 10 to 12 items,&quot; said Richard Holden, a 69-year-old Santa from Gastonia, N.C.

Cliff Snider, who&apos;s been playing Santa since he was a teenager, agrees.

&quot;I think the parents are saying, &apos;It&apos;s an economic thing. Just list two to three things you really want to have,&apos;&quot; he said. &quot;Parents are trying to encourage the children to be thrifty.&quot;

And the 64-year-old Snider does his best to help out. When he gets a big-ticket request, he typically responds: &quot;There&apos;s an awful lot of children asking for that this year. What else do you want?&quot;

At the Charles W. Howard Santa Claus School, Santas learn lines like, &quot;Wow, that&apos;s a big gift. Is there anything else you might like?&quot;

These days, though, Santas are having to use it less and less.

&quot;I think it&apos;s becoming more popular not to have that long list,&quot; said Tom Valent, dean of the Howard Santa school in Midland, Mich., which gets more than 3,000 letters to Santa a year and just graduated its 75th class. &quot;Families are teaching their children to be as much of a giver as a receiver.&quot;

Starlight Fonseca has been teaching her five children, ages 5 to 14, &quot;that we&apos;re not the only ones who have to cut things back. We&apos;re not the only ones struggling.&quot;

The 31-year-old mother and her husband Jose had been relying on a stipend from the University of Texas law school that Fonseca lost when an illness made it impossible for her to keep her grades up. She&apos;d hoped to graduate in May but was unable to attend school this semester and can&apos;t get student loans due to poor credit.

Fonseca tells her kids that &quot;to make it fair for everyone, Santa has to cut back for everyone. ... We paint it in a way that Santa is doing the best he can to make everybody happy at Christmas.&quot;
 
 Page: 1 2 Next» 
 Comments Leave a comment» 
DeseretNews.com encourages a civil dialogue among its readers. We welcome your thoughtful comments.
— About comments 
 About this ad Recommended Stories 
 &apos;Taxmageddon&apos; 

Sen. Orrin Hatch, R-Utah, took to the Senate floor Thursday to blast the estate tax.
 
 Pluto boasts 5 moons 

Pluto may have been kicked out of the planet club, but it has gained yet another companion.
 
 Syria&apos;s Iraq ambassador 

The Syrian ambassador to Iraq has defected, the most senior diplomat to abandon President Bashar Assad.
 What You May Have Missed 
 A Lutheran bishop&apos;s perspective on Mormon baptism for the dead A few of the oldest, longest continuous things in the LDS Church Vai Sikahema: No one is immune from the dangers of drug addiction Jimmer writes about what he has learned from his mother 
 About this ad Most Popular Across Site In World&amp;Nation 
 Study: $15 trillion in welfare spending has... Boo birds for Mitt: Romney draws negative... List of most memorable TV moments Once a panacea, now a mixed bag, year-round... Slap to Obama: GOP House votes to kill health... Louis Freeh: Penn St. disregarded children&apos;s... Child abductions from homes&apos;exceptionally&apos;... 10 influential women in U.S. politics 
 
 16-year-old Juan Diego student, athlete dies A few of the oldest, longest continuous... LDS Church issues statement on Mormon... Blue roundup: Jabari Parker releases list of... Sierra Newbold&apos;s family thanks police, asks... BYU football: Ian Dulan feels faster, quicker... Jazz GM Kevin O&apos;Connor officially announces... DirecTV loses 26 channels, MTV and... 
 Get The Deseret News Everywhere 
Subscribe
 
Mobile
 
Facebook
 
Twitter
 
RSS
 
Email
 Most Commented Across Site In World&amp;Nation 
 Blood in the water? Democrats ganging... 105 Boo birds for Mitt: Romney draws... 54 Study: $15 trillion in welfare spending... 40 Tough ID laws could block thousands of... 30 Slap to Obama: GOP House votes to kill... 24 Obama to push extension of middle-class... 19 Democrats want Romney to explain... 18 Mitt Romney and President Obama do not... 18 
 
 Utah and BYU football: Utes, Cougars... 251 Brad Rock: BYU, Utah football teams... 128 Brad Rock: Rock On: Early BYU grid... 109 Blood in the water? Democrats ganging... 105 Brad Rock: Cougars can&apos;t expect... 69 Cougars happy with move to... 66 In our opinion: Requiring photo ID at... 55 Boo birds for Mitt: Romney draws... 54 
 About this ad About this ad 
 Home News Sports Business Opinion Faith Family Life Obituaries 
 News» 
 Utah news World&amp;Nation Politics Census Fire Watch Education Salt Lake County Utah County Davis County Police/Courts Legislature Weather Immigration News Wire 
 Sports» 
 Utah Jazz BYU Cougars Utah Utes Utah State Aggies High school sports Real Salt Lake Scores and Stats Rugby On TV NFL MLB Salt Lake Bees Grizzlies Utah Valley Wolverines Weber State Wildcats Southern Utah University Sports Wire 
 Business» 
 Tech&amp;Innovation Money&amp;Politics Entrepreneurship Leadership Career Family Finance Business Wire 
 Opinion» 
 Editorials Op-Eds Letters Political Cartoons 
 Faith» 
 Featured Faiths MormonTimes LDS Church News Mission Reunions Faith Wire 
 Family Life» 
 Food Parenting Health Arts&amp;Entertainment Family Media Calendar Travel TV Listings Family Life Wire 
 Special Sections» 
 BYU, Utah rivalry week Census City Creek Elections 2012 Fire Watch LDS General Conference Mormons in America NCAA tournament Olympics Outdoor Retailer Rugby Signing Day Sundance Film Festival Utah Blaze Utah Grizzlies 
 
 Print Subscription About us Contact us FAQ Feedback Jobs RSS E-Edition Privacy policy Legal notices Advertise with us 
 About this ad
	</body>
</document>
