<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007464" url="http://leisureblogs.chicagotribune.com/thestew/2010/03/top-ten-at-10-annoying-restaurant-design-flaws.html" time="2012-07-13-00:26" support="5" score="0.010109219434275538" bingtitle="The Stew: Top 10 at 10: Annoying restaurant design flaws" webtitle="The Stew: Top 10 at 10: Annoying restaurant design flaws">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>Did the designers not think that floors in a a restaurant would get wet sometimes? ... ASK if we want to hear the specials and immediately bring extra napkins.</description>
	<body>
		Jobs Cars Homes Apartments Deals Contact Us Advertise Home delivery Perks 
 
 «Are you a foodspotter yet? | Main | &apos;Ginger Bred&apos; cookin&apos; on stage» 

March 08, 2010
 
Top 10 at 10: Annoying restaurant design flaws
 Share | 
 Posted by Phil Vettel 

The food can be transcendent and the service clairvoyant, but bad restaurant design can ruin any dining experience. We&apos;re talking specifics, not&quot;too noisy&quot;or&quot;too cold.&quot;Here are the things that bug us. Feel free to add your own; if we get enough suggestions, maybe restaurants will start paying attention.


 Wobbly tables. Fix&apos;em. Every busboy should know the old matchbook-shim trick . Backless bar stools and benches. Because some people still wear low-rise pants. What, is the plumbers&apos;convention in town? Ginormous menus. If they can&apos;t be placed on the table without breaking something, we have a problem. Too-close banquette tables. It&apos;s like the couple next to me are part of my date. Cold, dark bathrooms. Why do we even have to mention this one? Hard, uncomfortable seats. I can&apos;t fully appreciate the food when my kiester&apos;s numb. Clingy, rough-grain banquette fabrics. I want to slide in, not fight my way in. Tables too close to the front door. Every time someone enters or leaves, I get a weather report. Put in an airlock or hang some heavy curtains, but spare us the blast of outdoor air. Toilet fixtures that look like modern art. How do I work this thing? Modern art that looks like a toilet fixture. I&apos;m two martinis away from a public-indecency charge 

 
Posted at 10:00:00 AMin Phil Vettel , Restaurants 
 
Comments
 
Signs on restroom doors that are ambiguous, rather than stating&quot;Men&apos;s&quot;or&quot;Ladies.&quot;

Please do not make me scrutinize a heavily stylized outline of a person or read a language other than English to determine which door I should choose.
 
Posted by: Dan | March 08, 2010 at 01:44 PM 
 
1. I&apos;ve been to one restaurant lately that had a couple of seating issues. The backs of the chairs were extremely narrow, so they were very uncomfortable and you couldn&apos;t sling a coat or jacket over them. On the other side of the table was a banquette with a top that curved so low at one end that it was, to all intents and purposes, backless.

2. Leave enough room between tables so that people sitting down don&apos;t have to move to let the people at the next table in or out, and so the waiter doesn&apos;t have to pass the plate down the table because he is physically unable to get to the other end.

3. If you have a raised dining area, please make sure that the step up is sufficiently wide and sufficiently obvious that people don&apos;t take their lives in their hands coming and going. If your host/hostess is constantly saying,&quot;please watch your step&quot;as they lead patrons to their table, you&apos;ve got a problem.

4. Label your bathrooms&quot;Men&quot;and&quot;Women&quot;. Avoid foreign languages and cute little animals. Thank you.

5. List the desserts on the main menu, rather than just having a separate dessert menu. Some people like to consider what&apos;s available for dessert in planning their meal.
 
Posted by: jlp | March 08, 2010 at 01:49 PM 
 
1. While at a restaurant, we need to read the menu but not watch a live sporting event. The lighting in some places is set by drunks.

2. While at a restaurant, we need to read the menu so don&apos;t make the typeset so small that I need a magnifying glass. (I have great eyesight, BTW.)

3. If you know what a martini is, you should know what a Manhattan is. Yeesh.
 
Posted by:
 Lefty Lefty | March 08, 2010 at 03:11 PM 
 
I hate wobbly tables and there is no excuse for them. Waiters and bussers should always be prepared to take care of these.

Excellent points about the menus being too big AND including dessert on the regular menu. I am one of those who think about dessert from the moment I sit down and prefer to include or exclude dessert early in the meal. I&apos;ll bet restaurants who have desserts on the regular menu sell more of them.
 
Posted by:
 Abbie | March 08, 2010 at 03:32 PM 
 
1. It seems to be common sense, but if you are going to serve huge portions, you will eventually get larger patrons. Move the tables apart, and don&apos;t expect your patrons to use the same wiggles to get into a booth that they use to get into skinny jeans.
2. There&apos;s a candle on the table, but you never light it. Come on, we&apos;re about to blow $50+ on dinner, you can burn 39 cents worth of wax.
3. If you run a sports bar with 15 TVs showing different games, and customers are cheering/jeering for their teams, don&apos;t expect your servers will be audible while they are trying to recite today&apos;s specials or the beers on tap. A computer-printed flysheet with a decently-sized typeface would be most appreciated.
 
Posted by:
 Mike | March 08, 2010 at 03:38 PM 
 
Do not use a small, dark brown font on light brown paper in a room dimly light with yellow lamps.

Put the tables far enough apart so I don&apos;t have to drag my butt across someone else&apos;s meal in order to get to my banquette seat.

If the menu is large enough to need to be tied down, please take it away quickly. There&apos;s not enough room on a table at Capital Grille to hold four menus while you&apos;re having drinks.

I second the comment on cold bathrooms. I&apos;m paying enough for dinner for you to heat the bathroom and maybe even have hot water.
 
Posted by:
 steven stern | March 08, 2010 at 03:50 PM 
 
Hey Phil,

Restaurants would still be offering matchbooks because smoking in them would still be legal, as it should be, had do-gooders like yourself not opined otherwise. The primary reason why folks like me avoid bars and restaurants.

I am white, male, legal, English-speaking with advanced education. Establishments and their staff need me more than I need them.
 
Posted by:
 Jefferson | March 08, 2010 at 03:55 PM 
 
Jefferson- I don&apos;t think anybody needs you. Just stay home in your smoky den, order a pizza and rant along with Hannity. We will all be happier.
 
Posted by:
 Carl | March 08, 2010 at 04:49 PM 
 
Hi Phil,

Are you serious - what sort of solopsistic society are you participating in?

Yours,
K
 
Posted by:
 K. Kerouac | March 08, 2010 at 05:02 PM 
 
Enough light to be able to read the menu should be a no-brainer, yes?
 
Posted by:
 Ms. Anne | March 08, 2010 at 05:18 PM 
 
Jefferson - I agree with your comment. Pretty stupid of the author of the column to suggest the matchbook trick when you can&apos;t smoke in the restaurant any more.

My biggest issue with restaurant design: why do they put floors in that get slippery when they are wet? Smooth tile may look nice but it&apos;s a safety hazard. Was once at a restaurant and someone spilled tea on the tile floor; two servers fell in a matter of minutes before they could get it cleaned up. Did the designers not think that floors in a a restaurant would get wet sometimes?
 
Posted by:
 Kevin Raz | March 08, 2010 at 05:27 PM 
 
Jefferson- I don&apos;t think anybody needs you. Just stay home in your smoky den, order a pizza and rant along with Hannity. We will all be happier.

Posted by: Carl | March 08, 2010 at 04:49 PM

Carly-

Don&apos;t pay attention to Hannity. Never have. Funny, it is pricks like you who classify anything you don&apos;t agree with or can&apos;t comprehend as a rant. Shows a real lack of intelligence and maturity.
 
Posted by:
 Jefferson | March 08, 2010 at 05:30 PM 
 
&quot;If you know what a martini is, you should know what a Manhattan is. Yeesh.&quot;

Speaking of martinis.....A martini is gin and dry vermouth, a vodka martini is vodka and dry vermouth.&apos;Chocolate&apos;martini?? Apple-tini?? Jeez...maybe you could call it a&apos;cocktail&apos;or&apos;dessert in a glass&apos;? Just because you serve it in a martini glass doesn&apos;t make it a martini....if you served it in a pilsner glass, would you call it a beer?
 
Posted by: mikey | March 08, 2010 at 07:19 PM 
 
Could not agree more about the cold bathroom. Why do so few Chicago restaurants feel the need to heat this room?
 
Posted by:
 JA | March 08, 2010 at 08:35 PM 
 
How could everyone have missed the most obvious problem of all (especially in trendy new restaurants)? Too often the interior consists of all hard surfaces with nothing to absorb the noise. It gets deafeningly loud every evening at dinner simply because there is nothing to absorb the shouting of everyone all at once. Put up some drapes or ceiling tiles!
 
Posted by:
 Pete | March 08, 2010 at 09:44 PM 
 
1. No hot water in bathroom! The staff washes their hands in there as well, at least in theory. They are the ones handling and cooking the food. No hot water, and often, no soap, means a serious lack of hygiene.

2. Air conditioning set so cold in the summer that you need a coat or sweater to survive. My wife&apos;s major problem. If the restaurant is too cold, we walk out.

3. Please, make available half-size portions. Sometimes, people might not be so hungry, or might want to have a dessert without having to also take a container home with them.

4. Put the dessert menu on the main menu. Please!

5. If you have windows, make sure you have something to cover them when the sun is exceptionally bright. I hate going blind while trying to eat.
 
Posted by:
 Timerover | March 08, 2010 at 11:10 PM 
 
My #1 complaint is having to ask for a refill on water. If you see me eating ice as a means of staying hydrated, refill the stupid glass...please!

My #2 complaint is when I have to ask the price of something. A menu should include the price of ALL items!
 
Posted by:
 Haley | March 08, 2010 at 11:32 PM 
 
Jefferson-

It&apos;s self-abosrbed pricks like you that restaurants don&apos;t need. You think because you&apos;re educated, I should have to suffer through a smoke-tainted meal? If someone sits down next to you with noxious body odor, you would be offended, yes? Maybe move tables or get your food wrapped up in a tin foil swan? Overlooking state laws, a restaurant has every right to do what&apos;s best for its patrons and its staff. I can promise you that you and your reeking friends are in the minority. Every adjective you listed is overshadowed by your distrubing sense of entitlement. #*$&amp;^%#
 
Posted by:
 cheryl | March 08, 2010 at 11:55 PM 
 
If it takes you 4 tries and 20 minutes to bring me what I ordered (which was not a&quot;special&quot;order) and everyone else at my table is practically done with their entrees when mine finally arrives and mine is still not right but I don&apos;t complain because it&apos;s obviously pointless and I barely eat the charcoal brick you&apos;ve set in front of me, then you not only owe me an apology but you should offer to comp my meal or part of it.

And when I complain to the owner, an apology never includes&quot;we were short staffed.&quot;
 
Posted by:
 Sarah | March 09, 2010 at 12:38 AM 
 
How about serving water in bigger glasses? It saves the wait staff from constantly having to refill and keeps customers happy.
Also, for daily specials, put them on a simple printed sheet (1 per table is adequate) or on a board visible to all. Include pricing as well please.
A list of salad dressings available would also help. I&apos;m sure the wait staff get tired of saying&quot;ranch, italian, blue cheese, french...&quot;

 
Posted by:
 ChrisWG | March 09, 2010 at 06:24 AM 
 
A couple comments;
1. Put beer prices on the menu along with beers. That goes for soda, water as well.
2. No high top tables and definitely no high top chairs. I&apos;m short and those are hard to get into, sit on and get out of.
3. Larger waiting areas in front of the house
4. Take reservations, call ahead seating is so lame.
 
Posted by:
 Dining in Ohio | March 09, 2010 at 07:22 AM 
 
I don&apos;t know about the other women reading, but I hate when I go to a restaurant and have to hold my purse in my lap the whole time. How about some built in hooks next to the table or something to make it a little more convenient? Setting it on the floor is just gross and on the table is even worse! And if you hang it on the back of your chair, it gets bumped off every 5 minutes because your tables are too close together. Just saying...
 
Posted by:
 JR | March 09, 2010 at 08:17 AM 
 
How about adding closed captioning to the televisions if they are going to show sports or news. What good is a TV when you cannot tell what they are saying. We would be better off if it were turned off.
 
Posted by:
 RRumaner | March 09, 2010 at 08:17 AM 
 
Here&apos;s a thought - How about all fat people, smokers, those without college degrees, people accompanied by children, sports fans looking to eat and watch a game at the same time, people who need to use the restroom before,during, or after their meal, women with purses, and anyone else we can think of just not go out to dinner any more - then these issues will not be problems - oh and our restaurant industry will fade away. Our society is comprised of a bunch of whiny ass spoiled brats. Go live in Haiti or Chile right now and maybe these issues won&apos;t be so important to you. Perspective now people - sheesssh....
 
Posted by:
 M. Dannen | March 09, 2010 at 08:35 AM 
 
restaurants having the a/c on so high in the summer it feels like winter
 
Posted by:
 lamonth | March 09, 2010 at 08:41 AM 
 
I just have to reinforce some of the other comments:

1. The washroom is wear I must at least partially de-cloth in order to use this space, PLEASE don&apos;t freeze my *$&amp;(#&amp;$( off while I&apos;m there.

2. Half orders would be greatly appreciated. Frequently a full order is too much and the left overs don&apos;t keep well so it is a huge waste of food.

3. Went out with our infant son and friends and their 5 small children for lunch. Server insisted on telling us the specials. We couldn&apos;t hear him over the kids and the rest of patrons and no one was interested anyway. If you have a table with lots of kids ASK if we want to hear the specials and immediately bring extra napkins.

4. Dressings and dessert on the menu please. If you must put dessert on a separate menu bring it out with the regular menu at the start of the meal.
 
Posted by:
 TAKH | March 09, 2010 at 08:44 AM 
 
Sorry typo should be ...where I must.
 
Posted by:
 TAKH | March 09, 2010 at 08:45 AM 
 
Noisy spaces are my biggest complaint. I want to talk to my companions. Add some carpet, drapery or wall panels so we can talk. I seriously do not gop back to places that are too loud.
 
Posted by:
 Bubba | March 09, 2010 at 08:53 AM 
 
Speaking of Martinis and general Bar Etiquette...You should know what you are ordering. A martini is made with vodka or gin and dry vermouth either on the rocks (on ice) or straight up (in a cocktail glass with no ice). If you want either plain vodka or gin you should merely order the brand name either on the rocks (Grey Goose - on the Rocks) or straight up (Beefeaters - Straight Up).

ALSO, if you are ordering a specialty (flavored) martini, know what is in it before you order it, find that you do not like it, and then send it back. Many of the specialty martinis, i.e. apple-tinis, choco- tinis, etc. have varying recipes. The bartender or waiter would be happy to tell you how the drink is made locally.
 
Posted by:
 Alex | March 09, 2010 at 08:58 AM 
 
So, let me clarify for the writer what&quot;too noisy&quot;and&quot;too cold&quot;mean because, after all, he asked for specifics.

&quot;Too noisy&quot;means I can&apos;t hear my dinner partner speak in a normal tone of voice, much less hear the waiter. The trend toward those industrial ceilings with pipes and girders makes it almost impossible to control the noise level, even if the restaurant is not full. I don&apos;t want to feel like I&apos;m eating in a warehouse or factory.

&quot;Too cold&quot;means that I and my dinner partners have goosebumps, are shivering and fight to see who gets to hold their hands over the votive candle to try and keep warm. People wearing their coats while they eat should clue the restaurant manager on to the fact that it&apos;s&quot;too cold&quot;.
 
Posted by:
 Nancy | March 09, 2010 at 09:09 AM 
 
More pet peeves: 1. Restaurants that change their menu frequently, just for the sake of change. I don&apos;t mean one or two items; I will return to a restaurant because I liked something I ordered last time, not because I want to see&apos;what&apos;s new&apos;.

2. I absolutely agree with a the comments about restrooms lacking heat and hot water. You are spending a small fortune keeping your dining area at 60 degrees... are you afraid your patrons will overcrowd the restrooms trying to warm up?

3. @ Cheryl: your type of shrill,&quot;I know what&apos;s best for everyone else&quot;mentality allows no room for compromise, like allowing restaurants, taverns (and tobacco shops!) to have a separate, air-scrubber equipped room for those who choose to smoke, and those business owners who choose to bear the expense of adding the equipment. BTW, I don&apos;t smoke, I just don&apos;t believe those who do are somehow less than human.
 
Posted by:
 Mike | March 09, 2010 at 09:29 AM 
 
&quot;Wobbly tables. Fix&apos;em. Every busboy should the old matchbook-shim trick.&quot;

Should ____ what???!

This is just one of many typos I&apos;ve found in the Trib in the past 30 days. Perhaps this is why we anticipate the death of the Chgo local paper. The other paper has just as many problems. Perhaps the wrong staff were cut?
 
Posted by:
 db | March 09, 2010 at 09:32 AM 
 
Ok, Jefferson was a bit rude. That&apos;s no excuse for being far more rude in response.

As a non-smoking former restaurant owner, I have to agree with him about smoking sections in restaurants. I never had any trouble finding staff who also smoked and were more than happy to work that section. The ban was never about saving smokers from themselves; it was purely selfish on the part of the extremely vocal minority of non-smokers that pushed for it. Smokers were generally better customers, too.
 
Posted by:
 DG | March 09, 2010 at 09:37 AM 
 
How about cloth napkins that actually absorb liquid, and don&apos;t reject it because they are treated with stain repellent?
 
Posted by:
 Kitty | March 09, 2010 at 12:06 PM 
 
No poop in your food
 
Posted by:
 Jed | March 09, 2010 at 01:02 PM 
 
Sorry Bubba, a&quot;Martini&quot;is made with Gin and Dry Vermouth, A&quot;Vodka Martini&quot;is made with vodka and Dry Vermouth. Just because a lot of bartenders don&apos;t know what they&apos;re doing, doesn&apos;t make it right. If you go to a better restauant and order a&quot;Martini&quot;it will be made with Gin and Dry Vermouth, unless Vodka was specified.
My complaint with restaurants in general..1-tables to close, 2- banquette bench seating sucks, 3- undisciplined kids. actually, undisciplined kids should be first on my list.
 
Posted by:
 Jim O | March 09, 2010 at 01:11 PM 
 
@db Does it make you feel smarter to point out typos? Kudos on your ability to see
 
Posted by:
 Michelle | March 09, 2010 at 01:42 PM 
 
I hate it when too many tables are squeezed in and you have no privacy. If you can hear the conversations of the people on both sides of you...they can hear yours! It makes you want to shut up, which is not enjoyable.
 
Posted by:
 Linda | March 09, 2010 at 01:56 PM 
 
Too close tables! I hate it that the tables are at the same height of the bottom of my butt cheeks and when I scoot in, I am afraid of knocking over the neighboring tables wine glasses with my bum! Moving the table out so a patron can get in makes even the thinnest person feel fat - not a good feeling right before a meal. Also, if I wanted to dine with another couple, I would have gone on a double date.
 
Posted by:
 Kennen | March 09, 2010 at 02:18 PM 
 
Waiters that bring back a bunch of singles instead of a 5, 10 or 20-dollar bill so as to ensure a tip. if I need change for a tip, I&quot;LL ASK FOR IT.
 
Posted by:
 lil-doubtful | March 09, 2010 at 02:24 PM 
 
I&apos;m really enjoying all the comments. Keep&apos;em coming, please. Many of you are making points that I hadn&apos;t considered, which is what I expected.

A few comments need addressing:

Jefferson: Actually, a few restaurants (Sunda, one sixtyblue) continue to offer logo matchbooks to their customers. For which I am grateful, as I collect them. Matchbooks, not customers.

And I&apos;m sure we&apos;re all gratified to know of your whiteness/maleness/legality/English fluency/advanced education, but that really doesn&apos;t support the notion that dining estalishments need you more than you need them. Dining establishments need EVERYBODY, and it has been my observation that money spends the same no matter who is holding it.

K. Kerouac: Isn&apos;t&quot;solipsistic society&quot;a contradiction in terms?

db--the typo (actually, omitted word) was my doing. Thanks for pointing that out; I&apos;ll repair the damage.

 
Posted by:
 Phil Vettel | March 09, 2010 at 02:32 PM 
 
I personally am irritated when I see tables set up everywhere they can possibly be. A table does not need to be in the hallway to the restrooms, nor does it need to be 15 feet away from the back door of the restaurant, prompting a breeze every time someone from the back goes out for a smoke. I ate nearly an entire meal with my wool coat on at a restaurant recently. The food is that particular place&apos;s saving grace...but it is hindered by the cold air cooling it off every few minutes.
 
Posted by:
 Grace | March 09, 2010 at 03:13 PM 
 
Hard, backless, or otherwise uncomfortable chairs put me in a less than charitable mood. I recall an interview with Louis Szathmary back in the 1970&apos;s when The Bakery was one of the hottest restos in Chicago. He said that he bought deliberately uncomfortable chairs so he could turn tables faster. That was the last time I went to The Bakery. And I don&apos;t return to other places who currently do that.

Another pet peeve: White cloth napkins that leave fuzz all over your clothes, so you walk out looking like a cotton ball and have to send your pants/skirt to the cleaners prematurely. Come on guys, black is the new black. Hurray to those few restos that offer you a choice of black or white.
 
Posted by:
 MaryAnne | March 09, 2010 at 04:17 PM 
 
Yes yes yes. Although I would qualify my agreeance by stipulating that these ideas are really only pertinent when you choose a venue based on it&apos;s supposed civilized qualities, in expectation of a fine dining experience. You can&apos;t expect the taco shack and Mickey D&apos;s to play along...

Tables too close to the door: if I wanted to eat on the sidewalk, I would. Don&apos;t give me attitude if I politely ask if you might have an alternative to the front-n-center you just tried to seat me at.

Doublesided banquettes: I recently sat through an entire meal being shaken to the point of spilling water, because the guy behind me couldn&apos;t sit STILL!

Bathroom stalls so small you have to smear yourself against every surface just to get in and out of them: nasty. Unforgivable even in a dive!
 
Posted by:
 alicia | March 09, 2010 at 04:23 PM 
 
Jefferson: Actually, a few restaurants (Sunda, one sixtyblue) continue to offer logo matchbooks to their customers. For which I am grateful, as I collect them. Matchbooks, not customers.

And I&apos;m sure we&apos;re all gratified to know of your whiteness/maleness/legality/English fluency/advanced education, but that really doesn&apos;t support the notion that dining estalishments need you more than you need them. Dining establishments need EVERYBODY, and it has been my observation that money spends the same no matter who is holding it.

Felipe:

Thanks for the note. I glad to hear that matchbooks are still being offered. I, too, collect them.

Regarding my other comments, they appeared to have been posted.

In short, if restaurant owners/workers find the that hospitality is too difficult - providing smoking, or not providing smoking, having hot water in the men&apos;s room (and yes, there are quite a few places that don&apos;t) they need to find other work, I get tired of people and their excuses. Thus, if you don&apos;t like what you are doing get another job. And if that does not work, go back to school!

Thanks, Phil.
 
Posted by:
 Jefferson | March 09, 2010 at 05:31 PM 
 
I meant to say that after several attempts, they did not appear to be posted. Hey, I gotta train to catch!
 
Posted by:
 Jefferson | March 09, 2010 at 05:32 PM 
 
if you carry many different beers, unless you have trained your servers to be Beer Sommeliers who will match the beer to the food there is no excuse for not providing me with a written list up front. I like to try new beers and am probably over 200 at this point. Asking me&apos;what do you like&apos;is not productive. Give me the list and I will make my selection.

Like other commenters, I could do without 12 page menus. Choice is good, but there can be too much of a good thing. Besides, how many kitchens can produce 35 different entrees, 12 appetizers, and 8 deserts with equal quality? Pare the menu down and offer some good rotating specials. Your patrons, waitstaff, and cooks will thank you.
 
Posted by:
 Bankerdanny | March 09, 2010 at 07:46 PM 
 
Don&apos;t seat me next to an occupied table while the rest of the room is empty.
 
Posted by:
 mikep | March 09, 2010 at 08:02 PM 
 
Pepper in shaker with a&quot;salt&quot;lid and filled so full that it won&apos;t come out. Humidity encrusted salt shakers that nothing comes out of.......
 
Posted by:
 Jim | March 09, 2010 at 10:07 PM 
 
Coat room, coat rack, or coat hooks.

I came to sit among friends, not my coat.
 
Posted by:
 SharonD | March 09, 2010 at 11:52 PM 
 » 
Verify your Comment

Previewing your Comment
 
Posted by:  |  
 
This is only a preview. Your comment has not yet been posted.
 Your comment could not be posted. Error type: Your comment has been posted. Post another comment 
The letters and numbers you entered did not match the image. Please try again.

As a final step before posting your comment, enter the letters and numbers you see in the image below. This prevents automated programs from posting comments.

 Having trouble reading this image? View an alternate. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
Post a comment
 
()
 
Your Information

(Name is required. Email address will not be displayed with the comment.)

 Name is required to post a comment 

 Please enter a valid email address 

 Invalid URL 
 Name:
 
Email address:
 
URL:
 

Comment:
 
 The Stew RSS 

About this blog
The Stew: It bubbles, it simmers and you never know what you’ll find in each serving. It’s an authoritative go-to source for news about food, beverages and dining out in the Chicago area by the food and dining staffs of the Chicago Tribune.
Resources
  Illinois Restaurant Association 
  Inspections, City of Chicago Department of Health 
  Inspections, City of Chicago, Dumpster Task Force 
  University of Illinois Cooperative Extension Service 
  USDA Meat&amp;Poultry Hotline 

	</body>
</document>
