<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007409" url="http://www.sulit.com.ph/index.php/view+classifieds/id/1730986/HOUSE+%26+LOT+WITH+2+DOOR+APARTMENT+-+MALINTA+EXIT+ALONG+NLEX+" time="2012-07-13-00:22" support="3" score="0.015061203600537948" bingtitle="House &amp; Lot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along Nlex ..." webtitle="HouseLot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along Nlex Philippines - 1730986">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>House &amp; Lot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along ... CONDO IN QUEZON CITY NEAR GREENHILLS ONE CASTILLA PLACE ... Cars and Automotives; Jobs; Establishments and Business ...</description>
	<body>
		Sulit.com.ph SulitCars Sulit Real Estate 
 
 Ad History ▼ 
 (0) Saved Ads (0) Recently Viewed Ads Access more features with a Sulit Account ! It&apos;s FREE to sign up ! 
 

 Free Sign Up Sign In 
 
 House&amp;Lot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along Nlex Real Estate Philippines 
 Online Users: 21507 Search options Popular Searches : city , Condo for rent , rio , Apartment , Condominium 
 Categories ▼ 
 Apartment and Condominium Beach and Resort Commercial and Industrial Properties House and Lot, Townhouses and Subdivisions Land and Farm Memorial Lot Rooms and Bed Real Estate Services 
 Forum Help Post A Free Ad 
 Sulit Real Estate: 
 Sulit Real Estate Real Estate House and Lot, Townhouses and Subdivisions 
 Javascript is required by this system. Please enable javascript in your browser. 
House&amp;Lot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along Nlex
 
The advertisement posted in this page is already inactive and it is possible that the details here are already invalid. Content posted in this page is only provided for reference and does not constitute fact. Please be guided accordingly.

 View Inactive Advertisement 
 
House&amp;Lot With 2 Door Apartment - Malinta Exit Along Nlex
 194 views | 0 comment This advertisement is already inactive 
 Bedrooms Bathrooms Floor Area 1 1 70 m 2 

 Ad ID 1730986 Address Phase 1, Home Centrum Subd, Mapulang Lupa, Valenzuela City Date Posted October 28, 2009 Category House and Lot, Townhouses and Subdivisions Classification For Sale Short URL   More Details... 
 View 5 images Message to be posted (Required) What do you think about this ad posted on Sulit.com.ph? Starting a discussion on your Facebook Timeline... 
 

 Read this: Buying Tips 
 jaiwillem 
 Pauline Ann E. Covita 

 
 Registered: Oct 28, 2009 Last Sign In: Oct 28, 2009 Last Access From: Philippines 
 
 Feedback Score: 
 No feedback yet 
 
 Contact Details 
 4433610 09228566196 
 
Images
 
 Click image thumbnail to view actual image size.
	</body>
</document>
