<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007562" url="http://en.allexperts.com/q/Dealing-Bosses-Coworkers-1091/Don-t-know-boss.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:32" support="1" score="0.009954455118364494" bingtitle="Dealing with Bosses and Coworkers: Don&apos;t know what to do about my ..." webtitle="Dealing with Bosses and Coworkers: Dont know what to do about my boss?, fast food restaurant, mgrs">
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>fast food restaurant, mgrs, management teams: Shannon, It ... I am now the only person running this store with ... but what are you going to do when I have to leave ...</description>
	<body>
		You are here:

 Home Business Management Dealing with Bosses and Coworkers Don&apos;t know what to do about my boss? 
 
 Dealing with Bosses and Coworkers / Don&apos;t know what to do about my boss? 
 
Advertisement
 
 Expert: Doug Staneart - 6/11/2007

 Question 
I have been working as a manager of a fast food restaurant for ten years. I worked my way up from a crew member. Well for some background information a new supervisor came into the mix about a year ago. I was an assistant g.m at the time and this guy for whatever reason had it in for my boss at the time from day one. He was trying to implement things that would make us as the managers of this particular store look very bad. So obviously we had issues with doing them. Apparently he had a problem with us voicing our opinion. To make a long story short, we didn&apos;t want to have him as a supervisor so we were both transferred to different stores under another supervisor.
Now we fast forward to this year. My former boss left in December and I became a g.m. At the same time I found out I was pregnant. Last month this same supervisor took over and is now my supervisor once again. Since then he has been constantly trying to make moves I feel so that he doesn&apos;t have to deal with me. The day after he took over he wanted to send me to a store that everyone knows I do not want to be at. He is big on sending in management teams so if I went then all of my mgmt team was to go with me. They objected to being moved to the other side of town so that fell through. Since that time he has been implementing other things that add on significantly more time to try to fix problems when he knows perfectly well why those problems are there. Well just yesterday I get a call asking about one of my mgrs. and whether or not they want to be a g.m. The person said yes and from there things moved quite rapidly. All of a sudden he&apos;s calling me and saying that half of my crew has to go to the other store with this mgr for good. I tell him they are not going to want to go so instead he decides to take both of my managers and whoever will go with them. I am now the only person running this store with like one other mgr that he got from some other store. He knows that I am now six months pregnant and I don&apos;t understand why he made this move. Usually he moves whole mgmt teams or just one mgr. I feel like he is trying to force me to quit or ask to step down and I don&apos;t know what to do. I feel like anything I do now will cause me to get in trouble. They&apos;ve implemented a gm schedule that I cannot possibly follow because I have doctor&apos;s appointments for my baby that I&apos;ve been going to for months. It&apos;s already tough enough that I have to be on my feet all day among other duties and I just feel like he&apos;s making things more difficult for me. Any advice would be helpful.

 Answer 
Shannon,

It sounds like the major problem here is that the two of you are letting the challenge from early on fester into a problem that causes each of you not to talk to the other. Each of you are &quot;keeping your distance&quot; from each other, and it will continue to cause communication challenges.

In addition, both of you have tunnel vision where you are only looking at your own problems and not at each others. As a result, you think of of you is screwing the other.

This new GM (or regional... I&apos;m a little confused about the titles your company uses -- but the person in conflict with you,) is in a new position where he has to make a statement in order to justify his promotion. He has to make the stores run more efficiently, and he is experimenting hoping something will work. If you help him do that, he will like you will probably help you more.

He hasn&apos;t realized that the changes he is making is causing problems for you. Most new managers/leaders don&apos;t take into account how their changes will affect people.

Go to this person and say the following:

* I understand that you are under pressure to make changes. Is there anything I can do to help?

* I know you need my team to help in the other store. That makes sense for that store. I know you probably have a plan for this next part as well, but what are you going to do when I have to leave for a few weeks to have my baby?

* Of course, the pregnancy is a temporary obstacle to scheduling (laugh,) but I can use your help to make sure I can get to doctors appointments, etc. It hasn&apos;t been a problem so far, but since I don&apos;t have my full crew anymore, it will be a problem soon. Any ideas?

Start working as a team again. Show respect for the position even if you don&apos;t respect him.

Doug Staneart
 
 Questioner&apos;s Rating 

 Rating(1-10) Knowledgeability = 10 Clarity of Response = 10 Politeness = 10 Comment Thank you for your time. 


 Add to this Answer Ask a Question 
 
Related Articles

 Shopping Lessons - Depression New Manager Mistakes How To Lose a Remote Work Arrangement - A Look at the Lighter Side of Life Women Talk About Menstrual Cycle Problems Tiger Woods Masters Press Conference - Page 8 
 
 Dealing with Bosses and Coworkers 


 All Answers 
 
Answers by Expert:

 Joan Schramm Doug Staneart Dr Bruce Hoag, CPsychol Lora Banks Lee Fjelstad Shannon M. Reising Mary Coussons-Read, PhD 
 
 Ask Experts 

 Volunteer 
 
 Doug Staneart 

Expertise

Doug Staneart can answer questions about gaining cooperation from, motivating, and influencing coworkers and employers. He is also an expert on how to avoid and resolve conflicts as well as other issues dealing with long term business relationships.

Experience


Doug Staneart has been a speaker and trainer for over ten years specializing in public speaking, leadership training, and team building. Doug is CEO of The Leader?s Institute ( Leadership Training ) based in Dallas and author of the books 40 Ways to Influence People and Fearless Presentations . He has accumulated over 2700 hours of classroom coaching and training and began his career with Dale Carnegie Training where he was recognized on numerous occasions for superior instruction.
 
 User Agreement Privacy Policy 

©2012 About.com, a part of The New York Times Company . All rights reserved.
 
 About Us Tell Friends How to Ask How to Volunteer FAQ Tech Support Top Experts Expert Login 
 
Browse Answers:

 By Category Alphabetically 
 Find expert answers to: Find
	</body>
</document>
