<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007992" url="http://www.chron.com/life/article/Houston-newsmakers-entertain-city-in-the-usual-1983570.php" time="2012-07-13-01:04" support="1" score="0.0007197845848367293" bingtitle="Houston newsmakers entertain city in the usual style - Houston ..." webtitle="Houston newsmakers entertain city in the usual style - Houston Chronicle">
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>... Houston Community College&apos;s annual Flash and Trash ... used color-coded charts to help jurors keep track ... 30 minutes later while eating at a nearby fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		( skip this header )
 
 Register Sign In 


 
 Classifieds | Houston Weather | Houston Traffic | Mobile | E-edition 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012
 
 chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs La Voz 

 Jobs Homes Autos Shopping 

 Index▼ 
 Close [X] Quick links to other pages on this site | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Houston&apos;s best Tex-Mex is ... $31 million car wreck Tropical weather Cornyn vs. Holder Photo &apos;mistake&apos; that worked Starbucks at funeral home 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Hurricanes Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths 
 
 Texans Astros Rockets Dynamo Colleges UH Rice A&amp;M; UT High school Golf Outdoors MMA, Hockey&amp;more Tickets 
 
 FuelFix Chron 100 Markets Houston stocks World markets Currency Top workplaces Small biz Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater Celebrity Buzz Comics&amp;Games 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Delish Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Hill Country travel Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker Ski Colorado 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 Home price survey New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 
 «Back to Article 
 


Houston newsmakers entertain city in the usual style
 ALISON COOK , Houston Chronicle Copyright 2012 Houston Chronicle. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 ALISON COOK, Houston Chronicle 

Published 06:30 a.m., Sunday, December 26, 2004
 Tweet 
 Comments ( 0 ) Larger | Smaller Printable Version 

 Email This 
 Georgia (default) 

 Verdana 

 Times New Roman 

 Arial 
 Font 
 Page 1 of 1 Hey, we made it!
The year 2004 began with the Super Bowl tsunami and ended -- at least for now -- with the Rockets knuckling under to the Charlotte Bobcats . Ouch. But despite assorted calamities -- from a mighty freeway egg spill to the discovery of lead in Mexican candies, from thousand-foot gas plumes to the threat of pesticide-proof mosquitoes -- Houstonians kept on keeping on in this most entertaining of cities.

We peaked and plunged with the Astros and marveled over happenings great (water on ancient Mars!) and small (gazillion Metro light-rail crashes!). We suffered through utility rate hikes and explosions and not enough flu shots and too many revelations about the Houston Police Department crime lab, where the forgotten evidence room looked not unlike our back closet. We watched Kenny Boy Lay do the perp walk, Lea Fastow go to jail and a combination of sharks and flesh-eating bacteria scare everyone out of the water.

Finally it was over, and not a minute too soon to offer a prayer: May 2005 be bigger and better than Carlos Beltran &apos;s next contract.

 NEXT TIME, JUST SAY YOU HAVE A HEADACHE: Leo Gaytan of Baytown pleaded guilty to phoning in a bomb threat to the chemical plant where he worked so he could go home early.

 IT READ &quot;ALL I WANT FOR CHRISTMAS IS BILL O&apos;REILLY &apos;S LOOFAH&quot;: A SpongeBob SquarePants balloon with a holiday wish attached traveled from the Mexican state of Veracruz to Fort Bend County, where a hunter found it in some bushes.

 SHE WAS IN LINE WITH JUSTIN TIMBERLAKE , MADONNA AND ELVIS: During the Super Bowl celebrity-spotting mania, a Channel 11 viewer reported a Britney Spears sighting at the Fiesta grocery store near Reliant Stadium.

 PARKING HIS EGO WAS HARDER: When Clay Walker played the Cynthia Woods Mitchell Pavilion in The Woodlands, Landry&apos;s tycoon Tilman Fertitta called ahead to ask where he could park his helicopter.

 SOMEBODY&apos;S GOTTA TAKE UP THE SIEGFRIED AND ROY SLACK: Tilman Fertitta moved heaven and city ordinances so he could install four rare white tigers in his downtown Aquarium complex, which he had certified as a zoo.

 THE HORROR, THE HORROR: A Woodlands High School advanced-placement art teacher was suspended for asking a male student to pose for classmates wearing only boxer shorts.

 EVEN WORSE, THEY WERE NAKED: A pack of roosters terrorized an apartment complex in The Woodlands, pecking little kids, defecating on cars and chasing people in wheelchairs.

 ONWARD CHRISTIAN SOLDIERS: Five teenage boys were investigated for shooting two other boys with a pellet gun while quoting Bible verses at a Fellowship of The Woodlands vacation Bible school .

 WHEN TROUBLE DRIVES A MINIVAN : Shannon Rechter filed assault charges against Sandra Chiang , another west Houston mom, alleging Chiang slapped her for cutting into a school carpool line. Chiang accused Rechter of &quot;keying&quot; her car and causing $1,600 in damage.

 DESPERATE HOUSEWIVES: THE OUTTAKE REEL: William Wolfe , a nurse in Rusk County, was charged with attempted murder after he allegedly prepared a bubble bath for his wife, complete with candles and music, and then tried to electrocute her by pushing a radio into the tub.

 SHE REFUSED TO BUDGE UNTIL SHE COULD TALK TO TILMAN FERTITTA: A pregnant baboon escaped from her crate in a cargo area of Bush Intercontinental Airport , clambering into the rafters and missing her flight to a San Francisco zoo.

 ASK TILMAN: A local Tinseltown cinema was closed after a janitor reported seeing an 8-foot snake slithering between the first row of seats and the screen, but an extensive professional search turned up nothing.

 SNARLING DOGS OPTIONAL: Students at the Katy Independent School District disciplinary school enter past a security guard and metal detector, where the principal and teachers greet them as they lift their shirts and pants, empty their pockets and remove their shoes. &quot;We make it a very positive experience to start the day,&quot; said principal Patty Bing .

 IT WOULD BE PERFECT FOR THE KATY DISCIPLINARY SCHOOL: At a local showing of Jean Paul Gaultier &apos;s fall line for Hermès, three Houston women expressed interest in a leather corset fashioned with padlocks that had been shown earlier in Paris, only to find it was a one-of-a-kind item not for sale.

 WITH THIS TRASH BAG, I THEE WED : At Houston Community College &apos;s annual Flash and Trash fashion show, student Nga Dinh unveiled a bridal gown made of white plastic garbage bags formed into rosettes.

 TRASH BAGS ARE A KEY DESIGN ELEMENT: A newly svelte Anna Nicole, having lost 70 pounds on her Trim-Spa diet, unveiled her new clothing line, dubbed &quot;Tex-Sex,&quot; in Las Vegas.

 MAYBE THEY SHOULD HIRE ANNA NICOLE AS SPOKESWOMAN: The Houston Symphony launched a new advertising campaign called &quot;Be a Symphomaniac.&quot;

 USE IT THREE TIMES AND IT&apos;S NOT NECESSARILY YOURS: Debbie Reynolds , a last-minute substitute for Shirley MacLaine as narrator for a Houston Symphony fairy-tale theme concert, repeatedly mispronounced the name &quot;Prokofiev.&quot;

 SEEKS WORK MAKING LICENSE PLATES: Flournoy Davis Williams , one of four men who robbed four fast-food restaurants in a single day, was arrested after he dropped a job application on the floor of the first place they held up.

 EYE ON THE FRIES: House Majority Leader Tom DeLay railed against an &quot;unpatriotic&quot; German-language Subway sandwiches ad touting the movie Super Size Me because it contained a cartoon of a fat Lady Liberty holding aloft an order of French fries.

 TOO BAD IT DIDN&apos;T WORK: Tom DeLay admitted he had undergone a surgical procedure to tighten droopy eyelids that were blocking his vision.

 AN OFFICE AND HOTEL COMPLEX SHOULD FIX THAT! Developer Gerald Hines , eyeing a coastal site in Libya, said, &quot;There are 2,000 kilometers of beachfront in Tripoli. It&apos;s a beautiful sea that looks like Cannes or Nice 100 years ago.&quot;

 A MINE IS A TERRIBLE THING TO WASTE: The National Education Association asked President Bush to fire Education Secretary Rod Paige for calling the teachers union a &quot;terrorist organization.&quot;

 THEY WERE CARD-CARRYING MEMBERS OF THE TEACHERS UNION: When 14 people were sent to hospitals after being overcome by fumes at a north Houston Wal-Mart, police searched for two men seen in the lawn and garden section waving wands connected to canisters.

 DEATH BECOMES THEM: Bradshaw-Carter, funeral home to the carriage trade, planned such features as a Mercedes hearse, hand-woven willow caskets, crematory urns from luxury leather purveyor Pineider and an on-site mourning room done up as a library with an English antler chandelier and working fireplace.

 AND THERE WASN&apos;T A SINGLE BRUCE : Ten cowboys named Cody appeared on the list of contestants at this year&apos;s RodeoHouston.

 HOW GREEN WAS MY MEDIAN: Hordes of Super Bowl revelers trampled the brave new plantings along three Main Street medians, leaving only stubble.

 THE WOODLANDS ROOSTERS ARE ORGANIZING A REVENGE POSSE: Huntsville student Kyle Lincecum , outfitted in a fuzzy, 11-foot-tall blue bird costume to advertise a Katy Freeway mattress store, was ambushed and beaten by five teenagers on skateboards.

 PLUS A DOZEN DAY-GLO THONGS: When rapper 50 Cent entertained at the NFL players&apos; Super Bowl bash at the Corinthian, his rider specified dressing-room amenities including fried chicken, a tub of Cristal champagne and two boxes of condoms.

 IS THAT A MAMMOTH BONE IN YOUR POCKET, OR ARE YOU JUST GLAD TO SEE ME ? One of three men captured while looting an archaeological dig in Clute was discovered to have a foot-long, 38,000-year-old mammoth bone in his pocket.

 TILMAN OFFERED HER A RIDER SPECIFYING RADICCHIO AND MESCLUN : Besides her regular diet of hay and alfalfa, Shanti, the Houston Zoo &apos;s pregnant Asian elephant, was treated to a supplement of banana leaves, bamboo stalks, palm fronds and hackberry gruel.

 WE HEAR HACKBERRY GRUEL MAKES A GREAT MIXER: After Bernard Oczkowski was convicted of dumping cancer-causing waste from his metal-plating business, Judge Michael Peters sentenced him to drink a cocktail of toxic sludge.

 DRINK TWO GLASSES OF HACKBERRY GRUEL AND CALL US IN THE MORNING: Questioned about the fees his development company, ESPA, earned from subcontracts on county-ordered road work, Harris County Commissioner El Franco Lee said the conflict didn&apos;t give him &quot;heartburn.&quot;

 DON&apos;T FORGET A PADLOCKED LEATHER CORSET, AN ESPA SUBCONTRACT AND A PLUSH TOY OF RADAR THE WEATHER DOG : Hundreds of items were packed into a time capsule to be placed behind a granite wall in the new civil courts building, including a photo of the Commissioners Court, a toll road token and the 2004 county budget.

 REPENT, THE END IS NIGH: The elite and stuffy Houston Club, which counts George Bush père and James Baker among its members, hosted a Super Bowl hip-hop party and offered tickets on the Web site vinylpimp.com.

 OUR ROVING CULTURAL AMBASSADORS: Socialites Gracie and Bob Cavnar, celebrating his 50th birthday in Paris with pals, took along their toy poodles, Max and Mimi, so Gracie could work on her photo book American Poodles in Paris. 

 WANT TO GET FRIED WITH THAT? The manager of a Sugar Land Boston Market restaurant was arrested after police discovered that some customers would pay for cocaine elsewhere and pick it up with their takeout orders.

 CUPCAKES: THREAT OR MENACE? In an effort to follow state nutritional guidelines, the Houston Independent School District outlawed brought-from-home birthday cupcakes in its classrooms.

 PLUS A CUPCAKE ON THE SUMMIT: The downtown Hyatt began serving a Mount St. Sundae including vanilla, chocolate, strawberry and dulce de leche ice cream topped with wedges of apple tart, two kinds of cheesecake, chocolate and raspberry sauce, fresh berries, whipped cream and a cherry.

 OH, HONEY, YOU DON&apos;T WANNA KNOW: While visiting Houston to promote her book Bergdorf Blondes, New York society-and-fashion writer Plum Sykes was horrified when a waiter brought her a luncheon salad with a fried green tomato on top. &quot;What&apos;s that?&quot;she asked.

 RHYMES WITH &quot;DUD&quot;: When Newlyweds stars Jessica Simpson and Nick Lachey visited the RodeoHouston petting zoo, Lachey reported, &quot;I was petting the sheep, goats or llamas, whatever they&apos;re called. It ate my shirt and it left, what do you call it, cud?&quot;

 GOING IN THE WATER WILL COST EXTRA: Galveston city and county officials advanced the idea of charging parking fees along Seawall Boulevard and the Bolivar Peninsula.

 AFTER WHICH CITY COUNCIL BILLED HER FOR PARKING FEES : An endangered Kemp&apos;s ridley sea turtle laid 85 eggs at the foot of Galveston&apos;s Seawall, the fourth such nesting recorded on the island.

 THEY LOVE I-PODS, CHIHUAHUAS AND HOT-PINK HANDBAGS : Research scientists descended on the Chambers County Golf Course to study the lifestyle of baseball-size channeled applesnails that have invaded the area, laying their neon-pink egg sacs along its waterways.

 KINDA LIKE THE ENRON DEBACLE WAS A BUSINESS MALFUNCTION? After Justin Timberlake yanked off Janet Jackson&apos;s bra cup during a Super Bowl halftime number, revealing her breast clad in a decorative nipple guard, the pair claimed the incident was an innocent &quot;wardrobe malfunction.&quot;

 PHOTO OP 101: Animal-rights activist Annie Judah protested the Ringling Brothers and Barnum&amp;Bailey Circus by posing downtown in shackles and black bikini bottom, her back covered with faux lash marks and her nipples covered by flower-shaped stickers.

 BREAST INTENTIONS: About 50 moms staged a baby &quot;nurse-in&quot; at the Galleria to protest a security guard&apos;s request that a breast-feeding mother cover up.

 JANET JACKSON&apos;S SUING FOR THEFT OF INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY : British streaker Mark Roberts was convicted of criminal trespass for dashing onto the field during Super Bowl halftime wearing a fake referee&apos;s uniform, which he tore off to reveal a deflated football taped over his genitals.

 AND IF THEY WORK IN THE WOODLANDS, THEY HAVE TO WEAR BOXER SHORTS : The Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals upheld a Houston ordinance requiring topless dancers to wear and conspicuously display a city-issued ID card while performing.

 PROOF THERE IS A GOD: Sex-talking radio shock jock Howard Stern&apos;s ratings upon his debut on Houston&apos;s KIKK-AM were so minuscule they didn&apos;t even register in the Arbitron ratings.

 TWO TICKETS FOR THE BOURRÉ-N-BOLIVAR FUN PACKAGE, PLEASE : A Bolivar ferry captain was placed on job probation for allegedly leaving the controls unattended while she gambled at Bourré, a Cajun card game, with her crew members.

 I BIT THE LAW AND THE LAW WON: The Rev. Curtis Lucas of Richmond was convicted of biting a police officer on the finger during a routine traffic stop. Said the minister, &quot;If I had to repeat the events of that evening, I would have just signed the ticket.&quot;

 THEY WANTED HIM FOR THE ROBERT DURST TRIAL: Nathan Dale Campbell, who was acquitted by reason of insanity of slicing his girlfriend&apos;s eyes out, was summoned for Harris County jury duty.

 NOT ENOUGH: Two Texas City bank-robbery suspects were nabbed so quickly in their getaway minivan that they had to ask the arresting officers how much money had been stolen.

 NOT FAST ENOU GH: Two men accused of holding up a Shepherd Drive beauty-supply shop were arrested about 30 minutes later while eating at a nearby fast-food restaurant.

 HE WAS ARRESTED ON PROVOLONE CAUSE : After a Fort Bend County crime spree that culminated in the robbery of a pizza-delivery man, a teenage suspect was nabbed at his nearby home along with the empty pizza box and a receipt.

 PEEPHOLE BARBIE: Pasadena residents were plagued by a masked man who knocked on residents&apos; doors and waved a Barbie doll at whomever answered.

 YOU SAY HIBISCUS, I SAY CANNABIS, LET&apos;S CALL THE WHOLE THING OFF : Landscape contractor Blair Davis&apos; northwest Harris County home was raided in the middle of the night by a narcotics squad that had mistaken the Texas Star hibiscus in his front yard for marijuana plants.

 THEIR NAMES WERE LARRY, MOE AND CURLY: Rosenberg drug suspects were arrested after they shot out a street light so they could unload a truck full of marijuana in the dark. The gunshots caused neighbors to call police.

 EVERY COP&apos;S CRAZY &apos;BOUT A SHARP-DRESSED MAN: Greggory Lurice Mims was implicated in a home-invasion robbery after he dropped a camera containing a photo of himself -- sporting a tux, fedora and large handgun -- at the scene.

 LITTLE THINGS MEAN A LOT: Astros pitcher Roger Clemens was ejected from his son&apos;s youth league game after an umpire accused Clemens of spitting a sunflower seed at him.

 DON&apos;T WORRY, THEY WERE JUST SKULKING PLAINTIFFS&apos; LAWYERS: Alarm reigned in the tony River Oaks neighborhood over reports of numerous coyote sightings.

 DOH! Two days after holding up an armored-car company for about $4 million, Robert Jermaine Wilson allegedly picked out two cars and then went by his house with a dealership employee so he could arrange payment with still-banded bundles of cash.

 THE DOG ATE MY . . . OH, NEVER MIND: Delmy Margoth Ruiz, accused of cutting off her boyfriend&apos;s penis with a kitchen knife while he slept, claimed she had tossed the member onto the back deck, where a black dog picked it up and ran away with it.

 IF THINE RING FINGER OFFEND THEE . . .: Stephen Douglas James left his severed ring finger by the bathroom sink of a Port Bolivar motel room, along with a bloody divorce decree, a suicide note and a bloodstained kayak bobbing in the Gulf of Mexico, but police theorized he staged the scene to avoid trial on a sexual-assault charge.

 DONALD TRUMP IS ON THE LINE FOR MR. CARPENTER : Beau Carpenter, a NASA worker and Rice University MBA student, invented a $49.95 glow-in-the-dark thong that resists water and can be recharged with a car adapter.

 BUT IT STILL HURTS DURING POLE DANCES: Strippers at a Dickinson topless bar went wild for Carpenter&apos;s GloThongs, lining up to order them and suggesting that the battery be moved to the front for more comfort.

 NO CHARGE FOR THE HERRING SPITTLE: In a bid to attract more special events, the Houston Zoo made Roscoe the sea lion available to bestow kisses at wedding ceremonies.

 ROSCOE THE SEA LION MADE A CELEBRITY APPEARANCE: At a &quot;Voyage to Alaska&quot; ball staged by Citizens for Animal Protection, 10,000 pounds of ice sculptures decorated the ballroom while sound and video played of icebergs calving from glaciers.

 PARTÉE HEARTÉE: During an American Friends of the Louvre benefit party at the home of socialite Becca Cason Thrash, a fashion model, a waiter, an oilman and a cell phone accidentally tumbled into the indoor swimming pool.

 PRIDE GOETH BEFORE AND AFTER A FALL: Socialite Kristi Schiller, who broke her tailbone days before her birthday party, was gifted with a Fortuny fabric-covered doughnut pillow at the bash.

 I WAS A CHANGE-GRUBBING NEWS JUNKIE: Ronnie Luhn&apos;s one-bedroom home in Spring Branch was discovered by police to be crammed with 181 stolen coin-operated newspaper boxes.

 OH MARIO, MARIO, WHEREFORE ART THOU, MARIO? State Sen. Mario Gallegos admitted an extramarital affair with ex-stripper Susan Delgado, who had sued him for emotional and physical abuse that allegedly included spankings, then ran against him and filed an election challenge saying he didn&apos;t live in his district.

 THEY WERE A SPLINTER CELL OF THE WOODLANDS ROOSTER GANG: A marauding flock of guinea hens roved the Ella Lee Forest neighborhood, pottying on the azaleas, scratching in the flower beds, roosting in oak trees, issuing raucous alarm calls and eluding professional efforts to capture them.

 HE COULDN&apos;T INTEREST TILMAN IN HIS DEAL : Thirteen endangered red-footed tortoises and two Indian star tortoises disappeared from a Moody Gardens holding facility, and a company electrician later returned them unharmed.

 NEWS AT 10: DAVE WARD AND ROSCOE THE SEA LION : Channel 2&apos;s 10 p.m. news ratings&apos; win over perennially top-rated Channel 13 was attributed in part to the popularity of Radar the Weather Dog, a mutt that was adopted as the station mascot.

 CHANNEL 13 HAS COMMISSIONED A MARVIN ZINDLER PLUSH TOY: Foley&apos;s introduced a plush toy of Radar the Weather Dog, and hundreds of people lined up at stores to greet the dog during live appearances.

 DONALD TRUMP IS ON THE LINE, GENTLEMEN : Two Lake Jackson boys, ages 11 and 13, were accused of using a computer to make counterfeit $20 bills -- most with one side upside-down -- which they tumbled in a clothes dryer and sold to other kids for 50 cents or $1 each.

 C-U IN COURT: A 17-year-old Channelview high school student was charged with making terrorist threats after a teacher confiscated a detailed hit list titled &quot;P2K,&quot; which he told investigators meant &quot;people to kill.&quot;

 I BELIEVE I CAN FLY: Louis Paul Kadlecek, who had never been in a plane before, got so drunk on his 21st birthday that he broke into 16 hangars at the Brazoria County Airport, stole two planes and flew one into a power line, cutting off electricity to much of Clute and Lake Jackson.

 MMM, MMM GOOD: Texas A&amp;M food scientist Ralph Waniska discovered a way to make a tortilla that would have a shelf life of more than a month.

 NEXT PROJECT: HOW TO MAKE AN ODOR-FREE WHITE TRUFFLE: Texas A&amp;M geneticist Kevin Crosby developed and patented a mild version of the habañero chile, the hottest pepper known to humankind.

 YEAH, RIGHT: Metro officials unveiled plans for a possible subway segment of the city&apos;s light-rail line.

 CHA-CHINNNG: As part of a plan to overhaul school funding, state senators proposed to allow video slots in the Astrodome.

 ROSES ARE RED, LAP DANCES ARE BLUE: Huntsville middle and high schools were swept by a fad for jelly bracelets color-coded to certain sexual acts that the wearer is supposed to perform when someone breaks or snaps it off the wrist.

 (FILL IN THE BLANK) IS THE COLOR OF MY TRUE LOVE&apos;S HAIR : During former Rockets star Calvin Murphy&apos;s trial on charges he molested five of his daughters, prosecutors used color-coded charts to help jurors keep track of the 14 children he sired by nine women, eight of whom he was not married to.

 AND GUINEA FOWL REALLY GET HER GOING: Houstonian Jerry McMurray told TV talk-show host Maury Povich that his wife, Emily, is so afraid of mice that her screams once drew ambulance, fire and police personnel to their house.

 NEXT TIME SHE&apos;LL TRY &quot;CATHY HURTT&quot;: Sharon Durbin, passing herself off as &quot;Cathy Rosenthal,&quot; wrote 21 phony checks on Harris County District Attorney Chuck Rosenthal&apos;s personal bank account before she was arrested.

 AFTER WHICH HE AND CATHY ROSENTHAL WED IN A JAILHOUSE CEREMONY: During his armed-robbery trial for stealing $40 from an undercover cop, Wilbert Lillie attacked prosecutor Marc Brown, breaking his nose and giving him a concussion; he received a 50-year sentence.

 HE&apos;S WORKING ON THE YELLOW-BELLIED COYOTE POSITION: Tomball car salesman James Lee Cross, convicted of slapping his wife, was put on probation and sentenced by judge Larry Stanley to take a yoga class.

 CITY OFFICIALS: THEY&apos;RE JUST LIKE US! Mayor Bill White ordered a crackdown on cell phone and pager use after learning that city employees had run up more than $500,000 in roaming and directory-assistance charges since early 2001.
 Printable Version Email This Tweet Subscribe to the Houston Chronicle and receive access to the Chronicle for iPad App Houston newsmakers entertain city in the usual style Houston Chronicle Copyright 2012 Houston Chronicle. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
Published 06:30 a.m., Sunday, December 26, 2004
 The good, the bad and the tawdry Houston newsmakers entertain city in the usual style By ALISON COOK Houston Chronicle Hey, we made it! 
 More Houston Life 
 
 
 Comics&amp;Games 
 
 Delish (Recipes) 
 
 Flavor 
 
 Houston Grows 
 
 Gloss 
 
 Health News 
 
 Horoscopes 
 
 Weddings&amp;Celebrations 
 
 
Life blogs
 
 
 BabySteps 
 


 Botched song lyrics and other philosophies 

08:02 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Believe It or Not 
 


 Episcopal Church passes same-sex blessings,... 

07:33 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Bookish 
 


 Great fiction. Defined. 

7/11/12 at 10:49 a.m. | Comments 

 
 Design Houston 
 


 Designer Bill Stubbs is blogging and staging a... 

03:50 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Leon Hale 
 


 What do you think of this? 

11:15 a.m. | Comments 

 
 MeMo 
 


 The language is taking a turn. Because Gawker? 

12:28 p.m. | Comments 

 
 The Middle Lane 
 


 Joe Biden takes a stroll down the Middle Lane 

10:45 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Mom Houston 
 


 Taking parenting too seriously can be bad for... 

7/9/12 at 03:49 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Shop Girl 
 


 Mullet style: Would you wear a dress inspired... 

7/9/12 at 07:14 a.m. | Comments 

 
 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation Business Sports Entertainment Life Blogs Weather Traffic 
 
Topics

 29-95 Small Business PetsHouston MomHouston HoustonBelief Gardening Work&amp;Career Advice Recipes from Delish 
 
Neighborhoods

 Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad Contests 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery Mobile RSS Feeds Chronicle in Education e-Edition Breaking News Alerts La Voz (Spanish) 
 
Services

 Contact us Business directory Legal notices Send us tips About the company Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad Ad Choices 
 
 A quadrantONE partner 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
	</body>
</document>
