<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007423" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2009/07/25/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946.html" time="2012-07-13-00:23" support="10" score="0.0364761492669166" bingtitle="North Korea Opens 1st Fast-Food Restaurant: Report" webtitle="North Korea Opens 1st Fast-Food Restaurant: Report">
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000236" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="118"/>
	<description>The minced beef and bread at the new fast-food restaurant costs only $1.70, the newspaper said, but that would eat up more than half of the average North ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 Syria Guantanamo Bay Unearthed 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 43k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 22k Romney Campaign Releases New Ad Accusing Obama Of Spreading Lies 10k When Did Romney Leave Bain? 15k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k America&apos;s Best States to Live In 376 Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 377 CNBC Host Blasts Krugman, &apos;He Owes Us An Apology&apos; 1k 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Entertainment 
 Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 1k Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 49 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 18 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 428 Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Katie Couric&apos;s Photo Shows Up In Unexpected Place 33 Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 277 WATCH: Greg Gutfeld Freaks Out 2k 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Green 
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother 362 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 264 A &apos;Snow Monster&apos; In Mount Rainier Creek 496 Young Man Mysteriously Found Dead Inside Tiger Den 82 Waldo Canyon Fire Fully Contained 102 
 Like 104k   Go to Green More in Green 
 Energy Climate Change Animals Green Tech Green Holiday 
 You might also like 
 Politics Food World Science Healthy Living 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 912 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 531 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 212 Facebook Fires Yoga Teacher For Banning Smartphones In Class 653 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Culture 
 There Is Something Wrong With This Rock 211 50 YEARS 94 10 Movies To Watch At Comic-Con 2012 27 Bollywood Action Hero Dies At 84 34 Guess Who&apos;s Playing Janis Joplin? 659 
 Like 14k   Go to Culture More in Culture 
 Arts Books TV 
 You might also like 
 Black Voices Latino Voices Gay Voices Comedy Impact Education Religion 
 Travel 
 PHOTOS: Guess Who Has The Worst Traffic? 480 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 948 Boo: Now The World&apos;s Cutest Airline Spokesman 62 70-Year-Old Minister Takes 7000th Coaster Ride 53 Branson Reveals Space Plane Launch Date 
 Like 24k   Go to Travel More in Travel 
 Travel Video Destinations Themed Guides TSA Airlines 
 You might also like 
 Food Culture World GPS for the Soul Kitchen Daily 
 Food 
 PHOTOS: Jaw-Dropping Knife Ads Are Fairly Graphic LOOK: The World&apos;s Most Expensive Foods 125 Cooking Legend Dies At 90 31 Funeral Home To Sell Starbucks Coffee 29 Chain Food Showdown: The Best&amp;Worst Spinach Dips 23 
 Like 17k   Go to Food More in Food 
 Recipes Chefs Restaurants Desserts Cocktails Wine Beer 
 You might also like 
 Kitchen Daily Stylelist Home Travel 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 World 
 Foreign Affairs World Elections Arab Uprising Afghanistan War Syria Crisis Drug War Protecting Journalists World Videos Iranathon 
 
 
North Korea Opens 1st Fast-Food Restaurant: Report
 
 KWANG-TAE KIM   07/25/09 10:22 PM ET   Associated Press 
 React Important
 Fascinating
 Typical
 Scary
 Outrageous
 Amazing
 Infuriating
 Beautiful
 Follow   Fast Food ,   North Korea , Fast Food Korea , Hamburger , Minced Beef And Bread , Pyongyang , World News 
share this story
 Get World Alerts Sign Up Submit this story digg reddit stumble 
SEOUL, South Korea—You still can&apos;t get a hamburger in Pyongyang, but the suspiciously similar &quot;minced beef and bread&quot; is for sale at the North Korean capital&apos;s first fast-food restaurant, a news report said Saturday.

The Samtaesong restaurant opened in the isolated communist country last month in cooperation with a Singaporean company, according to the Tokyo-based Choson Sinbo. The Singaporean company, which the newspaper did not name, provided training to restaurant staff and supplied equipment.

The restaurant&apos;s interior appears to be styled after fast-food joints the world over, but the menu is careful not to call its signature fare a hamburger–lest it give the impression North Koreans had embraced the American icon.

North Korea&apos;s authoritarian government is concerned that outside influences could undermine the regime and pose a threat to leader Kim Jong Il&apos;s tight grip on the nation of 24 million. It balks at using foreign words and coins alternatives in Korean instead.

But this is not the government&apos;s first foray into foreign food. In March, the Choson Sinbo, widely considered a mouthpiece for the North Korean government, reported that Kim–a noted gourmand–had ordered the opening of the country&apos;s first Italian restaurant. The chefs there were trained in Italy and food made with imported ingredients was served.

The restaurants are unlikely to be frequented by ordinary people in North Korea, which is one of the world&apos;s poorest countries and experiences chronic food shortages.

The minced beef and bread at the new fast-food restaurant costs only $1.70, the newspaper said, but that would eat up more than half of the average North Korean&apos;s daily income. South Korea&apos;s central bank put last year&apos;s average per capita income at $1,065.

The restaurant also offers kimchi–Korean pickled cabbage–as well as waffles and draft beer. It plans to add croissants and hot dogs to its menu in the coming months but with Korean names, and will open another branch in the capital soon, according to the newspaper.
 FOLLOW 
 HUFFPOST WORLD ON Facebook: Like 55k Twitter:   Get Alerts CONTRIBUTE TO THIS STORY 
 Send Corrections Send us a Link Contact us 

 Send a Tip Send Photos/Videos Comment 
 
 Copyright 2012 The Local Paper. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 Fast Food North Korea 
 SEOUL, South Korea&amp;mdash; You still can&apos;t get a hamburger in Pyongyang, but the suspiciously similar&quot;minced beef and bread&quot;is for sale at the North Korean capital&apos;s first fast-food restaurant, a ne... SEOUL, South Korea&amp;mdash; You still can&apos;t get a hamburger in Pyongyang, but the suspiciously similar&quot;minced beef and bread&quot;is for sale at the North Korean capital&apos;s first fast-food restaurant, a ne... Filed by Lila Shapiro  |  
 More in World... 

 Clinton: North Korea&apos;s Nuclear Agenda A Serious... Afghans Protest Execution Of Woman Nawaf Al Fares, Syria Ambassador To Iraq,... North Korea TV Broadcasts &apos;Rocky&apos; Film And...     
 Comments 64 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 Comments are closed for this entry Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   3   Next ›   Last »  (3 total) Edward Leung 1 Fans 04:13 PM on 08/03/2009 They soon are going to have nuclear bombs with bread Edward_Leung: They soon are going to have nuclear bombs with bread http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Edward_Leung/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_28248211.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 me again I&apos;m not wrong.... 1017 Fans 09:20 AM on 07/27/2009 Dear Leaders Dog Burgers.... me_again: Dear Leaders Dog Burgers.... http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/me_again/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27805305.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program AirViceMarshalPark 696 Fans 02:51 AM on 07/27/2009 Bad news: the restaurant closed. The employees ate all of the cats by themselves. All of the employees were shot.

Good news: the restaurant reopens tomorrow with the new Soylent Burger. AirViceMarshalPark: Bad news: the restaurant closed. The employees ate all of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/AirViceMarshalPark/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27800188.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Driver125 33 Fans 12:47 AM on 07/27/2009 Alright! Pretty soon it will be down to the Quickie Dog for a burger topped off with a little kimchi--Ummmmmm, good! Driver125: Alright! Pretty soon it will be down to the Quickie http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Driver125/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27797225.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program TexasGiant 27 Fans 05:09 PM on 07/26/2009 Would be great if they throw in over-sized women&apos;s glasses with the happy meal. TexasGiant: Would be great if they throw in over-sized women&apos;s glasses http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/TexasGiant/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27779854.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 cognitivereddawn 16 Fans 04:42 PM on 07/26/2009 Followed by a firing squad? cognitivereddawn: Followed by a firing squad? http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/cognitivereddawn/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27778945.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 GoodFeathers 8 Fans 03:38 PM on 07/26/2009 Good luck N.Korea! We Americans didn&apos;t want to invade you because you don&apos;t have a drop of oil. So we decided to send in our fast food restaurants to cause the health care crisis and ruin whatever left in your country. GoodFeathers: Good luck N.Korea! We Americans didn&apos;t want to invade you http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/GoodFeathers/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27776700.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST COMMUNITY MODERATOR MissCupcake **JAZZ HANDS** 601 Fans 04:49 PM on 07/26/2009 This has nothing to do with American fast food. Do some research on North Korea. MissCupcake: This has nothing to do with American fast food. Do http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/MissCupcake/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27779172.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST COMMUNITY MODERATOR JanPoore 1737 Fans 03:17 PM on 07/26/2009 I suspect that the &quot;beef&quot; is dog or cat meat. And when they say Hot Dog, it will probably be actual dog.

Yuck! What an awful thought. We are so lucky to be living in America and not North Korea. JanPoore: I suspect that the&quot;beef&quot;is dog or cat meat. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/JanPoore/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27775949.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 LePlatypope 2 Fans 03:15 PM on 07/26/2009 Capitalism rides the coat-tails of fast-food, so there goes that enemy. LePlatypope: Capitalism rides the coat-tails of fast-food, so there goes that http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/LePlatypope/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27775861.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Antonio518 45 Fans 02:44 PM on 07/26/2009 Cuba has a fast food chain (El Rapido) For a dollar you can get a hamburger, a tropicola and fries, or a half chicken, tropicola and fries. Cubans make movie that are shown all over the world. Cubans trade with other countries, and have spanking new hotels and shopping centers, where Cubans can stay and shop if they have the money. . At Jose Marti airport in La Habana you can see Cubans leaving and coming back in droves. The planes are full of tourists, but also full of Cubans who have passports and business of holidays to take care of. I don&apos;t know about Korea, but I suspect that it is more successful and more vital than we are led to believe. Antonio518: Cuba has a fast food chain (El Rapido) For a http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Antonio518/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27774555.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program 3dtrix 2739 Fans 02:53 PM on 07/26/2009 You would be mistaken... 3dtrix: You would be mistaken... http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/3dtrix/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27774956.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER TFlint 739 Fans 03:15 PM on 07/26/2009 south Korea is prosperous. This article is about North Korea. A different country. TFlint: south Korea is prosperous. This article is about North Korea. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/TFlint/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27775848.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Maanu 14 Fans 02:07 PM on 07/26/2009 It&apos;s so easy to beat up on North Korea and the lack of freedoms there, and how Kim Jong is ill.
America, take a good look in the mirror. Give it a couple generations of forgotten gains, and we are a hair&apos;s breadth away from where they are today. They have stunted growth, we have the freedom to get fat, come down with diabetes, and be charged exorbitantly to have it treated.
Who has killed more people outside of their country, the US or Nor Kor? Not even close.
They&apos;ve got nukes, they&apos;re scary. Guess what, we&apos;ve actually used them.
Perhaps the reason we can laugh about North Korea is not because they seem crazy, but because their lunacy is backwoods compared to our sophisticated genocide.
They&apos;ve got propaganda for sure, but when&apos;s the last time you&apos;ve seen a North Korean blockbuster film?
It&apos;s called the lesser of two evils. Maanu: It&apos;s so easy to beat up on North Korea and http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Maanu/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27773058.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Kasado en jolt of terminus 196 Fans 02:06 PM on 07/26/2009 How smug we must feel to judge the rest of the world with our American standards. Unless a foreigner lives in a house ten times to large for their family, waddles their fat butts out to their SUV to drive two blocks for a Big Mac value meal, consume handfulls of medications to counteract their feverish / lavish lifestyles and strives to fill their huge house with cheap / planned obsolescent foreign made goods they are somehow less than us and subject to ridicule. I have lived in a great many foreign countries and a majority of the people there live their comparatively short lives with more humility, compassion, strength of charactor, frugality, and affinity than any two American life times combined. Yet, somehow, they are inferior to us. Kasado: How smug we must feel to judge the rest of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Kasado/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27773033.html History  | Permalink  | Share it bigsexyshaq 29 Fans 02:09 PM on 07/26/2009 If we all turned to Zen Buddhism, none of this would matter. But unfortunately, we have also lost our sense of values. bigsexyshaq: If we all turned to Zen Buddhism, none of this http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/bigsexyshaq/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27773149.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 pbcrunch 64 Fans 03:29 PM on 07/26/2009 Yes, shame on us for using our &quot;American standards&quot; to compare North Koreans&apos; lives to ours. We should applaud the North Koreans&apos; ability to live under the thumb of a paranoid tyrant who diverts 1/3rd of the country&apos;s GDP into the military; and their ability to live year to year with crippling agricultural disasters and the near constant threat of starvation is also laudable.

Seriously, what was the point of your post? It has nothing to do with the article, which was merely pointing out: a) North Korea opened a hamburger fast food joint but is not calling them &quot;hamburgers,&quot; like everywhere else in the world; and b) hardly anyone in North Korea will be able to afford to eat there. pbcrunch: Yes, shame on us for using our&quot;American standards&quot;to http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/pbcrunch/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27776359.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 LMPE I connect the most dissimilar things 1559 Fans 01:49 PM on 07/26/2009 If NK wants foreign food, wouldn&apos;t a Greek or Indian restaurant be healthier? LMPE: If NK wants foreign food, wouldn&apos;t a Greek or Indian http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/LMPE/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27772376.html History  | Permalink  | Share it bigsexyshaq 29 Fans 02:07 PM on 07/26/2009 Well you know how much NK loves American everything. bigsexyshaq: Well you know how much NK loves American everything. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/bigsexyshaq/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27773068.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER TFlint 739 Fans 03:17 PM on 07/26/2009 Or what about good old fashioned Dolsot Bi Bim Bap?. That will cost more than a hamburger. TFlint: Or what about good old fashioned Dolsot Bi Bim Bap?. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/TFlint/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27775945.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 stylenease 16 Fans 01:29 PM on 07/26/2009 What an attractive looking &quot;Catburger&quot;, no doubt made from ferel cats that roam the NK countryside. But wait a second, they are all starving so there probably aren&apos;t many spare cats to cook. stylenease: What an attractive looking&quot;Catburger&quot;, no doubt made from ferel http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/stylenease/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27771587.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program 3dtrix 2739 Fans 02:54 PM on 07/26/2009 Not cat-burgers - RAT-burgers. They ate the cats a long time ago, and so... 3dtrix: Not cat-burgers - RAT-burgers. They ate the cats a long http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/3dtrix/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27775009.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 totaldisbelief 394 Fans 01:20 PM on 07/26/2009 how nice for the top 600 families that get all the perks.....while the general population eats grass. totaldisbelief: how nice for the top 600 families that get all http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/totaldisbelief/north-korea-opens-1st-fas_n_244946_27771165.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Page:  1   2   3   Next ›   Last »  (3 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost av%2BoIzr1NlDiMVVHOmqGvu9ZarivL%2FsS8pIVwMHyz5nLdRyUI38JV7XutaXCMghBU2TJoj87kjzLoAd6f4mMBg8FcLk%2FR0Sw n23g1KxNmTj6iRfnNUuLgpcSJtUt%2B8pthPEt6MQtFSzkUvSugXwewptGVqyetpf5id%2BuwRhUsU%2F45P%2FPNBP9b2zwPZjPQklB 1 of 2 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 
 Like 7k World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 
 Like 9k &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 
 Like 4k Photos Of Kardashian Baby Are A Hard Sell 
 Like 66 Kim Kardashian Tweets Yet Another Bikini Pic 
 Like 45 Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 
 Like 762 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 
 Like 1k Penn State Administration, Joe Paterno Covered Up Jerry Sandusky&apos;s Child Abuse (UPDATED) 
 Recommend 1k Katie Holmes Used Disposable Phones To Orchestrate Divorce 
 Like 670 Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HPMG News 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
