<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007305" url="http://www.manta.com/mb_43_C4_12/restaurants_bars/hawaii" time="2012-07-13-00:16" support="1" score="0.0018400575006656227" bingtitle="Restaurants &amp; Bars in Hawaii (HI) - Company Profiles &amp; Company ..." webtitle="RestaurantsBars in Hawaii (HI)">
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>Clean cheery and air conditioned, Molokai Pizza ... events delivers Breakfast Platters, Fruit Trays ... Caterers in Hawaii · Cafes in Hawaii · Fast-Food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		%3c%46%4f%52%4d%20%69%64%3d&quot;%73%62%62%5f%6a%54%4a%65%56%44%77&quot;%20%6d%65%74%68%6f%64%3d&quot;%70%6f%73%74&quot;%20%73%74%79%6c%65%3d&quot;%64%69%73%70%6c%61%79%3a%6e%6f%6e%65&quot;%3e%3c%49%4e%50%55%54%20%6e%61%6d%65%3d%27%73%62%62%5f%53%71%46%5a%66%72%4e%27%20%74%79%70%65%3d%27%63%68%65%63%6b%62%6f%78%27%20%20%76%61%6c%75%65%3d%27%74%43%49%54%27%2f%3e%3c%49%4e%50%55%54%20%6e%61%6d%65%3d%27%73%62%62%5f%53%71%46%5a%66%72%4e%27%20%74%79%70%65%3d%27%63%68%65%63%6b%62%6f%78%27%20%20%76%61%6c%75%65%3d%27%78%73%6b%4a%27%2f%3e%3c%49%4e%50%55%54%20%6e%61%6d%65%3d%27%73%62%62%5f%53%71%46%5a%66%72%4e%27%20%74%79%70%65%3d%27%63%68%65%63%6b%62%6f%78%27%20%20%43%48%45%43%4b%45%44%20%20%76%61%6c%75%65%3d%27%78%67%79%6d%64%51%27%2f%3e%3c%49%4e%50%55%54%20%6e%61%6d%65%3d%27%73%62%62%5f%53%71%46%5a%66%72%4e%27%20%74%79%70%65%3d%27%63%68%65%63%6b%62%6f%78%27%20%20%76%61%6c%75%65%3d%27%45%6b%73%74%67%76%27%2f%3e%3c%2f%46%4f%52%4d%3e Sign In Email Password 
 Forgot your password? 
 New to Manta? Join Free U.S. Companies Worldwide Manta Connect Features Promote Your Business Add Your Company Search U.S. Companies Search only Restaurants&amp;Bars in Hawaii Search the World (except U.S.) Companies Chart It 
Hawaii Restaurants&amp;Bars

Manta has 5,109 
 companies under Restaurants&amp;Bars in Hawaii
 
 + Add Your Company for Free Top Featured Companies 
 
 
 1132 Cafe&amp;Catering 
 1132 Bishop Street # 131 , Honolulu HI 96813 map (808) 521-1857 0 Recommendations Our OFFICE CATERING for your meetings and events delivers Hot Breakfast and Lunch, Pizza, Breakfast Platters, Fruit Trays, Coffee-Catering, Lunch Boxe 
 Office catering 
 
 
 
 Ka Hoku&apos;ao Coffee ltd 
 Honolulu HI 96797 map 0 Recommendations We offer FULL Barista Catering Services with the BEST Aloha service! Let us cater your next event, and make it a memorable one for your attendees!   Our Catering Options:

Basic Set-Up:
Includes; Cafe&apos; Latte&apos;s, Cappuccinos, Cafe&apos; Mocha&apos;s, Americano&apos;s, Espresso, and Espresso Con Panna&apos;s both hot and iced.

Upgraded Set-Up:
Includes all beverages from the Basic Set-Up, as well as; Vanilla Latte&apos;s, Hazelnut Latte&apos;s, French Vanilla Latte&apos;s, Caramel Latte&apos;s, White Mocha&apos;s, and Caramel Macchiato&apos;s both hot and iced.

Ultimate Set-Up:
Includes all beverages from the Basic and Upgraded Set-Ups, as well as; Our Iced Creamy Blended Beverages (or Frappe&apos;s) ; including Coffee and Non Coffee Blended Beverages both, Vanilla, Hazelnut, French Vanilla, Caramel, Mocha, and White Mocha.

Freshly Brewed Hawaiian Coffee:
Available with any of these Set-Ups for an additional cost.

For More Information Contact:
catering.department@kahokuaocoffee.com Additional Info: Ka Hoku&apos;ao Coffee is about spreading the Word of God through people connections, coffee, and coffee related items. 
 Barista Catering Espresso Coffee Catering Frappe Catering 
 
 
 
 Mau Loa Coffee&amp;Deli 
 400 Hualani Street # 16 E , Hilo HI 96720 map 0 Recommendations Breakfast, lunch, dinner and a full service coffee bar offering liquor shots   Whether you are looking for a good home style meal, a sandwich, a snack or just a relaxing cup of coffee. Mau Loa Coffee&amp;Deli offers up a delicious variety of sandwiches, wraps, salads, plate lunches and snacks. We also offer the only full service coffee bar with optional liquor shots. Come on down to Mau Loa Coffee&amp;Deli today! 
 Coffee&apos;s 
 
 
 
 Aloha Deli Ice Cream&amp;Shave Ice 
 61-3642 Kawaihae Road , Kamuela HI 96743 map 0 Recommendations Restaurant, Ice Cream Parlor, and Shave Ice Parlor. Serving American and Asian Cuisines, Burgers, Sandwiches, Salads, and Daily Specials.   We are a family owned and operated restaurant and we strive to produce quality products for our guests. We started our first restaurant back in 1993, which was the original Aloha Deli, and since then, we have learned that providing simple but delicious unpretentious quality product is the key in establishing a great relationship with our local guests and guests from aroung the world. Customer service is an important part of our day to day operation and also to provide a warm family oriented atmosphere to all our guests. We look forward to your visit and to welcome you to Aloha Deli located below the Seafood Bar on Kawaihae Road across from the Kawaihae Harbor. Additional Info: We are known for our homemade Teriyaki Sauce, BBQ Sauce, Blackened Seasonings, Payaya Seed Salad Dressing, Oriental Salad Dressing, Caesar Dressing, and our very own Homemade Vegetarian Burger. 
 Food Frozen Dessert Shave Ice 
 
 
 
 Molokai Pizza Cafe 
 15 Kaunakakai Place , Kaunakakai HI 96748 map 0 Recommendations Clean cheery and air conditioned, Molokai Pizza offers delicious fresh dough pizzas, as well as a full dinner menu.   Serving our Island Community lunch and dinner daily since 1992, we also cater and offer birthday packages which include tokens to our family game room&quot;Molokai Fun&amp;Games Arcade&quot; Additional Info: Winner of the prestigious Goveners Kilohana Award, featured in Frommers and rated by Zagat, find money saving offers in Holo Holo Magazine, Entertainment, Fly Drive Guide Books and Molokai Dispatch. 
 
 
 Kruger of Hawaii, Inc 
 1132 Bishop Street # 131 , Honolulu HI 96813-2849 map 0 Recommendations Office Catering,
Take-out for made to order sandwiches and salads.
Espresso Bar   Our OFFICE CATERING for your meetings and events delivers Breakfast Platters, Fruit Trays, Coffee-Catering, Lunch Boxes, Sandwich Platters, Wraps, Croissant Platters, healthy Salads. Check our ALL DAY MEETING SERVICE for your seminars and training sessions.
Conveniently located in the lobby of 1132 Bishop Street in downtown Honolulu, we also offer Sandwiches, Salads, Soups, Pastries, Gourmet Coffee and Espresso Drinks for take-out. 
FOR THE MENU VISIT WWW.1132CAFE.COM 
 
 
 The Sundial Cafe 
 41-863 Kalanianaole Hwy Waimanalo, HI, 96795 , Waimanalo HI 96795 map 0 Recommendations The Sundial Cafe serves up fresh fruit smoothies, coffee, espresso drinks for beach goers and locals alike.   Located in the heart of Waimanalo, on the windward side of Oahu, The Sundial Cafe features healthy snack options along with delicious Hawaiian blend coffee drinks. Our goal is to give back to the children of the community by contributing to schools, charity organizations and to encourage sustainability, gardening, music, native Hawaiian culture and of course, ALOHA. Additional Info: We are focused on building community - from the ground up - with local families, local producers and local businesses 
 
 
 Splashers Grill 
 75-5663 Palani Road , Kailua Kona HI 96740-1601 map 0 Recommendations Casual dining restaurant with ocean views from every table. Affordable, family friendly. Breakfast, lunch and dinner. Try a cheeseburger or fish tacos 
 
 
 Tea At 1024 
 1024 Nuuanu Avenue , Honolulu HI 96817-5117 map 0 Recommendations A unique and unpretentious setting, Tea at 1024 has been serving Afternoon Tea since 1999. We host Bridal showers, Baby Showers and Catered events.   Additional Info: Voted&quot;Best High Tea&quot;by Honolulu Magazine. Awarded&quot;Talk of the Town&quot;two years in a row. A favorite place on Google and Yelp. 
 
 
 Menehune Coffee Company 
 75-5660 Palani Road , Kailua Kona HI 96740 map 0 Recommendations 100% Kona coffee especially for you.   The Menehune are the wee people of the Hawaiian Islands, also known as Nawao.
Our legendary mystical and shy forest dwellers only come out to work at night. Harvesting, processing, roasting, and packaging up all of the wonderful 100% Kona coffee especially for you. While working the little mischievous gods enjoy playing pranks, dancing, and singing. So we invite you to enjoy a little taste of aloha to start you day. See all featured companies Featured Categories · Restaurants in Hawaii · Coffee Shops in Hawaii · Caterers in Hawaii · Cafes in Hawaii · Fast-Food Restaurant, Chain in Hawaii · Chinese Restaurant in Hawaii · Cocktail Lounges in Hawaii · Pizza in Hawaii · Ice Cream Parlors in Hawaii · Japanese Restaurant in Hawaii 
 All 5,109 Companies Too many to display. Narrow by category or location below. Current Category for location Hawaii 
 All Industries ~ Restaurants&amp;Bars 
 Browse Subcategories 
 
 Bars / Taverns (335) 
 
 
 
 Confectionery (51) 
 
 Restaurants (4,723) 
 
 
 Get Listed on Manta. It&apos;s Free! 
Thousands of people add their company to Manta everyday.

Add your website links, social media, business information and more.

 Get Listed Now 
 Current Location for category Restaurants&amp;Bars 
 United States ~ Hawaii 
 Browse Cities 
 
 Honolulu (2,317) 
 
 Hilo (219) 
 
 Lahaina (213) 
 
 
 
 Kailua Kona (186) 
 
 Aiea (181) 
 
 Waipahu (160) 
 
 
 
 Kihei (156) 
 
 Kailua (150) 
 
 Kahului (111) 
 
 Kaneohe (107) 
 
 There are 76 cities in Hawaii with companies in the Restaurants&amp;Bars category.
We&apos;ve listed the top 10 (based on number of companies) above.

 See all cities for Restaurants&amp;Bars in Hawaii» 
Refine Your Results
 
Filter companies by:
 
Newly Formed Businesses
 Date Started: 1 week ago 2 weeks ago 3 weeks ago 4 weeks ago 5 weeks ago 6 weeks ago 7 weeks ago 8 weeks ago 9 weeks ago 10 weeks ago 11 weeks ago 12 weeks ago 13 weeks ago 14 weeks ago 15 weeks ago 16 weeks ago 17 weeks ago 18 weeks ago 19 weeks ago 20 weeks ago 21 weeks ago 22 weeks ago 23 weeks ago 24 weeks ago 25 weeks ago 26 weeks ago 27 weeks ago 28 weeks ago 29 weeks ago 30 weeks ago 31 weeks ago 32 weeks ago 33 weeks ago 34 weeks ago 35 weeks ago 36 weeks ago 37 weeks ago 38 weeks ago 39 weeks ago 40 weeks ago 41 weeks ago 42 weeks ago 43 weeks ago 44 weeks ago 45 weeks ago 46 weeks ago 47 weeks ago 48 weeks ago 49 weeks ago 50 weeks ago 51 weeks ago 52 weeks ago All since selected week Selected week only 
 Enhanced Profiles
 Has been claimed by a co. representative Has Twitter Has Facebook 
Company Revenue
 Less than $500,000 $500K → $1M $1M → $2.5M $2.5M → $5M $5M → $10M $10M → $20M $20M → $50M $50M → $100M $100M → $500M $500M → $1B More than $1Billion 
Number of Employees
 1 → 4 5 → 9 10 → 19 20 → 49 50 → 99 100 → 249 250 → 499 500 → 999 1,000 → 4,999 5,000 → 9,999 More than 10,000 
Ownership
 Public Companies Private Companies 
Location Type
 Headquarters (HQ) Branch Single Location   Recently Updated These Restaurants&amp;Bars have updated their profiles in Hawaii. Add your company now. 
 
 
 Puka Dog Hawaiian Style Hot Dogs 

Koloa, HI

Updated 7/11/2012
 
 
 
 Kua Aina Sandwich Shop 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 7/10/2012
 
 
 
 Mau Loa Coffee&amp;Deli 

Hilo, HI

Updated 6/29/2012
 
 
 
 La Tour Cafe- Downtown 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 6/28/2012
 
 
 
 Ala Moana Hotel 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 6/28/2012
 
 
 
 1132 Cafe&amp;Catering 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 6/26/2012
 
 
 
 Menehune Coffee Company 

Kailua Kona, HI

Updated 6/21/2012
 
 
 
 Kahale&apos;s Beach Club 

Kihei, HI

Updated 5/31/2012
 
 
 
 Ka Hoku&apos;ao Coffee ltd 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 5/16/2012
 
 
 
 Hula Dog Hawaiian Style Hot Dogs 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 5/8/2012
 
 
 
 Gyotaku Japenese Restaurant 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 5/5/2012
 
 
 
 House of Noodles 

Kapaa, HI

Updated 4/30/2012
 
 
 
 Cajun Gator 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 4/22/2012
 
 
 
 Aloha Deli Ice Cream&amp;Shave Ice 

Kamuela, HI

Updated 4/19/2012
 
 
 
 Splashers Grill 

Kailua Kona, HI

Updated 4/18/2012
 
 
 
 Ahualoa Farms 

Honokaa, HI

Updated 4/16/2012
 
 
 
 HIga Food Service 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 4/16/2012
 
 
 
 Kruger of Hawaii, Inc 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 4/5/2012
 
 
 
 South Pacific Distributors 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 4/1/2012
 
 
 
 Tea At 1024 

Honolulu, HI

Updated 3/22/2012
 
 
 See all claimed profiles in Hawaii Companies by Location: Hawaii Business Topics 
 Small Business Sales Expertise Human Resources Marketing Franchise Technology 
 Browse Companies 
 U.S. Australia Canada UK Worldwide 
 Resources 
 Videos Jobs White Papers Site Map 
 Manta Links 
 About Manta Contact Manta Manta Careers Media Resources FAQ Advertise With Us 
 Copyright©Manta Media Inc. All rights reserved 
 Note: Our Privacy Policy and Terms&amp;Conditions have changed 6/1/12 
 Blog Twitter Facebook Manta News
	</body>
</document>
