<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007329" url="http://www.hillbillyhousewife.com/frugal-breakfast-foods.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:18" support="9" score="0.023386532806800964" bingtitle="Frugal Breakfast Foods | Hillbilly Housewife" webtitle="Frugal Breakfast Foods | Hillbilly Housewife">
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001132" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>Everyone can grab a cup on the way out the door. ... for skipping breakfast or swinging into the fast food restaurant ... I heat them in the microwave and rewrap to take in the car.</description>
	<body>
		Hillbilly Housewife 

Low Cost Home Cooking From Scratch
 
 Home Recipes Articles Newsletter Ebooks HBHW On Twitter 
 
 Articles 
 Canning Cooking Frugal Living Gardening Gluten Free Living Holidays Living Well Making Money At Home Organized Home Shopping 
 Frugal Tips I&apos;m Looking For Requests Recipes 
 Appetizers Bath and Body Beans, Peas&amp;Lentils Beverages Bread&amp;Grain Recipes 
 Bread Machine Breads Corn and Cornmeal Freezer Muffins Oat and Barley Rice Whole Wheat 
 Breakfast Canning Casseroles Convenience Foods 
 Florescent Foods Pasta and Pizza Savory Sauces, Gravy and Condiments 
 Crockpot Dairy&amp;Eggs 
 Egg and Cheese Recipes Fats Powdered Milk 
 Desserts&amp;Sweets 
 Cake and Frosting Cookies, Candy and Bars Homemade Ice Cream Pies, Cobblers and Crisps Pudding, Gelatin, Sweet Sauces and Spreads 
 Fruits and Vegetables 
 Fruit Potato Vegetables 
 Gluten Free Recipes Holiday Recipes Holidays Laundry and Cleaning Recipes Light and Healthy Meat, Poultry,&amp;Fish 
 Beef, Pork, Ham and Lamb Recipes Chicken Fish Ground Beef and Ground Turkey Turkey 
 Pet Food Recipes Quinoa Salad Snack Recipes Snacks 
 Sandwich 
 Soup and Stew Recipes Soy&amp;Other Proteins 
 Non-Dairy Soy, Tofu and TVP 
 Video Recipes Wild Game 
 Uncategorized 
 You are here: Home / Articles / Cooking / Frugal Breakfast Foods 
Frugal Breakfast Foods
 

 
If you are a regular on the site, you already know that some of my favorite frugal breakfast items are homemade muffins and oatmeal. Pricewise almost nothing can beat either one of them, but if you are looking for a little more variety for that all-important first meal of the day, try some of these ideas instead. They are a much more economical option that hitting the drive-through of your favorite fast-food place but still give you some of that same taste (just better of course because it’s homemade.

1. Have a piece of casserole. It takes time to cook eggs and bacon for breakfast. No one wants to ruin their clothes with the mess it can create. On Sunday night, get breakfast done early. Put together a casserole using your favorite ingredients. Fewer eggs are needed in a casserole than when frying or scrambling them for breakfast each morning. Depending on the size of your family, the casserole may last two to three mornings.

2. Yogurt. Yogurt is a healthy and economical breakfast choice. When you are eating on the run, grab a container of yogurt and some dried or fresh fruit. Cutting up fruit on top of the yogurt adds carbohydrates to fuel you for the morning in addition to the calcium and protein in the yogurt itself.

3. Breakfast shake. This is even quicker and can be ingested while driving without taking your eyes off the road or both hands off the wheel. Put together some frozen fruit favorites, ice cubes, frozen yogurt, and unsweetened juice in a blender. Pour into Styrofoam cups to keep it cold. Everyone can grab a cup on the way out the door. The nutritional effect is about the same as yogurt, but without the spoon.

4. Pigs in a blanket. This is the homemade version. Whip up a batch of pancakes and freeze them in short stacks of three. A package or two of frozen link sausage is needed to create this quick and economical meal idea. Thaw out a stack of pancakes. Heat up three sausages in the microwave. Wrap a pancake around each sausage. Voila! Youï¿½ve got an instant pig in a blanket. Eat it as you watch the last of your favorite morning show or as you walk to the bus stop. It can be eaten in the car without too much fuss or mess. For a sweeter taste and less mess, add a little maple syrup or honey to the batter when making the pancakes.

5. Breakfast sandwiches. In the evening, while you are getting things ready for the next day, grill up a few breakfast sandwiches. Choose whatever you like: turkey slices, ham slices, cheese, tomato, bacon, etc. When the sandwich cools, cut it into bite size pieces and put it in a container. In the morning, just grab a container; pop it into the microwave for fifteen or twenty seconds and breakfast is served.

These breakfast ideas are time saving and money-saving too. They make use of items you buy normally and also whatever you have around the house to create delicious fare for a morning rush. No more excuses for skipping breakfast or swinging into the fast food restaurant every morning.
 Share From The Hillbilly Housewife: Christmas In July Ebook Sale 50% Off 
 




We&apos;re battling the heat with a HUGE Christmas in July Sale. Get any HBHW Ebook for 50% off using coupon code &quot;JULY50&quot;. 
Got an ebook you&apos;ve been eying for a while? Now is the time to grab it, because this special 50% Off Sale is only good through the end of JULY! Filed Under: Cooking Tagged With: frugal breakfast foods , frugal breakfast recipes 
Comments

 Wendy says: September 30, 2009 at 11:30 pm 
My mother used to make Malt O Meal or Cream of Wheat according to the recipe on the box. She’d put it in a tupperware cup pour about a 1/2 c or so of milk on the top then stirred with a spoon. We’d each get one as we walked out the door on a winter morning to catch the bus. The bonus is the cup was never too hot so it didn’t burn the hands, but it definately made a great“warmer”for the hands while waiting out in the freezing weather! Another version we had before the Choc O Meal came out was putting in a heaping teaspoon of Nestle Quick before stiring in the milk. It made a great filling“breakfast drink”, certainly less expensive than the soupy cold instant breakfast, and has more nutrients. As an adult, I still take this with me for that winter commute. It’s better for you than a large cup of coffee too.
 Reply Sunny says: March 11, 2010 at 2:56 pm 
Toast two slices of whole wheat bread. Lay slices on a big plate separately open-face sandwich style. Spread some healthier version peanut butter on each slice. Top each slice with a spoonful of natural sugar free applesauce&amp;spread it around a little.
Or instead of applesauce try sliced bananas on top.
Fast, cheap, healthy, filling, yummy, and kid-friendly!
 Reply Shan says: September 16, 2010 at 6:17 pm 
When I was in college, I used to buy the Pepperidge Farm bread (very-thinly-sliced sandwich bread—you could do this with homemade bread if you can slice it thinly enough) and put two slices with a slice of American cheese between them in the toaster, for a quick grilled-cheese sandwich on my way out the door to class. Yum!
 Reply Amy says: September 24, 2010 at 10:30 am 
I make homemade bread, slice it up and make french toast out of it. Then, I cut each piece into strips and freeze. When you need a quick breakfast, pop some in the microwave and you have french toast sticks! Just like the ones you get in the Burger King drive thru(but healthier)!
 Reply Ashley says: November 23, 2010 at 10:31 pm 
On a day I am not busy I make up double batches of muffins, chocolate chip oatmeal scones, mini loaves of banana bread, or some other quick bread. I always use soy flour, wheat germ, nuts, or something else to up the protein value. I individually wrap them in plastic wrap when cool. Put them in a ziplock bag (or cover in tinfoil if mini loaves) and freeze. In the morning I pop them in the microwave for 25-30 seconds. They are moist and warm as if I just popped them out of the oven. The mini loaves take a bit longer, but they have the advantage of feeding a couple people. This is also an easy way to have breads for a meal or a coffee break ready to go.
 Reply dorothy says: November 24, 2010 at 1:48 pm 
Having to watch my carbohydrates I buy the low-carb tortillas (the ones with 12 grams of fiber in them) and fill them with scrambled eggs to which I’ve added a little cheese and sometimes turkey pepperoni, roll them burrito style, wrap and freeze. They’re great for an on-the-run breakfast. I heat them in the microwave and rewrap to take in the car.
 Reply 
 
Speak Your Mind Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search This Site
 
Categories

 Angel Food Menus 
 Angel Food Recipe 
 Articles 
 Canning Cooking Frugal Living Gardening Gluten Free Living Holidays Living Well Making Money At Home Organized Home Shopping 
 Frugal Tips HBHW Newsletter Archive 
 Newsletters 
 I&apos;m Looking For Requests Recipes 
 Appetizers Bath and Body Beans, Peas&amp;Lentils Beverages Bread&amp;Grain Recipes 
 Bread Machine Breads Corn and Cornmeal Freezer Muffins Oat and Barley Rice Whole Wheat 
 Breakfast Canning Casseroles Convenience Foods 
 Florescent Foods Pasta and Pizza Savory Sauces, Gravy and Condiments 
 Crockpot Dairy&amp;Eggs 
 Egg and Cheese Recipes Fats Powdered Milk 
 Desserts&amp;Sweets 
 Cake and Frosting Cookies, Candy and Bars Homemade Ice Cream Pies, Cobblers and Crisps Pudding, Gelatin, Sweet Sauces and Spreads 
 Fruits and Vegetables 
 Fruit Potato Vegetables 
 Gluten Free Recipes Holiday Recipes Holidays Laundry and Cleaning Recipes Light and Healthy Meat, Poultry,&amp;Fish 
 Beef, Pork, Ham and Lamb Recipes Chicken Fish Ground Beef and Ground Turkey Turkey 
 Pet Food Recipes Quinoa Salad Snack Recipes Snacks 
 Sandwich 
 Soup and Stew Recipes Soy&amp;Other Proteins 
 Non-Dairy Soy, Tofu and TVP 
 Video Recipes Wild Game 
 Uncategorized 
 
 Home - Contact - I&apos;m Looking For Requests - Submit A Frugal Recipe - Submit A Frugal Tip 
 
Copyright©2012 HillbillyHousewife.com
	</body>
</document>
