<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007180" url="http://shanghaiscrap.com/category/food-and-meals/" time="2012-07-13-00:09" support="1" score="0.0011917533086481602" bingtitle="Shanghai Scrap » food and meals" webtitle="Shanghai Scrapfood and meals">
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>... on The Atlantic’s website: [Alice Waters] put ... is very much the case that several American fast food restaurant ... someone not been caught using a victim’s credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Shanghai Scrap 

Observations on Asia and the world by Adam Minter, an American writer in Shanghai.
 
 Other China correspondents write about politics; I write about carp. 
 Filed under: food and meals , sports —posted by Adam on March 17, 2012 @ 3:21 am 
It is not lost upon me that this week saw perhaps the biggest political story to emerge from China in two decades . Thus, it only seemed right that my Bloomberg World View column this week would focus on how Chinese netizens feel about the Asian Carp that are rampaging up the Mississippi, into the Great Lakes . I know, I know–how can you write about Asian carp when Bo Xilai is being relieved of his duties in Chongqing? And the answer, dear readers, is two-fold: a) sometimes these columns are turned in before breaking news, and b) I believe that most readers outside of China are more interested in rampaging Asian carp than Bo Xilai . I realize that’s a debatable, somewhat hard to swallow point for many of my China readers, but I stand by it. In any case,  I invite you to debate this and more in the comments to Chinese Fish for Meaning in US Carp Rampage .
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (2) 
 
 Rich Gluttons Hold Extravagant Meal at US Embassy, Beijing, Congratulate Selves for Promoting Healthy Eating in China. 
 Filed under: food and meals , health , Uncategorized —posted by Adam on November 27, 2011 @ 12:14 pm 
Bear with me, for a moment, as you read a passage from a dispatch now available on The Atlantic’s website :

[ Alice Waters ] put me to work beside her, cutting grilled slices of locally Beijing-made sourdough bread (from a bakery with the jaunty name Boulangerie Nanda) already soaked in olive oil from the McEvoy Ranch, in Petaluma, California; the oil, along with five donated Californian wines, was the only American ingredients used. I spread the bread with a crumbly, nicely cheesy handmade ricotta made by Liu Yang–a Beijing native who spent six years in France making cheese before moving back and starting a business he calls Le Fromager de Pekin–and drizzled more oil on top. And I broke into bite-sized chunks a Parmesan-like gouda made by Marc De Ruiter, a Dutch cheese maker in Shanxi, for his Yellow Valley cheese company (he recently closed it, unable to afford the expensive milk-testing equipment the government told him he must buy).

This is not, despite every indication, the account of a novelty dinner held at Waters’famous, and famously expensive Chez Panisse restaurant in Berkeley, California, but rather the truthful account of a meal recently held at, and partly sponsored by, the US Embassy in Beijing , ostensibly to“build awareness of organic food being grown by Chinese farmers for Chinese food.”

 

No doubt, that is a laudable goal. As someone who has been eating in China for nearly a decade, I’m quite aware–indeed, probably more aware than most of the organizers– of the food scandals that have plagued China for years . But I am also aware that food inflation is a serious quality-of-life issue ( and sometimes, a life issue) for hundreds of millions of Chinese , and thus I have no doubt that the visit of a wealthy Western chef promoting more expensive food is more likely to be ignored by, rather than improve, contemporary China. Alas, the effect of food inflation on a developing nation, it seems, was of little concern to Waters or the organizers of the event (I’m looking at you, US Embassy staff), who apparently couldn’t see past their own stomachs, to notice the needs of the Chinese stomachs just past the embassy gates. Writing of the fine cheese served at the event, the Atlantic’s correspondent, Corby Kummer , made it clear–and without irony!–that this event was first and foremost an opportunity to satisfy Western appetites (according to the Wall Street Journal, less than 1/3 of the attendees were Chinese ):

Cheese is a great rarity in lactose-intolerant China, and many of the guests wanted to know where they could find it.

I’m sure they did.

There is much low-hanging fruit to shoot here (the image of Waters, and her well-known eco-grounded belief in locally-sourced produce, jetting over to Beijing with her staff and bottles of olive oil to cook a feast that is both unaffordable and unappetizing to 99.9% of China, is but one). But what really troubles me about this dinner is the lack of introspection that led the organizers, Waters, and the correspondent to believe that, via their own gluttony ( and visits to expensive organic farms ), they are somehow promoting healthy eating in China.

They’re not. (more…) 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (25) 
 
 Instant (Noodle) Inflation 
 Filed under: Business in China , food and meals —posted by Adam on January 16, 2011 @ 10:45 pm 
 How hot is inflation running in China ? Fast enough that store clerks at my local convenience store don’t bother to replace the computer-generated price tags for instant noodles at a nearby convenience store. They just cross them out and write in the new (substantially higher) ones. Below, three impromptu price hikes on three well-known brands of instant noodles–low, medium, and“premium”priced.

 

 

 

[ UPDATE: Though the size of the increase is obvious, the value - for those outside of China - is not. So, for you folks, keep in mind that the conversion rate this morning is US$1 = RMB 6.61. And that means the value of the cheapest brand, up top, has gone from US$.41, to US$.45. The rest of the math, dear reader, is up to you.]

For those outside of China, you may be asking: why instant noodles?

Well. I once had an argument with a friend from Beijing about what, truly, is China’s modern staple food: the instant noodle, or the bowl of rice. We couldn’t come to agreement on that question, though we did, in time, agree that the disposable paper instant noodle bowl is a far more apt symbol of Chinese job security in the 21st century, than the iron rice bowl of Mao’s day (ie, today’s modern Chinese job seeker wants a disposable instant noodle bowl to sustain his/her family until the next disposable instant noodle bowl[®]). Point being: Chinese people eat lots of instant noodles, and thus the Party has long taken a keen interest in keeping the price of instant noodles stable. Thus, in 2007, in a country where price-fixing is as common as instant noodles, and mostly tolerated, the powerful National Development and Reform Commission went after instant noodle manufactures for, yes, price fixing ( an excellent WSJ report on that episode here ). Chinese inflation was running hot in 2007, and it’s running even hotter now and, as a result, it’s time to smack around the instant noodle makers again. This time, though, it’s the retailers doing the smacking: French hypermarket operator Carrefour is in the midst of a stare down with the Mainland’s most popular instant noodle manufacturer over price hikes due to rising raw material costs .

For more on rising wages among people who actually work with raw materials (and, presumably, eat instant noodles), see this recent Shanghai Scrap post .
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (4) 
 
 Conspicuous Consumption, Ningbo Edition: the Case of the Gold Dust Dumpling 
 Filed under: food and meals —posted by Adam on November 12, 2010 @ 12:04 pm 
The price of gold is currently hovering around a record US$1400/oz , leaving the sensible investor with, as I count them, three options:

 Buy it. Run from it. Eat it. 

Per the last option, I direct my readers to the Shang Palace Restaurant at the Shangri-la Hotel in Ningbo, China where, per chef’s instructions I suppose, shrimp dumplings are served with a light garnishment of 24k gold leaf.

 

Now, I may be a rube, but I’m no simpleton, and so I’m well-aware that edible gold leaf has been used to decorate desserts and cocktails for years, now . But adding gold leaf to dumplings strikes me as something a little different. Desserts and cocktails, after all, are already luxury edibles, whereas dumplings–shrimp or not–are staples of sorts. Seven floors down and around the corner from my Shanghai apartment dumplings like those above (minus the gold leaf) are available for RMB 20 (US$3) for 12 (given, pricey by China standards). In American terms we’re talking the relative equivalent of sprinkling a mushroom cheeseburger with 24k gold leaf (though I guess it wouldn’t surprise me if somebody was doing that before the housing bubble burst). [ UPDATE! In fact, they were: in comment six, below, my friend Karen McGrane points me to proof that at least one New York chef was serving a mushroom cheeseburger sprinkled with gold leaf around the time of the housing crash .]

If I were an Old Testament prophet, a Calvinist, or a New York Times columnist (“when the revolution comes…”), I’d have more to say about this. But I’m not, so I’ll end this post by pointing to a delightful 2005 Q&amp;A regarding edible gold that ran in the Washington Post . Worth a read.

[ End note : I was a guest at the meal at which those dumplings were served, and didn&apos;t have a chance to learn their cost. Still, I must admit, the commodities reporter in me was tempted to scrape the gold off mine, and into an envelope, in anticipation of US$1500/oz. ]

 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (9) 
 
 In praise of the English spoken at Chinese McDonald’s outlets. 
 Filed under: Appreciations and Recommendations , food and meals —posted by Adam on October 6, 2010 @ 5:48 am 
In case you’ve never had the experience, here’s what it’s like to walk into a Chinese McDonald’s and have the cashier assume–on the basis of your looks–that you’re not Chinese: You are greeted in English, and then handed a bi-lingual English-Chinese menu (typically kept beside the register). More likely than not, though, you won’t need to point at the pictures or the English/Chinese menu items, because, typically, the cashier has enough English to understand when you’re ordering a McChicken, a small fries, and a large Coke. In fact, in my experience at least, many Chinese McDonald’s cashiers are eager to brush aside my attempts at Chinese so as to prove that they can speak English.

This is a rather remarkable phenomenon when you think about it. After all, how many other places in the non-English speaking world, much less the non-English speaking developing world, have the luxury of being able to stash English-language speakers behind the counter at McDonald’s? Not many. Indeed, in my travels, I’ve found that English or other foreign language training is reserved for the“educated”-ie, those not destined for McDonald’s. But China, which requires English language study by all of its students (of varying quality, of course), has English-language McDonald’s cashiers aplenty–supplementing its considerable and impressive ranks of English-language service workers elsewhere in the economy.

It’s something that I’ve noticed over the last few weeks, as I traveled to several developing, and developed nations (and their respective McDonald’s restaurants–a story for another time), not one of which struck me as being as English-language friendly as China. For example, consider this Brazilian McDonald’s, visited this past weekend at a hypermart in São Paulo.

 

Signage aside, there was no bilingual menu, no eager English-speaking cashier. Instead, I found myself pointing at the pictures on the overhead menu, and miming the act of carrying a bag so that the cashier would know that I wanted my Salada to go. And, by and large, that’s the experience I had, two weeks ago, at a McDonald’s in the Ukraine (trust me: order the McBlintzes), where–in addition to my own troubles–I watched an American basketball player (mind you, a professional in the Ukraine) convey his order through an accompanying team assistant because the cashiers simply couldn’t get his meaning.

Now, before anyone misunderstand my meaning: I’m not advocating for English-language imperialism, or for Americans (like me) to remain linguistically oblivious when they travel abroad. Rather, I merely want to point out that–for the most part–it’s much easier for an English speaker to travel in China, than it is to travel in Japan (for starters: far more English in Chinese subway stations than Japanese ones), the Ukraine (try to find an English-language immigration officer at Lviv’s“int’l”airport), Brazil (see above), or any number of countries that are culturally, geographically, and politically closer to the Anglo-American axis. (more…) 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (13) 
 
 Shanghai Scrap’s Simple Guide to Expo 2010: Go After Dark. 
 Filed under: Appreciations and Recommendations , Expo 2010 , food and meals —posted by Adam on May 6, 2010 @ 11:34 pm 
Early yesterday afternoon I found my way down to the Expo 2010 (World’s Fair) site for what was supposed to be a ninety-minute visit, at most. But when I arrived the grounds were so empty (under 100,000 visitors yesterday), and the weather was so good, that I found myself spending the remainder of the day, into the night, down there with a friend whom I texted on the spur of the moment (“Nobody’s here. You should come down.”). Below, the view of the UK pavilion and, in the background, the Lupu Bridge, as viewed from the Dutch pavilion (Happy Street) around 8:30 PM.

 

It’s a gorgeous view, and what’s best about it is that–despite all of the reports about lines and waits (yes, at Shanghai Scrap, too )–there wasn’t any waiting at all. We just walked into Happy Street, just as we walked into every other pavilion but the UK and German ones (30–60 minute waits at both). It was a good antidote to all of the negativity that’s been swirling around Expo since the first day of the soft opening.  For an evening, at least, you could see that the Expo is an interesting and fun place to go (I try to get at the fun in this recent interview with China Beat )–especially in the dark, when the crowds mostly disappear.

And the night-time benefits go beyond just being able to walk into pretty much any pavilion whenever you like. Restaurants are empty. Entire squares are empty. Best of all, the grounds are filled with terrific performances. Last night, alone, I came across a wonderful jazz-funk outfit from Italy; street performers from Prague; a boy’s choir from South Africa; chamber music from Austria; some kind of wicked wild percussion thing (not sure what that was) in the square in front of the Pacific pavilion; a folk ensemble from Romania; and some skinny, hairy Danish dudes rocking out with toy-store keyboards in front of the Little Mermaid at the Denmark pavilion. Why the Expo organizers aren’t doing more to promote all of these great performances in the face of so much negative publicity about long lines, I’ll never understand. But whatever–take it from your friendly Scrap blogger and go to Expo after dark. It’s great.

A couple of additional notes on visiting the site… (more…) 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (15) 
 
 Time out from Expo 2010 for some Cuttlefish Cheese Bread 
 Filed under: Expo 2010 , food and meals , Weird China —posted by Adam on April 29, 2010 @ 11:37 am 
We’re going to briefly interrupt Shanghai Scrap’s non-stop Expo 2010 coverage to announce that–based upon what we just had for breakfast–Starbucks is doomed. For those who don’t follow the venerable coffee company, it’s been faltering for several years now, largely due to over-expansion into questionable markets in the US (though that appears to have been reversed in the last quarter). The only bright spot has been China, where the company operates 376 stores and–according to CEO Howard Schultz–it has plans to open thousands more. It won’t be easy, though, as he readily acknowledged last week : “[I]t’s a complicated market that requires significant discipline and thoughtfulness.” Exhibit #1 in the lack of discipline and thoughtfulness category: Cuttlefish Cheese Bread, now available at the Starbucks up my street. Click the photos to enlarge.

 

 

 

In case the photo doesn’t make it clear: the bread is blue.

Now it is very much the case that several American fast food restaurant chains have done well in China by localizing their menus ( KFC being the undisputed champion in that category ). But this isn’t localization; this is just someone saying,“We like bread and cheese; Chinese people like cuttlefish. So…cuttlefish cheese bread! We’ll make a fortune!”Given, that would be the case if there was anything remotely appetizing about cuttlefish cheese bread. Or, as my friend Jarret Wrisley (regular contributor to the Atlantic’s Food Channel , and soon-to-be Bangkok restaurateur ) tweeted earlier:“ Squid Ink? Cheese? Coffee? Yuck. ”Short the stock.

[And briefly: Starbucks, don&apos;t think I didn&apos;t notice the profiteering going on in your Expo outlets. Prices are, on average, 10% - 15% higher than in the city. But worse - and this really gets me - the Expo outlets have eliminated all sizes but Grande, forcing customers to up-size or leave. I actually found myself in an argument over this with an Expo barrista (first and last time that term is used on Shanghai Scrap) who insisted that I was being cheap, and that the prices are the same. Uh-huh.]
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (10) 
 
 Fair&amp;Balanced: Inside the South Korean Pavilion (my own Korean crisis) 
 Filed under: buildings , Expo 2010 , food and meals , Media —posted by Adam on April 28, 2010 @ 11:42 pm 
Last week I posted several photos of the North Korean Expo 2010 pavilion to some mild interest from the North Korean aficionado community (oh yes there is), worldwide. At the time, I must admit, it didn’t occur to me to post images of the South Korean pavilion because–from the perspective of a US citizen–the North Koreans are just so much more interesting. That, and the South Korean pavilion–unlike the North Korean one–wasn’t open during the soft opening. Apparently, this did not go without notice, and so–while life was continuing apace for everyone else–I received a deluge (okay, six) emails asking me why I didn’t give equal time to the Free South (with three coming–suspiciously!–in the last 90 minutes). Fair enough: below, an image taken of a musical rehearsal (in the background) in the South Korean pavilion during the soft opening, earlier this week.

 

Again, I would’ve posted more and better, but the pavilion wasn’t open to visitors during the soft opening. Still, this image should offer some sense of the exquisite beauty that is the South Korean pavilion. And, at that, I’m going to pass out from Expo fatigue. Meatier material, tomorrow.

[Oh, and warm Shanghai greetings to the Beijing press corps which, over the last 48 hours has swelled the ranks of media in Shanghai by ten-fold, at least. For the record: we know you&apos;ve arrived with heavy bags - and expense accounts. See you for dinner.]
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 Comments Off 
 
 “We got yer pizza…”American cuisine well-represented at Expo 2010. 
 Filed under: buildings , Expo 2010 , Expo 2010 - US Pavilion , food and meals —posted by Adam on April 23, 2010 @ 8:12 am 
Another observation from my day-long visit to the Expo 2010 (World’s Fair) soft opening : if you like American fast food, you’re in luck. KFC. Papa John’s. Burger King. Mister Donut. Starbucks (let’s call a spade a spade, shall we?). They’re all there. And so are some of the usual Chinese suspects , too. Makes sense, of course. After all, who’s up for fine dining after spending three hours in line to see a five-minute promotional clip about the wonders of–I dunno– Andorran tourism ? And so it should surprise nobody at all–not even me–that the USA’s Expo 2010 pavilion offers its visitors the following meal choices (click to enlarge–please):

 

Not exactly something for everyone, but certainly something for anyone who doesn’t feel like walking over to the nearby Papa John’s or Burger King. At an optimistic minimum, the menu should provide a good lesson in the forces (forces like USA pavilion sponsor Yum, Inc. , owner and pusher of KFC and Pizza Hut) that Michelle Obama has to overcome in her high-profile campaign against childhood obesity . Presumably, if and when she and the kids visit, they’ll pack a picnic .
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (13) 
 
 Something I ate… 
 Filed under: food and meals —posted by Adam on January 7, 2010 @ 9:50 am 
A friend just emailed to remind me that I once promised my readers that I would never again post three consecutive Expo-related items to this blog . Here at Shanghai Scrap, we keep our word! And though the next Expo-related post isn’t yet ready to be pushed out the door, I thought I’d better offer my reassurance to any and all who thought that I might be on the verge of the dreaded Expo hat-trick. Also, I’m a little tied-up with other projects at the moment.

 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (2) 
 
 The Dark, Totalitarian Hand of Häägen Däzs [UPDATED! With photo! Even more totalitarian!] 
 Filed under: food and meals , religion —posted by Adam on December 22, 2009 @ 10:56 am 
If you follow my tweets , you already know about this. But if not, well, here’s the deal. Yesterday, for reasons that I’ll explain in coming days, I stopped into a local Häägen Däzs. While there, I decided to take a photo of the store’s large Christmas tree. As I did so, I was gang-rushed by a rabid employee who succeeded in blocking my shot. Below, the photographic evidence.

 

I was asked to leave, and when I argued the point, I was pushed out.

Now, I don’t want to make more of this than really should be made of it. But, I can’t help myself and note that during the several years I’ve covered religion in contemporary China, I’ve never once been gang-rushed out of a church, mosque, or temple for taking a photo. And that raises a question: just what kind of jack-booted thugs have been hired to train/traumatize the beleaguered ice cream workers of Häägen Däzs? Thankfully, I don’t have to worry about it: there’s a Dairy Queen just up the street, and they didn’t argue when I took a picture of their Christmas tree. Let the boycott begin.

[ UPDATED 12/24 - Since posting this item, I&apos;ve heard from three people who have been prevented from taking photos in Häägen Däzs by company employees. In all three cases (and the one mentioned in comment #4 below), the individuals were taking photos of friends and family - not Christmas trees. So, on this basis, it appears that Häägen Däzs has a &quot;no photo&quot; policy, and I suspect - in agreement with a couple of the comments below - that they are inordinately concerned about their intellectual property, so much so that they make themselves less appealing to customers.]

[ SECOND 12/24 UPDATED : A friend just reminded me of a July 2005 Häägen Däzs in China story that I did. You can read it here , but the relevant fact–for the purpose of this post–is that a Häägen Däzs employee tried to prevent me from taking a photo of a Shanghai store’s exterior . Don’t believe me? Then click the June 23, 2005 image, below, to see the masked ice cream man come chasing out of the store, hands waving. Just what kind of paranoid dictatorship is at work inside that high-end ice cream empire?

 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (10) 
 
 Seoul 
 Filed under: food and meals , travel —posted by Adam on December 3, 2009 @ 7:28 pm 
For the next day or so I’m lost in a sea of acronyms, terrific street food, and unexpected good fortune. Posting resumes on the weekend, I believe.

 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 Comments Off 
 
 Happy Thanksgiving (on hiatus’til November 30) 
 Filed under: Appreciations and Recommendations , food and meals —posted by Adam on November 23, 2009 @ 11:47 pm 
In observance of the Thanksgiving Day holiday, Shanghai Scrap will be on hiatus until November 30. Except that, on Thursday, we’ll make a point of posting an image of what our Shanghainese Thanksgiving dinner looked like (though it won’t be Shanghainese food).

 

And since it’s Thanksgiving…sincere thanks to the ever-growing number of people who stop by, subscribe, and comment on my blog. I really appreciate the interest, and I’ll continue to do my best to earn it.

[In addition to giving thanks on Thanksgiving, we also watch American football. And among my favorite Shanghai Scrap posts is this one, from October, in which I interview one of NFL China&apos;s play-by-play men . If you&apos;re in China, hankering for a Lions or Cowboys game, this might tide you over a bit.]
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 Comments Off 
 
 “Want some chocolate, handsome?” 
 Filed under: Expat Life , food and meals , Snarkiness —posted by Adam on @ 11:39 pm 
On October 28 the Shanghai Daily ran what now stands as my favorite headline in the history of journalism :

 

The headline isn’t the best part, though. That honor is reserved for the story itself, which goes something like this: last year, the five individuals in the above photo began working as prostitutes in Shanghai. One day, one prostitute noticed that another was taking prescription sedatives for a sleeping disorder. A plot soon emerged:“let’s make some chocolate, lace it with those sedatives, and feed it to clients with the intention of robbing them after they collapse.”A winning concept, for sure (!), that succeeded on at least two occasions, and would have succeeded on a third had someone not been caught using a victim’s credit card at a cosmetics shop. (more…) 
 
 Share this: Share Reddit StumbleUpon Email 
 comments (6) 
 

 next page 
 Shanghai Scrap 
 pages: 
 Contact About Adam Minter Licensing and Permissions 
 Search: 
 
Twitter Updates


 follow me on Twitter Archives:
 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «May       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 Categories:
 air travel Appreciations and Recommendations arts buildings Business Business in China Catholicism Chinese stock crash computing environment Expat Life Expo 2010 Expo 2010–US Pavilion food and meals health Labor Media Minnesota Northwest Airlines Olympics Piracy religion scrap Shanghai History Snarkiness sports Trade travel Uncategorized Universe US China Policy US Politics Weird China 
 linkage:
 
Blogroll

 Bloomberg World View China Law Blog China Media Project China Rhyming chinaSMACK Chinopoly Danwei ESWN Far West China Granite Studio I&apos;m a Fucking Writer Imagethief James Fallows Jen Ambrose JPL Letter from China Megan McArdle Micah Sittig Minnesota Twins Paleofuture Shanghai Shiok! Shanghai Street Stories Shanghaiist The China Beat Urbanatomy 
 
 Meta:
 Log in RSS Comments RSS WP 
 

 Powered by WordPress 
 and the artsemerging theme
 by nathaniel stern 

image: detail of installation by Bronwyn Lace
 Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
