<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007169" url="http://themeparks.about.com/cs/disneyparks/a/WDWbestDining.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:08" support="6" score="0.017513061886631157" bingtitle="Disney World&apos;s Best Restaurants" webtitle="Disney World&apos;s Best Restaurants">
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001018" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>They are listed along with their top pick for the best Walt Disney World restaurant. Robb and Elissa Alvey of Theme Park Review, Les Chefs de France</description>
	<body>
		Travel 
 Theme Parks Search 
 Theme Parks Find Theme Parks Water Parks Roller Coasters 

 Share 
 Free Theme Parks Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 The 10 Best Restaurants at Disney World 

Heading to Disney World? Check Out the Top Dining Spots.

By Arthur Levine , About.com Guide
 See More About: 
 walt disney world florida theme parks epcot theme park dining 
 
Boma–Flavors of Africa at Disney&apos;s Animal Kingdom Lodge, one of the best restaurants at Walt Disney World.
 Walt Disney World. Used with permission. With the opening of Disneyland, Disney radically changed the experience of going to an amusement park. Florida&apos;s vast Walt Disney World upped the ante with multiple parks, hotels, shopping districts, and more, and changed the very notion of what it means to go on a vacation. Many Walt Disney World visitors, however, chow down on the same nondescript fast food typically found at traditional amusement parks. Not that there&apos;s anything wrong with that. But they are missing out on some extraordinary restaurants at the Florida resort and an opportunity to make their vacations more memorable.
Looking for more Disney World tips? Check out the Best Things to Do at Disney World 
There are so many great places to eat, it&apos;s difficult to determine the top 10 best restaurants at Walt Disney World. That&apos;s why I turned to 10 of the most popular and respected travel journalists covering the Florida theme park mecca, including some of my About.com colleagues, for some help. I asked them to provide ten of their favorite Disney table-service restaurants and ten of their top casual dining spots. I then threw their choices into a Cuisinart, poured them through a colander, ranked the results, and developed two top 10 lists.
Whether you&apos;re planning an elegant meal, want to grab a quick bite, or anything in between during your Walt Disney World visit, you&apos;re sure to find restaurants to please your palate as well as your wallet with these top dining spots:
 The Top 10 Best Walt Disney World Table-Service Restaurants - Includes both high-end and more moderately priced restaurants. The Top 10 Best Walt Disney World Casual Restaurants - Includes buffet and counter-service restaurants.

There are dozens of dining choices across Walt Disney World, and our esteemed panel listed a total of 44 different restaurants on their top-10 table-service lists. But there was general consensus on the 10 restaurants that floated to the top.
Bubbling just beneath the surface are a few table-service restaurants that didn&apos;t make the cut but bear mentioning:
 50&apos;s Prime Time Cafe at Disney&apos;s Hollywood Studios. The comfort food is fine, but the real appeal of the highly themed restaurant is the pitch-perfect 50&apos;s ambiance. The cost is moderate ($15 to $35 per adult). Sanaa at Disney&apos;s Animal Kingdom Lodge. The third restaurant at the African-themed hotel, which features exotic African- and Indian-inspired dishes, draws rave reviews. The cost is high ($35 to $60 per adult). Citrico&apos;s at Disney&apos;s Grand Floridian Resort. The inspired Mediterranean fare makes Citrico&apos;s among my favorite Disney World restaurants. The cost is high ($35 to $60 per adult).

Reservations, which are highly recommended for these popular Walt Disney World restaurants, can be made up to six months in advance. Call (407) WDW-DINE (939-3463) to make your dining plans.
 Best Restaurants at Walt Disney World Video 
Have you dined at a Walt Disney World restaurant and had a memorable meal? Share your review with the About.com Theme Parks community and see how other users have reviewed Walt Disney World restaurants.
Many thanks to following panel of travel writers who participated in the best restaurant survey. They are listed along with their top pick for the best Walt Disney World restaurant.
 Robb and Elissa Alvey of Theme Park Review , Les Chefs de France Charlyn Keating Chisholm, About.com&apos;s Hotels and Resorts Guide , California Grill Mike Collins of CoasterRadio.com , San Angel Inn Lance Hart of Screamscape , Nine Dragons Restaurant Dawn Henthorn, About.com&apos;s Florida Travel Guide , Artist Point Theresa Johnston, About.com&apos;s Orlando Guide , Biergarten Restaurant Robert Niles of Theme Park Insider , Les Chefs de France Teresa Plowright, About.com&apos;s Family Vacations Guide , 50&apos;s Prime Time Cafe Matt Roseboom of Orlando Attractions Magazine , Jiko - The Cooking Place Nancy Schretter of Family Travel Network , Boma–Flavors of Africa
 
 Readers Respond: Disney World&apos;s Best Restaurants
 Read responses (12) Share Your Picks 
The Best Walt Disney World Restaurants

 Top 10 Best Walt Disney World Table-Service Restaurants Top 10 Best Walt Disney World Casual Restaurants Best Restaurants at Walt Disney World Video 
 
More Walt Disney World Info

 Reader Reviews of Walt Disney World Restaurants Walt Disney World Overview Best Things to Do at Disney World 
 Related Articles 
 Disney World Tips - Top 10 Disney World Tips Disney World Tips - Top 10 Disney World Tips Best Restaurants at Disney World - California Grill at Disney&apos;s Contemp... Home Run Hot Dog Scores at Disney&apos;s ESPN Club - Reader Review: Walt Dis... Restaurants and buffets at Walt Disney World 
 
 Arthur Levine 
Theme Parks Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Related Searches prime time cafe florida theme park walt disney world travel journalists casual restaurants service restaurants Explore Theme Parks Must Reads 
 What&apos;s New at Theme Parks? Indoor Water Parks Florida Theme Parks and Water Parks California Theme Parks and Water Parks Theme Parks Photo and Video Galleries 
 Most Popular 
 Free Theme Parks Fantasyland Expansion Fastest roller coasters Water Parks in Illinois Water Parks in Ohio 
 See More About: 
 walt disney world florida theme parks epcot theme park dining 
 By Category 
 Find U.S. Theme Parks Find U.S. Water Parks Disney Theme Parks Six Flags Theme Parks Universal Theme Parks Roller Coasters Park Rides and Attractions Planning Park Trips Parks Photos and Videos Theme Park Bests Theme Parks in Canada Theme Parks Beyond the US Themed Casinos, Restaurants Theme Parks Resource Center 
 Theme Parks 
 About.com Travel Theme Parks Theme Park Bests Disney World&apos;s Best Restaurants 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
