<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007183" url="http://foodieshaven.tumblr.com/" time="2012-07-13-00:09" support="2" score="0.001960302219843506" bingtitle="Foodie&apos;s Haven" webtitle="Foodie&apos;s Haven">
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>We were given seats near the exit so ... and I remembered this chicken fast-food restaurant everyone seems to be raving about. The place ... peking duck right beside our table ...</description>
	<body>
		Thank you for your interest!
 
Add free and premium widgets by Addwater Agency to your Tumblelog!
 

 To hide the widget button after installing the theme: 

 Visit your Tumblr blog&apos;s customization page (typically found at http://www.tumblr.com/customize ). Click on Appearance. Click Hide Widget Button. Click on Save+Close. 


For more information visit our How-To&apos;s page. 

Questions? Visit us at tumblr.addwater.com
 [ close this window] 

 
 Home About Feed Me Blogroll Archives Ask Me Anything RSS 
 
 Postings 07 08 2012 
Lugang Cafe: Taiwanese Cuisine @ SM MOA
 
 
A few weeks ago, my family and I had lunch at Lugang Cafe in SM Mall of Asia. It was our first time in that Taiwanese restaurant and even though a nearer branch in Greenhills, San Juan could serve us, we thought the SM MOA branch is much more convenient, parking space-wise. Yeah, the one in GH is always jam-packed! Well now I know why .

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 4 days ago Comments Permalink 
 Chinese Lugang Cafe Pasay SM MOA Taiwanese 4stars 500plus 
 Share 

 06 27 2012 
Swensen’s: Ice Cream Parlor
 
This will be just a quick post (and backlog at that… this was taken last May 26), and not really a restaurant review per se, because I was too preoccupied catching up with my good ol’ college friend to really take notice of the whole Swensen’s branch in SM MOA. Forgive me, yeah? :)

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 2 weeks ago Comments Permalink 
 ice cream desserts sweets pasay SM MOA Mall of Asia 5stars 100plus 
 Share 

 06 24 2012 
Pastry Princess: Cupcakes Overload!
 
 

 Warning: Cupcakes overload ! On a side note, I miss Caroline and Max from the TV show 2 Broke Girls !!! My love affair for cupcakes grew because of that show. Can’t wait for season 2 already! Heehee! :)

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 2 weeks ago Comments Permalink 
 Quezon City cupcakes desserts greenhills towncenter pastry sweets 4stars 50plus 
 Share 

 06 09 2012 
Gravy Fix: Affordable Chicken Meal
 
My friends and I met up a few weeks ago and had lunch at Gravy Fix , found along Katipunan Avenue. All of us had one order each of Southern Fried Chicken (Php 120) as it was said to be one of their bestsellers. At a very affordable price, you get to have a 3-pc chicken meal (plain rice and mixed vegetables included) and it comes with iced tea. The chicken was tender and generally okay… but definitely no Bon Chon magic in the works here. It was simply just fried, not double fried chicken.

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments 1 note Permalink 
 100plus Quezon City katipunan 3stars 
 Share 

 06 04 2012 
Nanette’s Snack Haus Revisited
 
It was fun reliving some childhood dining places I’ve been to and one of those is Nanette’s Snack Haus along Maginhawa Street. Yes, that famous street along Diliman, Quezon City that is home to Crazy Katsu, Gayuma ni Maria, Van Gough is Bipolar, among others. Would you believe I used to live and grew up just parallel to this street??? Too bad that it was just in the recent years that this place was developed and became the food haven that it is today! Sayang, kung kailan wala na ako doon ! HAHAHA :)

Anyway, I’m glad (and actually surprised) that Nanette’s Snack Haus is still there when I passed by a few weeks ago. Never mind that it looked old and out of place now that many restaurants are around the area. For me, it is still the same way as I remember it!

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 maginhawa street filipino 100plus Quezon City 5stars 
 Share 

 05 31 2012 
Nice Mart: Korean Grocery&amp;Convenience Store
 
A few weeks ago, I happened to be along Kalayaan Ave. after running errands around the area. And this Korean Grocery&amp;Convenience Store called Nice Mart caught my attention so, I stopped by and entered. I was also hoping there would be Korean icecreams in there ‘cause it was frikkin’ hot that day. And boy did I find not just icecream… but other Korean goodies as well! It was the first legit Korean grocery I’ve ever been to so pardon me if I sound so giddy and excited. I seem to have this Korean food craze going on ‘cause of the cooking show Kimchi Chronicles (good show btw!). Anyway, here are some of the photos I took. :)

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments 1 note Permalink 
 convenience store grocery store korean kimbap quezon city 
 Share 

 05 28 2012 
Army Navy: Burger + Burrito
 
 Although Army Navy is quite known for its Burger and Burrito, I ordered neither on my recent trip to this American-Mexican fastfood restaurant. I was craving for something light and Mexican in flavor for an afternoon snack… so the Cheese Quesadilla (Php 105) won over the two.

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 100plus 4stars mexican american quesadilla Quezon City 
 Share 

 05 26 2012 
World Class Persian Kabab (Ya Imam Zaman)
 
 First off, I do not know if “Ya Imam Zaman” is the actual name of the restaurant and “World Class Persian Kabab” is just a description under the name. But anyhow, most people call it by World Class Persian Kabab, so World Class Persian Kabab it is!!! This branch along Santolan St., Corner Granada St. in Quezon City seems understated at first glance and I thought only people who are in serious quest for some Persian action , err, food knows this place. 

 
I mean, come on! Look at this restaurant. From the outside it looks kinda unattractive. Persian Kabab and then a CAR LOAN signage?? It will take more than just one look to actually realize that this is actually a restaurant… and well, the car loan biz is a totally different tenant in the building. But putting all those aside, I’m glad I was introduced to this Persian restaurant!!! Wanna know why?

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 Mediterranean Persian 24 hours 5stars 100plus Quezon City 
 Share 

 05 24 2012 
Quick Chow: Sbarro’s Chicago White Deep Dish
 
This is perhaps one of my default orders when visiting Sbarro , an American Italian restaurant which specializes in pizza. The Chicago White Deep Dish (Php 172) is a stuffed pizza composed of two crisp layers of dough overstuffed with 100% whole milk mozzarella cheese, pepperoni, ham, ricotta, Mama Sbarro’s own pizza sauce, and grated romano cheese.

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 100plus pizza italian american 4stars 
 Share 

 05 22 2012 
Amber: Home of Original Pancit Malabon&amp;Delicious Pichi Pichi
 
We recently had Amber delivered to our home. This Filipino restaurant is best known for its Pancit Malabon and Pichi Pichi.

We ordered the following…

 

Crispy Pata (Php 300), Fried Lumpiang Shanghai (Php 8/pc), and of course two things you must not forget to order, Pancit Malabon (Php 600) and Pichi Pichi with cheese (Php 150)!

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 200plus 4stars Delivery Filipino pork dessert 
 Share 

 05 16 2012 
Pancake House
 
There is something about Pancake House that is very inviting and comforting. Maybe the homey ambiance? The homey food? Or who knows, maybe I had my very first date in this place many years ago (and the memory just sticks)?… HAHAHAHA or not. ;) BUT ANYWAY, what I’m saying is… Pancake House is a restaurant I’ve grown to love over the course of time. I just keep coming back for their pancakes and waffles.

 

 Read More 
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 4plus breakfast pasta waffle taco manila 200plus 
 Share 

 05 14 2012 
Foodie’s Haven got featured!
 
 

You can read the entire article here .

I’d like to express my sincerest gratitude to Mr. Archie of The Food Techie for acknowledging my humble food blog. He asked me a few days ago if he can interview me about my blog, and so I happily replied. This is the first time ever Foodie’s Haven got featured! So again, thank you! :)
 
 Posted by Hazel 1 month ago Comments Permalink 
 featured interview food blog 
 Share 

 Welcome, have a seat! 
 Foodies Haven is just another food photo+blog of a girl who likes eating. 
P.S. Stay tuned! I have loads of posts to share since I&apos;ve been away for too long! Like the newly created Foodie&apos;s Haven on Facebook too! :)

 

 Foodie&apos;s Quotable Quote Life is too short to eat anything you do not like. -anonymous Get in touch Email: hazelnot AT yahoo DOT com
Twitter: @hazelsalcedo 
 

 Never miss an entry... Subscribe now! Enter your email address:
 

 Looking for something? 

 Thank you, come again next time! Exit here. 
 
 Check my Blogroll 


 Etcetera Feedjit Live Blog Stats hits: 
 
 
 

 

All photos on this blog is owned by Hazel, unless otherwise stated. Please ask for permission if you will use them. Next &gt; 
 Home About Archives Ask RSS 
 
 Borderline theme Addwater Powered Install Free Widgets See more themes by Addwater Questions? Comments? Powered by Tumblr 
 
 ↑
	</body>
</document>
