<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007541" url="http://www.lawcrossing.com/article/1236/Your-first-job-is-all-about-attitude/" time="2012-07-13-00:31" support="1" score="0.001644128193204023" bingtitle="Your First Job Is All About Attitude | Lawcrossing.com" webtitle="Your First Job Is All About Attitude | Lawcrossing.com">
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>Now, we all know that working the counter at a fast ... Americans fast-food restaurant fast-foods expectations hundreds ... all of the job listings it locates in one place.</description>
	<body>
		JOB SEEKERS,   
 
 EMPLOYERS, POST LEGAL JOBS  |  SEARCH LEGAL RESUMES 
 

 Share 
 
 

 
 ATTORNEYS LAW STUDENTS LEGAL STAFF 
 Search Legal Jobs Browse Legal Jobs Post Legal Jobs 
 
 
See Legal Jobs We Have Recently Researched and Located for You
 
 What Where 
 Show Recruiter Jobs    
 
 Show Refreshed Jobs    

 Select All Alabama Alaska American Samoa Arizona Arizona-Phoenix Arizona - Other Arkansas California California-Orange California-Oakland California-San Jose California-San Francisco California-Los Angeles California-San Diego California-Sacramento California - Other Colorado Colorado-Denver Colorado-Other Connecticut Connecticut-Hartford Connecticut-Other Delaware Delaware-Wilmington District of Columbia District of Columbia-Washington Florida Florida-Orlando Florida-Tampa Florida-Miami Florida-Other Georgia Georgia-Atlanta Georgia-Other Guam Hawaii Idaho Illinois Illinois-Chicago Illinois-Other Indiana Indiana-Indianapolis Indiana-Other Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Maryland-Baltimore Maryland-Other Massachusetts Massachusetts-Boston Massachusetts-Other Michigan Michigan-Grand Rapids Michigan-Detroit Michigan-Other Minnesota Minnesota-Minneapolis Mississippi Missouri Missouri-St. Louis Missouri-Kansas City Missouri-Other Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York New York-Buffalo New York-Albany New York-Rochester New York-New York City New York-Other North Carolina North Carolina-Charlotte North Carolina-Raleigh North Carolina-Other North Dakota Northern Mariana Islands Ohio Ohio-Cleveland Ohio-Cincinnati Ohio-Other Oklahoma Oklahoma-Oklahoma City Oregon Pennsylvania Pennsylvania-Philadelphia Pennsylvania-Pittsburgh Pennsylvania-Other Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Tennessee-Nashville Tennessee-Other Texas Texas-Dallas Texas-Austin Texas-San Antonio Texas-Houston Texas-Other Utah Vermont Virgin Islands Virginia Virginia-Richmond Virginia-Other Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Canada Canada-Alberta Canada-British Columbia Canada-Ontario Canada-Quebec Australia Australia-Melbourne Austria Belgium Belgium-Brussels Bulgaria China China-Shanghai China-Beijing Colombia United Kingdom England-London France France-Paris Finland Germany Germany-Frankfurt/Main Germany-Munich Germany-Dusseldorf Greece Greece-Athens Netherlands Holland-Amsterdam Hong Kong Italy Italy-Rome India Indonesia Ireland Israel Japan Japan-Tokyo Luxembourg Malaysia Mongolia New Zealand Nigeria Philippines Poland Qatar Russia Russia-Moscow Spain Spain-Madrid Saudi Arabia Singapore South Africa Sweden Switzerland Thailand Ukraine United Arab Emirates Vietnam Job Type: 
 Select a Job Type Select All Attorney Law Student / Clerkship Legal Staff Partner Judicial Clerkship Summer Associate / Internship Employer Type: 
 Select All Academic Recruiter Government In-House Judges Public Interest Law Firm 
+ Browse Legal Jobs    + Advanced Search    + Search Tips    + Upload Legal Resume 
 
 Legal Jobs &gt;&gt; Legal Articles &gt;&gt; Career Corner &gt;&gt;Your First Job Is All About Attitude back to all articles 
 Career Corner 
 Your first job is all about attitude 

 by Michael Kinsman       
 
 The first job can set the tone for a career. 
But I found myself watching a flustered 17-year-old scramble at the drive-through window of a fast-food restaurant just trying to do her job. Her actions clearly communicated that she was scared and baffled.

Now, we all know that working the counter at a fast-food business isn&apos;t the toughest or most challenging work out there. That&apos;s one of the reasons tens of thousands of American teens each year get their first jobs doing just that.

But it can be the toughest job in the world if you lack the preparation or confidence it requires.

That&apos;s an easy thing to forget as we look back.

Job performance is tied directly to training, temperament and confidence. If you feel that you understand your job duties, have been trained to perform them and like the work you are doing, you probably will be a success in that job.

Yet, things often are not that black and white.

How many times have you seen a new employee in a retail shop asking for assistance to complete a simple task? How often have you seen new employees take interminable periods to complete a transaction?

Your first job is often a very important life event. It could be one of the first times that you have been in the world alone with responsibilities. Often, you don&apos;t have friends or family to lean on and you have to handle issues smoothly as they arise.

This is a great jumpstart to maturity, but it also can be intimidating.

I like to tell people that in my first job, I was in charge of paper clips.

At the time, I had just started as an 18-year-old copy boy working for a newspaper. My department used hundreds of paper clips each week, but the penny-pinching publisher rarely let the newsroom have new supplies.

That meant that someone had to figure out a way to recycle paper clips.

I simply traced the path of paper clips after they left our department and found those spots where they would accumulate. Each day, I would take some from here, some from there and my department would have an adequate supply for its needs.

This wasn&apos;t brain surgery. It also wasn&apos;t exciting work. Yet, it was a job that needed to be done and I did it. Because I was successful in that, they soon gave me additional jobs that were more important and more meaningful.

Your first job is all about attitude. Nearly everyone has a job early in their career with mundane tasks, yet they still must be done. Our willingness to deal with those tasks as part of the whole job can often set a tone for our tenure in that job.

I felt sorry for the girl at the drive-through window because I could see she was flustered, but still trying to do her job.

Even when she shortchanged me a few cents, I couldn&apos;t say anything to her because she was obviously shaken.

Employers who hire young people have a responsibility to us all. These are the future workers of our country and employers need to instill proper workplace values and expectations in these young people.

It might seem academic to older people that teenagers need to learn about job expectations and opportunities when they start out. They also need to understand corporate culture and how they contribute to it.

These things are givens. But employers also have a responsibility to make sure that when they hire young people, they have given those people the proper training and education they will need to handle the job.

Employers need to make certain that young hires have a chance to succeed in their first jobs. It can set a tone for their entire career and it&apos;s simply a good business strategy. 

 
 Rate This Article 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Select    Current rating: 9.5    |    View top rated articles 
 
 

     Printable Version     PDF Version     Email to a Friend     Post A Comment     View Comment     Discuss 
 

 

 Popular Tags 
   teens   expectations   employers   corporate cultures   publishing   Americans   fast-foods   exciting   hundreds   fast-food restaurant 
 


 Featured Testimonials 
 
LawCrossing was the only tool I used in my job search, and I found my new job in two weeks. Need I say more.
 Meredith 

 
 

 Facts 
 
LawCrossing Fact #186: LawCrossing has virtually the largest collection of job listings in the world.

 
 
 
 &quot;We want to hear your thoughts. Please comment on this article (below)!&quot; 

 Comments 

 
 
 Article ID: 1236   

 Article Title: Your first job is all about attitude

 Comment not found for this article. 

 Comment 
 
 
 
Facebook comments:
 

 

 
 
 
 
 LawCrossing 
 PREMIER 
 The Job Search Program that Guarantees Success. 
Our career counselor creates a tailor-made job search strategy for you and walks you through every step of the process. Create your unique brand for just $2,495! more 
 
 total jobs 96,929 New Legal Jobs in Last 7 Days 16,999 
 
 SIGN UP NOW * Email:
    Only LawCrossing consolidates every job it can find in the legal industry and puts all of the job listings it locates in one place. 


 We have more than 25 times as many legal jobs as any other job board. We list jobs you will not find elsewhere that are hidden in small regional publications and employer websites. We collect jobs from more than 250,000 websites and post them on our site. We do not charge employers when we post their listings. We are private, and therefore far fewer people are applying for the jobs on our site than are applying for those on public job boards. 
 
   
 Real-Time Job Updates 
Sign up free and receive new jobs by email as soon as they become available.

First Name
 

Email
 

Areas of Practice
 Select Antitrust and Trade Regulation Bankruptcy Construction Corporate Employment Energy Environmental ERISA/Employee Benefits Government Health Care Immigration Insurance Intellectual Property - Litigation Intellectual Property - Other Intellectual Property - Patent Intellectual Property - Trademark/Copyright Internet/E-Commerce IP/Technology Transactions Litigation Other Patent Agents/Technical Specialists Real Estate Securities Litigation Tax Telecommunications Trust and Estates White Collar Crime 

Regions of Interest
 Select Alabama Alaska Arizona - Other Arizona - Phoenix Arkansas California - Los Angeles California - Oakland/East Bay California - Orange County California - Other California - Sacramento California - San Diego California - San Francisco California - Silicon Valley/San Jose Colorado - Denver Colorado - Other Connecticut - Hartford Connecticut - Other Delaware - Other Delaware - Wilmington District of Columbia Florida - Miami Florida - Orlando Florida - Other Florida - Tampa Georgia - Atlanta Georgia - Other Hawaii Idaho Illinois - Chicago Illinois - Other Indiana - Indianapolis Indiana - Other Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland - Baltimore Maryland - Other Massachusetts - Boston Massachusetts - Other Michigan - Detroit Michigan - Grand Rapids Michigan - Other Minnesota - Minneapolis/St. Paul Minnesota - Other Mississippi Missouri - Kansas City Missouri - Other Missouri - St. Louis Montana Nebraska - Omaha Nebraska - Other Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York - Albany New York - Buffalo New York - New York City New York - Other New York - Rochester North Carolina - Charlotte North Carolina - Other North Carolina - Raleigh North Dakota Ohio - Cincinnati Ohio - Cleveland Ohio - Other Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania - Other Pennsylvania - Philadelphia Pennsylvania - Pittsburgh Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee - Nashville Tennessee - Other Texas - Austin Texas - Dallas Texas - Houston Texas - Other Texas - San Antonio Utah Vermont Virginia - Northern Virginia - Other Virginia - Richmond Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming - Asia - China - Beijing - Asia - China - Other - Asia - China - Shanghai - Asia - Hong Kong - Asia - Japan - Other - Asia - Japan - Tokyo - Asia - Other - Asia - Singapore - Asia - Thailand - Asia - UAE - Abu Dhabi - Asia - UAE - Dubai - Australia - Melbourne - Australia - Other - Canada - Europe - Belgium - Brussels - Europe - Belgium - Other - Europe - England - London - Europe - England - Other - Europe - France - Other - Europe - France - Paris - Europe - Germany - Dussel - Europe - Greece - Athens - Europe - Germany - Munich - Europe - Germany - Other - Europe - Greece - Other - Europe - Holland - Amsterdam - Europe - Holland - Other - Europe - Italy - Other - Europe - Italy - Rome - Europe - Other - Europe - Russia - Moscow - Europe - Russia - Other - Europe - Spain - Madrid - Europe - Spain - Other - Mexico - South America 

 
 
 
 post your resume 
 Make your resume viewable to thousands of employers. Employers can look you up in our database. Get job alerts based on your resume. 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Whitelist LawCrossing Your privacy is guaranteed. We will never give out, lease, or sell your personal information. 
 
 Attorney Jobs   |  Law Student Jobs   |  Legal Staff Jobs   |  Legal Jobs   |  Browse Jobs   |  Search Jobs by Location   |  Search Jobs by Type   |  Legal Recruiter   |  Jobs 

 Our Partner Sites: 
 BCG Attorney Search 

 
Your browser does not support iframes.
	</body>
</document>
