<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007969" url="http://eddiesrailroad.blogspot.com/2011/03/historic-photo-chicago-transit.html" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="1" score="0.0005799151267388372" bingtitle="Eddie&apos;s Rail Fan Page: Historic photo! A Chicago Transit Authority ..." webtitle="Eddie&apos;s Rail Fan Page: Historic photo! A Chicago Transit Authority mid 1950s era Flxible Twin
Coach Company propane powered transit bus. Chicago Illinois USA. July
1969.">
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>Coming soon to the Elmwood Park Public Library ... Shiny, brand new Interstate Asphalt tank car ... The Taco Burrito King Mexican fast food restaurant...</description>
	<body>
		Eddie&apos;s Rail Fan Page 
 
 Welcome to my rail fan page!
Here you&apos;ll find information and pictures of railroad related items from the Chicagoland area, Wisconsin and Indiana.
Enjoy your stay.

All Aboard! 
 
 Tuesday, March 08, 2011 
 
Historic photo! A Chicago Transit Authority mid 1950&apos;s era Flxible Twin
Coach Company propane powered transit bus. Chicago Illinois USA. July
1969.
 
 Historic photo! A Chicago Transit Authority mid 1950&apos;s era Flxible Twin Coach Company propane powered transit bus. Chicago Illinois USA. July 1969. a photo by Eddie from Chicago on Flickr. 
I found this very historic Chicago Transit Authority bus photo from 1969, at My link page Northern California Bus Fans to the right of Your computer screen.

I was born in Chicago during the year of 1962, and I have happy childhood memories of the old late 1940&apos;s and 1950&apos;s era Twin Coach Company, and later Flixble Twin Coach Company propane powered transit buses once used by the CTA.

These big transit buses, were used all over the CTA system during the 1960&apos;s. They were retired from service during 1972 and 1973.
Believe it or not.....I miss them.

Thanks.
Eddie K
 Posted by Eddie at Tuesday, March 08, 2011 
No comments:
 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Followers
 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (1006) 
 ►  Jul (41) 
 Ice cream truck menu. Norridge Illinois. June 2012... The Forest Park Public Library presents&quot;Kiddielan... This Was The Rock Island Railroad Morning switching activity at the Burlington North... Remembering the steam era on the Grand Trunk Weste... H.O steam train on a tall steel trestle. The Isabella Street CTA purple line railroad cross... A man made lake in a large city park. Glenview Ill... Welcome aboard the&quot;Bus Day&quot;edition of Eddie&apos;s Ra... Westbound CTA Rt # 20 Madison Street bus at night.... Retired CTA 1955 Flxible / Twin Coach bus reanacti... The original 1947 Chicago Transit Authority logo. ... Green River Lines long distance bus. Chicago Illin... First Transit Ford bus runby. Glenview IL. April... The CTA turn around loop at North Halsted Street a... Mid 1960&apos;s vintage CTA Flxible bus at West 63rd Pl... Eddie at work. June 2008. Westbound CTA Rt # 80 bus runby. Chicago Illinois... A school bus heading south on Ridge Avenue. Wilmet... Chevrolet ice cream truck. Norridge Illinois. June... North Osceola Avenue getting fresh black top. Chic... Marine Corp Band Stars and Stripes Forever. Preserved Southern Pacific steam locomotive # 4449... The CTA orange line Midway Airport turning loop. C... Digital Live Sound Video: A former E,J&amp;E EMD roa... Southbound Canadian National freight train arrives... Union Pacific EMD GP 15 # 547. Chicago Illinois. S... Huckleberry Railroad 2006 - Railfans Charter Purple former Melbourne Australia W 2 class tram c... The motorman&apos;s cab of Illinois Terminal Railroad l... Maintaining the streets of Elmwood Park Illinois. Coming soon to the Forest Park Public Library!&quot;K... Chicago&amp;NorthWestern Railroad freight train wrec... Belt Railway of Chicago Alco Century series roadsw... The space between the locomotive and coach on a Me... Eastbound Burlington Northern freight train approa... Fast moving N B Amtrak Hiawatha. Deerfield IL. Apr... A former Atchinson, Topeka&amp;Santa Fe covered hopp... Eastbound yellow CCC garbage truck from the Skokie... Digital Live Sound Video: Southbound CTA Purple li... Rare Historical Photo. Chicago&apos;s Brighton Junction... 
 

 ►  Jun (152) 
 Saint Richard&apos;s Catholic Parish Church annual summ... Southbound CP container train with former Soo Line... An early 1970&apos;s era Illinois Central Gulf Railroad... Miller High Life Beer 1965 Chevrolet 30 picnic tru... 15&quot;gauge live steam Shay at Hillcrest&amp;Wahtoke R... Union Pacific Railroad John Deere front end loader... Southbound Canadian Pacific double stack container... W B BNSF empty unit coal train at nightfall. La ... A potted plant on the back porch. 
 

 ►  May (167) 

 ►  Apr (172) 

 ►  Mar (175) 

 ►  Feb (175) 

 ►  Jan (124) 
 

 ▼  2011 (1929) 
 ►  Dec (136) 

 ►  Nov (180) 

 ►  Oct (148) 

 ►  Sep (141) 

 ►  Aug (164) 

 ►  Jul (146) 

 ►  Jun (154) 

 ►  May (178) 

 ►  Apr (151) 

 ▼  Mar (192) 
 Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page! Coming to You... I spotted this wonderful Milwaukee ... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.o Scale ... Illinois Terminal # 415 departing Barn # 8 Stop. Northbound Canadian Pacific intermodal transfer tr... Passengers disembarking at the Metra Norwood Park ... Hobby City. 6910 West Cermak Road. Berwyn Illinois... Shiny, brand new Interstate Asphalt tank car. The ... Welcome aboard the&quot;Bus Day&quot;edition of Eddie&apos;s Ra... The Chicago Transit Authority in the year of 1952.... All Ways Transportation Company Ford paratransit b... the north terminal loop for the Chicago transit Au... Coming this Spring to the Elmwood Park Public Libr... Chicago&apos;s famous Lake Shore Drive. Chicago Illinoi... The CTA Forest Glen garage. Chicago Illinois. Janu... Eastbound Pace bus on Central Avenue. Wilmette Ill... The former Kiddieland Amusement Park Site. Melrose... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O Scale ... Niles Public Services GMC box van truck. Niles Ill... Eastbound CTA Skokie Swift train. Skokie IL. Mar 2... Coming soon to the Elmwood Park Public Library! Sa... Chicago&apos;s&quot;New&quot;parking&quot;Pay Boxes&quot;wich have repl... Double stack intermodal container train entering t... The Rock Island lives! Tinley Park Illinois. June ... Welcome aboard Edie&apos;s Railfan Page! Coming to You ... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O Scale ... Coming this Spring to the Eisenhower Public Librar... Eastbound CP freight with Soo engines. River Grove... Coming this Spring to the Franklin Park Public Lib... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O Scale ... Bob O&apos;s Hot Dogs on West Irving Park Road. Chicago... Southbound BNSF transfer train traveling over the ... The Memphis Main Street Trolley. Memphis Tennesee.... The Atchinson, Topeka&amp;Santa Fe Railroad&apos;s Illino... Westbound BNSF Railway double stack container trai... Coming soon to the Eisenhower Public Library. 4613... Digital Live Sound Video: Southbound Union Pacific... The 75th Avenue railroad crossing. Elmwood Park il... Coming this Spring to the Eisenhower Public Librar... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O Scale ... The Patio Restaurant. Bridgeview Illinois. Sunday ... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page! Coming to You... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O Scale ... Chicago Fire Department Chevrolet Stepvan support ... Silent Digital Video: Westbound Metra express comm... Chicago winter railroading. Chicago Illinois. Janu... Atchinson, Topeka&amp;Santa Fe hump yard switching. ... Hobby City. 6910 West Cermak Road. Berwyn Illinois... EMD switchers from the Central Illnois Railroad. C... A former New Orleans Public Service Company electr... Southbound Canadian National transfer train passin... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... Metra departs at sunset. Franklin Park Illinois. J... Indiana Harbor Belt RR maintenance of way departme... Eastbound Canadian National freight train. North R... Coming soon to the Franklin Park Public Library. 1... The Hesston Steam Museum. Hesston Indiana USA. Sun... Westbound Canadian National Railroad freight train... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... Westbound Burlington Northern freight train with w... Coming this Spring to the Elmwood Park Public Libr... Digital Live Sound Video, Canadian Pacific Railroa... City of Chicago Department of Streets and sanitati... Brown Wintertime grass. Chicago Illinois USA. Marc... The Oak Park IL Society Of Model Engineers. May 20... Peterbuilt dump truck. Deerfield Illinois USA. Sep... Central Illinois Railroad EMD switchers. Chicago I... Westbound Auto Rack train. Hayford Junction. Chica... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers added to E... Hi everyone!
This is Eddie K, Your host and photog... Digital Live Sound Video: Westbound Metra commuter... One of Chicago&apos;s Wendella sightseeing excursion bo... Westbound Metra comuter local arriving at the Metr... Speeding miniature 14&quot;guage live steam train. Th... Chicago Terminal Railroad switching local at work.... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... The Oak Park Society of Model Engineers H.O scale ... Hello everyone!
This is Eddie K, Your host and ph... Union Pacific locomotives idling above South Weste... Northbound Metra caboose hop. Glenview IL. May 201... A City of Chicago department of Streets and sanita... Eastbound BNSF Railway freight train. Riverside Il... Central Illinois Railroad EMD SW 1200 yard switche... Southbound Metra commuter train. Deerfield Illinoi... Welcome aboard the&quot;Bus Day&quot;edition of Eddie&apos;s Ra... A New York City Transit Authority GMC fishbowl win... Digital Live Sound Video: Westbound Pace bus cross... Coming soon to the Eisenhower Public Library. 4613... The original 1947 Chicago Transit Authority logo. ... Eddie at work. June 2008. Blue Pace bus at the La Grange Road Metra commuter... A Bluebird school bus up close. Glenview Illinois.... Westbound CTA bus on West Taylor Street in Chicago... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... Relective red markings. The Union Pacific M-19A Di... Saint Clair of Montifalco Catholic Parish annual s... The architecturally unique Parky&apos;s hot dog stand. ... Two Metra evening rush hour locals ariving at the ... Digital Live Sound Video: The Chicago Botanic Gard... Historic United States military cannon from World ... A large yellow CCC garbage truck. Des Plaines Illi... Digital live sound video: Westbound CTA Skokie Swi... Former Illinois Central diesel locomotives on the ... The train just cleared the Oakton Street railroad ... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... Eastbound CSX double stack train. Hayford Junction... The Belle of Louisville sternwheel steam boat. Lou... I found this photo at My link page Fallen Flags.O... Eastbound CanadianNational switching train heading... Northbound Canadian National local. Franklin Park ... The Hesston Steam Museum. Hesston Indiana USA. Sun... Small John Deere front end loader. Glenview Illino... Coming this Spring to the Eisenhower Public Librar... Canadian National freight train waiting on a hold ... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page! Coming to You... Westbound Metra express commuter train speeding th... City of Chicago Department Of Streets And Sanitati... Digital Live Sound Video: Southbound Amtrak Hiawat... I spotted this classic 1960&apos;s era pre Amtrak era ... Two BNSF Railway locomotives heading eastbound and... The former Metra Wood Dale Illinois commuter rail ... The&quot;New&quot;Wood Dale Illinois Metra commuter rail s... Old western Pacific wooden steam era caboose in mo... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page, from the city... Indiana Harbor Belt Railroad. Hello everyone!
This is Eddie K, Your host and ph... Eastbound mid day Metra commuter local. Chicago Ri... Digital Live Sound Video: The Chicago Botanic Gard... When the fun ends: Photos of the final days of old... Coming soon to the Elmwood Park Public Library. 1 ... Strasburg Railroad steam locomotive # 90 and train... looking east inside Crawford Yard. Chicago Illinoi... Welcome aboard Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page from the city ... Central Illinois Railroad. Chicago IL. Oct 2008. Coming this Spring to the Elmwood Park Public Libr... Being born and raised on the southwest side of Ch... Coming this Spring to the Franklin Park Public Lib... The classic College Avenue Metra commuter rail sta... Digital Live Sound Video: Northbound Metra crossin... Interior view of a Kenosha Wisconsin ex Toronto tr... Chicago&apos;s Brookfield Zoo train. ( Gone.) Brookfiel... Eastbound Metra / Burlington Northern commuter tra... Indiana Harbor Belt local heading west toward Manh... Eastbound CSX Transportation Co West 16th Street l... Digital Live Sound Video: Chicago Terminal Railroa... A CCC garbage truck from the City of Evanston Illi... A Belt Railway of Chicago EMD switcher spotting ca... Northbound Indiana Harbor Belt RR transfer train. ... Westbound Veolia Waste Services Mack garbage truck... Small John Deere front end loader. Glenview Illino... The Chicago Botanic Garden. Glencoe Illinois USA. ... Hi everyone!

This is Eddie K, Your host and phot... Welcome aboard the&quot;Bus Day&quot;edition of Eddie&apos;s Ra... Pace N.A.B.I bus idling at the CTA Linden Avenue t... City of Evanston Dept of Recreation, International... Silent digital video: Eastbound CTA Route # 78 Mon... Historic photo! A Chicago Transit Authority mid 19... Positive Connections Chevrolet van style school bu... Westbound Metra crossing N Narragansett Ave. Chica... A miniature live steam model of a 4-6-4 Hudson typ... Former Detroit, Toledo&amp;Ironton Railroad EMD road... Old Milwaukee Road steam era photo inside the&quot;New... BNSF Railway covered grain hopper car. Hawthorne J... Eastbound CTA Skokie Swift train. Feb 3rd, 2011. The Taco Burrito King Mexican fast food restaurant... Chicago Terminal Railroad switching local at work.... Wintertime at the Metra, River Grove commuter rail... Be sure to come down to The Eisenhower Public Lib... Growing up on the near southwest sid... Side by side Metras at Galewoood depot. Chicago IL... A former Illinois Central unit in the locomotive c... A former Conrail&quot;Trailvan&quot;piggyback trailer. Ben... Southbound Metra local at the Deerfield Illinois s... Mid day trash collection on South Harlem Avenue. R... Portillo&apos;s Restaurant on South Harlem Avenue near ... The&quot;New&quot;Wood Dale Illinois Metra commuter rail s... Coming this Spring to the Franklin Park Public Lib... Digital Live Sound Video: Chicago Terminal Railroa... Coming this Spring to the Elmwood Park Public Libr... Chicago Terminal Railroad switching local at work.... Northbound Amtrak Hiawatha. Northbrook IL. Dec 200... Western Pacific Railroad 50 foot double door box c... Westbound Metra local departing from Elmwood Park ... Tony&apos;s Subs on Waukegan Road. Deerfield Illinois U... The Oak Park IL Society Of Model Engineers. May 20... The Hesston Steam Museum. Hesston Indiana USA. Sun... Digital live sound video: Westbound Metra express ... A&quot;New&quot;City of Chicago epartment of Streets and S... Southbound Union Pacific empty unit coal train. Gl... Chicago, South Shore&amp;South Bend RR electric M.U ... Melting snow from Chicago&apos;s blizzard of 2011. Elmw... 
 

 ►  Feb (163) 

 ►  Jan (176) 
 

 ►  2010 (1576) 
 ►  Dec (157) 

 ►  Nov (150) 

 ►  Oct (155) 

 ►  Sep (110) 

 ►  Aug (149) 

 ►  Jul (50) 

 ►  Jun (140) 

 ►  May (133) 

 ►  Apr (133) 

 ►  Mar (126) 

 ►  Feb (119) 

 ►  Jan (154) 
 

 ►  2009 (1475) 
 ►  Dec (144) 

 ►  Nov (144) 

 ►  Oct (121) 

 ►  Sep (121) 

 ►  Aug (129) 

 ►  Jul (126) 

 ►  Jun (105) 

 ►  May (121) 

 ►  Apr (123) 

 ►  Mar (113) 

 ►  Feb (117) 

 ►  Jan (111) 
 

 ►  2008 (1226) 
 ►  Dec (121) 

 ►  Nov (127) 

 ►  Oct (104) 

 ►  Sep (95) 

 ►  Aug (105) 

 ►  Jul (56) 

 ►  Jun (1) 

 ►  May (111) 

 ►  Apr (117) 

 ►  Mar (100) 

 ►  Feb (163) 

 ►  Jan (126) 
 

 ►  2007 (1356) 
 ►  Dec (127) 

 ►  Nov (139) 

 ►  Oct (123) 

 ►  Sep (64) 

 ►  Aug (143) 

 ►  Jul (135) 

 ►  Jun (103) 

 ►  May (122) 

 ►  Apr (104) 

 ►  Mar (113) 

 ►  Feb (103) 

 ►  Jan (80) 
 

 ►  2006 (634) 
 ►  Dec (81) 

 ►  Nov (94) 

 ►  Oct (75) 

 ►  Sep (43) 

 ►  Aug (63) 

 ►  Jul (44) 

 ►  Jun (39) 

 ►  May (57) 

 ►  Apr (42) 

 ►  Mar (48) 

 ►  Feb (48) 
 
 
Links to other interesting sites.
 
 Playland Park Amusement Park from Justice Illinois @ Facebook.com Rail Pictures.Net Toon Tracker. Classic television cartoon theme songs. Eddie&apos;s Railfan Page 2006 photo albums and discussion group. The Oak Park Society Of Model Engineers H.O Scale Model Railroad Club. Tom&apos;s Trolley Bus Pictures Chicago&apos;s Baci Pizzeria from Taylor Street. Northern California Bus Fans. Roger&apos;&apos;s Basement. You Tube. 1970&apos;s music group Three Dog Night fan club page. My Flickr Photo Page Crosby Steam Whistles. Historic railroad photos from Fallen Flags.Org Tom&apos;s photos and comments. The Illinois Railway Museum. Dave&apos;s Electric Railroads. The Hesston Steam Museum. Yesteryear Depot. 
 
 
 
 Simple template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
