<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007202" url="http://www.stats.bls.gov/oes/1998/oes_def6.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:10" support="10" score="0.029937108390644916" bingtitle="Occupational Definitions - Service Occupations" webtitle="Occupational Definitions - Service Occupations">
			<query id="001085" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001096" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001081" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001091" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001075" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited ... cleaning kitchen work areas, equipment, and utensils. ... answering patient&apos;s call bell, serving and collecting ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Content 
 US Department of Labor 
 A to Z Index  |  FAQs  |  About BLS  |  Contact Us    E-mail: 
 U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics 
 Follow Us | What&apos;s New | Release Calendar | Site Map 
 Home 
 
SUBJECT AREAS»
 Inflation&amp;Prices Spending&amp;Time Use Unemployment Employment Pay&amp;Benefits Productivity Workplace Injuries International   Demographics Industries Business Costs Occupations Geography 

 
Resources For»
 Business Leaders Consumers Economists Investors Jobseekers Media Public Policymakers Students&amp;Teachers Survey Respondents   
At a Glance Tables»
 U.S. Economy Regions, States,&amp;Areas Industries International 

 
MORE»
 Announcements Commissioner&apos;s Corner Green Jobs Research Spotlight on Statistics Career Information for Kids Errata Other Statistical Sites 
 Subject Areas 
 
 Inflation&amp;Prices» 
 Consumer Price Index Producer Price Indexes Import/Export Price Indexes Employment Cost Index Contract Escalation Price Index Research Inflation&amp;Prices Overview   
 Pay&amp;Benefits» 
 Employment Costs National Compensation Data Wages by Area&amp;Occupation Earnings by Demographics Earnings by Industry County Wages Benefits Compensation Research Strikes&amp;Lockouts Pay&amp;Benefits Overview   
 Spending&amp;Time Use» 
 Consumer Expenditures How Americans Spend Time 

 
 Unemployment» 
 National Unemployment Rate State&amp;Local Unemployment Rates Mass Layoffs Unemployment Research Unemployment Overview   
 Employment» 
 National Employment State&amp;Local Employment State&amp;County Employment Worker Characteristics Employment Projections Job Openings&amp;Labor Turnover Green Goods and Services Green Technologies and Practices Employment by Occupation Work Experience Over Time Business Employment Dynamics Employment Research Employment Overview   
 Workplace Injuries» 
 

 
 Productivity» 
 Labor Productivity&amp;Costs Multifactor Productivity Productivity Research Productivity Overview   
 International» 
 International Labor Comparisons International Technical Cooperation Import/Export Price Indexes International Overview   
 REGIONAL OFFICES» 
 New England (Boston) New York-New Jersey (NY City) Mid-Atlantic (Philadelphia) Southeast (Atlanta) Midwest (Chicago) Southwest (Dallas) Mountain-Plains (Kansas City) West (San Francisco) Regional Overview 
 Databases&amp;Tools 
 
 Data Retrieval Tools» 
 Top Picks Series Report One Screen Multi-Screen Maps Calculators   

 
CUSTOMIZED TABLES»
 Text Files News Release Tables   
 More Sources of Data» 
 Discontinued Databases FAQs Special Notices More Sources of Data 
 Publications 
 
 Latest Publications» 
 The Editor’s Desk Monthly Labor Review Beyond the Numbers Compensation and Working Conditions Online Issues in Labor Statistics Program Perspectives Focus on Prices and Spending Regional Reports Spotlight on Statistics 

   Occupational Outlook Handbook Occupational Outlook Quarterly Magazines&amp;Journals Chartbooks Bulletins&amp;Reports Catalog of Publications Research Papers Copyright Information Contact&amp;Help 
 Economic Releases 
 
 Latest Releases» 
   
 Major Economic Indicators» 
   
 Schedules for news Releases» 
 By Month By News Release Current Year Prior Years   
 Archived News Releases» 
 

 
 Employment&amp;Unemployment» 
 Monthly Quarterly, annual, and other   
 Inflation&amp;Prices» 
   
 Pay&amp;Benefits&amp;Workplace Injuries» 
   
 Productivity&amp;Technology» 
   
 Employment Projections» 
   
 International Programs» 
   
 Regional News Releases» 
 
 Beta 
 
 STATE AND COUNTY MAP» 
 
 
 
Occupational Employment Statistics
 FONT SIZE: PRINT: OES 
Occupational Employment Statistics

 OES Homepage OES Overview OES FAQ Contact OES 
 SHARE ON: 
 
 BROWSE OES OES HOME OES OVERVIEW 
 DATA AVAILABLE SURVEY COVERAGE AND SCOPE ESTIMATES AVAILABLE FORMS OF PUBLICATION USES OF THE DATA 
 OES NEWS RELEASES OES DATABASES OES TABLES OES PUBLICATIONS OES FAQs CONTACT OES 
 
 SEARCH OES 
 
 OES TOPICS ARCHIVED DATA CHARTS&amp;MAPS INFORMATION FOR RESPONDENTS TECHNICAL DOCUMENTATION 
 TECHNICAL NOTE SURVEY METHODS AND RELIABILITY STATEMENT (PDF) OES CHAPTER IN THE BLS HANDBOOK OF METHODS (PDF) METROPOLITAN AND NONMETROPOLITAN AREA DEFINITIONS FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS ALL OES DOCUMENTATION 


 
Subscribe
to the OES Update
 
Occupational Definitions - OES Occupational Classification System

Service Occupations

First-Line Supervisors and Managers/Supervisors - Service Occupations
 
61002 - Fire Fighting and Prevention Supervisors
 Supervise and coordinate activities of workers engaged in fire fighting and fire prevention and control. 
 
61005 - Police and Detective Supervisors
 Supervise and coordinate activities of members of police force. 
 
61008 - Housekeeping Supervisors
 Supervise work activities of cleaning personnel to insure clean, orderly, and attractive rooms in hotels, hospitals, educational institutions, and similar establishments. Assign duties, inspect work, and investigate complaints regarding housekeeping service and equipment and take corrective action. May purchase housekeeping supplies and equipment, take periodic inventories, screen applicants, train new employees, and recommend dismissals. 
 
61099 - All Other Supervisors and Managers/Supervisors - Service Workers
 All other supervisors and managers/supervisors of service workers not classified separately above. 

Protective Service Occupations
 
63002 - Fire Inspectors
 Inspect buildings to detect fire hazards and enforce local ordinances and State laws. Investigate and gather facts to determine cause of fires and explosions and enforce fire laws. 
 
63005 - Forest Fire Inspectors and Prevention Specialists
 Administer fire regulations. Locate and report forest fires and weather conditions, usually from remote locations within forest or logging area. Inspect area for fire hazards and equipment for serviceability. May work from a station or patrol area. 
 
63008 - Fire Fighters
 Control and extinguish fires, protect life and property, and maintain equipment as paid volunteer or employee of city, township, State, or Federal government. 
 
63011 - Police Detectives
 Conduct investigations to prevent or solve crimes. 
 
63014 - Police Patrol Officers
 Maintain order, enforce laws and ordinances, and protect life and property in an assigned patrol district. Perform combination of following duties: Patrol a specific area on foot or in a vehicle; direct traffic; issue traffic summonses; investigate accidents; apprehend, arrest, and process prisoners; and give evidence in court. 
 
63017 - Correction Officers and Jailers
 Guard inmates in penal or rehabilitative institution in accordance with established regulations and procedures. May guard prisoners in transit between jail, courtroom, prison, or other point, traveling by automobile or public transportation. Include Deputy Sheriffs who spend the majority of their time guarding prisoners in county correctional institutions. 
 
63021 - Parking Enforcement Officers
 Patrol assigned area such as public parking lot or section of city to issue tickets to overtime parking violators and illegally parked vehicles. 
 
63023 - Bailiffs
 Open court by announcing entrance of judge. Seat witnesses and jurors in specified areas of courtroom. Eject or arrest individuals disturbing proceedings. 
 
63026 - United States Marshals
 Perform such law enforcement activities as serve civil writs and criminal warrants issued by federal courts; trace and arrest persons wanted under court warrants; seize and dispose of property under court orders; safeguard and transport prisoners and jurors; and maintain order in courtroom. 
 
63028 - Criminal Investigators, Public Service
 Plan and conduct investigations related to suspected violations of federal, State, or local laws. 
 
63032 - Sheriffs and Deputy Sheriffs
 Enforce law and order in rural or unincorporated districts or serve legal processes of courts. May patrol courthouse, guard court or grand jury, or escort defendants. Exclude Deputy Sheriffs who spend the majority of their time guarding prisoners in county correctional institutions. 
 
63035 - Detectives and Investigators, Except Public
 Protect property, merchandise, and money of store or similar establishment by detecting theft, shoplifting, or other unlawful practices by public or employees. Perform necessary action to preserve order and enforce standards of decorum established by management. Include Investigators who conduct private investigations, such as obtaining confidential information, seeking missing persons, or investigating crimes and thefts. 
 
63038 - Railroad and Transit Police and Special Agents
 Protect and police railroad and transit property, employees, or passengers. Include workers who coordinate security staff. 
 
63041 - Fish and Game Wardens
 Patrol assigned area to prevent game law violations. Investigate reports of damage to crops or property by wildlife. Compile biological data. 
 
63044 - Crossing Guards
 Guide or control vehicular or pedestrian traffic at such places as street and railroad crossings and construction sites. 
 
63047 - Guards and Watch Guards
 Stand guard at entrance or patrol premises to prevent theft, violence, or infractions of rules. 
 
63099 - All Other Protective Service Workers
 All other protective service workers not classified separately above. 

Food and Beverage Preparation and Service Occupations
 
65002 - Hosts and Hostesses, Restaurant, Lounge, or Coffee Shop
 Welcome patrons, seat them at tables or in lounge, and insure quality of facilities and service. 
 
65005 - Bartenders
 Mix and serve to patrons, directly or through wait staff, alcoholic and nonalcoholic drinks following standard recipes. 
 
65008 - Waiters and Waitresses
 Serve food and/or beverages to patrons at tables. Usually take order from patron and make out check. May set table with linen and silverware and take payment from patron. May serve customers at counter as well as table. Exclude workers who only work at counters. 
 
65011 - Food Servers, Outside
 Serve food to patrons outside of a restaurant environment, such as in hotels, hospital rooms, or cars. Exclude Food Vendors. 
 
65014 - Dining Room and Cafeteria Attendants and Bartender Helpers
 Perform any combination of the following duties to facilitate food service: Carry dirty dishes from dining room to kitchen; replace soiled table linens; set tables with silverware and glassware; replenish supply of clean linens, silverware, glassware, and dishes; supply service bar with food, such as soups, salads, and desserts; and serve ice water, butter, and coffee to patrons. May wash tables. 
 
65017 - Counter Attendants - Lunchroom, Coffee Shop, or Cafeteria
 Serve food to diners at counter or from a steam table. Exclude Counter Attendants who also wait tables. 
 
65021 - Bakers, Bread and Pastry
 Mix and bake ingredients according to recipes to produce small quantities of breads, pastries, and other baked goods for consumption on premises or for sale as specialty baked goods. 
 
65023 - Butchers and Meat Cutters
 Cut, trim, and prepare carcasses and consumer-sized portions of meat for sale or for use in food service establishments. Exclude butchers working in slaughtering, meat packing, or prepared-meat establishments. 
 
65026 - Cooks, Restaurant
 Prepare, season, and cook soups, meats, vegetables, desserts, and other foodstuffs in restaurants. May order supplies, keep records and accounts, price items on menu, or plan menu. 
 
65028 - Cooks, Institution or Cafeteria
 Prepare and cook family-style meals for institutions such as schools, hospitals, or cafeterias. Usually prepare meals in large quantities rather than to individual order. May cook for employees in office building or other large facility. 
 
65032 - Cooks, Fast Food
 Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited menu. Duties of the cooks are limited to preparation of a few basic items and normally involve operating large-volume single-purpose cooking equipment. 
 
65035 - Cooks, Short Order
 Prepare and cook to order a variety of foods that require only a short preparation time. May take orders from customers and serve patrons at counters or tables. Exclude Cooks, Fast Food. 
 
65038 - Food Preparation Workers
 Perform a variety of food preparation duties, such as preparing cold foods and maintaining and cleaning kitchen work areas, equipment, and utensils. Perform simple tasks such as preparing shellfish or slicing meat. May brew coffee and tea or prepare sandwiches. 
 
65041 - Combined Food Preparation and Service Workers
 Perform duties which combine both food preparation and food service. Workers who spend more than 80 percent of their time in one job should be reported in that occupation. 
 
65099 - All Other Food Service Workers
 All other food service workers not classified separately above. 

Health Service and Related Occupations
 
66002 - Dental Assistants
 Assist dentist at chair, set up patient and equipment, keep records, and perform related duties as required. 
 
66005 - Medical Assistants
 Perform various duties under the direction of physician in examination and treatment of patients. Prepare treatment room, inventory supplies and instruments, and set up patient for attention of physician. Hand instruments and materials to physician as directed. Schedule appointments, keep medical records, and perform secretarial duties. 
 
66008 - Nursing Aides, Orderlies, and Attendants
 Work under the direction of nursing or medical staff to provide auxiliary services in the care of patients. Perform duties such as answering patient&apos;s call bell, serving and collecting food trays, and feeding patients. Orderlies are primarily concerned with setting up equipment and relieving nurses of heavier work. Exclude Psychiatric Aides and Home Health Aides. 
 
66011 - Home Health Aides
 Care for elderly, convalescent, or handicapped person in home of patient. Perform duties for patient such as changing bed linen; preparing meals; assisting in and out of bed; bathing, dressing, and grooming; and administering oral medications under doctors&apos; orders or direction of nurse. Exclude Nursing Aides and Homemakers. 
 
66014 - Psychiatric Aides
 Assist mentally ill patients, working under direction of nursing and medical staff. 
 
66017 - Physical and Corrective Therapy Assistants and Aides
 Prepare patient and/or administer physical therapy treatment, such as massages, traction, and heat, light and sound treatment. Instruct, motivate, and assist patients with learning and improving functional activities. Normally work under the direction of a Physical or Corrective Therapist. 
 
66021 - Occupational Therapy Assistants and Aides
 Assist Occupational Therapists in administering medically-oriented occupational programs to assist in rehabilitating patients in hospitals and similar institutions. 
 
66023 - Ambulance Drivers and Attendants, Except Emergency Medical Technicians
 Drive ambulance or assist ambulance driver in transporting sick, injured, or convalescent persons. Assist in lifting patients and rendering first aid. May be required to have Red Cross first-aid training certificate. 
 
66099 - All Other Health Service Workers
 All other health service workers not classified separately above. 

Cleaning and Building Service Occupations
 
67002 - Maids and Housekeeping Cleaners
 Perform any combination of tasks to maintain private households or commercial establishments, such as hotels, restaurants and hospitals, in a clean and orderly manner. Duties include making beds, replenishing linens, cleaning rooms and halls, and arranging furniture. 
 
67005 - Janitors and Cleaners, Except Maids and Housekeeping Cleaners
 Keep buildings in clean and orderly condition. Perform heavy cleaning duties, such as operating motor-driven cleaning equipment, mopping floors, washing walls and glass, and removing rubbish. Duties may include tending furnace and boiler, performing routine maintenance activities, notifying management of need for repairs and additions, and cleaning snow or debris from sidewalk. 
 
67008 - Pest Controllers and Assistants
 Spray or release chemical solutions or toxic gases and set mechanical traps to kill pests and vermin such as mice, termites, and roaches, that infest buildings and surrounding areas. 
 
67011 - Elevator Operators
 Operate elevator to transport passengers and/or freight between floors of such buildings as offices, apartment houses, hotels, and stores. 
 
67099 - All Other Cleaning and Building Service Workers
 All other cleaning and building service workers not classified separately above. 

Personal Service Occupations
 
68002 - Barbers
 Provide customers with barbering services, including cutting, trimming, shampooing, and styling hair. Give shaves and shape contour of hair line. May sell lotions, tonics, and other cosmetic supplies. 
 
68005 - Hairdressers, Hairstylists, and Cosmetologists
 Provide beauty services, such as suggesting hair styles, cutting and treating hair and scalp, applying make-up, dressing wigs, and electrolysis, to customers. Exclude Shampooers, Manicurists, and Beauty School Instructors. 
 
68008 - Manicurists
 Clean, shape, and polish customers&apos; fingernails and toenails. 
 
68011 - Shampooers
 Specialize in shampooing hair and scalp with water or liquid shampoo and rinsing hair with prepared rinses. 
 
68014 - Amusement and Recreation Attendants
 Perform any of a variety of attending duties at amusement or recreation facility. Schedule use of recreation facilities, allocate equipment to participants of sporting events or recreational pursuits, collect fees for games played, or operate carnival rides and amusement concessions. 
 
68017 - Guides
 Escort individuals or groups on cruises, sightseeing tours, or through places of interest such as industrial establishments, public buildings, and art galleries. 
 
68021 - Ushers, Lobby Attendants, and Ticket Takers
 Assist patrons at entertainment events, such as sporting events, motion pictures, or theater performances. Collect admission tickets and passes from patrons. May assist in finding seats, searching for lost articles, and locating such facilities as rest rooms and telephones. 
 
68023 - Baggage Porters and Bellhops
 Carry baggage for travelers at transportation terminals or for guests at hotels or similar establishments. Additional duties include assisting handicapped persons, running errands, delivering ice, and directing people to their desired destinations. 
 
68026 - Flight Attendants
 Provide personal services to insure the safety and comfort of airline passengers during flight. Greet passengers, verify tickets, record destinations, and assign seats. Explain use of safety equipment. Serve meals and beverages. 
 
68028 - Transportation Attendants, Except Flight Attendants and Baggage Porters
 Provide personal services to insure the safety and comfort of passengers aboard ship, bus, or train. Greet passengers, explain use of safety equipment, serve meals and beverages, and answer questions related to travel. Exclude Flight Attendants. 
 
68032 - Wardrobe, and Locker and Dressing Room Attendants
 Care for costumes or uniforms. Distribute and keep record of clothing and related equipment issued and returned. Assist in dressing. May select and fit costumes for cast members, arrange for cleaning and pressing, and make minor alterations. Exclude Tailors and Dressmakers. 
 
68035 - Personal and Home Care Aides
 Perform a variety of tasks at places of residence. Duties include keeping house and advising families having problems with such things as nutrition, cleanliness, and household utilities. Exclude Nursing Aides and Home Health Aides. 
 
68038 - Child Care Workers
 Attend to children at child care centers, schools, businesses, and institutions. Perform variety of tasks such as dressing, feeding, bathing, and overseeing play. Exclude Preschool Teachers and Teacher Aides. 
 
68041 - Funeral Attendants
 Perform variety of tasks during funeral such as placing casket in parlor or chapel prior to service; arranging floral offerings or lights around casket; directing or escorting mourners; closing casket; and issuing and storing funeral equipment. 

Other Service Occupations
 
69999 - All Other Service Workers
 All other service workers not classified separately above. 

 1998 Occupational Employment and Wage Estimates 

 1998 National Occupational Employment and Wage Estimates 

 1998 State Occupational Employment and Wage Estimates 

 1998 Metropolitan Area Occupational Employment and Wage Estimates 

 Technical Notes and Survey Method and Reliability Statement for 1998 OES Estimates 

 Last modified: October 16, 2001
 Recommend this page using: Facebook Twitter LinkedIn 
 
 
tools
 Areas at a Glance Industries at a Glance Economic Releases Databases&amp;Tables Maps 

 
calculators
 Inflation Location Quotient Injury And Illness 

 
help
 Help&amp;Tutorials FAQs Glossary About BLS Contact Us 

 
info
 What&apos;s New Careers @ BLS Find It! DOL Join our Mailing Lists Linking&amp;Copyright Info 

 
resources
 Inspector General (OIG) Budget and Performance No Fear Act USA.gov Benefits.gov Disability.gov 
 
 Freedom of Information Act  |  Privacy&amp;Security Statement  |  Disclaimers  |  Customer Survey  |  Important Web Site Notices 
 
 U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics | Division of Occupational Employment Statistics, PSB Suite 2135, 2 Massachusetts Avenue, NE Washington, DC 20212-0001 

 www.bls.gov/OES | Telephone: 1-202-691-6569 | Contact OES
	</body>
</document>
