<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007818" url="http://www.webanswers.com/legal/when-you-are-parking-uphill-and-you-re-on-the-curb-which-way-do-you-turn-the-wheels-2d38b1" time="2012-07-13-00:46" support="1" score="0.00013387276773154768" bingtitle="When you are parking uphill and you&apos;re on the curb, which way do ..." webtitle="When you are parking uphill and youre on the curb, which way do you turn the wheels? - WebAnswers.com">
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="112"/>
	<description>Don&apos;t forget to set the parking brake after you cut your wheels and put your car in park. ... Specifically a fast food restaurant, 6 inches? 7 inches? 8 inches? The ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome New User! ( Create Account | Sign In ) 
 Answer Questions and Earn Money! Join Us 
 How WebAnswers Works | Become an Expert | FAQs | Advanced Search | Leaderboards | Earn Money Maximize 
 Start earning today! 
 
 You are here: Home   Categories   Legal   When you are parking uphill and you&apos;re on the curb, which way do you turn the wheels? 
     Which way do you turn your steering wheel When parking up hill with no curb? I hear a&quot;thud&quot;sound When shifting from park to reverse gear on a uphill /downhill road. Hello, i bought a certified used 2005 honda accord lx with approximately 55k miles on it.... Which way do you turn your wheels When parking on a hill? Ran over a parking curb in lowered car, what is the damage? My friend ran over a parking curb in my lowered car. on the ride home it made a rattling noise,... Which way should your wheel be turn ed When parked uphill with a curb? Click here to ask a question about anything! 

 
 Get paid for participating 
 Ask questions - It&apos;s FREE Get answers within minutes. Fun, fast and easy. Share your opinions with our community. Earn money for answering. See how. 
This Question has not been awarded yet.

 Post your answer now! 
 Find more related questions to When you are parking uphill and you&apos;re on the curb, which way do you turn the wheels? Question 
Submitted 818 days ago...
 
 Boracic619 

New User (1)
 
When you are parking uphill and you&apos;re on the curb, which way do you turn the wheels?


 Share | Abuse |   Answers Answer 1 / 1 - Submitted 799 days ago... 
 
 brainpack 

Brain (6,709)
 
To brace your car when parking uphill, you have to turn your wheels sharply away from the curb and back up slowly until the rear of the tire is against the curb. Don&apos;t forget to set the parking brake after you cut your wheels and put your car in park.
 Share | Link | Abuse         
 Answer This Question Now 
 
When you are parking uphill and you&apos;re on the curb, which way do you turn the wheels?

If your Answer is chosen as the “accepted” answer, you will earn ongoing royalties on this thread.
Simply type your Answer in the box below and post your answer.
 Learn more about how WebAnswers.com works 
 Add picture 
 

 Email Subscriptions 

 Author adds clarification

 All new responses Related Questions Parking a car 

Well I am a new driver and parking can be challenging for me. I rarely have to parallel park on my block I can just ride into the spot but I still have to adjust my car so that the rear end isn&apos;t sticking...
 Awarded to: Piarejuden | Category: Other&amp;Miscellaneous | 4 Replies Curb height 

What is the maximum allowable height for a curb/sidewalk at the entrance to a commercial property. Specifically a fast food restaurant, 6 inches? 7 inches? 8 inches? The maximum height or the range of heights...
 Open | Category: Other&amp;Miscellaneous | 2 Replies Can you fix chrome wheels that get scraped from a curb? 


 Open | Category: Car Makes | 1 Reply I have a Kabota BX23.When I turn the steering the wheels do not turn.What can I do to remedy it? 

Once when using the tractor the steering quit working. After sitting for a couple of hours it worked again. When driving down the road the wheels wander to the right or left as if there is lost motion in the steering....
 Open | Category: Other&amp;Miscellaneous | 2 Replies Parking at end of court 

What is the law (Hayward CA) for parking at end of a court? For over 10 years we have parked with front of car into curb to allow room for all cars at end of court. Please advise. Also is there a maximum number...
 Open | Category: Autos&amp;Transportation | 0 Replies   Overview | FAQs | Contact Us | Member Agreement | Privacy Policy | Site Map | Partners 

 * NEW Referral Program | Link to this page Copyright©WebAnswers 2012. All rights reserved. X 

 Close this window
	</body>
</document>
