<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007379" url="http://www.snagajob.com/restaurant-jobs/fast-food/little-caesars/" time="2012-07-13-00:21" support="10" score="0.027236053708841742" bingtitle="Little Caesar&apos;s Jobs | Little Caesar&apos;s Job Applications | Find ..." webtitle="Little Caesars Jobs | Little Caesars Job Applications | Find Fast Food Jobs on Snagajob">
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>You&apos;ll benefit from our training and career opportunities and receive reward and ... Fast Food Jobs Now Hiring Click on an employer below to see more fast food jobs and ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you an employer? To post jobs or get hiring solutions, please visit our employer website . Hide this message x 
 Browse Jobs Job Tips Join Today Sign In 
 
 FIND LOCAL JOBS 
 Search with keywords BETA 
Find Little Caesar&apos;s Jobs Near You


 Jobs by title 
 Team Members Shift Leaders Assistant Managers 
 Jobs by category 
 Full-time Little Caesar&apos;s jobs Part-time Little Caesar&apos;s jobs Little Caesar&apos;s jobs for teens 
 
See all Little Caesar&apos;s Jobs now hiring!
 
 
Similar Fast Food Jobs

 Papa John&apos;s Pizza Hut Domino&apos;s   Who else is hiring for fast food jobs ? Looking for more restaurant jobs ? We got&apos;em.
 
 
Little Caesar&apos;s Job Applications

 Team Members 

The Crew Member works productively as part of the restaurant team and performs their job responsibilities in such a way that all the products they make are of high quality and the customers they serve are satisfied.

 Job Responsibilities: 

 Serves customers according to the Ten Customer Service Standards, the Five Priority Guidelines, the Remedy Process, and the telephone and front counter procedures. Prepares high quality products consistently by following Little Caesars recipes, specifications and procedures as described in the C.A.R.D.S. materials and as shown on the station job helpers. Displays the proper image as outlined in the Little Caesars Orientation and Training Handbook and or as directed by the management staff. Cleans and organizes work stations and other assigned areas to help maintain the standards for restaurant image. Practices safety and security procedures as defined in the Little Caesars Colleague Orientation and Training Handbook and by government agencies. Follows Little Caesars&apos; policies, procedures, and standards of conduct as outlined in the Little Caesars Orientation and Training Handbook and as directed by management. 

SEARCH AND APPLY FOR LITTLE CAESAR&apos;S TEAM MEMBER JOBS NOW!

 Shift Leaders 

If you’re ready to take the next step in your career in restaurant management, our Shift Leader position is the right place to do it. Working as a Shift Leader will let you develop your management skills while still having the time to do the things you enjoy. You&apos;ll benefit from our training and career opportunities and receive reward and recognition for your efforts.

 Primary Qualifications 

 Execute cash management duties with POS and Shift Reports. Assist in the management of adequate inventory levels using the company’s systems and guidelines to minimize loss. Manage company’s assets by ensuring the restaurant is clean, safe and organized; complies with safety and security standards at all times You must be hard working, team-oriented, friendly, honest and have great customer service skills. Reliable transportation to and from work Ability to lift 50lbs Ability to lead a team with no supervision and build an atmosphere of teamwork, energy and fun Ability to work with phones, computers, fax machines and copiers Ability to successfully perform the job duties of all positions in the restaurant, including pizza delivery Communicate, train and promote quality standards to team members Professionally and promptly, respond to all customer concerns or issues. 

SEARCH AND APPLY FOR LITTLE CAESAR&apos;S SHIFT LEADER JOBS NOW!

 Assistant Managers 

As a top international pizza chain in business for more than 40 years, Little Caesars offers tremendous opportunities in operations management. As a family owned company, we take an active interest in the professional growth of our team members. This personal approach to career development allows our work force to feel recognized and rewarded.

We offer an outstanding training program that will develop you in all areas of restaurant operations. Little Caesars recognizes that today’s work force expects to be challenged and to have opportunities to grow. In fact, many of our Vice-Presidents started out as Crew Members and Assistant Managers. Our “promote from within” philosophy works . . . and we know it!

As an Assistant Manager at Little Caesars, you will have the opportunity to be a partner with us, in helping your restaurant to achieve sales growth and profitability. In addition, there is tremendous opportunity for advancement.

SEARCH AND APPLY FOR LITTLE CAESAR&apos;S ASSISTANT MANAGER JOBS NOW!
 
Restaurant Job Resource Center
 See all restaurant job articles » 
 
 Waiter / Waitress jobs 
 Want to be a Bartender? 
 Turn your restaurant job into a career 
 
Fast Food Jobs Now Hiring

Click on an employer below to see more fast food jobs and submit an online job application now!
 
 Arby&apos;s Bojangles&apos; Boston Market Burger King Captain D&apos;s Chick-fil-A Chipotle 
 
 Dairy Queen Domino&apos;s Pizza Dunkin&apos; Donuts Hardee&apos;s KFC Little Caesars McDonald&apos;s 
 
 Papa John&apos;s Pizza Hut Popeye&apos;s Sonic Drive-In Subway Taco Bell Wendy&apos;s 
 

 
Quick Facts: Little Caesar&apos;s


 Little Caesars was founded by Michael Illitch and his wife Marian in 1959. Mike Illitch also owns the Detroit Tigers and Detroit Red Wings. Little Caesars&apos; catchphrase &apos;Pizza! Pizza!&apos; originally referred to their pricing strategy that would give consumers two pizzas for the price of one. Little Caesars once held the record for filling the largest pizza order in history, delivering 13,386 pizzas to a single location in 1998. Little Caesars is the largest carry-out pizza chain in the world. 
 


 
Sign up for email Job Alerts
 Get local jobs delivered to your inbox. Email Address ZIP Code Submit 
 
 Snagajob Job Seeker Security Center Local Jobs Job Tips Job Seeker Blog My Job, My Health Coupons Right-Fit Degrees Help and FAQ Contact Us Employer Solutions Post Jobs Talent Sourcing Hiring Manager Training Manager Scheduling Manager Recruitment Ad Agency Advertise with Us Affiliate Program Contact Sales About Snagajob Careers Our Story Giving Back Life at Snagajob News ©2000-2012 SnagAJob.com, Inc. All rights reserved Privacy Terms of Use Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
