<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007973" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/12/brew_coffee_from_a_faucet_yes.php" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="1" score="0.000848679260639637" bingtitle="Brew Coffee From A Faucet With Your iPhone: Yes, There Is An App ..." webtitle="Brew Coffee From A Faucet With Your iPhone: Yes, There Is An App For That - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="43"/>
	<description>Why wait for a cup of coffee? This thing ... of the TopBrewer has yet to be announced, but expect ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Kitchen Gadgets 
Brew Coffee From A Faucet With Your iPhone: Yes, There Is An App For That
 By David Minsky Mon., Dec. 5 2011 at 9:26 AM Categories: Kitchen Gadgets 
 Pin It 
 
 
​ Makers of Denmark-based Scanomat decided that a substance almost as necessary as water should be as readily available. Coffee!

This ain&apos;t no typical brew machine. The TopBrewer looks like a a faucet and mounts to your countertop. It not only brews and dispenses coffee but also is equipped with undercounter components including two high-output grinders, a juicing system, the world&apos;s smallest milk frother, dispensing lines, and a refrigerator. Quit hating, Starbucks.
 
Why wait for a cup of coffee? This thing minimizes grinding time per cup to only one second, churning out four cups of coffee per minute, and with precision settings, it can sling a cup of espresso every 25 seconds.

It even cleans itself, both coffee and milk lines, after every use, and cleans itself again for about a minute after each day of heavy use.

What&apos;s more, this coffee contraption can be wirelessly interfaced with an iPhone or iPad. With a few simple taps of the screen, every function can be controlled, except refilling coffee beans and liquids, which requires you to actually get out of your chair.

It&apos;s environmentally friendly too, made entirely with recyclable stainless steel and aluminum. It saves energy by powering down to standby mode after periods of inactivity, taking only 45 seconds to power back up with the push of a button.

The TopBrewer employs a new boiler system that leaves the water cold, heating to temperature when brewed, ensuring maximum concentration of oxygen per cup, resulting in a better-tasting beverage, according to Scanomat&apos;s website .

The price of the TopBrewer has yet to be announced, but expect to pay at least a few hundred bones for it.

Now that Scanomat has blessed humanity with this new invention, can someone hurry up and invent a beer faucet?

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Coffee , Scanomat Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
How much does it cost?
 
This brew machine is amazing. Coffee faucet or beer faucet?
 
I&apos;m in awe. Those wily Danes have hit a home run with this one. If it uses high quality [read: coffee snob worthy] then even better.
 

TotalComments: 3
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Hy Vong Vietnamese Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
Grimpa Steakhouse
 View Ad | View Site 
Mo&apos;s Bagels&amp;Deli
 View Ad | View Site 
High Steaks BBQ
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 The Next Rendition of the Harding Dinner Series; Menu for Balloo and Zapata &quot;Dinner With Friends&quot; Developer Gil Dezer To Knock Down a Miami Institution Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
