<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007038" url="http://www.ar15.com/forums/t_1_5/1285501_McDonald_s_drive_through_line_cutter_gets_tased_LOL.html" time="2012-07-13-00:01" support="9" score="0.018797560915443535" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s drive through line cutter gets tased LOL - AR15.COM" webtitle="McDonald&apos;s drive through line cutter gets tased LOL - AR15.COM">
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>why would you want to cut in line? they wont even have your order? sounds like laquisha ... If cops can&apos;t resolve someone cutting in line at a fast food restaurant without ...</description>
	<body>
		Ammo Oracle 
 Range Search 
 Weapon Library 
 -------------------- 
 Online Store 
 Mail Server 
 Chat Server 
 Mobile Version 
  Login System    User Name 
 Password 
 
    Forgot Password 
 Login ? Tools AR15.Com 3 Gun Nation Archery Store Join The NRA 5,164 Online AR-15 AK-47 Handgun Armory Training General Outdoors Hometown Industry Equipment Exchange Archives Conduct Code General    General Discussion Gloftoe 
 John_Wayne777 
 joker581 
 krpind 
 mcculver5 
 Tango7 [ARCHIVED THREAD] - McDonald&apos;s drive through line cutter gets tased LOL   (Page 1 of 4) ARCHIVED   Previous Page Page:  - 1 - - 2 - - 3 - - 4 -  / 4 Next Page Author Message 
 AssaultRifler Get off my lawn
 Team Member 
 Joined: Sep 2004  USA 
 Posts: 30396
 Feedback: 100% (87) 
 Posted: 2/4/2012 8:16:29 PM 
 THE IMAGE ABOVE IS A PAID ADVERTISEMENT 
 http://www.fayobserver.com/articles/2012/02/03/1155055?sac=fo.local 

 Hope
 Mills, N.C. Authorities had to use a stun gun Friday on a woman who 
cut the drive-thru line at a Cumberland County McDonald&apos;s and became 
argumentative when employees wouldn&apos;t take her order. 
 McDonald&apos;s workers 
told deputies that the woman bypassed the order screen and the first 
drive-thru window, where customers pay for their orders, and went 
straight to the pick-up window at the restaurant, at Legion Road and 
Black and Decker Road in Hope Mills. 
 The woman had a 
3-year-old child in the car with her and asked if she could order and 
pay at the pick-up window, authorities said. When McDonald&apos;s employees 
told her that they didn&apos;t have a register at that window and she needed 
to go to the back of the line, she refused. 
 The woman blocked the line for 20 minutes, refusing to move, before workers called Cumberland County deputies. 
 Debbie Tanna, a 
spokeswoman for the Cumberland County Sheriff&apos;s Office, said the woman 
became belligerent when deputies arrived, and they had to use to Taser 
on her to subdue her and take her into custody.

&lt;snip&gt;
 &quot;Two or three officers entered the car with her and started trying to 
forcibly drag her out of the car, and that&apos;s when you could hear the 
clicking sound of the Taser one time,&quot;Rich said.&quot;They pulled on her a 
couple of times, and then they Tased (stunned) her again, and when they 
Tased (stunned) her the second time, she just flopped out of the car 
like a fish.

&lt;snip&gt;
 
 &quot;Bullets change governments far surer than votes..&quot;- Lord of War 2005

&quot;The trouble with socialism is that you eventually run out of other people&apos;s money&quot;Margaret Thatcher
 
 User Info 
 
 victorgonzales destroyer of liberals
 Team Member 
 Joined: Oct 2008  AZ, USA Posts: 17817
 Feedback: 100% (2) 
 Link To This Post 
 Posted: 2/4/2012 8:19:13 PM I hopr tht poor kid in the car has someone else to learn from. 
 I will outlive every democrat voter I know so I can piss on their grave. 
 User Info 
 
 Bama-Shooter You do your thing. I&apos;ll do mine.
 Site Staff 
 Joined: Apr 2004  USA 
 Posts: 84559
 Feedback: 100% (33) 
 Link To This Post 
 Posted: 2/4/2012 8:25:27 PM 
 American by birth, Southern by the grace of God.

Constitutional carry is a right not a privilege.

Any opinions expressed are my own and do not reflect upon any agency or organization with which I may be employed or affiliated. 
 User Info 
 
 Superreverb Member
 Team Member 
 Joined: Mar 2006  MD, USA Posts: 735
 Feedback: 0% (0) 
 Link To This Post 
 Posted: 2/4/2012 8:29:02 PM &quot;They pulled on her a couple of times, and then they Tased (stunned) her again, and when they Tased (stunned) her the second time, she just flopped out of the car like a Filet O&apos; fish.&quot; 

Fixed 
 &quot;Asking liberals where wages and prices come from is like asking six-year olds where babies come from.&quot;- Thomas Sowell 
 User Info 
 
 MACD Member
 Team Member 
 Joined: Jun 2006  TX, USA Posts: 14765
 Feedback: 100% (7) 
 Link To This Post 
 Posted: 2/4/2012 8:30:52 PM The Rosa Parks of our time 
 Romney is anti-gun
	</body>
</document>
