<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007901" url="http://www.tripbd.com/destination/Dhaka" time="2012-07-13-00:52" support="1" score="0.0015964177105101212" bingtitle="Dhaka Bangladesh - Travel Destinations Review | TripBD" webtitle="Dhaka Bangladesh - Travel Destinations Review | TripBD">
			<query id="001069" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>... Dhaka city, the garden with its rich collection ... and especially near Gulshan) sell imported condiments ... Attached to a fast food restaurant (&apos;Chicken King ...</description>
	<body>
		We are working rigorously on our site to launch the next major version. In the mean time we are deeply sorry for any problem you are facing browsing tripbd.com.
Please feel free to write us a line, any suggestion, any error you see on the site at info@tripbd.com or instead you can contact us via the contact form . 
 13 Jul 12, Fri
Dhaka 04:52 
 12 Jul 12, Thu
London 23:52 12 Jul 12, Thu
New York 18:52 13 Jul 12, Fri
Riyadh 01:52 13 Jul 12, Fri
Sydney 08:52 more about time + 
 dhaka
T:28°c | H:89% 
 chittagong
T:28°c | H:89% sylhet
T:27°c | H:95% khulna
T:28°c | H:89% barishal
T:28°c | H:89% more about weather + 
 USD 1 = BDT 81.93
BDT 1 = USD 0.0122 
 EUR 1 = BDT 99.938
BDT 1 = EUR 0.0100 JPY 1 = BDT 1.0334
BDT 1 = JPY 0.9676 GBP 1 = BDT 126.41
BDT 1 = GBP 0.0079 CAD 1 = BDT 80.382
BDT 1 = CAD 0.0124 more about currency + 
 Transport Information 
 Train Transport Bus Transport Air Transport Water Transport more about transport + 
 
 
 HOME DESTINATIONS HOTELS TOUR PACKAGES ARTICLES EVENTS BANGLADESH Travel Guide Contact Us 
 
 Home Dhaka 
 
Branding Bangladesh in Tourism
 + List your hotel, it&apos;s free. Select destination -Destination- Bagerhat  ⇒ Shatgombujj Mosque Bandarban  ⇒ Bandarban Barishal  ⇒ Barishal Bogra  ⇒ Mahasthangarh Chittagong  ⇒ Chittagong Comilla  ⇒ Maynamati Cox&apos;s Bazar  ⇒ Cox&apos;s Bazar  ⇒ Saint Martins Island Dhaka  ⇒ Dhaka  ⇒ Sonargaon Dinajpur  ⇒ Kantaji Temple Khulna  ⇒ Sundarbans Kustia  ⇒ Shilaidah Natore  ⇒ Natore Netrokona  ⇒ Birishiri Noagaon  ⇒ Paharpur Buddhist Monastery Potuakhali  ⇒ Kuakata Rajshahi  ⇒ Rajshahi Rangamati  ⇒ Rangamati Sherpur  ⇒ Gajni Sylhet  ⇒ Jaflong  ⇒ Madhabkunda  ⇒ Sreemangal  ⇒ Sylhet Select Price Range To Select by accomodation 
 single room double room tripple room 4 bed room suite banglow cottage dormitory 
 
 Call Us 24/7 

 +8801829440044 
 Featured Hotel 
 
 Hotel Agrabad 

 Chittagong 

Hotel Agrabad is a spectaculary designed and added with traditional hospitality of courteous,attractive and
 
 Pebble Stone Sea Resort Pvt Limited 

 Cox&apos;s Bazar 

The Cox&apos;s Bazar district of Bangladesh is completely packed with the natural b
 
 Hotel Lord&apos;s Inn (Pvt.) Ltd 

 Chittagong 

HOTEL LORD&apos;S INN&apos; a three star standard hotel with a multi cuisine restaurant,conference hall a new landmar
 
 
TripBD is your complete travel solution.
Do you need a hotel reservation? Bus or train ticket? tour package?
Just call 01829 44 00 44 or visit www.tripbd.com to send your requirement.
 
Dhaka - City of Mosques and Capital of Bangladesh

 Write a review on your latest tour at Dhaka 

 General Geography&amp;Weather To see To Do Trasportaions Entertainment Emergency Help 
 Showing - 1 of 339 Photo(s) || 0 Video(s) || 5781 View(s) Photo: TripBD Team   Pevious Next 83 Hotels | 3 Article(s) | 20 Member Visited 
A symbol of thriving, colorful and congested metropolis is the centre city of Bangladesh. Of some 12million people and growing steadily, Dhaka is one of the most frenetic places on Earth. The streets and rivers are filled with colorful chaos. Dhaka with its exciting history and rich culture; known to the world as the city of mosques and muslin. Experiencing the city for the first time can often seem overwhelming. The capital of Bangladesh Dhaka has attracted travelers from far and near through ages. It has history dating back to the earliest time. But the exact date of its foundation is not known. However, according to recorded history, it was founded in 1608 A.D. as the seat of the imperial Mughal Viceroy of Bengal. Having a happy blending of the old and new architectural trends, Dhaka has been developing fast as a modem city since 1982 and is throbbing with activities in all spheres of life, be it industrial, commercial, cultural or political.

Dhaka, formerly known as Dacca and Jahangir Nagar; is the principal city of Dhaka District. It is one of the major mega cities of South Asia. It’s situated on the banks of the Burigana River. Its metropolitan area has a population of over 12 million which makes it the largest city in Bangladesh. Dhaka was renowned for producing the world&apos;s finest muslin. As a cosmopolitan city, Dhaka has been the center of Persio-Arabic and Western cultural influences in eastern Indian Subcontinent. Today it serves as one of the prime centers for culture, education and business in the region.

The Days Gone By

The exact date of Dhaka’s foundation is not known. But the existence of urbanized settlements in the area that is now Dhaka dates from the 7th century. The Buddhist kingdom of Kamarupa and the Pala Empire ruled the city area before passing the control to the Hindu Sena dynasty in the 9th century. The name of the city may have taken after the establishment of the Goddess Dhakeshwari&apos;s temple by Ballal Sena in the 12th century. Dhaka and its adjacent area were identified as Bengalla around that period. The town itself consisted of a few market centers like Lakshmi Bazar, Shankhari Bazar, Tanti Bazar, Patuatuli, Kumartuli, Bania Nagar and Goal Nagar. Dhaka was successively ruled by the Turkicand Pashtun governors descending from the Delhi Sultanate before the arrival of the Mughals in 1608 after the Sena Dynasty.

The city was proclaimed to be the capital of Bengal under Mughal rule in 1608. As a result, the development of townships and a significant growth in population came. The first administrator of the city was Mughal subahdar Islam Khan. In honor of the Mughal emperor Jahangir, Subahdar Islam Khan named the town &quot;Jahangir Nagar&quot; (City of Jahangir), although this name was changed soon after Jahangir&apos;s death. The main development of the city took place under Mughal general Shaista Khan. The city then measured 19 by 13 kilometres (12 by 8 mi), with a population of nearly one million people. After the Battle of Plassey, the city passed to the control of the British East India Company in 1765. The city&apos;s population reduced in size dramatically during this period as the prominence of Kolkata rose, but substantive development and modernization ultimately followed. A modern civic water supply system was launched in 1874 and electricity supply was introduced in 1878. The Dhaka Cantonment was established near the city, serving as a base for British and Bengali soldiers.

Dhaka was declared to be the capital of the newly established state of East Bengal and Assam after the partition of Bengal in 1905, but Bengal was reunited in 1911. When India was partitioned in 1947, Dhaka became the capital of East Pakistan. The city observed major communal violence during the partition period of India. A large proportion of the city&apos;s Hindu population departed for India, while the city received a large influx of Muslims. As the center of regional politics, Dhaka saw an increasing number of political strikes and incidents of violence. The implementation of Urdu as the sole official language of Pakistan led to protest marches involving large crowds. Known as the Bengali Language Movement, the protests resulted in police firing which killed a number of peaceful student demonstrators. Dhaka remained a hotbed of political activity throughout the 1950s and 1960s. And the demands for autonomy for the Bengali population steadily gained momentum.

East Pakistan (present Bangladesh) was devastated by the 1970 Bhola cyclone, killing an estimated 500,000 people. The region’s more than half of the cities were flooded and millions of people were stranded. With public anger growing against ethnic discrimination and poor cyclone relief efforts from the central government, one of the greatest Bengali politicians Sheikh Mujibur Rahman held a nationalist gathering on March 7, 1971 at the Race Course Ground. An estimated one million people attended the assembly, leading to the March 26 declaration of independence of Bangladesh. In response, the Pakistan Army launched Operation Searchlight, which led to the arrests, torture and killing of thousands of people. After nine months of bloody battle with Bangladeshi Freedom Fighters, the Pakistani Army surrendered to the Mitra Bahini (put the English of this one…) on December 16 marking the end of the independence war of Bangladesh. As the nation&apos;s capital, Dhaka saw a rapid and massive growth of the city population in the post-independence period, as migrant workers from rural areas across Bangladesh moved to the city. The growth of commerce and industry along with the city&apos;s population has created further challenges to services and infrastructure. A real estate boom has followed the expansion of city limits and the development of new settlements such as Uttara, Mohammadpur, Bashundhara, Mirpur and Motijheel (more of the names of cities should come out…).
 83 Hotels | 3 Article(s) | 20 Member Visited 
Geography and Weather

 
 Dhaka 
 
 Nickname (s): City of Mosques
 
Coordinates: 23°42′0″N 90°22′30″E﻿/﻿23.7°N 90.375°E 
 
 Country 
 
 Bangladesh 
 
 Administrative District 
 
 Dhaka District 
 
 Government 
 
  -  Mayor 
 
 Sadeque Hossain Khoka 
 
 Area 
 
  - City 
 
153.84 km2 (59.4 sq mi)
 
 Population (2007) [1] 
 
  - City 
 
6,737,774
 
  -  Density 
 
43,797.3/km2 (113,434.5/sq mi)
 
  - Metro 
 
12,295,728
 
 Time zone 
 
 BST ( UTC+6 )
 

Dhaka is positioned in central Bangladesh, geographically it’s located at 23°42&apos;0?N 90°22&apos;30?E / 23.7°N 90.375°E, on the eastern banks of the Buriganga River. It lies on the lower reaches of the Ganges Delta and covers a total area of 153.84 square kilometres (59.40 sq mi). The city has seven principal Thanas–Dhanmondi, Kotwali, Motijheel, Paltan, Ramna, Mohammadpur, Sutrapur, Tejgaon–and 16 auxiliary Thanas–Gulshan, Lalbagh, Mirpur, Pallabi, Shah Ali, Turaag, Sabujbagh, Dhaka Cantonment, Demra, Hazaribagh, Shyampur, Badda, Kafrul, Kamrangir char, Khilgaon and Uttara (is it updated?). In total the city consists of 130 wards and 725 mohallas (is it updated?). As a district, Dhaka district has an area of 1463.60 square kilometres (565 sq mi); and is bounded by the districts of Gazipur, Tangail, Munshiganj, Rajbari, Narayanganj, Manikganj. The land is characterized by tropical vegetation and moist soil, which is flat and close to sea level. This leaves Dhaka vulnerable to flooding during the monsoon seasons due to heavy rainfall and cyclones.

A hot, wet and humid tropical climate is the main characteristics of weather of Dhaka. The city is inside the monsoon climate zone, with an annual average temperature of 25°C (77°F) and monthly means differs between 18°C (64°F) in January and 29°C (84°F) in August. Almost 80% of the annual average rainfall of 1,854 millimeters (73 in) occurs between May and September. (Check if it is updated or not!) Increasing air and water pollution come from traffic congestion and industrial waste are serious problems affecting public health and the quality of life in the city. Water bodies and wetlands around Dhaka are facing extinction as these are being filled up to construct multi-storied buildings and other real estate developments. Coupled with pollution, such erosion of natural habitats threatens to destroy much of the regional biodiversity.(too much of negative words…can you rephrase?)
 
 
  Weather averages for Dhaka  
 
 Month 
 
 Jan 
 
 Feb 
 
 Mar 
 
 Apr 
 
 May 
 
 Jun 
 
 Jul 
 
 Aug 
 
 Sep 
 
 Oct 
 
 Nov 
 
 Dec 
 
 Year 
 
 Average high°F (°C) 
 
76
(24)
 
80
(27)
 
87
(31)
 
89
(32)
 
91
(33)
 
88
(31)
 
90
(32)
 
88
(31)
 
87
(31)
 
87
(31)
 
83
(28)
 
77
(25)
 
85
(29)
 
 Average low°F (°C) 
 
58
(14)
 
63
(17)
 
72
(22)
 
77
(25)
 
79
(26)
 
81
(27)
 
81
(27)
 
81
(27)
 
80
(27)
 
77
(25)
 
69
(21)
 
61
(16)
 
73
(23)
 
 Precipitation inches (mm) 
 
0.3
(7.6)
 
0.8
(20.3)
 
2.3
(58.4)
 
4.6
(116.8)
 
10.5
(266.7)
 
14.1
(358.1)
 
15.7
(398.8)
 
12.5
(317.5)
 
10.1
(256.5)
 
6.4
(162.6)
 
1.2
(30.5)
 
0.2
(5.1)
 
77.9
(1,978.7)
 
 Source: weatherbase.com 2009-04-15 
 
 
Places to See

Dhaka mostly was a city of the Mughals. In the years of their dynamic rule the following Governors and princely Viceroys who ruled the province, ornamented it with many noble monuments, mosques, tombs, fortifications and &apos;Katras&apos; often surrounded with beautifully laid out gardens and pavilions. The Parliament building designed by Louis Kahn is unquestionably something to see along with numerous memorials, parks and mosques. Places worth visiting include: Ramna Park, Lal Bagh Fort and museum, Old Dhaka, the Shahid Minar memorial, the Shadarghat port, Ahsan Manjil, Bangabandhu Memorial, National Poet&apos;s Graveyard, Suhrawardy Uddyaan, National Leader Mausoleum, Banga-Bhaban, Shadhinota Stambha, Curzon Hall, Old High Court and 1857 Memorial, the Botanical Gardens, Baldha Garden, Sitara Mosque, Baitul Mukarram Mosque as well as Hindu, Buddhist and Christian churches and temples.

 Ahsan Manjil : Ahsan Manzil was once the palace of the Dhaka Nawab Family ; it is now a museum. The pink palace has a Tk 2 entrance fee (???) and a small exhibition about the history of the palace and a garden. Mosques around Dhaka : Dhaka has several hundred mosques for which it’s known as the city of Mosques. Well-known are Baitul Mukarram-National Mosque, the Seven Domed Mosque (17th century), Star Mosque (18th century) inlaid with mosaic and tiles , Chawkbazar Mosque and Huseni Dalan Mosque. Hindu Temples : the main Hindu Temples that you should see are - Dhakeshwari Temple (11th Century), Ramkrishna Mission. Churches : As Dhaka was the main city of Bengal during the Christian colony period, there many beautiful Churches you can see. Such as - Armenian Church (1781 A.D.) St. Mary&apos;s Cathedral at Ramna, Church of Bangladesh or former Holy Rosary Church (1677A.D.) at Tejgaon. Buddhist Temples : Dhammarajika Bouddha Maha Vihar, Atisha Dipankar Sarak, Kamalapur is a Buddhist Temple that you might see. The National Memorial : Situated at Savar, 35 km. from Dhaka city. The memorial designed by architect Moinul Hossain is devoted to the holy memory of the millions of unknown martyrs of the war of liberation. Lalbagh Fort : It was built in 1678 A.D. by Prince Mohammad Azam, son of Mughal emperor Aurangazeb. The fort was the scene of bloody battle during the first war of independence (1857) when 260 sepoys stationed here backed by the people revolted against British forces. Monuments of the Lalbagh which are outstanding include the, tomb of Pari Bibi , Lalbagh Mosque, Audience Hall and Hammam of Nawab Shaista Khan now housing a museum. The fort is closed on Saturday but open until 5pm every other day. 1857 Memorial : ( Bahadur Shah Park) Built to commemorate the martyrs of the first liberation war (1857-59) against British rule. It was here that the revolting sepoys and their civil compatriots were publicly hanged. Curzon Hall : Beautiful architectural building named after Lord Curzon. It now houses the Science Faculty of Dhaka University. Old High Court Building : Originally built as the residence of the British Governor, it illustrates a happy blend of European and Mughal architecture. National Park : Situated at Rejendrapur, 40 km. north of Dhaka city, this is a gigantic (1,600 acres) national recreational forest with facilities for picnics and rowing etc. Central Shahid Minar : Symbol of Bengali nationalism. This monument was built to honor the martyrs of the historic Language movement of 1952. Hundreds and thousands of people with floral wreaths and bouquets gather (most march barefoot) on 21 February every year (designated by the UN as International Mother Language Day) to pay respect to the departed in a solemn atmosphere. Celebrations begin at midnight. National Poet&apos;s Graveyard : Revolutionary poet Kazi Nazrul Islam died on the 29 August 1976 and was buried here. The burial ground is adjacent to the Dhaka University Mosque. Suhrawardy Uddyan (Garden) : A Popular Park. The vow of independence of Bangladesh was taken here and the Father of the Nation Bangabandhu Sheik Mujibur Rahman gave the clarion call for independence on the 7th March 1971. The place is famous for its lush greenery and gentle breezes. An eternal flame in remembrance of the martyrs of the war of Liberation burns here. Mausoleum of National Leaders : Located at the southwestern corner of Suhrawardy Uddyan, it is the eternal resting place of great national leaders, Sher-e-Bangla A.K. Fazlul Haque, Hossain Shahid Suhrawardy and Khaja Nazimuddin. Banga Bhaban : The official residence of the President, located in the city. One can have an outside view of this grand palace. Baldha Garden : Unique creation of the late Narendra Narayan Roy, the landlord of Baldha. Year of establishment was 1904. Located in Wari area of Dhaka city, the garden with its rich collection of indigenous and exotic plants is one of the most exciting attractions for botanists, naturalists and tourists. Ramna Green : A vast stretch of green garden bordered by a twisting lake near the Sheraton Hotel. 

 Parliament House: Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban (Parliament House) located at Sher-e-Bangla Nagar has distinctive architectural features. Designed by the famous architect Louis I. Kahn, it may be called an architectural wonder of this region.Sonargaon: If you feel the need to escape and take a break from the chaos of Dhaka, Songargon, about 29 km. from Dhaka offers you the chance to do just that. The town has a few worthwhile sights that are separated from one another and whilst going from sight to sight, you have the opportunity experience rural life and take in the less chaotic surroundings. Sonargaon is one of the oldest capitals of Bengal. It was the seat of Deva Dynasty until the 13th century. From then onward till the advent of the Mughals, Sonargaon was a subsidiary capital of the Sultanate of Bengal. The main places of interest in Sonargaon are the ruins of Panam Nagar, the local crafts museum or the Lok Shilpa Jadughar (charges an entrance fee), the tomb of Sultan Ghiyasuddin, the Goaldi Mosque, and the shrines of Panjpir and Shah Abdul Alia. The first two lie on one side of the Dhaka-Chittgong Highway and the rest lie on the other side. Once at Mograpara, a rickshaw may be hired for sightseeing. It is best to hire the same rickshaw for a fixed amount (BDT 200-250) to visit all the places in Sonargaon. Most rickshaw pullers know the more popular destinations like Panam Nagar, the Lok Shilpa Jadughar, etc. Some may not know of the tomb of Sultan Ghiyasuddin or the Goaldi Mosque and the shrines. Usually rickshaw drivers who are locals from the village know all of these places. Frequent bus services to Sonargaon operate from Gulistan, Saidabad and other bus stands in Dhaka. Tickets may be bought on roadside counters. Mention your destination as Mograpara as you might end up at the Pan Pacific Sonargaon Hotel instead. The price of the ticket from Gulistan bus stand is Tk 22. Hajiganj is another place of historical interest, situated about 10 kms from Mograpara bus stand. However, the above mentioned places usually take up most of the day and it is best to return to Dhaka before evening. Sonargaon and Hajiganj may be combined into a single day if one sets off very early from Dhaka.

Things to Do

The main thing you can do is to go outdoors for a picnic in places like Zoo and Botanical garden. Dhaka also has several museums on offer where you can learn about the country, its people and culture. In the surrounding areas you can also enjoy a picnic in one of the designated &apos;picnic areas&apos; whilst en route to a nearby village to take a look at local arts and crafts.

 Bangabandhu Memorial Museum : The residence of the father of the nation Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman at Dhanmondi (Road 32) has been curved into a museum. It includes a rare collection of personal effects and photographs of his life and times. He was assassinated in 1975 along with most of his family members. Liberation War Museum : Positioned at Segun Bagicha area of the city (close to National Press Club) the museum contains exceptional archival photographs and items used by the freedom fighters throughout the nine-month long Liberation war in 1971. Ahsan Manzil Museum : On the bank of the river Buriganga in Dhaka the pink majestic Ahsan Manzil has been refurbished and turned into a museum recently. It is an example of the nation&apos;s rich cultural heritage. It was the home of the Nawab of Dhaka and a silent spectator to many events. The renovated Ahsan Manzil is a monument of immense historical beauty. It has 31 rooms with a huge dome atop which can be seen from miles around. It now has 23 galleries displaying portraits, furniture and household articles and utensils used by the Nawab. Dhaka Zoo : Widely known as Mirpur Zoo, colorful and attractive collections of different local and foreign species of animals and birds including the majestic Royal Bengal Tiger are available here. Botanical Garden : Adjacent to Dhaka Zoo, Botanical Garden built on 205 acres of land at Mirpur. You can do both the zoo and the botanical garden in one trip. National Museum : Placed at the central point of the city Shahbag, the museum contains a large number of interesting collections including sculptures and paintings of the Hindu, Buddhist and Muslim periods. Next to the Museum are the popular public library and the Charukola (Arts and Crafts) Institute under Dhaka University. Science Museum : The museum is a modern learning center related to the latest scientific discoveries. It is situated at Agargaon. Institute of Arts and Crafts : Located in the scenic surroundings of Shahbagh the Institute of Arts and Crafts (Charukola Institute) has a representative collection of folk-art and paintings by artists of Bangladesh. 

 Other attractions in and around Dhaka include: Aparajeya Bangla monument, picnic spots such as Chandra and Salna, industrial estates of Tongi, Narayanganj, Demara, Tejgaon and cruising by country boat in the nearby river at Ashulia or a visit to a village to see jute cultivation, weaving and pottery making. Last but not least, a rewarding experience is simply traveling by a horse driven cart or rickshaw along the busy Dhaka streets and observing the local everyday scenes. 

Buy

One of the main things you must do in Dhaka is shopping. And if you go shopping ready to bargain then there are definitely bargains to be had among the bazars and markets of Dhaka. To get a feel for what things should cost in the local markets check prices in the western-style fixed price shops and then deduct 10%. If you prefer hassle free shopping then head to Bashundhara City, a huge shopping center with more modern shops and other amenities you would expect to find in a mall.

 Banga (or Bango) Bazar , is a block west of the Gulistan bus station on Kamruzzaman Sharani Street at the edge of Old Dhaka. This is a place you must visit for shopping. For shopaholics this is probably a paradise but for others it can be a nightmare. There are thousands of small stalls crisscrossed by narrow walkways which are often jammed with people. The quality varies widely but the prices can be cheap, cheap, cheap, after you bargain vigorously. New Market, located on Mirpur Road in Dhanmondi, just west of Dhaka University. This is the biggest market in the city and it has more class, more room and just as much choice. Prices may be a little higher because the stall rent is likely to be more expensive. As well as clothing, there is leather, linen, jewelry, household goods, CDs and DVDs and so on. It is closed on Tuesdays. Bashundhara City on Pantha Path just west of the Pan Pacific Sonargao Hotel. This multi-storey complex is the closest imitation of the malls found in Asia. It is the newest and most modern place to shop in the city with small shops straddling over a whopping 10 floors. Garment products are also be found cheaply at- Pallwell Market (BB (What is this?): Gulistan area, just West of Motijheel); PM (??): Purana Paltan area (just beside Jonaki Cinema Hall). Many items only have minor defects, but do not meet export requirements. Pink Pearls are available in many handicraft stores, with some dedicated outlets in Gulshan Aaron g: A well known chain of handicrafts, with several outlets around Dhaka and one in London. It is owned by BRAC (a large NGO) and sells clothing at moderately high prices besides handicrafts. Aranya : 60 Kemal Ataturk, Banani is another good store with beautiful crafts. Supports fair trade practices. 
 
Transportation

For traveling within the city main mode of transport is cycle rickshaws and auto rickshaws, with close to 400,000 rickshaws running each day–the largest number for any city in the world. For this reason Dhaka is known as the rickshaw capital of the world. Comparatively low-cost and non-polluting cycle rickshaws nevertheless cause traffic congestion and have been banned from many parts of the city. Scooters, taxis and privately owned automobiles are increasingly becoming popular with the city&apos;s growing middle class. The government has overseen the replacement of two-stroke engine taxis with four-stroke &quot;Green taxis&quot; which run on compressed natural gas that’s why local people call it CNG.

 Cycle-rickshaws are the most accepted form of transport, and works well for short distances -- mainly on side streets. They are the reason behind the bulk of the cities horrendous traffic, and charge around BDT. 5 (Put in USD as well…but is this information updated? Plz check) per kilometer. Negotiating a fare beforehand is a must as a foreigner. Cycle-rickshaws in rich areas such as Banani and Gulshan cost a little higher. Moreover, foreigners should also be warned that cycle-rickshaws will sometimes begin the ride with a pitch to sell drugs or prostitutes. One or two simple, but firm, declines will generally solve the situation. If you&apos;re a woman -- it&apos;s particularly inadvisable to ride around alone in cycle-rickshaws after dark -- you&apos;re a slow-moving target asking for trouble from thugs and muggers. (No idea why this is here…) Auto-rickshaws (also known as &apos;CNG&apos;) are also plentiful and have meters, which drivers can sometimes be persuaded to use. For longer distances they’re the cheapest way - an 8km ride from Old Dhaka to Gulshan might cost around Tk 100. The meters start at Tk 14, but for shorter distances you&apos;ll likely have to negotiate a fare instead. The city does become very jam-packed at times so allow plenty of time for getting around. Taxi/Cab: can also be found plying the roads, some yellow and some black, all with meters. Black taxis start the meter at Tk 30 while yellow taxis are a little nicer and start at Tk 40. Black taxis are typically in infamously poor condition and lack air conditioning. Yellow taxis are compulsory to have air conditioning, (they consist of Toyota Corollas mostly, Mitsubishis or Hondas even). They are also considered far safer by the local Dhaka elite, (When compared to black taxis and auto-rickshaws). Put the numbers of them here… Public buses: are operated by the state-run Bangladesh Road Transport Corporation (BRTC) and by private companies and operators. Buses run routes on the main roads, but are dreadfully crowded and noisy, signed only in Bengali. If you go too far distance, take a comfortable, luxurious A/C bus or a train. 

In case of traveling in or out from Dhaka you can follow the ways given below: -

 By Air 

 Zia International Airport is well served by international flights from most continents. Following airlines have flights to different part of the world - Thai Airways has direct flights from Bangkok (also flies to Chittagong direct). There are also gateways from Nepal on GMG Airlines, Hong Kong on Dragon Air, Malaysia, Singapore, Delhi, Kunming and Kolkata. You can also travel to Dhaka from Middle East by Gulf Air, Emirates, Qatar Airways, Etihad Airways, Kuwait Airways, Saudi Arabian Airlines, Iran Air, Yemenia, and to Chittagong by Oman Air and Air Arabia.

 By Bus 

Dhaka is the natural hub for the country’s bus companies, as it’s the capital and geographical center of the country. There are several bus stations around Dhaka, and which one you need to be at depends where you want to go, so ask around before heading out to one of them. Most are as crowded as you would expect them to be (because of population).

 Sayedabad bus station: Placed at the eastern part of the city, useful for buses to the eastern half of the country including Sylhet and Chittagong Division.

 Gabtali bus station: Located at the western end of the city, serves most of the western half of the country including Jessore, Rajshahi and Khulna Division.

 Mohakhali Bus Station: 

There are many bus service providers like Green Line, Shyamoli, Silk Line and Shohagh who serve the major cities and tourist attractions with luxurious buses. They all have a few offices around the town, the most central being those near the Eastern Hotel on Inner Circular Rd in Central Dhaka, just north of the Motijheel area. Green Line serves Chittagong (5-6 hours), Cox&apos;s Bazar (8-9 hours), Rajshahi (4 hours), Sylhet (5 hours), Khulna (7 hours) and Jessore (5-6 hours) in its comfortable VOLVO buses. It also has a couple of super luxury SCANIA buses to Chittagong and Cox&apos;s Bazar for a comfortable floating around the country. Seats are huge and fully recline. The qualities of these buses are similar to Business class of an airline (There are also Hino A/C luxury buses as well as VOLVO and SCANIA). Lately, the S.Alam and the Saudia, two of the leading (non-air conditioned) bus service providers have jointly launched a MERCEDES-BENZ luxury bus service to Chittagong, Cox&apos;s Bazar and some other major cities. One of the ticket counters has been opened at the Panthapath (near Rasel’s square at Dhanmondi Road: 32), an area where you can locate all major luxury bus ticket counters. Rephrase, if possible place a table so that it’s readable.

If you are coming to Bangladesh from India, then you must know that there are a number of land entry points for Buses from India. The most popular way is the regular comfortable a/c buses from Kolkata to Dhaka via the Haridaspur / Benapole border post. Shohagh, Green Line, Shyamoli and other private bus companies operate daily bus services. Government buses run under the label of the state owned West Bengal Surface Transport Service Corporation (WBSTSC) and the Bangladesh Road Transport Corporation (BRTC). WBSTSC and BRTC both run buses from Kolkata every Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday at 5:30AM and 8:30AM, and 12:30PM while from Dhaka they leave on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday at 7:00AM and 7:30AM. The normal journey time is around 12 hours with a one-way fare of Indian Rs.550 or Tk.600-800, (approximately $8-12). If you&apos;re only headed to Haridaspur the fare is Rs.86, or Tk 116. The journey should take around 2.30 hours. Check the cost! I guess this has changed a lot!

 By boat 

From Sadarghat in Old Dhaka, most ferries arrive and leave. The area of Sadarghat and its surrounding streets are incredibly hectic, so allow plenty of time and watch your bags and pockets carefully. If new here, fight your way to the left on the frontage road and then make your first right - this turns into Nawabpur Road and leads north to the hotels. Even if you aren&apos;t staying in this area, it&apos;s easier to walk several hundred meters north to catch an onward rickshaw; the ones near port are at a standstill.

The Steamers run to Barisal and Khulna are called the Rocket Steamers (P.S. &apos;Tern&apos;, &apos;Masud&apos; and &apos;Ostrich&apos;). They departed from the Sadarghat several times per week around 6pm. To Barisal is Tk 480/300 in first/second class, while all the way to Khulna will run Tk 1010/610 and will take 26-30 hours. Tickets should be booked at the BIWTC office in Motijheel just east of Dilkusha Circle I. It&apos;s open until 5PM Su-W and until 2PM on Thursdays, closed on Fridays. A quick heads-up in that the link to the BIWTC tariff mentioned above is in &apos;Takas&apos; and one should double check the fares. Chandpur is the second major river station 3 to 4 hours journey from Dhaka and 5 to 6 hours Journey from Barisal. Multiple other boats are available for short and long distances - head to Sadarghat or Badam Tole ghat (about 1 km further west) and ask around. Tickets aren&apos;t pre-sold, and bargaining is likely necessary.

Communication and Network

Dhaka has a highly developed communication and network system, as it is the capital of the country. It has both land line and mobile phone network and all the head offices also located here. So if you countered any problem with your network or phone you can directly go to the head offices for help. It is well connected to the world through the high speed internet and you can find every kind of communicating system that you can think of.
 
Eat

Dhaka has a vast variety of food catering to all budgets. Old Dhaka is swarming with cheap Bangladeshi food where a meal can be had from Tk 50 ($0.70), while in the expensive neighborhoods like Gulshan and Banani you can find just about any type of cuisine you can imagine - Chinese, Indian, Thai, Vietnamese, Greek, Mexican, and franchises such as Pizza Hut, KFC are plentiful - at prices that the majority can&apos;t afford. Reservations are usually not required in most restaurants. A lot of the Buffet-style restaurants in this neighborhood have Taka: 250 to 400, fixed price menu. Bangladesh is known for its sweets. Local sweets (misti/mishti) like Rasgullah and Gulab Jamun are excellent. To the uninitiated these are bite-sized soft cheeseballs dipped (drenched) in syrup, coming in white and red varieties. Shops all through the town (and especially near Gulshan) sell imported condiments from the U.S., Dubai and Malaysia at a premium. Imported chocolate is especially expensive - and usually not in the best condition as it gets melted and re-solidified daily in the tropical heat. Fresh is better. Be careful when buying food from street vendors as health and hygiene standards are not always topnotch. Unlike Bangkok -- street food in Dhaka is only for locals. Foreigners should stick to larger, organized (and unfortunately a little expensive) food outlets.

 Old and Central Dhaka 

Restaurants are jam-packed throughout the narrow alleys and along the main streets - duck into one of them and you&apos;ll likely not to be too upset. A full meal will usually run less than a dollar, though fish will push it closer to two.

 Hotel Al-Razzaque : 29/1 North South Rd (Nazira Bazaar), on the ground floor of the hotel is a large and popular restaurant, busy anytime of the day with Bangladeshi families and businessmen. Food is pretty darn good, if unpredictable in its timing. Sometimes you&apos;ll have a choice of chicken and mutton curries, fish and vegetables; other times its Chicken Biryani or the highway. Fish will double the price of your meal, at least. It&apos;s sandwiched between a clean and well-stocked juice bar and a clean and well-stocked sweet shop. Each plate cost 80 Taka. (sure about the cost? Also USD??) Hajjee Beryani in: Old Dhaka was famed for its lines of beryani (spelling inconsistency) restaurants. Some of the more prominent outfits are still going and Hajjee Beryani is one of them. It revels in its eccentric reputation for opening only at certain times and only cooking a certain amount (well below demand) Hotel Star International Thathari bazar, Near Nawabpur Bazar and Bismillah Kabab Address-Nazira Bazar, cook fantastic Beryani. Jharna Grill: is in Pan Pacific Sonargaon Hotel. The crown restaurant in the hotel serves excellent seafood. Expect to pay Tk 3,000 (USD??)for a 3 course meal with drinks. The hotel has other good restaurants too. Cafe Jheel: Located at the opposite of the National press club. Serves good local dishes for the budget tourists. Expect to pay Tk 150-200 (USD??) for a 3 course meal. Although you can possibly get lunch/dinner for as low as Tk 60. (USD??) 

 Gulshan / Banani (you can take info from http://www.imhungrybd.com/ ) 

These areas are packed with crowded stylish and expensive restaurants, an attraction for the Dhaka elite who like good food or just want to be seen in their shiny new sedans.

 Bamboo Shoot: placed at Gulshan Avenue (upstairs from Agora department store). A Chinese/Thai restaurant that prides itself in offering &apos;authentic&apos; food, and this is backed up by the number of Chinese expiates seen eating there on any given night. Dhanshiri , Gulshan 2(beside the Westin) : The food is first-class and they serve decent local dishes. However, make sure to check prices on the menu card before ordering and examine the bill afterwards. There are better places to get Bengali food, but Dhashiri&apos;s location is especially convenient. El Toro , House 1A, Road 138, Gulshan I, stays open between 11:30AM-10:30PM. An incredible Mexican restaurant serving burritos, enchiladas, quesadillas and the like. Muy Delicioso! Mains around Tk 250-300. A&amp;W Rootbeer , immediately south of Circle I, Gulshan. Yes, the American chain, and in full swing. A burger, fries and root beer float will set you back almost BDT.300, which seems to be no problem for the well-off young Bangladeshi teens that fill the tables. Andersen&apos;s of Denmark , House 34, Road 136, Gulshan Circle I. Excellent ice cream such as mint chocolate chip, Oreos&amp;cream and banana fudge, sundaes and milkshakes, cappuccinos, espressos and hot chocolate. Defy the urge to spend the entire day here. Attached to a fast food restaurant (&apos;Chicken King&apos;) serving fried chicken and steaks. CoFi 11 , House Number 34, Road Number 21, Block B, Banani (Take the road opposite of Priyo Departmental Store&amp;Fahim Music in Kemal Ataturk Avenue, i.e. Road number 18, cross the South East Univeristy Campus&amp;immediately make the 1st left turn&amp;its the 2nd house on the right. Very close to the Swiss Embassy). Possibly the best coffee available in Dhaka, they import beans from Colombia, Guatemala, Kenya, and Indonesia and even Starbucks beans and offer exotic drinks like lemogini, Shikanjee, Guava Frappe, Mango Yogurt&amp;Mandolito. They also have espresso dipped brownies and good sandwiches. Free WiFi. They also have live musical performances on the 1st Saturday of every month&amp;on the Wednesday of the 3rd week of the month Heritage , House 10, Road 109, Gulshan-2. Run by British-Bangladeshi celebrity chef Tommy Miah, this Mugal décor restaurant features Bangla-fusion food. Spaghetti Jazz , Gulshan. Respectable Italian that delivers pizza and pasta! Bella Italia , Gulshan 1. Situated near Gulshan circle 1, beside the Gulshan-1 market. The owner was employed in the restaurant business in Italy and this place serves fairly authentic thin-crust pizzas and pastas. Mains are around Tk 300. Sura , Gulshan 2. Korean restaurant sited across near the Egyptian embassy. Table-top barbecue and most popular Korean dishes are available, along with a selection of sushi and sashimi. Well-liked with Koreans and other expiates. Expect to pay at least Tk 500 per person for a 3 course dinner. 

 Dhanmondi 

 Hotel Star -Opposite of Abahani Club. Renowned for its beef and mutton Kabab. Xindian -Dhanmondi 27 and Shankar crossing. One of the more luxurious restaurants in Dhaka which has been recognized lately. Jeni Kabab An old and prominent restaurant for Kababs. Red Onion Situated opposite the Medinova Medical Center. Mama Halim New Circular Road 2nd Floor, (Opposite of Aarong) Moghbazaar. Sells especial Halim for which it’s renowned. Coopers - Kalabagan. It has several branches throughout Dhaka. Very famous for cakes and fast food. Western Grill -Science Lab. Expensive and hygienic fast foods are available here. Xing ling -Jigatola. A medium quality old Chinese restaurant which provides both Chinese and Thai food. 

Drink

There is a party network within the different expat clubs (Dutch Club, Canadian Club, Scandinavian Club, International Club, American Club, etc.) and some Bangladeshi clubs (Heritage, Privilege, etc.). These clubs generally require membership to enter, or befriend a member and have them sign you in. From there, you can purchase a book of tickets or a cash card and then use it to order your drinks.

Even though alcohol is most simply available at the international clubs and top hotels, there are quite a few local places to find a drink for the enterprising traveler. Local bars are to be found in most neighborhoods but can be hard to locate due to lack of advertising. Popular brands of beer (Heineken, Carlsberg, Tuborg, Foster&apos;s etc) and major types of liquor are available at these places, and at much lower prices than at hotel bars.

You can try: (There are others like Galaxy etc.)

 La Diplomat at Road 20, House number 7, near Gulshan 1. Don&apos;t expect to be rubbing shoulders with any ambassadors, however. The Dip , like most other Bengali bars, is a smoke-filled murky room where many of its patrons would rather not be acknowledged too easily. Definitely an experience, nonetheless. Beers cost upwards of Tk 150 (Price sure???) and &quot;tots,&quot; which are single ounce servings of gin, vodka or whiskey, are available from Tk 70(local brands)-Tk 200 (Price sure???). Female patrons may feel slightly uncomfortable.  

There is a duty paid shop in Mohakhali which is only allowed to sell alcohol to passport-bearing foreigners or their drivers who bring their passports in when they buy. The address is 12 Abbas Garden, New Airport Road. Their stated opening hours are from 9:30pm - 4:30pm, and closed on Fridays. To get there you need to go towards the flyover as if you were going to Banani, but instead of going on to the flyover, you take the second left after it begins. You will see a tiny sign labeled &quot;Abbas Garden.&quot; Turn left and tell your transport to wait while you purchase.
Zakaria International, Galaxy International, E ram, Parjatan, Sakura

Places to stay

The price of the hotels differs on the basis of tourist season and off season. Go to the hotel page or click here . You will find all the information you need to choose a suitable place to stay at Dhaka.
 District Commissioner Office - (02) 9556628 Residence - (02) 8316144
District Judge Office - (02) 7118729 Residence - (02) 9359914
Civil Surgeon Office - (02) 8313352 Residence - (02) 8924195
Medical College Office - (02) 8626812-23 Residence - (02) -
Jail Office - (02) 7310192 Residence - (02) -
 «Previous Destination 
 Cox&apos;s Bazar Next Destination» 
 Jaflong 

TripBD.com is offering management services for
 1. Corporate Picnic
2. Small Family Picnic
3. Picnic Packages
 .
Some of the PICNIC Spots that we already arranged are:
- Meghna Village Holiday Resort
- Utshob PICNIC Spot
- Nahar Garden PICNIC Spot
- Shofipur, Bangladesh Ansar&amp;VDP Academy
- Elenga Resort
- Nawab Ali Hasan Ali Royal Resort
etc.

For more information call +8801829440044 or email at info@tripbd.com

 WE ARE THANKFUL TO ALL THE HOTELS FOR THEIR COOPERATION TO MAKE TRIPBD A SUCCESS! 
 HOME ABOUT US HOTELS Tour Packages ARTICLES CONTACT US DISCLAIMER PRIVACY POLICY TERMS OF USE FEEDBACK [+] 
 
 
 ©2009-2012 TripBD - Branding Bangladesh in Tourism. All rights reserved. design, develop
&amp;maintain by
	</body>
</document>
