<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007365" url="http://www.zazzle.com/morning_exercise_and_good_breakfast_card-137438420563778815" time="2012-07-13-00:20" support="3" score="0.0022751641171673393" bingtitle="Morning exercise and good breakfast greeting cards from Zazzle.com" webtitle="Morning exercise and good breakfast greeting cards from Zazzle.com">
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Be careful about what you order, though, if you plan to pick up your breakfast at a fast food restaurant. ... Smart Cars in U.S. Card</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 Sign in  
 My Account Track My Order Order History 
 Wishlist 
 
Loading...
 
 Cart 
 Free Shipping On Orders Over $50 
 Click for Code 
 Shop Departments  
 
Loading...
 
 Create  
 
Loading...
 
 Gift Center T-Shirts 
 Search Today ONLY: 50% Off Stickers , Buttons &amp; Magnets For Zazzle&apos;s Birthday!   Use Code: ZBDAYFLAIR50    See All Birthday Deals Home &gt; Books, Magazines&amp;Comics &gt; Comics &gt; Cartoon Art   Product  Design Many of us get up very early in the morning to prepare our kids to school. You&apos;re lucky, if you don&apos;t have to. Still, before heading for the office, you should spend at least 30 minutes working out or jogging to get your body ready for the full day of work. A daily exercise in the morning helps release your stress and keeps you in good health. Of course, do not skip the breakfast - the most important meal of the day. A good breakfast provides you the nutrition and energy needed to face another day of challenge. Be careful about what you order, though, if you plan to pick up your breakfast at a fast food restaurant. Visit Cartoosh.com today for more cartoons! Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... Loading High Resolution... DISPLAYNAME See on your wall! Customize it! No minimum orders•No setup fees•Ships tomorrow* ! Like 

 Help us personalize your shopping experience by telling us what you like! (learn more) Share this with your friends! Share Facebook Twitter Other networks... See all your likes | Unlike Share Facebook Twitter Other networks... Link... 
Greeting Card
 
Keep in touch with Zazzle custom greeting cards. Customize all parts of this folded card–inside and out, front and back–for free!

 5&quot; x 7&quot; (portrait) or 7&quot; x 5&quot; (landscape). Printed on ultra-heavyweight (120 lb.) card stock with a gloss finish. Each card comes with a white envelope. No minimum order. May be available on Note Card size Postage rate for this size card (up to 1 oz) is $0.45 
 Read more... 
This cool custom card template designed by the very imaginative artist cartoosh is tagged under cartoon, cartoons,&amp;office humor. No matter what you&apos;re looking for, Zazzle has custom card templates for a plethora of different occasions. Find this Seller&apos;s unique cartoons and office humor custom card in the Seller&apos;s * Work Out store category alongside a plethora of other cool design options designed by an artist online in the community marketplace.

The best way to send your family&apos;s season&apos;s greetings, this custom card will unquestionably look appealing when printed with this Zazzle seller&apos;s cartoons illustration. One of the many examples of picks, this art looks awesome printed on our quality card stock. Once it is made, the remarkable comics custom card displayed above will quickly become a hit with your friends and relatives. Unbelievably original, this morning exercise and good breakfast card acts as a prime example of the unique card ideas listed in the Seller&apos;s * Work Out shop. Category.
 
Morning exercise and good breakfast greeting cards
 4.8 (1676 reviews) In stock! Out of stock 
Quantity:
	</body>
</document>
