<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007874" url="http://undergroundwellness.com/tag/cnn-happy-meals/" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="3" score="0.00280956428210002" bingtitle="Cnn Happy Meals | Underground Wellness" webtitle="Cnn Happy Meals | Underground Wellness">
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>How about that stupid farm bill? I can go on and on. The government’s ... No one goes to a fast food restaurant to order fruits and veggies. And kids who play with toys ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Blog Videos Podcast Protandim 
 Protandim International Protandim Studies 
 Store Be My Guest!! 
 
Posts Tagged‘cnn happy meals’
 
 Childhood Obesity Solved: Take Away Their Toys! 
 Tuesday, November 9th, 2010 
 

Give me a break.

The latest big news in the health world (besides the guy who lost 20-something pounds eating Twinkies and Doritos) is that the City of San Francisco’s Board of Supervisors banned Happy Meals with toys.

Cool…

Yes, childhood obesity is a huge problem in dire need of intervention. And I do agree that addressing this issue will likely require a series of small victories. But in my opinion, this is nothing to get excited about. It’s actually pretty ridiculous when you think about it.

It’s been ages since I set foot inside of a fast food restaurant. However, in all of my previous visits, I can’t seem to recall witnessing any seven year-olds ordering their own Happy Meals with their own money.

Maybe it’s just me. Maybe I just wasn’t paying attention to the stampede of little rug rats demanding Buzz Lightyear with their fries and Cokes. But if my memory serves me, I recollect grown-ups buying obesity. Toys included.

As usual, when grown-ups have trouble using common sense, government has to step in and play the role of babysitter, this time punishing them by taking away their toys. If Big Babysitter really wants to make a difference, I suggest a little quiet time in the corner for those who enable children to eat such garbage, their parents.

The root cause of obesity has nothing to do with action figures. Rather, it has much more to do with grown-ups who can’t say no.

Prior to drawing up such legislation, government may want to take a look in the mirror. If they are truly intent on ending childhood obesity, they should probably do something about that atrocious school lunch program. Or maybe that upside-down food pyramid. How about that stupid farm bill?

I can go on and on. The government’s own laws and agricultural policies are bigger contributors to obesity than animated movie characters.

In typical babysitter form, punishment came with an ultimatum. If Ronald McDonald improves the nutritional value of his menu options by the end of next year, offering more fruits and vegetables, we’ll get our toys back.

Be a good boy, Ron.

This is just plain silliness. No one goes to a fast food restaurant to order fruits and veggies. And kids who play with toys don’t buy their own Happy Meals. Parents do.

It’s long past time for parents to come home and send the babysitters on their way. Legislation is a poor replacement for parenting and education.

And toys don’t cause obesity.

Probably not the most eloquent blog I’ve ever written. I just had to get that off of my chest.

Sean Croxton
Food Realist
	</body>
</document>
