<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007513" url="http://southerncaliforniadiningservicesfun.com/?p=76" time="2012-07-13-00:29" support="2" score="0.0056838246129321205" bingtitle="Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Services Reviews ..." webtitle="Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews - Panda Express">
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>You can tell it has been frozen ... to the lack of staff at the counter, they have one cashier and one taking the order. ... but then Panda Express is fast food restaurant in ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement
 
 Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews 
 Reviews for Movies, Restaurants, Entertainment and Lifestyle In SoCal RSS 
Register to Subscribe to this blog and receive notification by email for new posts.
 
 Username 

 Password 

 Remember Me 

 
 
 Register Recover password 
 
Bookmark
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Blogroll

 A) Movie Reviews etc. B) Southern California Gardening c) LA Grub Street D) Street Gourmet LA E) WordPress Blog 
 RSS ‹Prev Next› Jul 01 
Panda Express
 by Napoleon on  July 1st, 2011 at  4:18 pm Posted In: B) Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine 
Panda Express is a chain of casual fast food restaurant offering American Chinese food. It is the largest fast food offering Chinese food in the US.

Panda Express offers a variety of Chinese food including the most common Chinese entrée’s like Orange Chicken, Kung Pao Chicken, fried rice and Chow Mein (noodles) and other stir fried entrée’s. They claim they do not use MSG. They are based in Rosemead, California (a Southern California city in the San Gabriel Valley).

 

 

 
 

Their restaurants have typical fast food ambiance with Oriental decor, brightly lighted with strong bright colors like red and orange, clean and looks very commercial. It is not the typical one store/family owned Chinese place. The location I visited has a clean rest room, water, soap and paper towels are available.

The taste of most of their entrée’s are not very authentic Chinese food. The food taste a little bit Westernized. It is not terribly bad but not good either. Their egg roll doesn’t like an egg roll should be. You can tell it has been frozen, you can taste more the oil it was fried in than the flavor of the egg roll itself. The mushroom chicken is quite tasty though. The orange chicken is dry. Their chow mein is one of the best chow mein I have tasted.

Portion wise, they don’t really give you that much food. If you are buying half chow mein and half rice, they only give you one scoop each which is not much. If you are on diet and on portion control, Panda Express may be good for you.

 

 

I have been visiting their Rancho Cucamonga and Ontario locations for quite some time. They are busy most of the time, there’s almost always a line during dinner. This is probably due to the lack of staff at the counter, they have one cashier and one taking the order. Sometimes the store manager is at the counter helping. At the Rancho Cucamonga location, I never see a store manager last that long. Every so often they have a new store manager.

If you are in a hurry and want convenient Chinese fast food, they are okay. It is not PF Chang but then Panda Express is fast food restaurant in a strip mall or food court in a mall.

 

 

 
 
 
 Share this: Digg Email Print Facebook Reddit StumbleUpon 
 └Tags: chinese cuisine , chinese fast food , chinese food , fast food 
 
Discussion (8)¬
 Comments RSS 
 Hay J April 26, 2012 at 7:51 am | # | Reply 
While not the best Chinese food place, they are much better than your average Chinese place.
 H Jan April 5, 2012 at 10:08 pm | # | Reply 
This is not the best Chinese place, they really are so fast food.
 Kathleen AB March 28, 2012 at 7:06 pm | # | Reply 
Their Chinese food is so blah! I can cook a better Chinese food than this place.
 
 Carrie Zen April 1, 2012 at 11:59 pm | # | Reply 
That is so true. The food is blah for a Chinese food and the portion size are so small. That would work maybe if you are in a diet.

Their price is not cheap either.
 
 Jimmy B February 16, 2012 at 7:47 pm | # | Reply 
Good enough for a fast food Chinese.
 Edward A October 20, 2011 at 5:41 pm | # | Reply 
Panda Express is so Americanized chinese food. They give you so small portions, not enough at all to fill you!
 Horacio Pierre August 16, 2011 at 1:09 pm | # | Reply 
You made some decent points there. I did a search on the issue and found most people will go along with with your website.
 
 Louise October 2, 2011 at 7:25 pm | # | Reply 
This could not possibly have been more heplful!
 
 
 
Comment¬
 Cancel reply 
 
 NAME— Get a Gravatar 

 EMAIL 

 Website URL 

 

NOTE - You can use these HTML tags and attributes:
 &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Categories

 A) Welcome to Southern California B) Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine C) Home&amp;Garden D) Fun&amp;Entertainment E) Movies F) Performing Arts Theater G) Places of Interest H) Services I) Shopping J) Los Angeles County K) Orange County L) Riverside/San Bernardino County M) San Diego County N) ADVERTISE WITH US 
 
Recent Posts

 Zaky Mediterranean Grill Pantages Theatre Barleymash Taco Luv Ontario International Airport ArcLight Cinemas Armstrong Garden Centers Larkin’s King Taco Sicha Siam Thai Cuisine Mt. Fuji Garden Center Commerce Casino The Gumbo Pot Aria Restaurant El Morfi Grill, Parillada Argentina Off Vine India Sweets&amp;Spices Jiffy Lube Victoria Gardens Advertise With Us Geffen Playhouse Fleming’s Prime Steakhouse&amp;Winebar I Love Tufo&amp;BBQ LA Live Tropical Food Express Two Guys From Italy Restaurant Pierre Garden Restaurant El Pollo Loco Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden Rise of the Planet of the Apes Americana at Brand In-N-Out Burgers Captain America: The First Avenger Citadel Outlets Bad Teacher 
 
Kontera Ads
 
 Random Post 
 
Blogroll

 A) Movie Reviews etc. B) Southern California Gardening c) LA Grub Street D) Street Gourmet LA E) WordPress Blog 
 
Advertisement
 
 tidzzhirtz ALTERNATIVE UNISEX ATTIRE - tidzzhirtz clothing company introduces a variety of alternative attires for unisex semi-formal to sports wear to a line of trend setting one of a kind zhirtz and jacketz that will definitely give you an ace &quot;umph&quot; to your rugged sense. 
 
©2011-2012 Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews | Powered by WordPress with Easel | Subscribe: RSS | Back to Top↑ 
 Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
