<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007484" url="http://www.jobjournal.com/article_printer.asp?artid=1999" time="2012-07-13-00:27" support="4" score="0.0028532560614813406" bingtitle="CAREER SNAPSHOT: Food Server (California Job Journal)" webtitle="CAREER SNAPSHOT: Food Server(California Job Journal)">
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>... workers greet customers, escort them to seats ... Some employers, particularly fast-food restaurant ... All workers receive training on safe food handling procedures and ...</description>
	<body>
		Select &apos;Print&apos; in your browser menu to print this document.
 
 Issue: April 29, 2007 

 CAREER SNAPSHOT: Food Server 
 by CJJ Staff 
 
Job Prospects: Excellent 

Typical Annual Compensation (entry level):

 Bay Area . . . . . . $17,929 - 32,840 Sacramento . . . . $16,417 - 30,071 Central Valley . . . $15,844 - 29,020 

 Wages increase with experience. For potential earnings, go to Salary.com . 

Job Market Update

Job openings are expected to be abundant for food service workers. While population growth will create many new jobs, the majority of openings will arise from high turnover since food service work is often a short-term source of income for students and those between jobs in other fields. However, keen competition is expected for positions in popular restaurants and fine dining establishments, where potential earnings from tips are greatest.

Job Duties

Food and beverage servers and related workers are the front line of customer service in restaurants, coffee shops, and other dining establishments. Waiters and waitresses, the largest group of these workers, take customers’orders, serve food and beverages, prepare itemized checks, and sometimes accept payment. Their specific duties vary considerably, depending on the establishment. Some workers greet customers, escort them to seats and hand them menus, answer questions, explain menu items and specials, and keep tables and dining areas clean and set for new diners. Most work as part of a team, helping co-workers to improve workflow and customer service. In coffee shops, servers are expected to provide fast, efficient, courteous service. In fine dining restaurants, where more complicated meals are prepared and often served over several courses, waiters and waitresses provide more formal service emphasizing personal, attentive treatment and a more leisurely pace.

Dining room and cafeteria attendants help waiters, waitresses and bartenders by cleaning tables, removing dirty dishes, and keeping serving areas stocked with supplies. Sometimes called backwaiters or runners, they bring meals out of the kitchen and assist servers by distributing dishes to diners. They also replenish the supply of clean linens, dishes, silverware, and glasses in the dining room.

Bartender helpers keep the bar area clean, wash glasses, and assist the bartender as needed.

Counter attendants usually handle all the needs of customers seated at the counter. They also prepare fountain specialties, such as milkshakes and ice cream sundaes, and may prepare short-order items, such as sandwiches and salads.

Job Requirements

Food service jobs are open to virtually anyone. One-fourth of food and beverage servers are 16 to 19 years old, usually with little or no work experience. While high school grads have an edge, lacking such a diploma is not a barrier. What’s most important is a clean, neat appearance and a service-oriented, pleasant personality.

Most servers pick up their skills by observing and working with more experienced staffers. Some full-service restaurants provide new employees with classroom training that alternates with periods of on-the-job experience.

Servers may meet with managers or chefs before each shift to discuss the menu and any new items or specials, review ingredients for potential food allergies and any food safety concerns. Additional topics may include coordination between the kitchen and dining room, or any customer service issues from the previous day or shift.

Some employers, particularly fast-food restaurant chains, use self-instruction or online programs with audio-visual presentations and instructional booklets to teach food preparation and service skills. All workers receive training on safe food handling procedures and sanitation practices.

Working Conditions

Food service establishments typically maintain long hours and offer flexible, varied work opportunities over two or three shifts. Many servers work evenings, weekends and holidays.

Long-Range Prospects

After gaining experience, dining room and cafeteria attendants and bartender helpers can advance to waiter, waitress or bartender. Some advance to supervisory positions, such as dining room manager, maitre d’, assistant manager or general manager. In larger restaurant chains, workers who excel often enter the company’s management training program.
 For more information on food server careers, visit these websites: 
 FoodService.com – Industry website includes news, resources, links, equipment and a complete career center. Click on‘Search Jobs’under the‘Employment Center’heading.

 Hcareers.com –Job board includes listings for hospitality, restaurant and retail jobs. Read employer profiles, post resumes and check out links to other industry websites.

 HospitalityAdventures.com – Website for Adventures in Hospitality Careers includes job listings for hotels, resorts, restaurants, cruise ships, casinos, clubs and more. Post resumes and apply to openings online.

 HospitalityCareerNet.com – Recruiting service for hospitality professionals seeking jobs in the hotel, restaurant, gaming, cruise line and club segments of the industry. Search jobs, build a resume, research employers, and take an assessment to match your profile with employers’needs. The site also features industry news from Hotels magazine.

 HospitalityOnline.com – Job listings from all types of employers in the industry.
 
 Copyright 
2012
 JJ Acquisition Corp. All rights reserved .
	</body>
</document>
