<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007988" url="http://www.cracked.com/funny-5682-chipotle/" time="2012-07-13-01:03" support="4" score="0.0034725279551495766" bingtitle="Chipotle | Cracked.com" webtitle="Chipotle | Cracked.com">
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Chipotle Mexican Grill is a fast food restaurant ... think it&apos;s cute when you order in Spanish - so cute in fact that they will give ... Why Credit Card Companies Will Own Your ...</description>
	<body>
		You Might Be A Zombie! iPad App Horror On Cracked Write For Us 
 
 Login or Register Face Book Connect 
 Cracked.com 
 Articles Browse By All Articles Movies&amp;TV Music Celebrities Tech Sex Sports News Science History Weird World Video Games Videos Columnists Browse By Daniel O&apos; Brien Soren Bowie Robert Brockway Chris Bucholz Gladstone Michael Swaim Seanbaby Cody Christina H. David Wong Jack O&apos;Brien John Cheese Luke McKinney Brendan McGinley Adam Tod Brown Forums Quick Fixes Photoplasty More 
 Topics Cheat Sheets LinkSTORM Asstrology Craptions Classics Popular Greatest Hits Sketch Competition 
 

 Categories: Movies&amp;TV Video Games Music Sports Tech History Science Celebrities Weird World 
 
 Random Article Get Our RSS Feed 
 
 Home Topics Chipotle 
 
Chipotle


 
Chipotle Mexican Grill is a fast food restaurant that tries to make &quot;mexican burritos and stuff&quot; but ended up inventing &quot;epic burritos and stuff&quot;
 Meanest, Badest motherfucker in town 
Just The Facts

 If you do not have a Chipotle near you, your city is not worth living in McDonalds owned a majority interest in Chipotle from 1998 to 2006. This is funny because Chipotle is actually good If you can finish 3 Chipotle burritos then you&apos;re a champ If you order in spanish, you&apos;ll get free chips (as long as you&apos;re not in Cleveland) 

Chipotle: Better than sex in Mexico
 
Well maybe not, I can&apos;t really say since I have never had sex in Mexico. But it could very well be true.

But this ties very well with the fact that Chipotle tries to make mexican food. I&apos;d guess that it&apos;s actually better than the real stuff but no one knows for sure since Americans don&apos;t go to Mexico. In fact, Mexicans are usually the ones who come to the U.S. - my guess is the majority of illegal immigrants don&apos;t come here for jobs or to meet Mel Brooks - I think they just want some damn Chipotle. Or maybe they want to work at a Chipotle so that they can get free burritos?

That would explain why in every single Chipotle except the ones in Cleveland, most employees are of hispanic descent (Mexican) - this is really actually great for high school kids who take Spanish. Why? Because the hispanic (MEXICAN) employees think it&apos;s cute when you order in Spanish - so cute in fact that they will give you free Chips (the assholes normally charge like 1.50 for chips).

So next time you go to Chipotle, make sure you do the following:

 First Mexican in Assembly Line: 

Hola buenos dias, yo quiero un Burrito con frijoles negros y Barbacoa

 You just ordered a Burrito with black beans and Barbacoa 

 Second Mexican in Assembly Line: 

Me gustaria la salsa roja, queso, mais y sour cream. A y tambien me puede regalar una bolsa de papas?

 You just asked for the hottest sauce, cheese, corn and sour cream (no one knows how the fuck to say that in Spanish so fuck it) . Then you asked for free chips.

Works every time, but then again I&apos;m actually fluent in Spanish and I&apos;m not some asshole highschooler who is getting an A in Spanish 3. In fact, I&apos;m so badass that when I was in highschool (that&apos;s right - I graduated already, bitches) I took Bilingual Spanish, Bilingual Spanish 2 and then Bilingual Spanish 3. In other words I could rape you in Spanish.

Anyways now I go to college in Cleveland and we have this Chipotle in a hippy and sceny little street called Coventry (seriously, half the kids...like shit). Anyways, as it turns out the Chipotles in Cleveland don&apos;t have Mexicans but that&apos;s only because they have a lot of African Americans (black people, anyways). They have one white guy. Oh and the manager is sweet. But I managed to get free chips anyways. If you live in city like Cleveland where Chipotle is ran by black people instead of Mexicans then try the following:

At the cash register say &quot;Hey if you think of a number between 1 and 15 and I guess correctly, can I get free chips?&quot;. I did this once, I guessed 4 and I got free chips. But I&apos;m really good looking so maybe I got it wrong and the lady just wanted my penis.

I didn&apos;t give it to her but I took my free chips and ate the shit out of them.

 

 You&apos;ll need some special tricks for this location 
 
Thinking of making a friend? Take them to Chipotle
 
I give potential new friends tryouts because I&apos;m a huge douchebag like that. They better be cool, I don&apos;t want to be seen with lame people. One of the first tests I make them go through is the Chipotle Challenge.

It&apos;s not really a challenge though, unless you&apos;re a gigantic pussy.

I and all my other douchebag friends take the tryout to Chipotle and we all order a burrito. If he orders a set of Tacos then he fails. No real man orders tacos. Tacos are for women and children.

 

 Remember in that movie Titanic how the lifeboats were only for women and children? These tacos work in the same way. Except unlike in the movie, if a man wants one of these then he&apos;s gay. 

If he orders a Burrito Bowl then he&apos;s labled a pussy and he fails. This is worse than ordering a Taco because he&apos;s trying to not be a sissy but instead he ordered the sissiest meal of them all. Ordering a Burrito Bowl at Chipotle is like ordering a salad at McDonals. It&apos;s retarded. Not to mention the fact that it only removes like, what, 200 calories? It&apos;s still a near-1000 calorie bomb. Might as well go all out, no?

 

 Seriously? 

While I don&apos;t have anything against actual homosexuals, I really don&apos;t want to be seen with a friend who orders a set of tacos or a burrito bowl.

If he orders a Burrito, the bastard better put rice on it. Not doing that is a crime. If he orders extra anything, then he gets bonus points. If he orders in spanish without me telling him anything, I know that he&apos;s smart as fuck.

Chipotle has really helped me pick a good set of friends. It can help you too.
 
Recommended For Your Pleasure
 
 
 Awful Romantic Comedies They&apos;ll Probably Make Next 
 772,973 views 
 23 Movie Plots Easily Solved by Everyday Technology 
 313,476 views 
 8 Everyday Words With X-Rated Origins 
 1,501,011 views 
 12 Bizarre True Stories Behind Famous Band Names 
 1,198,570 views 
 6 &apos;New&apos; Gaming Innovations That Are Way Older Than You Think 
 830,212 views 
 Add New Comment To turn on reply notifications, click here 
 3 Comments
 Recent Votes You | Show Profanity 

 More Comments 
Trending Now
 
 The 6 Creepiest Lies the Food Industry is Feeding You 6 Famous Symbols That Don&apos;t Mean What You Think 9 Actors Who Do the Exact Same Thing on Every Movie Poster 
 
 
Staff
 
 mrbutter 
 
Friends&apos; Recent Activity
 
Flashback
 
 6 Completely Legal Ways The Cops Can Screw You By: Cezary Jan Strusiewicz 3,124,435 views 9 Houses You Won&apos;t Believe People Actually Live In By: Eric Yosomono , Mike Cooney 1,151,034 views 8 Words You&apos;re Confusing With Other Words By: Christina H 1,057,743 views Crazy Eight: The Top Crazy Girlfriends in Movie History By: Michael Alarcon 745,083 views 5 Modern Sports That Started As Excuses for Sex and Violence By: Mark Hill 714,349 views 
 
Greatest Hits
 
 21 Images You Won&apos;t Believe Aren&apos;t Photosphopped (Part 8) By: Joe Russo 4,995,506 views 14 Photographs That Shatter Your Image of Famous People By: David Wong 4,417,732 views The 6 Most Horrifying Lies The Food Industry is Feeding You By: Pauli Poisuo 3,787,240 views 7 Movies That Put Insane Work Into Details You Didn&apos;t Notice By: J.F. Sargent 3,772,058 views 5 Ways Modern Men Are Trained to Hate Women By: David Wong 3,704,855 views 
 See More 
Cracked Shows
 
 
 4 Creepy Hidden Truths Behind Popular Scary Stories By: After Hours   415,302 views 
Elsewhere ...
 
 Article 
 The 5 Most Half-Assed Attempts to Take Over a Country 
 By: Evan V. Symon ... Video 
 The Awful Truth about Movies &apos;Based on a True Story&apos; 
 By: Mike Cooney ... Columnist 
 The 5 Saddest Second Careers of Celebrities 
 By: John Cheese Topic 
 Restroom Etiquette: Since There Seems to Be Some Confusion 
 By: paulieslapass Photoplasty 
 American History as Misunderstood by a 5-Year-Old 
 By: CRACKED Readers Infographics 
 Why Credit Card Companies Will Own Your Grandkids [CHART] 
 By: David Wong 
 
 Advertise Write for Cracked Contact Us Link to Us Sitemap Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy AdChoices 

 Popular Topics: Boobs Zombies Hipsters Urban Legends Skyrim 

 Go to our Mobile Version 
 Cracked, Cracked.com, the &quot;Cracked&quot; logo, and Demand Media are each a trademark or a registered trademark of Demand Media, Inc. in the United States and/or other countries.
Copyright©2007-2012. Demand Media, Inc. Driven By Demand Media
	</body>
</document>
