<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007951" url="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/80beats/2010/02/24/ocean-researchers-find-a-new-cause-for-alarm-the-atlantic-garbage-patch/" time="2012-07-13-00:55" support="1" score="0.0009581599491542049" bingtitle="Ocean Researchers Find a New Cause for Alarm: The Atlantic Garbage ..." webtitle="Ocean Researchers Find a New Cause for Alarm: The Atlantic Garbage Patch | 80beats | Discover Magazine">
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="57"/>
	<description>Maybe you think the end of the world is so near, that it ... once saw a guy empty his car ashtray on the ground at a fast food restaurant literally 5 feet away from a trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe Today» 
 Renew Give a Gift Archives Customer Service 

 Facebook Twitter Newsletter 
 SEARCH 
 Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Technology Space Human Origins Living World Environment Physics&amp;Math Video Photos Podcast RSS 
 « Italian Court Convicts Google Execs for Hosting Illegal Video More Watery Eruptions, and More Heat, on Saturn’s Moon Enceladus » 
 Ocean Researchers Find a New Cause for Alarm: The Atlantic Garbage Patch 
 
 In summer 2008, DISCOVER set sail for the Great Pacific Garbage Patch , that Texas-sized soup of tiny plastic bits that might now be an intractable mess in the middle of the ocean. With appearances in newspapers, magazines, and even“ Good Morning America ,”the Pacific patch became the newest target for environmental hand-wringing, and raised questions over whether it would even be possible to clean up. However, the ocean currents that cause the Pacific gyre don’t just happen in the North Pacific. Scientists at the Sea Education Association just finished a two-decade-long study of the North Atlantic and found similarly sad results.

The team dragged nets half-in and half-out of the water to take a trash census. The researchers carried out 6,100 tows in areas of the Caribbean and the North Atlantic—off the coast of the U.S. More than half of these expeditions revealed floating pieces of plastic on the water surface [ BBC News ] . Like the Pacific gyre, the Atlantic one—located mostly between 22 and 38 degrees north latitude—contains a dizzying number of small plastic pieces that used to be bags, bottles, and other consumer products. Lead researcher Kara Lavendar Law says it’s difficult to compare the two, but researchers in both places collected more than 1,000 pieces during a single tow of a net [ The New York Times ] .

 This similarity is no surprise, according to ocean researchers Marcus Eriksen and Anna Cummins. Both gyres are areas of little to no ocean currents, surrounded by strong ocean currents that prevent trash from escaping once it arrives. Worldwide, there exist five major oceanic gyres and it is hypothesized by Eriksen and Cummins that all of these gyres will collect marine debris, much in the same way that the North Pacific does [ Huffington Post ] . You can see the locations in the above image. The North Atlantic gyre that SEA studied also contains the Sargasso Sea , so the plastic is mixed up with the seaweed that grows there.

Most depressingly, reports from the Pacific gyre indicate that fish are beginning to ingest the plastic as pieces get smaller and smaller. And Captain Charles Moore, who discovered the Pacific patch in the 1990s, says cleaning up so many pieces spread out so far would be an impossibly difficult and expensive task. Besides, if people don’t stop throwing away plastic, it wouldn’t do much good.

Related Content:
80beats: Ships Set Sail to Examine the Vast Patch of Plastic in the Pacific Ocean 
The Intersection: Voyage to the Vast Island of Garbage 
DISCOVER: The World’s Largest Dump: The Great Pacific Garbage Patch 
DISCOVER: The Dirty Truth About Plastic 
DISCOVER: Think You Can Live Without Plastic? 

 Image: NOAA 
 Share 
February 24th, 2010 3:29 PM Tags: ocean , plastic , pollution 
by Andrew Moseman in Environment | 14 comments | RSS feed | Trackback &gt; 
 
14 Responses to“Ocean Researchers Find a New Cause for Alarm: The Atlantic Garbage Patch”

 1.   Art Says:
 February 24th, 2010 at 5:05 pm 
I am preaching to the choir, but, if you aren’t going to recycle it (good option), or stop buying so much stuff that’s packaged in plastic (best option), the least you could do is put it in a trash can for the city to take care of. Here’s a novel idea: if you are in your vehicle and you polish off the remainder of your 128 ounce big gulp, throw the emptied container in your floorboard until you get home instead of being a degenerate scumbag. Same goes with cellophane for the smokers.

Littering is inexcusable, especially near bodies of water. INEXCUSABLE. I wish I could take back all junk I threw out the window before I pulled my head out of the mud.

Maybe you think the end of the world is so near, that it doesn’t matter. It just might be, if we don’t start acting right.
 2.   Jeremy Says:
 February 24th, 2010 at 10:07 pm 
It’s bad enough that there’s all this plastic there…but keep in mind that we’ve been adding all kinds of great chemicals to our plastics : fire retardants, pthalates, PBDEs and BPA.

Those can leach into the water…. get into the food chain…and end up contaminating us when we eat fish, or animals that have been fed fish meal. It’s particularly bad for infants.

So no, this isn’t just a problem that’s“way out there in the ocean somewhere.”It’s coming home to roost, too.
 3.   Katharine Says:
 February 24th, 2010 at 10:25 pm 
I don’t expect the trashing of the environment is going to let up until some really nasty stuff happens.
 4.   Mike Says:
 February 25th, 2010 at 12:22 pm 
I see littering all the time…I have seen groups leave their spot at California beaches, leaving behind giant scattered piles of trash (mostly from fast food). I’m a wimp too…too scared to mention to the group that they should clean it up…if you saw some of them, you would be too ;-). The few times I have mentioned it (to a less scary group) I was told to f*ck off. Sometimes I will pick some up…often it’s overwhelming and I just try to tune it out.

Anyway…the worst I have seen is at areas along the Texas coast. In Port Aransas, at the jetty, one can see dozens of fisherman leaving behind all kinds of trash, nets, fishing lines, plastic bags…last summer i saw a sea turtle wrapped up in fish line swimming in the water, although it seemed to be doing OK. You can see seemingly infinite trash wedged between the granite slabs along the walkway too.

It just seems so many humans are not able to carry a little bit of trash back and dispose of it properly. Many of these areas do have trash bins that are available. There is too great a disconnect to nature now…a dangerous ignorance that permiates society. They can’t see that they are destroying what they like doing, or what feeds them (fishing for example and leaving behind all their trash). For many, I think it’s just a lack of awareness, they are not actually bad people…I know people who care about the planet, but will leave behind trash…when made aware they are like“oh, wow, thanks!, I meant to throw that away!”.

I was in Spain for 3 weeks in 2008 and saw it there too….trash (plastics) on many beaches and floating in the water. Sadly, I think it will become catastrophic before governments and people actually wake up to it and do something about it or make a change. Personally, I can’t even comprehend how someone could leave such a mess at any scenic place. To leave a pile of red and white KFC trash on a Malibu beach and just walk away.
 5.   Jake Says:
 February 25th, 2010 at 1:10 pm 
Is it just me or does this illustrate the misdirection of policy makers? Cap and Trade? Global Warming? Whatever! Lets focus on what is real–the garbage. We can see this problem happening! It’s not a debate and there is no need for one! Lets come up with policies that will actually help the earth instead of delay action or shift polution to third world countries.
 6.   Kate Says:
 February 25th, 2010 at 1:17 pm 
I agree, Jake!
 7.   William H Says:
 February 25th, 2010 at 3:37 pm 
If true (remember the lies about global warming) , then here is a problem that needs world attention to correct, particularly since most shipping is flagged through Liberia and Panama and thus avoids the restrictions and requirements of American- and EU-flagged freight. A simple solution would be to require all of a nation’s ships to be flagged by that nation. Right now, any nation can flag any other nation’s ships and because of the incredibly lax standards of Panama and Liberia, that is why most ships of all sorts, from freighters to pleasure ships are flagged through those two nations.
 8.   LLORNKCOR Says:
 February 26th, 2010 at 12:03 am 
I once saw a guy empty his car ashtray on the ground at a fast food restaurant literally 5 feet away from a trash can. I was amazed that this person actually USED an ashtray and then just decided to litter all at once. I was so mad that I followed him hoping I could see where he lived (I’m quite vindictive) but an even better opportunity presented itself. I am a smoker who NEVER disposes of cigarette butts or cellophane improperly, and get very angry when others do, so I myself had an ashtray full of ashes and butts (I know it’s a filthy habit). He went to the grocery for his next stop and thankfully left his window down. I took my ashtray and dumped it in his fast food beverage and put the lid back on. I didn’t stick around to see the aftermath but I’m pretty sure he received some sort of message from it. I hate humans.
 9.   Jeff Says:
 February 26th, 2010 at 1:09 am 
Willam H: By the lies about global warming, do you mean the lies and misrepresentations told by the anti’s, claiming that the scientific evidence does not strongly support that climate change is happening?

LLORNKCOR: Great story!!!
 10.   Scuba_Steve Says:
 February 27th, 2010 at 6:45 am 
I happened to be in Little Cayman a couple of years ago staying at the Southern Cross Club. Beautiful beaches, fantastic views. Wonderful atmosphere. I went wading with a friend and we then swam out from the resort to a very small island about a quarter mile away that was just inside the reef. Expecting a pristine tranquil place we were awed when wandering around the surf line to see a huge assortment of blue, pink, red, green and black sand and stones. Wandering slightly inshore we saw birds nests and a lot of garbage. Upon closer inspection of the coloured sand we saw earlier we discovered that the colour was bits and pieces of plastic. Flip Flops, milk bottles, bottle tops, syringes, fishing line, crowd control barrier netting…. you name it there were traces of it everywhere.

Anything out there that was able to be washed inside the reef had been collecting on this tiny island where no one hardly ever goes. for a long time. We returned to the resort, and a day or so later I flew home. I remember that trip not for the fun times I had with friends, but for the images i keep with me of the garbage that hides just beyond the perceptive range of view.

For centuries people assumed when they tossed their crud into the waters it would be carried away, out of sight out of mind–gone forever, and it was…. to them.

But all that stuff we tossed in the rivers, lakes, streams and oceans made of non decaying material has to wind up somewhere. Too bad that most people just turn a blind eye to it because nowadays when you scratch the surface of paradise it bleeds the colours of a dying rainbow…….
 11.   Lisette Root Says:
 March 6th, 2010 at 11:20 pm 
I believe as humans we must do at least one thing for our precious earth and only home. I believe we should make using plastics so expensive that we go back to using glass again. If we can’t have cap and trade, we should tax the hell out of all synthetic non biodegradable polymers.
 12.   Project Kaisei Says:
 August 9th, 2010 at 2:30 pm 
Ocean Voyage Institute is making a HUGE effort to clean up this mess. They are currently raising funds to go the North Pacific Gyre this summer with a team of volunteers to collect the plastic and trash that has accumulated there, as well as researching environmentally friendly ways to dispose of it. You can help save our oceans and the wildlife that live there by visiting http://www.dreamsailraffle.com , as well as posting our website on your pages!
 13.   Sandy Beach Says:
 June 5th, 2011 at 6:02 pm 
Just wanna input on few general things, The website design is perfect, the content material is very fantastic : D.
 14.   Gary Adams Says:
 December 13th, 2011 at 7:48 pm 
I don’t know about you, but I don’t throw plastic into the ocean. All my household trash goes to a local landfill. How is this material getting into the ocean? My guess is that most of it is actually coming from Asia and Arica.
 

Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 
 




 
 
 
80beats Daily Newsletter
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Twitter
 Follow @discovermag 
 
Facebook
 
RSS Feed
 
The RSS feed for 80beats is here .
 
Sci News in 140
 rockahn.net 
on 80beats
 Recent Comments 
Comments

 Iain on Praying For a Breeze: Windy Conditions Help Male Mantises Mate (and Survive) Veronique Greenwood on Mysterious Cambodian Disease May Have a Name. But Why Is It So Lethal? Toby on Mysterious Cambodian Disease May Have a Name. But Why Is It So Lethal? Erin on Mysterious Cambodian Disease May Have a Name. But Why Is It So Lethal? Pippa on Mysterious Cambodian Disease May Have a Name. But Why Is It So Lethal? Marie on E. Coli That Cause Urinary Tract Infections are Now Resistant to Antibiotics 
 Recent Posts 
Posts

 Graphene, Heal Thyself: Carbon Molecule Can Rebuild Holes Look At This: A Space-Eye View of Colorado’s Burn Scar Mysterious Cambodian Disease May Have a Name. But Why Is It So Lethal? Motion-Sensing Gloves Could Let Deaf People Speak Aloud, Through Your Cellphone Praying For a Breeze: Windy Conditions Help Male Mantises Mate (and Survive) 
 Categories 
Categories

 Environment Feature Health&amp;Medicine Human Origins Journal Roundup Living World Mind&amp;Brain News Roundup Photo Gallery Physics&amp;Math Space Technology Top Posts Uncategorized 
 Archives 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 
 
About 80beats
 
80beats is DISCOVER&apos;s news aggregator, weaving together the choicest tidbits from the best articles on the day&apos;s most compelling topics.
80beats is written by Veronique Greenwood and Valerie Ross. This team darts through each day&apos;s science news faster than the ruby-throated hummingbird that beats its wings 80 times per second. Send ideas, tips, suggestions, and complaints to [azeeberg at discovermagazine dot com]. 


 
Copyright©2012, Kalmbach Publishing Co.
 
 Privacy - Terms - Reader Services - Subscribe Today - Advertise - About Us
	</body>
</document>
