<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007398" url="http://www.tilt-rotor.com/VT/Survival/Survival.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:22" support="4" score="0.006101500318307954" bingtitle="Surviving the Student Life in Wichita - Welcome to Kosuke&apos;s ..." webtitle="Surviving the Student Life in Wichita">
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>A Wichita born fast food restaurant. They serves roast beef ... I always get my order forgotten... Chipotle: Fast food ... If want to spend lots of money for a cup coffee ...</description>
	<body>
		Surviving the Student Life in Wichita 

 Last Updated on 2004/11/25 

 

 Being a student at Wichita State University as an international student is 
quite tough. That&apos;s what I have learned over the years. No matter how much you earn, or wants to spend. There are some basic stuffs 
you can know in order to survive years of academic life in Wichita. Since I have 
left Wichita on November 1st, 2004, there is no guarantee that the stores shown 
here still exists today, but just as a reference. So, here are some of gotta know stuffs in order to survive life in Wichita!

List: (click to Jump)
 
 Restaurants 
 General Burgers Deli Japanese Korean 
 Treats (Donut, Coffee, Diner...) Drugstores Supermarket, Grocery Stores Liquor store Bars Entertainment 
 (Movie theaters, Video rental) Shopping Mall Grocery Store Electric Appliances Clothing Bookstores Office Supplies Banks Others Tools and lumbers (DIY store) Computer 
 Components Automobile (Excluding the dealers to be fair...) Government Office 
 
 
 
 Restaurants: 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis A         Applebee&apos;s American North Rock Rd. A nationwide 
 franchise restaurant. Steaks, burgers, sandwiches, salad, and some drinks. Arby&apos;s Fast food 
 (Burgers) on Rock Rd, 
 north of K-96 I 
 have not been there yet.           B         Bangkok Thai food South Rock Rd, near Pawnee. My friend from Thailand told me that they have more traditional 
 taste than at&quot;Thai Traditions&quot;. Their soup is a lot Spicier than 
 at Thai Traditions and makes me cry. I guess which place to pick is depending on 
 your preference... Barn&apos;rds Fast food 
 (Burgers) on Woodlawn, 
 south of 21st A Wichita 
 born fast food restaurant. They serves roast beef burger. The BBQ seasoned 
 roast beef take a long time to prepare. Beijing Palace   Chinese, Buffet Harry and 
 Rock Rd A Chinese buffet. I think the largest in the town. 
 I used to go there back in 1996 but I am no longer a big fun of all you can 
 eat food... Bionic Burger Fast food (Burgers) Meridian and Harry (SE corner) Another local restaurant. This place has home made fries. 
 Oily, but my host father just loves it. I think this place tastes okay. Braum&apos;s Fast food 
 (Burgers) on Rock Rd, 
 north of K-96 Ice creams, milk, they have some chicken burgers and more. Buffalo Wild Wings Sports Bar on 
 North Rock Rd, 
 just south of K-96 If you feel like buying tons of chicken wings, here is the place 
 you can go. I went here with other Engineering Council members, and we ate 2 
 buckets (100 pieces each) of wings! Burger King Fast food 
 (Burgers) at SW corner 
 or 21st and Woodlawn Whooper 
 is the best! One of my friend likes to eat at here so I ended up going there 
 often. Boston Market Fast food 
 (Chicken) (CLOSED) 
 at NW corner of 29th and Rock Road. Chicken and side dishes. Their chickens are 
 pretty good. Dine-In or To-go. A bit expensive but worth it. I used to go 
 there a lot. but the store closed.           C         Chili&apos;s Grill and Bar Family Restaurant American, Mexican Central and Rock I always get my order forgotten... Chipotle Fast food 
 (Mexican) at NW corner of 29th and Rock Road Mexican fast food. I like this one a lot but I just don&apos;t go much. 
 All branches in Wichita used to be Boston Market. Cibola $$$, 
 Fancy food North Rock Rd. (Bradley Fair) I have never 
 been there but I heard it&apos;s pretty expensive Cici&apos;s Pizza   Pizza 37th and 
 between Woodlawn and Rock Rd. A 
 pizza place. I like their tomato sauce. Cinnamon&apos;s Deli Sandwich South side on 21st, between Oliver and Woodlawn. Sub Sandwiches, soups. It&apos;s cheap to 
 buy a set in stead of just a sandwich. It was a bit cheaper than eating at 
 Jason&apos;s Deli City Bites Sandwich SE corner of 21st and Woodlawn. A bit cheaper then Jason&apos;s Deli. I usually see a discount 
 coupon on Sunflower newspaper. Carlos O&apos;Kelly&apos;s Mexican North Rock Rd. Mexican 
 Food, I have not been there yet.           D         Dairy Queen Fast food, Burgers N. Rock 
 Road, near the 32nd street It 
 is located right near by the NorthRock14. Denny&apos;s American (Closed) Very first restaurant I visited in the U.S.           E                   F         Fazoli&apos;s Fast food, Italian North Rock Rd. 
 Rock Rd, just north of K-96 over pass Italian Fast Food Submarino (Baked Sub), Spaghetti, Lasagna...           G                   H         Hana Cafe Japanese, Korean Rock Rd. South of Central. Japanese/Korean food. A bit pricy but tastes good. Hometown Buffet American, Buffet NW corner of 
 Central and Woodlawn I have been here several times. The food is not so bad and you can eat a 
 lot.           I         Il Vicino Italian, Pizza Central and Oliver? They have a nice pizza but a bit pricy... IHOP (International House of Pancake) Pancake? North Rock Rd. I have never been there           J         Japan Express Fast food, Japanese NE corner of 21st and Rock Rd. Japanese 
 fast food restaurant. It is not my kind of food but I go there sometimes. Jason&apos;s Deli Sandwich SE corner of 21st and Rock Rd.  (Bradley Fair) Sub Sandwiches, salad or fruits bar.           K         Kentucky Fried Chicken Fast food, chicken On 21st 
 street, between Oliver and Woodlawn. Nationwide 
 (worldwide?) Fried Chicken 
 store Kobe Japanese, Teppanyaki Carriage Lane Japanese 
 food restaurant, Teppan Yaki I have been this place once Kyoto Japanese. Teppanyaki Central and Woodlawn? A Japanese 
 food restaurant, Teppan Yaki. I have been to this place once with my host family. I have to explain that Japanese don&apos;t cook food like that... Kwan Court Chinese, Sushi, buffet North Rock Rd. I have been there only few times. They have buffet and other 
 Chinese dishes           L         Long John Silver&apos;s Fast food, Fish fries On 21st street, between Oliver and Woodlawn  Fish or Chicken fries. The 
 food in this place is very oily...           M         Malaysia Cafe Fast food, Malaysian SW corner of 21st and Rock Rd. Similar to the Japan Express, you can eat Malaysian 
 fast food Mama San&apos;s Japanese 13th and West. You can eat real Japanese style dishes. (I think it is a little 
 salty...) Price is around $10. Manna Wok Korean Harry and Oliver Korean Food, Cheap but good. McDonald&apos;s Fast food, Burgers At NW corner of Hillside and 17th Street. I have been to this place many times when I was 
 an IELC student. Mr. Goodcents Sandwiches North Rock Rd. I get their 
 subs when I am teaching ARC classes. Not so bad Macaroni Grill Pasta, Italian North Rock Rd. (Bradley Fair) Italian 
 Food, Pastas...           N                   O         Outback Steakhouse Steak North Rock Rd. (Bradley Fair) Steak, 
 Australian style?. On the Border Mexican North Rock Rd. (Bradley Fair) Mexican 
 Food, not so bad but too much food sometimes. Osaka   Japanese   A Japanese 
 food restaurant,           P         Papa John&apos;s Pizza Pizza 21st St. near Rock Rd. A former 
 vice president of the Pizza Hut created this (?) P.F. Chang&apos;s Chinese 13th and Webb A very nice food at affordable price. 
 My friends and I agree with the taste of brown rice over the white rice. Pizza Hut Pizza at SW corner of 21st and 
 Woodlawn Originated in Kansas? 
 (The first store was at Bluff and Kellogg, where is in the middle of state 
 highway today...       at SW corner of 21st and Rock Rd.   Q                   R         Red Lobster   Seafood 333 S. Armor, west of TowneEast             S         Schulotsky&apos;s Fast food SE corner of Central and Woodlawn.  (Funny name, serious business?). I have been to this 
 place only once. This may be a good alternative from regular burgers. Spangles Fast food 
 (Burgers) on 21st, 
 near Woodlawn A Wichita 
 born fast food restaurant, cheaper than going to other places.
A local 
 fast food store. They are cheaper than McDonald&apos;s, but also better taste (in 
 my opinion)
 #1, Gourmet Supreme Subway Fast food, Sandwich on 21st street, near Woodlawn.  If you don&apos;t want to eat hamburgers, here is a place you can go Sumo Restaurant Japanese, Teppanyaki North Rock Rd. A Japanese 
 food restaurant, Teppan Yaki or Sushi bar Scotch and Sirloin   Steak, $$$ 5325 E. Kellogg but the location is a little off... I have been 
 there only once when I was working for Itochu Aviation Inc., No Shorts 
 please... Souper Salad Buffet, Salad SE corner of Kellogg and Rock. A salad buffet. This is my favorite place since I cannot 
 make any salad. They have salad, soup and tacos           T         Taco Bell Fast food 
 (Mexican) at NE corner of 21st and Rock Rd. Cheap Mexican food. They used to use a dog in 
 their Ads. Taco Tico Fast food (Mexican) at North Rock Rd. I have never been there before Thai Tradition Thai Carrigeparklane?  This is one of my favorite place I usually go.
 Pad Thai Timberline Steakhouse and 
 Grill Steak 21st near Rock Rd. right behind 
 of Dillon&apos;s           U                   V         Vietnamese 
 Restaurant (I don&apos;t know the name...) Vietnamese Just south of 13th and Broadway. I like their #1 set, rice noodle in a big bowl!
 #1 set           W         Wendy&apos;s Fast food, Burgers At SE corner 
 of 21st and Woodlawn             X                   Y         Yen Ching Chinese Central and Rock Affordable 
 and good restaurant. The environment inside reminds me the movie&quot;Crouching 
 Tiger Hidden Dragon&quot;...           Z                   
 
 
 
 Treats: Donuts, Diner, Coffee 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Daylight Donuts   Donuts 8909 W 
 Kellogg Dr. Donut shop Dunkin&apos; Donuts   Donuts   Not found in 
 Wichita Jimmy&apos;s Diner Shakes North Rock 
 Rd, near 29th. You get to 
 drink shakes and some more. The inside looks like 50s or 60s Krispy Kreme Donuts SW corner of 
 Central and Rock Rd. Donut shop. Opened here in December 2001 Starbucks Coffee Coffee NE corner of 
 Central and Rock Rd.  If want to spend lots of money for a cup coffee, you 
 should go there (I am not a big fun of coffee...) Opened 2003/05/07 Rock Road and Central   Coffee Rock Road 
 and 29th Opened May 
 2004           
 
 
 
 Drugstores: 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Osco Drugs   Drugstore   One of 
 common drug store. You can get prescription drugs. Walgreen&apos;s   Drugstore   Another 
 famous drug stores                     
 
 
 
 Supermarket, Grocery Stores: 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Albertsons   Groceries   They used to 
 be at 21st and Rock Rd. Now there is no Albertsons left in Wichita. ALDI Groceries 21st St. 
 Between Woodlawn and Rock Rd. a super 
 cheap supermarket. They opens only limited hours and you might see some out 
 of stock items. China Market Groceries, 
 Asian Just south 
 of 21st and Broadway, if you need to buy rice, noodles and some other 
 oriental stuffs, you can try here Dillons Groceries 21st St. and 
 Rock Rd. (NE corner) A local 
 supermarket. They have sold it&apos;s distribution unit to a Texas company back 
 in 2000(?) They cannot beat Wal-Mart in most of the time, but people who 
 don&apos;t need to save money in Kansas like them better. Food 4 Less   Groceries     K-Mart   Groceries 4200 W. 
 Kellogg       Groceries 4830 S. 
 Broadway   Sam&apos;s Club Whole sale North Rock 
 Road, North of K-96 A kind of 
 Wal-Mart, but you can only buy in a larger unit. Thai Binh Supermarket Groceries, 
 Asian 21st and 
 Amidon(?) I don&apos;t know much about it. Wal-Mart Groceries at 29th and 
 Rock. You can buy groceries, items you need pretty much in everyday life. 
 They can also change oil and tires...           
 
 
 
 Liquor Shop 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Jacob Liquor Exchange Liquor Store NW corner of 
 29th and Rock Rd. You can buy almost all kinds of drinks!                     
 
 
 
 Entertainments: Movie Theaters, Video Rentals 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis All Star Sports (East)   Sports at just 
 north of Central and Webb. Mini golf, 
 Go Kart, Shooting Golf. All Star Sports (West) Sports at 21st and 
 Ridge(?) Mini golf, 
 Go Kart, Shooting Golf Blockbuster Video Video, DVD 
 and game rental 21st St. and 
 Rock Rd. (NE corner) You can rent 
 DVD, VHS and some Game software from them Dillon&apos;s Video, DVD 
 rental 21st St. and 
 Rock Rd. (NE corner) Dillons also have a small section of video rentals Hollywood Video Video, DVD 
 rental North Rock 
 Rd. Similar to 
 the Blockbuster Video NorthRock14 Movie 
 theater North Rock 
 Rd. Near K-96 14 screens, this one is bigger and has better seats than the 
 NorthRock6, which was closed now. NorthRock6 Movie 
 theater (CLOSED on 
 2003/07/29) N. Rock Rd. This movie theater was the place where we could hang out. I have 
 lots of good memories... Palace (East) Movie 
 theater NW corner of 
 Kellogg and Greenwich They used to let us watch movie for only $1.50! The 
 fun place to go back in 96, 97 and maybe 98. Palace (West)   Movie 
 theater   I have not 
 been there yet. Warren Theaters (Downtown) Movie 
 theater Old town 
 area I have not check this place out yet... Warren Theaters (East) Movie 
 theater E. 13th St. 12 screens, you can drink alcoholic beverages if 
 you are 21 or older! Warren Theaters (West) Movie 
 theater 21st and 
 Tyler I don&apos;t go there often since it&apos;s a bit far. 
 I watched Godzilla and the Pearl Harbor           
 
 
 
 Bars: 
 (Sports bar, Piano bar...) 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Bennigan&apos;s Bar Douglas and 
 Rock Rd. Drinking 
 Place, I have been there few times Fingers   Piano Bar at SE corner 
 of 21st street and Woodlawn, this store is located behind of Hobby Lobby. Old Chicago Sports Bar? Kellogg and 
 Rock Rd. Drinking 
 Place, Tanner&apos;s Bar at SE corner 
 of 21st street and Woodlawn, I went to 
 the one in KC before. Burgers, beers and so on...           
 
 
 
 Shopping Malls 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Towne East Mall   Shopping 
 mall NW of 
 Kellogg and Rock Rd. A shopping 
 mall located just north of Kellogg Street and Rock Road.
The stores: 
 Sears, Old Navy, Express,

  Towne West Mall   Shopping 
 Mall West St. Another 
 shopping mall located in the west side. My personal opinion thinks this 
 place is better...
The stores including           
 
 
 
 Electric Appliances Stores 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Radio Shack   North Rock 
 Rd. A nationwide 
 electric appliance chain, they are smaller than other kind of places such as 
 Best Buy and Circuit City, but if you need to save some money, or cannot 
 find a certain kind of battery, you should check this out. Best Buy Electric 
 Appliances, Music, Video, PCs North Rock 
 Rd. (Tallgrass Center) A nationwide 
 electric appliance store Circuit City Electric 
 Appliances, Music, Video, PCs East Kellogg Electric Appliances. CompUSA Electric 
 Appliances, Music, Video, PCs North Rock 
 Rd. Electric 
 Appliance store, heavy on PC, DVD and Games. They also sells parts for the 
 hand made PCs...                     
 
 
 
 Clothing 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Dillard&apos;s   Department 
 store TowneEast 
 Mall, TowneWest Mall   Eddie 
 Bauer     Bradley Fair   Gap     Bradley Fair   Kohl&apos;s Department 
 store North Rock 
 Rd. They sells shoes, shorts and regular clothing. They 
 sometimes carry Speedo! J C Penny   Department 
 store TowneEast 
 Mall,   Old Navy     TowneEast 
 Mall,   Sears   Department 
 store TowneEast 
 Mall,   Express (Structure) 
      TowneEast 
 Mall, The Express 
 and the Structure used to be two different companies but they merged 
 recently. Gordmans Department 
 store   I have not 
 been there yet.           
 
 
 
 Bookstores 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Barns&amp;Noble Bookstore, 
 Cafe, Internet? One at NW 
 corner of Rock Rd and 29th St. A book store, CDs, 
 coffees, Godiva chocolate...     Bookstore, 
 Cafe, Internet? The other 
 one is at SE corner at Kellogg and Rock.   Borders Bookstore, Cafe, Internet? North Rock Rd. 
 between 21st and 13th street, You can also buy CDs, have some 
 coffees at cafe. I think they have live music performance in the evenings 
 sometime. Books To Go Bookstore, Hillside, 
 south of 17th St. If you think WSU 
 bookstore is too expensive, you may save some money by going there. WSU Bookstore   Bookstore, 
 Merchandise on campus, 
 inside of RSC you can buy 
 our textbooks, they also buy them back at the end of the semester for very 
 cheap price.
            
 
 
 
 Office Supplies 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Kinko&apos;s Office 
 supply, binding, fax, internet, copying North Rock 
 Rd. Photocopies, 
 Fax, internet access, printing and more. Office supplies Office Depot Office 
 supplies NW corner of 
 29th and Rock Rd. If you need to buy folders, notes, pens, 
 boxes, PDA and some computers also. Office Max Office 
 supplies North Rock 
 Rd. just north of K-96 Pretty much the same as the Office Depot.           
 
 
 
 Banks 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Bank of America   21st and 
 Hillside, Right across the Fairmount Towers. One of the largest bank in the U.S. (When I came here 
 in 1996, the name of the bank was Bank IV, then changed to NationsBank, 
 later changed again to this Bank of America) Commerce 
 Bank     on campus, 
 inside of RSC   Credit 
 Union   on campus   Intrust Bank         Emprise Bank         Sunflower 
 Bank                             
 
 
 
 Sporting Goods: (Running, Swimming, Biking and more) 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis First 
 Gear   Running     Finish 
 Line, The   Sports 
 General     Gart Sports Sporting 
 goods 21st between 
 Woodlawn and Rock  This place is called&quot;Wichita Sports&quot;when I came 
 here, then went bankrupt and later reopened as&quot;Jumbo Sport&quot;but it went 
 bankrupt again and now it is called&quot;Gart SportS&quot; Dick&apos;s Sports Sporting 
 goods 21st and 
 Rock Rd. Sporting 
 goods. Foot 
 Locker, The         Adventure Sports Diving, 
 Skiing, Rollerblade, Skateboard Central and 
 Woodlawn (NW corner) Located on 
 NW corner of Central and Woodlawn. If you want to buy rollerblades, 
 skateboards, or wants to get SCUBA license and gears, here is the place you 
 can go. I have got my SCUBA diving license from them. Bicycle X 
 Change         L&amp;M 
 Schwinn Bicycle Shop Douglas and 
 Rock                                           
 
 
 
 Others 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Toys R Us Toy store SE of 
 Kellogg and Rock Rd. You can buy toys. 5th Avenue Gift Gift shop Located on 
 SE corner of Central and Woodlawn. If you are looking for a fancy gifts, you 
 might want to try this. They have some cosmetics, candles, teas, chocolates 
 and more... Party City Party goods North Rock 
 Rd. For 
 Halloween and other parties. Usually get crowded easily so you should go 
 there in advance. Verizon Wireless SW of Rock 
 Rd. and 21st If you want 
 to buy a cellphone, here is a place to go Cricket   Wireless 21st and 
 Woodlawn If you want 
 to buy a cellphone, here is a place to go T Mobile   Wireless Rock Rd. and 
 Kellogg If you want 
 to buy a cellphone, here is a place to go Sprint   Wireless     Hallmark Gift, Cars SE corner of 
 21st and Woodlawn   Biker&apos;s 
 Edge   Motorcycle     Dental Corner   Dentist Oliver 
 between 21st and 17th A dentist 
 closest to campus. My friend is working here right now. Best Cleaners   Dry Cleaning on 21st, 
 near Woodlawn The dry 
 cleaning place I usually use. YMCA Fitness Center N. Woodlawn                                 
 
 
 
 DIY: Tools, 
Lumbers, homebuilt computer, 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Ace Hardware DIY Hillside and 
 Douglas   Home Depot DIY North 
 Woodlawn If you need 
 to buy tools, pipes, nuts and bolts and so on. Stars Lumber Supply   DIY Central and 
 Woodlawn(?) Wichita born 
 company? Hobby Lobby Hobbies SE corner of 
 21st and Woodlawn I don&apos;t know much about it. National Computer   Computer 
 components Lincoln and 
 Oliver? Computer 
 equipment for home build ones. Motherboard, CPU, CD-ROM drives, speakers, 
 keyboards and more...           
 
 
 
 Computers, Hobbies    
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Wings Over Wichita Airplane Webb and 
 Central If you want to buy 
 something related to airplane, headsets, books and videos for the training. 
 I bought my DC headsets here.                     
 
 
 
 Automobile 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Pepboys Parts, 
 Tires, Batteries, Garage, Shop On east 
 Kellogg, right by the turnpike The labor is 
 cheaper than at Dealer&apos;s garage. You can buy tools. They have cheap tires 
 but not brand named. NTB 
 (National Tire and Battery)   Tires, 
 Batteries 505 S. West 
 St., right north of Kellogg I have 
 replaced my tires once here. As the name says, they sells tires and 
 batteries. It is cheaper than doing at automobile dealers.  AAA Kansas Auto club 4817 E. 
 Douglas, East of Oliver You can get 
 maps, travel reservation,     Auto club 7130 MW. 
 Maple #200, Near Ridge Rd.   Midas   Brake, 
 Muffler North Rock 
 Rd. Near K-96   Rapid 
 Auto Center   Brake, 
 Muffler   Used to be&quot;Rapid Brake and Muffler&quot; Avis   Rent-A-Car at Airport   Budget   Rent-A-Car at airport   Enterprise   Rent-A-Car many 
 locations in Wichita   Hertz   Rent-A-Car at Airport, 
 or East side at Webb and Central   Farmers 
 Insurance Auto 
 Insurance Douglas and 
 Rock Rd. This is the 
 insurance agency I have been doing business with for whole my Wichita life. 
 They will give you several discounts.
 Good student discount (for GPA 3.0 or higher, 25% off) Preferred Customer (no accidents, speeding ticket for 3(?) years, more 
 than 25% off) Graduation discount (with your diploma, 5% off) 
 American 
 Family Insurance   Auto 
 Insurance     QuikTrip Gas Station Central and 
 Rock Rd.   Phillip 66                             
 
 
 
 Government Offices 
 
 Name: Pictures: 
 (Click to enlarge) Type: Location: Synopsis Drivers License Office Drivers 
 License 1823 W. 21st St. Suite 42a Wichita, KS 67203 You can get 
 your ID, IP or DL issued. The place is at SE 21st Street and Amidon, but it is located behind of all stores. 
 7:00am - 5:00pm Tuesday to Friday 
 Tag Office Vehicle 
 Registration 2120 N. Woodlawn Suite 370 Wichita, KS 67208  This 
 is the place you need to go when you are registering your vehicle for the 
 first time
  Social Security Office Social 
 Security 8533 E. 32nd St. N Wichita, KS 67226-6515 If you are 
 applying for a SSN, you need to come over here. 
 7:00am-7:00pm Mon-Fri 
 
  Vehicle Inspection   Vehicle 
 Inspection   If you purchased your car from outside of the 
 state, you need to register your car here. 
   
 
                      
 
 

Go back to Top 

Go back to Home
	</body>
</document>
