<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007292" url="http://www.activediner.com/fast-food/restaurant/des-moines/ia/us/region-131" time="2012-07-13-00:15" support="2" score="0.004756581184720807" bingtitle="fast food Restaurants in des moines, ia" webtitle="fast food Restaurants in des moines, ia">
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>Billiard/Pool Tables; Bistro; Breakfast; Brewery/Pub/Tavern ... 1 - 10 of 165 fast-food restaurant listings found. ... Two Girls One Cup Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Mexican 
 Chinese 
 Italian 
 Burger 
 Thai 
 Bagel Shop 
 French 
 Vietnamese 
 
 more... 
 24 Hours American Bagel Shop Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Billiard/Pool Tables Bistro Breakfast Brewery/Pub/Tavern Brunch Bucktown Bistro Buffet Burger Business Lunch Cafe Cafeteria Cajun/Creole Cantonese style Casual/Family Catering Chicken Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Coffee Shop Comfort Food/Home Cooking Country Dance Floor Darts Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Dim Sum Diner Dinner Early Bird Special European Fast Food Fine Dining Fireplace French Fun and Games Greek Happy Hour Hong Kong Cuisine Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Indian Indian/Pakistan Irish Italian Italian (Traditional) Karaoke Kids Friendly Kosher Late Night Dining Latin Live Entertainment Lunch Mexican Middle Eastern Open Kitchen/Tour Organic Outdoor Seating Pizzeria Romantic Scenic View Seafood Senior Discount Smoking/Non Smoking Spanish Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Sushi Bar Take Out/Carry Out Thai Truck Stop TV/Satellite Vietnamese Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access 
 
 




Popular Cities
 West Des Moines 
 Urbandale 
 Ankeny 
 Clive 
 Indianola 
 Altoona 
 Webster City 
 Johnston 
 Waukee 
 Perry 
 
 more... 
 Adel Bondurant Bouton Carlisle Cumming Dallas Center De Soto Dexter Granger Grimes Lacona Martensdale Mitchellville Norwalk Pleasant Hill Polk City Redfield Rockwell City Van Meter Windsor Heights Woodward 
 
 



 
 
 
   
 
 



 
   United States  &gt;  Iowa  &gt;  des moines 
fast food Restaurants in des moines, ia
 1 - 10 of 165 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt;   
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Wall 2 Wall Mart 
Mexican, Seafood, Casual/Family, Fast Food
3308 Indianola Ave, Des Moines
(515) 282-4004   LATEST REVIEW   
Excellent food, lots of choices and everything is very tasty and prepared well and quickly. They have the absolute BEST SALSA in town. They give you three different kinds of Salsa and chips free when you dine in. Try the Giant Burrito! Great lun...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 4.8 
 B&amp;B Grocery Meat&amp;Deli 
Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food
2001 Southeast 6th Street, Des Moines
(515) 243-7607   DESCRIPTION 
B&amp;B Grocery, Meat&amp;Deli is a neighborhood grocery store with an outstanding deli and old-fashion meat market. It has been family owned and operated since Archie and John Brooks opened it in May 1922. 

Since then five generations of the Brooks ...
 LATEST REVIEW   
B&amp;B;is the best place to go and get a great sandwich. The people there are the best. It reminds me of a store I would find back home in Boston. I love the sandwiches and the meat is excellent
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 4.0 
 Big Tomato Pizza CO 
Pizzeria, Fast Food
2613 Ingersoll Avenue, Des Moines
(515) 288-7227   LATEST REVIEW   
The food is wonderful. It has a very diverse and unusual list of ingredients. I really like the slices after midnight but I think they should sell slices all day long! The service is not that great. Don&apos;t ever get delivery (they couldn&apos;t find my apar...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   advertisements 
 
 
 
 RATING 3.8 
 Drake Diner 
American, Diner, Fast Food
1111 25th Street, Des Moines
(515) 277-1111   LATEST REVIEW   
The food was fantastic, but what wait to get it! We were seated immediately, but waited 20 minutes for a server. Our food then sat in the kitchen window for a long time and our watiress was not in sight. We would go back for the food and hope the w...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 3.8 
 Two Girls One Cup 
Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food
3705 Ingersoll Avenue,
Jovphglrzazhh, Des Moines
(515) 274-1208   DESCRIPTION 
 two girls one cup.com 
 LATEST REVIEW   
It&apos;s certainly better than the overpriced slop they serve at Palmer&apos;s Deli. Jason&apos;s Deli is better in my opinion. It isn&apos;t much of a &quot;Deli&quot; really, it&apos;s a sandwich shop. The Mama Mia is their best sandwich by far. The staff seem to be the resident pe...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 2.0 
 Buzzard Billys 
Cajun/Creole, Casual/Family, Fast Food, Business Lunch
100 Court Avenue, Des Moines
(515) 280-6060   LATEST REVIEW   
I love the diverse food and the atmoshpere is awesome!! The service is never very good but the food makes up for it!!
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   A Taste Of Thailand 
Thai, Casual/Family, Fast Food, Business Lunch
215 E Walnut Street, Des Moines
(515) 243-9521   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 
Fast Food
1250 East Army Post Road, Des Moines
(515) 287-6831   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 
Fast Food
208 Johnson Court, Des Moines
(515) 265-1957   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 
Fast Food
3917 East 14th Street, Des Moines
(515) 266-8853   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   


 
 Next &gt;&gt; 



 Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for? Try searching here...
 
      Know of a restaurant we don&apos;t have?   Click here to add it. 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
