<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007078" url="http://www.katom.com/cat/ice-makers.html" time="2012-07-13-00:04" support="23" score="0.06817490845402494" bingtitle="Commercial Ice Makers | KaTom Restaurant Supply, Inc." webtitle="Commercial Ice Makers | KaTom Restaurant Supply, Inc.">
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000069" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000079" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000754" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000066" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001254" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000063" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000760" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="47"/>
	<description>Cashier / Reception Stands; Merchandising Carts &amp; Kiosks ... ice dispenser can take pressure off of your fast food restaurant ... takes up space in a restaurant that could be put ...</description>
	<body>
		Need help with your purchase?

Chat with a KaTom specialist
 No, thanks Residential Clearance ( Log In or Register ) Track my Order 
RESTAURANT SUPPLY, INC.
 1-800-541-8683 
 Restaurant Equipment 
 Commercial Refrigeration Commercial Ice Makers Ovens&amp;Ranges Food Warming Equipment Commercial Fryers Grills, Griddles, Char-Broilers, Hot Plates&amp;Accessories Sinks, Faucets&amp;Accessories Shelving&amp;Carts Commercial Dishwashers Slicers Work Tables, Butcher Blocks&amp;Equipment Stands Commercial Mixers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Vegetable and Salad Dryers Hoods&amp;Accessories 
 

 Kitchen Supplies 
 Textiles, Aprons, Towels, Smocks, Pot-holders, Gloves Baking Supplies Storage Containers&amp;Food Bar Crocks Steam Pans&amp;Covers Kitchen Utensils Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Cookware Knives, Turners&amp;Accessories Hot Food Pans, Covers&amp;Accessories Food Pans&amp;Accessories Foodservice Brushes Can&amp;Bottle Openers Time Clocks&amp;Timers Signage 
 

 Tabletop 
 Serving Items Dispensers Silverware&amp;Flatware Table Tents, Card Holders&amp;Decorative Drinkware Baskets Dinnerware Shakers&amp;Mills (Salt, Pepper, Cheese&amp;Other) Presentation Cookware / Serveware Cooling Tubs Menu Covers&amp;Guest Checks Cash&amp;Carry Items Dessert&amp;Pastry Carts Buffet Stands and Risers Table Coverings / Tablecloths 
 

 Countertop 
 Concession Equipment Food Warmers Mixers&amp;Accessories Drink Dispensers Condiment&amp;Food Dispensers Toasters Chop, Core, Dice, Slice, Wedge and Fry Cutters Coffee&amp;Tea Equipment Blenders Hot Dog Equipment Popcorn Machines, Accessories&amp;Supplies Food Processors Meat Processing Equipment Pancake, Waffle,&amp;Crepe Supplies Induction Range 
 

 Bar Supplies 
 Bar Refrigeration Bartending Supplies Bar Drinkware Portable Bars Speed Rails Wait Service Supplies Wine Supplies Bar Matting Glass Racks and Hangers Bar Glass Washers Blenders&amp;Mixers 
 

 Furniture 
 Outdoor Furniture Coca Cola Series Furniture Tables&amp;Bases Portable Bars Youth Seating Crowd Guidance Systems Restaurant Booths Restaurant Seating Chairs Cluster Seating Bar Stools Cashier / Reception Stands Merchandising Carts&amp;Kiosks Kitchen Countertops Rubbermaid Indoor / Outdoor Planters Patio Heaters 
 

 Catering&amp;Buffet 
 Tabletop Serving Items Carts Catering&amp;Buffet Storage Containers Steam Pans&amp;Covers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Dinnerware Coffee Percolators&amp;Urns Tea Brewers&amp;Dispensers Commercial Coffee Makers: Thermal / Airpot Brewers Food Pans&amp;Accessories Catering Food Carriers Serving&amp;Buffet Series 
 

 See
More 
 Pizza Equipment Replacement Parts Request a Quote Shop By Brand Buyer&apos;s Guides Learning Center KaTom Kids Jamie Oliver Free Shipping KaTom Coupons Janitorial Go Green 
 
 Order #: Zip Code: Katom  &gt;  Restaurant Equipment  &gt;  Commercial Ice Makers 
Shop By Category
 Undercounter Ice Makers 
 Head Only Ice Makers 
 Head&amp;Bin Combination Ice Makers 
 Ice Dispensers 
 Outdoor Ice Makers 
 Water Filters 
 Ice Maker Accessories 
 
Shop By Brand
 Manitowoc Ice 
 Hoshizaki 
 Ice-O-Matic 
 Scotsman 
 Supreme Metal 
 San Jamar 
 Rubbermaid 
 Infra 
 Tablecraft 
 Browne Foodservice 
 Vollrath 
 Win-Holt 
 Winco 
 Summit Refrigeration 
 Cambro 
 
Commercial Ice Makers

If you&apos;re in need of ice for your business you&apos;re in luck! KaTom sells commercial ice makers that produce impurity free ice for your clientele&apos;s beverages and more. We will include a free water filter with your purchase of a qualified unit! Having a hard time deciding if you need an commercial ice maker for cube, pearl, or flake ice or what size Commercial Ice Maker you need to keep up with business? Our staff will help you choose a commercial ice maker with the capacity, ice type, and speed!
 
 Undercounter Ice Makers 

Does your restaurant have little space for a large ice machine but must have ice for the buffet and/or drinks? KaTom Restaurant supply has your ice needs covered with a commercial undercounter ice maker! These models stay neatly out of the way while still making large amounts of ice. KaTom&apos;s commercial undercounter ice makers come in all sorts of ice styles and capacities so you&apos;re sure to find a model for your business&apos;s needs. The commercial undercounter ice maker for you is just a click away!
 Manitowoc Ice QY0134A Ice Maker W/ 80 lb Bin, Half Dice, 145 lb /24 hrs, Air Cooled 
$1,513.68
 Manitowoc Ice QD0132A Ice Maker w/ 80 lb Bin, 145 lbs/24 hr, Full Cube, Air Cooled, 115/1 V 
$1,513.68
 
 Head Only Ice Makers 

Is your commercial head ice maker on it&apos;s last legs of life. Save money (and your existing holding bin) by purchasing a commercial head ice maker from KaTom Restaurant Supply! We sell several trusted brands so finding the fit for your ice bin will be no problem. Need cube ice or even flake ice? KaTom&apos;s selection of commercial head ice makers come in both styles as well as half cube, crescent, and nugget ice. Experience the great customer service and item pricing KaTom has to offer today!
 Manitowoc Ice IY-0454A-161 Ice Maker, Half Cube, 450-lb/24-Hr, Air Cooled, 115 V 
NEW LOW PRICE
 Manitowoc Ice ID-0852A-261 Ice Maker, Full Cube, 940-lb/24-Hr, Air Cooled, 208-230/1 V 
NEW LOW PRICE
 
 Head&amp;Bin Combination Ice Makers 

Your business ice maker needs are just a click away at KaTom Restaurant Supply. When it comes to quality ice makers and bins you can count on KaTom&apos;s superb selection. Are you more interested in nugget ice or maybe flake style ice? No problem; KaTom carries ice makers that produce nugget, cube, crescent, half cube ice and more. Since KaTom keeps your budget in mind when pricing ice bins and ice machines you can be sure to find a model in your budget range.
 Manitowoc Ice ID0452A161B400 Ice Maker w/ 290-lb Bin, Full Cube, 450-lb/24-Hr, Air, 115 V 
NEW LOW PRICE
 Hoshizaki KM-515MAH B300PF Ice Maker w/ 300-lb Bin, Crescent Style, 501-lb/24 Hr, Air 
NEW LOW PRICE
 
 Ice Dispensers 

A drink just isn&apos;t the same without the refreshing kick of cold ice. Make portioning ice a quick and easy job with a commercial ice dispenser from KaTom! Adding a commercial ice dispenser can take pressure off of your fast food restaurant by making drinks self serve or quick to make for waiting customers. KaTom sells models for all types of ice including cube, nugget, and flake ice at large and small capacities. Cool down with a commercial ice dispenser from KaTom.
 Manitowoc Ice SN12A Ice Maker&amp;Water Dispenser, 12-lb Bin, 325-lb/Day, Lever Activated 
NEW LOW PRICE
 Manitowoc Ice SN-12AT Ice Maker&amp;Water Dispenser, 12-lb Bin, 325-lb/Day, Sensor Activated 
NEW LOW PRICE
 
 Outdoor Ice Makers 

Ice making machinery too often takes up space in a restaurant that could be put to better use. Keep your space free with a commercial outdoor ice maker from KaTom Restaurant Supply! The commercial outdoor ice makers we feature on our website are made with durable stainless steel and are for built in or free standing utilization. Experience the free shipping and great pricing you get with a KaTom commercial outdoor ice maker!
 Hoshizaki AM-50BAE Undercounter Ice Maker w/ 22-lb Bin, Top Hat Style, 55-lb/Day 
NEW LOW PRICE
 Hoshizaki C-100BAF-AD Undercounter Ice Maker w/ 22-lb Bin, Cubelet, 92-lb/24 Hr 
NEW LOW PRICE
 
 Water Filters 

Without commercial water filters the water food businesses use to make ice, drinks, and food would be impure and not really worth drinking. Keeping your water clean and impurity free is as easy as buying one of many quality commercial water filters from KaTom Restaurant Supply. Reduce the odors, bad flavors, and lime in your water with a commercial water filter and TASTE the difference pure water makes!
 Manitowoc Ice AR10000 Arctic Pure, Primary Water Filter Assembly 
NEW LOW PRICE
 Ice-O-Matic IOMQ Replacement Filter Cartridge For Ice-O-Matic IFQ1, IFQ2 
$53.69
 
 Ice Maker Accessories 

Sure you have a fantastic ice maker but what are you going to use to scoop or transport the ice you need? Choose from a wide variety of commercial ice maker accessories at KaTom. Our commercial ice maker accessories include mobile ice caddy units and even ice safety funnels that help prevent wet floors and slips. Save your ice and your business&apos;s budget with KaTom Restaurant Supply&apos;s competitively priced ice maker accessories!
 Supreme Metal D-12-IBL Drop-In Ice Bin, 18 in x 12 in x 11 in 
$256.50
 Supreme Metal D-24-IBL Drop-In Ice Bin, 18 in x 21 in x 10 in 
$336.60
 
Be in the know and receive exclusive savings
 
KaTom Restaurant Supply

 About KaTom Career Opportunities Product Review 
 
Customer Care

 Contact Us Return Request Order Tracking My Account Financing&amp;Leasing Shipping Information 
 
Shopping With KaTom

 Restaurant Equipment Kitchen Supplies Tabletop Countertop Bar Supplies Furniture Catering&amp;Buffet Shop By Brands 
 
KaTom Policies

 Return Policy Shipping Policy Privacy Policy Terms of Use Secure Shopping 
 
Let&apos;s Get Social

 Facebook Twitter YouTube Google Plus Pinterest 
 
What People Think of KaTom.com
 
Copyright©2001-2012 KaTom Restaurant Supply Inc. All rights reserved.
 
Safe Shopping Guarantee
 
 E-Mail Us With Questions Live Chat 1-800-541-8683 
 Monday - Friday 
 8am - 8pm EST 
 Name 
 E-Mail 
 Phone 

To verify that you are a human user, please answer:
 What is the sum of ? 
 What is the best way to contact you? E-Mail Phone 
 Questions or Comments
	</body>
</document>
