<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007060" url="http://us.businessesforsale.com/us/search/Miscellaneous-Restaurants-for-sale-in-Illinois" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="1" score="0.0003467544659816346" bingtitle="Miscellaneous Restaurants for sale in Illinois, IL, buy a ..." webtitle="Miscellaneous Restaurants for sale in Illinois, IL, buy a Restaurant in Illinois, IL on BusinessesForSale.com">
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... Naperville, Illinois. 75 seat (licensed for 90) fully furnished restaurant ... Turnkey Fast Food Restaurant In Illinois For ... for anyone looking to enter the restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		BusinessesForSale website uses cookies. To understand more about cookies and their benefits please see our Cookie Policy . By continuing to use this site you consent to our use of cookies on this device in accordance with our cookie policy.
 Choose country 
Choose your country

 Argentina France Mexico Spain Australia Germany New Zealand Sweden Brazil Greece Poland Thailand Bulgaria India Portugal UAE Canada Ireland Singapore UK China Israel South Africa USA Cyprus Malaysia 

Or view all businesses for sale

 Worldwide 
 USA 
 Log in Help 
 Business for sale 
 Buy a Business 
 Advanced search Mid Market Register as a buyer Business resources Email alerts Business wanted Finance wanted Discuss Shortlist Services directory Selling a Business Blog 
 Buy a Franchise 
 Browse franchise opportunities Franchise A-Z Franchise resales Advertise your franchise 
 Sell a Business 
 Create a business for sale advert Buyers seeking businesses Buyer leads by email preferences Prospect buyers shortlist Selling a Business Blog How to sell a business 
 For Brokers 
 Finance wanted Buyers seeking businesses Services directory 
 
 
 
 This search: Save Get Email Alerts Clear Edit with advanced search 
 
 
 filter Food (155) filter Restaurants (63) filter Misc. Restaurants (23) 
 
 filter USA (1673) filter Mid West (104) filter Illinois (23) filter All Cities 
 
 
Miscellaneous Restaurants For Sale in Illinois

 Around 480,000 restaurants together generate more than $400bn a year for the US economy. With more than half of Americans eating out at least once a week, there’s plenty of custom to fight for if you’re interested in buying a restaurant . Find out how Gordon Ramsay turned round Le Bistro or listen to this Restaurateur on understanding your customers . 
 (What is RSS?) 
 Results per page: 10 25 50 

 Sort by: Time: newly added/updated Asking Price: lowest first Asking Price: highest first Asking Price: newly reduced Sales Revenue: lowest first Sales Revenue: highest first Cash Flow: lowest first Cash Flow: highest first 
 
 Showing 1 - 10 of 23 Miscellaneous Restaurants for sale in Illinois, IL 

 1 2 3 NEXT 

 American Business Acquisitions Inc. State sponsored by:
 Search other businesses for sale represented by this leading business broker. View American Business Acquisitions, Inc&apos;s businesses for sale&gt;&gt; 
 Updated 
 Restaurant In Quaint Central Illinois River Community Central Illinois, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $99,000 Sales Revenue: $42,529 Cash Flow: up to $50k 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Central Illinois American Restaurants in Central Illinois 
 
 Guidant Financial 401(k) Small Business Financing Use IRA, 401k and other retirement funds as a loan down payment or to purchase a new business or franchise. By rolling your existing retirement funds into Guidant’s 401(k) small business financing plan you can invest in a small business or franchise... without tax penalties! Click here for more 
 Updated 
 Sports Bar Restaurant Billiard Pool Hall Chicago Northwest Suburbs, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $150,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Bars in Chicago Miscellaneous Restaurants in Chicago Snooker and Pool Centres in Chicago 
 
 
 Updated 
 50 Year Old Restaurant Outstanding Food In Peoria Peoria, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $449,000 Sales Revenue: $450,000 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Peoria 
 
 
 
 Great Steakhouse Restaurant And Lounge West Central Illinois, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $299,000 Sales Revenue: $198,000 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Illinois 
 
 
 
 Great Little Pub In Peoria Peoria, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $30,000 Sales Revenue: $146,000 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Pubs in Peoria Miscellaneous Restaurants in Peoria 
 
 
 
 Two Banded Gas Stations And Restaurant In Illinois East Central Illinois, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $1,695,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in East Central Illinois Gas / Petrol Service Stations in East Central Illinois 
 
 
 
 Beautiful Bar And Restaurant In Peoria Peoria, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $235,000 Sales Revenue: $460,000 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Bars in Peoria Miscellaneous Restaurants in Peoria 
 
 
 
 Historic Restaurant In Peoria Illinois Peoria, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $680,000 Sales Revenue: $600,000 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Peoria 
 
 
 
 Profitable Italian Restaurant In Chicago Chicago, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $199,900 Sales Revenue: $838,317 Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Chicago Italian Restaurants in Chicago 
 
 
 
 Billion Dollar FutureGen Gas Station In Western Illinois Western Illinois, Illinois 
 Asking Price: $439,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 
See more businesses in:

 Miscellaneous Restaurants in Western Illinois Gas / Petrol Service Stations in Western Illinois 
 
 
 Showing 1 - 10 of 23 Miscellaneous Restaurants for sale in Illinois, IL 

 1 2 3 NEXT 

 
Franchise Opportunities that match your search
 
 Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Franchise 
 
We believe the Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop franchise has a commitment to quality and attention to detail goes into every restaurant and sub sandwich and has helped Lenny&apos;s to become one of the fastest growing sub sandwich chains in the country. At Lenny&apos;s we specifically recruit well-capitalized franchisees who have a desire to develop a multi-unit restaurant company, area exclusivity, and preferably some restaurant experience.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 Cianci European Eatery Franchise 
 
At the Cianci European Eatery franchise we have created delectable cuisine born out of the bustling, bistros of Europe. A palate nurtured in the healthy eateries of a burgeoning American marketplace. This is the inspiration for us at the Cianci European Eatery.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 Entrees Made Easy Franchise 
 
At the Entrees Made Easy franchise our expert planning and preparation eliminates most of the customers&apos; work, while wholesale buying saves them money. As a new Entrees Made Easy franchisee you will undergo 2 weeks of intensive training, both classroom and in-store, covering all aspects of the Entrees Made Easy franchise business from menu selection, food purchase, customer service, cash management, advertising, promotions, and opening and closing procedures. After the original training, there is ongoing support for the life of the franchise.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 Mandler’s The Sausage Concept franchise 
 
Americans have adamantly proclaimed their affection for the hot dog. At the Mandler’s The Sausage Concept franchise we have taken this phenomenon one step further by upgrading it and embellishing with the result being a high quality European-style sausage alternative as a full meal at a reasonable cost.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 See more franchises&gt;&gt; 
 
 Sector Sub Sector (optional) Category (optional) All Sectors (493) Food (155) Restaurants (63) Misc. Restaurants (23) 

 All Countries (5820) USA (1673) All Regions Mid West (104) All States Illinois (23) All Cities 
Filter your search

Age of Listing

 Anytime (23) Last 3 Days (3) Last 14 Days (3) Last Month (5) Last 3 Months (11) 

Type of Business

 Real Property (6) Lease (4) Relocatable (0) Work From Home (0) Accommodation Included (1) Franchise (0) Price Reduced (1) Mid Market (0) In Receivership (0) Owner Financed (3) Unique (0) 
 
Asking Price ($)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
Cash Flow ($)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
Sales Revenue ($)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
 
Start a new search
 
 
 
 
Buy a Restaurant in Illinois, IL or find a Business Broker at BusinessesForSale.com. If you own a Restaurant and are considering selling, visit our Sell a Restaurant section.
 
 Franchise Opportunities Acheter une Franchise Business Opportunities Blog Find a Business Opportunity Starting a Business 
 
 © 1997 - 2012 Dynamis Ltd 

 
 
BusinessesForSale website uses cookies. To understand more about cookies and their benefits please see our Cookie Policy . By continuing to use this site you consent to our use of cookies on this device in accordance with our cookie policy.
	</body>
</document>
