<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007878" url="http://tdn.com/news/local/article_2ad048e0-c9f8-11e0-b8e2-001cc4c03286.html" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="2" score="0.0025510496190905025" bingtitle="Several new businesses slated for former Hilander Bowl site" webtitle="Several new businesses slated for former Hilander Bowl site">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>A Jack-in-the-Box fast food restaurant and possibly a motel and a ... RV&apos;s, Boats. Motorcycles, ETC; Place An Ad; MPG Ratings ... at 1509 Allen St., just off Interstate 5 at Exit 39.</description>
	<body>
		× 
Subscribe Now!

Welcome!

Welcome Back!
 
Thank you for reading and relying on tdn.com for your news and information. You have now viewed your 30-day allowance of FREE pages. Want to read more?
 
Thanks for being a frequent visitor to tdn.com . You have now viewed of your FREE premium pages this 30-day period. After you have viewed FREE pages, we will ask you to purchase a subscription.
 Starting at $7.95 
Digital only

If you are not a current newspaper subscriber, please purchase a subscription for $7.95/month for an online-only subscription. As a online-only subscriber, you will have unlimited access, including our premium content such as breaking news, local, state and regional news, sports, weather, obituaries and more.

We hope you continue to enjoy the quality journalism produced by The Daily News Online.
 Purchase Starting at $2.95 
Print discount

As a newspaper subscriber, please subscribe for unlimited access to all of our online content for as little as $2.95/month. As an online subscriber, you will have unlimited access to poststar.com, including our premium content such as breaking news, local, state and regional news, sports, weather, obituaries and more.

We hope you continue to enjoy the quality journalism produced by The Daily News Online.
 Purchase 
 [x] No Thanks 

Already subscribed? Click here to login. 
 
 Please Wait…
 
Need Help? Call: 360-577-2571 

 [x] Cancel 
 
 Mobile e-Edition Subscriber Services Advertise with Us Contact Us 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 Contribute 
 Article Event Photo Video 
 My Account 
 Edit Profile Subscriptions Logout 
 
 70° Clear 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 75° 51° Saturday 82° 54° Sunday 67° 51° Monday 74° 52° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 Area News This Day Business State World Politics Health Weird 
 
Latest National News
 
 Thousands fall victim to utility payment scam 

As much as President Barack Obama wants your vote, he&apos;s not actually offering to pay your monthly bills.
 
 Ga. woman gets 3 years for buttocks injections 

A Georgia woman with no license to practice medicine has been sentenced for injecting customers&apos; buttocks with commercial silicone in hotel rooms and using glue and cotton balls to prevent the substance from leaking out.
 
Recent National News

 More abortion restrictions anticipated in Miss. 2 sophisticated border drug tunnels discovered Expert: Fla. teen attacker ill, not responsible New recordings show Zimmerman&apos;s many police calls Questions ready for Fort Hood suspect&apos;s jury pool Obama: I need to do a better job of inspiring Father charged in 3 daughters&apos; deaths in Wisconsin Congressman&apos;s &apos;mood disorder&apos; raising questions 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 Prep College Basketball Football Baseball Youth Sports 
 
Latest
 
 Paterno&apos;s legacy may now be damaged beyond repair 

For decades Penn State was considered special, immune from the corruption of college athletics by virtue of Joe Paterno&apos;s high ideals, long li…
 
 APNewsBreak: Allmendinger bringing experts to test 

People familiar with AJ Allmendinger&apos;s suspension say the NASCAR driver has elected to bring his own experts to witness the testing of his &quot;B&quot;…
 
Recent

 Reggie Jackson says he made mistake naming players Hewitt advances to Hall of Fame semifinals Top-seeded Fernando Verdasco advances in Umag Molinari rips up Scottish Open with 1st-round 62 First Chinese-born driver tests in Formula 1 Mickelson cuts short holiday to find some form Kite has record-breaking 28 in 9 at US Senior Open Nike taking Paterno&apos;s name off child care center 
 
 Opinion 
 
Topics

 Editorials Reader Commentary Letters to the Editor Staff Columnists Editorial Cartoons 
 
Latest
 
 Editorial Cartoons 

Check out our gallery of recent cartoons from Nick Anderson, Clay Bennett, Lisa Benson and Signe Wilkinson.
 
 Cepeda: Time to stop overgeneralizing about immigrants 

CHICAGO -- When people get passionate, they get sloppy.
 
Recent

 Letters: Differing views New kayaking trips welcome addition to Mount St. Helens experience Gerson: Obama in denial Letters: Congrats to Castle Rock No More Mandatory Life Sentences for Juveniles Milbank: Rep. Walsh’s ‘Ashleigh’ moments Letters: A major tax cut Dionne: An economics of national pride 
 
 Entertainment 
 
Topics

 Movie Times TV Listings Restaurants Books Events Calendar Photos Lottery Horoscopes Columbia Views Lower Columbia Living 
 
Latest
 
 2 accused of extorting Wonder ordered to trial 

A judge has ordered two people accused of extorting Stevie Wonder to stand trial.
 
 Steven Tyler exiting as &apos;American Idol&apos; judge 

Steven Tyler says he&apos;s exiting &quot;American Idol&quot; to put rock `n&apos; roll first.
 
Recent

 Rolling Stones celebrate 50 years on stage Comic-Con begins with action-packed preview night Adam Sandler looks to rise again in &apos;Transylvania&apos; Beanie Sigel gets 2 years for Philly tax charges `Twilight&apos; fans treated to 7-minutes of final film Fox&apos;s Ed Henry goes with squares to add flair Girl crusaders get cold shoulder from Teen Vogue Rodin Museum in Philly reopens with look from 1929 
 
 Neighbors 
 This Day Calendar Restaurants Births Obituaries Legals Recipes Volunteer Opportunities Charitable Opportunities 
 Get It! 
 
Topics

 Classified Ads Get It Garage Sale Map Place An Ad Print Ads Purchase Reprints Coupons 
 
 Latest Local Offers 
 
 Coldwell Banker Bain 

Coldwell Banker Bain is very proud of its newest real estate o…
 
 About Face MD 


 
 All Out Sewer 


 
 Sessions Plumbing and Heating 

Four generation family owned since 1967. We specialize in heat…
 
 Homes 
 Homes For Sale For Rent Homeseller Magazine 
 Jobs 
 Local Jobs Top Jobs Work For TDN 
 Cars 
 Cars/Trucks RV&apos;s,Boats,Motorcycles,Etc Place An Ad MPG Ratings 
 
 
 Hot Topics Facebook Contest Cardboard Boat Regatta Timber Carnival Coal Trains Counterfeit Bills Concealed Weapons 
 
 Home / News 
 
Several new businesses slated for former Hilander Bowl site
 Print Email 2011-08-18T20:15:00Z 2011-08-21T10:29:46Z Several new businesses slated for former Hilander Bowl site By Amy M.E. Fischer / The Daily News The Daily News Online August 18, 2011 8:15 pm  •  By Amy M.E. Fischer / The Daily News (0) Comments 
A Jack-in-the-Box fast food restaurant and possibly a motel and
a Starbucks will be built on the former site of the Hilander Bowl
in Kelso.

According to Kelso City Manager Denny Richards, developers have
turned in site plans for the vacant lot at 1509 Allen St., just off
Interstate 5 at Exit 39. As soon as the plans are revised and
approved, construction may begin.

The Jack-in-the-Box is definitely coming, Richards said. The
site plan lists a 52-room motel, but Richards doesn&apos;t think the
developers have confirmed a deal yet. However, a Starbucks is &quot;a
strong possibility,&quot; he said Thursday.

Last December marked the demolition of the 50-year-old Hilander
Bowl, which had stood vacant since 2004. A group of Central
Washington investors formed the Kelso-Highlander Group LLC
specifically to develop the property, which they bought from Twin
City Bank for $1.15 million. The bank paid $1.77 million for it at
foreclosure in June 2008.

&quot;I was excited when they tore the ugly building down, and now
I&apos;m really excited we&apos;re going to have some new businesses there,&quot;
Richards said. &quot;I think that&apos;s going to be really good for
Kelso.&quot;
 View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
More News stories
 
 
 Windy Ridge thoroughfare set to open Friday 
 
 Coal facilities would tie up NW railroads, study says 
 
 Longview School District to sell off surplus office equipment 
 
 Man charged in old Lewis County murders appears in Alaska court 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 The Daily News Online. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
Most Popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 
 Ryderwood man drowns in Cowlitz Police Blotter: July 6 Police Blotter: July 7 Police Blotter: July 10 Metered model for local content coming to tdn.com County aims to put 2 away for life on &apos;3 strikes&apos; law Police blotter: July 8 Police Blotter: July 9 
 
 Rise in concealed weapons permits showing no signs of slowing (51) Karen L. Fittro (9) Herrera Beutler delays decision whether to support Mount St. Helens national park study (8) Gerson: Obama in denial (6) County aims to put 2 away for life on &apos;3 strikes&apos; law (6) Guest Column: State&apos;s rail plans don&apos;t include coal (6) Women accused of spending spree on dead man&apos;s debit card (7) Gerson: The crime of circumcision (4) 
 
Poll

 It&apos;s been 50 years since the first James Bond film premiered. What&apos;s your favorite 007 movie? 
 Loading… 
 &quot;Goldfinger&quot; &quot;From Russia With Love&quot; &quot;Dr. No&quot; &quot;Casino Royale&quot; Other Not my cup of tea 
 View Results 
 Don&apos;t miss out! Sign up to receive email alerts!
 Email Address: [close] 
Hi my name is . My zipcode is . Please send me email alerts about the following:
 Daily Deal
 Information on Special Deals and Promotions
 Details on upcoming contests
 Morning Headlines (Sent directly to your email at 7am every day)
 TDN Prep Updates (Get game day coverage along with Friday night Football scores) Featured Businesses Find: 
 Home contractors, pizza, beauty salons 
 Near: 
 City&amp;State, or Zip Code 
 Browse the full business directory 
 About Face MD 
 
 Acupuncture Northwest 
 
Contests and Deals
 
 Auto Racing Challenge 



Pick the 10 drivers you think will finish 1st through 10th for each race. Your top 15 races count as your overall score. Compete for great nat…
 
 Today&apos;s Deal 



Great deals from local businesses. Sign up now to receive
exclusive offers and email updates when new deals become
available.
 
Latest Local Offers
 
 Finance a Classic Car with Cowlitz Credit Union 

Finance a Classic Car with Cowlitz Credit Union and we will d…
 
 WE CAN LICENSE YOUR BOAT! 

Do you have a boat or recreational vehicle? Come to C&amp;L…
 
 Cowlitz Credit Union: small in size, not service. Meet our great staff at 821 Washington Way today! 


 
 All Out Sewer - Awesome Summer Savings! 

10% off plumbing and septic services through July 30th! Call u…
 
Participate
 
 Team Sports Recognition of Excellence 
 


 Submit your team photo to the Dick Hannah Recognition of Excellence. Your photo could appear in the sports section of the Friday edition of the printed paper and will appear in the online photo gallery! 
 
 Youth Sports Photos 
 


 Submit your youth sports photo to the McCord Brothers youth photo page. Your photo could appear in the sports section of the Sunday edition of the printed paper and will appear in the online photo gallery! 
   
Marketplace

 Jobs Garage Sales Homes 
 
Video
 
 Sections 
 Homepage News Sports Opinion Entertainment Obituaries Classifieds Jobs Cars Homes 
 Services 
 Find Longview Jobs Contact Us Place a Classified Ad Subscriber Services Events Calendar RSS 
 Other Websites 
 E-edition MyTDN.com NIE 
 
 ©Copyright 2012, The Daily News Online , 770 11th Ave Longview, WA | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Longview Apartments Longview Attorneys Longview Auto Dealers Longview Auto Parts Longview Auto Repair Longview Beauty Salons Longview Car Rental Longview Dentists Longview Doctors Longview Flowers Longview Hotels Longview Insurance Longview Loans Longview Mortgages Longview Movers Longview Pizza Longview Realtors Longview Restaurants Longview Storage Longview Tax Preparation Longview Travel More Longview… Kelso Apartments Kelso Attorneys Kelso Auto Dealers Kelso Auto Parts Kelso Auto Repair Kelso Beauty Salons Kelso Car Rental Kelso Dentists Kelso Doctors Kelso Flowers Kelso Hotels Kelso Insurance Kelso Loans Kelso Mortgages Kelso Movers Kelso Pizza Kelso Realtors Kelso Restaurants Kelso Storage Kelso Tax Preparation Kelso Travel More Kelso… Kalama Apartments Kalama Attorneys Kalama Auto Dealers Kalama Auto Parts Kalama Auto Repair Kalama Beauty Salons Kalama Car Rental Kalama Dentists Kalama Doctors Kalama Flowers Kalama Hotels Kalama Insurance Kalama Loans Kalama Mortgages Kalama Movers Kalama Pizza Kalama Realtors Kalama Restaurants Kalama Storage Kalama Tax Preparation Kalama Travel More Kalama… Woodland Apartments Woodland Attorneys Woodland Auto Dealers Woodland Auto Parts Woodland Auto Repair Woodland Beauty Salons Woodland Car Rental Woodland Dentists Woodland Doctors Woodland Flowers Woodland Hotels Woodland Insurance Woodland Loans Woodland Mortgages Woodland Movers Woodland Pizza Woodland Realtors Woodland Restaurants Woodland Storage Woodland Tax Preparation Woodland Travel More Woodland… Castle Rock Apartments Castle Rock Attorneys Castle Rock Auto Dealers Castle Rock Auto Parts Castle Rock Auto Repair Castle Rock Beauty Salons Castle Rock Car Rental Castle Rock Dentists Castle Rock Doctors Castle Rock Flowers Castle Rock Hotels Castle Rock Insurance Castle Rock Loans Castle Rock Mortgages Castle Rock Movers Castle Rock Pizza Castle Rock Realtors Castle Rock Restaurants Castle Rock Storage Castle Rock Tax Preparation Castle Rock Travel More Castle Rock… Rainier Apartments Rainier Attorneys Rainier Auto Dealers Rainier Auto Parts Rainier Auto Repair Rainier Beauty Salons Rainier Car Rental Rainier Dentists Rainier Doctors Rainier Flowers Rainier Hotels Rainier Insurance Rainier Loans Rainier Mortgages Rainier Movers Rainier Pizza Rainier Realtors Rainier Restaurants Rainier Storage Rainier Tax Preparation Rainier Travel More Rainier… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing tdn.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with tdn.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
