<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007832" url="http://www.grit.com/food/recipes/recipe-for-chowchow.aspx" time="2012-07-13-00:47" support="2" score="0.003926610028609569" bingtitle="Recipe for Chowchow - GRIT Magazine -- Rural America, Vegetable ..." webtitle="Recipe for Chowchow">
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... crock or buy a 5-gallon food-grade plastic bucket with a tight-fitting lid from a fast-food restaurant ... information below to receive 1 ... By paying now with a credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Edit Your Connections / Sign In Sign Out or Join! Welcome! Close Sign in with your Grit account Email Address: * Password: * Forgot Your Password? Customer Number: * ZIP/Postal Code: * Enlarge 
 
 Country: Select Country AFGHANISTAN ALBANIA ALGERIA ANDORRA ANGOLA ANGUILLA ANTIGUA AND BARBUDA ANTIGUA/BARBUDA ARGENTINA ARMENIA ARUBA ASCENSION ISLAND AUSTRALIA AUSTRIA AZERBAIDJAN AZORES ISLANDS BAHAMAS BAHRAIN BANGLADESH BARBADOS BELARUS BELGIUM BELIZE BENIN BERMUDA BHUTAN BHUTAN BOLIVIA BOPHUTHATSWANA BOSNIA-HERZEGOVINA BOTSWANA BR VIRGIN ISL BRAZIL BRUNEI DARUSSALAM BULGARIA BURKINA FASO BURMA BURUNDI CAMBODIA CAMEROON CANADA CAPE VERDE CAPE VERDE CAYMAN ISLANDS CENTRAL AFRICAN REPU CHAD CHANNEL ISLANDS CHILE CHINA COLOMBIA COMOROS COMW INDEP STES CONGO COOK ISLANDS COOK ISLANDS CORSICA COSTA RICA CROATIA CUBA CYPRUS CZECH REPUBLIC DENMARK DJIBOUTI DOMINICA DOMINICA DOMINICAN REPUBLIC EAST ASIA* EAST TIMOR ECUADOR EGYPT EL SALVADOR ENGLAND EQUATORIAL GUINEA ESTONIA ETHIOPIA FALKLAND ISLANDS FAROE ISLANDS FED REP GERMANY FIJI FINLAND FORMER CZECHOSLAVAKI FR WEST INDIES FRANCE FRENCH GUYANA FRENCH POLYNESIA GABON GAMBIA GAZA GEORGIA GERMANY GERMANY-WEST GIBRALTAR GREAT BRITAIN GREECE GREENLAND GRENADA GUADELOUPE GUATEMALA GUINEA GUINEA BISSAU GUINEA-BISSAU GUYANA HAITI HONDURAS HONG KONG HONG KONG HUNGARY ICELAND INDIA INDIAN OCEAN ISL INDONESIA INDONESIA IRAN IRAN IRAQ IRAQ IRELAND ISLE OF MAN ISRAEL ITALY IVORY COAST (COTE D&apos; JAMAICA JAPAN JORDAN KAMPUCHEA KAZAKHSTAN KENYA KIRIBATI KOREA KUWAIT KYRGYZSTAN LAO LAOS LATVIA LEBANON LEEWARD ISL LEM LESOTHO LIBERIA LIBYA(N ARAB JAMAHI) LIECHTENSTEIN LITHUANIA LUXEMBOURG MACAO MACEDONIA (FORMER) MADAGASCAR MALAWI MALAWI MALAYSIA MALAYSIA MALDIVES MALI MALTA MARSHALL ISLANDS MARTINIQUE MAURITANIA MAURITIUS MAURITIUS MAYOTTE MEXICO MOLDAVIA MONACO MONGOLIA MONGOLIA MONTSERRAT MOROCCO MOZAMBIQUE MYANMAR (BURMA) NAMIBIA NAURU NEPAL NETHER ANTILLES NETHERLAND ANTILLIES NETHERLANDS NEW CALEDONIA NEW HERBRIDES NEW ZEALAND NICARAGUA NIGER NIUE NORTH KOREA NORTHERN IRELAND NORWAY OKINAWA OMAN PAKISTAN PALAU PANAMA PAPUA N GUINEA PAPUA NEW GUINEA PARAGUAY PERU PHILLIPPINES PITCAIRN ISLAND POLAND PORTUGAL QATAR QATAR REUNION ROMANIA RUSSIAN FEDERATION RWANDA SAINT KITTS AND NEVI SAINT LUCIA SAINT TOME AND PRINC SAINT VINCENT AND GR SAMOA SAMOA SAN MARINO SAN MARINO SAO TOME/PRINCI SAUDI ARABIA SCOTLAND SCOTLAND SENEGAL SERBIA SEYCHELLES SIERRA LEONE SINGAPORE SLOVAK REPUBLIC SLOVENIA SOLOMON ISLANDS SOLOMON ISLANDS SOMALIA SOUTH AFRICA SOUTH KOREA SOUTH KOREA SOUTH KOREA SOUTH PACIFIC IS SOUTH WEST AFRICA SPAIN SRI LANKA ST CHRISTPHR/NV ST LUCIA ST VINCENT/GREN SUDAN SURINAME SWAZILAND SWEDEN SWITZERLAND SYRIA TAIWAN TAJIKISTAN TANZANIA THAILAND TOGO TOKELAU IS TONGA TONGA TRANSKEI TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO TUNISIA TURKEY TURKMENISTAN TURKS CAICOS TUVALU UGANDA UGANDA UKRAINE UNITED ARAB EMIRATES URUGUAY UNITED STATES OF AMERICA UZBEKISTAN VANUATU VATICAN CITY STATE VENEZUELA VIETNAM VIRGIN IS, BRIT WALES WALLIS/FUTUNA I WEST AFRICA WEST INDIES WESTERN SAHARA WINDWARD ISL YEMEN (ADEN) YEMEN (SANAA) YUGOSLAVIA ZAIRE ZAMBIA ZIMBABWE Use your social network account 
Save time by using your existing account to sign in to Grit and Cappers.
 

 
We’ll never share your online information or post anything to your account without your permission.
 * Denotes Required Fields Don&apos;t Have an account? 

 
 
 About Us   Shopping   Contact Us   Newsletter HOME BLOGS COMMUNITY GARDEN ANIMALS TOOLS FOOD PROPERTY LAND FOR SALE 
Recipe for Chowchow

 Try this recipe for Chowchow when you want a delicious, vegetable-packed treat. 
 Shirley Splittstoesser
September/October 2010 
 Enlarge Image Image Gallery Chowchow is an excellent recipe for getting rid of that excess garden bounty. Lori Dunn 
 Article Tools Image Gallery Print E-mail Comments RSS 
 Main Story:
 Sell Homemade Jams and Jellies at Your Local Market 
 
RELATED CONTENT
 

 
 Cooking With Eggs: Recipes for Every Meal 

Branch out from mundane breakfast choices with a delicious Ham and Egg Casserole Recipe, or take yo...
 
 Growing Organic Goes Global 

More food outlets are selecting organic produce, and that means a greater market for producers....
 
 Know Your Farmer, Know Your Food Program Promotes Local Food 

See a map of USDA-supported local food projects in the U.S. at KYF Compass’ website....
 
 The Food Project Connects Communities to Fresh Food 

Program puts next generation of farmers to work in Boston region....
 
 Homemade Bagel Recipes and Other Boiled Bread Recipes 

Boiled breads, like bagels, pretzels and dumplings, turn out soft and chewy. Enjoy a few homemade b...
 
When the first frost threatens to wipe out your garden or when you decide to plow under the garden, it’s time to make Chowchow. The best time to make Chowchow, however, is when you want more of this mouthwatering treat. Take out your grandmother’s 5-gallon crock or buy a 5-gallon food-grade plastic bucket with a tight-fitting lid from a fast-food restaurant, because this Chowchow recipe is worth trying.

8 to 12 medium heads green cabbage, shredded
2 cups canning salt
1⁄4 cup coarse ground black pepper
2 gallons Heinz white vinegar
8 pounds onion, shredded
6 pounds cucumbers, unpeeled, diced into 1⁄8-inch cubes
1 gallon dill pickles (Vlasic Kosher), reserve and store juice in refrigerator, dice pickles into 1⁄8-inch cubes
3 pounds garlic, chopped
20 to 30 fresh jalapeño peppers, diced (optional to include seeds, which will increase hotness)
40 to 60 plump, fresh serrano peppers, sliced thin
6 ounces dried pequin chiles, half ground and half left whole
6 ounces dried arbol chiles, ground

Place cabbage into 5-gallon crock or 5-gallon food-grade bucket. Pour salt and black pepper evenly on top. Cover with tight-fitting lid. Let sit at room temperature 24 hours. The cabbage will have wilted to 1⁄4 volume.

Boil vinegar and add to cabbage. Stir well. Add onion, cucumbers, dill pickles, garlic, jalapeños, serranos, pequins and arbol chiles. Stir well. Cover with tight lid and let sit at room temperature for 1 to 2 weeks. (Optional: Stir occasionally.) Taste to determine if you need to add some of the stored dill pickle juice to the chowchow.

Pack into clean quart jars. Wipe rims of jars with clean, wet cloth. Seal. Process in hot water bath or pressure cooker according to manufacturer’s directions. Yields 15 to 18 quarts.
 RSS | Comments | E-mail | Print 
 
 
Archived Comments
 

 4294971532 MY COMMUNITY 
 MOST POPULAR 
 READ E-MAILED 
 
 How to Grow Asparagus Build Your Own Natural Swimming Hole Breaded and Fried Zucchini Recipe Coop Training New Flock Members- Coming Home to Roost Easy Zucchini Recipes to Use Up That Surplus 
 
 Build Your Own Natural Swimming Hole Coop Training New Flock Members- Coming Home to Roost Backing a Trailer Simplified Bench Plans: Easy Woodworking Project Pig Breed Guide 
 

 
 
 
 
 
Pay Now&amp;Save 50% Off the Cover Price
 
 First Name: * 
 Last Name:  * 
 Address: * 
 City: * 
 State/Province: * 
 Zip/Postal Code: * 
 Country:
 USA Email: * 
 
 
 DIGITAL ONLY PRINT WITH FREE DIGITAL PRINT ONLY 
 
 (* indicates a required item) 
Canadian subs: 1 year, (includes postage&amp;GST). Foreign subs: 1 year, . U.S. funds.
 Canadian Subscribers - Click Here 
 Non US and Canadian Subscribers - Click Here 
 
 
 
Live The Good Life with G rit ! 

For more than 125 years, G rit has helped its readers live more prosperously and happily while emphasizing the importance of community and a rural lifestyle tradition. In each bimonthly issue, G rit includes helpful articles, humorous and inspiring articles, captivating photos, gardening and cooking advice, do-it-yourself projects and the practical reader advice you would expect to find in America’s premier rural lifestyle magazine.

Get your guide to living outside the city limits delivered straight to your mailbox. Subscribe to G rit today! Simply fill in your information below to receive 1 year (6 issues) of G rit for only $19.95!

 SPECIAL BONUS OFFER! 

At G rit , we have a tradition of respecting the land that sustains rural America. That’s why we want you to save money and trees by subscribing to G rit through our automatic renewal savings plan. By paying now with a credit card, you save an additional $5 and get 6 issues of G rit for only $14.95 (USA only).

Or, Bill Me Later and send me one year of G rit for just $19.95!

 
 
 
 Home | E-Newsletter | Products | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | About Us | Contact Us | Subscribe | Customer Service | Site Map | RSS | Press Room | Advertising | Media Kit | Career Opportunities 
Copyright 2012, All Rights Reserved | Ogden Publications, Inc., 1503 SW 42nd St., Topeka, Kansas 66609-1265
 Mother Earth News • Utne Reader • Natural Home • The Herb Companion • Grit • Capper&apos;s • Motorcycle Classics 
 Farm Collector • Gas Engine Magazine • Good Things to Eat • Ogden Publications 
Special Interest Websites : Great Green Careers • Herbs for Health • Steam Traction
	</body>
</document>
