<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007502" url="http://www.familycircle.com/health/weight-loss/diet-tips/10-fat-fighting-secrets/" time="2012-07-13-00:28" support="1" score="0.0008619022199765888" bingtitle="10 Fat Fighting Secrets - Family Circle - Teens, Family, Food ..." webtitle="10 Fat Fighting Secrets">
			<query id="001232" bing-rank="118"/>
	<description>... the number of restaurants, the percentage of meals eaten out and the amount of money spent on food away from home. Eating at a fast-food restaurant ... its container ... throw ...</description>
	<body>
		You Need To Have Javascript and Flash To Make This Site Work Well. 
 { Healthy Family Challenge 2012 Slow Cooking Win $250! } 
 
 
 Subscribe | Newsletter | Customer Service | Free Stuff LOG IN |  JOIN NOW 
 Food 
 Healthy Eating 
 Family Dinners Tips Breakfast Lunch Snacks Heart Healthy Low Calorie 
 Desserts 
 chocolate Cookies Cakes Fruits Frozen Ideas Pies 
 30-Minute Dinners Slow Cooker Comfort Food Main Ingredient 
 Chicken Beef Pork Pasta Fish Vegetarian Turkey 
 Breakfast Recipes Kitchen Tips Grilling Holiday 
 Valentine&apos;s Day Easter Halloween Thanksgiving Christmas Mother&apos;s Day July 4th Fathers Day 
 Drinks&amp;Cocktails Seasonal Recipes 
 Holidays 
 Christmas 
 Recipes Cookies Decorations Gifts Planning 
 Valentine&apos;s Day 
 Recipes Gifts 
 Easter 
 Recipes Decorations 
 Mother&apos;s Day 
 Gifts Recipes 
 Father&apos;s Day July 4th Halloween 
 Recipes Decorations 
 Thanksgiving 
 Recipes Decorations Tips 
 
 Home 
 Crafts 
 Projects Holiday 
 Decorating 
 House Tours Projects Ideas color Outdoor Flowers 
 Organization 
 Rooms Tips 
 Green Living Cleaning Circle of Excellence 
 Teens 
 Parenting 
 Communication&amp;Bonding Discipline Self Esteem Sex Talk Celebrity Parents Stepparenting Grandparenting 
 Jobs Dating&amp;Sex Drugs College Prep School 
 Homework Fashion, Gear&amp;Supplies Back to School Teachers&amp;Coaches Issues 
 Activities Ask Rosalind 
 Rosalind 
 
 Health 
 Weight Loss 
 Diet Plans Diet Tips 
 Walking 
 Walking Playlists Walking Tips Walking Workouts 
 Fitness 
 Exercise Tips Playlists Workout Routines 
 Health Concerns 
 Aches&amp;Pains Allergies&amp;Asthma Bone Health Cancer Cold&amp;Flu Diabetes Heart Skin 
 Emotional Health 
 Depression Stress Wellness Self Improvement 
 Tools Family Health 

 Healthy Family 2012 
 Family 
 Money Travel Technology Fiction Books Pets Volunteering&amp;Charity Video Games Photo Galleries Relationships 
 Style 
 Beauty 
 Bargain Beauty Beauty Tips Hair 
 Fashion Prom 
 Prom Hairstyles Prom Dresses 
 Videos 
 Momster Blog In the Magazine 
 
 
 Subscribe Give a Gift Newsletter 

 
 Home   &gt;   Health   &gt;  Weight Loss   &gt;  Diet Tips 
10 Fat Fighting Secrets

By Dayna Winter, R.D.
 
 Share Print 
 Prev   1 2 (of 2)   Next A Few Simple Changes 
Shedding excess pounds is a cinch when you know the right weight-loss tips. A few simple changes are all that are required to fat-proof your body without dieting. Here you’ll find the know-how you need to get into those slim-fitting jeans fast! Bonus: These stay-thin eating strategies will keep you healthy over the long term.
 1. Eat more lean protein. 
The debate over how much protein is ideal continues. One thing that’s becoming clearer is that eating a little more protein and a little less carbohydrate can help you maintain lean body mass and adhere to your dietary regimen. Why? Higher protein diets may make you feel fuller on less food. Your body also works harder to digest protein than fat or carbs, which means more calories burned. This is not a license to eat bacon-cheeseburgers, according to Cathy Nonas, R.D., principal investigator for the Centers for Obesity Research and Education and author of Outwit Your Weight (Rodale). Get your protein from healthier choices such as fish, nonfat dairy and soy products. The National Academy of Sciences (NAS) recommends getting 10 to 35 percent of daily calories from protein.
 2. Dine in more often. 
The rise in obesity parallels a rise in the number of restaurants, the percentage of meals eaten out and the amount of money spent on food away from home. Eating at a fast-food restaurant may be easy to do, but ultimately it’s hard on your body. If you’re eating out every day of the week, try cutting back. When you do eat out, choose grilled food. Skip the high-fat, high-cal fixings such as cheese and sour cream and opt for soup or salad instead of French fries. When you can, eat at home, where you have more control over what’s on your plate.
 3. Indulge your cravings. 
If you resist sour-cream-and-onion potato chips only to eat an entire bag of rice cakes, you haven’t done yourself any favors. Denying a craving can lead you to eat everything but the kitchen sink in an effort to avoid eating what you think you shouldn’t have. Instead, indulge in a reasonable portion of the food you crave. Take a small serving of the food out of its container, then put the rest away. Sit down and savor the extravagance. Then go do something else—away from food.
 4. Load up on the good stuff. 
Most of us are not eating enough fruits, vegetables and whole grains. A diet devoid of these foods is one of the reasons for the rise in obesity, according to Paula Quaromoni, D.Sc., R.D., assistant professor in the departments of epidemiology and social and behavioral sciences at Boston University’s School of Public Health. In a recent study, she compared women with different eating styles to see if it had an effect on their weight. Turns out those who ate a diet rich in fruits, vegetables and whole grains were less likely to gain weight over the years. Those who consumed too many unhealthy snacks, fatty foods and sweetened drinks were more likely to gain.
 5. Always read labels. 
Don’t throw food in the shopping cart without reading the label. Look at how many calories are in a serving and what a serving size is. Check the saturated fat content and other ingredients like sugar. Ingredients are listed by the amount the product contains, with the most at the top of the list. If sugar tops the list, pick something else: Added sugars do nothing for your figure but make it fuller.
 Next Page &gt;&gt; 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Related Topics in Weight Loss 
 Diet Plans 
 
Please confirm your comment by answering the question below and clicking &quot;Submit Comment.&quot;
 Pinterest Facebook Twitter Newsletter 
 Viewed E-Mailed 
 Most Popular 
 Slow-Cooker Chicken Recipes Easy Slow-Cooker Meals Sweet Charity: Winning Bake Sale Treats 18 Things You Can Get Rid of Today Tasty Cupcake Recipes 
 Most E-mailed 
 Homemade for the Holidays: Easy Felt Crafts Money Lessons from Real Families 15 Grilled Vegetable Recipes Smart Swaps: Healthy Fast-Food Choices 10 Fun Ways to Decorate with Color Back-to-School Rx: Solutions to Your Problems 
 Your Account 
 Help Resources Customer
 Service Member
 Benefits Update
 Your Account Terms of Service Privacy Policy Free Newsletter AdChoices Register Log In 
 FamilyCircle.com 
 Momster Photo Galleries Newsletters Facebook Twitter Advertise on
 FamilyCircle.com 
 Family Circle Magazine 
 Subscribe Renew Give a Gift Media Kit Contact Us 
 Parents Network 
 Parents 

 Family Circle Top Baby Names Ser Padres 

 ©Copyright
 
 , Meredith Corporation . All Rights Reserved|By using this site, you agree to our Terms of
 Service.
	</body>
</document>
