<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007087" url="http://www.resturantmealathome.com/tag/menus/" time="2012-07-13-00:04" support="6" score="0.008942432470359562" bingtitle="Menus - Make Great Restaurant Meals" webtitle="Menus - Make Great Restaurant Meals">
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="84"/>
	<description>... the cost of a ‘value meal’ at a fast food restaurant ... start at the home page and can enter a ... catering restaurants or look for restaurants that accept credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Make Great Restaurant Meals 

You Are A World Class Chef!
 
 Home Blog 
 
 Restaurant Food Restaurant Meals Restaurant Menu Restaurant Recipes 
 You are here: Home / Archives for Menus 
 Interactive Online Menus Help Restaurants Attract More Customers 
 April 10, 2012 By gorestur Leave a Comment 
 
Fayston, VT (PRWEB) February 29, 2012

George Soules Photography today announces a new service to create online interactive menus for restaurants. To stay ahead of the competition, restaurant owners need a variety of strategies to convince diners to choose their establishment over the one next door. One of the newest and most effective ways to attract new customers and remind regulars why they should come back again is to use interactive menus on restaurant web sites.



Interactive restaurant menus let people move their mouse over entr
 Filed Under: Restaurant Food Tagged With: Attract , Customers , Help , Interactive , Menus , More , Online , Restaurants 
 Chef Don Eliminates the ?What is for Dinner Dilemma? with Chef-tested Menus, Recipes, Meal Planning and Categorized Shopping Lists 
 March 23, 2012 By gorestur Leave a Comment 
 
Palm Bay, FL (PRWEB) March 9, 2011

Menus-n-More.com eliminates the ?What is for dinner? dilemma that families face every day. The new website saves time, saves money and reduces impulse buying at the grocery store. With its chef-created menus, chef-tested recipes, and categorized shopping lists, Chef Don makes food shopping, menu planning and cooking at home easier than ever before. Chef Don explains his reason for creating the web site, ?There are other sites available that allow people to create menus. But at my site, I do the work so my subscribers don?t have to.



The recipes at Menus-n-More.com are all easy to prepare and most will be on the table in one hour. Each recipe has a photo of the finished product. Any recipes that need explaining have photos showing how-to preparation steps.? Chef Don also provides his personal e-mail so subscribers can ask questions and receive answers about cooking and food preparation.



When asked if the recipes are gourmet, Chef Don replied, ?The meals on the menus are not fancy, but they are delicious. The recipes are simple to follow. A subscriber can print them out or view them on their phone when they are at the grocery store. For less than the cost of a‘value meal’at a fast food restaurant, subscribers get chef-planned meals and recipes. Menus-N-More.com makes it convenient and easy to cook at home.?



Chef Don is a trained chef located in Palm Bay, Florida. He has over 20 years experience in the food service industry. He has worked at hotels and upscale restaurants throughout his career. For more information about Chef Don or his subscription service, go to http://www.menus-n-more.com.



Contact:

Chef Don

http://www.menus-n-more.com

e-mail: chef(at)menus-n-more(dot)com



# # #







Related Restaurant Recipes Press Releases 
 Filed Under: Restaurant Recipes Tagged With: Categorized , Chef , Cheftested , Dilemma , DINNER , Eliminates , Lists , Meal , Menus , Planning , Recipes , Shopping 
 Introducing MenuElephant.com, a New Website that Offers Restaurants Free Advertising by Posting Menus for Free 
 October 25, 2011 By gorestur 463 Comments 
Scottsdale, AZ (PRWEB) September 6, 2007

MenuElephant.com is a new nationwide website that will let any restaurant, bar, coffee-shop or any other type of eating or drinking establishment place their menus for free. Then, anyone can access the site for free without signing up for membership or having to login. The process for the restaurant involves filling out a simple, one page form. Then they just scan their menu as JPG file and send it to the site for posting. They may also purchase a low-cost banner ad that appears near the top of the search results page.



The website visitors start at the home page and can enter a location, such as city, state or zip code, then a restaurant name or type, such as Mexican or Italian. They can also choose any keyword such as vegetarian, burgers, or delivery. They next view a list of the available restaurants meeting the criteria along with a Google map and the restaurants locations. They click on a listing to go to the next page. There they will see the restaurant name, details, and information regarding payment, services and a close-up Google map to guide them to the restaurant location.



Finally, the remainder of the page is the actual restaurant menu. If there are multiple pages, the user clicks on the bottom tab to go to the other pages. There is no membership fee or sign-up of any kind for the user or the restaurant, and the business owner can update their information in a few minutes. The site is paid for by Google ads, banners and nothing else.



MenuElephant is scheduled to have menus from anywhere in the United States. Future plans call for an International edition for travelers to find restaurants in any English-speaking country. In addition, restaurants without a website can publish a link to their menu page allowing them to advertise their business on coupons, the Yellow Pages, and other media.



MenuElephant was founded by Sue Marie and Jeffrey Hauser. They already run a health information website, http://www.thenurseschoice.com. The name http://www.menuelephant.com refers to the largest land animal, hoping theirs will be one of the largest and most used websites in the hospitality industry.



###




 Filed Under: Restaurant Menu Tagged With: Advertising , Free , Introducing , MenuElephant.com , Menus , Offers , Posting , Restaurants , Website 
 Restaurants Can Now Advertise Their Menus Online for $52 per Year and Customers Have Access to Search a Wide Range of Menus Nationwide 
 October 17, 2011 By gorestur 512 Comments 
Rutherford, NJ (PRWEB) November 18, 2005

AnyMenuOnline.com recently launched a new website that enables restaurant owners to advertise their menus and other services online for as little as $ 52 per year. They can reach more people then any local Yellow Pages costing as much as $ 6,000 for a half-page display ad or a local newspaper with a cost of as much as $ 3,000. That is only one dollar a week for the potential of reaching millions of customers. There are no other hidden fees guaranteed.



Restaurant owners can edit, change, and update content to their menu. They can provide printable customer coupons, provide daily specials, or complete changes to their menu.



Any Menu Online will provide step-by-step instructions on how this is done.



By a click of the mouse, consumers will find a wide range of menus from four-star restaurants to your local pizza and sub shops. You can search by using the name of the restaurant, city, state, zip code, or keyword (Italian, pizza, deli etc.). Then just click on the restaurant name and there is the menu!



Consumers can try a new restaurant and not have to worry that they have no idea of the food selection or prices.



AnyMenuOnline.com does the research for the consumer and all they need to do is decide on which to choose. Not only will you see the wide range of restaurants menus but also their beverage and wine list, kid friendly, reservations suggested or required, ?bring your own,? nonsmoking available and much more! Look out for Promotions our restaurants may offer such as free appetizers or discounts!



Featured restaurants are listed on the home page for 7 days and links to your menu are on every page of the web site providing more exposure to your restaurant.



Planned advertising for AnyMenuOnline.com will include newspaper, radio, billboards, TV, stickers, handouts, mailers, etc.



About AnyMenuOnline



Located in Rutherford, NJ AnyMenuOnline is an online menu database that includes restaurant menus, photos, directions and services. Restaurant owners have access to change menus, photos and offer discounts and gift certificates. Site users will have free access to browse these restaurants by ethnicity, zip code, or restaurant name. A direction link will be provided to have instant directions. Icons will show specific services such as a wine bottle that serves liquor, or a car to a restaurant that offers delivery.



Contact Information:



Michael Santa Lucia



AnyMenuOnline



Ph: (201)926-1135



Fax: (201)460-8075



website: http://www.anymenuonline.com



###





Related Restaurant Menu Press Releases 
 Filed Under: Restaurant Menu Tagged With: Access , Advertise , Customers , Menus , Nationwide , Online , Range , Restaurants , Search , Their , Wide , Year 
 MustHaveMenus.com Announces New Menu Editor App to Assist Restaurants with Holiday Menus 
 October 2, 2011 By gorestur 1 Comment 
 
Ashland, OR (PRWEB) December 4, 2009

MustHaveMenus announced today that it has released the Menu Editor, an online menu creation application that allows restaurateurs to create custom Christmas menus and other event menus, just in time for the holiday party season.



?Creating menus can be one of the most time consuming tasks for any restaurant,? said Jim Williams, CEO of MustHaveMenus. ?Our new Menu Editor makes it easy for a restaurant owner or manager to produce a customized Christmas menu for a holiday buffet, brunch or Christmas party.?



For many restaurants, menus are usually created using common desktop software. The menu is saved on the user?s personal computer, and must be updated from there. Using the Menu Editor, a MustHaveMenus member can select from a number of professionally designed menus. The user can enter menu dishes and prices online, and save the data. Customized menus can then be downloaded as a PDF, allowing members to print copies, email the menu to their customers, or post the menu to a restaurant website.



MustHaveMenus, launched in 2006, is dedicated to providing the best restaurant marketing and restaurant management solutions to its customers. Along with the Menu Editor, MustHaveMenus offers high quality menu templates, food images and graphics, and food icons that help customers design the perfect menu. MustHaveMenus also offers a restaurant management and marketing guide full of resources for busy restaurateurs, such as inventory spreadsheets, signage and articles that describe how to build a successful business.



The Menu Editor app can be used to update a large selection of holiday menus, for events such as Christmas parties, holiday buffets, or Christmas brunches. A selection of dessert menus are also Menu Editor-ready, making it easy for restaurant owners and managers to offer their customers updated dessert listings.



?One of the most useful features of the Menu Editor is that menus can be saved online, tied to your MustHaveMenus account,? said Williams. ?Your menu is safe, secure and easily accessible at any computer with an Internet connection. Next time you prepare for a holiday meal, your entire history of holiday menus will be right there.?



In the future, the Menu Editor will be expanded to include menus from every dining menu category on MustHaveMenus. Users will also be able to add their logo or other images to Menu Editor menus and move their dish names and descriptions among different menu designs.



MustHaveMenus is a leading provider of menus, restaurant marketing and restaurant management resources for the food service industry. Customers can register for a free seven day trial at MustHaveMenus.



###







More Restaurant Menu Press Releases 
 Filed Under: Restaurant Menu Tagged With: Announces , Assist , Editor , Holiday , Menu , Menus , MustHaveMenus.com , Restaurants 
 Customer Serves Up Take Out Restaurant Menus Online 
 September 25, 2011 By gorestur 62 Comments 
 
Los Angeles, Calif. (Vocus) April 3, 2007

C. Neil Talbot remembers that day four years ago when he was at home with a friend, they were hungry and badly wanted to make a quick run to a local Thai restaurant to get some take out food.



But Talbot couldn’t find the Thai restaurant menu.



He knew he had it somewhere.



After all, he’d get a menu on his front door every Thursday. But he’d either throw them away or they’d fall to the ground and litter the neighborhood.



“I suppose you could guess at what you wanted,”says Talbot,“but we really wanted to see a menu.”



That’s when the idea came: What if take out restaurant menus were easily available online?



He cooked up a business plan and now GrabTakeout.com is a booming web site offering menus from Japanese Restaurants, Chinese Restaurants and many other take out restaurants.



“Grabtakeout.com helps to solve the eternal question of what do you want to eat,”says Talbot.



Grabtakeout.com is easy to use and has all the ingredients consumers would want. It’s easy to use, you just enter your city and state and/or zip code and you’ll find menus from restaurants in your area. You can also look for delivery restaurants, catering restaurants or look for restaurants that accept credit card and checks.



And it’s also a good deal for restaurants. It’s free for restaurants to post their menus and the web site has just about every cuisine: from Japanese Restaurants and Chinese Restaurants to Mexican Restaurants.



“Most restaurants are under the impression that they need a web site,”says Talbot,“but they don’t know anything about the Internet. Even though you build an expensive nice-looking web site, no one goes there.”



Talbot says people want menus and a one-stop shopping source for take out restaurants.



“It’s made my life easier and I know it’s doing the same thing for other take out restaurant lovers.”



About Grabtakeout.com: GrabTakeout.com is a free, easy to use Internet based restaurant search engine. It connects consumers with food in their area. Whether it’s Japanese Restaurants, Chinese Restaurants, Italian Restaurants, or simply take out restaurants, you can find it on GrabTakeout.com.



About Neil Talbot: Besides being a lover of take out food, Neil Talbot is a software system architect. He designs, develops complex software systems for the U.S. government. He lives in the Los Angeles area.



Interview Availability: Neil Talbot is available for television, radio and newspaper interviews.



Contact: Neil Talbot, Grabtakeout.com

Email: Neil.Talbot @ grabtakeout.com
 Filed Under: Restaurant Food Tagged With: Customer , Menus , Online , Restaurant , Serves , Take 
 OpenMenu? is Changing the Restaurant Industry by Standardizing Online Restaurant Menus and How the Information is Stored and Shared 
 September 24, 2011 By gorestur 378 Comments 
Columbia, SC (PRWEB) February 8, 2011

Have you ever had a craving for fried calamari, pasta carbonara, or molten lava cake, and tried to search for a restaurant in your area that serves it? It was probably not that easy. That?s because there is no standard for the way restaurants share their menus across the internet. OpenMenu? solves that issue by eliminating the use of clunky Flash menus, slow-loading PDFs, and fuzzy scanned images, all of which make getting accurate menu information difficult, if not impossible.



The OpenMenu? Format, or standard, sets the foundation for an open system of regulating and distributing menus across the internet. Chris Hanscom, founder, states, ?To truly move the restaurant industry forward, as it relates to the internet and mobile solutions, a standard is needed. Now, restaurants only have to update their information and menu once, and that information is disseminated internet-wide.?



No longer does a restaurant have to worry about updating its information in the dozens or hundreds of locations where it resides. Restaurants maintain their menu through an OpenMenu? Registrar in a single, online location. This menu is then officially registered with OpenMenu? and distributed to anyone providing a restaurant-based solution ? a totally open system for the benefit of the restaurant.



No more out-of-date menus and restaurant information. Update a menu in one location, and it?s updated everywhere downstream.



For information: http://OpenMenu.com or

Contact: press(at)openmenu(dot)com



###






 Filed Under: Restaurant Menu Tagged With: Changing , Industry , Information , Menus , Online , OpenMenu , Restaurant , Shared , Standardizing , Stored 
Search
 &lt; 
Connect with me:
 
Recent Posts

 Hyatt Regency Chicago and Momma Cuisine Team Up to Sponsor Charity Dinner for Jamie Oliver’s Food Revolution and Chicago-based Purple Asparagus Online Fitness and Weight Loss is a Booming Business as FitOrbit Seeks to Add Several Hundred Personal Trainers Intorrent Technologies Deploys Cloud VoIP Phone System to Ski Area; Delivers Better Customer Experience “Recipes From Historic New England”, a Travel, History and Cooking Guide All Rolled Into One Kaldi Now In Five Connecticut Specialty Food Stores Hilton Head Chef Named“Platinum Partner”for Sustainable Seafood Denver?s Own Hodsons Bar and Grill Extends Its Summer Live Music Program A-1 Freeman Moving Group Hosts 2012 Best Restaurant of Oklahoma City Social Media Contest Award Winning Bed&amp;Breakfast Celebrates the Change in Seasons Buffalo Lodging Associates Opens Courtyard by Marriott Buffalo-Airport Hotel Director Mark E. Ridley Unveils ?Unhood Your Mind? PSA to Honor the Memory of Trayvon Martin 
 
Categories

 Restaurant Food Restaurant Meals Restaurant Menu Restaurant Recipes Uncategorized 
 
Tags
 2011 2012 Announces Annual Best Celebrates Chef Cooking Cuisine Culinary Dining DINNER Family Food Francisco Free From Gourmet Holiday Hotel Introduces Italian Jose Launches Local Menu National Offer Offers Online Open Program Recipe Recipes Resort Restaurant Restaurant.com Restaurants Season Service Their This Website Wine York 
 Return to top of page 
 
Copyright©2012  Privacy Policy | Web Hosting by Brain Host
	</body>
</document>
