<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007953" url="http://hv.greenspun.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg.tcl?msg_id=0001Iu" time="2012-07-13-00:55" support="35" score="0.05370397765014061" bingtitle="Why does McDonalds lie in their ads? - the Greenspun family server" webtitle="Why does McDonalds lie in their ads?">
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000031" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000380" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000004" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000157" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000661" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000693" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001190" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000406" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000656" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000130" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000629" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>... every other fast food (and many non-fast food) restaurant ... GOT HOME AND HAD TO GO BACK AND PICK UP REST OF ORDER ... oh about 15 people waiting at the front counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Why does McDonalds lie in their ads?
 greenspun.com : LUSENET : Corporate Suckup Forum : One Thread 
 
 
 This McDouble does not look much like the ads ...
See: The McDouble Lie
What is your experience?? Leave it below.

-- rp ( editor@zpub.com ), December 11, 1997 
Answers
 The McDouble Lie 
 
 As Advertized 
in the window 
 As Delivered
 Friday, September 13, 1997
McDonalds @ Market&amp;7th in San Francisco 


-- richard ( zpub@sirius.com ), December 30, 1997. 
 Target: McDonald&apos;s Reason for boycott: Censorship Sponsor of boycott: McLibel Support Campaign For more information: Phone: +44 (0)171 713 1269
Email: info@mcspotlight.org 
WWW: http://www.mcspotlight.org/ 
 Target&apos;s address: Oak Brook, IL 60521
USA
Email: postmaster@mcds.com 
 Explanation: The McLibel Support Campaign urges consumers to boycott McDonald&apos;s fast-food restaurants in response to the company&apos;s efforts to censor its critics. McDonald&apos;s has used threats of legal action for many years to silence criticism of its business practices. Through the use of libel suits, McDonald&apos;s has attempted to stifle the voices of protestors criticizing the company&apos;s policies regarding promoting unhealthy food, targeting children in advertising campaigns, being anti-union and paying low wages, cruelty to animals, etc. 
 Source: The Boycott Board 

-- The Boycott Board ( info@2street.com ), December 30, 1997. Disney&amp;McDonald&apos;s Linked to $0.06/Hour Sweatshop in Vietnam Summary: Seventeen year old women are forced to work 9 to 10 hours a day, seven days a week, earning as little as six cents an hour in the Keyhinge factory in Vietnam making the popular giveaway promotional toys, many of which are Disney characters, for McDonald&apos;s Happy Meals. After working a 70 hour week, some of the teenage women take home a salary of only $4.20! In February, 200 workers fell ill, 25 collapsed and three were hospitalized as a result of chemical exposure. 
-- more 

-- Mike Rhodes ( clr2@igc.apc.org ), January 01, 1998. OPRAH - A RE-RUN OF McDONALD&apos;S DISASTROUS UK McLIBEL SUIT?
Deja vu for the main protagonists Lyman and Engler via McDonald&apos;s UK libel link.
Lyman&apos;s McLibel testimony to be evidence in Oprah trial.
-- McLibel lives on in US &quot;Beef Libel&quot; case 

-- ( foo@bar.com ), February 13, 1998. Actually, they really don&apos;t. Everything you see in a print ad is fairly accurate-provided you ignore the 20 odd hours spent in retouching every major print ad campaign they make. Removing brown lettuce, discoloured saauce, burnt meat etc....

-- Jeff ( svisfgvdart@eartgggng.net ), March 20, 1998. Its probably a fine line between colour glossies, and the real product. Most Retailing is much like this.
What irks me, is that half the product appears to fallout, when being picked up (a la lettuce strings !)
Whatever happened to the old fashioned lettuce leaf !
Would probably cut their o/heads a bit too !

-- Dave Cruickshank ( dcruick@nz1.ibm.com ), March 30, 1998. Well, the answer is obvious. If their products were honestly portrayed in photos and on TV, we would all accelerate past the Golden Arches toward a REAL restaurant, or better still: home. McDonald&apos;s food is the worst. Absolutely without any value.
Try this: (I have) Buy a burger from Ronald. Take it home, away from the big posters and playground and tackiness. Remove the meat patty and place it on a plate, patting it dry to remove the horrible &quot;sauce&quot; that they squirt on every one. Cleanse your palate with H2O and have a bite of the patty. Evaluate the meat on its own merit: texture, flavor, character, etc. I DEFY you to finish the piece of shit. I once wrote a polite letter to McD&apos;s corporate stooges and offered my evaluation of their products (after I had shed over twenty four dollars to feed my family of four a modest meal). I received no answer.
I would NEVER consider another thrip to McDonalds.

-- Buzz ( buzzo@Feelgud.net ), April 19, 1998. Obviously the real reason for the lies is Kangaroos are too cute to kill.

-- ( LAACoop@AOL.com ), August 15, 1998. I think that there are too many complainers on this plant &quot;for sure&quot;
the plan truth of the matter is if you are not in agreement with the policy,proceedures,service and taste of a companies product then don&apos;t visit that establishment. If the majority of people who truly hate all of the above did just that then the place in question would be out of business. Oh but then you would have nothing to complain aobut seem to me you are perputuating your own problem to contine to do your complaining. MY GOODNESS WHAT A LIFE YOU HAVE MADE FOR YOURSELF YOU ARE A POOR PITIFUL CREATURE

-- Whirl ( whirlie_girlie@yahoo.com ), August 31, 1998. BECAUSE THEY CAN...........
........AND BECAUSE NOBODY WOULD BUY THEM OTHERWISE!

-- lynsey price ( grant.ward@ukonline.com ), September 02, 1998. IT ALWAYS SEEMS TO ME THAT WHEN YOU GO TO MC DONALDS NO MATTER WHAT 
YOU ORDER YOU NEED TO ORDER A SALAD DRESSING TO GO WITH ALL THE 
THROWN ON LETTUCE.
AND BESIDE THE POINT THE FOOD LOOKS BAD THINK OF THE GANG BANGERS THAT 
MADE YOUR FOOD PANTS DOWN TO KNEES ALL THOSE PIERCINGS AND GREEN HAIR 
I GUESS THAT AFTER SEEING THEM AND YOU STILL ORDER ITS YOUR OWN FAULT 
JUST SHUT UP AND EAT YOUR FOOD....IF YOU DARE.

-- TIM ( PLANETZOORBA@MAILCITY.COM ), November 15, 1998. I HATE FUCKING McDONALDS. THEIR FOOD TASTES LIKE SHIT. AND THEIR BOZO 
EMPLOYEES ARE JUST TOO STUPID AND DUMB. AND THEIR ADVERTISING IS CRAP.
----DID YOU SAID FUCKDONALD&apos;S?

-- The Spicy Zorro ( 1-800-I&apos;m HOT@aol.com ), January 28, 1999. Mcmurder supports police brutality, the deforestation of rainforsets 
for grazing grounds (killing hundresds of unique species). Also Mcshit 
 uses discrimination against anyone who looks different than the 
average joe schmoe. Once there was 10 punks inside Mcprofit across 
from Disneyland, and they called the cops, and they all had a police 
report filled out against them saying they were harrassing the 
customers. Then when the officers were asked about why they were 
arresting the idividuals we got responses like, &quot;Want to observe my 
knightstick&quot;, or when asked for a badge number (Which was 352 J. Berns 
of Anaheim Police Department) he said, &quot; Want it across your fuckin 
head&quot;. This is a regular and typical thing at Mcdeath every day. 
Mcbitches bribes cops with Deathburgers (The Murder Mac) every day so 
that protestors will be stopped and their profit will thrive. At 
febuary 20th, there was a protest against Mcshit and the APD for their 
support of Police brutality. The cops (instead harrassing and 
arresting real criminals) decided to waste 5 cops time and have them 
ready to write up a ticket if any itty bitty little law was broken. 
They finally found a way after 7 hours of protesting to get us to 
stop. A person brought O.C. Register signs and wrote on the back of 
them, so the cops decided that they would blackmail us by saying if we 
did not stop the protest then they would arrest everyone in possession 
of the signs for stealing and vandalism. The protest was stopped. But 
its not over. Protest your local Mcmurder. Propaghanda by the deed. 
Nothing is going to happen if you sit and complain. By the way the 
protest we did stopped alot of business, and the Mcshit was almost 
totally empty. SO LETS EMPTY OUT THOSE FUCKERS!!!!!!!!!
-P.S. Meat is Murder

-- John Herrington ( rampage@myownemail.com ), February 21, 1999. Who cares what the hell the ads look like? It&apos;s not like anyone 
actually went in there with the firm belief that they would recieve a 
carefully crafted burger as seen in the ads (other than the occasional 
Eskino who has never seen a McDonalds in their life). I guess the 
Eskimos should be reimbursed, but all you babies who whine about the 
accuracy of the ad&apos;s portrayal of the McDonalds burgers should get a 
life and make your own burgers. Better yet, franchise your own 
McDonalds and live up to the ad&apos;s standards, you would have me as your 
customer every day. 
PS I hate McDonalds, they are bastards and their food does taste like 
shit, but ppl who complain about crap like you do are contributing 
NOTHING to society.

-- Steven Adams ( oregun@mindspring.com ), March 04, 1999. Mc Donald&apos;s does not lie. I would like to see you try to make a 
better burger. Ray Kroc must be rolling in his grave.

-- Peter Piff ( www.piffman@ 74. com ), April 16, 1999. You, my friend, are the reason that the First Amendment should be 
withdrawn!

-- Who Cares ( Noneofyourdamn@business.com ), April 20, 1999. You sad wankers. Nothing beats a McDonalds. There not going to 
advertise using a wank burger that looks like its just been dug up are 
they you idiots. Get a fuckin life tossers.

-- tony paterson ( ecsapate@livjm.ac.uk ), May 04, 1999. more tipical bleeding heart wining from a socialist pinko dipshit who 
probably eats at wendie&apos;s when none of your mascara wearing hippy fag 
friends arnt looking. why dont you just accept that the real reason so 
many peopel eat at mcdonalds is because they are real people who like 
to eat real food and you are not. if you had have a brain you would 
wake up and stop whining an go feed yourself to a stpuid whale to save 
the earth. what it comes down to is you are just jealous cause you 
dont hae reasons and logic and common sense like us, the beef-eating 
real people of the USA. if you were lead by rationality like us 
instead of crybaby emotions like a tipical commie then you would get 
down on your knees and give head to Ray Crock because without him the 
children of USA would starve to death and the blood would be on your 
hands COMMIE FAG!
GO DIE, IRRATIONAL PINKO HIPPOCRIT!

-- Leroy Costello ( saddsak@sob.com ), August 02, 1999. Please note that I take great offence to your advertisement about the 
McDouble lie as I work in a McDonalds in Scotland and we do not sell 
the McDouble, so please get your facts right before you start giving 
false information to people who live in Britain.

-- Mr Burnett ( saltire_enterprises@usa.net ), November 11, 1999. I has a trik dat likes to put chicken nuggets in my pussy. they is 
warm&amp;slippery. dey luv Yo mcnuggets!

-- Lacey Pooty ( ho@7th&amp;broadway.com; ), January 25, 2000. To believe you would receive a burger such as the one advertised is childish and ignorant. Although once, in a convalescent home I saw quite the burger. I would like to digress from the burger topic to tell you about my christ experience. My cat, Thomas (r.i.p.) had used my grandfather&apos;s shower stall as a catbox. When my grandfather saw this, he looked up and uttered,&quot;Christ&quot; Then, he shoved Thomas&apos;s face into the fecal mess and bellowed,&quot;Christ cat!&quot; V-dogg has to go now, so peace out,yo.

-- Vladmir Wilton Vukovic esq. ( v-dogg@dahut.com ), June 25, 2000. I visited this site to research a speech I&apos;m doing next week in 
school against McDonalds&apos;. We were asked to choose a subject and this 
is one I feel strongly about. Your resources have been helpful and 
informative, I don&apos;t know how I will narrow it down to three minutes! 
However I was saddened to hear the ignorant, shallow and conformist 
comments of some of your visitors. They seem to think that if they 
write all in capitals, criticise you personally a bit and spell words 
wrongly (I SINCERELY HOPE that some of these misspellings were just 
typos...) that you will take the slightest bit of notice of their 
frankly pathetic views. A good site, nonetheless.

-- Jade Green ( pinkgirl47@hotmail.com ), November 16, 2000. I find it astonishing that most of this information is not known to the majority of the consumers in the world, and that should tell you of the incredible corporate power it holds... enough to silence the truth..
I&apos;m a meat eater but i would never eat at mcdonalds or any other fast food chain... But the important thing is not to immediately frown upon those who do for they are uneducated Through pointless bickering we can solve nothing.....
education is the most powerful tool, and is not something that can be forced.... when it is.... this results in immediate defiance. Before I knew about mcdonalds destructive power if someone got up in my face and bitched me out for eating one of there hamburgers.... i would have gone back in and ordered 20 of them out of spite... 
we are the environment, its time we stopped our self destruction.

-- dan ( lucifuge88@webtv.net ), November 23, 2000. McDonalds at Washington Court House Ohio South Elm Street likes to 
advertize specials and then does not follow through.Fries are still 
partially frozen instead of cooked.Their milkshakes are curdled 
their hamburgers still ooze blood from improperly cooked patties. You 
don&apos;t even get anything that resembles any kind of food.Let alone 
their pictures of their ads.

-- Richard Lewis ( zpub@sirius.com ), November 28, 2000. I have never had a bad meal at McDonalds. I go there for quick and 
easy food. And that&apos;s what I expect. If you really expect to get a 
gourmet hamburger within three minutes then the only person lying to 
you is yourself. If you don&apos;t like it, don&apos;t eat there. That is 
what makes America so great freedom of choice. So if you really want 
to stick it to them and support the constitution, eat at home.
P.S. If you think they are bad, have you ever eaten at Burger King?

-- Dan Chase ( kingadrock21@hotmail.com ), December 08, 2000. I had a friend who worked at Mcdonlads and when they are cooking the 
food they don&apos;t care where is gos or what is in the kitchen. They put 
meat or hamburger buns in the microwave with roaches and and rats. 
People find chicken heads in their chicken nuggets and and rat parts 
in the meat.The fries are made with fake fat and the employies who 
make the food don&apos;t eat it because they know what happens to it. The 
employies at the counter don&apos;t know whats happening to the food so 
they eat it. People go there to get cheap food, but they don&apos;t 
realisze what they are eating. They don&apos;t clean their ovens and they 
kitchens where they work at disscusting.

-- Tina Jones ( mellon44@yahoo.com ), December 13, 2000. Listen up fools. You people love to slam Mcshnoinkles. Why?? 
Mcshnoinkles is America. And if you dont love Mcshnoinlkles then you 
don&apos;t love America. It is a beautiful representation of society. Fast 
paced, cheap, a little dirty, consistent, and guaranteed 
satisfaction. There is nothing anyone can do about it. So enjoy it 
rather than diss it. You guys are just angry at your parents. I love 
you Mcshnoinkles...Don&apos;t listen to these freaks. With out you I would 
never be able to handle a road trip over an hour long.
Long live Mcshnoinkles!
sincerely, Tilvetri

-- will ryan ( ryanjw17@hotmail.com ), December 19, 2000. I agree with Will or Tilvetri whatever your name is. Mcdonalds or 
Mschnoinkles as you call it, is great. I have seen Mcdonalds make 
many children smile. It seems to have made there day. A childs smile 
represents happiness and joy and is a damn good representation of 
this country&apos;s future. It employs thousands of Americans who may not 
have a job otherwise. The food tastes good and nobody has died. Back 
off Mcdonald haters. Where else can you get a couple of value meals 
to satisfy you on a road trip. Open late nights and great fucking 
breakfasts as well. LONG LIVE McSHNOINKLES

-- sam silverstine ( s_silvestri@hotmail.com ), December 20, 2000. i will tell you right now that I have worked at Mcdonalds since 
feb. 2000 and i have worked in a couple of their stores. and the 
crap that they make there is horrible. if you only knew how thoses 
people handle your food you would be digusted beyond belief. People 
drop the food on the floor pick it up and put it on sandwiches, leave 
it bloody and red from the grill, or burnt to a crisp, small as a 
half dollar, put sweat on the burgers, make sandwiches without 
gloves, and take out slimy stinky dripping garbage bags and come 
right back to prepare the food without washing their hands. And 
before this food even comes to the store its mutilated and buffed up 
with chemicals. If you are a fan of the mighty wings you will see 
that they have increased in size DRAMATICALLY due to chemical 
enhancing. So every time you eat those wings rememeber its about 25% 
chicken and 75% chemicals

-- ( tizarus@hotmail.com ), December 20, 2000. listen Tizarus....aint nobody dying. Shut your hole before I cram it 
with an extra value meal. Im out. 2000 represent thug life 
mcshnoinkles!

-- sam silverstine ( s_silvestri@hotmail.com ), December 21, 2000. Why is everyone boycotting McDonalds? Who, in their right mind, 
would actually want to eat there in the first place? Personally, I 
can&apos;t stomach much of anything from McDonalds, mainly due to the 
sodium and fat content. I can feel my chest tightening just 
breathing the fumes as I drive past the place.
If you feel the need to go out for a burger, why not find one of 
those little family-run places that actually form the patties from 
ground beef on the premises? Chances are, their shakes will taste a 
hell of a lot better, their burgers will taste &quot;grilled&quot; instead of 
like &quot;salted meat-flavored product&quot;, and their fries will be thicker 
and taste like potatoes instead of salted, fried Cream of Wheat 
sticks.
But to the original question... The reason McDonalds lies in their 
ads is the same reason every other fast food (and many non-fast food) 
restaurant lies in their ads. They have the photos for their menus 
done in kitchen studios so that the food will look appealing. You 
can&apos;t seriously expect to get your hamburger like the one in the 
picture, with the little drops of dew on the tomato slice, etc. If 
you&apos;re paying $7.00 (U.S.) for a Big Mac, then it&apos;d be reasonable to 
have those expectations. But my guess is that you&apos;re not paying half 
that much.

-- Dixie Wrecht ( dixiewrecht@law.com ), December 25, 2000. Nobody can expect the product they buy to live up to the expections 
set in advertisments, this is true in all fields not just fast food. 
However, you should be able to expect better quality then a southern 
fried chicken&apos;s head in with your hotwings as some poor lady did as 
reported today in the Saturday Mirror.

-- chris bourke ( yousuckass13@hotmail.com ), January 06, 2001. i agree macdonalds is wank, i have worked there for nearly two years 
now. What some of u people are saying is ridiculous, rat meat in 
burgers??!! what the fuck is all that about!!
 If u don&apos;t like macdonalds, don&apos;t fucking eat there! Stop Bitching 
about it and get on with your lives!!

-- Joe ( psykowz@yahoo.com ), January 07, 2001. Of course the sandwiches don&apos;t look as advertised, you must have 
manure for brains.

-- Cam Volter ( captain@hawking.net ), January 12, 2001. The McDouble in England seems fine to me. I can&apos;t see why you&apos;re all 
complaining. If McDonalds was that bad, they wouldn&apos;t be a multi-
million dollar fast food company.

-- Craig David ( jimmy@dicksplat.com ), January 18, 2001. Very interesting. Why don&apos;t you guys try alt.mcdonalds? You&apos;ll find 
the McDonald&apos;s staff as warm and friendly as ever. Only don&apos;t 
criticise McDonalds, or they&apos;ll flame you back to the stone age.
I guess that&apos;s a grilling.

-- Playtime Fontaine ( playtime_fontaine@deja.com ), January 22, 2001. Yo, what did you think of V-dogg&apos;s cat story

-- Vladmir Wilton Vukovic Esq. ( v-dogg@dahut.com ), January 23, 2001. Im english and i agree. Im doing an Art course on Food and Drink and 
im focusing on How Fast food chains lie. Thanks for supplying some 
really cool pictures for me to stick into my sketchbook
Cheers JONNY 
Its about time someone did something about Corporate lies!!!

-- Jonathan Baverstock ( jonny4nat2@hotmail.com ), January 24, 2001. I dont see why everyone is jumpin on the bandwagon to slag off 
mcdonalds.I think they are lush.After a spot of retail therapy in town 
they are icing on the cake.They arent as bad as they are being made out 
to be.If you dont like them dont eat them - it cant be simpler than that.If 
you do like them and want to eat them then do so,this must be the case 
for a lot of people as maccy ds are a v.v.v.v.v.v.v popular food outlet!!All 
u goths out there who dont want to eat them so u can sace the world,do 
it quietly u pathetic attention seeking people!!!!!!!!!!!

-- Ronald mcdonald(in honour) ( jimmy@dicksplat.com ), January 30, 2001. The picture you put up, first of all was 4 years ago. Second It&apos;s 
not the company that lies it&apos;s the way you treat the sandwich when 
you get it. The person reciving the sandwich was not really taking 
care of it and probally throwing it on the floor a couple times then 
showing it. And then it&apos;s wrapped in paper so it&apos;s not going to be 
like the window.

-- Zachary Joseph Hartley ( kizasa@hotmail.com ), February 04, 2001. Simple answer for you. Burger King and McDonalds suck, but 
ESPECIALLY Burger King and ESPECIALLY McDonalds. Eat at Wendy&apos;s. 
When you can hear us chatting in back while working it means we&apos;re 
having fun, and less reluctant to put a little more effort into 
making food the way you like it.

-- Compute ( crazyc@famvid.com ), February 05, 2001. Let them eat shit! Seems that the customers are in a big hurry and 
willing to pay far too much for unhealthy food. As one of the Poe 
people , I find other options.You are what you iz!

-- Mack ( anticombine@hotmail.com ), February 16, 2001. Please quit complaining about the quality of the McDouble when this 
burger does not even exist. The sole reason that this burger was not 
prepared with the utmost attention to quality and customer 
satisfaction, was that you made it at home in your poorly decorated 
kitchen. If you want to sample the pure quality of McDonald&apos;s food, 
please visit your local franchise location and you will undoubtedly 
find that your food was prepared with the utmost attention to quality 
and customer satisfaction. 
Thank You and long live McDonald&apos;s.
Yours Truly,
Cheryl J. Sexton

-- Cheryl Sexton ( cs190700@oak.cats.ohiou.edu ), February 19, 2001. You guys have no fucking idea about McDonalds. How can u crtisize a 
company that is so successeeful you cant! The only people that do are 
just jeolous of Mcdonalds succesess. 
And by the way McDonalds are a bussiness and therefore need to make 
money and use there ads to do that and they are very succesessful in 
makin them money so u cant critisize them either

-- Paul ( Macciatto456@hotmail.com ), February 24, 2001. You _have_ to love the fries. Seriously. mmmmmmm....*drool*

-- Michael ( michael+mc@limit.org ), March 04, 2001. every time i go to mcdonalds i see the people behind the counter are 
all insanitary. i watched a man sneeze and had me my order. People 
that work there are so fucking gross. You would think that McDonalds 
would take the Chickens Head out of the McNuggets befor serving that 
to a customer. I wish they would wear Hair Nets. The bathrooms never 
have toilet paper in them. The people that work there are all 
illiterate........ BITCH

-- michelle ( michelleschulz_01@yahoo.com ), March 26, 2001. Big Mac Mc-d-l-t Quarter Pounder with Some cheese Filet of Fish a 
hamburger a cheeseburger a happy meal big tasty lots of fries regular 
or super size....You get what Im saying. Long Fucking Live McDonalds!

-- Tilvetri ( s_silvestri@hotmail.com ), April 02, 2001. I urge all of you to read Eric Schlosser&apos;s book, &apos;Fast Food Nation-
The Dark side of the All American Meal.&apos; Great, informative reading, 
and consistent with your worst fears about McDogballs. I quit 
McDogballs for good after a co-worker broke a crown off his teeth 
while biting into a McDogballs &quot;Hamburger.&quot; I almost puked from 
hearing the story. I also heard McDogballs has pre-printed forms for 
dental compensation in the event of hitting a foreign while eating 
the slag they call food. They truly suck, and are sucking the life 
out the diverse nature of our great country. Peace.
-slayer

-- nayslayer ( vista@yahoo.com ), April 06, 2001. i love to chew on those little pieces of tendon in the chicken 
mcnuggets. they have a distinct flavor that seems to be addictive.
when i bite into one of those chewy little morsels, i lose myself in 
their rubbery goodness. i often feel that more restaurants should 
make deep-fried tendons available, so that mcdonald&apos;s wouldn&apos;t 
monopolize the deep-fried tendon market. 
as for the mcdouble, i have always found that this sandwich is always 
prepared with the utmost attention to quality and customer 
satisfaction. though i am not sure that this sandwich truly exists. 
Thus, your website has no true focus.
thank you

-- Joel Smith of the Winchester Smith&apos;s ( smithj21@hotmail.com ), April 16, 2001. I am the founder of this website, and after some careful 
considerations, I&apos;ve decided that I must be an absolutely pathetic 
moron to have created a site with this focus. I came to feel this way 
upon reading the comments of the previous contributor. He discredited 
my entire postulation, as to the existence of the McDouble. I now 
admit it-there is no McDouble. I fabricated the McDouble&apos;s entire 
existence so that I could entice women into my pathetic life by 
showing them my very own website. I am sorry for all the lies I&apos;ve 
told, as well as the time all of you contributors wasted in posting 
your comments. In closing, I would like to say that I also love those 
chewy tendons in the Mcnuggets. Perhaps, one day, all nations will 
unite to create a world that allows such tendons to have their very 
own place in the fast-food industry.
Yours truly,
Richard

-- Richard &quot;no-life&quot; Brown ( zpub@sirius.com ), April 16, 2001. Some of you peopla have no idea what McDonalds are doing in this
world. The Rainforest used to cover 14% of the world&apos;s surface and now
only 7% with and area the size of California every year. In 25-30
years, if we carry on like this the rainforest will be completly
destroyed. This would cause the extinction of more than half the
world&apos;s species of animals, plants and insects. Ok Mcdonalds cannot
be wholey responsible for this but they are doing a good blodie job of
contributing to it by burning rainforests to make room for their
cattle ranching. The rainforest is only one of many things they are
doing to destroy this world but just remember next time you have a
Mcdouble(or whatever im not familiar with the names as i never! go
there) not only have you helped kill the one cow that your burger was
made out of but also you have helped to severely threaten the worlds
population of beautiful animals and plants.(many of which we haven&apos;t
even discovered yet.)
Oh yeah over here in Scotland people are complaining about are weather
but they dont realise that destroying the rainforest prevents carbon
dioxide converting into oxygen so that it will help increase the green
house effect which scientists believe that will make Scotland an even
wetter place.
I have also heard about the horendous stories of finding mice in the
freezers along with the burgers and the thought of what some poeple
have said about the conditions that they are making this food in
absolutely disgusts me. McDonalds are down right bastards and i say we
think twice before you go there for your tea tomorrow. Why not visit
a nice restaurant instead(they are not all expensive!)
bye

-- Becky Baird ( bexxy69@hotmail.com ), April 21, 2001. I used to like Mcdonalds, up till 1992. I turned vegetarian 
overnight and decided the safest form of food would be the fries 
and barbecue sauce. After nearly getting through a large Fries, I 
dipped a large frie in and caught sight of something in the 
sauce. I thought it was a broken frie, it turned out to be a rear leg 
of some kind of rodent. I was so disgusted I took pictures and 
Informed the envriomental agency. After 2 months the outcome 
was that Someone i.e. me, had planted the said rodent. I hadnt, I 
had no reason, as I have said I foolishly love the food, I was 
offered 10 in Mcdon gift vouchers. Bastards. I never believed 
any stories of malpractice in their food in the early eighties, how 
wrong I was. By the way the pics are available to any 
anti-mcdonalds website, please email me and ill send them by 
return, with a sworn affadavit of its validity. Fuck Mcdonalds, Fuck 
their globalisation, Fuck the Happy Meal Toys that some poor kid 
in Vietnam is making for 10cents and hour.

-- Uk Mcdon hater ( sonyboyz_uk@yahoo.co.uk ), April 22, 2001. I was totally addicted to Mc D&apos;s until about 2 weeks ago when I heard 
some sick, true stories about that dump... there have been traces of 
faeces (i.e shit) in the meat from cows. My brother&apos;s friend worked 
there with this freak and the freak told him that he had jerked off 
over a burger when nobody was looking that morning. My friend also 
worked there and saw guys cleaning the fry cookers with powdery 
cleaning stuff and not wiping it off properly, fries being cooked 
there the next day. She told me that they would drop food on the 
floor and sell it anyway, or step on it and then sell it. Stay away.

-- Hel Da ( hel01d@hotmail.com ), May 03, 2001. All the idiots defending macdonalds seem to be illiterate - what a 
surprise.

-- colin sad ( colinsad@hotmail.com ), May 05, 2001. mmmm mmm mmmm mmmmmmmm its mac time! i love maccas juicey burgers. 
when you chew that chewy meat and before you swallow it it feels like 
its still kickin in ya mouth! Then i love eating the left over mushy 
lettuce and soft tomata and gooooey cucumbers on the wrapping which i 
ate over. LOVELY. you couldn&apos;t ask for much more...........except 
something like whats on tv ads!

-- Carlos Luither ( blankdeath6@hotmail.com ), May 13, 2001. I WENT TO MCDONALDS SATURDAY NIGHT WAITED IN DRIVE FOR 28 MINUTES 
BEFORE GOT OUR FOOD THEN IT WAS WRONG I CALLED WHEN I GOT HOME AND 
HAD TO GO BACK AND PICK UP REST OF ORDER AND THEY DIDNT SAY I AM 
SORRY OR ANYTHING WHAT A DUMP

-- MATTHEW EDGIL ( ROLLTIDEEDGIL@AOL.COM ), May 14, 2001. WEll i actually worked at mcdonalds. For six months. i was paid 5.25 
an hour. After six months i was offered a promotion to assistent 
manager with a raise of .25 cents. Bull shit. I quit. They have 
cardboard meat. there eggs are made of an orange water thing. They 
had bad service. They would understaff and we would be stuck with a 
line of thirty people with only six people working. If we complained 
we just got lectured for working harder.They should be taught a 
lesson.

-- stephany marguia ( hot_chica786@yahoo.com ), May 16, 2001. mcdonalds is fu**** good i dont know were ur a** goes but my 
hamburgers look good im am from h-town in texas and u s***

-- pissant ( sidhajshd@aol.com ), May 19, 2001. I work at a McDonalds and I just want ot say that the average 
customer today is to spoiled. They want fast and fresh food and want 
to be waited on hand and foot. They wait until it is their turn in 
line to order to think about what they want. &quot;You guys don&apos;t take 
checks, what do you mean i am on the badcheck list&quot; They want so 
much for so little. They expect all this and when it comes to paying 
for the food they think it is too expensive. They treat us employees 
like crap, they show no respect, the only reason there is crappy 
service is because the managers can&apos;t find someone else who will take 
the sameamount of crap from customers. If you are going to order food 
know what you want. This morning a young man asked for sausages no 
egg. I rung up two sausage sides because he didn&apos;t want me to read 
back the order. He wanted to Sausage McMuffins with no egg. I can&apos;t 
read your mind stupid customer. All I have to say is that you should 
McKiss my Ass, you ungrateful bastards! If McDonalds did not exist, 
kids around the world would die of starvation. Now a days parents 
are too lazy to cook home meals so the feed their kids fast food 
everyday. It is not our fault if kids are getting fat from our food 
because that is all you serve them! My job is so hard. My co-
workers make minimum wage, It is hard to find someone who will work 
so hard for so less. Most of our profits go into charities and 
replacing sandwhiches for people who forget to tell you that they 
don&apos;t want something on it until they get it. My fellow McCommrades, 
Unite! We will strike and America will die!!!! Imagine a world where 
you have to cook, you have to go grocery shopping, wash dishes, think 
about it! I am only fourteen years old and I can figure it out, why 
do you stupid people not get it? McDonalds is good! Sure the food 
is fattening but do you want to buy a veggie burger, and broccili 
instead of fries, juice instead of pop. This does not make sense! 
&quot;In return of the Jedi, Chewbacca is on Endor this does not make 
sense, a seven foot wookie on a planet with 2 foot tall ewoks! This 
does not makes sense&quot;-my good friend Jonny Cochraine, Fellow 
customers you do not make sense! That is all I have to say!

-- Alex McDonalds-employee ( morpheous13@yourmom.com ), May 20, 2001. Alex is my brother and just to let u guys know,&quot;He is very spoiled&quot;. 
I am only 13, and im more responsible then him. He expects everyone 
to do his work at mcdonalds. He even yells at the costomers. 
Everything he said about himself is a lie. For example, the add up 
above said he is, &quot;work working&quot; its a bunch of bull crap.Oh... ya 
fell free to email me everyone.

-- brother of the alex mcdonalds employe ( matty@beenhad.com ), May 21, 2001. Well first I would like to say that McDonald&apos;s is hard work. I worked 
@ a McDonalds were we won The Best of the West award. This contest 
was from Paso Robles All the way to Los Angeles. I felt verry proud 
of all the awards we got. But like the guy on the top said it is 
verry hard work and it really sucks when the customers stand in line 
looking @ you mad like it is your falt that the customer in front of 
them is taking tooooooo long to order with a bunch of kids running 
around throwing straws and lids all over the place. Thewn when it is 
there turn they go &quot;uuuuuuuuuuuuuuhhhuhh I don&apos;t know what I will 
have, Maybe I will have a #1, no never mind I will have a #5 it&apos;s 
less expensive&quot; Like a $1.40 is a whole shit load of money more. Oh 
and then they come back and say &quot;I forgot to order this without 
onions&quot; In conclusion to all those people who haven&apos;t worked at a 
McDonalds shouldn&apos;t be talking shit if they don&apos;t know.

-- Maria Palomino ( Rugrat93444@aol.com ), May 21, 2001. MCDONALDS SUCKS SCROTUM THIER FOOD IS WHACK AND THE MEAT IF THAT&apos;S 
WHAT YOU WANT TO CALL IT IS SO HARD IT TASTES LIKE A BOARD. thE 
LETTUCE DON&apos;T EVEN GET ME STARTED ITS BROWN AND IN THE WRAP NOT ON 
THE SANDWICH THE TOMATOES ARE SLICSD SO THINYOU PROBABLY NEED A LAZER 
TO DO IT AND THE SAUCE IS SO THICK AND HORRIBLE THAT IT SHOULD BE 
ILLEGAL FOR THEM TO EVEN BE OPEN AND IN KENTUCKY THE SERVED SOME LADY 
A FRIED CHICKEN HEAD COME ON YOU HAVE TO HAVE SOME REALIDIOTS WORKING 
FOR YOU TO DO THAT SO HOW DO THEY SELL CHEESEBURGERS FOR $.49 BECAUSE 
EACH ONE COSTS ABOUT 18 CENTS TO MAKE SO THEN YOU ADD 5 CENTS FOR 
LABOR AND THEY STILL DOUBLE THIER MONEY SO JUST SCREW MICKY D&apos;S I GO 
EAT SOME BURGER KING HA HA HA.

-- william bubba redneck ( yourmom@aol.com ), May 24, 2001. I want some answers. I am a vegetarian and I keep KOSHER. I was so 
upset when I found out that in all those french fries I have always 
eaten, there is BEEF FLAVORING! They always claimed it used 
vegetable oil. I feel violated and am extrememely upset. I would 
like to join a class action law suit. Any ideas? Please email me!
Sarah

-- Sarah Katz ( Trntyforev@aol.com ), May 25, 2001. I have four kids ages 1, 7, 15&amp;18 years old. The only meat they 
have ever eaten in their life and the only meat I have eaten since I 
was 16 (I am 40) is Mc Donalds french fries. I&apos;m so angry.

-- Subhadra H. ( SubhadraH@aol.com ), May 25, 2001. FALSE ADV. I AGREE I WENT TO THAT PLACE AND ORDED A FISH MEAL WITH 
EXTRA SAUCE (BECAUSE IF YOU DONT THEY DONT PUT ANY ON)AND I GOT NHOME 
AND THE WHOLE FISH WAS COVERED IN SAUCE INSIDE AND OUT THEY ALWAYS 
FUCK SHIT UP!!! EVERY TIME WITH OUT A DOUBT.

-- DAN TRIPOLI ( DPTRIPLEEE.@AOL.COM ), May 26, 2001. What a pleasant board. All of my suspicions of Mcdonalds are true, 
but is Wendy&apos;s the same story?

-- Santana Shilling ( lenny@thwt.com ), May 29, 2001. Lets look at the symbols. First start with the clown.We all know 
clowns are laughing on the outside and plotting murder on the 
inside.He&apos;s about 6&apos;8 and he always hangs around children, a 
pedaphile no doubt. He can smell the change in their pockets and most 
likely will do anything to remove their pants for it.The golden 
arches. If you look at them, they&apos;re really 2 tombstones nestled 
together in a crowded cemetary. Over 1 billion motherfuckers buried 
under them golden arches.Mayor Mc cheese is only a puppet headed 
dictator, no real power.The fry guys are the three hitmen of the 
apocalypse, so cute and disarming all led by the hamburgler,who doing 
his masters evil work, spends the night sneeking into the houses of 
unsuspecting parents to steal away with their children. And finally 
we have Grimace, what the fuck is grimace.A grimace is a look of 
pain, it&apos;s the look of a greasy burger induced heart attack,a high 
cholesterol artery choking piece of plaque,thats what grimace looks 
like. Fast food cancer burgers made from polyurethane gluctose, 
protoplasmic asshole discharge and a pinch of grimace jizzm,all 
smothered with a secret sauce made of a mixture of laundry detergents 
and sypilis dick drippings, very tasty....would a clown lie?

-- John keroauc ( kero12469@aol.com ), May 31, 2001. Well we all have something interesting to say dont we. I have been a 
McDonalds employee for two years and i have to admit that being 
aworker instead of a customer at maccas gives me a totally different 
perspectivwe of what maccas really is. K! People work there for a 
minimum wage. Have the world fatest Dickheads as head of staff 
(managers). I bet you ask anyone who works at maccas if they enjoy 
there job. 99.95% of workers woudl say they hated it. It really isnt 
easyt being a worker who has constantly got someone on there back for 
6,7,8 hours. Not good johny, and add tot hat a cockhead saying hurry 
up... Not fast enough... You didnt say &quot;WOULD YOU LIKE FRIES WITH 
THAT&quot;. Stuff the fries I say. Customers need to understand it is 
slave labour and that we do work our asses of. Please customers be 
more tolerant with the workers and for once in your life say have a 
nice day instead of the other way around... or you know what. Take 
your food shove it up your arse and go cook the bloody food yourself 
ya lazy people.!!!!

-- ( jpannowitz@yahoo.com ), June 01, 2001. Listen, yeah Mcdonalds does have its down points, but some on,dont 
take it out on the workers. I have worked at McDonalds for over a 
year now, and its not my fault shit happens. If you want to point 
fingers at why McDonalds sucks, blam the freaking managers who dont 
pay us enough to give a crap if we see you smile. I dont get paid 
enough to make a freaking Cheesburger perfect. If i make it wrong, 
take it back, i dont care, your wasting more of the companys money 
anyways. So next time you get all mad and throw a hissy fit and a 
worker at mcdonalds just think, would you want to be in the same 
position making $5.90, having to listen complain about how their damn 
picky ass kids wanted no onions on their crapy food, no you wouldent!!
So have some compassion!! I would love to see you smile, if i got 
paid for it!

-- Lindsay Russell ( Linds2003@aol.com ), June 02, 2001. The problem is solved easily..... If you don&apos;t like something don&apos;t 
go there. If you have a problem with their product don&apos;t buy it. NO 
Where in their ads do I see YOU MUST HAVE TO SURVIVE or people that 
fail to buy our product will be shot. What is the problem here? ?

-- Mac Customer ( okmokan@hotmail.com ), June 03, 2001. Mc Donalds are so corrupt!

-- Mackenzie Adamaszek ( tartanass@mail.com ), June 05, 2001. About a month ago I read in the paper some little girl bit into a 
McMurder Burger and found a rat head in it.It still had whiskers and 
teeth.Disgusting!Even Jay Leno commented about it on his program one 
evening!I used to live by a McDonalds and would go there often for a 
rootbeer.(They can&apos;t fuck that up can they?).I&apos;d watch these guys make 
burgers with no gloves.They&apos;d slap the oily meat burger on the flat 
little bun,pick up a peice of cheese and then shower it in lettuce.My 
god,wear some gloves people!They&apos;d wipe their foreheads dripping with 
oil acne sweat and continue working.What&apos;s with these new McRibs?It&apos;s 
a mutilated burger drowned out in BBQ sauce.What scares me is that 
these are made in the back out of people view *shudder*.My 
friends and I would go to this one McDonalds for lunch during school 
and the workers (who were in their late 20&apos;s at that hour) would hit 
on chicks from my school.They should look at who they hire more 
closely!I would also like to say I think KFC is even more 
disgusting.Can anyone tell me how their gravy is made?Well if you 
can&apos;t,here&apos;s how they do it:They scrape the sludge from the deep 
frier,add water and call it gravy.MM MM MM.Sounds good doesn&apos;t 
it?No...

-- Amber ( beat_me_up_girl@hotmail.com ), June 05, 2001. because in there own fucked up lil world every thing they say is 
true,they probly dont think there lying, do you think they eat at 
there own fucking place fuck no!!! they probly eat at the big ass 
fancy fucking french places

-- Shoo Hunter Ressler ( shoo7373@aol.com ), June 09, 2001. I would hesitate to even call what McDonald&apos;s serves up - &quot;food&quot;. I 
have yet to receive anything which remotely looked like what was 
pictured on the menu and I can honestly say, in the 35+ years of my 
experience whith this chain, that I have NEVER received anythin HOT.
I now only frequent this chain as a last resort - I&apos;ll take Wendy&apos;s 
any day over McD&apos;s garbage.
And, I would like to ad that the SERVICE at McD&apos;s is somewhere 
bewteen extraordinairly rude and non-existent. Let&apos;s face it, the 
only reason they are still in business is that they market to 
children whose parents only take them there to shut them up.
I had a terrible experience at a McD&apos;s in Charlotte, NC, a few years 
ago. In fact, the experience was so bad that I wrote a letter to both 
McD&apos;s and the area Managar, whose name I procured form another store 
manager. You would think a corporation as large as McD&apos;s would want 
to hear about bad service, so the could react and correct it. Not 
so.!! I never heard a word from anyone. That sunk the nail in the 
coffin lid for me and I have gone out of my way,since then, to avoid 
their establishments and pass along the word to anyone I can that 
McD&apos;s is out to brain wash kids, in order to stay in business. Food? -
- HAH.! I would call it &quot;garbage on a bun&quot;.

-- Paul Eberth ( Oceandivvr@aol.com ), June 10, 2001. The only brains in mcdonalds are in the burgers- if you eat in this 
shithole then you deserve all that you get you as you clearly have 
shit for brains as well as for lunch.

-- ok yardy ( colinsad@hotmail.com ), June 13, 2001. I have no faith in fast food establishments. I have been screwed 
many times at mickey ds. Once I ordered a quarterpounder, went home 
and took it out of the bag to find a burger that someone was nibbling 
on other than myself. I didn&apos;t know mcdonalds had food tasters... I 
took the burger back and the manager told me that one of the workers 
made a mistake and put her lunch in my bag. Yuk! And I would really 
like to know why is it everytime I go to the mcdonalds in my freaking 
neck of the woods their always out of ice cream or the machine is 
broken. Maybe it is for the better.

-- Leslie E Trotter ( nvmykiss@aol.com ), June 14, 2001. Having read some of your complaints it can be concluded that you are 
all either exeptionally bored or extremely worthless. I advise that 
you should all get a life.

-- Eric Bentley ( PIFFJAW@aol.com ), June 14, 2001. This is by far, the funniest fucken thing I have ever read on this 
piece of shit computer. Thank you.

-- Londyn Alabastor ( poontang@suckit.com ), June 16, 2001. The guy who wrote a few up...I think 2.I&apos;m just very bored.I&apos;m taking 
my anger out on mcdonalds

-- Amber S ( beat_me_up_girl@hotmail.com ), June 20, 2001. to the folks who eat at mcdonalds. please rest assured that the meat 
used in the various sandwiches are of the highest grade A shit that i 
am able to produce from my ass. of course every now and then one 
slips by that isn&apos;t quite up to par, but for those particular 
defective shits we add a new sauce and give it a whole new identity 
and call it the mctastyshit. we stand by our advertisements and offer 
the public the best possible close proximities of the mcshit 
sandwiches pictured in the ads. so please stop by for lunch. 
remember, we want to see you smile!

-- ronald b. mcdonald ( ron@thegoldenarches.com ), June 21, 2001. hi all you stupid mother fuckers and fuckees. hope you enjoy eating 
shit because that&apos;s what you get when you go to mcdonalds. don&apos;t try 
to pick the rat parts out of your sandwiches, cause that&apos;s the most 
nutricious thing at no extra charge. by the way, the dude who made 
that sandwich didn&apos;t wash his hands after taking a dump in the filthy 
restroom.

-- david thomas ( mcturdburglar@mickeydee&apos;s.com ), June 21, 2001. Hi- before I found this site, I didn&apos;t realise that mc donalds were 
cutting down the rain forrests to grow cows- I didn&apos;t think their 
burgers were made of real beef!Seriously! I do know for a fact that 
their chicken source(containing those yummy tendons we all love so 
much)comes from genetically altered chickens- they are fed through a 
tube, don&apos;t have feet or beaks, and are crossed with frog DNA to make 
them grow quickly. (Hey, everyone who tries frog says it tastes like 
chicken.) Same for Kentucky Fried Chicken- that&apos;s why they changed 
their name a while back to KFC- the USDA wouldn&apos;t let them call it 
chicken legally. But really, if you think Mc Donalds is bad, try 
eating what they eat in most third world countries(where they make 
the happy meal toys)-you&apos;ll beg for a big mac! But since I don&apos;t like 
it, I won&apos;t eat it, if only because everyone who defends it seems to 
be illiterate and have the I.Q. of Rain Man(no-wait-he could do math 
in his head).

-- b.k. ( embrikal@aol.com ), June 22, 2001. I am a store Mangaer for a McDonald&apos;s in Massachusetts, I would 
like anyone who dares to make a Big Mac in 35 - 50 second&apos;s put it in 
a bag with hot fries and a hand it to a customer with there dirnk in 
less then 90 seconds total time!!!!!!!!!! Our people do there best 
to make a product that you people are just going to complain about 
anyways. You want it to look like the picture than stop complaining 
that we take to long. Where else can you find a company that will 
give you a guarantee of 90 seconds or less and also that the food you 
order will be made as you order it. Unlike B.K. we make every 
sandwich when you order it. And we guarantee it to be right or will 
fix it. If you have a problem of how you&apos;re food looks than open 
you&apos;re mouth and say something to the Manager so they can make it 
right. Other wise stop complaing. You&apos;re response is appreciated.
As McDonald&apos;s says &quot;Every complaint is a gift&quot; &quot;one out of ten 
people who have a complaint say nothing and never come back&quot; how do 
you expect us to fix the problem when you don&apos;t say anything?

-- Jason ( Jasonpied@aol.com ), June 25, 2001. McDonalds does just fine, great fries, quick service, best Cokes (and 
for you northern folk &quot;Sodas&quot;) out of any fast food restraunt. Wow, 
all this McDonalds talk has made me hungry, guess it is time for a #2 
Supersized with a Coke. :o)

-- Brian P. ( Brian@home.net ), June 25, 2001. Yeah, everytime I get a burger it looks like someone sat on it and 
not like the one in the ads. Why do they wear plastic food handling 
gloves and then count money still wearing the gloves and then go back 
to making the food wearing those same gloves? It kinda defeats the 
purpose. The fish is always hard because it sits in the crisper 
drawer for hours and then when they put it on the bun it is soggy 
from the microwave. When I was growing up in the stone age, their 
food was much better, everything was made when you ordered. There 
were no microwaves. They used to toast the buns in a toaster. The 
baked apple pies that they have today suck. I loved the crispy ones 
that used to be deep fried in animal fat!! I still like the shakes 
though, they haven&apos;t changed much. I don&apos;t eat there much anymore I 
have heart disease and I get chest pains every time I eat there.

-- steven ( naysayer1@juno.com ), June 26, 2001. The dirtiest people work at Macdonalds- who else would worth of 
minimum wage every single day, in stupid little uniforms with job-
titles like &apos;Team Leader&apos;, at a job where you can actually get fire 
based on the results of your &apos;smile test&apos; ?...
I like their nuggets though, but they also give me bad gas and chest 
pains.

-- Diego Sanchez ( pinko@delbeero.com ), June 27, 2001. You all suck for eating pig fat anyway. Now horsefat is different. 
The way it slides down your throat and and squishes into your 
intestines, later to leave your rear endin a georgous brown hue.

-- Eric Bently ( PIFFJAW@aol.com ), June 27, 2001. McDonald&apos;s has gotten NASTY over the years!!! They need to do 
something quick!!!! They also have the WORST fries out there!!!

-- patty kneeland ( nursepdk64@aol.com ), June 27, 2001. To the disgruntled store manager:
Please use a spelling and grammar check before sending out your child-
like defense.
Please pull through to the next window.

-- Tyson ( bigbeefy@aol.com ), June 28, 2001. Alright all u fuckers have no lives, go make ur own greasy shit, or 
stop eating meat. Have u ever heard that meat processing plants where 
you buy the meat to cook it at home can get jacked too? think about 
that now, or how there is genetic altered shit in our grocery stores, 
worry about more important shit and broaden your horizons over fast 
food in general I am not taking sides, I just want to make people 
more aware

-- SungHo Choi ( sungho@ureach.com ), June 30, 2001. Ronald McDonald and McMaggots. A new line in Los Angeles, Ca.No extra 
cost.

-- Jacoby&amp;Myers ( xxx@u812.net ), July 05, 2001. i have worked for shitdonalds for over 3 years and i would never eat 
there again after what i have seen. the food is nasty the 
restaurants are unsanitized and nobody washes there hands. i hate 
mickey ds!

-- mat ( skew02@yahoo.com ), July 09, 2001. While I agree there are businesses out there who should be shut down 
by the dept. of health, there are plenty that ARE clean. Working at 
McDonald&apos;s has taught me that the general customer expects what we 
can&apos;t do-- Make you 100 % happy in less than 90 seconds. It takes you 
awhile to place your order, especially when you can&apos;t decide what you 
want before you are &quot;ready&quot; to order.Then you have to dig through your 
pockets for money only to realize you don&apos;t have it. Then you argue 
about the price, get mad when we can&apos;t read your minds, and expect 
that $20 order (with special orders) to be ready by the time you 
finally pay for it. We have to make sure your food is hot, fresh, and 
served fast.It does take some time to make it and get it together. We 
aren&apos;t genies. It&apos;s not our fault the guy ahead of you took 5 minutes 
to order and pay, and ordered so much food that we had to cook more.
You have no problem waiting 1/2 hour for supper to be made at home; 
why can&apos;t you wait a mere 3 minutes for someone else to make it for 
you? You spend all your time complaining - why not get behind the 
counter and put yourselves in our shoes? AND try to do it at minimum 
wage!! (by the way- it&apos;s ALOT of work for minimum $$ )Try to be a 
little more couteous and patient and understanding - YOU REAP WHAT YOU 
SOW You can&apos;t expect to scream in our faces and treat us like crap and 
expect us to smile and take it. You wouldn&apos;t want to be treated that 
way-please don&apos;t treat us like that.If you knew all that goes into 
getting that food to you the way it should, you&apos;d be looking at fast 
food in a whole different light.

-- Tracy ( tcrump@twcny.rr.com ), July 10, 2001. !!MCDONALDS SUCKS!! 
McDonalds is a very bad restaurant. Their food tastes like crap! 
Anyways in the ads, there like &quot;Try our JUICY Big Mac only for a 
buck!&quot; And it&apos;s not even juicy. Meanwhile you&apos;re eating it and that 
shit sauce is dripping down your chin and the burger looks like crap, 
unlike the one in the ads. I prefer HARVEY&apos;s because they actually 
take time to cook the real meat that they serve you!

-- Anthony A ( golden_grin@hotmail.com ), July 12, 2001. Lets have a TV party. I burned down three Mcdanalds and ate two 
puppies before the police stopped me. no lie. look for me in your 
local Pittsburgh News. UP THE REVOLT! BURN THE MURDEROUS CLOWN!

-- Gavin the dirty Carbunkle ( Punkemon87@aol.com ), July 16, 2001. They don&apos;t lie on the ads, they fail to produce in the stores!

-- ron mcdonaldson ( mcdonalds@hotmail.com ), July 17, 2001. Let me tell you a little story about McDonalds. About a year ago, I 
took my little brother to McDonalds because for whatever reason he 
may have, Micky D&apos;s is his favorite(who can resist Ronald??)Well he 
is only 10 years old and you know how kids just love the &quot;happy 
meals&quot;..... Happy meal my ass...... his had a cheeseburger, and when 
we got home, he carefully unwrapped his pile of gook that most of us 
refer to as &quot;food&quot;, took a bite, and the burger part was missing!!!! 
They had given him a bun with mustard, ketchup,pickles, onions, and 
cheese, but with no burger. Now I&apos;m not the most intelligent girl in 
the world, but when you order a cheeseburger, you would think that 
the actual BURGER would be included. ;( To make the matter worse, I 
went back to yell at that them and to see if there was a logical 
reason why the burger was missing...I get to the counter.. and the 
cashier did not speak english so she was clueless as to why I was 
pissed.It just goes to show that you dont have to be a bright person 
in order to be employed at McDonalds...hell, you dont even have to be 
an english speaking u.s. citizen to be employed by the company 
that &quot;loves to see you smile&quot; yeah......I&apos;ll be smiling when I reach 
over the counter and choke your ass..........lol.....
MCDONALDS SUCKS!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!1

-- Jennifer ( kerropi1414@aol.com ), July 17, 2001. I agree McDonalds and Satan&apos;s Spawn Ronald suck. I just had
two chessburgers and a med. fry and coke. Now I have to shit.
Figures anyway I save a lot of money from not buying laxitives.
What&apos;s up with these money games they are always promoting?
Monoply... I have never heard of any winning. I have personaly 
won cokes and sandwich&apos;s, but where are all the Millionaire&apos;s
from these games? Probably just another McGank...

-- Goober ( djtaylor@ev1.net ), July 18, 2001. THEY LIE BECAUSE IF THEY TOLD THE TRUTH WHO WOULD BUY WHAT THEY 
ADVERTISE. As a mother and worker i frequented Mcd&apos;s when they were 
first born and back then they were very good. However over the years 
they have changed the food so much that you have to look at what your 
eating to remember what it was that you bought. My last experience 
was over 10 years ago when i bought their double burger. It was so 
bad that the seagulls wouldnt eat it. I havent been back since and 
have no intentions of returning; nor will I bring my grandchildren 
there.

-- Evylyn Burns ( RinkyDindy@aol.com ), July 19, 2001. I happen to think Mc Donalds is a fine oraganization!!! I fully 
support Mc Donalds effort to provide a NUTRITIOUS meal and a CLEAN 
eating establishment. Their concept of SUPER-SIZING is quite ingenius 
as well as affordable. Often I like to rub Quater-Pounders all over 
my pulsating genitalia while singing &quot;WE LOVE TO SEE YOU SMILE&quot;! When 
I am out of salt I run over to &quot;Mickey D&apos;s&quot; and scrap dried urine off 
their restroom toilets and re-sell it to the manager to apply on 
their fries! THEY LOVE IT!!!!! and so do you. So pleeeeeaaaaase 
eat at McShit!!!!! We love to seeeee YOU smile!!!!

-- turd ferguson ( cr8ve69@aol.com ), July 20, 2001. If mcdonalds or burger king or any fast food chain for example were 
to make burgers that look like the ones in the ads everybody would be 
waiting in the drive thrus and the lines for about two hours.
And another thing.
I hate eating inside mcdonalds,i like the drive thru,the 
reason,whenever i go inside to eat (very rarely),the place is a 
pigpen,there is trash still rotting on the tables,there is trash on 
the floors,nobody is cleaning it,and there is nothing but annoying 
little kids running around the place,i mean,im trying to eat my meal 
and there are kids screaming and running around the dump,and after i 
have finished my meal i sometimes have to use the restroom,and the 
restroom is a shit pit,there is nothing worst than going in the 
bathroom after eating and seeing big fat logs of crap in the tolet.

-- Justin ( jthomas14@netzero.net ), July 23, 2001. hey all i think that mcdonalds is allright i dont like the fish thing 
but i like the big mac. i have never gotten sick from eating there so 
untill i do i will continue to eat there. who cares what it is made 
out of if it tastes good? didnt the guy on survivor eat a rat? hes ok 
i think i didnt here he died. and what is up with all you losers who 
swear while trying to get your piont across? that is stupid. i think 
mcdonalds has to be doing something right or they would not be the 
sucesful buisness they are. i lik eto talk to peeps on line os if you 
wanna email me go ahead :)

-- Ask me and i will tell you : ) ( look125@aol.com ), July 24, 2001. Okay all you complainers.... here&apos;s what you need to do. I hate McD&apos;s 
also - don&apos;t trust the so called &quot;meat&quot; that they use in their 
so-called &quot;food&quot;! SO - we no longer live in the city - we have 40 
acres out in the country, and we raise our own meat. When you raise a 
chicken, turkey, duck, rabbit, sheep and/or cow from birth and know 
allow them to free range on your property, you know what they are 
eating, you know they are not on hormones or antibiotics, and you know 
you&apos;ve got fine, healthy animals. When you butcher them yourself, you 
know they haven&apos;t been contaminated in any meat-packing warehouse 
nightmare. City people don&apos;t like to get their hands dirty - don&apos;t 
like the idea of &quot;killing&quot; an animal - well I say, if you&apos;re a meat 
eater, quit being a hypocrite! And quit bitching! If you don&apos;t like 
fast food joints - DON&apos;T EAT THERE!

-- Cheryl in KS ( cherylmccoy@rocketmail.com ), July 28, 2001. uh...uh...THEIR FOOD SUCKS!!!

-- matt ( matty@beenhad.com ), July 28, 2001. i work at McDonalds and all i have to say is that they are not the 
nicest group of people in the world they talk behind your back and 
when you can;t work they make you feel about 2 inches big . they only 
good thing is that they do let you pretty much poick when u can work 
but they work they make you do is to much for what they are 
paying. all the pictures you see on the boards are all fake food 
its all done to try and sell a buger that has been sitting thee for 
about 3 hours and no one cares if its good or not. i have been told 
i should not talk aout this stuff so much b.c the customers will hear 
me. well i hope they all here this don;t be fooled by the smiles are 
free and the dumb clown. Its all just a way for you to come in and 
drop about $40 on food that i would feel bad giving to an animal. 
noting about them is nice or freindly they might smile at the 
custormers a little but for the workers McLies are just anohter 
part of the job not hte mention the McJoke they call a paycheck.

-- ??? ( nospy007@aol.com ), August 03, 2001. Each and every one of you needs to visit http://www.slowfood.com.
SLOW Food to the rescue!
kmf

-- Kurt Friese ( chefkurt@devotay.com ), August 03, 2001. Man you people have fucking problems. Yes, McDonalds IS absolutly 
revolting and disgusting {even tho the feices, roden, chicked head, 
stepped and jizzed on burgers taste good}. But for fuck sake, dont 
complain. FAST FOOD PLACES ARE HERE TO SERVE YOU, if you dont like 
there service, go make it yourself or find another restruant! For 
fuck sake, why complain!? Either DONT EAT THERE, or suck a cock! It 
fucking stupid, I think people who complain are poor wel-fare 
assholes.
Its so stupid, I was at Tim Hortons yesterday, and people were 
comlpain about A FUCKING STRAW RAPPER ON THE FLOOR, and they called 
the hot line and comlpined! WHAT THE FUCK! Go crap it up Micheal 
Jacksons ass you l337 F@gg07...

-- Jeremy L. Leroy {not} ( fuckmeharder@underage.org ), August 08, 2001. Why do dog&apos;s lick their balls? Ask a rhetorical question, get a 
rhetorical answer.

-- AAA ( anon@anon.com ), August 11, 2001. I work in Mcdonalds in the Uk.
I&apos;m not saying it&apos;s the best food in the world but if you don&apos;t like 
it dont fucking eat there, this shows how dumb some of u r by eating 
in a restaurant that u dont even like.
Your DUMBNESS shows through agian on the lying adverts.
In the adverts&amp;posters the company uses Wax Food (Yes, WAX FOOD)
Now unless you like eating wax food the ads&amp;posters r lies.
U may also notice that when being filmed the camera is right up close 
to the burger which makes it look a lot bigger, McDonalds do assume 
that some of it&apos;s customers have brains&amp;notice this.
The only way you&apos;ll get a real burger like the one in the ads is if 
you&apos;re gay enough to ask for the burger like the advert, in which 
case you&apos;d have to wait for about 2hrs.
P.S - ALL U COMPLAINERS R GAY&amp;SHOULD BUY A LIFE INSTEAD OF BUYING 
BURGERS AND TESTING THEM!!!
P.S.S - US EMPLOYEES LAUGH AT U SOO MUCH WHEN YOUR BACKS TURNED
P.S.S.S - FUCK OFF YOU&apos;RE ALL STUPID!!
P.S.S.S. - YOU MUST ENJOY ALL THE FUCKING INSULTS U DUMB AZZ
P.S.S.S.S - IF YOU&apos;VE READ THIS FAR AND R NOT A COMPLAINER (NO 
INSULTS R DIRECTED TO U
P.S.S.S.S.S - FUCK OFF
P.S.S.S.S.S.S - THANK YOU!!!

-- Sebastian ( Zipsta_z@hotmail.com ), August 19, 2001. Fuck the mcdonalds shit hole of a cesspool of fuckers! All they do is 
fuck up, and cover they&apos;re fuck, only to fuck the hell up again... 
They&apos;re food, sucks, it fucked up , the only good thing is that they 
know it, they accept it, they will come to accept it, they are fucked 
up.

-- ANTIMAC ( fuckmackdonalds@hotmail.com ), August 20, 2001. You fucking people have no lives. I work at McDonalds and yeah I 
wouldn&apos;t eat the meat if I was some starving child in a third world 
country but still. You have to get over it. So what if you dont like 
how it tastes. Dont eat there.

-- Kim ( sparklediva245@aol.com ), August 20, 2001. we got fucked with the game and now mcdonald&apos;s say lets play a new 
game.how about you play with my nuts mcdonald&apos;s

-- john dunn ( nogood187@excite.com ), August 22, 2001. u all have no lives other than to complain about food that you don&apos;t 
have to eat if you don&apos;t want to, spoiled ass bastards!

-- Shandra ( xoxo@ureach.com ), August 23, 2001. I LOVE MC Donalds THEIR FOOD IS GOOD YOU ARE THE LIERS

-- allison snyder ( angelgirls45@hotmail.com ), September 13, 2001. i got on this site because i thought it would be funny but instead 
its nothing but a bunch of whiny little bitches who dont know how to 
spell.get a fucking life and like everyone else says DONT FUCKING EAT 
THERE!

-- michelle davis ( chelleigh79 @hotmail.com ), September 17, 2001. It is very strange how we all got possessed by the antichrist who 
calls himself Ronald Mcdonald.I bet that no matter how much any of 
you people say that you hate mcdonalds,you still sometimes get an 
uncontrollable urge to go get some type of mcdonalds menu item.My 
motto is as long as it taste good.I personally don&apos;t think about all 
of the shit that&apos;s put into their meat.Wait a minute,that is fucking 
gross,but I&apos;m possessed.They love to see me smile.Some dumbasses in 
this world don&apos;t know how to do anything except say UUH do want that 
supersized?Thats why idiots go work there.Every one knows that only 
low educated people who are immature enough to blow a snot rocket on 
your burger work for mcdonalds.But who cares?If every one who at one 
point in time had something fucked up with there meal banned together 
and protested against mcdonalds,we could probably shut them down.But 
we won&apos;t.We&apos;ll just keep right on eating cum burgers and shit shakes 
because we are all trapped under the spell.Mcdonalds is satan.By the 
way,I know nothing I said was anything close to the subject,but the 
point is still the same-Mcdonalds sucks.

-- David Davis ( DAVISDAVID4@aol.com ), September 17, 2001. After reading all these different points of view, I just wanted to 
remind everyone that they are not forced to eat at McDonalds, or 
anywhere else for that matter. I hate eating liver, but you don&apos;t 
see me intentionally eating it and then blaming the poor liver 
because it tastes terrible. It tastes gross because its not my 
taste. To others however, it tastes quite good. To hate something so 
trivial so much as to actually create a web site about it is insane.
I happen to be a manager at McDonalds, and have worked there for over 
three years. And just so everyone knows, I eat there all the time. 
I see how it is made, and I know what is in it, but I still eat it. 
Maybe there are a few employees that will do the things that people 
were discribing, but in my three years, even when i was just crew, i 
have never seen anything even remotly like those things.
As for the service, some of the people that work there are morons, i 
can admit that, but its like that anywhere where there are teenagers 
working. You&apos;ve got to remember that these people are working for 
minimum wage. They have to put up with stuck up customers yelling at 
them, managers yelling at them, working crappy shifts (lets see how 
smiley you can be at 5:00am or 1:30 in the morning all for the $5-6 
they make per hour. I was insulted when i read the comment that the 
only employees that work there were idiots. I was a straigt A 
student in high school and am now studying finance in college. 
McDonalds is a great job when your in school because of its 
flexibility.
I cant even tell you the number of times a customer has been so rude 
to me, or made a snide comment that I have broken down and cried. 
People are just so mean it&apos;t unbeleivable. For a $5 meal, you cant 
expect perfection (especially in under 110 seconds, which is what we 
are supposed to strive for). I used to be the nicest, shyest person, 
but dealing with those customers, and the crap that they give all in 
the name of fast and fresh, i have become a cynical, mean person. I 
use to love talking to customers when i first started, now i honestly 
dont care if they smile, as long as they leave. And its the 
customers that did that.
As for the advertising, please name me a company, or an advertsing 
campain that doesnt try to make their product/service look or sound 
the best, that is the point of advertising!!
And when you complain about McDonalds the corporation, please 
remember that they employee thousands and thousands of people. And 
has anyone ever heard of RMCC (Ronald McDonalds Children&apos;s 
Charities). I would like to know of a huge &quot;money hungry&quot; 
corporation that donates tons of money, not to mention staff for this 
organiztion.
I think that i have writing enough for now, if you have any comments 
about any of the things i have writen (intellegent comments, not 
personal attacks please), feel free to email me or leave them on this 
comment board.
Thank you

-- Kim Williams ( Kmbrly7Williams@aol.com ), September 17, 2001. i think mcdonalds food is gross because numberous of my classmates got
sick back in 1989 and i don&apos;t eat there. they need older people
working there and reveiw food safety alot more closely.

-- shawna ( s_mckerrell@hotmail.com ), September 18, 2001. when i eat at mcdonalds i remember why i do not come here very offten 
for the food is not very good.it takes about one year to for me to 
foget how bad it is,but than i remeber why i was not eating here when 
i order something from mcdonalds the pizza was not to bad but it is no 
longer able order that there now i would have to be starving and get a 
free meal if you can call it that to eat there right kwow i am very 
hungery and have no money for i will say (and i don`t want to)i am 
very poor if i got free mcdonalds food i would force my self to eat. 
get how bad the food is

-- kelly a anton ( antoneshynkelly@hotmail.com ), September 20, 2001. Corporate America SUCKS, They lie for the bottom line$$$$$$$$$$$.
But remember, you are still free to make a choice and the dicision is 
yours. 
I personally will only eat their Filet of Fish sandwich and a bag of 
fries. 
And you can bet that somebody somewhere is spitting in the speacial 
sauce that is going on your Big Mac.

-- JC ( cnclmnjoe@netscape.com ), September 20, 2001. I come from a small island and have never heard of Mcdonalds. Could 
somebody explain what it is.

-- Officer Rubydoo ( bsp80a@bangor.ac.uk ), September 21, 2001. THE PROPLEMS WITH MICKYSHITS IN MY AREA IS THE FUCKING PEOPLE WHO WORK
THERE IS BECAUSE THE MUSHROOM HOUSES CLOSED DOWN, AND THE NONSPEAKING
ENGLISH FUCKERS HAD NO WERE TO GO. BUT THE FOOD PROBLEM WOULD BE FIXED
ALL THE SEATS WERE REPLACED BY TOILETS AND YOU WILL BE ABLE TO GIVE 
BACK THE SHIT BEFORE YOU LEAVE.
SO HAVE A NICE SHIT AND KICK THE FUCKING CLOWN IN THE ASS!

-- BILL G ( HERES YOUR MOMMA @AOL.COM ), September 21, 2001. Everytime I eat at Mcds I get the shits. I have to plan my drive time 
to maie it home in time to shit out great spouts of burning gut 
grabbing shits. Defcon 5 shits. Shits that splatter off the bowl and 
back up onto my ass. Shits that would scar bin laden.
Bobby

-- Rovbert Dassford ( bobbobbobob@ock.net ), September 24, 2001. There is a pretty simple answer to all of the comlaining about 
McDonalds.. if you don&apos;t like it, don&apos;t eat there. But don&apos;t make all 
these stupid claims about their food, and ruin it for people like me 
who have been eating there my whole life, and STILL love it. Yes, 
I&apos;ve found a hair in my food, or had a really greasy fry here and 
there, but it doesn&apos;t really matter to me. I don&apos;t return my food, or 
complain, or throw it out. I pick out the gross part, and eat the 
rest. I don&apos;t know about MickeyD&apos;s in the states, but I&apos;m from 
Canada, and it&apos;s a clean, quick, cheap place to get something that 
tastes good, and holds you over until you get to actually sit down and 
enjoy another meal. McDonalds is a staple of Canadian youth, and if 
you disagree, DON&apos;T EAT THERE!

-- Lauren ( chevybaby88@hotmail.com ), September 25, 2001. The McDonald&apos;s in my small city has this timing grid feature for 
customer drive-thru waiting. After you place your order, you can only 
remain on the grid for a certain amount of seconds. Then, if your 
order is still not ready, you must pull ahead and park or pull aside 
and park in the lot so that a worker can bring you your food.
I was told several times by rankled employees that they would get in 
trouble by their manager if the customer&apos;s car sat too long on the 
timing grid. This makes them look bad, so they command customers to 
drive off the grid. They get upset if you mention that there are no 
cars waiting behind. It doesn&apos;t matter to them.
Why? Because they don&apos;t have the food prepared and can&apos;t get it 
prepared on time. They belittle the customers if they are having a 
bad day or bad period.
Yeah, that&apos;s what I meant. Period!

-- dinosaur ( dinosaur@williams-net.com ), September 25, 2001. FIRST OF ALL, MCDONALDS IS FUCKING GAY!!!!!!!!! I FOUND PUBIC HAIR 
IN MY HAMBURGER!!!!! IN APPLE VALLEY, MN THE STORE MGR. IS A FLAMING 
HOMOSEXUAL!!!!! AND GRIMMACE LIKES TO TOUCH LITTLE KIDS!

-- mcdonalds_can_eat_my_shit ( fuck_mcdonalds@fuckmcdonalds.com ), September 27, 2001. Mcdonlads is horrible! they tear down our rain forests to raise their 
cattle just beacuse its cheaper and mistreat animals. they are one, 
if not the most powerful and rich fast food chains and have the power 
to change this but they are cheap bastards and only care about money, 
not their customers, animals or the earth!im trying to get a petion 
started so if u want to help or know of anyother ways i can help 
please e mail me.

-- Heather ( glitterpunkpixie@hotmail.com ), September 27, 2001. Let&apos;s dig a little deeper, (if some of the more feeble minds can)...
Inside the food industry, Chicken McNuggets, or ANY similar product 
from a store or restaurant, is called &quot;MDB Chicken.&quot; MDB 
means &quot;mechanically de-boned.&quot; The MDB machine is a huge Orwellian 
gadget that you feed chickens into, and viola!, on the other end, out 
comes the cooked, processed, mechanically de-boned, shaped, sized, 
chemically treated, flavored, fleshy little nuggets of profitmaking 
shit---yum! Nice machine...parts and pieces of head, feathers, guts, 
rot, feces, mice, insects, filth and disease and chemical flavoring 
all mixed together and cooked and shaped so the average (especially 
American average) person can dunk the result in more industrial waste 
and call it great...all without question or regard for one&apos;s own 
health!
Simple---if the ad told the truth, NO ONE would eat there. (Or is 
it &quot;their?&quot; Ask that &quot;straight A&quot; manager of a few posts prior).
I was gonna complain about the lousy food/service and the lack of 
hygiene, but since I don&apos;t speak Spanish, nobody would listen. Soon 
McDux will be hiring unemployed Arab pilots. Great complaint dept.
Wake up citizens! You are so easily duped by advertising, combined 
with your inability to cook or survive on your (you&apos;re??) own. 
Thanks Mommy! Thanks Dad! I&apos;m sure we can trust the government, 
though!
However, if they cooked-up some MDB terrorists, I would chow down!
PS: Some advice---if you wish to be understood, learn to spell! 
This topic is REALLY, REALLY serious...
PSS: &quot;Gonna&quot; IS a word. MY word...so fuck you! Eat a chicken!

-- Randall the Scandal ( rscan@earthlink.net ), September 29, 2001. Let&apos;s dig a little deeper, (if some of the more feeble minds can)...
Inside the food industry, Chicken McNuggets, or ANY similar product 
from a store or restaurant, is called &quot;MDB Chicken.&quot; MDB 
means &quot;mechanically de-boned.&quot; The MDB machine is a huge Orwellian 
gadget that you feed chickens into, and viola!, on the other end, out 
comes the cooked, processed, mechanically de-boned, shaped, sized, 
chemically treated, flavored, fleshy little nuggets of profitmaking 
shit---yum! Nice machine...parts and pieces of head, feathers, guts, 
rot, feces, mice, insects, filth and disease and chemical flavoring 
all mixed together and cooked and shaped so the average (especially 
American average) person can dunk the result in more industrial waste 
and call it great...all without question or regard for one&apos;s own 
health!
Simple---if the ad told the truth, NO ONE would eat there. (Or is 
it &quot;their?&quot; Ask that &quot;straight A&quot; manager of a few posts prior).
I was gonna complain about the lousy food/service and the lack of 
hygiene, but since I don&apos;t speak Spanish, nobody would listen. Soon 
McDux will be hiring unemployed Arab pilots. Great complaint dept.
Wake up citizens! You are so easily duped by advertising, combined 
with your inability to cook or survive on your (you&apos;re??) own. 
Thanks Mommy! Thanks Dad! I&apos;m sure we can trust the government, 
though!
However, if they cooked-up some MDB terrorists, I would chow down!
PS: Some advice---if you wish to be understood, learn to spell! 
This topic is REALLY, REALLY serious...
PSS: &quot;Gonna&quot; IS a word. MY word...so fuck you! Eat a chicken!

-- Randall the Scandal ( rscan@earthlink.net ), September 29, 2001. OOOOOPS! Sory about the dubble posts. Stoopid #$@$#@* co-workers, 
probbly. Or this allahdammed keyboard!!!!!!!!! Of course it&apos;z not 
ME! (I&apos;m two smart). I eat at McDonald&apos;s StyroFood For Numbnutz, 
and I&apos;m thinking about rELigIoN a lot lately... 
I leaned on the TAB key looking for my dictshunairy.

-- Randall the Scandal ( rscan@earthlink.net ), September 29, 2001. to all the people out there complaining about mcdonald&apos;s....i work at 
mcdonald&apos;s and i admit its not my favorite place but the reason is 
because of rude people like u. i am tired of slaving trying to serve
people like u who dont know what its like putting up with bullshit 
from customers who are never satisfied no matter what u do. people
like u need a reality check because no matter what ad or restuarant 
if u think its gonna be perfect or identical to the picture then u r
dillusional and u need serious help. and instead of bitching about 
stupid shit, you should be out there helping people in need. life is 
not perfect or like in the movies and as long as people keep fighting
over useless stupid shit its only gonna keep getting worse. word of 
advice : &quot;wise up and do some good for once instead of worrying about 
a stupid hamburger&quot;!

-- tina green ( ladybugg10111111@aol.com ), September 30, 2001. If you&apos;re saying that McDonalds lies because their photos don&apos;t look 
anything like the finished product, well that is just the way all 
restaurants are. I have yet to find a company (other than a car 
company) that actually sells a product that looks just like the ad. 
But, there is no excuse for the quality for the product and the 
rudeness of the employees which is why I choose not to eat there. 
The last time I did I got a burger with a sour tasting, greasy hair 
stuck right in the middle of the burger. The assistant manager was 
extremely rude and uncaring so to make a long story short, my lawyer 
was successful in getting the assistant manager fired along with two 
cooks, a formal apology letter and the health department was called 
in and I will never eat in any McDonalds ever again for as long as I 
live. Even other fast food restaurants are better than McDonalds in 
every way, even the bad ones. McDonalds is even the Worlds largest 
buyer of cow eyes. Hmm, I wonder what hamburger they put the cow eyes 
into. The sad thing is that these things just don&apos;t have to happen 
if most of the employees were paid and treated better and the 
managers cared...but they don&apos;t. Like I said, never ever again in my 
life will I ever eat at a McDonalds anywhere on the face of this 
planet.

-- Phil ( phil@Imsosure.com ), October 16, 2001. yes i will agree that the mc shit burgers 99% of the time swallows, 
yet look at the rest of the fast food chains. burger king taste like 
a large burnt piece of flame broiled coal. every time i bite into one 
i think i am nawing on coal. now wendys that burger has no taste, 
thats why they pile on the special dave&apos;s sauce and the square patty, 
how boring. jack in the box is sauced out also. taco bell, my god 
that stuff smells processed before you start nawing on it and you 
just fear what the end result will be. so now we have established 
that all of the above chains do not have a high grade of food 
product, what do they offer. quick and cheap, in a society that 
demands speed, they are some what quicker that the average 
restaurant, not always giving the best of service. then again what 
restaurant does unless you have an owner or materde 6 ft. up the 
waitstaffs ass insuring that all of the clients butts resemble a 
tissue at the local lipstick counter by the end of the evening.the 
staff at these fast food chains are for the most part underpaid and 
some if not alot don&apos;t give a shit about insuring quality. do you 
really expect mgrs to motivate underpaid employees to produce a 
product that even closely resembles a photo that some ad agency in a 
foo foo surrounding spent days producing and color enhancing with 
computers.not to mention they have 8 cars waiting in the drive thru 
with about 2.5 people per car and oh about 15 people waiting at the 
front counter. we all just become an assembly line. if you do then 
you have the brain capacity of the roach that was just nuke in the 
microwave with the burger you just bought.these ads are sellers, they 
attract, kinda of like flowers to insects. and i imagine some of the 
insects have ended up in my burgers. the best ads and gimicks attract 
the most consumers and its a war zone, they are working the #&apos;s and 
they figure a certain % will get pissed and never come back, yet the 
rest might like them because of the yellow archs. it sound stupid, 
but color does have a great deal to do with attracting the customers. 
lets talk about cleanliness, the mac d&apos;s play ground area with the 
climb through thing is nothing more than a host house for bacteria. 
which i would imagine at the end of the day the staff scraps off and 
adds to the next days secert sauce. sick kids play and sneeze and 
spit and yes i imagine some have lets just say accidently pissed and 
#2&apos;d in these things or braf&apos;d. then your little johney or sue or 
what ever you vocally id your offspring by - walk, play and then come 
running to the table to begin consuming those wonderful crappy happy 
meals which i might ad for the most part have chocking hazard 
toys,their hands covered with the bacteria from the play area. do 
you honestly think those play areas have been cleaned on a regular 
basis. hell lets go out on a limb ( EVER ), vegas would take those 
odds. the part about employees placing food that has fallen onto the 
ground back onto the grill, happens alot. i worked in the restaurant 
business for a while, it happens even in the best restaurants. how 
can you expect someone who does not pratice cleanliness in their own 
home to come to work and say gee! i&apos;m a pig at home, but i will be 
squeeky here. get real. its not going to happen. the mgrs are ran 
into the ground by corp by working about 75 hours a week and are 
again underpaid. yes they chose that job.one thing you have to relize 
is that they may be slinging a lot of happy meals out of these 
places, yet the overall att. is not that happy. but the bottom line 
is when its really late and you have had some cocktails and you are 
on the way home w/ the munchines, these dumps we call restaurants and 
complain about on a regular basis have food that taste damn good 
about 2:30am. p.s i almost forgot one, what a burger, i will have to 
say for the most part they have the best burger, fries taste like 
shit tho.

-- bobsnard ( bobsnard@aol.com ), October 18, 2001. There is so much bullshit in america!!!!!!!
there have been hundreds of thousads of people who have died in wars 
just to give all of us the gift of choice.
if you hate it dont buy it, if you want to say it just fuckin say it,
And if you dont you dont like it go fuck yourself..................

-- Jose Perez ( poonking69@hotmail.com ), October 19, 2001. McDonalds lie in their ads. Oh my God, what have you been doing for 
the majority of your life to think that ads tell the truth?
Yes, the food is bad. But its better here in the UK and Europe becuase 
of EU cattle restrictions ( no implants, etc etc ), so the meat here 
is a lot safer. The problems caused are because of the American 
attitude to profit over health.
The fact that the majority of responses to this argument are 
semi-literate worries me. Speaking from personal experience, I haven&apos;t 
eaten a McDonalds for about 5 years. It can be done. If we all voted 
with our wallets and feet then McDonalds would have to do something.
The majority of people working in McDonalds round here ( in the UK ) 
are around my age (17) and 4.25 ( about 7 dollars an hour ). That is 
above the rate where I work ( about 5 dollars an hour ).
To sum... eh, you get what you

-- Arthmelow ( Arthmelow@excite.com ), October 31, 2001. McDoucher&apos;s sucks ASS! I used to work there and they fired me &apos;cause I 
gave the McFinger to this bitchassmotherfucken pig I know whose name is 
scott deninger. He&apos;s a flamer. And those fucken McYokels fired me! 
McDammit!! McFuck those bastards in the McFucken ass!!!! KILL THE 
CLOWN!! The only difference between Ronald and Hitler is that you can&apos;t 
see Ronald&apos;s McMustache.

-- Phil McCrevis ( dicklips_blink182@hotmail.com ), November 01, 2001. YEAH! MOTHERFUCKEN MRS. PRESTON IS A GODDAMN WHORE! IF YOU WANT TO 
CONTACT THIS FAT SACK OF SHIT, SHE WORKS AT BATESVILLE HIGH SCHOOL, 
BATESVILLE, IN 47006. YOU MIGHT WANT TO PACK A WAEPON. SHE ATE TOO 
MUCH BEEF AT THE McFAT FARM AND SHE ROLLS WHEREVER SHE GOES. OH YEAH!

-- Phil McCrevis ( dicklips_blink182@Hotmail.com ), November 01, 2001. Hey I should also mention that while I was employed at the golden shit 
factory, I once witnessed a manager (Chrissy Schene, Batesville, IN 
47006) rapin the shit out of Darrell Walls. He had third degree burns 
on his ass from the grill and he was screamin but she wouldn&apos;t stop 
because she weighs 500 fucken pounds. I had sex with the managers too, 
but not that forcefully. Damn that was some fucken nasty shit, watchin 
all that fucken fat flyin around. Looked like a fucken huge big mac on 
a rollercoaster, with the steam from Darrell&apos;s burin ass on the grill 
fillin up the whole damn kitchen. She made him promise to never tell 
or she&apos;d fire him. Not a big deal, right? Wrong. Darrell&apos;s family is 
poor and they need the money so he had to stay. No one else in town 
would employ him because he is handicapped and mentally retarded. This 
is a sick fucken crime and a goddamn shame. It should not go 
unpunished. DOWN WITH THE CLOWN! (And those fat-bitch-retard-cripple-
raping manager pigs too)

-- Phil McCrevis ( dicklips_blink182@hotmail.com ), November 01, 2001. Fuck all you stupid hippie shits! McDonalds is cool

-- Todd Burr ( pubicdandruff@aol.com ), November 02, 2001. FUCK RONALD, FUCK HIM IN THE ASS WITH A BIG RUBBER DICK, AND THEN BREAK 
THE REST OFF AND BEAT HIM WITH IT YA FILL-THY CUM SUCKING BASTRARDS, 
EAT THE SHIT THAT FALLS OUT MY ASS YOU RED HEAD PRICK.
SHAWN LEE HARTFORD MADE LOVE TO THERESA MARIE DAGENBACH ON HER BED, ON 
HER FLOOR, IN THE BATHTUB.
SUCK ME PECKER AND STICK IT IN YER&apos; ASS YAH FUCKIN&apos; HONKY.
BEAT ME WITH A RUBBER GLOVE, AND STRETCH THE SHIT BETWEEN MY 
MOTHERFUCKIN ASS YOU SHALLOW CUNT!!!

-- shawn hartford ( kzoguy11@hotmail.com ), November 02, 2001. BLOW ME MCDONALDS, FUCKIN&apos; BLOW ME.

-- Gay Lord Fucker ( kzoguy11@hotmail.com ), November 05, 2001. SARAH SHOENTRUP... GIVES HEAD REAL GOOD, DAMN U WISH U HAD HER. SHE 
GONNA BE THE NEXT COYOTE UGLY CHICK, ONLY NUDE!! DAMN, IF THAT AIN&apos;T 
ENOUGH, WELL THEN SHE WILL FUCK THE SHIT OUTTA U!!! EMAIL HER AT 
PIMPLOVER420@YAHOO.COM

-- Harry Sacks ( kzoguy11@hotmail.com ), November 05, 2001. HEY RONALD...BLOW ME

-- scrotum bob ( kzoguy11@hotmail.com ), November 05, 2001. ha ha ha ha ha ha!!!!!!! shawn you slay me 
FUCK MCDONALDS!!!!!!!
this website is mine now biotch
come lick my testicles slut and play me a song!
bend over backwards and smoke me like a bong!
suck on my wang whore and call it a wong!
everybitch loves my dick it is so long!
ha ha suck my McDick

-- Michael Rotch ( dicklips_blink182@hotmail.com ), November 05, 2001. ...BITCH

-- shawns shlong ( kzoguy11@epals.com ), November 05, 2001. stick your dick in a leaf blower and get some free head!
Sick_Tips.com

-- big scones magoo ( fuckyouandyourbitchassmommatoo@hotmail.com ), November 06, 2001. theresa dagenbach
sarah shoentrup
trista gunter
angela lewis
jenny ramsey
lindsay cutter
jenny kerker
jacklyn hunter
ashley panter
heather oliver
leslie marticke
karen werner
lisa tran
kelli herbert
jessica gilette
amy feller
jenni vonderheide
tricia thornsberry

i fucked all these sluts and you can too!
1-800-free-fuk

-- george jefferson ( supa_pimp_69@aol.com ), November 06, 2001. You dumb bitch, you didn&apos;t fuck any of them you cum sucker, you haven&apos;t 
had your dick in anything but a dog.

-- Harry Sacks ( budtoker420@matchmaker.com ), November 07, 2001. Yous&apos; a dumb bitch, you didn&apos;t fuck any of them you cum sucker, you 
haven&apos;t 
had your dick in anything but a dog

-- Harry Sacks ( turn-your-head-and-cough@hotmail.com ), November 07, 2001. Blow my beanbag you ass knob. Stop being a hoser and lick the chode 
off my hair on my ass!!!!!!
P.S. you&apos;re a douche bag

-- Phil McCrevis and Mike Rotch ( blunts4bitches@eatmydick.com ), November 08, 2001. i have no problem with mickey d&apos;s BUT after reading all this shit, im 
having 2nd thoughts!! i just have to say...coporate lies for 
advertising and money so dont be shocked when u c something out of 
place!

-- sandra ( cgigles324@aol.co, ), November 17, 2001. i just found this website by accident, and i needed to write all of 
you. IF U DONT LIKE MC&apos;Ds, THEN DONT GO!!!!!!!!!!!! Im amazed that 
all the people that dont have better things to do than make a f&apos;n 
site to bash MC&apos;Ds. GET A LIFE.

-- todd ireland ( tireland72@aol.com ), November 18, 2001. Amen Todd Ireland!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

-- Lindz ( skad_star@yahoo.com ), November 19, 2001. ROTTON RONNIES IS GREAT. I LOVE GOING THERE AND EATING SOME OF THEIR 
QUALITY FOOD.
THANKS RONNIE, I LOVE PUKING OUT OF MY ASS FOR THREE FUCKING 
HOURS!!!!!!!!
P.S. WHEN I HAD A BIRTHDAY PARTY WITH RONNIE HE TRIED TO TOUCH ME
THEN HE STARTED FONDLING THE FRYGUYS.

-- iloveuRONNIE!!!!! ( ron@shit.com ), November 19, 2001. it was by accident that i got this site. and i must say those of you 
that are so free with your critisim of Mcdonalds, you really need 
some serious reality checks. Have you ever bothered to ask for the 
nutrition booklets that they have. Do you have a clue, obvsiouly not. 
I wourked for McDonald&apos;s for nearly 19years. and to read some of the 
junk you people call comments, is not even close. If you have never 
worked there or even taken the time to read anything but the funny 
papers you might have just a small bit of insite as to what 
Mcdonalds is and has been for many years. 
 It is a company that stands for the best and believs in going that 
extra mile for the customer. and for you little whiners, that may 
have worked there and did not like it , you must have been in need of 
a few basic lessons on responsibility. The amount of learning tools 
and the mgt that the company has goes above and beyond. Obviously you
were one of those that could not recognize a customer and needed to 
sell shoes. Had it not been for the standards that i got from 
Mcdonalds i would not have known what a rest. chain was suppose to 
offer. It is now and has always been a company for it&apos;s people and 
it&apos;s customers. 
As for the people being illirate. Guess again. Most have college and 
a lot have it because the company paid for it and allowed thier 
people the time to go. So if you have not honestly tried it don&apos;t 
knock it. GET A LIFE. MCDONALDS DOES NOT LIE. TO BAD YOU ARE TO 
ARRAGANT TO SEE REALITY. I WOULD WORK FOR THE COMPANY AGAIN ANY TIME 
ANY PLACE. IT IS THE BEST AND NONE CAN COME CLOSE.

-- fran oppelt ( etrahar@aol.com ), November 20, 2001. Hey fran, what a loser you must be to have worked at McDoucher&apos;s for 19 
years! I&apos;m laughing my ass off right now! I worked there for half a 
year and I know how bad they suck so shut up with your &quot;arrogant 
consumers&quot; shit. No one cares. (Also--learn how to spell, you fucking 
inbred!)

-- Ben Lickenia ( TheKing@cockfeather.com ), November 26, 2001. This is the funniest fucking content on the Internet. Thanks, guys!

-- master blaster ( mb@gti.net ), November 28, 2001. I was dining in a McDonalds restaurant about 2 months ago and 
witnessed something horrrrrible. This guy was talking to some girl 
about how his dick was all big, and she was like &apos;whatever, pull it 
out!&apos;. Anyway, after many more &apos;pull it out&apos; taunts, this guy did the 
unthinkable. Yes, he &apos;pulled *it* out&apos;, put it right in this girls 
face, swung it around a &apos;lil, said &apos;see!&apos; and then proceeded to run 
out of the restaurant. This is hardly the dining experience I would 
like to replicate and I have therefore decided to boycott mcdonalds.
Not to mention McDonald&apos;s menu is loaded with calories, fat, and 
cholesterol, but the real story behind the burgers, chicken nuggets, 
and egg sandwiches is the awful lives and cruel deaths of the animals 
whose bodies wind up sold alongside plastic toys.
Cheers!
*BIG* Don Imus

-- Don Imus ( brew@eurocompton.net ), November 28, 2001. Fox news reported a McDonalds employee getting pissed off at a 
customer at the drivethru and throwing a cup of hot coffee on him and 
his son. I saw the woman being lead away in handcuffs on the news. 
The news snippit ran too fast for me to see what city this happened 
in. Anyone else hear this? Can I get some details? If McDonalds 
will pay some looser a million bucks for spilling coffee on himself, 
what the hell is this worth?

-- Lee Liska ( laliska@netzero.net ), November 29, 2001. WHEN I SEE MCDONALDS EMPLOYEE, I GET ANGER, I SHOUT, &quot;HE IS FUCKMAN!&quot; 
I SAY FUCKMAN FOR KILL BABY ANIMALS, THERE EAT, HAHA DICKS

-- fuckman ( redsky@aol.com ), November 30, 2001. this is mad fucking gay and you are all fucking 
queer6666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666

-- jeff jones ( jeffjones@hotmail.com ), December 03, 2001. this is mad fucking gay and you are all fucking 
queer6666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666
666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666666

-- jeff jones ( jeffjones35@hotmail.com ), December 03, 2001. I THINK THE SOONER MC-DAMN-SHIT-CURDLING FOOD STOPS GLOBALISING THERE 
MASS CAPITALIST PROPAGANDA THE BETTER.ITS COMPLETE EXSTORTIONISM AND 
EXPLOITATONISM: PREYING ON THE WEAK CONFormISTS just wont 
do.ignorant, insicure uncultured ,cloned ,american bum-suckers ( 
EXSPECIALY AMERICANS-DUMB BELIGERANT FUCKUPS)open your fucking eyes 
and stop destroying the world american greed monging nazi descendants
bin larden hurry up and nuke america

-- TYSKY AIROV ( BOLSHEVICS@BTOPENWORLD.COM ), December 04, 2001. I totaly agree that you food is nasty at McDonalds. I should know I 
have been working there for over a year but for those of you who 
stero-type the employees are very wrong!!!! I do not hvae green hair 
i have one piercing and that is in my ears and I am working to pay 
off some of my college I have my doctorit and I am specializing in 
pediatric surgery right now!!!!! how many of you out there can say 
that for yourselves!!!!! as a Dr. i can say that the food is eddible 
but not healthy but then again anything deep fried is not healthy. If 
you don&apos;t like it don&apos;t eat it i certainly don&apos;t!!!!

-- sorry no tell ( kimmy_joy_02@hotmail.com ), December 04, 2001. i belive the majority of the people whop have listed their complants 
have to much time on their hands, and probably need to get a job 
themselves, if you have a problem with an establishment such as 
mcdonalds just stop going there. spend more time with your children, 
and less time wasting your time on pointless websites such as this one
the only reason im wasting my time here is to help your children by 
trying to get you to stop wasting your time, please find a cure for 
a diease or something, get off your yuor probably over fed ass and go 
to the park.

-- brian j. meastes ( egroj_tqm@yahoo.com ), December 04, 2001. Those RAT BASTARDS at mcdonalds lied to the american public for a 
year about there BS contests. They knew for a year no one really had 
a chance to win, yet they continued with it any way. They made a big 
profit off all the people going there to play. Do you know how they 
repay them?!??!?!?!?!? There was someone who won the 1,ooo,ooo$ prize 
in ohio and mcdonalds said it was cool at first, than turned around 
and said the serial number didn&apos;t match the 1,000,000$ prize! They 
sent this person 5 mcdollars! lol What crooks!!!!
You noticed the bastards aint running any promotions and wont be 
until their stupid asses resolve this. They should have from the 
beginning now if they even think of holding a contest the lawyers is 
going to go on every news show with this. Right now it isn&apos;t of 
interest to the public, but it will be if they try another bullshit 
contest.
By the way, the original ticket was &quot;destroyed&quot;! I guess they were 
hoping this person didn&apos;t have it noterized!!!!!
They are crooks and frauds, all the money they made for a year off 
the &quot;fake&quot; promotion and they couldn&apos;t straighten out onw mistake. I 
personally know the person and hope they take it to a jury trial and 
RAPE mcdonalds!!!

-- They are crooks ( notna12@hotmail.com ), December 05, 2001. A McDonald employee here in Sweden told me that the small &quot;holes&quot;
or indentions at the back of the bun into wich the hamburger is 
put is actually &quot;mold holes&quot; because the McDonalds buys thousands upon 
thousands of buns to a reduced rate!

-- Jan Sundberg ( jan.sundberg@bahnhof.se ), December 09, 2001. my name is casey chelson and i want to screw grimmace

-- casey chelson ( Cchelson@hotmail.com ), December 10, 2001. Tim torrini is a FUCKING FAGGOT!!!!! HE HAS FUCKED GRIMMACE IN THE 
ASS MANY TIMES!!!!!

-- tim torrini ( sedfcasd@uygdu.com ), December 10, 2001. i appoligize he did not screw grimmace!!! but he still likes him!

-- kurt olson ( poopoo@hotmail.com ), December 10, 2001. cowboys butts drive me nuts

-- caset chelson ( manlover@bigdick.com ), December 10, 2001. Because they don&apos;t live up to there promises. Duh!

-- D L Lewis ( debsbillserv@netscape.net ), December 11, 2001. your some snake. I used work in McDonalds dont tell any 
one !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

-- Jim Bob Jones ( jimbob@hotmail.com ), December 11, 2001. MCD&apos;S is a fast food place.WHAT DO YOU EXPECT????WHAT ARE YOU DOING 
ON THIS WEB SITE TALKING ABOUT MCD&apos;S???BETTER YET ,WHAT I&apos;M I DOING??
I MUST BE REALLY BORED TO READ THIS CRAP!!!!!!

-- adam ( sapwood8@aol.com ), December 14, 2001. I would have to say if your defending McDonalds you have to be the 
stupidest fucks ever, so please do me a favor and get a fucken life! 
Thats all I have to say about that!

-- Britt ( bolson46@hotmail.com ), December 17, 2001. McDonalds just SUCKS!!! I worked there for a two and a half years. I 
found that Mcdonalds is noting but one big lie!! It was the worst 
place I have ever worked. Not only do they not care if they see you 
smile, but they don&apos;t even care if you get food poisioning!! Screw 
the whole corporatuion, because they screwed me!! I was a hourly 
manager and was promised a promotion for over 9 months. When it came 
down to it, they gave it to someone who had only worked there for 3 
months!! I ent over backwards to kiss thier asses, and all I got was 
alot of BULLSHIT!!

-- becky downs ( freakytoker@hotmail.com ), December 20, 2001. It is a bi mcRIPPOFF! I ordered 2 McChicken sandwiches to take to 
work late and so the damned things wouldnt take on a likeness to some 
kind of toxic mess asked that no sauce be put on, ok no prob! but 
when I asked for tauter or mayo on the side they fricken charged me 
95 cents for a shot of tauter(I worked for the clown when i was a 
kid! thats how I know they use oversized caulk guns to shoot the 
ooozzzz on thier products,so i got a shot/ a shot of tauter in a 
clear cup that maybe would suffice one sandwich) what the hell a 
clear plastic cup costs a buck WOW must be a better value than the 
toxic value meals they are selling, by the way look at the cost of a 
sloppy thrown together VALUE meal and really think is this a real 
value? ok here is the deal!!! we have a choice to walk in the door or 
drive to the window,ive chosen in the last year not to do either they 
lost customers with me and my family, ya we are impatient as a 
country, BUT i think people are finally tired of getting ripped off 
not just the clown but B.K and hardees(extremely slow service) ct 
Wendys do have a decent value menue but order a meal for a family of 
4 WOW now concider a chick. sand. at almost 5$ doesnt add up to me! 
can now take my family to an mom and pop diner/or FAMILY restaraunt 
pay just a bit more maybe a buck or 2 sometimes get all you can eat 
and see the value (CAUSE I AM NOT PAYING FOR THE PAPER BAG/WRAPPINGS 
FRY BOXES/ECT that clutterour roadsides)oh yea dont forget those 
supersized/biggie/valuesized drink containers cups laying wverywhere 
OH that isnt the fault of the restaraunts ITS nonthinking bastards 
who throw it out the window! we all hve the choice to say NO but 
convienance and people just being lazy LAZY and chugging down deep 
fried fatty junk food no wonder why so many people are overweight 
hell they got a mcD deepfryer for a gut! and just what the mchell is 
in the mcChicken anyway? last time I ate a real chicken the meat 
texture didnt look like a sponge THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU EAT BECAUSE YOU 
ARE WHAT YOUE EAT besides heart attacks really suck!

-- just me ( deano32@earthlink.net ), December 20, 2001. I worked at McDonald&apos;s for a year when I was a teenager. It is 
the most frustrating, horrible job you can imagine. At $5.25
I slaved behind the counter as people yelled and screamed at me 
while all I could do is smile and try to fix the problems
that naturally came from working there. The managers yell at 
you as you strive to make the food, as the line grows incessently
and you beleive you will get a break and you ask if you can have one 
and the manager says: &quot;NO! You see that line, We&apos;ve got to get 
that out!&quot; I would make the greasy, grimy food for hours and hours,
no breaks, or when I would finally get one, I would have to go
right back to the slave pit. It&apos;s hot in the back and stressful.
You make the food as fast as you can, and it&apos;s never fast enough. 
Each order comes and when there is a let down, you clean, clean clean.
We had to clean the disgusting toilets! I had to go on garbage detail 
and litter patrol in the parking lot and mop the floors and wash the 
tables. And then my friends would show up and laugh and tease me. I 
dropped that job! McDonald&apos;s is indeed a horrible place. Work there 
for a month and find out. Look at your paycheck and realize how hard 
you trully work. So little for all that slave labor they make you do.
And the uniforms invite swarthy comments. Watch your server how they 
seem frustrated by the length of their shift, the time is endless. An 
8 hour shift at McDonald&apos;s is awful! 2 ten minute breaks which half 
the time you never get, and 1 measly horrible half hour lunch! No 
wonder we were so inclined to eat there. Not only do you suffer under 
the slavery whip of what you are actually making, you eat it too.
I could not stand it anymore, so I found a retail job, which paid 
twice as much. So much for that. I promise after each cleaning job I 
ALWAYS washed my hands. But again be nice to that poor human being on 
the other side of the counter! They have had a hard day. Anytime you 
work with food, where you have to hurry and you try and try to meet 
the demands on you and deal with mean people who yell at you. Just 
remember that Mcdonald&apos;s managers treat the employees like crap as do 
a long list of customers. Indeed Mcdonald&apos;s is a bad place.
Peace!

-- Mike Rasmussen ( No email@I value my privacy.com ), December 21, 2001. Some more about my Mcdonald&apos;s experiences. When you where that crappy 
uniform, you look like a peice of crap. You have to always where a 
hat and your manager always watches to see if you smile.
If you don&apos;t smile you get yelled at and written up. SO when you are 
getting yelled at by a customer all you can do is stand there and
we were taught to say, &quot;Im sorry, Ill fix that right away!&quot; The 
Mcdonald&apos;s I worked in had a tally sheet to see that we answered that 
way every time. We were supposed to nod when yelled at even if we 
wanted to swear at them. Then we would scurry around and try to fix 
it, although the person on the other side always has complete control.
That is the way Mcdonald&apos;s wants it. The employee has no rights while 
on the job, the public comes first. Can&apos;t you tell by what they wear?
Look at the uniform? It is so ugly! McDonald&apos;s makes their uniforms 
that way to make their employees look like serfs. The worst is when 
you are making the food. I worked at a McDonald&apos;s that wanted us to 
wear an apron while we worked with the public and in the back. It used 
to be that only the food preparation crew wore the aprons, Our manager 
wanted us to look uniform. It was the ugliest outfit I ever wore.
We looked like little slaves. I had to wear a green shirt, green hat, 
black pants and dress shoes! Dress shoes! I once wore my tennis 
shoes and my manager yelled at me for that! I would sweat constantly 
as I ran to and fro trying to please the host of people that wanted 
food. When you were behind the register people would just stare at 
you and treat you like crap when they finally got to the front of the 
line. They would scream, you screwed up my order! and I was not the 
one who MADE the order, it was my retard coworker who makes me suffer 
the wrath of this customer and on cue, I say, &quot;Ma&apos;am or Sir, I will 
fix that right away!&quot; Then they would shout, &quot;well hurry up!&quot; &quot;Chop 
Chop, I can&apos;t wait all day.&quot; I would lumber to the back and fix the 
order myself. Then come back and deal with another person who can&apos;t 
make up their mind and then it slows down, and i find myself lugging 
garbage out to the corner or cleaning the frier, (a dastardly awful 
experience). Scrubbing the damn thing and then trying to wash it. 
All the while your sweating and then you get your lunch break of a 
half hour and you hate the food. You hate the situation. The 
managers would always understaff us. Once I was the only one 
preparing the food for a line of 30 people. Actually, I was making 
the burgers and my coworker was trying to do the fries, he had only 
been on the job 2 days! You getting the picture of the horror of 
McDonald&apos;s? And then I would watch as my coworker&apos;s would make a 
burger and NOT wash their hands. YUCK! I have seen some strange 
stuff! I leave you knowledge that I have not eaten at McDonald&apos;s 
since I quit the job. May you all be wise and avoid this horror of 
horror&apos;s. I could tell you about all the stuff I found while trying 
to make the bathrooms presentable. SUCKS! I hated that job.

-- Mike Rasmussen ( Its just me@I have more to add.com ), December 21, 2001. listen buddy mcdonalds is a good food company if you thin k you can 
serve 100 custumors that are as dumb ass you in 10 minutes i would 
like to see it but if you cant well maybe you should just shut up!
and if you wanna compete angainst them you can try but 
a&amp;w;,harveys,burgerking,etc, also tried and who is still on top ! 
yes the answher is correct MCDONALDS!!
if you can invent a 21 billion dollar company! call me
!

-- steve ( blaze@hotmail.com ), December 23, 2001. As you can see my many arrows have brought you to the top. An 
advertising ploy is well overused by some, such as McDonald&apos;s. Now 
we see how it works, although the product sucks. I realized this 
from the message of a freakin&apos; gigalo who had no idea of this 
revolutionary concept. For more pearls of wisdom you may scroll back 
to see some more of the things that I have said. 
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
1
Wanna see what I have to say go to the top.

-- Eric Bentley ( PIFFJAW@AOL.COM ), December 23, 2001. Ever notice mcShitheads ad&apos;s never have anything to do with wether 
the food tastes good or not?
its always ronald macshitheads or some prefab vision of a macdonalds 
utopia world.
Mac grimace or whatever,cheese burglar
all meant to deflect attention away from the fact the food looks and 
tastes fucking awfull!!!
If u rarely eat the shit,it realy is disgusting to eat...
I think that if teens and brainwashed adults actually think this shit 
looks and tastes like real food,its because they eat so much 
Mcdonalds/BurgerKing/whatever that theyve forgotten what a real 
burger and fries tastes like,so the Macshithead food tastes normal!
There&apos;s places in every neighbourhood where u can get a decent burger
(that isnt the color of a gravestone (grey)and its on a bun that isnt 
like a used Kotex napkin) and real fries someone actually cut the 
same day u eat them.
but then u might not get your food in 7 seconds as its actually 
cooked for u.
and what a miracle! u can actually say &apos;i only want mustard and 
onions on that without having to wait 15 minutes while the fucking 
assembly line retools for your order!
The whole &apos;Mcdonalds&apos; culture thats been carefully produced by the mc-
shitheads marketing armies has nothing to do with the food,,,
the food&apos;s just a necessary evil to get you to part with your cash..
its about being a corporate whore with the likes of wal-mart...or 
tying in with every fucking movie and sporting event known to mankind 
as long as they can make a buck on it...
Its about idiotic mascots (i firmly believe ronald mc-shithead is the 
anti-christ:)
its about &apos;brand marketing&apos;so the kids will only ever want to go to 
mcdonalds
not because the food tastes like fucking food...but thats what theyve 
been brainwashed to believe is the normal thing to do,,
and when they have kids of their own they will already be part of the 
mcdonalds cult....
its sad the the umpteenth degree...

-- Davinci5156 ( davinci5156@hotmail.com ), December 26, 2001. Mcdonalds is your kinda place
they serve you rattlesnakes
stick raw pickles up your nose
serve french fries between your toes 
My brother ordered a chocolate shake
they served him a polluted lake
Mcdonalds is your kinda place 
they serve you rattle snakes

-- Smokey Mc Pot ( eepee123@excite.com ), January 07, 2002. You sad little fucks, If any of you had any balls you&apos;d admit that 
any one who goes into Mcdonalds&apos; CHOSES to go into mcdonalds- there 
is no man with a gun &quot;escorting&quot; you to the front door and forcing 
you to order and eat- same thing goes for smokers - you are the one 
who is chosing and making the action of picking up the cigerette 
lighting the lighter and smoking the thing- just put it down- JUST 
PUT IT DOWN! In this if you don&apos;t like it- don&apos;t buy it!IF you hate 
it- find a real reason to complain to mcdonalds- not enviro-bull-
shit, not animal cruelty, not &quot;product of capitalism&quot; offense&quot; 
Sheesh who taught you to think?

-- Doug ( NOONE@theglobe.com ), January 14, 2002. I WISH ALL YOU HEARTLESS PEOPLE WOULD FOR ONCE STOP WORRYING ABOUT 
YOUR BELLYS AND THINK ABOUT THE SICK ,BARBARIC GOINGS ON BEHIND THE 
SCENES .HAS NOBODY BEEN BROUGHT UP TO CARE ABOUT ANIMALS.DOES NOBODY 
THINK THAT ANIMALS HAVE A RIGHT TO LIFE THE SAME AS US,DOES NOBODY 
THINK THIS IS A SICK COMPANY.I WISH BEFORE PEOPLE BOUGHT ANYTHING 
FROM THERE THEY WERE MADE TO SEE INSIDE AN ABATOIRE THEN MAYBE 
PEOPLE MIGHT CHANGE THEYRE GREEDY IGNORANT MINDS.
SORRY FOR SOUNDING HARSH.

-- rebecca gilman ( beckydarlin@bigfat 69.freeserve.co.uk ), January 24, 2002. ok well your order of two things should only take us like a week 
from friday

-- i isa not that stupido ( rhwc0001@aol.com ), January 24, 2002. One day everyone will be insane,then if you are one of the few who 
arent insane,they will run up to u and shout &apos;you are not like 
us,therefore u must be insane!&apos; &apos;Lock him up!&apos;
and lets furthur suppose that the next morning the hundreth monkey 
suddenly learned to peel spuds.
and in closing,if i didnt have cheeze,like,everyday,would you still 
want me?

-- Simone Smelton ( davinci@worstwitch.every1.net ), January 25, 2002. visit FUCKMCDONALDS.CO.UK NOW

-- McDonalds 001 Woolich ( 00001@mcdonalds.co.uk ), January 30, 2002. MCDONALDS IS GOOD FOR THE PRICE. REMEMBER YOU GET WHAT YOU PAY FOR. 
AND I WANNA KNOW WHO DOESN&apos;T LIE IN THEIR ADS? I HAVE NEVER SEEN ANY 
FAST FOOD THAT LOOKED LIKE THEIR ADS. WHY ARE YA BEIN SO HARD ON 
MCDONALDS? ITS OBVIOUSLY NOT THAT BAD, ITS THE NUMBER ONE FAST FOOD 
PLACE IN AMERICA! IF YA WANT TO BITCH WE COULD TALK ABOUT CAPTAIN 
D&apos;S. EVERYTIME I GO THERE ICAN BE THE ONLY ONE IN LINE AND STILL WAIT 
45 MINUTES. SO LEAVE MCDONALDS ALONE. I LIKE IT AND SO DO MY KIDS!

-- MICHELLE DAVIS ( CHELLEIGH79@AOL.COM ), February 03, 2002. Listen, I&apos;ve sat here and read all this BS and to you who CLAIM to 
have worked or are working at McD&apos;s If all that was going on ie. 
sweat on burgers, dirty grills and ovens employees not washing hands 
etc. You remember you were/are there also you could stop it. 
Another thing ALL states have a state health department ! and they do 
make stops at ALL resturaunts and grade them.That would be those 
alphabet leters you see on the doors when you enter DUH. The 
resturaunts are NOT warned ahead of time of the visits so if the 
stores were as you say they would definately be SHUT DOWN. Make sure 
you have your facks straight. And to all of you who complain about 
poor service etc. I&apos;m willing to bet money you have never worked in 
fast food. Come to MY MCDONALDS i&apos;ll be happy to give you an 
application right along with all the other complainers that enter my 
store.
My store is not only inspected by the state but also by the federal 
govermant because it is located on a military base. And we all know 
how anal retentive the military is. 
My store is the cleanest store in my area. We date all products and 
serve only what we ourselves would be willing to eat. 
So before you take a BITE out of McDonalds think about the meals you 
prepare in your homes for your families when you don;t wash your 
hands, or spill a ciggarette ash in the food, or scratch your butt 
then chop that tomatoe, or drink the milk from the carton and return 
it to the fridge. 
You would be amazed at what steps Mcdonalds goes to, to provide the 
Best for their customers, Sure you can have bad experiences we have 
those everywhere we go. But don;t make an Ass of yourself standing at 
the counter or posting childish remarks on a web site. Grow up act 
your age and get a life. And if you think you can do the job 
better, Then FILL OUT AN APPLICATION. We pay well ! 
And we are always looking for good HONEST help. 
If you want it to be the best then MAKE IT THE BEST .

-- M mooney ( Boss7774@yahoo.com ), February 08, 2002. It seems this thread has been defiled by people whom aren&apos;t aware 
enough to realize they are wasting thier time and our time posting 
opinions without any real substance. I don&apos;t really expect this to be 
any more effective in persuading those of you that have nothing more 
to say than &quot;fuck&quot; and &quot;you are gay&quot; and long pages of spam that it 
is probably past your bed time. I assume you have school in the 
morning. This is not aimed toward those of you that actually gave 
opposition without sounding like a 12 year old kid that just learned 
how to swear.

-- Ryan Capistrant ( nayr@place.com ), February 18, 2002. m mooney this is for you. Yes I have worked in fast food before my 
first job was burger king and about a year ago I worked at arby&apos;s. 
 The source of my discontent derives from the quality of the food 
itself thus I haven&apos;t eaten the stuff for about 4 years now. But if 
that was the only thing I despised about fast food and Mc Carcass 
then I wouldn&apos;t even post. The fact of the matter is your corporation 
owns and is owned by corporations that are responsible for numerous 
atrocities worldwide thus making them responsible in the Charles 
Manson/Hitler sense of responsibility. As well as sucking up the 
wealth of small town after small town by undercutting prices. Small 
buisness cannot take those kinds of hits. I&apos;ve wittnessed this my 
whole life. I really hope that you are aware of what I am talking 
about and even more that you would be able to admit it if you were. 
But if you want validation of these things I say I can dig for it and 
post it or give you information for how to find it yourself.

-- ryan capistrant ( nayr@place.com ), February 18, 2002. Check out McSPOTLIGHT.com chock fulla stuff

-- ryan capistrant ( nayr@place.com ), February 18, 2002. Why is everyone cursing at each other for their opinions about their
experience with McDonalds and other fast foods. Everyone who post
their message has the choice to vent their anger on their EXPERIENCE
with the fast food chain. We are not here to judge or criticize one
another. The most important thing is get your facts straight before
you blast a company. Don&apos;t go by what you hear, go by what you know to
be the factual truth. It is time for all of us to agree to disagree
and be respectful not disresprectful of each other&apos;s responses. I do
not eat at Mcdonalds or any other fast food because it is my choice. I
have every right to make that decision. I do not allow my children to
each at McDonalds. First of all the majority of the food is chemically
enhanced and deep fried. Eating fried foods isn&apos;t good for anybody.
Too much dough is not good for us either. Bottom line is fast food
will eventually make you fat. Most people who eat fast food don&apos;t feel
like or have the time to go home to cook anyway (I have been guilty of
that in the past too.)

-- Errica B Hutty ( erricah@msn.com ), February 19, 2002. McDonalds is good ......if you dont like it then dont eat their and 
shut up so the rest of us who want to can

-- katrina thompson ( S_****8@hotmail.com ), February 20, 2002. YOUR OBVIOUSLY GAY

-- PooPoo Mcnealy ( wilby24@yahoo.com ), March 01, 2002. I think the NcDonalds you eat at can have an effect on the quality of 
the meal you get....................It depends on where you go 
people!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!

-- Chris Duke ( cduke7@hotmail.com ), March 07, 2002. So just when i have an issue with mcdonald&apos;s and i&apos;d like to ask the 
coorporation for a legitimate answer their system for email 
communication is down. Recently i saw an add on tv for 2 for $2.22 on 
fish sandwiches. They already had this special on big macs but on 
fridays they implemented the fish sandwich deal i assume for our 
friends who practice catholism. Unfortunately when i went to my local 
mcdonald&apos;s they were not participating in this special and had no 
idea of it. Is this some sort of discrimination by offering meat so 
cheap but not fish during a season when the consumtion of meat is 
frowned upon. Granted participants vary, but how do they determine 
which ones will offer this special. Apparently I missed something 
when they censused my town to ask how many of us were catholic and 
would appreciate such a special on fridays. thanks a lot mcdonalds.

-- Shelby Koons ( beastiegirl70@hotmail.com ), March 08, 2002. Mc Donald&apos;s sucks, Burgur King sucks, Wendy&apos;s sucks, Arby&apos;s sucks, 
Taco Bell sucks, Pizza Hut sucks, Domino&apos;s sucks, Dairy Queen sucks, 
They all suck dude, don&apos;t eat there, I don&apos;t. There are all kinds 
of small &quot;hole in the wall&quot; resturaunts out there who will take to 
go orders if you call ahead of time. What a bunch of whiners. &quot;One 
time at band camp, I ordered a Mc Rib and told them to hold the 
sauce, and they put it on anyway, fuckin bastards.&quot; I have an idea, 
GO SOMEWHERE ELSE IDIOT. Most of you assholes whining about it 
probably don&apos;t need any more Mc Shit anyway. As far as you animal 
rights activists, up until there untimely massacre the cattle used 
for Mc meat carry on a very good life, a hell of a lot better than 
that dog or cat that you abandoned along the road sometime in your 
life, besides that THAT&apos;S WHAT THEY WERE BORN TO DO, FEED US. 
Anyway, get a life and have a nice life, bunch of idiots

-- u suck ( roadkilljoe@yahoo.com ), March 13, 2002. damn right!

-- Eric Shon ( Thebigone@yahoo.com/ ), March 15, 2002. This post is hilarious. I don&apos;t like McDonalds. But that&apos;s my 
choice. If someone else wants to eat it, go ahead. I&apos;m sick and 
tired of all of these activist groups getting rich off of their latest 
cause.
If you look at the severance pay and salaries the heads of these 
activist groups are getting paid, I don&apos;t blame them for bitching and 
complaining all the time.
Half of the garbage that is said about these companies on such posts 
are untrue. I got a feeling that if the truth were known, Greenpeace 
and such other organizations would have a lot more dirty laundry than 
McDonalds.

-- dc ( dc@yahoo.com ), March 22, 2002. Cock

-- bertum muffitt ( nmckenn@hotmail.com ), April 01, 2002. Hey, I love McDougals! In fact, while eating a divinely inspired 
Chicknet Mcnougat I suddenly gained true self awareness and inner 
peace. An interesting side-note here, I actually found a three carat 
diamond ring in a Big Mack that I was eating last Friday. They told 
me I could keep it, and then they gave me a matching 14K gold 
bracelet! This food is so fantastic that it can actually cure certain 
types of cancer. A McLean with onions cured my brothers asthma. A 
box containing a quarter pounder with cheese is being flown at this 
very moment to the middle east to assist in the peace talks there. 
Also, many people dont know that a McDonnals apple pie personally 
choreographed the dance moves in Britney Spears last video. A couple 
of quick historical facts: a Filet O Fish samich was actually the 
first sandwich to navigate alone around the fierce Horn Of Africa, 
and this same value meal later helped the British Empire to defeat 
the Dutch during the Boer War.

-- Mayor McCheesy ( deadrnhell@aol.com ), April 02, 2002. McDonalds is now the epitome of the cruise bar. A great place to 
meet up with men after you&apos;ve picked up a lowfat venti latte at 
Starbucks and gone shopping for your I&apos;m-not-gay-but-my-boyfriend-
is T-shirt. The crowd is a melting pot of ages, sexual styles and 
endo-, exo- and meso-morphologies -- you don&apos;t have to be stunningly 
pretty or pumped to score a burger at McDonalds. Recently a 
contingent of street tough circus clowns has begun making an 
appearance, as have, curiously enough, a few guys wearing stain-
resistant leather chaps and cowboy hats. It is probably no 
coincidence that McDonalds is now ground zero for the wild leather, 
bear and bathos scene in North America. Different nights of the week 
at Mickey Ds have different themes, including but not limited to: 
underwear, burgers, tattoo/chains, fries, leather, chicken nuggets, 
and uniforms. At McDonalds, the later the hour, the hotter it gets.

-- El Felcho ( elfelcho@aol.com ), April 02, 2002. you are what you eat...

-- ( x@x.com ), April 04, 2002. i just don&apos;t like it. it taste&apos;s funny

-- r. smith ( sparky_butterfilly@hotmail.com ), April 06, 2002. aaaall haters of mcDONALDS FFFFFFUUUUUUUCCCCCKKKKK UUUUU fuck you

-- juan craze ( craze@msn.comj ), April 06, 2002. If you turn them there GOLDEN ARCHES upside down you done got 
yourself one hell of a set of ASS CHEEKS, minus the curdled 
cellulite found on most MICKEY D customers&apos; (and female &quot;swing&quot; 
managers&apos;) tail ends. Look, I&apos;ve had my share of MkChikins and have 
enjoyed most every one. But it just hasn&apos;t been the same since the 
counterpersons stopped wearing the polyester smocks and pants and 
the little paper triangle hats. Yeah, and that mass murder in San 
Diego where that fuckface shot all those MAC-A-MANIACS back in &quot;84&quot; 
kind of took the wind out of my McBurgaler. I would like to show my 
appreciation to the higher ups at America&apos;s most successful 
restaraunt chain. You fellas finally relized that most level headed 
people with BIG ASSES seriously don&apos;t like sitting on pebble and 
cement tables and benches when they are scarfing down your wonderful 
product while enjoying the outside air overwhelmed by the scent of 
your deep friers and OPEN FLAMES (yeah right). Koodo&apos;s to you for 
taking out the outside lobby and adding Jungle Jims to kill the kids.
AT McDonalds
WE DO IT ALL FOR YOU............
WE DO IT ALL FOR YOU
WE DO IT ALL FOR YOU.

-- DEE CEE ( coleontheknoll@hotmail.com ), April 07, 2002. Q. what do you say to a retard with a job?
A. Big Mac and fries please
seriously i have eaten at burger king and they suck too, but theyre a 
hell of a lot better than the compressed cow cack they serve up at 
mcdonalds

-- angus mcblubber ( thief_41@hotmail.com ), April 07, 2002. Mc donalds are a waste of time, they crack me up. &apos;I would like a 
fatburger with flies please&apos; I get all sorts of responses LOL

-- lol ( support@microsoft.com ), April 09, 2002. Oh ffs, I am sick of hearing the retards on this page arguing that 
they should be allowed to eat in McDonalds if they want to. Apart 
from their bad grammar, spelling, etc, they are totally missing the 
point. Look at the impact that this company has had on the 
environment, such as the deforestation of rainforests for their new 
cow fields. Look at the filth that litters the street outside because 
the retards are to stupid to eat it without throwing it everywhere. 
Try sitting on a hot underground train whilst one of the retards is 
stuffing the McDonalds filth into itself, and its nauseating 
offspring. The smell is FOUL! The list is endless, but because of the 
stupidity of the retard, we all have to suffer.
So FFS, stop coming out with your PATHETIC excuses that you can eat 
there if you want. All of us are affected by your childish taste 
in food, along with the environment we are all forced to share. 
Eventually when a full enquiry is launched in McDonalds, and its 
filth is banned by the European Union or equivalent in the States, I 
wonder what will the retard find next to eat? So long as it really 
doesnt effect us, I dont care.

-- ( x@x.com ), April 12, 2002. I think Mcdonalds is full of false advertising. They show big huge 
burgers that look so good, and when you get the actual burger its 
small and pathetic. They make all the food seem so galamourous and 
it is really bad for your health, causing obesity and high 
chloresterol....I think Mcdonalds need to fix thew pictures in their 
ads and then we will see how many costomers they have!

-- Jenna Springall ( qt_jen5@hotmail.com ), April 15, 2002. Shut the hell up guys, 
I think you guys should give Ronald some credit,
He tries his hardest to cook you guys burgers,
but you guys rush him, so sometimes they might get a little burnt 
and crisp,
why can&apos;t u all just forgive him? we all make mistakes!

-- Mark Sloan YEAA!! ( markymarky6969@hotmail.com ), April 15, 2002. I think the sterotype that all McDonald&apos;s workers are stupid, 
unintelligent people is completly misleading....and more 
impriatntly...complete and utter bullshit. I myself am an employee at 
McDonalds. I maintain a 3.5 at my private catholic school in phoenix, 
AZ, I got a 1400 on the SAT...and ive yet to talke the ACT. I havce 
recebtly learned some awful things about our food..(Which is why I 
dont eat there anymore).....but....ultimitly....whose choice is it to 
eat there?? The answer to that rhetorical question in the consumer! So 
Lets stop blaming a faceless corporation, and start acting. If you are 
against it with such intensity, then boycott the products. Talking 
does shit...but in the end..we can all agree...that taco bell is mUCH 
wo

-- Andy Smith ( andy2003bcp@hotmail.com ), April 23, 2002. Hi there, well, how can I start? I and my wife used to go to Mac 
once in a while and we used to stop at Mac while we were traveling 
and in the road. We liked the place and we liked seeing people in 
there. My wife and I used to talk about which fast food restaurant 
has the most delicious French fries; I liked Mac fries and my wife 
disagreed. Any ways, we just heard from friends that the people at 
Mac use oil derived from pork and the use it from preparing 
hamburgers to fries. I was shocked to hear that and I had been 
thinking all a long that they used vegetable oil as one of their 
workers told me this after I raised my concern to her. Now I am 
really discussed and angry and I will not forgive them if that is 
true. So, can any one confirm this to me and very one like me? If 
you are a worker at Mac or used to be and you want to retaliate, 
please let us know because I am thinking of taking a legal action 
against them. Regards.
Please, send me an email.

-- Rich Moon ( alhonorsfriends@hotmail.com ), April 24, 2002. I&apos;d like you to all know that McDonalds use MEALWORM and PROTEIN 
BEETLES in there &quot;meat&quot; those are thousands of insects that are 
blended in to their &quot;meat&quot;. Enjoy!

-- Ron Jeremy Da Big Schlong ( mexfoal@hotmail.com ), April 25, 2002. Right, well what can I add. I know, how about the truth for a start.I 
have been working in McDonalds for five years now and for a start yes 
there are some morons behind the counter but PLEASE, sterotyping, how 
pathetic is that? If i was to take you to court for slander, I would 
win. Anyway, i have worked in about 20 different restaurants in south 
england and wales and i have yet to see many of the accusation s you 
people make actually happen. Rich Moon, your concern over the oil 
used is easily remedied, McDonalds has brought out a booklet on what 
is in the food and what is used to cook it along with other info such 
as how much fat is in each burger. There is also a link to the info 
from there website, so use your head and the net and look for 
yourself as you won&apos;t get an ounce of truth out of this lot. as for 
the peole who believe that mere mortals can produce an exact replica 
buger to match the T.V. adds, WAKE UP AND GET A LIFE. Apart from the 
fact that you wouldn&apos;t wait for it to be made like that, its a burger 
restaurant not a fast food restaurant. what about all the money that 
McDonalds has pored back into the local community, such as the RMCC 
houses for terminally ill children and there families.
As to the rest of the people who boycott McD&apos;s and go to places like 
Wendys, HELLO!!!!!! Wendy&apos;s is the only major burger restaurant who 
have had a massive out break of food poisoning, that killed loads of 
people! Don&apos;t nelieve me it was one of the major headlines back in 
the early 80&apos;s, and if you don&apos;t like McDonalds , then don&apos;t go 
there.Duh!!!! 
26/4/2002

-- helen martin ( helkierra@hotmail.com ), April 26, 2002. so i have green hair, piercings, shag like a bitch and spit on ur 
burgers just cus i work for the clown? and how would u know all this? 
because u, at some point in your miserable life visited that place ur 
so against? I dont know about what ever countries u fools are from 
but in the uk, our mcdonalds have standards, well trained employee 
and put it this way, i&apos;ll eat the food, not cus i&apos;m a &apos;broke student&apos; 
like you&apos;d expect me to be. In fact, because of my relatively well 
paid job, i have more money than alot of my peers, and i dont need to 
scrounge of the state by goin on the dole etc. I wouldn&apos;t go as far 
to say i love my job but for at least its better than complaining 
about something o know little or nothing about.

-- laz &apos; mc employee &apos; t ( candeekorn@uboot.com ), April 28, 2002. and another thing, if you&apos;d like to look up the RMCC (the mcdonalds 
charity) You&apos;d see where some of that &apos;corporate&apos; money goes, TO UR 
OWN FUCKIN CHILDREN!!! and also, do u think trading standards or 
environmental health would allow maccies to trade if there were rats, 
filth, hamburgers made of card etc, your all really stupid for 
believing the rumours and jokes thats people tell you. YOU ALL FELL 
FOR IT SUCKERS!!! now who are the dumbasses?? (\_/)
 (o&apos;.&apos;O)
 (&quot;) (&quot;)

-- laz t ( candeekorn@uboot.com ), April 28, 2002. REALLY. EVERYONE PULL OUT YOUR OLD PHONIX BOOKS AND LETS WORK 
ON THE SPELLING.... is it to much to ask?? Huh, really...........?

-- deecee ( coleontheknoll@hotmail.com ), May 01, 2002. Personally, I think that McDondals is a pretty ok place to eat at! I&apos;m 
actually about to start working there but thats not why I said it, I 
said it because if you have a problen then use common 
sence.............DONT EAT THERE! And some one was right Some of you 
guys need to check your spelling!Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha !

-- Agnes Ieshia Robinson ( 3robinai@eshapooh.com ), May 10, 2002. McDonalds is great.If you dont like it then dont eat there.

-- nick ( mcnick@hotmail.com ), May 10, 2002. OMG! did you see the one with lacey pooty?and her s/n? what a 
slut(hey that rhymes. the what a slut part. i&apos;m a poet and i didn&apos;t 
even realize it. LOL - an example of JARGON a word i learned in 
english for MCAS. Mr. Johnson&apos;s the best!!!!)
and the one with jade green?she was saddened to hear the 
ignorant people bla bla bla.and SINCERELY HOPED. what a 
loser. Shut up bitch!
But seriously. if you want to waste your time trying to change the 
whole fuckin world you must be crazy. Not everyone&apos;s gonna 
change their lives just because some people don&apos;t like 
McDonalds. Have you ever thought that people like the food? I 
know it&apos;s bad that they kill kangaroos or whatever(i dont know if 
its just a rumor) and that the people only get $4.00 a week for 
working, but just give it up. i am &quot;saddened&quot; like jade but 
because you people are so annoying. Let other people live their 
lives how they want to.
P.S. if you ever write to this thing you&apos;ll se a note at the bottom 
that says not to make fake email addresses. Well I kinda broke 
the rules.SORRY. well actually i&apos;m not but that&apos;s ok. did you 
seriously think my address was 1 800 64 giant? so DON&apos;T 
EMAIL ME BACK. besides i won&apos;t ever come back to this site 
again cuz some of you sicken me. 
and their fries are the best!!!!

-- blue baboon ( 1 800 64 GIANT@hotmail.com ), May 15, 2002. I LOVE BRANDON JAMES DAVIES!!! he&apos;s so hottt. know what 
else i love? McDonalds. HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA
i&apos;m hungry so i&apos;m gonna go to McDonalds, get me some fries wit 
a burger, and get to brandon&apos;s house.

-- what if i don&apos;t have a name? eva think of that ( a$$ho@i don&apos;t know what yu did last summer.com ), May 15, 2002. I&apos;ve worked at a McDonalds for over a year and a half, and I still 
eat food there whenever I work. There is nothing wrong with people&apos;s 
food. If someone drops something we throw it away, or if it is a 
spatula or somethin, we wash it off. We have to keep our areas 
clean, or we don&apos;t get to leave on time, and can get in trouble. 
Most of the employees are smart and can do there job, there are a 
select few who can&apos;t, or won&apos;t do there job, and there the ones who 
get fired or quit. So before you trash McDonald&apos;s, maybe you should 
work there and see what it&apos;s like.

-- Your Friendly Neighborhood McDonalds employee ( OzzyDemon9@aol.com ), May 20, 2002. Micky DEES ROCKS SO TAKE IT UP YOUR ASS CUZ IS THE BEST FAST FOOD 
JOIN IN DA WORLD IM GOING TO EAT THERE RIGHT NOW YUMMMMMMMMMM!

-- Amanda HudandKiss ( yarightimtellingyoumyemail@hotmail.com ), May 24, 2002. been there worked that. I flipped buggers in the burgers. A nasty snot
rocker in the fish tartar sauce, you never knew.

-- ( a@snot.story ), May 24, 2002. You all have no fuckin life! Bye.

-- Wouldn&apos;t you love to know! ( getalife@yousuck.com ), May 26, 2002. I dont know what they r saying about sticking McDonalds food up my 
Michael Jacksons ass thats rude so. STOP 
ITTTT!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

-- Marissa Jackson ( leavemjalone@NOW!.com ), June 01, 2002. I find it humorous that all of the people who placed a negative 
comment misspelled at least one word incorrectly! To the person 
saying that Mcdonalds is REAL FOOD, your mother must have been a 
horrible cook!!!

-- JEANA ( rajeana_h@hotmail.com ), June 03, 2002. I love dipping my fries in big mac sauce ... i love mcdonalds...
YUMMMM

-- ronald mcdonald ( iloveronald@yahoo.com ), June 03, 2002. To Jeana:
It&apos;s most amusing how you comment on the spelling of others. I 
see no flaws in your spelling, but you might want to fix up those 
basic grammar errors.

-- Eric Bentley ( PiffJaw@aol.com ), June 04, 2002. Listen..The world has changed since the 1970&apos;s...We want to eat the 
whales,not save them( bunch of big,boring fucking fish )..McD does a 
great fish sandwich..maybe,just maybe,whales are being 
used.......Hippie pussies used to whine about &quot;red meat,red meat.&quot;. 
Hey ! I got your fucking red meat over here! At McD&apos;s!Great 
burger,from an unlamented stupid fucking cow.....Hippie &quot;sensitive&quot; 
guys are always soooooooo fucking health conscious..They want and 
EXPECT to live to be 125 years old. So they fuck with us,the real 
people who don&apos;t give a fuck about endangered whales,cows,and other 
four legged shit.....I love animals....BECAUSE THEY TASTE SO FUCKING 
GOOD!!!!! Pass the salt.

-- Hugh G.Rection ( Dump Israel@aol.com ), June 05, 2002. i&apos;m dreading the day my kid says that they want to go and eat at 
McDonalds. i worked there for a good year or so when i was a 
student, and it was not a nice place to work. having sliced my thumb 
open on one of the burger flippers and bled over the grill station, 
akll that was done was to wipe the blood off the hot plate, and 
salvage as many burgers as weren&apos;t covered in my blood - these were 
then made into sandwiches. that&apos;s my personal experience, as to the 
rest, the corporation, like any other, cannot be expected to have a 
conscience, just as it has no body. it just wants your money at the 
expense of anything. the employees are exploited by the corporation 
and by the consumer. but the horrible reality is that if they don&apos;t 
work there, their dole or welfare, if such exist, will get cut off. 
the food is so bad as that is yet another way to extract the maximum 
out of limited resources. the food is not good, cannot be good, 
because it is jammed full of crap to give it flavour, texture and so 
on. what tastes &apos;really good&apos; are the cancer-inducing chemicals 
which you gobble down when you eat one of their products. as someone 
has previously said, go to a mom&amp;pop;joint - don&apos;t be such a willing 
agent of your own demise as to pay McDonalds the price of anything.
p.s. isn&apos;t it weird how the most abusive responses come from 
McDonald&apos;s enthusiasts, is it something in the food? 
p.p.s. moreover, when you go past one of those places, they smell 
like shit

-- gwyl williams ( gwilym_williams@yahoo.co.uk ), June 09, 2002. Your Mum.

-- M. C. Donlalds ( mcdonaldsrules@hotmail.com ), June 11, 2002. And Your Fucking Dad.

-- M. C. Donalds ( mcdonldsrules@hotmail.com ), June 11, 2002. Does anybody know where the toliet is?

-- Herbert ( !!!@hotmail.com ), June 11, 2002. i have solid evidence that ronald macdonald takes it up the arse and 
fucking loves it. i have pictures.1000 a photo. please contact me if 
you would like one.

-- josh bates ( gaylords@eatshit.com ), June 11, 2002. IM SITTING NEXT TO SOME UGLY MOOSE, SHE SMELLS OF FISH! I WOULD 
RATHER EAT A MCDONLADS THAN THIS SMELLY FISH!

-- JODIE ( JODIE@SLUTS.COM ), June 11, 2002. in used to work in macdonalds in reading in the uk. i regulary wiped 
my hot, sweating bell end over the burgers. it used to really turn me 
on. that would explain to all you people who have ever ate a makky 
d&apos;s in reading why they were so cheesy. thanks for your time. just 
thought you should know. josh

-- some dude in england ( battyman@myarse.com ), June 11, 2002. i also thought you should no that i used to put my index finger up my 
bum bofore handling the food. i thought it was amusing. HAHA SUCKERS. 
have you ever wondered why the buns always have the brown greasy 
stuff on them. enjoy your burgers people!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

-- some dude in england again ( battyman@myarse.com ), June 11, 2002. I WORKED IN MCDONALDS ONCE, THERE WAS ONLY ONE TOLIET, WHICH WAS 
OFTEN OUT OF ORDER, SO INSTEAD OF GOING ACCROSS THE ROAD TO USE THE 
TOLIET IN BURGER KING, I USED TO DROP MY LOAD ON THE GRILL, FRY IT 
AND SERVE IT TO MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC. CHEERS FOR YOUR TIME, JODIE.H.

-- JODIE ( JODIE@SLAG.CO.UK ), June 11, 2002. HAS ANYONE EVER FOUND A GINGER PUBE IN THEIR MEAL? SORRY.

-- TOM GOLD ( GINGER@HOTMAIL.COM ), June 11, 2002. GOT A SPARE FAG?

-- EDD ( EDD@HOTMAIL.COM ), June 11, 2002. i was going to say that i think your all gay but then realised that i 
would be insulting myself. long live MC Queers baby yeah.

-- ADI G ( young blood@hmail.com ), June 11, 2002. HI, MY NAME IS CAM, I LIKE DRUGS, THEY ARE REALLY COOL, I ALSO LIKE 
MY TEACHER PAM, SHE IS WELL FIT MAN, I WOULDNT MIND BENDING HER OVER 
A TABLE....YEAH...OHHH.....I&apos;VE GOT TO GO TO THE TOLIET, BYE.

-- CAM4PAM ( CAM@DRUGED-UP.CO.UK ), June 11, 2002. my name is scott. i&apos;m 17 .i am i training at a McDonalds restuarant. 
i love it. and i love the clown. i think i&apos;m in love with him. please 
help me. i thought this should be know to the population of the 
world. i spend every second of every day thinking about him. it makes 
my 13 &quot; nob stand on end and it gets embrassing as i can&apos;t get close 
enough to the counter to serve the costomers. i&apos;m very sorry for 
this. still my love for ron go on and on. i will marry him on day if 
he ever leaves all the little kiddys alone.

-- yes its a 13 incher!!!!!!! ( bigcock@hmail.com ), June 11, 2002. COULD ANYONE TEACH ME TO SHAVE PLEASE?

-- SCOTT.H ( SCOTT@HOTMAIL.COM ), June 11, 2002. i am ronald McDonald. really i am. i am not taking the piss. i love 
the kids but not in a sexual way. i have fun with them making the 
laugh and smile. this is my life so stop insulting it or i&apos;ll find 
you and put you in my fucking burgers!!!! eat shit and die.

-- dave k ( clown@hmail.com ), June 11, 2002. I THINK MY MUM&apos;S A MAN.

-- ADI. ( FCUKYOU@HOTMAIL.COM ), June 11, 2002. No comment.

-- Anonymous ( nottelling@nowhere.com ), June 11, 2002. Listen, all this bullshit you liberal fucks say about McDonalds 
destroying the rainforset is just that, bullshit. You goto south 
america, africa, or wherever you say they&apos;re cutting down trees and 
take pictures of it. Then, find some way to prove its McDonalds 
doing it. You&apos;ll have a hard time becuase its not McDonalds, it&apos;s 
locals who are trying to earn a living and feed their families. 
Listen, i hate mcdonald&apos;s food, and believe me I hate defending 
them, but all this shit you all are saying is preposterous and there 
is no proof to back it up. Feel free to email me.

-- Ross (Conservative, Capitalist) ( pharinc@peoplepc.com ), June 13, 2002. Ha Ha, this is a fake e-mail address. Now this website will 
experience technical diffulculties. Nobody messes with the clown!
-peace

-- Smokey McPot ( haha@yourmom.com ), June 17, 2002. I work at Mc Donald&apos;s and for all the complete idiots writing in, 
there is such a thing as the Health Department. If all the things you 
people are saying were true, don&apos;t you think Mc Donald&apos;s would have 
been shut down by now? And to those who know a friend, or your 
sisters-husbands-baby cousins-auntie who work there, I don&apos;t know 
which of you is the bigger idiot-the one who &quot;works there,&quot; and told 
the story, or the friend who believed it.

-- Deeanne ( chickissqueaks@yahoo.com ), June 17, 2002. To Jeana: 
It&apos;s most amusing how you comment on the spelling of others. I see no 
flaws in your spelling, but you might want to fix up those basic 
grammar errors.
-- Eric Bentley (PiffJaw@aol.com), June 04, 2002.
THE WORD IS GRAMATICAL... &apos;BASIC GRAMATICAL ERRORS&apos;.

-- Tim Butler ( tim_butler@hotmil.com ), June 18, 2002. Congratulations! I was waiting to see how long it would take someone 
to catch that.

-- Eric Bentley ( PIFFJAW@aol.com ), June 18, 2002. After that I don&apos;t mean to insult you, but the word is in 
fact &quot;grammatical&quot; and not &quot;gramatical&quot;.

-- Eric Bentley ( PIFFJAW@aol.com ), June 18, 2002. Sorry, That&apos;s what my American Computer dictionary corrected it to! 
Bill Gates has a lot to answer for.

-- Tim Burton ( tim_burton@htmail.com ), June 19, 2002. McDonalds do lie in their ads. They are EVIL. I work at McShits and I 
get treated like crap from managers AND customers. And screw all you 
people you are complaining about us. If you don&apos;t like us or the food 
than stop going there. It is that simple. If you happen to get a 
stupid employee (there are many) than just deal with it. I know many 
intelligent people who I work with that are just trying to make a 
buck. So just give us a fucking break! If you had to work in the 
conditions we work in...than you might be grumpy and make mistakes. 
You never know...if you piss us off....we can spit in your food. I&apos;ve 
never seen it happen, but that doesn&apos;t mean it doesn&apos;t. So I guess 
what i&apos;m trying to say is have some freakin&apos; respect, and lay off!

-- Morgan Campbell ( morgancampbell@hotmail.com ), June 19, 2002. You know you could sue the company. The correct word is 
grammatical. Make no mistake. Merriam-Webster agrees with me. 
Congratulations on your change of names.

-- Eric Bentley ( PIFFJAW@aol.com ), June 19, 2002. Ok... I heard that the fries wern&apos;t even made out of potatoes. but 
something oily and looks like wax. I actually woudl like to remain 
anomunous so i wont tell you my name. I heard most of the fry is 
made up of this. the employes and managers do not know about this. 
and it&apos;s pretty disqusting! this oily wax stuff is also not good for 
u.
Do you want plastic in your body? or do u want your kids to be 
eating artifical potatoes (PLASTIC)!????? everyone loves the fries 
but there not REAL! NEW YORK FRIED. thats where they make real 
fries. they leave the skin to show the whole world!

-- Alex T. ( xandert_2000@hotmail.com ), June 20, 2002. Listens I know all you slim shadys are pisses about mcdonalds having
shitty food but listen it is a goddamn fast food what the fuck r.u.
xpecting haute cusine?! c&apos;mon blow your hedz out your asses i mean
very low paid mcdonald&apos;s employees who actually at the restaurant
should be treated with more respect cuz their the 1&apos;s who make
mcdonald&apos;s work so it&apos;s just fast food you ass holes so it is not
gourmet food and if you don&apos;t like make you own motherfucking food!!!
and do any you shits know what mcdonald&apos;s food is made of?!? i think
not case closes see you assholes universe later- T.T.

-- Tom Taffe ( tomtaffe@hotmail.com ), June 28, 2002. Ok, if you don&apos;t like McDonalds, don&apos;t Fucking go there! How hard is 
that. I can also see where the employees are coming from. They work 
their asses off for close to nothing, and you just can&apos;t be easy on 
them, can you?!? These are people, too. Would you be very happy with 
their jobs from the already given experiences? No. Neither would I. 
Mcdonalds is meant to be nothing more but something to keep you full 
until you need to eat again, and I think they are doing their job 
with that. It adds to the economy, a good deal in fact. If you want 
us to go into an economic slump, then go ahead, boycott it. Some 
people don&apos;t have time to make dinner, that&apos;s the only reason why 
they go there. Also, I see alot of people metioning Wendy&apos;s as an 
alternative, they are not gonna be much better. Am I the only one who 
wonders why their meat is square? That&apos;s not normal. Lastly, I&apos;ve 
seen people saying that we&apos;ll run out of oxygen if we cut down any 
more of the rainforest. Plankton provides most of the oxygen on this 
planet. In Conclusion, If you think McDonalds sucks, stfu and don&apos;t 
eat there!

-- Um...Not George? ( What do I put here@dumbass.com ), June 28, 2002. If you want to know why people boycott McDonalds read FAST 
FOOD NATION! Once you read it you may think twice about 
eating any fast food.

-- rareform ( photoreel@yahoo.com ), July 03, 2002. To much time to bitch people.... If you don&apos;t like McD&apos;s don&apos;t go 
there. If you do like McD&apos;s then keep going. but please find 
something more constructive to do with your time besides bitch. 
Thank you!

-- Rodney Smith ( yahoo@yahoo.com ), July 04, 2002. Hello, My name is Srinivas. I live in India, am 25 year old young 
guy, single. I&apos;m Christian.
My Postal address:
Pilla Naga Srinivasa Rao,
Jillellamudi Vari Lane,
Eastern Street,
Eluru-534001,
Andhra Pradesh-India.

-- Pilla Srinivas ( Pilla Naga Srinivasa Rao ) ( pilla_srinivas@hotmail.com ), July 04, 2002. The whole point should be that most people who eat fast food are the 
very people who most need to stop eating a diet that is high in fat 
and sodium, loaded with preservatives and low on fiber. Skyrocketing 
rates of colon and stomach cancers in the west should convice most 
people that an apple is a far better snack than a McMeal. But people 
are mostly stupid,ill-informed dorks who could care less about the 
science. They will never get sick, or so they think. So, let them 
eat and dieI say. Its a illusion of freedom but thats all we really 
have. The real problem I have with McDonald&apos;s is the the way they 
conduct business in the third world. Until people become more aware 
of the power they hold collectively as consumers, then I am afraid 
nothing will change.; just look at who is President of the Excited 
States of America. Does anyone really expect big changes soon? Other 
than a looming war in the Middle East.

-- Dave McCullough ( can_boy6@yahoo.com ), July 06, 2002. Why do people winge, It&apos;s like turn over the channel on the tv, Go 
else where to eat, Stop bloody moaning, I think some people are not 
happy unless they moan, To fast, To soon, maccy d&apos;s are easy and 
plentyfull, But they could extend the breakfast till say 1130,

-- A.Turner ( a_r_turner@hotmail.com ), July 06, 2002. They lie in their ads because it would be entirely too difficult to 
teach the counter people how to speak and understand english. That 
way when they completely screw up your order they can pretend they 
don&apos;t understand why you are bringing food back. I try to eat there 
about once a year, and always end up taking the crap right back and 
getting a refund. They don&apos;t like it! I don&apos;t care!

-- pucking my guts out now ( eatshitatmickeyd&apos;s@hotmail.com ), July 08, 2002. I have been against the changes in McD for over ten years. When I 
lived in Illinois, the chain called Steak and Shake who cook the 
orders when they are ordered are much faster than standing in line at 
your stores. I have moved south and in Memphis I was trying to get 
something quickly while on a route and your stores on Union Ave in 
Memphis took over ten minutes to take care of no one. The niggers 
working in them could care less about helping a customer. Your fast 
food chain has gone down the verbial drain. Hardees and the other 
chains are now better than you even when they are slow to get an 
order done. You have nothing but trash running your stores and 
working in them. I have submitted a report to Washington and to the 
Better Business Bureau to close you down forever.

-- LS ( drmotoe@earthlink.net ), July 09, 2002. ...like seriously...i mmean as if...frog or spider...your choice...

-- ... ( ...@... .com ), July 10, 2002. McDonalds taste absolutely horible, and i never eat there. Forget all 
the stories, and the rumors, just dont eat there. The people that do, 
you are incredibly gross because you are feeding yourself cancer. Ill 
prove it, go here:
http://cbc.ca/stories/2002/04/24/Consumers/chipscancer_020424
or:
http://www.commentarypage.com/pergram/perg043002.html
which states:
A team of scientists in Sweden has now made what they describe as 
an &quot;unexpected finding.&quot; The Swedes have discovered that French 
fries, potato chips and other high-carbohydrate foods may contain a 
cancer causing substance. Deep frying potatoes produces high-levels 
of acrylamide a bi-product the Environmental Protection Agency has 
declared a &quot;medium hazard probable human carcinogen.&quot;
GREAT! EAT UP!

-- ronald isnt very nice ( this_is_not_a_real_address@fakeaddress.com ), July 12, 2002. I think I&apos;ll skip the cancer. Thanks for the information, ronald isnt 
very nice.

-- rich ( richiejjj@hotmail.com ), July 12, 2002. There was also a study done on a college kid who ate nothing but 
McDonalds crap for an entire year. His gums receeded and his hair 
started to fall out. He also lost bone mass. Makes ya wanna run 
right back to the kitchen and develop some cooking skills doesn&apos;t 
it? You really are what you eat folks!

-- =) ( ronaldwantstokillyou@youdipstick.com ), July 12, 2002. Have you ever noticed that there is a mcdonalds located every 3 
blocks in cities? Thats sick. What a waste of space. That place taste 
like they ate your food, spit it out, recooked it, and gave it to 
you. Yeah, you are what you eat.

-- im RONNIE MCDONNIE ( ?????@???????.com ), July 13, 2002. mcdonalds lies because they are corp. america bitches, much like enron
or worldcom they make a huge profit on false claims, but instead of
duping the shareholders they fuck you and me. It is the same
mentality, they know their product eats dick, and puts your health in
jeopardy, yet they continue pushing the shit like crack on people who
don&apos;t see through the smoke. Lies, the same in every company that
controls the american political system, infest our minds and abuse our
trust. Do you think their is a correlation btwn the blitzkrieg of
false marketing, the sheer amount of fast food in america, and the
fact that one third of the entire population is overweight? the
McDouble is only another tool in the long line of arch deluxe, mcrib,
mclean false dreams of a decent product, fuck you McDonalds, fuck you
up your stupid asses.

-- ( genemorgan@mac.com ), July 13, 2002. How is a 79 cent hamburger &quot;fucking you and me&quot;? This has got to be 
the most ridiculous thing I&apos;ve ever seen. 98% of you who have 
commented on this page need to calm down....stop complaining....and 
move on. Your McWords of McDeath are doing NOTHING for 
whatever &quot;cause&quot; has got you all fired up, I assure you.

-- &quot;A Corporate American Bitch&quot; (I guess) ( lilaggie96@yahoo.com ), July 18, 2002. McD&apos;s.......
It&apos;s not real meat like you buy at the store. Alot of people like 
that shit. The people that say they eat there everyday probably do. 
They also probably weigh in at 330 - 380 lbs. and are very unhealthy.
You couldn&apos;t PAY ME ENOUGH MONEY to put that shit in my mouth.
-toche&apos;
-jb

-- JA Bernabei ( jbernabei@neo.rr.com ), July 19, 2002. simple.. I don&apos;t eat at Mc Donalds, I don&apos;t eat fast food. Period. And 
if you actually expect to get good food from minimum wage crap 
factory, you get what you deserve.. every time you complain and go 
back. How many times do you have to put yourself through the &quot;same old 
shit&quot; routine? Some of you, every... single... day. I&apos;d bet if you 
walked in tomorrow, came back in a week.. you&apos;d see alot of fresh 
faces behind the counter.. and maybe that one dick from the drive 
through, mopping the piss off the mens room floor. Do yourselves a 
favor.. don&apos;t go back.. not even if it&apos;s 59 cents, or 6 for two 
bucks.. yeah, that&apos;s cheap...but it&apos;s my 2 bucks that I still have in 
my pocket. Just stop it.

-- William Van Derhaus ( auslander1@yahoo.com ), July 20, 2002. who cares about the burgers they pay their staff in pennies treat 
them like shit its no wonder theirfood is also shite

-- phil evans ( philevans999@lineone.net ), July 21, 2002. McDonalds food was okay when I was in a hurry, but recently I stopped 
being in that much of a hurry where McDonalds is concerned. The 
problem being that everytime I have eaten there recently, I have 
gotten sick. This, even after asking for &quot;no pickles&quot; in the hopes of 
getting a fresher sandwich. I have concluded that this &quot;poorly 
prepared food&quot; has do with the handling of the food or lack thereof. 
The problem is that McDonalds hires irresponsible, non-caring, 
ignorant teenagers that have a lack of respect for people in general. 
The bigger problem is that the managment does not know how to manage 
or are afraid to manage for fear of being sued by a lower life form 
that is working there for low wages. My suggestion for a solution to 
the problem is that McDonalds should hire responsible adults that are 
paid better wages with long term benefits and that the employees who 
prepare the food should be required to eat the food as well.

-- Lisa ( ptingnmy2cents@aol.com ), July 26, 2002. It is very funny to see peoples brand loyalty!!! 
I have been involved in political campaigns since I was about 13 
years old and I always meet the same oppositition. They usually like 
many on this post have nothing better to do than to swear and call 
activist liars!! Open your eyes for a moment here, the world exists 
outside of corporate America. 
I am watching a Mc D&apos;s flip my historical downtown upside down, it 
has already forced the city to change roads. In other words it is 
making the city government spend money on them so that they can make 
money, while the city looses it. 
Little restaurants will be destroyed by the McDonalds. Not because 
MD&apos;s is better but because they use cheap products, cheap labour, and 
they have ignorant brand loyalty to make money.
For all you people spewing ignorance I suggest you read something 
from Edward L. Bernays. He created the PR industry in the States and 
he believes you are all an &quot;ignorant herd&quot; that need to be led. His 
techniques have been used by America (ww1), Hitlers germany, and 
corporations at large! These techniques go off of Freudian 
psychology and are the reason people eat at Mc D&apos;s restaruants, 
regardless of their workers rights abuses, regardless of the numerous 
health and safety act abuses, regardless of their HORRIBLE use of at 
times under tested animal products (steroids, GMO).

-- Justin Williams ( greenboy@positive-youthfoundation.com ), July 29, 2002. Very long, drawn out and absolutely boring perspective!

-- Lisa ( ptingnmy2cents@aol.com ), July 31, 2002. I LOVE MCDONALDS YOU GUYS HAVE GOT TO MUCH TIME ON YOUR HANDS , GET 
A LIFE AND STOP EATING ALL THE DAMN GRASS

-- DAVID MCDONALD ( SUEYHOGSS@HOTMAIL.COM ), August 12, 2002. CHECK OUT httP://WWW.ARROWPOST.COM AND SPEND YOUR MONEY THERE INSTEAD

-- cRUSTY_SURfEr ( surfskier@mail.com ), August 27, 2002. Keep your US crap food, look what it is doing to you fat US bloopers, 
On my many visits to relations in the US I was amazed at the gross 
fat people waddling along in the heat in bloody shorts, I ask you, 
and then there was McDonalds fatty foods, tell bird brain Bush to 
start with McDonalds before he starts bullying the rest of the World, 
he would be saving more US lives than killing the World`s children.
McDonalds ,excuse me while I puke.

-- oliver burns ( oliver@freecrow.freeserve.co.uk ), September 05, 2002. McDonalds lies because they know their clientele will believe the 
shit they spew. Let&apos;s face it, people who eat at McDonalds are 
pretty un-educated (educated people know better and simply do not eat 
there). So they lie because they know the uneducated fat asshole 
masses who eat their form of death will lap it up and keep keep 
coming back. Who Fucking cares anyway&apos;s..... these fat bastards will 
die eventually, and with it so will McDonalds..... and what will be 
left will be healthy, educated people enjoying quality meals!
Cheers
Let the loser idiots wipe themselves out!

-- Spence Lee ( spencelee32@hotmail.com ), September 12, 2002. It ain&apos;t Harvey&apos;s, but McDonalds is good enough when in a rush for a 
meal. The PROBLEM is that the majority of Americans, British, etc.. 
etc... eat TOO much fast food, making them the 1-2 fattest nations in 
the world. There are cigarette warnings about lung cancer, teeth, 
etc.. but nothing about cholesterol, heart disease, etc.. that helps 
kill nearly as many as smoking in the U.K. Go figure. For those in 
Canada its probably just a matter of time till those nice red packs 
of fries have a half-pack warning label with a picture of a horrible 
heart or fat bastard on it with &quot;Cholesteral causes heart disease&quot;, 
just like the Tobacco packs do now with Cancer.
As for the advertising, some of it is a lie, but as an adult now, I 
STILL like Cheese Burgers the best, 3 pickle slices and all.

-- Dave Smith ( rlp@canada.com ), September 30, 2002. come on mcdonalds is the biggest food company in the world, it 
grosses more that microsoft, so it is one of the biggest companys in 
the world. if it is so bad then why do so many people every day go 
there, of course you aint going to get the exact looking burger as on 
the ads, but think of the amount of food they need to cook so quicky, 
you all think that the world revolves around you get a life mcdonalds 
need to keep cooking food for example----- runs of 9 cheese of ham 
burgers, runs of 4 big macs and 1/4 s. for the small meat this cooks 
in only 50 seconds so could you be arsed dressing each 1 perfect if 
you where on a shite wage. i think not, chicket products come in runs 
of up to 8 and the new steak can only make in runs of 4. so think 
about it, and the meat aint going to be the dogs bollocks, its fast 
food not le cuisine la template, french)) it needs to be cooked and 
made up in a fast time, so think cock suckers think about it get the 
facts right 1st 7th. nice.

-- rupert rothenbottom ( holty2000@Yahoo.com ), October 07, 2002. I believe we can&apos;t just start pointing and shouting and campaiging 
against this corporation , more knowledge and truth is needed on this 
subject , and the rest of you people ...... you all force your view 
on people , i&apos;d rather hear the thoughts and views of one of the 
farmers who suffer from mcdonalds greed.

-- Gizmo ( hippycommune02@hotmail.com ), October 20, 2002. I have heard the most disgusting things about the food that 
macdonalds serve, For instance, their &quot;100% beef patties&quot; are only 
100% beef because the company that makes and sells the actual patties 
is called, yes, you guessed it, &quot;100% beef&quot;; apparently, they&apos;re 
actually made of horse meat. The chicken nuggets are not chicken, but 
instead are rabbit meat, with chicken flavouring. Also, the soft 
serve is made out of pig fat. The latest I have heard is that urine 
and faeces have been found in the beef patties. So my opinion is, 
it&apos;s gross, it&apos;s disgusting and unbelievably unhygenic. But that&apos;s 
just me. If you want to continue eating &quot;beef&quot; and &quot;chicken&quot; 
and &quot;ice-cream&quot; then you can go on doing so, but thankfully, it won&apos;t 
be at my expense.

-- Just Paying Maccas Out ( jus_bernz@hotmail.com ), October 21, 2002. MCDONALDS ARE LOVELY THEY TASTE GREAT LOOK GREAT, WHATS ALL UR 
PROBLEM U A SAD BUNCH OF MOTHER FUCKERS, DONT LIKE IT DONT EAT IT. 
PLUS WHO GIVES A SHIT ABOUT WHATS IN THEM AS LONG AS THEY TASTE NICE!

-- Stacey ( mcdonaldsrule@hotmail.com ), October 29, 2002. I made a trip to McDonald&apos; s to get breakfast at 9:30 at 10:oo I 
decided it was time to get my money back and go somewhere else. 
Finally the line started to move again I went in to get the money or 
see if we could get the food today only to find they were still not 
working on our order a young lady from the drive up was practicing 
basketball with the wrappers another young lady was busy playing in 
the cheese and not putting it on the sandwiches the only employee in 
this store working was the manager and a young man who was 
continually being told to come on I wont be returning to this 
restuarant appearently my services was not worth there time nor my 
money. I personally would be ashamed to state I worked at a place 
with this reputation and will make a point to tell everyone I know of 
the poor service and quality of employment I experienced

-- nova ( itsmenova@yahoo.com ), November 03, 2002. Hey,
I have a friend who works at McD&apos;s and he likes it there. He&apos;s been 
there a few years, and claims it&apos;s one of the cleanest McDonald&apos;s 
Restaurants in the city. However, he does admit they&apos;ve had their 
share of bad employees.
According to him, an employee was once caught early in the morning 
pissing into the hole of the drink machine that brings water into 
it. He unhooked the main hose and stuck his penis in. It seems he 
may have been doing that a number of times before getting caught! He 
was fired immediately.
Another time, a guy was flipping burgers on a hot day. The employee 
was wearing shorts, and a wedgy had formed in his butt. He took the 
spatula, stuck it up under his shorts and used it to leverage the 
underwear out of his butt crack. He then promptly took it out and 
flipped burgers some more. I&apos;m told he was let go of.
Over a long period of time at this one store, a relatively new 
employee had been the one who would go to get new boxes of lard. One 
day, when he hadn&apos;t returned promptly, someone went into the storage 
room to see what was up. I should mention that once in a while 
before this happened people had noticed a hole about 1.5&quot; in diameter 
on one side of the box, but thought nothing of it. Anyway, on this 
particular day the other employee walked in to catch the first guy 
having sex with the lard! I guess the feel of the lard was quite 
pleasurable, and he had gotten used to doing it... also, 
the &apos;evidence&apos; of his deed would generally be burned away along with 
the nutrients in the french fries. Of course, he was immediately 
fired.
In general, I&apos;m told, the employees are good and clean. But, some 
are not. Some in fact have their hormones in an uproar and that&apos;s 
why some of these things take place. For example, my friend says 
there are a few of his colleagues who are constantly having sex in 
the basement, in the stairwell, and even outside in the back of the 
restaurant in the summer.
Of course formal charges are rarely laid. I would imagine McDonald&apos;s 
would not want this sort of report being picked up by the media.
-mazingman

-- Johnny Walker ( mazingman@rogers.com ), November 04, 2002. Hey again,
Just thought I&apos;d point out that I don&apos;t have first-hand knowledge of 
the stories I mentioned in my previous post, so of course we must 
take this with a grain of salt. But my friend was quite serious when 
he told me these things...
thx.

-- Johnny Walker ( mazingman@rogers.com ), November 04, 2002. Working at Mcdonald&apos;s is slavery. Working for a wage of 6.75 per 
hour, you spend days toiling in absolute drudgery. But it is work,
and can be at times enjoyable. The days go by quickly or slowly 
depending on who you work with and how the customers are. To all
workers, and customers alike remember this, to get a good order is to
treat others well. An employee will react better to a customer who is 
good natured understanding and well informed. As is a customer better 
when an employee is good natured understanding and well informed. My 
experience is that McDonald&apos;s was not always fun, here&apos;s a story, 
There was a day where the Managers treated me like shit, here I was in 
my uniform being yelled at by customers and managers alike, why? Not 
for not working hard but because of the frustration. Being busy we 
all tend to get overwhelmed. If you must know how overwhelming it can 
be try working at a Mcdonalds for two weeks, see if you will what it 
is like to stand behind the counter and be expected to smile when a 
coworker calls in sick and customers wonder why it is slow? Or when 
you are performing multiple tasks and you have 25 cars at the drive 
through some laying on their horns, the lobby is full and you are 
running to and fro trying to please the hungry masses? To be customer 
aware one must work to serve! The service industry is and will always 
be a place for the one who can survive with patience, even those who 
are incredibly patient on the job such as I have our days. The above 
situation, being busy and having customers who are not aware of what 
they want, and then get mad at you because you are the one in uniform 
who they can scream at and you and only you can smile and say yes 
sir/yes ma&apos;am and then you and only you are expected to fix their 
situation. Multiply this a dozen times and then ask yourself would 
you be willing to do this for 6.75? And clean toilets, and fix greasy 
grimy food, and wear an ugly uniform to boot, day in and day out? 
Understand, if you can overcome this situation with pride in your work 
and make a grumpy customer laugh ah, then you have what it takes to 
make the situation shine. Try it? Balance your coworkers etc. 
Mcdonalds is great for a training ground of real life. Work there I 
dare you before you complain and you will see that 90% of all 
McDonald&apos;s employees do indeed do their best. Those 10% who don&apos;t 
don&apos;t survive that long. Have a great day and SMILE!
John Jones

-- John Jones ( John_Jones @hotmail.com ), November 10, 2002. Do you really want to help fight the war on junk food? Visit 
http://www.TakeAFruitBreak.com
Thank you, bless you, and keep on keeping on!
Johanna

-- Johanna Garrick ( info@takeafruitbreak.com ), November 15, 2002. ronald smiley love you so, maybe more if you would go, ronald smiley fill my tummy, make me sick and take my money, ronald liar liar so, want the world to really know, ronald smiley hurts our kids, TAKES THEIR HEARTS AND FEEDS THEM FIBS. we don&apos;t like ronald.....he sure is a clown. from kez.

-- kerry kay ( zac@oalink.com.au ), November 16, 2002. &quot;The McLibel Support Campaign urges consumers to boycott McDonald&apos;s 
fast-food restaurants in response to the company&apos;s efforts to censor 
its critics. McDonald&apos;s has used threats of legal action for many 
years to silence criticism of its business practices. Through the 
use of libel suits, McDonald&apos;s has attempted to stifle the voices of 
protestors criticizing the company&apos;s policies regarding promoting 
unhealthy food, targeting children in advertising campaigns, being 
anti-union and paying low wages, cruelty to animals, etc.&quot; well... 
first of all its their product they have a right to promote it... if 
children are number 1 in their demographics, then why shouldnt they 
target them? fast food stores obviously can not afford to pay high 
wages (which unions will inevitably incur) ... costs are way too 
high to offer huge wages, which is why people do not work at fast 
food chains for a lifetime! i dono about that animal thing but im 
pretty sure its false... anyways...

-- Kristof ( k_pimpson@hotmail.com ), November 18, 2002. I am a manager at a mcdonald&apos;s restaurant and the reason what you get 
does not look like the pictures on the menu board is because they are 
plastic models of the sandwiches...it isn&apos;t real food. if you go to 
mcdonald&apos;s, it&apos;s because you want fast food. i&apos;d like to see you 
make dozens of sandwiches looks beautiful in under 50 seconds. if 
you want your food to look nice, go to a real restaurant, not fast 
food.

-- Andrea ( ace_aladdin69@hotmail.com ), November 20, 2002. IF YOU PEOPLE DONT LIKE IT, DONT EAT IT!!!!!!!!! ITS SIMPLE...BITCH 
ABOUT SOMETHING ELSE! GET A DAMN LIFE.

-- dave kirk ( osudk33@aol.com ), November 21, 2002. You people need to calm down please!! I may be from Japan but I have 
tried McDonalds millions of times and like it. Children in the U.S 
who eat McDonlads most of the time will get overweight and end up on 
diets just to save themselves, dinking 1% milk for a living. I have 
seen kids who are only 8 and who already weigh over 200 pounds or 
maybe 300 my point is maybe the parents who are giving these kids 
food should think about cutting down, people around the U.S who are 
under the age of 12 have already gone threw bypass surgery in order 
to live and think Oh I am saved and slim , now I can go back on my 
bad eating habits and they get fat again and then the parents come 
in bitching suing them since they think its their faults when it is 
not. Honestly in my opinion parents should not have been letting 
their child have money to go buy these fast foods. Luckily they are 
changing the food this febuary, as I will say IF YOU DONT FUCKIN 
LIKE IT THEN DONT FUCKIN EAT IT!

-- Kenjetsu Nobunaga ( kenjigaliant@yahoo.com ), November 25, 2002. im not sure where some of your friends have worked, but i&apos;ve worked at 
mcdonalds for 2 years and there have been no chicken heads or rat 
pieces served, and people are scheduled to clean for their shift. and 
sorry but i have to comment on the advertising poster argument, im 
surprised that some of you take it seriously and expect your burger to 
look perfect. the key words here are fast and food. it is also a 
policy that anything to hit the floor, goes in the garbage, including 
paper bags. i will admit that the serve can be crappy, but rather 
than campaign and complain, move on. this is hardly a cause worth 
fighting for. yet &quot;the customer is always right&quot; so if you are 
unsatisfied, try calling the management at the restaurant and they 
would be happy to help.

-- duckie ( dodiezone@hotmail.com ), November 26, 2002. I worked at McDonalds for 2 days , I thought it was a great place to 
work for 2 days!

-- Roger Comer ( comer@northlink.com ), December 01, 2002. dont eat that shit!!! about half of mcdonalds hamburgers have 
traces of feces in them! so unless your really dying for a juciy 
shit burger id stay away from that shit...no pun inteded

-- budha man ( foo@bar.com ), December 09, 2002. i think you are all fuckin gay

-- jonny hart ( pimprocker@rock.com ), December 17, 2002. Wow, I have never read such uneducated comments. Do any of you 
realize that McDonald&apos;s has the #1 ranked College in the world? 
Hamburger University is visited by students world wide. If you want 
to try to eat the burgers in the pictures, I hope you like raw meat 
with a quarter missing from the back and a wax coating. All 
resurants do this in their ads. It takes HOURS to make those 
sandwiches, and I don&apos;t think anyone wants to wait that long. 
McDonald&apos;s does not &quot;smear&quot; all their burgers with sause. With the 
exeption of a Big Mac, Chicken and Filet. The sandwiches have 
nothing more than Ketchup and mustard. The same stuff you buy in a 
store and put on your burger at home. The Mayo can be bought at any 
grocery store, as well as the lettuse, tomatoes, buns, etc. The meat 
is real beef and all beef. Mater of fact, the beef in the sandwiches 
is all raised and buchered in the USA. The chicken is real chicken 
and the fish is Cod. McDonald&apos;s holds themselves to the highest 
standards in the industry for quality, service and cleanlyness. The 
store inspections are often and difucult. Your experiance at one 
store is NOT an accurate reflection of all stores.
There is now possible way to pay the employees better than minimum 
unless you want to pay $10 for a cheeseburger. McDonalds is the only 
fast food resturant the has a medical van that provides treatment to 
children in the slums. The only fast food resturant chain that 
provides homes to parents whose children are hospitalized. 
McDonald&apos;s can&apos;t be to blame for parents bad choices anymore than 
Mattel, Walmart, Barbie, Burger King or any other company that 
targets children. The parents make the desion to buy or not to buy 
the products. If your child is wining because they want McDonalds 
and you don&apos;t want to buy it, don&apos;t. It the freedom of choice and 
children do not always get what they want. If you want the prize and 
don&apos;t want the buy the food. Then just buy the prize. Try just 
buying the prize with Lucky Charms.
The last thing McDonald&apos;s wants to do is harm their customers, since 
no customers equils no money. Honestly, I feel customers need to 
take classes on politeness. Employees can&apos;t keep that smile with 200 
people putting them down. Considering the vast majority of employees 
are highschool kids and college kids, for most of them, McDonald&apos;s is 
their first job, and in most places, McDonald&apos;s employees are highly 
sout after employees for other businesses. They are well trained and 
able to handle all sorts of complaints and customers. They learn 
responcibility and timelyness. The employees that don&apos;t measure up 
are terminated, and in my experiance, have a dificult time finding a 
job afterwards.
Dis on McDonald&apos;s all you want but look around and see what they have 
done for comunities. Blame the parents not the companies.
PS. My kids only eat fast food 1 or 2 times a month, I am not a 
McDonald&apos;s employee or representitive, and I hold to my opinions.
Mandy

-- Mandy ( msladydeath@aol.com ), December 18, 2002. I might not have much of job to some people but i do get paid as much 
as a factoy person.Are lettuce isnt brown and i always keep up fresh 
food. Don&apos;t knock it til you tryed itIt&apos;s the food you would make at 
home.

-- Annette A Vankirk ( mcqueenoldly@aol.com ), December 20, 2002. Well am not really botherd ! its just i have to do an assignment 
about for uni !
I dont like the food any way, and the place are usally full of 
muppets, called malcom.
If people want to die of a heart attacts then eat their. The bugers 
are full of crap.

-- james harrison ( harrisonjames69@hotmail.com ), January 05, 2003. Fuck Mcdonalds, give me a chicken curry (minus chicken heads)and 
Carlsberg any day.
P.S. Read &quot;Fast Food Nation&quot; Enough said.
Fianna.... Jan 06 2003

-- Paul Reenan ( baileyr@eircom.net ), January 06, 2003. I love it. This is the kinda thing that keeps the world in 
wonderful chaos. Something as trivial as HAMBURGERS! So what if 
they have some shit in them? So what if little kids in Indochina 
make toys for their Happy Meal for next to nothing? If you don&apos;t 
get sick from eating there, and those kids wouldn&apos;t have a job 
otherwise, then there is nothing wrong. I do not work for or know 
anyone who works for a McDonald&apos;s, but I eat there sometimes. The 
food is, on the average, good, and the service sucks. Compromises. 
Regardless, its relatively cheap, and, although not healthy for the 
most part, easy to get in a rush and edible. That&apos;s my two cents.
P.S. Oh, and for the love of GOD please learn to spell. At least 
some of you. Please.

-- Anthony ( kain23789@yahoo.com ), January 23, 2003. Ok - we all know that the &apos;meat patties&apos; aren&apos;t exactly fillet-mignon. 
Fry it, add sauce, &apos;cheese&apos;, a pickle or two, a toasted bun - it&apos;s a 
cheap handy - some would say tasty -snack. The thing is, as the 
massive Greeley, Colorado beef recall in June &apos;02 showed yet 
again, not only is the food not healthy - i.e. high fat, high sodium, 
- it can kill you. The meatpacking company, ConAgra, was forced 
to recall 19 million pound of ground beef - enough for 150 million 
hamburgers. This was due to an e. coli outbreak. This can - and 
has been fatal. Children have died - in America - as a result of 
this kind of extreme food-poisoning. Of course the &apos;odds&apos; of it 
happening to you are minimal - you are much more likely to be 
hit by a drunk driver.
 To be balanced, though, I must say I used to find this kind of 
fast-food very tasty. I just don&apos;t eat it anymore - because it&apos;s 
dangerous.
 I also look left and right before I cross the road...

-- chazzer ( slapcow@hotmail.com ), January 25, 2003. Man this is just one big bich session like does it realy matter. who 
realy gives a flying fuck. P.S this page is getting way to long, 
realy do something

-- big ron ( donyjob@dotnet.com ), February 03, 2003. Although i am a prostitute, i occasionally get past the exceptionally 
high standards of mcdonalds and enjoy a rigorous beef sandwich, then 
go home with my newfound STD&apos;s to my homosexual husband Paul Gyle who 
works in a shitty shop in portadown, northern Ireland.

-- Roberta Gyle ( the_filthy_sanchez@hotmail.com ), February 23, 2003. Although i am a prostitute, i occasionally get past the exceptionally 
high standards of mcdonalds and enjoy a rigorous beef sandwich, then 
go home with my newfound STD&apos;s to my homosexual husband Paul Gyle who 
works in a shitty shop in portadown, northern Ireland and abuses the 
trust of young boys, but a smart one dumped him innit, making me the 
single earner- more hardcore jizz for me then!

-- Roberta Gyle ( the_filthy_sanchez@hotmail.com ), February 23, 2003. If you dont like it then dont eat it, quit complaining about it. 
And some of you are complete ignorent fucks, not many but a few. 
its simple JUST DONT EAT IT IF YOU DONT LIKE IT OR DONT AGREE WITH 
IT!!! if you do then its all the same, enjoy. personaly i think its 
crap but i doo eat it sometimes more for convenience then anything. 
and sorry if i cant spell.....its a stupid fucking thread,its not a 
big deal.

-- Mike Ronning ( spikenob@crackdealer.com ), March 02, 2003. I love the food. It is quite tasty. I love the quick service.

-- A LEE ( aqsas@yahoo.com ), March 08, 2003. I don&apos;t know if This board is really dead or not. I haven&apos;t worked 
at a Mc Donald&apos;s before. But I have worked at a Kentucky Fried 
Chicken and Burger King before. And well even though it could get 
gross sometimes. We never ever were that gross (you know not washing 
hands.. bloody meat and what not) I think largely a lot of this is an 
exaggeration. But One thing though. I read a few posts back about 
not knowing when a sanitation and or a health inspection comes 
around. That&apos;s not true. Places know when an inspector is coming, 
so that&apos;s why many of these places aren&apos;t shut down.
Also, I&apos;ve seen numerous posts saying that you get what you pay for. 
For a burger fries and a soda you pay nearly 5-6 dollars. For a 
family of 5 that&apos;s 25 Dollars. For that price I think everyone 
should go to their local diner or hell go to their pancake house.. 
Get a soda and a burger (the ones here come with fries) and spend a 
dollar more and know that your food is of a higher quality. I think 
it&apos;s just come down to people being lazy and not wanting to wait for 
food nowadays.
Also someone said that Mc Donald&apos;s makes children happy or something 
along that line. Yes, it may make those children happy. But 10 
years down the line when they are just another overweight citizen. 
You&apos;ll see how happy they are. Now I&apos;m not anti Mc Donald&apos;s. I&apos;m 
just anti Fast food. I feel that if you Are going to be Anti Mc 
Donald&apos;s you should not eat at any other fast food place. Anywhere 
where your food has been precooked or is pretty much waiting for 
you.. well.. is just as evil as Mc Donald&apos;s. There is no picking and 
choosing. There is no Well I&apos;m going to protest Mc Donald&apos;s and then 
turn around and eat at Burger King. Anyway.. my rant is done :) I 
hope I&apos;ve made sense.. and if no one reads this anymore.. well.. 
nevermind then
Arienette

-- Arienette ( glitrbtch@aol.com ), March 11, 2003. -I am a manager at McDonald&apos;s, and have been for 2 years, and I only 
make $6.00 an hour. Excuse me for being a little bitch, but quite 
frankly I don&apos;t give a damn if you like our food or not. I eat it, 
my momma, eats and my daddy! And we are alive and well. So what if 
we are a little slow. Its not like we get a lot of recognition for 
what we do. We are HUMAN and working at McDonald&apos;s is not as easy as 
you think. We have a lot of rules and regulations to follow and our 
standards are higher than any other fast food establishment. By the 
way, the reason we don&apos;t wear gloves is because we wash our hands on 
the hour every hour. If you don&apos;t like it bend over and kiss my 
ASS!!!

-- Chuck ( masterchucky@hotmail.com ), March 12, 2003. If any of you have been reading this message board because you 
honestly want facts about why McDonald&apos;s and some other fast food 
chains have nearly destroyed the health and well-being of Americans 
and others around the world then you need to read Eric Schlosser&apos;s 
Fast Food Nation. It is an informative critical piece of 
investigative journalism and holds a tremendous amount of truth on 
fast food corporations and slaughterhouses. I am not a vegetarian 
and this book&apos;s goal was not to make me one. However, I do feel as 
a citizen of this amazing United States, we have the right to be 
informed about what we are putting into our bodies and we can each 
make our own choices about what we decide to eat. I have decided 
that it is a better choice for me not to eat at McDonald&apos;s or any 
other fast food restaurants. Read this book and make your own 
choice or be informed some other way, but don&apos;t be ignorant to the 
fact that fast food, although cheap and easy, may not be the most 
healthy choice you could make for yourself or your children.

-- Susannah Holmes ( susannaholmes@msn.com ), March 15, 2003. yo i work at mcdonalds in the uk, and me and my mate who also works 
there have made this site - its &quot;1001 ways to slack off at 
mcdonalds&quot;, with loads of great ideas for others who work there. we 
havent got many yet, but we have a growing archive. i think the food 
is ok, but working there is bollocks. nontheless, others who work 
there can take heart, because of all these cool ideas. sign our 
guestbook, and spread the word to all your workfriends!! 
YEEAAAHHH !!!!
www.geocities.com/mc_slackers

-- Rolstron McPhee ( allodave76@hotmail.com ), March 17, 2003. You are all missing the point, and the point is, they dont have a 
responsability to make the food healthy, they dont have a 
responsability to make sure everyone is happy with the way their 
burger looks. The fact is, that most people accept that mcdonalds 
does touch up their commercials and print ads, that the burger you 
buy isn&apos;t exactly like the commercial, but does that stop the mass 
population worldwide from buying it? No, and it won&apos;t anytime soon. 
So get off your high horses. If you don&apos;t like it, dont eat it.

-- Steve ( rochettes@beer.com ), March 19, 2003. I also forgot to mention that if we were to blast mcdonalds for lying 
intheir comercial, than we need to blast everyone in the commercial 
industry. Do you think that mcdonalds is the only company to do 
this? Cereal commercials use glue instead of milk, ice cream 
commercials use colored fat---yes, fat--- to simulate ice cream, and 
how smooth it is to scoop and serve. The point is, thats 
advertising. Nobody gives you what the product is, they give you 
what will make you interested in buying it. So please, have a big n 
tasty on me.

-- steve ( rochettes@beer.com ), March 19, 2003. for a company that started from nothing and turned themselves into 
billion dolar company you&apos;d think would owe the customers (who made 
them so rich) a decent meal. Instead they have raised prices and 
dropped standards. McDonalds is destroying the world.

-- shimmy shekker ( bigherby@yahoo.com ), March 23, 2003. http://www.disgusting.co.za
Makes interesting reading and sublime pictures.

-- Sadly sickened ( disgusting@sick.co.za ), March 31, 2003. in response to the post by -- Your Friendly Neighborhood McDonalds 
employee (OzzyDemon9@aol.com), May 20, 2002. 
i worked at mcdonalds for a summer and i and one other employee were 
the only competent people in the place and no it is not clean at all.
btw what the hell is the grimace? i really want to know

-- McDonalds Sucks so does grimace ( Samfisher864@aol.com ), April 09, 2003. All food purchases are political.
Here in America we don&apos;t bother to vote in elections - but we vote 
everyday with our dollars - whether we know it or not.
THINK about where your food comes from and then buy 
accordingly.
If you like McDonalds eat there, but don&apos;t do it while ignorant of 
the impact of this huge corporation on the planet and on your 
personal health.
Think.
PS This whole post would be shorter and sweeter without the 
word &quot;Fuck&quot;. (Not that I have anything against fucking - I just hate 
when it&apos;s use as a superlative is abused. It really should be 
saved for special occasions.)

-- Reverend Wolf ( coffeesnob3@earthlink.net ), April 09, 2003. I dont usually get caught up in these pathetic debates but felt the 
need this time.
Alot of the problems stem from the American McDonalds I cant comment 
there but I can say that in the UK we have much better standards 
better pay well if your first language is english your ok.
The Health&amp;Safety and Food Safety and all the other related bodies 
over here dont give a crap about how big McDonalds is if they find 
anything wrong they will close the place down and indeed there have 
been some stores which have been closed down.
I have worked at McDonalds whenever I needed extra cash etc and have 
been with them for about 6 years and usually my pay is 6 per hour 
for all you Yanks that is $10 per hour and our minimum wage is 4.35.
When people are so desperate for a job that they will work for a 
pittance then they shall recieve a pittance.
As usual you Yanks have created these problems yourself by the 
reasons stated in pasts posts and the major one being IGNORANCE a 
major factor that has been standing out in most of the posts.
Expecting too much for so little etc not giving a crap about what it 
takes to make your food etc.
When I first started I was faced with customers who gave us abuse 
etc but instead of just accepting it I told them in their faces if 
they didnt like it then go elsewhere. This carried the message that 
staff were not going to tolerate crap from the customer.
In the worst stores security personal are employed to protect crew 
members as over here we are treated like people and not just 
mindless subordinates.
Most customers start giving crap due to other reasons stress at work 
etc and they think McDonalds employees wont and cant do anything 
back. So all you employees stand up for yourselves mind you we dont 
have the risk of anyone shooting us.
Oh Im getting late for my next shift have to go now.

-- Secret MCD employee ( data323uk@lycos.co.uk ), April 10, 2003. i hate that mcdonalds actually calls what it makes food.Now there is 
false advertising.

-- Mr scot tum licker ( mortimersmuscle@hotmail.com ), April 12, 2003. I WORKED FOR MCDOANLDS FOR TWO AND A HALF YEARS IN NEW ZEALAND 
DISTRUBUTION AND I CAN TELL YOU ABOUT THE SEUAL HARRESSMENT BYT EH 
DAUGHTER (SUSAN DAVIES) THE DAUGHTER OF THE DIRECTOR OF MCDONALDS 
DISTRUBUTION FOR THE PACIFIC RIM BASED IN NEW ZEALAND. I CAN TELL YOU 
ABOUT THE BUN FREEZER NEVER BEEN CLEAN (THE FLOOR) IN THE TWO AND A 
HALF YEARS WHERN I WAS THERE. I CAN TELL YOU ABOUT THE SEXUAL 
HARRESSMENT AND ALL THE WITINESS I HAVE AND THE FACT THAT THEY HAVE 
PAID THEM ALL OFF INCLUDING MY FAMILY AND THE NEW ZEALAND POLICE AND 
THE HARRESSMENT FROM THEM AS WELL TO PROTECT SUSAN DAVIES.
I CAN TELL YOU ABOUT THE FIJIEN COACROACHES COMING BACK FROM FIJI IN 
THE BOXES (DEAD I HOPE)I CAN ALSO TELL ABOUT WHAT I DID AND THAT IS 
URINTE IN CONTAMINATED WATER (IN A BARREL) THAT WAS LEFT THERE FOR 
TWO DAYS AND I APOLOGISED AND LEFT MY JOB BUT HAD TWO APOLOGISE TWICE 
FOR I WAS ONE OF THEIR HARDEST WORKERS AND I BELIEVE THAT THEY MAY 
NOT HAVE WANTED ME TO LEAVE.
I CAN TELL YOU ABOUT THE TIMES (TWICE) WHEN THEY POISONED ME WITH 
MCHICKEN BURGERS WHILE WORKING THEIR AND NOT EVEN GETTING AN 
APOLOGIY. TO THIS DAY I HAVE TRIED TO GET THE WORD OUT ABOUT 
MCDONALDS AND THE FACT THAT THEY ARE ONE OF THE MOST CORREUPT 
COMPANYS I HAVE EVER WORKED FOR AND THE FACT THEY HIDE AND PAY OFF SO 
MANY PERSONS ITS NOT FUNNY TO KEEP THEIR PRECIOUS NAME INTACT.

-- EMIL JOSEPH FISHER ( TATAI@YAHOO.CO.NZ ), May 01, 2003. Hi! How are you? Me fine. Yes they lie in their ads, like the ads 
when at the end it said SMILE, and it means respect and friendly and 
homy, it is far from it, here is a letter that I sent to them in 
February and my letter siad anonymous, the finally found out who 
wrote this letter, it was me, so a young lady there found out it was 
me, I think family is working there or something, and she treated me 
very rude at the drive thru twice already, saying to me that if the 
order is not ready and if someone else is at the back of my car
I will let you park there for the others, but at the same time there 
was nobody there at the back of me and she said once that my order 
was not ready, because of the fries, but I saw her put the fries in 
bag and she let them stay there and I was waiting for about five 
minutes, and she finally gave me the bag but my food was all cold and 
the fries was harden. And now everyone is laughing at me there and I 
think I will become an anti-Mcdonald person because of all this. my 
letter below was not that harsh, it was very human and understanding 
and way below that is the letter that I am contemplating to send 
there, but I do not know if it will do good, I think this forum will 
therapeutic for me, because it has been hell for me with them lately.
Those teenagers can not even accept criticism, can you imagine going 
in the real work force when graduating from college, they will 
harrass the bossses and the managers of thsoe business, anyway, I had 
to do this, it is the first time posting on those kind of forum or 
thread and it is very intimidating. I am 35 byt he way, but in the 
second letter contemplating I lie because I want to confuse them, it 
is not me, but I think it is agains my principle I think. Anyway here 
it goes the letter and the second one. No respect at all those 
teenagers and young adults through 21. At least overhere.
There is something worst than that that happend to me but will stay 
it this way, I was mistreated a lot by them and by a Dairy Queen here 
too. I do not know, what I got on my face that those youngster do not 
like, I am starting to question myself. I am being very polite with 
them saying thank you and please and have a nice day and all those 
protocols. But with no avail.
February 20th, 2003
Dear Sir or Mrs:
Hi! How are you on this day? 
 I am French but I am writing in English, 
because
I am more comfortable with that language.
 I am living in Edmundston.
 I am and I was a big customer of yours for a 
long while, but now I am writing you this if I may please.
 Here it is:
As you know I was a big customer of yours, 
now it had change, because of the deplorable service that you are 
giving. The young ladies and men, but the young ladies in the most 
part, because it is almost all ladies who serve us at the Drive Thru 
or at the stand, very rare some men, will serve us, anyway it is not 
my purpose of this letter. Yes the service is very abysmal and the 
food too. 
 Concerning the service, the young people who 
serves us at your Edmundston outlet, lacks some respect and some 
civility. They are rude and selfish and do not care at all 
about the feelings of others, especially the clients, I was going at 
your outlet about three times a week, quite a big customer and I was 
paying around eight dollars per meal, quite
expensive now, to eat at your outlet, and as a return, I think we the 
clients, we deserve a a lot more than the way they are treating us or 
at least me and my parents. 
 They have no smile in their face, no courtesy, 
no tact and the most important thing, the love to work and the uses 
they are doing, it is quite apparent right in their eyes, I have 
tried everything possible, even giving them tips and be nice to them 
and to say take care and the like, but with no avail. The service
and the persons working at the two posts, drive thru or stands lacks 
a course in human development and human relation, I think, they would 
need a good doze of humility and to wake them up.
Concerning the foods, well lets start with the hamburgers or
quarter pounders or the chickens, especially sandwiches, in take out 
or eat in, the hamburgers are all squeezed so much, that the bread 
are all dent or all tear apart and the meat inside are all cold or so 
squeezed that the sandwich is all in a bad shape and the fries, many 
times, I was given, the left overs, only small tidbits and all curly 
and all hard and not chewable at all, and it seems that they were 
cooked many times over, and the large coke
are half full or empty and it is only ice and it does not taste like 
coke, it taste like washout water. They are doing this on purpose.
They never give pails and napkins, and we always have to ask for some 
ketchup, and when we ask for some more, they give us less, we do not 
have any condiments or few. The fries are always at the bottom of the 
bag, not in its container, and the food, is always cold. The positive 
though, service is quite fast usually. But this is the only positive 
though.
The ones at the service, when at the Drive Thru, we are showing them 
our debit card to pay, they are always angry and they are showing the 
eyes you know, and they are almost throwing the gadget in our faces. 
Quite sometimes, the clients in front of me had dogs and the ones
(usually young ladies) at the drive thru at the service, were 
touching the dog and the dogs were liking their hands, and after this 
they were serving me or somebody else after, not quite sanitary, and 
they were doing some favoritism for their friends, when I got inside 
for service and sometime at the drive thru, they were parking me at 
the side, and serving their friends, I saw it, they were having some 
fun mocking at me or somebody else, I was just ordering a coke and a 
small hamburger. I got laughed at and right in front of my face, even 
one of the manager. I said to myself, I do not have the rights to to 
have something here?
He was treating me, just like I was a criminal. Is it good service 
with all this said, I do not thinks so. It needs a lot of 
improvement, because in the past years it has dwindled 
quite rapidly. 
So here is the things that I saw in the past years, especially the 
past three years:
1. Lack of respect
2. No smile
3. No appreciation to serve the clients
4. No love for the job (Far cry of what people in my age at your 
restaurant was back then)
5. Always rudeness
6. Not sanitary(dog liking and such that I saw)
7. The sandwiches are all squeezed and in mush
8. The fries are always cold or re heat or something like that 
9. The sodas do not taste like sodas and not full at all and to much 
ice(I know that you have a limit of ice to put in)
10. No condiments at all, even no pails and napkins(the necessity). 
When asking for a big bunch of small ketchup, we only have four or 
even none. The ones at the service, not very concentrated.
11. The most important thing of all, passion to serve the clientele, 
they have none of it. They all do this to shove it off and next and 
shove it off again.
12. Lack of civility(always groaning and using some foul language 
especially with me) I am doing nothing to them, I am just going there 
to get some foods and be polite. I will explain myself of what type 
of a person I am in the next section.
13.Only one young lady who respected me a lot and she is not there 
anymore, she is gone to study, she was good and very nice and do not 
see her a lot lately in the past year.
14.The service is fast usually.
15. The young ladies are attacking my intelligence a lot, they sees 
me like I was an idiot. That is lack of respect and civility that I 
was talking about. Young men are always working somewhere else, they 
are less attacking me or my parents.
About myself, I am a devout Christian and
I care about humanity a lot and is trying to follow the ten 
commandments as much as possible, I care about all of you there. And 
for your success. My past time is Astronomy and to study religions 
and ancient civilizations and the new sciences like nanotechnology 
and the like. I really care and try to like and to respect the others 
very much and to be passionate and know my uses. Practicality. I am 
call the humanitarian, I am planning in the future to do some church 
planting for some religion
in some area in need. That is the type of man I am. Maybe I look like 
an idiot, but I am not. So as you can see that I am not doing this to 
harm everybody at your outlet, but to help. To wake people up.
 I will come back to your outlet and see what is 
going on and if I do not see some improvement, I will post this 
letter on the web or go higher in the hierarchy of Mcdonald&apos;s 
Restaurants, even if it is by myself delivering this letter to the 
CEO on the International Headquarters. I am really serious.
And this is a really serious letter and matters. I am not playing the 
fool here.
Thank you very much of hearing my cries and the 
patience that you have to read this letter, it is appreciated.
Thank you for your attention and collaboration.
Take good care of all of you and stay safe. God be with you all and 
us all. Prayers.
Client of yours
 Anonymous
(doing this
 for a 
reason)
P.S. Do you want to say to the ones at the Drive Thru to accept tips 
from the debit card if possible. I forgot that. 
 I really hate to complaint, I rather like to write you a 
compliments letter, but at this conjecture I can not.
The second letter contemplating:
Dear McDonalds:
Hi! How 
are you? Me I am fair to semi-fine. I am getting poorer everyday. 
Anyway, this is not my purpose of
this letter, my purpose is this:
I do not 
know if you remember the letter
that I sent you I think in February. Concerning the service, and I 
explained
who I was at the end of the letter, and I was courageous enough to go
to the CEO of McDonalds Canada or the World and handed them the 
letter
myself, if I did not see any progress on your service here in 
Edmundston at
your outlet. Well your note back then was an F to D-, but now it has 
gone up to a D to a D+, it is improving concerning the fries and the 
pails and
a few smiles, and you finally woke up and have now some young men 
serving us, this is why to big improvement in the mark, it is a 
breath of
fresh air, to see young men have the same treatment has young ladies
and equal opportunity, because it was becoming more and more one 
sided.
I think, when I said, it was rare to have young men or men serving 
us, did
something, I do not know. The only thing they are struggling, 
especially
young ladies and some men, it is in the condiments side, they are not
very generous, always forgetting the ketchup and the like, with 
practice I thing it will come, and to park on the side to serve 
friends before me it happened again in the past weeks, completely 
unprofessional, maybe
because my car is burning oil and is a rust bucket, and sometimes it 
can smell awful, maybe this is why, when you are poor you are poor, 
there will
be less tips from me from now on. When your commercial on television 
is 
saying smile, there is not a lot still on the employees face and in 
some employers too, sometimes you are giving the stare of why you are 
here.
Besides that, I will go less time, I am on a diet, I could go take 
your light meals but the letters on the sign outside are not big 
enough, can not read it.
To small. This is a thing to fix. I will go again that is for sure, 
but not in the time that I was going usually. Service has improved, 
so this is encouraging for the future. I will send you another report 
within the next year, because my visits will be less and less. BEING 
LAUGHED AT I WILL NEVER ACCEPT THAT IN SUCH A PLACE.
I care about everyone there working, they are hard workers, I will 
pray for all of you. I really do care. If you known me, you will all 
see.
This letter is a very serious one, not to waste the Managers and 
employees time. I wanted to be more positive this time. It is 
positive nut a lot to do to have an excellent for me it is an 
excellent mark as a B+. I am confident it will go there in the 
future. Take care of those hamburgers they are sensible.
Take care and a la prochaine. Smile very important.
No matter how is the life of all of you in your personal life, to 
smile at someone can help relief stress., Just to help that is all.
Client more 
 
 satisfied.
P.S. About the being laughed at thing, well let me put it that way:
This is a complete lack of professionalism and lack of maturity and 
lack
of judgment, lack of RESPECT most of all. Can you believe this when 
they will go to work in some office or somewhere like that and can 
not face criticism and always trying to get even or to laughed at 
those who wants service or something like that and not face humility 
like a good Christian
or a good citizen, this is the low end of respectability. I am fed up 
about this
especially in place like yours or anywhere matter of fact. It is good 
to be
tough, but it is not good to laughed and to improvised things. This 
is the 
most of the teenagers to day and young adults to age 21 or a bit 
older are at.
Mcdonalds before was class and respect and the employees was the most 
high in standard now, there is none of that. Sorry I have to tell it 
as it is.
I am not angry but very very upset.
I using my tools to convey my message. This is the tools of 
controlling
my emotions.
Again take care and please be careful out there, life is rocky, 
believe me I know, I know crisis.
Like you all still. That is why I am doing this.
P.S.2 Concerning the healthy meals list outside with the price, it 
is too small, I think when you are in your late forties the eyes are 
less capable.
I am doing some self explanatory here to explain better what is the 
condition, and imagine other people. I should go to the Optometrist to
have a subscription to have glasses, or contact lenses. Because I will
need it to order those meals of what I ordering.
You can share this letter to all the employees if you want, it will 
help
them to improve. I am not doing this for me solely but for your outlet
to succeed and by the way I am forgiving. I will forgive them. Maybe
I am to advance in age to understand teenagers and young adults.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PATIENCE TO ALL WHO READ ALL THIS, IT IS 
APPRECIATED, I NEEDED TO SHARE THIS.
TAKE CARE AND PRAYERS TO ALL OF YOU.
SERGE.

-- Serge ( wisdomandhumanity@yahoo.com ), May 12, 2003. I think that Mc Donalds stink. i can&apos;t really be bothered to go into 
any detail, because i have no sink basin to puke into afterwards. 
infact, they disgust me MORE than nestl (and Kraft, Procter&amp;Gamble and Sara Lee). they&apos;re all greedy pigs who get other people 
to do their dirrty work. 
and yes this is partly to do with mc donalds food. its made by SLAVE-
 LABOUR 
when i go past that resturant i see people munching on huge, fatty, 
greasy hamburgers. i still wonder if they know Mc Donalds dirty 
little secret........

-- Hannah Parkens ( racho_da_emu@yahoo.co.uk ), May 18, 2003. word to the death of corporate bull shit. food should be cooked. 
however bitching about it does no good. simple solution:
eat there if you like it.
dont eat there if otherwise unsatisfied.
Plus on a more personal note; the Mc D&apos;s here in japan put terriaki 
sauce on their burgers and believe me I didn&apos;t like the ones in the 
states so having a foreign hamburger with foreign fixings was a 
simple cross your fingers and pray type of experiment. I didn&apos;t like 
it.
The fries were okay though and they only took like 5 minutes to make 
it. It was cheap and well cooked, it just didn&apos;t taste good to me. 
Arguably better than the states but unfortunately i do not know about 
the rest of the world.
simple plans, simple solutions, simple means, for simple minds.

-- D00lvl - USAF ( the_dirty_old_man_down_the_hall@yahoo.com ), May 31, 2003. Hmm...
So much debate over such a little burger... literally. It&apos;s not the 
high fat content, the poor hygeine, or even the underpaid oppressed 
staff that bothers me. Although believe me it does- but that is not 
my main concern. My main concern is the &quot;hidden cost&quot; of such a 
(supposedly) cheap form of food. Heart disease and a generation of 
fatty fatty bom bom children not withstanding, it&apos;s the forest 
degradation that is the main concern here. Fat children? Birth out 
some more. Unhappy cattle? They&apos;ll breed some more. Million year old 
trees that take endless years to grow and mature... hmm, that&apos;s a bit 
of a tricky one. Unless they can figure out how to splice tree DNA 
with some hapless animal, I doubt we&apos;ll be birthing out any of those 
in a hurry. Which poses the problem or, should I say, the question, 
is this food, this food that everyone freely acknowledges doesn&apos;t 
taste that great, worth the price? All this grumbling about 
your &quot;McHappy&quot; meals... Take a step back and really try to envision a 
world without rainforests. They do a lot more for our race than 
merely look pretty. If you don&apos;t know what I&apos;m saying then go read a 
book on them. There are endless texts written about forests, 
indicative of their importance to our world and our existence. When 
the rainforests are gone, the habitat a mere memory, and we are left 
wondering where they went, know this: the trees went into the $3.95 
burger you&apos;re so eager to devour and then have the audacity to 
complain about. You think you&apos;ve got problems? Try being a tree.

-- long time reader, first time writer ( willthereeverbearainbow@hotmail.com ), June 01, 2003. Most of you are stupid and not educated. Most of you can&apos;t even 
spell...but that&apos;s beside the point. Why in the world would you 
believe what you do and complain like you do, but still go there? 
Then you wonder why Mcd&apos;s still thrives. I don&apos;t get it. Some of 
you have it right. If you don&apos;t like it, don&apos;t go there. I&apos;ve 
worked at a Mcd&apos;s for five years now. I&apos;ve never seen a chicken 
head nugget or a rat in my burger. I assure you, I&apos;ve eaten there 
enough times, that if this sort of thing really happened, I&apos;d surely 
have seen it by now. But sorry kids, no such luck. I&apos;m sure some 
Mcd&apos;s are better than others, but all the food comes from 
essentially the same place. And jeez, if you have enough time to 
write a friggen who knows how long letter like the above, then you 
need to find something better to occupy your time. Take up a hobby 
or something. This person said they were a frequent customer yet 
had plenty to complain about and continued to visit the 
establishment. Don&apos;t go there if these things are happening. 
Anyways, I have better things to do. Get over it.

-- I work for a living, what do you do? ( dont ThinkSo@blahblah.com ), June 06, 2003. I currently work at one of my local mcdonalds as a latenight 
manager, wich means I&apos;m there all night at our 24 hour drivethrough 
dealing with every drunk schmuck that tries to drive or walkthrough 
my lane. I CLEAN every machine in the restaurant, do all the 
prepwork, wich I have to add is done with fresh produce becasue we 
can&apos;t keep anything in the storerroom due to consumer demand. If 
anything looks even remotely off, or even hours past the holding 
time we THROUGH IT AWAY!!! I&apos;ve only been with the company for 4 
months and i&apos;m already making 8 bucks an hour wich is 2.10 above 
albertas minimum wage so I ain&apos;t complaining.
I came accross this forum while looking for the *correct* way to ban 
a costumer from my store.

-- Miranda Mae lee ( Raven_13_fem@hotmail.com ), June 09, 2003. Not only does McDonalds Lie about the looks and tastes of their 
burgers from store to store, that 10:30am lunch time is getting kind 
of old, some of us hefty meals in the morning. Sweet meals make my 
stomach hurt. This morning I was away from home and I stop into a 
McDonalds on the corner of Paramont an Carson streets in Long Beach, 
CA.It was 10:20am The guy who takes the orders says by their clock 
itis 10:20, No lunch. Ten minutes? Danm!

-- tyna inniss ( tynainn@hotmail.com ), June 13, 2003. why just attack mcdonalds?nothing looks like it does in the adverts 
wat about kfc,burger king,and not just fast food chains.ive seen lots 
of deceiving ads including cosmetics,loans and bank accounts.there is 
worse going on in the world than that.get a life.

-- marie reed ( niomifairweather@orange.net ), June 25, 2003. i think if u dont like mcdonalds dont go their im only 12 yrs old but 
i think some of you 40 year olds should stop whining like 4 year 
oldsif u dont like it dont go but stop being 
babies!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!1

-- fuck you ( huckleberry@hollywoodkids.com ), July 06, 2003. i totally agree with marie its everywhere and probably half of u ppl 
complaining work at a kfc or mcdonalds or burger king anywhere so 
shut up and its called FAST FOOD SO ITS NOT GONNA B PERFECT!!!!!!!!!!

-- fuck you ( huckleberry@hollywoodkids.com ), July 06, 2003. I dont know what the hell the majority of you people are talking 
about McDonalds for, because I work there and we are clean and give 
100% customer satisfaction we have had few complaints about our food 
and that was only because the pickles or onions were still on there 
instead of complaining about fast food why dont you get your lazy ass 
up and cook for yourself. I enjoy working at McDonalds I get 50 
minutes of break everyday I work and it is all paid plus free food. 
So instead of wasting time and talking shit about mcdonalds go into 
the kitchen and make yourself a crispy chicken sandwich

-- ( usa_froggie00@hotmail.com ), July 13, 2003. slavery must be stoped now. the burgers are not even burgers false 
meat not any thing like the adds on the banners

-- roger bright ( zimby001@hotmail.com ), July 22, 2003. I do not go in. McDonalds is CRAP food

-- gary wilson ( gary@wilerocks.fsnet.co.uk ), July 22, 2003. What is all your fuckin problem? If Mcdonalds was as bad as you sed 
it was then why is it like the best fast food site inthe world and 
why did i make 1000 in only 5 hrs. If it was that bad how come we 
have to send ppl away because were too full. How come we run out of 
2000 Happy Meal boxes in 1 day??? SHOVE THAT DOWN YOUR FUCKIN NECK! 
No one asked yout o go to McDonalds so dont fuckin go if you dont 
wanna go! GET A LIFE YOU LOOSERS

-- Ronald McDonald ESQ ( member_of_staff@mcdonalds.GET_A_LIFE.com ), July 24, 2003. McDonalds lies in their ads because the do not really sell food, well,
at least not food as we know it. Reconstituted chicken parts glued
togther with egg white, breaded and deep fried.
One does not even want to know what is in their ground &quot;beef&quot; and what
the federally acceptable levels of rat hair and excrement are.
Then their ads, geez, the sandwich should at least look something like
the product.
Anyway, I am McDonalds free for over 5 years. Join me.

-- Nobody&apos;s Here ( fubar@fst1.com ), July 31, 2003. Moderation questions? read the FAQ
	</body>
</document>
