<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007382" url="http://aliensandufos.forumco.com/topic.asp?TOPIC_ID=492&amp;whichpage=19" time="2012-07-13-00:21" support="23" score="0.05021973860802874" bingtitle="Aliens &amp; UFOs Among Us/Free the Herd Forum - Weekly Filer&apos;s Files ..." webtitle="Aliens&amp;UFOs Among Us/Free the Herd Forum - Weekly Filer&apos;s Files - Powered by ForumCo.com - The Forum Company">
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000482" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000490" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000499" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000498" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000495" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000493" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000484" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000478" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000470" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000479" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000494" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000476" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000485" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000475" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000469" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000488" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>Who knows... just those connected to high places and ... 12 years old, when I saw a gray being sitting by my food ... black object move behind the rear view mirror and exit ...</description>
	<body>
		Aliens&amp;UFOs Among Us/Free the Herd Forum Home | Profile | Register | Active Topics | Active Polls | Members | Private Messages | Search | FAQ 
 Username: 
 Password: 
 Save Password Forgot your Password? 

 
 
 



 


 
   All Forums 
   Aliens&amp;UFOs Among Us/Free the Herd 
   Aliens and UFOs 
  Weekly Filer&apos;s Files   New Topic  Topic Locked
   Printer Friendly 
 

 Previous Page | Next Page 

 
 
 Author  Topic  Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 of 21 
 Elrick 
 Galactic Member 
 


 

 USA 
 5595 Posts 
 
 Posted - 04/02/2007 : 2:07:47 PM     

FILERS FILES # 12 - 2007
By George Filer

See all the photos at: You must be logged in to see this link. 

Eastern MUFON Director
March 21, 2007

Dedicated to drowned 5 year old Georgie Filer V whose motto was

Be Happy



Space Station Films UFO

This weeks files cover: Mars: City of roads and large towers, Space Station Films UFO, President Carters sighting, Reference Last Weeks Filers Files: Five Year-Old Goes to Heaven Speculation on UFO Activities, and August Weather map of UFO sightings.

Unidentified Aerial Phenomena were spotted over: Alabama, Arkansas, Arizona, California, Illinois, Indiana, Kansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Texas, Vermont, Washington and Washington DC. UFOs were also seen in Australia, Canada, Columbia, Jamaica, and United Kingdom.

These Files assume that extraterrestrial intelligent life not only exists, but my hypothesis is that the over one hundred UFOs reported each week represent technologically advanced spacecraft conducting surveillance of Earth. I personally became interested in UFOs when I chased one over England when flying for the US Air Force. Ive been investigating them ever since. The US Air Force under Project Blue Book investigated UFOs for more than twenty years, we continue this research. Our goal is to uncover the secrets of UFOs. We are continuing the investigation and make the assumption we are not alone in the universe. Based on the large number of sightings we can assume Gods universe is greater than ever imagined. The Scientific Study of UFOs for the benefit of humanity. Expect More Sightings.



International Space Station Spots UFO



Jeff Challender reports, The International Space Station has been manned continuously since 1 November 2000. This in spite of a 2 year hiatus on US Space Shuttle flights subsequent to the loss of Shuttle Columbia on 1 February 2003. The Space Station crew commander is Michael Lopez-Alegria, Soyuz Piot/Flight Engineer is Mikhail Tyurin and the worlds first woman space tourist, Anoushe Ansari, occupies the third seat. The US Space Shuttle Discovery came calling in December during the STS-116 mission with docking on 11 December 2006. Supplies were delivered, and four EVAs were mounted from the Quest airlock to add the P5 Truss Segment and retract a stubborn solar array. Discovery left for home on 19 December, landing safely at KSC.

The EVA was not planned, and was added to retract a stuck KURS antenna on the Progress 23 cargo freighter that reached the ISSy on 26 October 2006. Docking was achieved in spite of this stubborn antenna. EVA 17 began with problems encountered in Cosmonaut Mikhail Tyurins Orlan space suit. His cooling system, did not work properly and he suffered abnormally high temperatures and his helmet visor repeatedly fogged over. The malfunction also created ice in the form of snowflakes, which drifted across the field of view for the first hour or so on EVA. The pesky antenna was finally cut loose with a bolt cutter, then tied down out of the way. EVA 17 lasted from 4:27 to 10:45 AM for a total 6 hours 18 minutes. Seven minutes before the crewmen opened the hatch, two interesting objects crossed the field of view at lower right of image. One of these is almost certainly a bit of debris knocked loose by the activities of the crew within the airlock. Its behavior was typical of such things.

A second object did NOT behave in a typical manner! It moved at very high velocity, and literally streaked by, at least when watched at original speed. When the video was slowed down to 10% normal, it could actually be seen to move in fits and starts. This thing was not moving smoothly at all, but was flitting and stopping, and flitting again.

I cant account for this. There is nothing normally seen in space which can do this. Not meteors, ice chips, debris, satellites, or astronomical bodies. Considering the reports of numerous snow flakes associated with the faulty subliminator in Cosmonaut Tyurins space suit that day, it might be tempting to assume that this object was merely one of them. BUT, the airlock hatch was not opened for another seven minutes. The clouds of ice flakes coming from Tyurins subliminator could not have escaped the airlock compartment until that hatch was opened to space.

The pictures are enlarged to make them easier to see. All animated GIFs of the anomaly are composed of 22 frames captured from the original video tape recorded live at the time. There are NO gaps in the sequence. All frames with the object in sight are included. This anomaly is outlined with a semi-transparent circle to help you find it. Note the speed of its passage across the field of view. Now we have the same 250% zoomed view just as it appeared originally. The object moves so fast, it makes one wonder how a bit of debris or ice, which is NOT common on ISSy, could be accelerated to such speeds. This object defies explanation. This is not only for its incredible speed and ability to start and stop so fast, but also for the fact that the shadow of the PIRS module did not obscure it in the first few frames of its traverse, as was the case with the second object. Thanks to Jeff Challender You must be logged in to see this link. 

MARS: CITY OF ROADS, LARGE TOWERS

Norman Bryden writes, In this section of a Mars Global Surveyor image there are several interesting structures. Please look slightly to the left and above center is a lighter colored area.

If you look closely you can see what looks like an oddly shaped tower with a road passing behind this structure. To the upper right of this section is another slightly lighter oval-shaped area. There is what appears to be a group of large oddly shaped tower-like or building-like structures. If you look closely you can make out features similar to beams and levels such as scaffolding and girders. Near the lower right hand corner of this section is what looks like some kind of shiny dome structure, with a road leading up to the edge. This area looks to be densely populated with structures. Details such as this demand further investigation as it looks like Mars was once or still is inhabited by a technologically advanced race. Thanks to Norman Bryden Link to NASA Image:
 You must be logged in to see this link. You must be logged in to see this link. 
Joseph P. Skipper discovered a skull like formation taken by Mars Spirit Rover 513 near Gustuv Crater.

President James Earl Carter

When Governor of Georgia at a Southern Governors Conference I dont laugh at people any more when they say theyve seen UFOs. Ive seen one myself. It was the darndest thing Ive ever seen. It was big; it was very bright; it changed colors and it was about the size of the moon ....We watched it for ten minutes, but none of us could figure out what it was.



&quot;One things for sure, Ill never make fun of people who say theyve seen unidentified objects in the sky. If I become President, Ill make every piece of information that this Country has about UFO sightings available to the public and scientists. [Later, after he had been elected to the Presidency, he changed his mind.]

Reference Filers Files 11, Child Goes to Heaven

In Derrel Sims many cases, we often hear about dead relatives, religious figures or even the images of trusted friends being used as screens deliberately designed to make the abductions more acceptable to the victim. It is only when the victim becomes witting and refuses to buy into these images that the ruse fails. I myself recall several incidents of refusing to believe the images being shown to me of family members who were trying to persuade me to trust them and cooperate. It is, of course, difficult with a child, and one does not want to instill fear or negativity.

Right now, Derrel is working on a multi-generational case involving a small girl, and he and the relatives are very careful how they treat her detailed reports. It would be a great service to Vickis mother if you invite her to contact Derrel about this type of situation. The above case involves the family of a minister, and Derrels own personal faith would make him particularly sensitive to the imagery that is being employed in this situation. Sincerely, Jolene Rae Harrington, Asst. Director MUFON-LA

Speculation on UFO Activities?

David writes, Your article about the child visiting heaven got me thinking, what if each of us had our own personal UFO or some kind of cloaked device mostly invisible of course attached to us to simply monitor all our doings and goings on? This device could record all our experiences, and even our thoughts manifest upon this earth life. It could be this recording that near death experiencers see when they report having had a life review?

What if this device is some kind of relay mechanism that when the personal attach (human on Earth) flows their thoughts directly back into it, it somehow becomes visible? I further speculate and deduce that it could be connected to a larger flying saucer or other shaped service tenders who maintain these devices! Wow, what a science fiction story eh? But, it would explain some observed and reported phenomena, such as the reverend who is able to call the UFOs at will (they are simply his own personal monitor devices). Many people report simply wishing to see them and UFOs do appear!

Maybe most, if not all, human beings are monitored this way? Or maybe just the trouble makers or those more likely to be up to some thing? Who knows... just those connected to high places and people? These devices could be a method to influence behavior such as John Lennons assassin, Britney Spears actions or Kurt Cobains suicide, and other murders? The list could be endless. The general idea would be the ability to sabotage, cause accidents and provoke trouble on Earthlings like in Iraq today by the Shias from Iran as an example. What if orbs we often see in photographs were packages of data coming from or going to the aliens? I admit its pretty wild way-out theory eh? Should be easy to test, if this were true, then many more people could conduct a simple let me see you experiment. Proper commands would have to be found and/ or the UFO monitors could be able to reprogram them to NOT show up, and that idea then of course gives me a perfect out if they DONT appear! Thanks to David.



Summary of UFO Sightings August 2006

August 2006 had 339 NUFORC sightings and 103 MUFON reported sightings for an increase of seventy sightings over June. Coastal sightings and Midwest sightings dominated. Detailed version of the map is available at. You must be logged in to see this link. Thanks to Steve Reichmuth California Mufon skipjack@earthlink.net 

Arkansas Cigar




Little rockOn March 2, 2007, at 4 PM, I came out of the house and looked up at an airplane spreading chemtrails from the west. I noticed a cigar shaped craft traveling really slow over the city. The object was coming out of the north and traveling southeast. The airplane flew over it and this cylinder craft continued on for awhile still moving slow. At this point my sister came out of the house and I showed her the object as well. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Alabama Flying Triangles

MadisonAround 8 PM, I was driving home heading east on Highway 72 on February 28, 2007, when I noticed two bright lights three hundred feet above a field that was located next to a Grocery Store. They were very close and seemed to be motionless. I decided to pull into the store parking lot near the field so I could observe. I was speaking on the phone to my boyfriend. I could see two big lights and a multitude of lights arranged in a triangular shape. I rolled down my window and the only sound was that from the highway behind me. The first craft began to move south at a maximum speed of 10 mph. Then a moment later the second craft followed.

The first craft had a row of four white lights, then a row of three, the middle light on this row was red. Then a row of two lights and one light to complete a triangle. The red light in the center of the craft was blinking, but all other white lights remained solid and consistent. The second craft was exactly the same as the first, however it lacked the red light, only white lights in the shape of a triangle. As the crafts moved over head you could make out a faint shape around the triangle, the only way you could even notice was that it would block out stars as it moved even though the triangle part wasnt over the star yet. Both craft continued at this slow pace until I could not see them from the front anymore and then they became invisible in the night sky. I live close to Red Stone Arsenal so I cant say that it wasnt a military plane, but it sure wasnt a plane as we know it today.




TrussvilleI was driving to my friends house on Chalkville Road at night on March 15, 2007. I saw a remarkably lit triangular shaped craft right in front of me that did not look like any conventional airplane. This craft had a large red, circular light in the middle of it with one white light on its nose, and three white lights on its rear. I also think there was one white light on the other two sides. There were no blinking lights, the lights on it all stayed constant. The craft was on its side when I first saw it, then it flattened out as it flew off into the distance, heading west. My car has a digital compass in the top center console, so I know the direction is correct. Also, I had my drivers side window cracked and I didnt hear any engine noise. I wish I had taken a picture with my camera phone because it was close enough to make a good picture. The large red light in the middle of it had me perplexed and stunned. Thanks to MUFON CMS
Arizona Unknown Object Filmed (Photo)

PhoenixI thought you may be interested in this UFO photo that I took on August 12, 2006, at 8:26 PM, of a round white light traveling real slow through the night sky. There are 8 star like objects, almost in U-shape. There is no way this can be stars, not with a 4 megapixal camera. There were no aircraft nearby and there was no sound. It looked like it stopped for a few seconds then continued on. The UFO made sharp right and left turn. Luke AFB is southwest of me. I saw it in the night sky for 3 or 4 minutes. Thanks to Brian Vike. To view the pictures: You must be logged in to see this link. 

Ash Fork -- -- My wifes sister called us and asked us if we had seen what she and her four girls were witnessing on March 13, 2007 at 8:50 PM, about 50 miles west of Flagstaff. We went outside but saw nothing. We live in Prescott Valley, she lives in a remote area, and described four triangle shaped objects. When she looked through her binoculars, she could see four white shaped Pyramid UFOs that remained overhead for at least 20 minutes before moving off. She has no camera.

Investigators Notes: The primary witness has not yet been interviewed. If her report is accurate, the sighting would be somewhat similar to the 1997 Phoenix lights in that triangular shaped objects were sighted. In this sighting the witness noticed that the objects were actually pyramid shaped when viewing through binoculars. More information is needed to say anything more definitive about this sighting. Any updates will be posted. Thanks to Bill Puckett You must be logged in to see this link. 

California Air Force Reserve Videotapes UFO

SacramentoOn February 28, 2007, I was driving down the highway on my way home from the mall at 11 AM, and saw a red blinking light in the sky. At first I didnt think too much of it, just another airplane. But when I looked up again, I saw that the light was moving very very slow, too slow to be an airplane, and way to close to the ground. As I got closer to it, I saw the outline of a craft, and saw that it was cigar shaped. I pulled out my cell phone to try to get a picture of it, but I began to swerve and I didnt want to hit a car, so I put my phone away. When I passed it, I looked back and it looked to be just hovering over the highway. I saw a cigar shaped craft with a red light in the middle. I was freaked out by the whole thing. I kept driving and eventually lost sight of it. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 


RiversideThe witness reported he sighted an object on March 3, 2007, about 2:30 PM. Twenty minutes after the first sighting he saw a second object. He was outside playing with his kids and noticed a black triangular shaped object with white glowing tips moving to the south. He immediately grabbed his Sony DVD Camcorder and began taping.



He said, The object changed into an orb and then eventually into a disc that wobbled. He lost sight of the object as it approached the sun. The witness then went to converse with a neighbor about his sighting and then noticed a second object towards the east. He again grabbed his video camera and began taping. This object was triangular shaped and moved towards the south, but it displayed a rapid side to side movement. This object was pulsating. The witness zoomed into both objects with his camcorder. The witness stated that he saw military aircraft in the area probably from March Air Reserve Base.

Investigators Notes: This sighting was reported by a highly credible witness. The witness is an Air Reservist (Aircraft Structural Maintenance Worker). Obviously the witness is familiar with state-of-the-art military aircraft. He plainly stated that this was not ours. The fact that the witness noticed that the first object changed shapes is most unusual. We are Thanks to Bill Puckett You must be logged in to see this link. 

Indiana Triangle in the Sky for a Long Time

South BendMy sister came in telling me there was something in the sky and many were outside watching on March 11, 2007, from 8:00 to 11:00 p.m. I went out there and there was a very bright triangular shape in the sky, in the distance and very high up as well. It seemed to be descending very slowly. We were looking at it through tree branches and it was definitely moving around slowly. Due to us watching this and not our cat, he got run over. I went back to look later and the UFO had moved southeast in the sky. It hovered for quite a while. I went back in for ten minutes and came back out and it was gone. Illustration of triangle.



I stood outside of an on and watched it there for probably a few hours, and it seemed to be spinning because it would get dimmer and brighter randomly. We called 911 and they said thousands of people have called and they didnt know what it was. On the news, they said it was a possible meteor but I dont believe that. We got a picture and what I saw looks nothing like the picture but I assumed my camera adjusted for the exposure. I have a picture with a green dot at the top and a red one at the bottom and I have one zoomed in on the UFO. I was saddened to her about the loss of their pet. Thanks to Brian Vike, Director HBCC UFO Research Home

Illinois Flying Rectangle

Du Page CountyI was driving east on Route I-88 and noticed the object circling like a blimp at the 122 mile marker. As I got closer I realized it was not a blimp, and was rectangular and way too big. It stopped circling and flew northwest slow at first, but by the time it began to cross the express way it picked up considerable speed. It was far outpacing the commercial airline traffic in the sky. I have only seen fighter jets move this fast. By the time I got to the 128-1/2 mile marker it had again slowed and started circling. It was many miles north of me at that point. By that time I was able to get my camera out of the case and set to its highest resolution. I took a few pictures from the side of the road. I only showed one to Fox TV, I have a couple more. The object then traveled directly north and continued on in a straight line until it was too far away to see anymore. Please go to youtube.com and plug in OHare lights ufo in the search column, There is ten minutes of video. Thanks to MUFON CMS

Kansas Photo



ManhattanShortly after midnight in June 2006, my family and myself were out in our hot tub there was some kind of meteor coming into the sky when 10 or 12 of theses objects came into a formation in the sky above us. My wife said get the camera and when I got back outside I snapped this photo. Take a good look up close at it if anyone out there can tell me what I have would be great because we do not have any explanations for it. Thanks to MUFON CMS

Louisiana UFO Sighted Near 2 Truck Accidents!
Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 


KentwoodThis Triangle shaped UFO with flashing lights appeared just above the trees near my car on interstate 55 going south on February 28, 2007. It hovered not far from my car. When I saw it I felt drawn to it as if I had been in contact with it before, but it was a good feeling! It moved towards an 18 wheeler truck that was on fire about half a mile north of my car. It then hovered over this area. There was another 18 wheeler about one mile north of this one and it was completely turned over. Neither one of these trucks seemed to have any contact with other vehicles, which I found strange! Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Mississippi Huge Triangular Shaped

TupeloIm online looking for others that might have seen a triangle object over northeast Mississippi Union County on March 9, 2007 around 7 PM central. My daughter and son-in-law spotted this triangle shaped object just above tree level and in their words it was HUGE. It seemed to hover for a few minutes and before they could grasp what was happened it sped off and within seconds was out of their sight.

Investigators Notes: This report was received second hand from the mother of one of the witnesses. The sighting sounds to be of a non-conventional craft considering that it was very large, hovered, and rapidly sped off. I have written to the witness to obtain more details. Anyone in this area who witnessed a similar sighting is urged to file a report. Thanks to Bill Puckett You must be logged in to see this link. 

Ohio Sightings

CLEVELANDAarons report, There has been heavy fighter jets traffic over the area when UFOs are spotted. I do not know what type. I did speak to someone I know who saw ten of them. Late Friday night/Saturday morning March 10, 2007, multiple witnesses spotted a silver color UFO over the BP building. It disappeared for a few minutes and then reappeared and thats when he started filming a video. The main witness reports, I and other people saw a strange light over the BP building and it was bouncing and flying around at 2 or 3 AM. Some people thought it was a kite or weather device.. Others thought it was something that they had never seen before.. Thanks to Sam Phillips and Aaron. See the video at You must be logged in to see this link. 





Akron On March 7, 2007, at 9:15 PM, a huge cloud-colored, wing-shaped fast moving unidentified object flew low over Akron.
This huge winged-shaped form was soaring swiftly and moved quickly over my house and property. As it moved away, I saw only one wing. When it approached there were two distinct wing/fog/cloud forms. When it passed by me there was only one wing to its shape. The whole thing took about 25 seconds. It was triple times higher than the trees/house. The sky is clear tonight - lots of visible stars. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 



Pennsylvania UFOs Spotted Near Military Base.

Willow GroveI received a report at 22:00 hours (10 PM) while working at dispatch (NAS Willow Grove) On March 3, 2007 about a large number of objects circling over Elkins Park area. No Naval or Air force flight operations were confirmed. The report of objects was laughed off by Air Force Security Watch Commander.

The objects in flight moved slowly in circular formation. They would stop and go randomly making no sounds other than whooshing sounds during acceleration or course change. The lights were described as white emitted from the center and red and blue lights on outer areas of the objects. The one object was described as spider like. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 


Texas UFO Squadron



We were extremely surprised to see what appeared to be a squadron of UFOs in the picture after downloading. There was no sound of any aircraft and nothing was seen when the photo was taken on March 19, 2007. Thanks to MUFON CMS

Vermont Watching a Failing Engine on a UFO

Island PondMy friend and I were sitting out on the back porch, it was the first sunny day we have had in awhile. That was when she pointed up to the sky and we saw then what looked like a silver ball floating down from the sky like a leaf on February 28, 2007. She ran inside to get binoculars and the ship turned over. With the binoculars we could see so much of this equipment. The metal was very shiny and smooth as if molded. We could see what looked like 5 or 6 engines all spinning in different directions in side those tubes were more tubes spinning in the opposite direction as the big tube. Instead of fire coming out of these it looked more like lava or coals being sucked into these tubes. The engines or what not seemed to stop spinning from the inside tube first then the outside one would stop. It then again appeared to turn and you could see the saucer shape. It fell behind 2 mountains the smoke trail was gone within 10 minutes... Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Washington Solid Bright Red Light



Port Orchard On March 5, 2007, at 7:25 PM, a solid bright red light was seen moving very slowly across the sky at very high altitude. It was a steady light, not blinking. The object stopped moving and was still for a minimum of 5 minutes. We were able to get photos of the object, but were very far away and we were not able to distinguish details of the object like size or shape. We saw a few helicopters circling the area after the object disappeared. There were no real indicators of normal aircraft traffic like noise, blinking lights, trails, or a change in orientation of the light. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. ((NUFORC Note: Witness provides photo of object. PD))
Washington, DC Saucer

The witness reports seeing a hovering saucer-shaped object near tree-top level, with yellow flashing lights making no sound on March 5, 2007, at 7 PM. The saucer was then approached by a second triangular or flying wing shaped object that was also silent. It was not well lit, and was bronze colored. The triangle hovered nearby and seemed to fade slowly from view, possibly obscured by a cloud. The witness watched for ten minutes, then had to leave. The first object was still in view at that time. (nuforc note: we spoke via telephone with the party who submitted this report for a friend. The friend did not want to be identified, but the caller sounded to us to be quite serious-minded and credible. pd) Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Australia Triangle


Perth One hundred miles north of Perth, there is a screenshot of a claimed triangle UFO photographed over Australia on Google Maps. The triangle shaped object may be some sort of drawing. Source: You must be logged in to see this link. 

Canada Photo

WhitbyPaul Shishis writes, The flap in Ohio that occurred March 8, 2007, also confirms suspicion that Ontario also experienced a flap. Any resident in Southern Ontario will agree that aircraft activity was very high. The chemtrail activity in our skies, gave this observational insight to anyone who looked up.

I talked to another witness who spotted a UFO over Whitby. I also received word from a co-worker, that she had seen something zoom straight up the sky, leaving a weird trail behind on Friday, March 9, 2007, at about 7:45 AM. My co-worker also witnessed a sighting. This was her first sighting from across the street facing south, while having her smoke. That would be a total of seven witnesses at work, seeing what I have pointed out. HBCC reports that UFOs were seen in Durham, Ontario the same day.

Based on the frequency of recent sightings in and around Toronto, you dont have to be a detective to see whats actually unraveling here. Its starting to open, as our space and time gives more evident signs that cannot be no longer ignored. P.S. I have attached more about what I have experienced and feel important that must be SHARED because I care. Thanks to Paul Shishis,

Colombia Egg Object Seen Falling Rapidly

BOGOT On March 3, 2007 at approximately 18:30 hours a small egg shaped object was seen at a distance. The object was beige in color but was not glowing and seemed to be solid. The object was descending at a fast rate and appeared to break up on contact with the ground. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Jamaica 18 Small Lights

Montego BayAt 19:30 PM, on February 28, 2007, while at a local pub I sighted about 18 small lights moving at a slow speed towards the west. I am not one to believe in UFOs, BUT on this night I now believe they are real. We went for beer after work at a local bar near to the seaside, after about ten minutes someone beside me said what is that in the sky above the sea. I looked over towards the sea then sighted about 18 small low lights, orange in color, all moving at exactly the same speed and all the same in size. We moved closer towards the lights to get a better look. It seemed to me that it was one very big object then it suddenly went dark. Thanks to Peter Davenport Director You must be logged in to see this link. 

Mexico: Sightings



Mexico CityThe Journey of Hispanic Ufology reports a video belonging to Carlos Rodriguez Lopez was taken on February 17, 2007, who saw a possible UFO to the north of Mexicos capital city. This evidence was secured on from the Progreso Nacional district. You must be logged in to see this link. The landscape is seen to the left as dark area of photo.

United KingdomStrange Lights

Somerset County GazetteLaura Thorpe reports, strange lights in the night sky have prompted readers of the Somerset County Gazette to question the existence of UFOs. At about 10 PM on Monday night, March 13 2007, a sighting of a strange glow in the sky was reported by Fay Boyd of Kingston St Mary, Richard Fowle of Cheddon Road in Taunton, and his son Edward. Mrs. Boyd told the County Gazette: There was a long vertical light, it was not a star but I have no explanation for it.As far as I can tell it didnt stay there very long, I dont normally believe in the paranormal but it was very strange. The object was seen as a vertical shaft of light by witnesses. The photo was taken by Richard Fowle.

Stargazer, Taunton states, This fascinating occurrence could be the rare phenomenon known as the Zodiacal Light, a ghostly cone of illumination caused by the reflection of the Suns light from millions of tiny particles in the plane of the Earths, and Venus orbits. Its visible just after twilight, a vast faint triangular glow rising from Venus upward into the constellation of Aries. If it is the Zodiacal Light itll be visible until about March 20 towards the west. Thanks to Reporter : laura.thorpe@countygazette.co.uk 



Basildon Echo News reports seven people have now come forward to claim they saw a UFO this week. All reported seeing a large mysterious triangular object, with flashing red lights. Electrician Graham Hearson, 45, of Westcliff, claimed he saw a UFO in Basildon while driving on the A127 about 5 AM on Monday. Pitsea couple Michael and Jane Pittaway said they too had seen fast-moving lights about 11:30 PM on Sunday. Tree surgeon Terry Waller, 29, of Rayleigh, said he and two friends had seen something similar on Tuesday night. He said he had seen red lights and heard a weird noise. Yvonne Simmons, 53, of Rayleigh, was ringing on behalf of a shy friend who also lives in Mr. Wallers Street. She said her friend reporting seeing flashing lights and hearing a whirring noise about 7 PM on Tuesday. If you sighted a UFO this week and have a photo to prove it, contact Echo You must be logged in to see this link. 

Cosmic Intelligence Awareness Research

We are pleased to offer Commander Bethune&apos;s &quot;Report from Alcyone&quot; I can send you a Download or CD of some of best UFO photos ever taken. The Report costs $12.00 and shipping charges for the CD are $3.00.



Sign UP to Keep Getting These Files

We need your help to continue sending you the latest UFO news. It is my mission to keep the most cutting edge news you need to know. You may contribute by donating and providing input to the National UFO Center. Read our breaking research before it hits the press and television news. It is time to subscribe or renew and keep informed.

I urge you not to procrastinate and sign up for these files. I am, offering a great CD free gift of UFOs over North Carolina for signing up. Dont miss the latest secrets of the universe. These files have been sent since January 1997, and we urgently need your help to continue. We started a web site several years ago often getting a half million hits per month. Frankly, we need your help and support just to meet web, publication, office and webmaster expenses. Only a few people who have enjoyed these files for nine years have chosen to provide a donation.

Im requesting a donation of 50 cents a week or $25 per year to enable me to continue with Filers Files. These files cannot exist without your help. So you wont miss a single breaking news story or the increased evidence for UFO and life in the universe, George A. Filer has been bringing you the latest in UFO news since 1995, on radio, television and the Internet. Dont miss the latest images of UFOs from Earth and Mars. Subscribe today and receive a free UFO Photo CD. Holidays are the time to donate, to buy a book, or a CD of the last eight years of these files.

Be sure to ask for the CD. Send check or money order to:

George Filer,

222 Jackson Road,

Medford, NJ 08055.

You can also go to:

ttps:// You must be logged in to see this link. for Majorstar @ aol.com You may use Paypal, Visa, Master Charge, or American Express.

JOIN MUFON!

Become a MUFON member today! Benefits of membership include a subscription to the monthly UFO Journal which contains current investigations, sightings reports, articles by world-renowned researchers and more. To join now, click here. You must be logged in to see this link. 

Filers Files is copyrighted 2007 by George A. Filer, all rights reserved. Readers may post the COMPLETE files on their Web Sites if they credit the newsletter and its editor by name, and list the date of issue. These reports and comments are not necessarily the OFFICIAL MUFON viewpoint. Send your letters to majorstar@aol.com. Sending mail automatically grants permission for us to publish and use your name. Please state if you wish to keep your name or e-mail confidential. CAUTION MOST OF THESE ARE INITIAL REPORTS AND REQUIRE FURTHER INVESTIGATION. If you wish to stop receiving these files please send a message to majorstar@aol.com 

If you are considering moving get my free report!

We can help you make a smart move with our free report. Learn how you can obtain the best real estate agent to help you relocate, buy or sell a home. To get a free copy of this report e-mail me at: Majorstar @ aol.com



George A. Filer You must be logged in to see this link. 






--------------------------------------------------------------------------------


&quot;Fulfilling my potential would seriously cut into my sitting around time&quot;.
	</body>
</document>
