<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007666" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/14142906/feasibility-report-on-restaurant" time="2012-07-13-00:38" support="4" score="0.006904525833439622" bingtitle="feasibility report on restaurant - Scribd" webtitle="feasibility report on restaurant">
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000301" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>1.5 fast food restaurant 2 scope of the project 3 restaurant profile 3.1 objectives 3.2 mission statement 3.3 our team 3.4 plus point of our restaurant than the</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 50 Comment Go Back 
   FEASIBILITY REPORT ON ESTABLISHING THE HARMONY RESTRAURANT In partial fulfillment of Entrepr eneurship&amp;Management of Innovations SUBMITTED TO:- PROF. KISHOR BARAD PROF. VIPUL PATEL SUBMITTED BY: - LIMBACHIY A HEMANG D. 13 P A T E L B H A I L A L M . 2 1 P A TEL KIRA N J. 30 P R A J A P A T I M A H E S H S . 4 7 V.M. PATEL INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT GANPAT VIDYANAGAR, KHERVA   PREFACE It is a pleasure to keep this report in front of you. Project report is vitally important for M.B.A students because it develops the feelings among the stu den ts abo ut ind ust ria l env iro nme nt and bus ine ss to dev elo p the pract ical base. Theoreti cal knowledg e is true only when we apply the same in the practical. In the final year M.B.A there is a subject named “Entrepreneurship and man age men t of inn ova tio n” Pro jec t’. Und er the sai d cur ric ulu m a student has to do a detail analysis of a particular company. At the same time we must know that what are the Strengths and weakness of the company by an al yz in g ov er al l or ga ni za ti on al st ru ct ur e an d it s op er at io ns . An d simul taneo usly anal yze the oppo rtuni ties and thre ats for estab lishi ng the restaurant. In order to establish co-relation between the theoretical studies and practical training, it was suggested that some company should be analyzed a n d a c c o r d i n g l y w e h a d d o n e t h e a n a l y s i s o n “ HARMONY RESTAURANT ”.   ACKNOWLEDGEMENT W e, the below ment ion ed stude nts of the V . M. Patel Inst itu te of Man age men t, Khe rva , here b y pay ou r very si nce re tha nks to t he Prof . Ki sh or Ba ra d fo r gi vi ng us th e wo nd er fu l op po rt un it y fo r do in g a entrepreneurship and management of innovation in our interest area as a part of our study. W e would like to extend our sincere thanks to the V . M. Patel Institute of Management, Kherva, affiliated to the said university for giving us the op po rt un it y to in cr ea se ou r pr ac ti ca l kn ow le dg e in ou r in te re st of management area. We also thanks to Prof. Kishor Barab who motivated us to undertake this project. He spent innumerable hours pursuing th e first draft, suggesting many const ructi ng and valuable modificat ions and critique s and there after largely c ontributed i n editing th e final draft. The contents o f the repo rt have been considerably enriched in the process. We are also thankful to all the professors of the institute for their very good support. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Deepak Sharma 
please mail As quick as posible.. itz urgent
 reply 07 / 01 / 2012 Deepak Sharma 
Dear sir , please mail me this project on my gmail id
 reply 07 / 01 / 2012 Kuldeep Soni 
this is what is need,,plzz sir kindly send it on my email id today..i need it ni urgent.. kuldeepsoni10@yahoo.co.in 
 reply 06 / 29 / 2012 sandipgold 
Dear sir, this is compatible project report for us, please mail me on my mail ID
 reply 06 / 21 / 2012 Seng Mai 
Excellent project. Could you please send me a copy? My address is katherine1433@gmail.com . Thanks.
 reply 06 / 21 / 2012 Manjiri Durge 
This is excellent. Could i have a copy ? my address is manjiridurge@gmail.com thanks a lot.
 reply 06 / 14 / 2012 Sayan Saha 
great job..................
 reply 06 / 03 / 2012 Deepak Priyani 
Dude can u please send me a copy of it on deepak_priyani@yahoo.com it would mean a lot man
 reply 04 / 27 / 2012 Show More Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
feasibility report on restaurant
 80,904 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: ( 23 Ratings) Upload Date: 04/11/2009 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
