<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007778" url="http://www.mygames4girls.com/games/cooking/the-mexican-restaurant.html" time="2012-07-13-00:44" support="1" score="0.001437908623810104" bingtitle="cooking games : The mexican restaurant - girls games" webtitle="cooking games : The mexican restaurant - Girls Games">
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>Help Rufus to wait tables in this mexican restaurant. ... you’re a fan of free girls games like this shop ... ve just got a job working in this brand new fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Girls games 
 Jeux de cuisine Jeux de fille Juegos de chicas Mädchen Spiele 
 
 Girls games » games » cooking » The mexican restaurant To play these girls&apos;games, you must install Flash Player Lea, Lilou&amp;Lee LOG IN or SUBSCRIBE FOR FREE New girls games 
 Girls Games 
The best games section for girls !

 Make up games Dress up games Cooking games Decoration games 

 Fun games Celebrity games Free games Exclusive Games 

 

 + 33 new things on the homepage this week ! click here ! 
 Games by theme 
New themes everyday !

 memory games pet games baby games jigsaw games glee games Difference games puzzle games barbie games 

 spongebob squarepants games beyonce games bike games animal games Robert Pattinson games adventure games princess games manga games 

 dog 

 + 33 new things on the homepage this week ! click here ! 
 Music videos 
Discover all our video clips selection !

 TOP 20 Music videos Random song 

 Jessie Ware - Wildest Moments Conor Maynard - Vegas Girl Owl City + Carly Rae Jepsen - Lady Antebellum - Wanted (...) Train - 50 Ways to Say (...) 

 

 + 33 new things on the homepage this week ! click here ! 
 Forum for girls My Profile HiDolls ! 
HiDolls, your virtual world just for girls!

 Updates&amp;Rankings Become a VIP! Go to HiBank 

 My Profile Edit my account 

 

 Get more DEEZ et become a VIP! Click here! 
 
 
cooking games : The mexican restaurant

 Girls games are best on mygames4girls.com!
To have fun playing girls games, you need to install the Adobe Flash Player
 Download 
More Girls Games

 
 Online Mermaid Games 
 
 Gnomeo and Juliette 
 
 Mario Bros the plumber 
 
 Holiday in the Maldives 
 
 
 Currently 4.16/5 1 2 3 4 5 

 4.2 /5 (58 votes)
 Loading... 
Help Rufus to wait tables in this mexican restaurant.
 
Help Rufus the little Mexican boy in these restaurant girls games, who has opened a restaurant in this game for girls. There’s lots of mexican food like chocolate, salsa, burritos, cheese, nachos and soda. You must click on distributors for the contents to fall onto plates or into glasses to make up the orders of the customers that come into the restaurant, just like in other girls games in this section.

Don’t make mistakes in this cooking game! There are several levels of difficulty with waitress games . First, you will have only one dish on the tray and then you need to manage more of them as soon as possible. Now it’s up to you to prove yourself, Rufus really needs your help in this game for girls!
 
Also discover:

 restaurant 
 
More restaurant games for girls:

 
 Animal Restaurant 

You might have served hundreds of customers in our waitress games and management games for girls, but we bet you’ve never come across a (...)
 
 Panda’s restaurant 

In order to earn money to repair his plane, Tony the panda has been forced to land his plane and interrupt his journey. He’s decided to (...)
 
 run a restaurant 

In our newest of restaurant games, you need to do your best to run this restaurant with only the chef to help you. When your customers (...)
 
 Burger Shop 

For cooking games you often have to look after or work in restaurants. In Lora’s burger shop you’re going to have to manage the whole (...)
 
 
The top 8 new games for girls in this section cooking :

 baking games Cooking Sushi! Eating Chilies Cooking a Summer Cake Cooking course for girls Pancakes for girls Make hamburgers Cake Decorating Game 
 
The mexican restaurant comments from girls:
 Leave your comment! jade123 10.03.2012à17:42 
 gggggggggggggrrrrrrrrrrrreeeeeeeeeeaaaaaatt Advertising Leave your comment! 
girls games, the free website for girls to play dress up games and more!

Games by themes

 adventure animal baby babysitting baking barbie beauty Ben 10 beyonce bike boy boyfriend bratz Britney Spears burger cafe cake cat christmas coloring couples dance decorating Difference disney dog doll dolphin dora the explorer easter fairy family farm fashion fashion designer football garden and gardening glee hair halloween Hannah Montana Hello kitty hidden object High School Musical home horse and horse riding hotel house jigsaw jobs Justin Bieber Katy Perry kids kissing Lady Gaga learning logic love makeover management manga manicure mario maze memory mermaid Miley Cyrus model monster high mother Music Mygames4girls.com nail Nicki Minaj pet pizza princess pucca puzzle racing restaurant Rihanna Robert Pattinson school Selena Gomez selling Shooting shop simpsons song spongebob squarepants sports store sue tara duncan Taylor Swift Thanksgiving Three Wise Men Twilight Valentine waitress wedding winx work 

 Girls games air hostess game Princess Elliana’s big night! Create Your Perfect Boy! decorate your snowboard Baker girls game 

 Fun games Easter egg hunt game Shrek The skipping rope game Bubbles Arcade Game Vanessa Hudgens dress up 

 Music videos Mike Posner - Cooler Than Me Vanessa Hudgens - Say ok Lloyd - Be the One Lady Gaga ft. Beyoncé - Telephone Kylie Minogue - Timebomb 

 Forum for girls If you could have any super (...) What sport do you play? Your ideal pet ! The Best Halloween Costume (...) Girls vs Boys - the big debate! 

Sitemap

 games for girls make up games dress up games cooking games decoration games 

 Super fun games celebrity games free games 

 Music Keane - Silenced By The Night Top 20 All music 

 Forum for girls! 

 Girls games Lea, Lilou&amp;Lee Friends of the site Legal terms and conditions Advertisers Games for webmasters Partners Contact
	</body>
</document>
