<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007307" url="http://garyshood.com/apply/" time="2012-07-13-00:16" support="2" score="0.0024360029648427825" bingtitle="Unofficial Application For Jewel-Osco" webtitle="Unofficial Application For Jewel-Osco">
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000698" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>If you want a real job at Jewel, go to the store ... Osco because it&apos;s better than applying for a fast-food restaurant ... attitude with the customers, are willing to leave ...</description>
	<body>
		Gary&apos;s Hood 
 Home Auto Typer For Runescape Myspace Band Player Grabber 
 Articles 
 Block Online Advertisements Clicksor Advertising Sucks FreeBSD vs. Gentoo Get Listed In Search Engines Go See Rambo IV IE vs Firefox vs Opera Illegal Immigrants Internet Filters Are Racist John Kerry Hates The Troops Keith&apos;s Jew Gold Mydosty Proxy Hosting Sucks Net Audio Ads Sucks Psychz Hosting Is Amazing Religulous - Not Playing Here Ron Paul Is Insane Run As The Root Account Stop Checking For Flash WoW Gold Guide Stop Ruining The IMDb 250 
 Programs 
 AdSense Earnings In Conky Auto Typer For Runescape Can&apos;t Access Hardware Clock Diablo II Refresh Rate Fix Gaim Transparent Tray Icon Last Seen Script For MIRC Linux Auto Typer MPlayerplug-in Looping Audio Neopets Auto Buyer Password Protect Any File Project Wonderful For Conky Remove The Ad Box On AIM Skulltag Setup On Linux Solve Crossword Puzzles Spell Check In Konversation Stylish Google Font Size Fix Unknown media type in type Perl Net::Oscar Version Fix Google Plus Video Linux Fix Can&apos;t Access LSI WebBios 
 Web Applications 
 Convert And Compress Audio Convert And Resize An Image Dictionary Definitions Lookup HTML/CSS Site Validator HTML To BB Code Converter Inverted Flipping Animation Myspace Comment Bomber Online Virus Scanner 
 Interactive 
 An Argument With A Woman Hangman Jewel-Osco Job Application Orange Tree Game Rambo Rock, Paper, Scissors Unbeatable Tic-Tac-Toe 
 Myspace Generators 
 AIM Link IM Generator Band Player Grabber Comment Box Generator Create Link/Picture Code Custom Flash MP3 Player Layout Generator Layout Previewer Music Video Search Myspace Surveys 
 YTMND 
 Eminem Eatin&apos; His Daughter Homer&apos;s Black Power Salute Now The Baby&apos;s In The Trash Wheel Of STDS 
 Contact 
AIM:   Garys Hood Bot 
Email: admin@garyshood.com
RSS:  Subscribe 
Privacy: Policy 
 
Unofficial Application For Jewel-Osco
 Application 
So you&apos;re running low on cash and you have no other skills that are worth mentioning. Sounds like you need a job at Jewel-Osco. Thankfully you can apply here and finally get that dream career you deserve.
 
Holy crap, you are all stupid. This is NOT a real job application. Don&apos;t post your phone numbers here or ask for an actual job. This is a joke. If you want a real job at Jewel, go to the store and ask for one.
 
 Leave A Comment 
 Name: 

 Email: 

 Site: 

 Please note I&apos;ve deleted about a few hundred spam comments in the last few days. Don&apos;t leave spam, the links are set to nofollow anyways. 

Enter the number: 
Comment: (*required) 
 
 
 
 linda buckley 
IM&quot;interested in workin for your company,can u please E-mail me back soon.

07-23-2008
 
 Seymour 
luv Jewel

08-09-2008
 
 Michael John Hilbert 
I&apos;m looking for full time employement. I&apos;m interested in working for your company. I would like to work the grave yard shift but, i would be willing to work the evening shift. I&apos;ll work weekends and holidays. I don&apos;t have a cell phone or a home phone but, i only live two blocks away. If it is alright with you i will check in every once in while for an answer or interview. Thank you.

09-02-2008
 
 Ren 
Liked the stealing the blind guys cane..cool

09-17-2008
 
 Edwin 
haha i got 12 points i&apos;m starting on monday!!!! which is today somehow -.-

09-21-2008
 
 Lawrence 
Can I be notified when i can work?

09-25-2008
 
 mallory harris 
If hiering please give me a call at NUMBER REMOVED

11-13-2008
 
 Lan Dong 
I am willing to work the evening shift and also weekends.

11-28-2008
 
 eunice banks 
i like jewel osco

12-06-2008
 
 D&apos;angelo 
I always wanted to see how it was to work at jewels

12-16-2008
 
 Anita 
Hello!
My name is Anita. I hope that you write me back with a good news because I so like Jewel-Osco and I like working. I propose part time.
Happy Holidays?
12/21/2008

12-21-2008
 
 me 
JEWEL IS TEH SUXXXXORZ!!111111one DONT WORK HERE

01-29-2009
 
 Rick Astley 
Jewel makes me want to move to china and shoot myself in the face....

01-29-2009
 
 earlita 
i am a very hard worker and most of all i am a people person and i will make your team very proud of me.

02-15-2009
 
 Castle Massey 
I&apos;m a very hard worker, I hope you contact me. Thank you

02-20-2009
 
 Renzo 
looking forwerd to work for you

02-26-2009
 
 Savith Leitan 
Hello, I hope that you find my credentials to be fitful. I was born in London, England, and at the age of four I moved to Cathedral City, California. I attended Cathedral City Elementary School, then went to James Logan Middle School. I graduated last year from Cathedral City High School as Valedictorian of my class. I am now looking for a job to help pay my tuitions through college. I am just starting out, so there are not many places that could use a High School Graduate, so I&apos;m applying at Jewel-Osco because it&apos;s better than applying for a fast-food restaurant job. If you need to contact me, please call me or email me. Thank you for taking your time to read this, you won&apos;t regret hiring me.

Home Phone - (760) 225-0644
Cell Phone - (760) 225-2021
Home Address - 504 Della S. Lindley Drive, Cathedral City, CA 92240
E-mail Adress - savithleitan@cathedralcityhigh.net

03-28-2009
 
 Owner of Boon Productions 
OMFG!!!!! ITS NOT A REAL JOB APPLICATION U DIMSHITS!!!!!!!! ITS JUST A GAME!

gosh
&quot;what you didnt hear me?&quot;
&quot;ok then....&quot;
&quot;GOD DAMN IT YOUR ALL STUPID WHORES! ITS NOT A REAL FUCKING APPLICATION!&quot;
&quot;GOD!&quot;

04-01-2009
 
 ahmed 
job

04-05-2009
 
 ahmed 
for job

04-05-2009
 
 jennifer 
I will luv workin for Jewel-osco.so please call Thank You

04-27-2009
 
 chris petty 
need work call soon

06-06-2009
 
 peter 
jewel osco sucks

06-24-2009
 
 jessica perry 
i relly need a job because i like to keep my self buzy at all the time and i like to work and i would love to work for your company at any time

07-31-2009
 
 ben 
never eat yellow snow! suckafuckinfatone! thank you and have a great day! ;}

08-18-2009
 
 Gusty 
Yeah, can I start next-next Monday?

08-26-2009
 
 Anonymous 
wow all you people really think this is a job ahahahha what a bunch of idiots

09-18-2009
 
 rob 
im looking for a full time job.

10-15-2009
 
 Alexander 
I think working at jewel would be a great job. please email me.

11-21-2009
 
 jay l 
i really need this job

11-23-2009
 
 brian reed 
My name is brian. I Hope that you write me back with good new because i like jewel osco and i like working. i propose part time

12-09-2009
 
 Anthony Fosco 
My name is Anthony Fosco. I am 18 years old and I am really looking for a job. I am a junior in high school and I drive.

12-27-2009
 
 Nadia 
hi my name is Nadia, I really to work in jewel ASAP.

02-10-2010
 
 Nadia 
hi my name is Nadia, I really want to work in jewel ASAP.

02-10-2010
 
 andrew 
can a kid work there i need a job

02-13-2010
 
 Jasmine Richardson 
MY name is jasmine richardson and i am 13 years old going on 14 in september i am looking for a job dosent matter what it is if u guys dont hire me do you somewhere else i can go.

04-14-2010
 
 Chris Hansen 
I&apos;m on to you now.

06-05-2010
 
 Jake Winkelman 
Since a young age ive loved acting like an employee at stores. I would often do stupid stuff up at the walmart or osco while wearing my school id. Stupid customers thinking I work there would then yell at me. I am addicted to customer complaints. It is my passion to work at a store for chicken feed for the rest of my life while getting belittled by customers hard core. I also like to show up to work drunk and smile while customers go on about nonsence. Please hire me. this is my dream job. I have experience too. Its not like you can just hire any old kid to do this job off the streets anyway. It takes years and years of experience to work at the jewels. Thanks for your time and consideration.

06-06-2010
 
 Kris Ugaleti 
Hellow Chris Hansen. I was just returning your email to confirm we want to hire you at jewel. We are very interested with young people who have no experience and are slow learners. If you have an attitude with the customers, are willing to leave this job any day without notice, or are fond of the no call no show this is the place for you. We have a high turn over rate here and the customers dont seem to understand this job is a joke. Because you meet all these aspects and understand all of what ive mentioned you can expect to start work on monday. you will be getting about 12 hours a week and will be making minimum wage which is now 8.25 in illinois. Not bad if I do say so. Please feel free to anger the customers. they yell at me all the time and I need someone not afraid of being fired to put them in their place for me. Once again thank you chris hansen.

06-06-2010
 
 christina 
hi i am interested in working for u because i really need a job asap .
email me please!

06-17-2010
 
 christina 
hi iam interested in your company please call email me very soon

06-17-2010
 
 Anonymous 
LOL I got 30/30 points and I stole the old huys Cane!


07-06-2010
 
 charles williams 
Im looking for a job asap!!!

07-07-2010
 
 dorian walton 
this will be my first job. and i am determine to work for you!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

07-26-2010
 
 Antoinette 
lookin forward to workin at this job really need it

08-01-2010
 
 teairra craig 
IM A SINGLE MOTHER THAT WILL LOVE TO WORK TO SUPPORT MY CHILD AND GET OFF WELFARE CAN U PLZ CONTACT ME AT MY EMAIL THANK U

08-20-2010
 
 John 
I like pie.

08-22-2010
 
 Anonymous 
i want to go back to osco

08-27-2010
 
 Harry B. Ver 
I enjoy working in the personal care department. Shaving cream and razors are not my strong suits.

08-29-2010
 
 Beverly Newman 
I&apos;m 56 year old widow I&apos;ve been unemployed for 2 years. Looking for a job to support myself. Please call me at 815-390-5109 thank you

09-17-2010
 
 Anonymous 
I am looking to work for the jewel osco team. I am looking to start off as part-time first. I am willing to work weekdays, weekends, and holidays. I have a house phone no cell phone. my house phone number is 1-847-516-9637. If it is alright with you I will check in every once in while for an answer or interview. Thank You.

10-02-2010
 
 Joe 
HIRE ME FOSHO

10-06-2010
 
 Liza 
Hi, i&apos;m willing to work for Jewel.
I am fluent in bullcrap, and understand fxckery pretty well. I&apos;m available every holiday, and every weekend, whenever your heart desires to have people randomly push cars in parking lots.

Thank you, get back to me soon!

10-06-2010
 
 Abdul 
Hi i need the job do you have any job please.

11-08-2010
 
 Major 
I was a dick to the old lady and told the old guy to go and google the damn thing, and the coffee, i told the parents they are terrible living beings.

11-12-2010
 
 refugio salinas 
looking for a jop oportunity in jewel-osco

12-10-2010
 
 Bloody Meat 
Here at Jewel-Osco we want you to bust your ass and bend over for us as we see fit. We will make sure your union reps get more than enough money to absolutely nothing for you. We will promise you raises and promotions but we will give you nothing. We will treat the customers with higher regards than you. Thank you for applying to your Friendly Algonquin Jewel Osco. P.S. if you are also a customer and complain about the service you are guaranteed to get at least one expensive item for free. We don\&apos;t care if it cost $40+. Enjoy it on us.

12-11-2010
 
 hello its me 
hello its me

01-26-2011
 
 Kareem Anderson 
i am a hard worker. i listen and can learn easily.

02-13-2011
 
 melissa corcoran 
hi my name is melissa im 25 soon to be 26, ive been a stay at home mother for the past 9 years now, working evening shifts at bars... but lately ive decided that i wouldnt want my children working at bars for tips, so im going to lead by example so here i am filling out this application. ive been withens father) for almost 10 years, both our kids grandparents live within minutes of our home and both my girls are in school, so babysitters have and will never be an issue. im a good hard worker i take pride in things that i do i would say im kind of a perfectionist... i would rather spend 2 hours making sure 1 thing is perfect then do 5 things in those 2 hours with several mistakes. im proud to say that ive been here for my children throughout their childhood, but im 100% ready to start a career and not meaning to sound mean, but a little life of my own. as i said im a hard worker im very responsible, and im a people person. please contact me if your interested im available to start as soon as possible and im willing to work any shift available. thanks, melissa corcoran

04-09-2011
 
 i play runescape 
omg so many people think this is a real job application.. pathetic

04-30-2011
 
 Mustapha 
I want a job so call soon as possible and I want to save money for collage.

06-13-2011
 
 Frank 
I would like to work as a grocies clark at Jewel food store at 4660 West
Irving Park Rd

07-07-2011
 
 Brendy 
You&apos;re the one with the barins here. I&apos;m watching for your posts.

07-22-2011
 
 Fat 
Jewel is not worth it unless you want to have a real career there don&apos;t waist your time there.

08-26-2011
 
 joshua harris 
Im intrested in working at jewels osco please email me back as soon as possible.

08-30-2011
 
 Jon Trollinski 
Hello I are a reterd. I am liking to apply for a job at this store Jewel. I would like to join rest of retards working at Jewel. I can blink my eyes really fast when I want to sometimes. My moms name is Irene she says I have a fetish for getting yelled at. I dont know how she finded out but whenever she yell at me I get giggity. So please give me this job. I am very experienced in sorting white beans from red beans and tuna from salmon, so that packer job will be no problem for me. I can push 5 carts at once. So dear manager of the store Jewel please hire me I will work whenever I have to.

03-20-2012
 
 Steff 
Blah blah

03-21-2012
 
 Patrick McManamon 
I am a 17 year old male student who is looking for to help his family.

04-10-2012
	</body>
</document>
