<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007219" url="http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/sonic-drive-in-georgia-c160869.html" time="2012-07-13-00:11" support="2" score="0.002129533937915498" bingtitle="Sonic Drive In Complaints, Reviews - Working for sonic!" webtitle="Sonic Drive In Complaints, Reviews - Working for sonic!">
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000231" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>Contact Allied Irish Bank (Your Order Number PFCDC726091 ... much stress that goes into working at a fast food restaurant. ... Good Luck to Sonic and my advice GET OUT NOW.</description>
	<body>
		The most trusted and popular consumer complaints website 
 
 Everything 
 Everything Complaints Articles News&amp;Stories Recalls Videos Groups Questions 
 Home News&amp;Stories Tips&amp;Tricks Questions Videos Photos Recalls Groups Submit Complaint Connect With: Login Register 
 
 
 
Recently Discussed Complaints
 1. (0 mins ago) 
 Swamp people 
Graphic massacres of alligators 2. (0 mins ago) 
 Franklin Furniture 
Recliner with lifetime warranty 3. (6 mins ago) 
 Organic Financial Inc 
Avoid them at all costs 4. (7 mins ago) 
 Elected Idiot 
Hickenlooper Blooper 5. (7 mins ago) 
 Auto Services Company, Inc. 
refusal to honor warranty 


Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks
 
 
 
    What is an Annuity? 
 
 
 
    5 Tips to Great Deals on a Gym Membership 
 
 
 
    Are Crystal Table Lamps Right for Your Home? 
 

 
Latest News&amp;Stories
 
    French Total wins gas drilling tender 
 
    Deceptive Marketing For Prepaid Calling Cards Targeting Immigrants 
 
    Who&apos;s Paying For What? Washington Takes Aim at Secret Political Money 
 


Latest Questions
 sueing cr england not getting my welfare check from govement Neotel SA NO RESPONSE MY MISSING MOBILE PHONE E-MAIL my order 

 
 
 
Sonic Drive In, Georgia Complaints&amp;Reviews - Working for sonic!
 Review all Sonic Drive In, Georgia complaints 
Sonic Drive In
 
 Posted: 2009-02-06 by    fancy 
 
 
 Working for sonic! 
 Complaint Rating: Company information: 
SONIC
 Georgia 
 United States 
 Tweet I will never ever work for this place again! I hated it! Asst. Managers don&apos;t even get paid nine dollars if you start off you are only getting around seven dollars if you have been working there for a lets say eight years good luck in getting over 8 dollars! I&apos;m so ill! THey cut car hops pay to 3.15 because&quot;OH THEY MAKE TIPS TO MAKE UP THERE MIN. wage!&quot;NOT TRUE!! mostly in the winter time is that not true!! THE GMS never know what to do at there job yet they are getting paid double what the asst. manager is getting paid, but make the asst. managers do the jobs they are suppose to be doing! THey are always understafed! OR it might just be the way they liked setting me up I always had only 3 people on my shift I was lucky if there was four. Before i quit I would only have me and a cook! YET the customers wonder why it took so long for there food and why it came cold! THere is your reason especially if there were only two people! TWO PEOPLE to take orders that ALWAYS AVERAGE 2 mins to take an order because the people beeped in and don&apos;t know what they want, the cook does not know the head set so normally you have one person taking 5 different orders... do the math by the time your finished taking the last order the first order is really late! THen you still have to make the drinks and the Ice cream that takes time and you have to finish make the food and bag the order and get it out! THere is no way that food is going out good and or on time! NO one understands what an Asst. Manager has to do there, the amount of stress we take on!
I&apos;m not here to complain about the customers I&apos;m here for you not to take it out on the car hops or managers, it is not fair how sonic treats there employees, Luckily I had enough sense to leave that horrible place! I don&apos;t understand how they have the money to have a sonic bowl for football, but they can&apos;t treat there employees like the way they want there store ran. So if you meet a car hop that seems annoyed just understand most likely they are just upset that they are having a ton to do for just 3.15 an hour...I don&apos;t know why they are staying for this job, but someone has to do it.
DON&apos;T WORK FOR SONIC! Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants Share with others:          
 Was the above complaint useful to you?
	</body>
</document>
