<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007209" url="http://www.business.com/retail-and-restaurant/restaurant-and-foodservice-furnishings/" time="2012-07-13-00:10" support="8" score="0.010991926783858474" bingtitle="Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings - Find Restaurant and ..." webtitle="Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings - Find Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings Vendors, TipsAdvice, Buying Guides - Business.com">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>Counter Tops and Cabinets for Restaurants; Restaurant Chairs ... Whether you&apos;re furnishing a fast food restaurant or a funky bistro, the selection of furniture is a key in ...</description>
	<body>
		About Us | Login | Advertise With Us | Contact Us Find a Vendor Guides Blog Home » Retail and Restaurant »Restaurant And Foodservice Furnishings 
 
 
 
 Bar Furniture Restaurant Banquet Tables Restaurant Table Tops 

 Counter Tops and Cabinets for Restaurants Restaurant Booths Ropes and Stanchions for Restaurants 

 Menu Boards Restaurant Chairs Table Cloths 

 Metal Furniture for Restaurants Restaurant Furnishings Waiter and Waitress Stations 

 Printed Menus Restaurant Furniture Wood Restaurant Furniture 
 
 
 Find Compare Research 
 
Purchasing Resources for
 Restaurant And Foodservice Furnishings
 Sponsored Links 
 Foodservice Management 

Online Certificate programs Cornell School of Hotel Admin

 www.ecornell.com/ Foodservice 
 
 Hotel Furniture , Italia 

Contract, Restaurant Interiors,CafèFarm Holidays, Residence, Outdoor

 www.papie.it/eng 
 
 Hotel furniture 

China Hotel furniture Suppliers High Quality, Competitive Price.

 www.made-in-china.com/ 
 
 Food Service in the UK? 

Increase your Product Sales today! Call now for a Free Consultation

 www.sagegreen.com/ 
 
Compare Restaurant Furnishings Price Quotes and Save!
 Step 1 2 What is your timeframe to begin this project? 
 Less than 30 Between 30-90 days More than 90 How large is your company? 
 1 - 50 employees 51-250 employees 251-1000 employees More than 1000 First Name * 
 Last Name * 
 Company Name * 
 Email * 
 Zip or Postal Code * 
 Phone (xxx-xxx-xxxx) * 
 Additional Information 
 Back 
Sending information, just a moment, please...
 Congratulations! 
Thank you for your interest. A Business.com account representative will be in touch with you within one business day.

To reach us directly, please contact us at customerservice@business.com .
 
An error occurred with your quote request. Please try again or email us at: info@business.com for assistance.
 
Download Restaurant And Foodservice Furnishings White Papers
 Tips&amp;Advice to help you make your decision on Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings 
Eating out is a favorite past time of many people. It&apos;s an experience that people seek out to relax and enjoy themselves. When you run a successful restaurant, you understand this and seek to provide a quality experience for your customers. This includes providing quality furniture to match your quality service and food.

If you are looking to update your restaurant with new outdoor furniture, then you will want to look through the guide provided on Business.com to begin your search. Outdoor restaurant furniture comes in an enormous array of styles, colors, and designs. Chairs, tables, booths, umbrellas and many other necessities and decorations are available.

The first step is knowing what you feel your restaurant would benefit most by having. You may want something high end made of wood and metal or perhaps something more casual, like folding tables. Whatever you are looking for, Business.com has extremely impressive resources for finding the inventory that you want.

You may want to utilize the insight of an expert through the information available. Take advantage of this accessible forum for resources on outdoor restaurant furniture. Click on the links provided to help your business stay on top of its growing needs.
 
Related Articles

 Pricing and Costs of Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings Types and Styles 

 Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings Education and Training 
 
Restaurant and Foodservice Furnishings
 Restaurant and foodservice furnishings set the atmosphere for your restaurant 
 Tweet 
Determine the formality or casualness of your restaurant by carefully selecting its furniture and decor. Whether you&apos;re furnishing a fast food restaurant or a funky bistro, the selection of furniture is a key in setting the mood; keep that in mind when you&apos;re shopping for furnishings for your restaurants.

Ensure that the restaurant furniture you&apos;re purchasing is intended for the use it&apos;ll experience. Paying for leather booths and exposing them to hours of direct sunlight isn&apos;t going to provide you with the long-term functionality you were expecting.

1. Save money with wholesale restaurant furniture.

2. Choose fast food restaurant furniture for strength and durability.

3. Purchase restaurant furniture designed for outdoor use.
Find furniture for restaurants at wholesale prices

Investigate wholesale restaurant furniture sources to help you get the highest quality of restaurant furniture at the best price available. Working directly with the wholesaler saves you the price of the middle man retailer, allowing you to purchase more furniture or better quality furniture.
 Try:  CPAPC Restaurant Design&amp;Supply, Inc. stands ready to fully supply your restaurant needs at wholesale prices, leaving you more money in your pocket to help your restaurant business succeed. Beaufurn Beautiful Furniture has a wide array of wholesale commercial restaurant furniture, some ready for immediate delivery.

Select commercial restaurant furniture designed for fast food restaurants

Fast food restaurants must stand up to a tremendous amount of traffic. Between car seats and kids&apos; shoes and the quick turn over, you have to make sure the fast food furnishings you select are sturdy enough to withstand fast food traffic.
 Try:  ADL Contract Furniture can provide you with several different seating options specifically designed to meet the needs of the fast food restaurant owner. Plan It Furniture is ready to meet all of your fast food restaurant furniture needs, including booths and booster seats.

Buy dining furniture made to withstand outdoor weather conditions

Outdoor seating can add to your capacity and create a second atmosphere for your diners to enjoy. Outdoor seating takes a beating that most other furnishings will never see. Verify the furniture you&apos;re purchasing can stand up to your local weather conditions. If it&apos;s not, you&apos;ll want to use portable furnishings that you can store during the harshest weather conditions.
 Try:  Furniture Leisure has a wide array of outdoor restaurant furniture including picnic tables and pool furniture. Central Restaurant Products can provide you with seating, lighting and fencing as part of your outdoor restaurant furniture.


 Take advantage of refurbished diner furnishings to save you money. Used restaurant furnishings can be picked up from restaurants going out of business or from companies who specialize in refurbishing restaurant and foodservice furnishings. 
 Tweet Research White Papers Business.com Home | About Us | Find Vendors | Business How To Guides | Business Blogs | Advertise With Business.com | Advertiser Login | Network Partners 
 Privacy | Terms Of Use 
©1999-2012 Business.com Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
