<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007558" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g293890-d1998271-Reviews-Thee_Fast_Food_Restaurant_and_Bar-Kathmandu.html" time="2012-07-13-00:31" support="1" score="0.00017811133541115426" bingtitle="Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar, Kathmandu - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar, Kathmandu - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar, Kathmandu: See unbiased ... I was really lucky to find this place. They are ... rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select ...</description>
	<body>
		Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar, Kathmandu
 
 Home Kathmandu 
 Kathmandu Tourism Kathmandu Hotels Kathmandu Vacation Rentals Flights to Kathmandu Kathmandu Restaurants Things to Do in Kathmandu Kathmandu Travel Forum Kathmandu Photos Kathmandu Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Asia &gt; Nepal &gt; Kathmandu &gt; Kathmandu Restaurants &gt; Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar 
 
 All 199 Kathmandu Restaurants» 
Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar
 Thamel, Tridevi Marg , Kathmandu , Nepal Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #117 of 199 restaurants in Kathmandu 1 Review Cuisines: American, Indian, Nepali Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
1 review from our community
 UUUberMan Reviewer 5 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “Good, cheap food, shisha and tongba!” Reviewed January 22, 2011 via mobile 
I was really lucky to find this place. They are much cheaper than every other place in Thamel (a veg Nepali set costs 100 rupees, shisha is 200, and tongba is 100). It&apos;s not the nicest looking place, but the staff is friendly, the food is good and the prices are hard to pass up. To make it better, their... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by UUUberMan for Kathmandu 1-1 of 1 review 1 
Been to Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Thee Fast Food Restaurant and Bar, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Radisson Hotel Kathmandu 153 Reviews Read reviews Kathmandu, Nepal Kantipur Temple House 235 Reviews Read reviews Kathmandu, Nepal Hyatt Regency Kathmandu 377 Reviews Read reviews Kathmandu, Nepal 
 All hotels in Kathmandu (118) 
Free Kathmandu Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Kathmandu restaurants

 Dwarika&apos;s Hotel Gaia Restaurant&amp;Coffee Shop chez caroline Bricks Cafe OR2K Roadhouse Cafe Thamel House Restaurant Funky Buddha Kathmandu Delices de France French restaurant Krishnarpan Restaurant BK&apos;s Place Mike&apos;s Breakfast Cozy Cafe&amp;Restaurant Fire and Ice - Kathmandu Lhakpa&apos;s Chulo Kaiser Cafe Le Sherpa Flavor&apos;s Cafe&amp;Restaurant Yangling Tibetan Restaurant Yeti Cafe Restaurant and Bar 
 
Hotels around Kathmandu

 Radisson Hotel Kathmandu 4.0 out of 5, 153 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Backyard Hotel 4.5 out of 5, 86 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Hotel Ganesh Himal 4.0 out of 5, 195 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 Kathmandu Madhuban Guest House 4.0 out of 5, 45 reviews Last reviewed Jul 8, 2012 Hotel Blue Horizon 4.0 out of 5, 174 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 Hotel Moonlight 4.0 out of 5, 86 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 Hotel Greenwich Village 3.5 out of 5, 13 reviews Last reviewed Jul 4, 2012 Sacred Valley Inn Kathmandu 4.5 out of 5, 108 reviews Last reviewed Jun 22, 2012 Elbrus Home 4.0 out of 5, 35 reviews Last reviewed Jun 11, 2012 Family Peace House 4.0 out of 5, 18 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Hotel Sunset View 3.5 out of 5, 8 reviews Last reviewed Jun 9, 2012 Hotel Tenki 4.0 out of 5, 14 reviews Last reviewed May 28, 2012 Shivapuri Retreat 4.0 out of 5, 1 review Last reviewed Apr 26, 2012 Hotel Metropolitan Kantipur 4.0 out of 5, 2 reviews Last reviewed Apr 25, 2012 Lhasa Guest House 4.0 out of 5, 1 review Last reviewed Apr 19, 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 O Poeta in Cascais 4.0 out of 5, 37 reviews Reef in Saint Augustine 3.5 out of 5, 119 reviews Hotel Saravana Bhavan in Chennai (Madras) 4.0 out of 5, 22 reviews Senso Maleva 1.0 out of 5, 3 reviews Kobe&apos;Japanese Steak House in Honolulu 3.5 out of 5, 59 reviews El Foco in Cozumel 4.5 out of 5, 42 reviews 
 Hotels 
 Residencial Pao de Acucar 4.0 out of 5, 236 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 Ibis Bay Waterfront Resort in Key West 3.0 out of 5, 272 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Desert Sand Hotel 3.5 out of 5, 43 reviews Last reviewed Jul 8, 2012 FogCatcher Inn in Cambria 4.5 out of 5, 546 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor®features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, vacation packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
