<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007811" url="http://buyitcanada.com/Montreal/Restaurant-Traiteurs/" time="2012-07-13-00:46" support="2" score="0.0008779092706788639" bingtitle="Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs Catering : BuyItCanada.com" webtitle="Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs Catering : BuyItCanada.com">
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>And since its inception, Second Cup ... Fast food restaurant chain, Burger King Restaurants of ... As we enter the new millennium, Giorgio Restaurants are changing with the times.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Content 
 Home Montreal Links Quebec Links Add-a-Link 
 Canada Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs 
Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs
 Custom Search 1 2 3 Next Last 
 Wendy&apos;s - Quality Is Our Recipe Nouveau Populaire 
 Wendy&apos;s®is the real choice in fast food. We deliver quality fresh food with real ingredients that provide the best tasting fast food at wendys.ca. www.wendys.ca 
 Restaurant La Perle Noire - Vietnamese, Thai and Sushi Bar Nouveau 
 Le Meilleur Restaurant Apportez Votre Vin au Rive Sud de Montral reconnut pour sa Fine Cuisine Vietnamien, Thalandaise et Bar Sushi. Le Meilleur Restaurant Vietnamien et Sushi prs des villes de Brossard, Longueuil et Montral. The Best Bring your Own Wine Restaurant in South Shore of Montral recognized for theirs Vietnamese, Thai Foods and Sushi Bar. The Best Vietnamese and Sushi Restaurant near Brossard, Longueuil, Montral. 4190, boul. Grande-Alle, Greenfield Park, Qubec J4V 3N2 Phone: 514-462-9899 laperlenoire.ca 
 Pizza Hut Populaire 
 Get it Hot. Get it Fresh! Get it Online! Convenient way to place your Pizza Hut order from your own PC. Choose your crust and then choose your toppings. Its that easy! www.pizzahut.ca 
 Tim Hortons Populaire 
 The chains biggest drawing card remains its legendary Tim Hortons coffee. The special blend is also available in cans, as are Tim Hortons hot chocolate and English Toffee and French Vanilla cappuccinos, so customers can also enjoy these great tasting products at home. www.timhortons.com 
 Starbucks Coffee Company Populaire 
 Starbucks Coffee Company is the leading retailer, roaster and brand of specialty coffee in the world. The Company&apos;s other brands enhance the Starbucks Experience through best-of-class products, including Tazo Tea Company and Hear Music. www.starbucks.com 
 Boston Pizza Populaire 
 The Boston Pizza restaurant provides for &quot;two experiences under one roof&quot;, with a full service, family friendly casual dining restaurant and a separate sports bar. Most restaurants also have an outdoor patio to accommodate guests during the warmer months. A typical restaurant is 5,500 to 6,500 square feet and has seating for 180 to 225 guests inside with another 50 to 75 seats on the patio. www.bostonpizza.com 
 Subway Restaurants - Canada Populaire 
 The first SUBWAY restaurant in Canada opened in June of 1986 in St. Johns, Newfoundland. With so many SUBWAY restaurants, it is no surprise that you could find one just about anywhere in Canada, from Banff and Jasper National Parks to Bishop OBryne High School in Calgary. www.freshenergy.com 
 McDonald&apos;s Restaurants of Canada Ltd. Populaire 
 In 1967 the first McDonald&apos;s restaurant outside of the United States opened in Richmond, British Columbia. Every day since then, McDonald&apos;s Canada has been proud to provide our customers the same great taste, outstanding value, quality and superior service that the Golden Arches is known for worldwide. www.mcdonalds.ca 
 The Keg Steakhouse&amp;Bar - A steakhouse with a difference. Populaire 
 Great Keg steaks, a casual atmosphere, and friendly, knowledgeable service are the proud trademarks of The Keg Steakhouse&amp;Bar. Visit, and experience firsthand The Keg philosophy of welcoming you not as a customer, but as a guest. Every location offers a truly comfortable and satisfying dining atmosphere accompanied by a fun and casual bar setting. Each is a welcoming destination on its own, and together they create an energetic and inviting, uniquely gratifying restaurant experience. www.kegsteakhouse.com 
 A&amp;W Food Services of Canada Inc. Populaire 
 A&amp;W;is Canada&apos;s original hamburger quick service restaurant chain, and today is one of its fastest growing. The first A&amp;W;drive-in restaurant in Canada opened on Portage Avenue in Winnipeg in 1956. The combination of great tasting burgers, onion rings and frosted mugs of famous A&amp;W;Root Beer served by friendly carhops was an instant hit. A&amp;W;quickly flourished across the nation through the late 50&apos;s and 60&apos;s. In many communities, A&amp;W;was the first branded food service restaurant to come to town. Because we were there first, A&amp;W;drive-ins became the gathering place for the community. Millions of Canadians today carry vivid memories of special moments of their lives that were played out at their local A&amp;W;drive-in. www.aw.ca 
 Quiznos Sub Populaire 
 Subs, Lunch Sandwich, Salad, Catering, Quick, Fast Food www.quiznos.ca 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza - Dominos.ca Populaire 
 Menu for Dominos pizza Canada including the various pizza toppings, side items as well as pizza nutrition information and Dominos coupons. Pizza choices including pepperoni pizza, Ultimate Deep Dish, Crunchy Thin Crust, and more. www.dominos.ca 
 Second Cup Populaire 
 From a humble beginning in 1975 as a shopping mall kiosk that only sold whole bean coffee, Second Cup has become Canada&apos;s largest specialty coffee retailer. And since its inception, Second Cup has grown to more than 360 cafs across Canada and over 15 cafs internationally, making Second Cup a second home to hundreds of guests every day. www.secondcup.com 
 Burger King Restaurants of Canada Inc. Populaire 
 Fast food restaurant chain, Burger King Restaurants of Canada Inc., offers nutritional information on menu items such as WHOPPER(R) sandwiches, burgers and French fries. Check out what&apos;s new for Kids. Refer to the &apos;Find a BK&apos; section of the site to find a restaurant near you. www.burgerking.ca 
 MR.SUB - More than Enough Populaire 
 The first MR.SUB restaurant opened in Toronto, Ontario in March of 1968. Right from the start, the concept was simple: sell quality subs, make them fresh, and serve them fast. And above all, give customers value for their money. www.mrsub.ca 1 2 3 Next Last Custom Search 
Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs
 Canada Montreal Restaurant-Traiteurs ADVERTISEMENT ADVERTISEMENT 
 Home Montreal Links Quebec Links Add-a-Link Modify-a-Link 
 | Advanced Search | Advertise | Contact | Frequently Asked Questions | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | A free Canadian service since 1999. Submit your free Canadian link today. Visit the faqs page for instruction on how to add your link. Copyright 1999 - All Rights Reserved. BuyItCanada Trademark of BuyItCanada Information Services Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
