<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007473" url="http://www.businessweek.com/ap/2012-04/D9U38P081.htm" time="2012-07-13-00:26" support="6" score="0.025010483121784256" bingtitle="March US foreclosure activity down near 5-year low - BusinessWeek" webtitle="March US foreclosure activity down near 5-year low - BusinessWeek">
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>March US foreclosure activity down near 5-year low ... the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place ... Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments ...</description>
	<body>
		Businessweek - Business News, Stock Market&amp;Financial Advice Bloomberg Businessweek 
 Businessweek 
 
 Global Economics 
 
 Corporate Income Growth Presents a Rorschach Test 

Are slowing corporate income forecasts merely conservative estimating or a sign that the troubles from Europe and China are arriving?
 
 Global Economics 

 
 China&apos;s Deflationary Threat 
 
 What Can Europe Learn From Alexander Hamilton? 
 
 College Grads Find Retail a (Meager) Route to Job Market 
 
 The Price of Too Big to Fail 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Corporate Income Growth Presents a Rorschach Test 
 
 Fair Britain on His Shoulders 
 
 Why Young and Old Americans Have More in Common Than You Think 
 
 Now Wall Street Doesn&apos;t Want Your Money? 
 
 June Jobs: Five Things You Need to Know 
 
 
 Sections 

 Africa China Current Events Calendar Emerging Markets Energy Europe Global Economics India Latin America Blog: Econochat 
 
 Companies&amp;Industries 
 
 Where Vacationing Media Moguls Enjoy More Than Scenery 

Allen&amp;Co.&apos;s annual conference in Sun Valley has been the birthplace of many big media deals
 
 Companies&amp;Industries 

 
 RIM&apos;s Annual Shareholder Meeting Tomorrow, Lawsuit? 
 
 Alcoa 2nd Quarter Profit, Revenue Beat Estimates 
 
 Pay-As-You-Drive Insurance Gets a Push From Progressive 
 
 What&apos;s in Your Digital Wallet? 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Test-Driving Tesla Motors&apos;s Super-Fast Model S 
 
 How the Mormons Make Money 
 
 College Grads Find Retail a (Meager) Route to Job Market 
 
 The Imitator&apos;s Edge 
 
 U.S. Airport Capacity: Failure to Launch 
 
 
 Sections 

 Autos Company Research Energy Executive Research Health Care Job Search Management Manufacturing Telecommunications Transportation Blog: The Management Blog 
 
 Politics&amp;Policy 
 
 Mitt Romney Stinks at Being Rich 

He&apos;s outraising Obama, but the GOP nominee is becoming a caricature of an out-of-touch plutocrat
 
 Politics&amp;Policy 

 
 Italian PM Says He Won&apos;t Serve Beyond End of Term 
 
 U.S. Commodities Regulator Sues Peregrine 
 
 U.K. Lawmaker Expects Barclays CEO to Be Recalled in Probe 
 
 What Can Europe Learn From Alexander Hamilton? 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Why Young and Old Americans Have More in Common Than You Think 
 
 Will &apos;Living Wills&apos; Prevent the Next Meltdown? 
 
 The Make-Believe Debate Over Health Care 
 
 Why Mitt Romney Won&apos;t Take a Stand 
 
 June Jobs: Five Things You Need to Know 
 
 
 Sections 

 2012 Campaign Congress Courts Legislation White House Blog: Joshua Green on Politics 
 
 Technology 
 
 A New Contender in Bloody Gaming-Console Wars 

A startup called Ouya wants to take on Sony and Microsoft in the video-game console wars
 
 Technology 

 
 In Silicon Valley, Hardware Is Hot Again 
 
 Gartner Raises IT Spending Growth Projection 
 
 Twitter Ads Hit or Miss With Small Business 
 
 CEO Guide to Mobile Advertising and Marketing 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 As Innovation Declines, ITU Hopes to Ease Mobile Patent Wars 
 
 Test-Driving Tesla Motors&apos;s Super-Fast Model S 
 
 A New Contender in Bloody Gaming-Console Wars 
 
 Want to See the Future of Mobile Coverage? Go to a Baseball Game 
 
 Why Links Matter: Linking Is the Lifeblood of the Web 
 
 
 Sections 

 Apple Apps&amp;Software CEO Tech Guide Consumer Electronics Facebook Google Mobile&amp;Telecom Personal Technology Science&amp;Research Social Media 
 
 Markets&amp;Finance 
 
 Pay-As-You-Drive Insurance Gets a Push From Progressive 

To qualify for discounts, motorists must first plug a monitoring device into the dashboard, sharing when and how far they drive and how often or hard they brake
 
 Markets&amp;Finance 

 
 The Price of Too Big to Fail 
 
 RIM CEO Fails to Reassure Investors 
 
 How to Play Bank Stocks Ahead of Earnings 
 
 Election-Year Investing: Summer Rally? 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Corporate Income Growth Presents a Rorschach Test 
 
 A Racial Legacy of the Subprime Crisis: Damaged Credit Scores 
 
 China&apos;s Deflationary Threat 
 
 Now Wall Street Doesn&apos;t Want Your Money? 
 
 Will &apos;Living Wills&apos; Prevent the Next Meltdown? 
 
 
 Sections 

 Banks Commodities Currencies Hedge Funds Investing Mutual Funds&amp;ETFs Private Equity Real Estate Regulation Stocks&amp;Bonds Wall Street 
 
 Innovation 
 
 Test-Driving Tesla Motors&apos;s Super-Fast Model S 

The all-electric Model S sedan has just hit the streets. The car is electric, and it flies
 
 Innovation 

 
 Want to See the Future of Mobile Coverage? Go to a Baseball Game 
 
 Sony Scores Big with the Amazing Spider-Man 
 
 As Innovation Declines, ITU Hopes to Ease Mobile Patent Wars 
 
 The Imitator&apos;s Edge 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Zack Parisa&apos;s Forest Inventory Software 
 
 Google’s Nexus 7: It&apos;s Here to Snuff Kindle&apos;s Fire 
 
 The Lucrative Business of Fake, Life-Size Dinosaurs 
 
 Wanted: Apps to Manage Your Money 
 
 Before IPhone and Android Came Simon, the First Smartphone 
 
 
 Sections 

 Copyright Fix This/Health Care Innovators Patents Privacy Reinventing Business Trademarks 
 
 Lifestyle 
 
 Odd Jobs: Professional Balloon Twister 

Todd Neufeld is America&apos;s most popular artist of latex and helium
 
 Lifestyle 

 
 David Kalt, Guitar Hero 
 
 Chef Ricardo Zarate&apos;s Office Bag Lunch 
 
 Secret of the Unbeatable Rock-Paper-Scissors Robot 
 
 Ask Claire Suddath: No Office-Related Question Is Too Strange 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Test-Driving Tesla Motors&apos;s Super-Fast Model S 
 
 How David Einhorn Was Out-Bluffed at the Poker Table 
 
 The &apos;Portlandia&apos; Bump: Oregon&apos;s Thriving Film Scene 
 
 Office Upgrade: The Magneto Lamp 
 
 Bunker Down 
 
 
 Sections 

 Books Fashion Food&amp;Drink Gadgets&amp;Accessories Hard Choices Travel Workplace 
 
 Business Schools 
 
 The Doctor Is In: Johns Hopkins B-School Gets a New Dean 

Dr. Bernard Ferrari takes over the Carey School as it transitions its programs to a focus on health care. He talks with Bloomberg Businessweek about what lies ahead
 
 Business Schools 

 
 Employers Warm Up to Online MBAs 
 
 How I Got Here: General Mills&apos; Anton Vincent 
 
 MBA Startups Find Alumni Angels With Money to Burn 
 
 MBA Pay: Peering Into the Future 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 A Day in the Life: Sustainability Manager 
 
 B-School Photo of the Week: ESADE 
 
 B-School Twitter Roundup 
 
 Favorite Professors: Emory&apos;s Allison Burdette 
 
 Have Business Schools Found Their Way? 
 
 
 Sections 

 B-School Calendar Compare B-Schools Financial Aid Finding a Job Forums MBA Admissions Rankings&amp;Profiles Undergrad Programs Blog: Getting In Blog: Business School Explained 
 
 Small Business 
 
 To Boost Small Business Credit, Think Small (Banks) 

As the big banks cut back on small loans to entrepreneurs, their smaller counterparts are crucial for making up the difference
 
 Small Business 

 
 Worker Shortage? Teach Teens Manufacturing Skills 
 
 Remaking the Family Farm 
 
 Accelerators Try to Get Startups to Stick Around 
 
 Can You Really Learn to Cook Professionally Online? 
 
 
 Recent 

 
 Divining the Future of Small Business Hiring 
 
 Odd Jobs: Professional Balloon Twister 
 
 A Microfinance &apos;Heretic&apos; on How to Fix the Industry 
 
 Twitter Ads Hit or Miss With Small Business 
 
 The &apos;Portlandia&apos; Bump: Oregon&apos;s Thriving Film Scene 
 
 
 Sections 

 Advice Commentary Financing Legal Documents Policy Profiles Blog: The New Entrepreneur 
 
 Video&amp;Multimedia 
 
 Slideshows 

 
Social Media Misfires
 
Bunker Down
 
Stand-Up Desks: 10 Options Reviewed
 
Five Workplace Dramas As Yet Unscripted by Aaron Sorkin
 
 
 Photo Essays 

 
The Wealth Gap and Upward Mobility
 
Rangoon&apos;s Mix of Colonial and Modern
 
 
 Charts 

 
Just Shazam It
 
Germany&apos;s Economy Catches the Euro Flu
 
 
 Videos 

 
Bio-Batteries Powered by Sugar
 
Roubini: 2013 Perfect Storm May Surpass 2008 Crisis
 
Apple May Sell 6 Million Smaller iPads This Year
 
Mitsubishi UFJ Suspends Two London Traders
 
 
 
 The Associated Press April 12, 2012, 04:04AM ET 
March US foreclosure activity down near 5-year low

By ALEX VEIGA
 
Story Tools

 order a reprint digg this save to del.icio.us 
 
 LOS ANGELES 
More U.S. homes are entering the foreclosure process, setting the stage for a surge in properties repossessed by lenders this year.

The number of homes that received first-time foreclosure notices rose 7 percent in March from the previous month, foreclosure listing firm RealtyTrac Inc. said Thursday.

That marks the third consecutive monthly increase this year and reflects stepped-up efforts by banks to take action against homeowners who fail to keep up with mortgage payments.

&quot;We&apos;re not out of the woods yet with foreclosures,&quot;said Daren Blomquist, a vice president at RealtyTrac.&quot;There are more batches of foreclosures coming through the pipeline.&quot;

Foreclosure activity, as measured by the number of homes receiving foreclosure-related notices, slowed sharply in the fall of 2010 when claims surfaced that some banks and mortgage servicers were processing foreclosures without verifying documents.

A $25 billion ((EURO)19 billion) settlement reached in February between the biggest U.S. mortgage lenders and state officials has paved the way for banks to take action on unpaid mortgages, many of which have been in a procedural limbo for months or years. And it&apos;s those homes that could ultimately be foreclosed-upon and end up back on the market.

Foreclosures typically sell at a discount to other homes and can drag down the value of neighboring properties, so the prospect of more foreclosures means it could take longer for home prices in some areas to bounce back.

The U.S. housing market remains weak, even after the best winter for home sales in five years and steady improvement in the job market. Home prices are now back to 2002 levels, according to the Standard&amp;Poor&apos;s/Case-Shiller U.S. home price index.

Rather than a large wave of bank-owned homes crashing onto the market at once, it&apos;s likely the new crop of foreclosures will arrive in smaller waves throughout the year, Blomquist said.

Still, many of the homes entering the foreclosure process now are properties with loans that have gone unpaid for a long time, not instances of borrowers just starting to fall behind. That suggests the possibility that the number of homes at risk of foreclosure could begin to taper off once banks tackle the crop of homes with long-overdue mortgage payments.

&quot;The faster we can move some of these old foreclosures through the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place to recover,&quot;Blomquist said.

At the end of last year, some 1.5 million U.S. homes had mortgages that had gone unpaid at least 90 days, according to Mortgage Bankers Association data.

First-time foreclosure notices, such as warnings of initial default, are the first step in the process that can potentially result in a home being foreclosed upon. Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are paid. Sometimes, a bank will allow that the home be sold for less than what the borrower owes on their mortgage, a so-called short sale.

All told, 101,939 U.S. homes received a first-time notice in March, the biggest monthly increase since October, RealtyTrac said.

Thirty-one states posted a monthly increase in homes with a first-time foreclosure notice. Nevada led the pack with an increase of 153 percent.

Even so, foreclosure activity overall -- as measured by the number of properties receiving a notice of default, scheduled for auction or repossessed by lenders -- sank in March to the lowest level since July 2007, the firm said.

In all, 198,853 homes received a foreclosure-related notice last month, down 4 percent from February, and down 17 percent from March last year.

Banks took back 55,075 homes in March, down 14 percent from the previous month, and down 25 percent from March 2011.

RealtyTrac expects banks will repossess close to 1 million homes this year. Last year, lenders took back 804,000 homes.

For the first three months of this year, foreclosure activity fell 2 percent compared to the last quarter of 2011 and was down 16 percent from the first quarter of last year, the firm said.

 
BW Extras

 Podcasts Mandel on Economics Behind the Cover CEO Guide to Tech more… 

 RSS Feeds Most Popular Top News Innovation Trends more… 

 E-mails Asia Insider MBA Express BW.com Insider more… 

 Blogs Blogspotting Hot Property Tech Beat more… 
   
Most Popular Stories

 Read E-mailed Discussed 

 Three Types of People to Fire Immediately Lego Is for Girls Google&apos;s Spreading Tentacles of Influence Gatorade Goes Back to the Lab Impress Potential Investors in 12 Steps 

 RSS Feed: Most Read Stories 

 Three Types of People to Fire Immediately Which Is America&apos;s Best City? Lego Is for Girls Top B-School Stories of 2011 Professional Women and a Secure Retirement 

 RSS Feed: Most E-mailed Stories 

 Facebook&apos;s Holocaust Controversy America&apos;s Best, Affordable Places to Raise Kids Bullpen Diaries 

 RSS Feed: Most Discussed Stories 
 
Most Popular Multimedia

 Slide Shows 

 Tuition-Free Colleges Twenty Tips for First-Time Managers The Best Design Schools in the World 

 RSS Feed: Most Popular Slide Shows 
 
BW Mall - Sponsored Links

 Buy a link now! 
 
Social

 Follow us on Twitter Join us on Facebook Connect with us on LinkedIn Subscribe to Bloomberg Businessweek Bloomberg 
 
Links

 About Advertising Careers Feedback Custom Publishing Manage Subscription 

 Mobile Newsletters Privacy Policy Reprints&amp;Permissions Sitemap Terms of Use [+] Rate This Page 
 
Get Businessweek Delivered
 
 Planet Deere 
 Subscribe 
 @2012 Bloomberg L.P. All Rights Reserved. Made in NYC Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
