<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007680" url="http://www.forrent.com/apartment-community-profile/1019513.php" time="2012-07-13-00:38" support="26" score="0.0759248332740145" bingtitle="Park at Barrington Place, The Apartments For Rent in Holiday ..." webtitle="Park at Barrington Place, The Apartments For Rent in Holiday, Florida - Apartment Rental and Community Details - ForRent.com">
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000683" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000581" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>Park at Barrington Place, The in Holiday, FL ... on the left (plaza Drive) Behind the McDonalds fast food restaurant. ... Car Loan Application; Moving Center; Free Moving Quotes</description>
	<body>
		Careers Advertise Managers&amp;Owners 
 Connect with Facebook Why Connect? 
 Search Relocation Tips Mobile Senior Living En Español 
 
   Home  ›  Search  ›  Results 
 
Park at Barrington Place, The

4348 Plaza Dr Holiday, FL 34691-2820
 
Check Availability
 Questions or Comments? Receive parenting and Kids&apos; Camps information from Parenthood.com. 
 ForRent.com Privacy Policy 
 
Moving Resources
 
 Check Your Credit 

 (866) 308-4221 
 
 Save Compare · Print · Email A Friend · Check Your Credit 
 
Floor Plans
 
 Name Beds Baths Price Floor Plan Room Planner Availability Amelia 1 1 $565 Check Availability Beechnut 1 1 $565 Check Availability Destiny 2 1 $600 Check Availability Camelia 2 1 $640 Check Availability Elm 2 2 $745 Check Availability 
 
Features&amp;Amenities
 
Description

The Park at Barrington Place Welcomes You to Your New Home! Our spacious one and two bedroom apartment homes offer everything you need, from generous-sized closets fabulous amenities. Exceptional value, size and service is our motto. A perfect Pasco County location puts you near shopping, banking, dining and sandy beaches and so much more. So come join us at The Park at Barrington Place Where we have something special For everyone. Come visit today!!
 
Features

 $299 Moves you in!! Elevators in Every Building Water/Sewer/Pest Control Included 3 Sparkling Pools Controlled Access Gate System Laundry Facility in each Building Resident Business Center Private Screened In Balcony/Patio select units Spacious Floorplans/Walk-in Closets 24 hour Fitness Center Upgraded Light Fixtures/Plantation Shutters Enclosed Pet Area&amp;Playground 
 
or call (866) 308-4221 
 
Pet Policy

Pet Friendly, Large Pet&apos;s Welcome! Certain Breed Restrictions Apply.
 
Amenities

 • Accepts Credit Card Payments • Accepts Electronic Payments • Air Conditioning • Apartment • Business Center Onsite • Carpet • Cats Allowed • Ceiling Fan • Club House • Controlled Access • Courtyard • Dishwasher • Elevator • Fitness Center • Garbage Disposal • Garden Style • Garden Style • Housing Vouchers Welcome • Internet Access • Large Dogs • Laundry Facility • Market Rate • Microwave • Military • Mixed Use • Mixed Use • Patio or Balcony • Pets Allowed • Playground • Pool • Public Transportation • Small Dogs Allowed • Surface Lot • Tile Floors • View • Walk In Closets • Water Sewer and Trash • Window Covering • Wireless Internet Access 

 
Additional Information

Year Remodeled: 565

Apartments in Community: 244
 
Park at Barrington Place, The in Holiday, FL
 
The Park at Barrington Place in Holiday, FL, is conveniently located by the Sponge Docks in Tarpon Springs, Howard Park and beach and a short drive to Clearwater, Dunedin, and New Port Richey. There is plenty of shopping including Westfield Countryside&amp;Gulfview Square Mall. Our apartment homes for rent include spacious walk-in closets, patios, and washer/dryer hook-ups. We also offer a gated community, 3 pools, business center and elevators. Call us today for great move-in specials!

 Oodle Marketplace, part of the ForRent.com Network 
 
or call (866) 308-4221 
 
Location of Park at Barrington Place, The
 Show Map Show E-Map 
Property Information
 
 or call (866) 308-4221 
 
 

 Park at Barrington Place, The 

 4348 Plaza Dr 
Suite # 330
 Holiday, FL 34691-2820 

 Send to Cell 

 Click to Talk 

 See Your Walk Score®62 

 Fax : (727) 942-2386 

New Owner, New Management&amp;New Attitude.

Unbelievable Pricing without Compromising your Lifestyle!!!

 See Other Equity Management Communities 


 
 
Specials and Promotions
 
$299 Moves you in! Click here for Details.
 
Directions and Office Hours
 
Directions

From Clearwater, travel north on U.S. Hwy 19 just past Sunray Drive--we are on the left (plaza Drive) Behind the McDonalds fast food restaurant. From Hudson, travel south on U.S. Hwy 19 just past Moog Rd.--we are on the right (Plaza Drive) behind the McDonalds fast food restaurant.


Office Hours

Mon-Fri 9 AM - 6 PM
Saturday 10 AM - 5 PM
Sunday 1 PM - 5 PM

 
Finance Center
 Check Your Credit 
 Car Loan Application 
 
Moving Center
 Free Moving Quotes 
 Movers Checklist 
 Storage 
 
Getting Settled
 Find a Job 
 Find a Roommate 
 Furniture 
 
More Holiday Apartments For Rent
 
 FL Apartments Greater Tampa Bay Apartments Pasco County Apartments 
 
 Holiday Apartments 34691 Apartments 
 
 About Holiday Holiday Real Estate 
 
 Key Vista Apartments 
 Connect with Facebook Why Connect? 
Park at Barrington Place, The Apartments for Rent in Holiday, Florida

Park at Barrington Place, The Apartments for rent in Holiday, Florida offers floor plan (1-2 bedroom, 1.0-2.0 bathroom) and amenity options that meet a wide range of tastes and needs. The apartment amenities include Accepts Credit Card Payments, Accepts Electronic Payments, Air Conditioning, Apartment, Business Center Onsite, Carpet, Cats Allowed, Ceiling Fan, Club House, Controlled Access, Courtyard, Dishwasher, Elevator, Fitness Center, Garbage Disposal, Garden Style, Garden Style, Housing Vouchers Welcome, Internet Access, Large Dogs, Laundry Facility, Market Rate, Microwave, Military, Mixed Use, Mixed Use, Patio or Balcony, Pets Allowed, Playground, Pool, Public Transportation, Small Dogs Allowed, Surface Lot, Tile Floors, Unspecified, View, Walk In Closets, Water Sewer and Trash, Window Covering, and Wireless Internet Access! View information on available prices, photos, virtual tours, floor plans, amenities, pet policies, property details and have instant contact with the community at Park at Barrington Place, The in Holiday, Florida.
 
Receive Apartment Matches by Email
 
Follow Us

 
 
Resources
 
Moving Center

 Free Moving Quotes Movers Checklist Affordable Storage Units 
 
Finance Center

 Check Your Credit Car Loan Application 
 
Getting Settled

 Find a Job Find a Roommate Furniture Renters Insurance 
 
Site Links

 Home Visitor Agreement Managers&amp;Owners Privacy Policy Advertise Fraud Prevention Tips Press Room Accessible Housing Contact ForRent.com About Us Site Map Apartment Tips Careers Order a Magazine 
 
Search Links

 City Zip Code Name Military College 
 
ForRent.com, Dominion Enterprises, Property Managers, Owners and paid advertisers are not responsible for typographical errors. Prices are subject to change without notice.
 
ForRent.com is part of the Homes.com and ForRent.com Network

 ©2012 Dominion Enterprises, All Rights Reserved . Equal Opportunity Housing 
 X Connect with Facebook Why Connect? X X 
Send property information to my cell phone
 Enter your cell phone number -
	</body>
</document>
