<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007341" url="https://litigation-essentials.lexisnexis.com/webcd/app?action=DocumentDisplay&amp;crawlid=1&amp;doctype=cite&amp;docid=45+Fla.+L.+Rev.+163&amp;srctype=smi&amp;srcid=3B15&amp;key=8ac472c540201d4d53048ce7e19387dd" time="2012-07-13-00:18" support="1" score="0.0015308041392092153" bingtitle="FRANCHISING AND CONSUMERS&apos; BELIEFS ABOUT &quot;TIED&quot; PRODUCTS: THE ..." webtitle="ARTICLE: FRANCHISING AND CONSUMERS&apos; BELIEFS ABOUTTIEDPRODUCTS: THE DEATH KNELL FOR KREHL?">
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="203"/>
	<description>... to purchase a second, &quot;tied&quot; product in order to ... involve a business format system--a fast-food restaurant chain ... article, as well as basic economic realities, confirm ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip over navigation Browse Law Reviews and Treatises Skip over navigation Sign in with your lexis.com® ID to access the full text of this article.   -OR- Order the full text of this article if you do not have a lexis.com® ID.   Price:  US $15.00 (+ tax) Yahoo!®Currency Converter     Subject to Terms&amp;Conditions 
Copyright (c) 1993 Florida Law Review
Florida Law Review

ARTICLE: FRANCHISING AND CONSUMERS&apos; BELIEFS ABOUT&quot;TIED&quot;PRODUCTS: THE DEATH KNELL FOR KREHL?

April 1993

45 Fla. L. Rev. 163

Author
 Robert W. Emerson* ** 
Excerpt
 I. INTRODUCTION

If a franchisor requires its franchisees to purchase certain products, either directly from the franchisor or from a source financially related to the franchisor, can the franchisee successfully challenge such a requirement? Or can the franchisor defeat such a challenge by proving that the franchise and the&quot;tied&quot;products are so closely linked that they actually constitute a single product?

Franchisors have defeated many franchisees&apos; challenges using a number of arguments based in economics, marketing, and even consumer psychology. This article examines these arguments in light of the contention that a franchise and certain products sold at a franchise are, for antitrust tying purposes, a single item. 1 This article focuses on judicial notions of public perceptions about franchises and their trademarked products. Judges&apos; ideas about what the consuming public believes when it purchases products have influenced an entire line of antitrust tying cases. This article contends that the underlying premise of these cases is flawed both empirically and as a matter of policy. After analyzing the law and economics in Part II, this article compares judicial guesswork about public beliefs with actual public beliefs as reflected in a random public survey. It concludes by outlining a simpler, more sensible approach to resolving the basic tying question: When is a franchised trademark separate from the products sold under that trademark?

II. FRANCHISING AND THE SINGLE-PRODUCT DEFENSE TO ANTITRUST TYING ALLEGATIONS

A. Tying Law and Economics 

In antitrust law, a tying arrangement requires buyers ...     If you are interested in obtaining a lexis.com® ID and Password, please contact us at 1-(800)-227-4908 or visit us at http://www.lexisnexis.com/ . Search Documents   eg., Environmental Insurance Coverage Under the Comprehensive General Liability Policy See Related Content   Lexis®Web - Beta       
Lexis®Web - The only search engine that delivers free web content specifically from legal sites validated by LexisNexis®attorney editors and includes tools for faster research and more relevant results.
   
 
 
 
   LexisNexis®Products   
 LexisNexis®Services at www.lexis.com LexisNexis®Store LexisNexis®Web Communities 
     Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | Copyright ©2012 LexisNexis, a division of Reed Elsevier, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
