<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007634" url="http://www.mahalo.com/arbys/" time="2012-07-13-00:36" support="2" score="0.0035352065643344246" bingtitle="Arby&apos;s - Mahalo.com" webtitle="Arbys">
			<query id="000230" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000747" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>Arby&apos;s is a fast food restaurant chain that features roast beef ... Cheddar Roast Burger with curly fries and a drink. ... Number of franchises</description>
	<body>
		login | register 
 
 Home How To Courses Answers 
 Search 
Arby&apos;s
 Tweet 
 Arby&apos;s is a fast food restaurant chain that features roast beef sandwiches and is found in 48 states and five countries. It has a variety of menu items in addition to roast beef such as chicken sandwiches and sides. It has positioned itself as a more adult fast food establishment in contrast to McDonald&apos;s and Burger King .

On September 29 , 2008 , Triarc Companies Inc. merged with Wendy&apos;s International, Inc. to form Wendy&apos;s/Arby&apos;s Group, it is the third largest fast food restaurant company in the United States . http://www.arbys.com/about/ 

On April 9 , 2010 , Arby’s Restaurant Group, Inc. made a national launch of a new Value Menu, adding more lower priced items to its menu that will be supported by new
advertising creative. http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Arbys-Launches-National-Value-bw-3301501486.html?x=0&amp;.v=1 
 
A.R.B.Y.S
 
When the Raffel Brothers were thinking up a name for their fledgling business, they settled on the initials R.B. which stands for Raffel Brothers. It also stands for roast beef, and in the 1980s , marketers turned the entire Arby&apos;s name into an acronym for &quot;America&apos;s Roast Beef, Yes Sir.&quot;
 
Arby&apos;s Menu
 
 Roast beef sandwiches Chicken sandwiches Market Fresh sandwiches Chopped salads Toasted subs Curly fries Potato cakes Mozzarella sticks Potato bites Onion petals Jalapeno poppers Beverages Desserts 
 
Arby&apos;s Value Menu
 
 Jr. Roast Beef Jr. Chicken Sandwich Jr. Ham and Cheddar Sandwich Value Curly Fires Value Shakes Value Soft Drink Turnovers 
 
Arby&apos;s $5 Combo Commerical
 Save Cancel URL | Web Search YouTube 5min Vimeo Flowplayer Ustream 
 YouTube 5min Search 
 
Select a video
 Arby&apos;s Commercial 2009
	</body>
</document>
