<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007184" url="http://peshawar.saintclassified.pk/community-2" time="2012-07-13-00:09" support="1" score="0.0009389577456174636" bingtitle="Community Peshawar" webtitle="Community Peshawar">
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>The only fast food restaurant, institutional sales of machinery and ... Government and semi Government Sami&apos;a by fiber glass ... A company of his Islamabad office for sales exit ...</description>
	<body>
		Community - Peshawar 
 
 Send Free SMS 
 Post a Free Classified Ad or 
 Select a Category Business Directory Classes Community For Sale Jobs Naukri Employement Matrimonial Shaadi Rishta Personals Real Estate Property Services Vehicles Search 
 Sign in  or  Sign up 
 
 
Category: Home &gt; Community



Results for Community in Pakistan   Showing  1 - 62  Record(s) 
 
 
 computer institute, please contact me, 12 latjeli anyone, here to teach 
 
I opened a computer institute and an internet cafe just for women and children under 12 lat.jeli anyone interested to join this institute, please contact me. Mr. staff is avai...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jul 05 ,
 one week ago       
 We need volunteers for change, submit and join, president of the, Ullah and work 
 
Salam GUYS! How are you I hope it will be well lit and I&apos;m with people on social Faiz Ullah and work as president of the SGP and in need of volunteers from all over Pakistan, ...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jun 22 ,
 3 weeks ago       
 We need volunteers, is kogoo contact, ask JION us, the people SOCIAL 
 
I am from the people SOCIAL PRESIDENT Faiz Ullah and I voulunteers to change, if you want to volunteer and then ask JION us if you still can not raise his hand and voice is ko...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jun 22 ,
 3 weeks ago       
 I need people to create websites, revenue hogi , me zaati, le k yo 
 
Assalam-o-alaikum przyjacielMujhe AIK AISE zarurat Dost ki on ...... jo ko website design and management of Karna Janta ho ......... me zaati us bande ko domain and hosting Du...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jun 05 ,
 one month ago       
 I greet you, plz see the description, 03,014,352,040 balay2007yahoocom, age, every type, mature than me, 
 
im 32 years of age from Peshawar, im looking for girl freind that needs to be mature than me, has to be heavy body, regardless of age, every type of female can contect, 03,014...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
May 21 ,
 2 months ago       
 &apos;;&apos;; &apos;;] [] [] [&apos;; &apos;; Asalaamualikom;&apos;; &apos;;&apos;;] [] [] [, panel to u, makybravoTextCashNetworkcomHello buddys is, communication on the 
 
makybravo.TextCashNetwork.com
Hello buddys is a form panel to u guys to get cash in ($) in the function may have a very Easy just to achieve
Or a group of friends and start ...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Apr 03 ,
 4 months ago       
 Conditional girl , Nativity Mr Shaker, unconditional girl please 
 
If you want unconditional girl please Nativity. Mr. Shaker 03128222781-03329242407
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Apr 03 ,
 4 months ago       
 maky , start cash , any network can, 
 
www.makybravo.cashnetwork.com
In my site. One can see that any network can start cash
: &quot;:&quot; {} {} {&quot;&quot;: &quot;{} {} {
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Mar 30 ,
 4 months ago       
 We are in search for a singer (near Islamabad and Peshawar) , or cold and , and words of , We have two 
 
Hello everyone!
We have two boys with orchestra .. We make beats, music and words of our own at home one month ago .. But now we have something like that and saw that we need...
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Mar 24 ,
 4 months ago       
 Looking for decent woman / beautiful and educated for marriage 2ND (AGE 25 35) , and wonderful want , Divrorced wants to , Looking for God 
 
May Allah help me in finding a life partner is not it? Looking for life partner strong for the second marriage and I am working as Banker I am 42 years old and looking for a l...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Mar 06 ,
 5 months ago       
 BG School of Music between competition , 92 321 9006469 , place at later , educational talent BG 
 
BG stimuli talent consulting and organization of a competition between schools music (up to grade 5)
We need sponsors for the event.
Schools can Interseted schools and prima...
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Feb 27 ,
 5 months ago       
 Marriage , 40 for marriage , 40 for marriage , 35 40 for 
 
Male Age I want an honest and sincere (35-40) for marriage
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 # # # # # # Good news for Arabic learners under 
 
# # # # # # Good news for Arabic learners under the supervision of expert teachers of Arabic Slang practice management duties ... ykm # beginning of February 2012 Course Durat...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Mother Child Health and Education Welfare Organisation NGO dedicated to the health 
 
Mother Child Health and Education Welfare Organisation NGO dedicated to the health of very low fees for courses is done by ultrasound in 3 months, also for free demo classes, ...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 PHP Web Developing Software House in PWX learn in 3 months Free 
 
PHP Web Developing Software House in PWX learn in 3 months Free Demo Contact 0345-9532281,0344-2253516 for 3344 ... ... ... ... ...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Under the supervision of professional web development, designing CMS-Joomla/SEO learn in just 
 
Under the supervision of professional web development, designing CMS-Joomla/SEO learn in just 2 months Ksoft Defense Computer Institute 0300-3389845, 35486924, www.ksoftint.co...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Old refrigerator, AC, Split unit fryrzr very poor condition and old sofa 
 
Old refrigerator, AC, Split unit fryrzr very poor condition and old sofa bed for sale Rome Matters foam coolers are also bought washing machines and household goods sales valu...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Each special and general alert is. That my client house No. 99 
 
Each special and general alert is. That my client house No. 99 Street No. 9 skeeter E-11 / 4 National Police Foundation, the size of 35x65 buying needs and housing co-Ali Chau...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Apnacash.com Apnawork.com and Pakistan became the first surprise with an 
 
Apnacash.com Apnawork.com and Pakistan became the first surprise with an automatic guarantee of work at home web site contact 0333-2334950 Earn a $ 106597 ... ... ... ... ...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Dish TV, three months free money only in 6000, CCTV cameras and 
 
Dish TV, three months free money only in 6000, CCTV cameras and UPS are also fitted 0315-5143579/03009143624 CM .27670)...... .... ...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 The only fast food restaurant, institutional sales of machinery and submit a 
 
The only fast food restaurant, institutional sales of machinery and submit a new kitchen design professional staff Learn 0300-9484995 CM. 129676 ... ... ... ... ... ... ... .....
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 F-8 8-c ksytlabynkt Chavez Center in skin contact is available for parties 
 
F-8 8-c ksytlabynkt Chavez Center in skin contact is available for parties and wedding and engagement meeting 0300-8154444 Joseph C. M. Zubair .27420)...... .... ...
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Government and semi Government Sami&apos;a by fiber glass for each type of 
 
Government and semi Government Sami&apos;a by fiber glass for each type of special exception ? fiber and steel work is satisfactory. 0345-5226276/0300-5039412 CM. (27706 .............
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Please visit our car as my car is Honda City model 2011 
 
Please visit our car as my car is Honda City model 2011 pick-and-drop only one kilometer decent women 25 / - Rs contact 0333-3777207 IR)........... ..... ......
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Bakshi&apos;s new almanac was published in 2012 near today Unani, Homoeopathic medical 
 
Bakshi&apos;s new almanac was published in 2012 near today Unani, Homoeopathic medical store if you do not receive, please call the free SMS on this number 0315-9219379 and mnguayy...
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 A. Additional building standards for construction of houses rynuysn map work including 
 
A. Additional building standards for construction of houses rynuysn map work including labor rates and material rates very reasonable price done by an expert engineer supervis...
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Rawalpindi and Islamabad office of two private cars are available for pick-and-drop 
 
Rawalpindi and Islamabad office of two private cars are available for pick-and-drop one of the office ladies and gentlemen will be given priority 0304-5170085 (.27240 M )........
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Murtaza Haider Ali aliphaticality usayauld ID card number in an apartment 42000-9964516-1 
 
Murtaza Haider Ali aliphaticality usayauld ID card number in an apartment 42000-9964516-1 Tadpoles ryzurts Flat No. 104, Plot No. 163 / C, PECHS, Block 3 Karachi identificatio...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Mr. Zeeshan Hussain son of Jalaluddin NIC :4230i.i353613-1 by Mohammad righteous 
 
Mr. Zeeshan Hussain son of Jalaluddin NIC :4230i.i353613-1 by Mohammad righteous son Abdul Sattar NIC :42301-0925076-1 flat 1, person Plaza, First Floor Ratan tlaw street numb...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Mohammad Yousuf Dad Mohammad Qasim sknh L-5, Sector 11-L, North Karachi Quarter 
 
Mohammad Yousuf Dad Mohammad Qasim sknh L-5, Sector 11-L, North Karachi Quarter No. 85 / 1 area 40 yards and the Orangi settlement small field Nazimabad employer Fatima Bai al...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Obaid-ur-Rehman Usmani Usmani inky son Jacob in my name / my own 
 
Obaid-ur-Rehman Usmani Usmani inky son Jacob in my name / my own house, No. R-i.i hears bungalows Scheme No. 33 situated in Gulistan-e-Hijri Karachi am selling a home or insti...
 Carpool - Transport Services - School Vans - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 All allocations and victims Mehran City Phase I, Phase II is to 
 
All allocations and victims Mehran City Phase I, Phase II is to inform that my face pzysn (control) to obtain the documents getting done for the registration list as High Cour...
 Carpool - Transport Services - School Vans - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 Faheem Ahmed and his son continued in his disobedience and wrong punctuation 
 
Faheem Ahmed and his son continued in his disobedience and wrong punctuation because of all moveable property and gyrmnqulh aaq do after today me and my family members have no...
 Carpool - Transport Services - School Vans - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 View our special user Apartment G F C - 2, Block 79, 
 
View our special user Apartment G F C - 2, Block 79, including a motor garage brqbh brqbh 85.1 22.4 square yard square yard, the view Town Ship in DHA Karachi aurtmam payments...
 Carpool - Transport Services - School Vans - Peshawar 
Jan 31 ,
 6 months ago       
 One workshop per day , in the field , Youth Launches Workshop , in the city 
 
&apos;&apos;Training Network for Youth &quot;
Launches
Workshop one day
In
&quot;CV and cover letter to write the Commissioner and payment functions and a better future&quot;
In Peshawar
By Syma...
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 30 ,
 6 months ago       
 A registered company coverage kuafs enhance the food and tea are needed. 
 
A registered company coverage kuafs enhance the food and tea are needed. Contact: I-10 Center, Office No. 1, First Floor, Near PSO pump hmyrplazh, .051-4442959 MM ..........
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 receptionist male mileage for hotels, Pakistani and Continental hook kick, head waiters 
 
receptionist male mileage for hotels, Pakistani and Continental hook kick, head waiters / waiters, House keepers, store keepers, drivers, security guards retired Army needs th...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Experienced house yellow chef (Chef), which forks Continental U.S. and other 
 
Experienced house yellow chef (Chef), which forks Continental U.S. and other foreign countries cooking skills are aged over 40, and at least 15 years experience single housing...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Hira Model School vermicelli Islamabad Highway near Faizabad skyyurty Guard to stop 
 
Hira Model School vermicelli Islamabad Highway near Faizabad skyyurty Guard to stop number 2 will be given accommodation and honest people call mknty 051-2841921,0333-5266483 ...
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 5-year experience with a construction company to park Premavera (P-6) with experience 
 
5-year experience with a construction company to park Premavera (P-6) with experience of building aptryr need to be given priority 0315-5411900 CM sky ).................... .
 Lost And Found - Claim Lost Money - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Former military guard and a security company in urgent need of shelter, 
 
Former military guard and a security company in urgent need of shelter, food and best salary contact puck drop 051-2614462/2106235/0300-5347909 CM sky ).................... .
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 receptionist for the NGO SHARP Islamabad office / clerical needs. Www.sharp-pakistan. 
 
receptionist for the NGO SHARP Islamabad office / clerical needs. Www.sharp-pakistan.org visit our website for details. The deadline for receiving applications is 15 January 2...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 A company of his Islamabad office for sales exit yktyu Required qualifications 
 
A company of his Islamabad office for sales exit yktyu Required qualifications Internet so gryjut computer knowledge need only a computer to know men walk in interview for 9 t...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 PTI is a number that former Army NCO / JCO who retired 
 
PTI is a number that former Army NCO / JCO who retired janitor and former military&apos;m number 2, contact: Amin Higher Secondary School, Fazal Town Link Road, Airport Road, Rawal...
 Volunteers - Community Help - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Senator calls for a multi-mail address and choose who you want to 
 
Senator calls for a multi-mail address and choose who you want to have to sit in your house aurdftr education and work experience, not a prison will be taught. 45 thousand Ear...
 Musicians - Artists - Bands - Actors - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Islamabad multinational company uhzrat women part-time full-time night-time need not be confined 
 
Islamabad multinational company uhzrat women part-time full-time night-time need not be confined to utjrby hrmah education earn 40 thousand jobs will be taught free pick and d...
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 Akau?nts, simultaneously keeping, tax e-filing services for obtaining contact 0321-5888864/051-8435286 CM . 
 
Akau?nts, simultaneously keeping, tax e-filing services for obtaining contact 0321-5888864/051-8435286 CM .25233)..... ............
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 maid home for housework, major, Army retired drivers, (including reasonable accommodation, food, 
 
maid home for housework, major, Army retired drivers, (including reasonable accommodation, food, salary) need to contact 051-8435286 CM .25233)..... ............
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 A multi-national company attractive salary of 13,000 male mileage Staff ntr eye 
 
A multi-national company attractive salary of 13,000 male mileage Staff ntr eye view Monday, Tuesday, 1 AH Office arcade King Fist floor contact phone number 051-2574488 Islam...
 Events - Exhibitions - Parties - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 A monthly magazine for booking a number of television commercials for 9 
 
A monthly magazine for booking a number of television commercials for 9 Inter Inter uyusumuarmurkh mydyt girl at January 9 to 10 at a time contacted CM 2274315 (25126 )..........
 Community Activities - Sport Partner - Peshawar 
Jan 14 ,
 6 months ago       
 
Refine Your Search
 
 
 Pakistan SaintClassified TV 
 
 


 1  2    &gt; 
 Select a Category Business Directory Classes Community For Sale Jobs Naukri Employement Matrimonial Shaadi Rishta Personals Real Estate Property Services Vehicles Search 
 Copyright©2010-2012 SaintClassified, Inc. Sitemap | Terms Of Use | Privacy Policy Like Us and get Updates
	</body>
</document>
