<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007965" url="http://preppingtosurvive.com/2011/08/11/making-the-most-of-resources/" time="2012-07-13-01:01" support="9" score="0.014024972191707296" bingtitle="Making the Most of Resources | PreppingToSurvive.com" webtitle="Making the Most of Resources  |  PreppingToSurvive.com">
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001240" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>... reception. ... my food ... take. She was NOT suffering. She could have cancelled that satellite TV service, sold the TV, quit smoking, gotten a job at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home What Is Prepping? Write A Guest Post Glossary of Terms 
 Subscribe: Posts | Comments PreppingToSurvive.com Preparing to survive the end of the world as we know it 

 
Making the Most of Resources
 
August 11, 2011

 Financial , Getting Started , Prepper Mindset 
 
I had an experience a few days ago that I want to share with you. I think it is probably pretty typical of “American thinking” these days, but I’d like to hear your feedback too.

 

 My Experience 

I was in line at a StuffMart, putting my carefully planned tax-free purchases on the conveyor belt while two 20-ish aged ladies in front of me checked out.

Once everything was rung up, the cashier told them their total and they pulled out a card to swipe through the machine. The card they used was the welfare card our state issues- one I see customers in front of me use more and more.

Once swiped, the sweet grandmotherly cashier politely told them that they only had $7 and change left and it would not cover their purchases. (Note- in most places, benefits are reloaded onto the card on the 1st day of the month and this was the 5th).

The ladies then said, “Well, never mind about the stuff in the bags. We’ll just get these.” They held up 2 large soft drinks.

I imagine that my mouth was hanging open, though I’m not sure. I was stunned.

I know I have to remind myself periodically that I am NOT typical- that denying oneself impulse buys, planning ahead, budgeting, and making long-term goals are no longer the “American way,” but still I couldn’t believe they made the choice they did.

 My Ponderings 

Several things were swirling through my brain at once:

 They have $7 left and they bought sodas?! How did they not have any idea what the balance was? What will they eat for dinner tonight? And tomorrow? And the rest of the month? If meals for the rest of the month aren’t really a concern, why do they qualify for the welfare card? Will a child go hungry now? 

(Let me insert at this point that I do not mean to say that all welfare recipients waste the benefits provided them or that there is never a valid reason to receive them.  They very well may be the difference between eating or not eating for thousands if not millions, especially right now.  I think this issue- questionable use of resources- applies across the board, regardless of income.  I think it is indicative of a bigger cultural problem).

I was so surprised that they bought those drinks that I asked the cashier after they left if the benefits card pays for things like that. She said, “Oh Honey, it will buy nearly any junk food you can think of, but don’t try to buy a bar of soap with it.” What?! What kind of program is this?!

For the past few days, I have been mulling this over in my head. I’m not sure how typical this kind of behavior is in the general population, but I suspect it’s not uncommon. As a whole, we are far removed from the hard-working, pull-yourself-up-by-the-bootstraps mentality that used to characterize Americans.

 The Take-Away 

All this has gotten me to thinking about its relation to preparedness. A few things have come back to me several times.

 Are we using our resources to the best of our abilities? How much do we squander on things of no real or lasting value (like soft drinks)? How often are we checking things off our long-range goals? Are we identifying an important item and actively working towards its acquisition (maybe a water filter or quality pressure canner or root cellar)? Do we just shrug off the hard stuff (like budgeting) for the immediate gratification? If what I witnessed was typical, how quickly will society unravel under the slightest hardship? 

 So, what do you think? 

Related Posts

 Finding Money The Most Likely Scenario Returning To Grandma’s Wisdom Parable Of A Good Man; Do You Know Him? 
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Digg StumbleUpon Email Print 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Financial , Getting Started , Prepper Mindset ← How To Remove A Stuck Wheel The Bandwagon Changes Direction → 
30 Comments on“Making the Most of Resources”

 Jarhead Survivor Says:
 August 11, 2011 at 2:45 pm 
Sickening isn’t it? Here in Maine I read a story awhile back about a woman who needed cigarettes. What she did was buy a bunch of water bottles, then went out in the parking lot and dumped them out until she had enough returnables for a pack of smokes. How’s that for wasteful?

 Reply 
 
 Joe Says:
 August 11, 2011 at 3:38 pm 
Now that’s disgustingly clever in a really bad way. I wonder just where she would be if she’d use that creativity for good.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 August 11, 2011 at 3:43 pm 
Jarhead,

That is amazing. Don’t get me started about spending money on cigarettes instead of food, especially if one gets any handouts from the govt!

Our church has an ongoing ministry to provide food for local children to take home to eat over the weekend (when they aren’t getting free school breakfast and lunch) and I’ve wondered how many of their parents are choosing to spend their money on cigarettes rather than buying their children food. I know that many convenience stores no doubt sell more cigarettes and beer (at premium prices) than bread and milk. It makes me sad.

 Reply 
 
 Jarhead Survivor Says:
 August 11, 2011 at 7:47 pm 
It infuriates me. If you’re out of work and need food for the kids I can see getting some assistance. But you ran out of smokes?? No way!!!

 Reply 
 
 Padre Says:
 August 12, 2011 at 10:31 pm 
With that 7$ my soup kitchen could have fed at least two people a full meal soda included but instead it gets thrown down the tubes–that is the new American story: well meaning but haphazard flailing to help the poor, the oppressed, the downtrodden that ends up hurting us all!

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 August 14, 2011 at 7:57 pm 
Padre,

I’ve thought the same thing- some well-meaning politicians probably long ago haphazardly put the programs together with very little study. I was stunned that our state’s program buys doughnuts and soft drinks but not soap- so it’s set up to perpetuate poor food choices, high blood pressure, obesity, etc., and you can’t get soap to wash your hands before you eat the junk!

Your soup kitchen is a great example of how“independent businesses”are so much better qualified to provide the services our country needs than big inefficient government. Private organizations know how to make a dollar stretch and provide something of worth.

 Reply 
 
 Steph Says:
 November 1, 2011 at 8:57 pm 
It’s lobbyists making sure junk food stays on those program in addition to other government subsidies they receive. All legal bribery. Really upsets me.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 November 1, 2011 at 9:06 pm 
You’re right. And probably the agribusiness companies have deals so they can unload all that high fructose corn syrup they produce with government subsidies!

 Reply 
 
 
 
 Rob Says:
 August 14, 2011 at 9:37 am 
Not all benefits are placed on the card on the first of the month. It depends on day of the month. I am currently on Food Stamps. Ours comes on the 7th of the month. Do we want to be no, but have to be. for my kids. I have been out of a job for 20 months. Unemployment here is 11%. You can buy anything that you can eat, but no booze.

We had someone ask us if he could buy us something at 7 11 and we could give him some cash. Sorry, you are out of luck I told him. We have many folks that beg on the corners of busy streets looking for money. They work in teams, pool their money together to buy beer and some food, and a cheap motel or they sleep outside.

If they would work as hard looking for work or working, They would have more money..

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 August 14, 2011 at 9:06 pm 
Rob,

I so appreciate your input. I’m sure there are a lot of stories like yours out there right now. I could not let my children suffer if I had any choice either.

Your point about cheating the system came up a few weeks ago while we were with a number of friends. In addition to the fraud we’ve seen, several mentioned their experiences trying to help out people they (initially) thought were truly in need. A couple of people (Joe included) had been hit up for money outside restaurants. Joe offered to buy the man anything he wanted for breakfast but the man was insistent that he just needed money so he could pay the fee to get into the homeless shelter that night (which is bogus- there is no charge). When Joe persisted in his offer of breakfast, the man said a few choice words at him and left instead.

It’s a shame that those folks are the visible ones that too many of us have contact with. It makes us prone to cynicism and those who are truly (and inconspicuously) doing their very best are probably overlooked.

Thanks for sharing your experience. I pray blessings on you and your family.

 Reply 
 
 Dan Says:
 August 22, 2011 at 6:32 pm 
I am on food stamps. It breaks my heart to see people buy pop and junk food. Still, there is one more thing. Pre made food. We have three generations of people who only know how to buy and eat frozen pizzas, deserts and the such. They have no idea how to cock or care less. Its all they know. The government and corps encourage this.

I am embarrassed to use food stamps. But, I have no choice. I cant find work. I feed the 5 of us on less than 200 a month. It is hard and nutrition is sketchy at times. There are weeks I dream of fresh fruit or greens. I can tell when we are not getting enough vitamins. We are tired. Unbalanced and unable to think straight. I wonder if that si what they want.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 August 23, 2011 at 7:53 am 
What a good point about the pre-made food, Dan! You are so right that, as a culture, we are more and more reliant on highly processed, nutritionally void“food.”

I am truly perplexed at the guidelines of the food stamp program. I have been stunned at the junk that is able to be purchased, but also stood in line behind someone who tried to buy a healthy rotisserie chicken and heard that was denied. The explanation given by the cashier was that it was ready-made and hot, so it wasn’t allowed. But frozen Frankenfood is alright?

A few days ago, we picked up one of our son’s friends after school. He proceeded to pull out packages of“cheese flavored snacks”and a soda. It made me sad to hear that all he had eaten that day was empty, chemically-laden calories. He’s probably pretty typical.

It’s interesting that you are wondering if“they”might want us to be off-balance from nutritional deficiency. I hadn’t thought about it that way- not only dependent on their political whims, but weakened also. I’ve always wondered why we perpetuate expensive health problems (like obesity, Type II diabetes, etc through the donuts and sodas allowed with food stamps). Maybe it serves a purpose, though- especially for one political party in particular.

Any chance you can put in a fall garden for those greens, maybe in a few pots? Now is actually a perfect time for spinach, broccoli, etc b/c they do much better in cool weather. Seeds may be on clearance now also. I just started seedlings to transfer to our garden once I pull out the dying squash and cucumbers. Every little bit of“real”food helps.

I will keep your family in my prayers. I hope you find work soon. Thanks for your insights.

 Reply 
 
 Jarhead Survivor Says:
 August 23, 2011 at 9:15 am 
I have no problem with someone with a legitimate need using governmen t assistance; however, where I lose patience is when someone abuses this privilige. If you get food stamps (or whatever) use it to feed your family. Some people take advanate of it to buy cigarettes or beer or whatever. How? Read this: http://bangordailynews.com/2010/08/19/news/bangor/bangor-food-stamp-scam-dumps-water-for-deposit/ 

 Reply 
 Rob Says:
 August 23, 2011 at 11:03 am 
The Chicken could not be bought because it was“cooked already”Most foods from the deli can not be bought. Now you can buy everything you need to cook the chicken at home but not cooked already at the store. But if it came from say General Mills already cooked you can buy it, cause it is not hot.

Beer, liquor, and“smokes”can not be bought with FS. Some folks will buy an item for say cash to buy their booze. Some“Retailers”allow customers to buy booze, but end up getting caught and shut down.

 Reply 
 Elly Says:
 September 26, 2011 at 9:41 pm 
This has to be a newer way of thinking. My mother and I were on food stamps and welfare for a while. I remember my mom crying at the register when they said we didn’t have enough to pay for my brother’s formula. I would never be so wasteful.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 September 26, 2011 at 10:52 pm 
That breaks my heart to hear, Elly. It may be a“newer”way of thinking or maybe it has more to do with the character of the person using the benefits. Your mother apparently raised you with a different mentality than many I see. That may also explain why you are thinking in terms of preparing for yourself rather than expecting that it’s someone else’s responsibility.

I’m constantly amazed at what I see people who claim to be cash-strapped spending money on- new apps and ringtones for their cell phones, gourmet drive-thru coffee, etc. These are luxuries,“extras”- not necessities and not“basic human rights.”Until we collectively get our priorities straight (pay rent and buy food before upgrading our electronics and don’t use credit), it’s hard to imagine that we can straighten out the bigger problems.

Thanks for your comment, Elly.

 Reply 
 
 Practical Parsimony Says:
 November 6, 2011 at 1:38 am 
Right now, I am sitting in a cold house so I won’t run up a big bill heating the house. I get food stamps and go to food banks. Yes, I do buy cokes. But, I also buy milk and orange juice, cook from scratch, ALWAYS. I don’t smoke or drink. I never can afford to go to movies. I check out videos from the library and watch them on my laptop that a friend bought and allowed me to pay for it a little each week. I cannot afford to hook my very old tv to anything that will bring viewing into my home. Is a Coke so bad for me to buy? No. Did these women have children? How did they spend all their money so soon? Baffling.

I get very angry when I see people on fs buying the largest pizza in the store, astoundingly expensive cuts of meat, popped popcorn, fruit punch, crackers, chips, cookies, premade jello, premade pudding, and have small children or not. One woman spent $500 on her fs card and the only things she got not prepared/microwavable or the things/junk I just mentioned were a gallon of milk and a roast.

Week before last, I got 50 lbs of free bananas, and this last week, I got 13 free pumpkins that I will cook, freeze, dehydrate for myself. I am not trying to promote my blog, but go there and see how frugal people live on food stamps. I think it is my duty to get the most for my money, so I shop sales and then use coupons, just like it was cash from my pocket instead of on a fs card. So, I am careful so I can afford Cokes.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 November 6, 2011 at 7:48 am 
Thank you so much for your comment! I appreciate your perspective and I will check out your blog. I’m sure I can learn some more cost-saving techniques from you.

I should have mentioned in the original piece that I don’t begrudge anyone their“pick-me-ups”or little luxuries. Everyone needs a break from the norm, especially when that norm is very restrictive. For me, a world without chocolate is a bleak place!

What I suspect I was seeing that day checking out was two women with little financial sense or impulse control, products of a generation brought up to think they“deserve”EVERYthing. The Occupy Wall Street college kids often being shown on the news are good examples. They have every electronic gadget available, designer clothes, and so on, yet they clamor about unfairness.

Some rules shouldn’t ever change- you NEED food, reasonable clothing, and shelter. Pay for those first. Then, if you work hard etc., you may be able to acquire the luxuries of life (like electronics…) but they are NOT your rights. I’m afraid we, as a society, have raised at least one generation who have this all skewed- someone (their parents or the govt…) should provide all their needs free of charge so they can use“their”money for luxuries.

Thanks again for taking the time to comment.

 Reply 
 
 Practical Parsimony Says:
 November 6, 2011 at 10:04 am 
Unfortunately, I see this in older people. The woman with the $500 worth of processed garbage was about my age.

I own a laptop and cell phone, but not the fancy phones, just one that makes calls since I don’t want any of the other options. A grocery checker said, when I complained about garbage-with-food-stamps mentality, that another professional like me used coupons and bought ingredients, not prepared food. The people I see doing this run the gamut from my generation, my children’s generation, to my grandchildren’s generation. Oh, the grandchildren ages are watching the choices and choosing the garbage. Most of this is a generational problem.

I was not being confrontational and reacting about my buying cokes. I was just saying cokes could be part of a well-chosen shopping trip. I was not at all offended and reacting. Yeah, don’t stand between chocolate and me. I have found cheaper ways to get my chocolate fix than in previous years.

While I don’t wear“designer clothes,”I do wear some expensive (by many standards) clothing. I have had it a long time. A new-used-once Coach purse was given to me. Two Winter Silks sweaters were Christmas gifts. One Dell laptop (dead now) was given to me as a Christmas gift from a former bf. Present Dell laptop was charged on friend’s credit card and I paid a bit each week for over two years to cover laptop and interest. A Fossil purse was half gift and half swagbucks acquisition. It was the only style in leather that I would carry. I hate bling on my purse and only buy leather because I can use it for years. A clothes closet yielded a great warm jacket for everyday wear in the yard and a nice black pencil skirt for dressy.

Free food is everywhere. Look at today’s post on my blog.

Since tv is HD, I cannot afford to have television reception.

 Reply 
 
 
 Ginnamom Says:
 November 23, 2011 at 11:49 am 
As a mother or 3 children I am a stay at home mom. My hubby works 40+ hours a week but still with bills and such we don’t quailfy for most things…We have insurance through his job that takes a good chunk of the pay check. We applied for subsidized housing to help pay our 950/month rent, and we pay all utilites including oil heat…Having said this with cost of living going up we finally bit the bullet and applyed for Food stamps…we quaify for 58 dollars a month for a family of 5. On the months that have 5 weeks when my hubby gets 3 pay checks we get 25 dollars a month…We are not even middle class my hubby makes less than 30k a year. Now with 2 teens in the house 25 is barely a meal but I make the most of what I have becuase it does not carry over then I have to use it all. I will often use it to buy Meat or other staples sometimes our local butcher shop offers a meat bundle pack for @ 50 bucks I will buy that. Sometimes if there is really good sales on say canned veggies or rice and such I will buy that…I also make use of other resources I live near amish So I will often barter with them giveing them a ride into town for some milk,or meat or eggs. I make alot from Stratch jams,jellys, butter etc…. Our whole family voulnteers at a local food bank and because we help we get food there too. Now Some would say that I should go get a job that I shouldn’t be a stay at home mom. I used to work but I have 3 special needs kids and the cost of childcare exceeded my pay. So I look for ways to save money we have by gardening,canning,etc etc…Not everyone that needs a little extra help is like the ladies buying soda…Some are but now with everyone struggling I think there are far more people like my family than the women getting soda. Yes I do get soda occasioanlly but it is a luxuary not a need. and I don;t use my food stamps to buy it. Also one thing that I wish food stamps would buy are esentials like soap,Toilet paper,laundry and dish soap, female items,diapers etc…

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 November 23, 2011 at 12:41 pm 
Ginnamom,

Thanks so much for your comment. I’m sure you are correct that there is an ever-growing section of the population that only very reluctantly is receiving food stamp benefits and uses them very wisely. And, as you mentioned, the benefits may be close to nothing because of arbitrary cut-off lines.

I completely understand what you mean about childcare and working. I am a teacher by trade, but when we reached the 2 child mark, my take-home pay all went toward childcare and it seemed unwise to continue, especially with all the extra stresses on us to be out the door at 6:30 am etc. If my children had special needs, I would make the same choice you have.

I hope what I witnessed was an anomaly, but from what I hear from others, it probably isn’t. I think, as a culture, our ideas of“needs vs wants”is skewed. There was an article in our local paper that absolutely nauseated me. It showed an overweight woman standing in front of her huge flat screen TV smoking in a room well decorated with nice furniture and the title said something about the Baby Boomers scraping the bottom of the pantry shelves. It proceeded to tell a (sob?) story about how this lady with one 16 yr old daughter and a husband who was working could hardly feed her family. She said she couldn’t find a job and on and on, though the classified ads had plenty listed- but probably none she would be willing to take.

She was NOT suffering. She could have cancelled that satellite TV service, sold the TV, quit smoking, gotten a job at a fast food restaurant- any number of things. She didn’t have childcare to pay for or young children who would be home alone after school. As a friend of mine put it,“I wish I could be that poor and get a big flat screen.”

Yes, absolutely there are many families truly struggling and my heart goes out to them. I know that a continued downward spiral in the economy (that I expect) could see nearly every one of us in the same situation and I prep in part to protect against that. But it is ridiculous stories like the one in our paper that remind me that some people just make poor or selfish choices that all taxpayers fund. If that lady is sitting around watching TV all day and not feeding her daughter because she won’t cancel her $60/month satellite, she is a mighty poor parent with her priorities way out of line.

I pray blessings on you and your family and hope that things get easier soon. It sounds like you are doing every thing you can and making the most of the resources you have available. It’s great that you are giving back by helping out at the food bank- most people would never think of that. Thanks so much for your perspective.

You’ve given me an idea too- maybe I should do an occasional posting of recipes that feed a lot of people thriftily. I always think in terms of large meals because of how many I feed at each meal, but I like to have leftovers too (that feels like free food!). We eat a lot of rice and beans along with our meats and such. I’ll ponder on that. Maybe you could share some of your favorites too. I’d appreciate your perspective.

 Reply 
 
 Rita Says:
 March 18, 2012 at 3:46 pm 
My parents died when I was a kid&amp;I was then raised by retired grandparents, living on SS&amp;for a while, we could not get SS benefits. In those days, there was something called commodities, foods that were packaged by the government. We would get more than 100# of flour a month, plus beans, peanut butter, cheese (American cheese like), butter, peanuts, oatmeal, cornmeal, powdered milk, lard, canned meat (usually pork), coconut, rice, and occasionally a few other things. We always had homemade bread, always. The canned meat was not so good, the peanut butter was horrible. We had a huge garden and canned many vegetables and fruits to get us through the winter. We raised chickens and always had fresh eggs and chicken to eat.
Food stamps is made too easy for people to use and we have raised a generation (or 2) of people who have no idea about the importance of good nutrition and good food.
Soft drinks and fast food is on my never do list. I cook and eat at home, and eat very well. But that is how I was raised.

 Reply 
 
 Laura Says:
 March 18, 2012 at 9:08 pm 
Thanks for your input, Rita.

I think you are very right about things coming too easily nowadays. And I think it has to do with a generational difference, as you mentioned. I keep reading about parents of adult children who should be enjoying the fruits of their own labors by now, instead being constantly barraged by requests for money by their 30-something offspring who could make a sacrifice or two instead. I can’t imagine trying to guilt my parents into paying my bills for me while I indulge in eating out, satellite TV, cigarettes and alcohol, etc. To some degree, the senior parents must have had a hand in raising children that turned into those kind of irresponsible adults, but parents never want to see their children in need. That would be hard.

Joe’s great-grandmother lived on shockingly little and qualified for the commodity foods you mentioned. Even then, she put aside 10% of her tiny monthly income for“the needy.”What a difference between her and many of the selfish people I see now who feel entitled to their every desire!

 Reply 
 
 loji Says:
 July 6, 2012 at 12:12 pm 
give them food not food stamps. greens and bean would go a long way towards cutting down on waste and cutting down on waists.

 Reply 
 
 
Trackbacks/Pingbacks

 Prepping On A Shoestring Budget | PreppingToSurvive.com - August 17, 2011 
[...] Making The Most Of Resources [...]
 Backyard Chickens, Part 14 (or Why are my chickens bald and not laying?) | PreppingToSurvive.com - September 19, 2011 
[...] Making The Most of Resources LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;AdOpt&quot;,&quot;0&quot;); LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;Origin&quot;,&quot;other&quot;); LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;LangId&quot;,&quot;1&quot;); LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;Autotag&quot;,&quot;food&quot;); LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;Tag&quot;,&quot;raising-chickens&quot;); LD_AddCustomAttr(&quot;Tag&quot;,&quot;raising-chickens&quot;); LD_AddSlot(&quot;wpcom_below_post&quot;); LD_GetBids(); Share this:TwitterFacebookDiggStumbleUponEmailPrintLike this:LikeBe the first to like this post. Raising Chickens←Joe’s Prepping Diary: 09/18/2011 [...]
 Alternatives to Kitchen“Throw-Aways”| PreppingToSurvive.com - October 29, 2011 
[...] Making The Most Of Resources [...]
 New Uses for Newspaper | PreppingToSurvive.com - November 3, 2011 
[...] Making the Most of Resources [...]
 A Rise in Arrests of Young People | PreppingToSurvive.com - December 24, 2011 
[...] Making the Most of Resources GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;AdOpt&quot;,&quot;1&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Origin&quot;,&quot;other&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;LangId&quot;,&quot;1&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Autotag&quot;,&quot;education&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Autotag&quot;,&quot;religion&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Autotag&quot;,&quot;science&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Tag&quot;,&quot;current-events&quot;); GA_googleAddAttr(&quot;Tag&quot;,&quot;current-events&quot;); GA_googleFillSlot(&quot;wpcom_sharethrough&quot;); Share this:TwitterFacebookDiggStumbleUponEmailPrintLike this:LikeBe the first to like this post. Current Events←Gift Idea: Meal in a Jar Quote of the Week: Paul on Transformation→[...]
 Saving Money by Challenging the Status Quo | PreppingToSurvive.com - June 19, 2012 
[...] Making the Most of Resources [...]
 
 
Leave a Comment Click here to cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Popular Latest Comments Tags 
 
 You Might Be a Prepper If… January 2, 2012 A Different Kind of Food-in-a-Bucket Plan March 22, 2012 Pre And Post TEOTWAWKI Handgun Decisions May 6, 2011 Making the Most of Resources August 11, 2011 Three Weapons Every Prepper Needs April 7, 2011 

 When the SHTF – Gardening Afloat, part 3 July 11, 2012 When the SHTF – Gardening Afloat, part 2 July 10, 2012 When the SHTF – Gardening Afloat, part 1 July 9, 2012 Quote of the Week: Franklin on Liberty July 7, 2012 Should Genetically Engineered Crops be Labelled? July 5, 2012 

 Mitchell: A good alternative for veggies may be to store som... Warren: Excellent post. But it raises more than a few ques... themostsecretestprepper@gmail.com: How many much more prepared do you think America i... Jimmy Cracked-Corn: This is going to be a bit more difficult if you&apos;re... When the SHTF – Gardening Afloat, part 3 | PreppingToSurvive.com: [...] Interesting Facts About Our Food Supply Sha... 
 Barter Book Reviews Bugging Out Children Communications Current Events Emergency Response EMP Faith Family Financial Fire First Aid Food Preparation Food Storage Frontier Medicine Getting Started Growing Your Own Food Guest Post Health Hunting Weapons Knives Knots Morale Boosters Navigation Nutrition Prepper Mindset Prepping Diary Product Reviews Quote of the Week Rabbits Raising Chickens Recommended Purchases Reviews Root Cellar Security Self Defense Self Sufficiency Skills Survival Kits Survival Myths Video Water Wild Edibles Wilderness Survival 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 2,080 other followers

 

 
 
Subscribe
 
Subscribe to our RSS feed and social profiles to receive updates.
 
Pages

 Glossary of Terms What Is Prepping? Write A Guest Post 
 
Categories

 Barter (4) Book Reviews (21) Bugging Out (6) Building Community (2) Children (21) Clothing (3) Communications (5) Current Events (34) Ducks (1) Emergency Response (22) EMP (6) Faith (7) Family (12) Financial (12) Fire (6) First Aid (13) Food Preparation (21) Food Storage (28) Frontier Medicine (20) Geese (2) Getting Started (18) Growing Your Own Food (16) Guest Post (20) Ham Radio (5) Health (11) Hunting Weapons (9) Knives (6) Knots (7) Light (1) Morale Boosters (5) Navigation (6) Nuclear Disaster (4) Nutrition (21) Pets (1) Prep Question (1) Prepper Mindset (34) Prepping Diary (25) Preserving Food (2) Product Reviews (5) Quote of the Week (52) Rabbits (6) Raising Chickens (24) Recommended Purchases (15) Reviews (5) Root Cellar (5) Security (22) Self Defense (10) Self Sufficiency (28) Skills (13) Soap Making (3) Survival Kits (15) Survival Myths (5) Training (3) Uncategorized (1) Video (6) Water (5) Wild Edibles (12) Wilderness Survival (25) 
 
Blogroll

 ApartmentPrepper.com BackDoorSurvival.com BearRidgeTradingPost.com BulletsBeansAndBullion.blogspot.com DestinySurvival.com EndOfEmpireNews.blogspot.com FoodStorageAndSurvival.com IfItHitsTheFan.com KnightsAndDreams.com LewRockwell.com NorthernHomesteader.WordPress.com OutdoorsNative.com PoormansPrepper.com Prep-Blog.com PreparednessAdvice.com PrepperWebSite.com PrepPlace.blogspot.com reThinkSurvival.com SHTFBlog.com SHTFPlan.com StealthSurvival.blogspot.com SuburbanSurvivalBlog.com SuburbanSurvivalist.wordpress.com Survival-Spot.com SurvivalBlog.com SurvivalCache.com SurvivalGearGuru.com SurvivalMedicineBlogDotCom.wordpress.com SurvivalTipsAndTricks.com TacticalIntelligence.net Teotwawki.ws ThePreparationStation.com TheSurvivalistBlog.net TheSurvivalMom.com TNGun.com TroublesomeTimesAreHere.blogspot.com UrbanSurvivalSite.com 
 PreppingToSurvive.com Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Fresh News by WooThemes . Follow 
 Follow“PreppingToSurvive.com” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 2,080 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
