<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007063" url="http://gluten.lovetoknow.com/Gluten_Free_Fast_Food" time="2012-07-13-00:03" support="1" score="0.0005321951565769982" bingtitle="Gluten-Free Fast Food - LoveToKnow: Answers for Women on Family ..." webtitle="Gluten-Free Fast Food">
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Something as simple as going out to eat at a fast food restaurant ... Order your burger &quot;protein style&quot; at In-N-Out which ... Blizzards made with Reese&apos;s peanut butter cups ...</description>
	<body>
		Gluten Free 
 LoveToKnow » Health&amp;Fitness » Gluten Free » Gluten-Free Foods » Gluten-Free Fast Food 
 
Gluten-Free Fast Food
 By Chris Dinesen Rogers 
Among the many challenges that people with celiac disease must cope is finding gluten-free fast food when you want a quick bite. Unfortunately, not all fast food chains have been quick to reach out to those with gluten allergies. Yet, options are available and growing each day.

The Importance of Gluten Free

It soon becomes apparent to the parent of a child diagnosed with celiac disease that the condition has a psychological component as well as the physical one. It can be difficult for a child unable to snack and eat like other children.

They feel different and are embarrassed. That is why it is so important to find ways to bring normalcy to their lives to conquer feelings of low esteem they may feel. Something as simple as going out to eat at a fast food restaurant can have a huge impact.

Challenges When Eating Out

Perhaps part of the reason gluten-free fast food has been hard to find is the added expense to restaurants. Not only must products be researched and found gluten-free, but the staff has to be trained in proper food handling. This is an important factor for a restaurant that plans to serve gluten-free foods . If the staff reuses utensils they used on products containing gluten or not using separate fryers for gluten free foods, the purpose is defeated.

As you research gluten-free fast food, review the fast food company&apos;s website for information regarding their commitment to serving these products. A quick read will tell you how seriously they take this issue and how sensitive they are to the needs of those with gluten allergies.

Gluten Free Fast Food

Celiac disease patients soon learn the necessary tricks to find gluten free options. Hamburgers or other sandwiches without buns offer safe alternatives. Arby&apos;s roast beef is gluten free and makes an easy fast food option. Order your burger &quot;protein style&quot; at In-N-Out which will deliver your burger wrapped in lettuce rather than a bun.

Of the fast food restaurants, Wendy&apos;s is among the most gluten-free friendly. Wendy&apos;s website provides a detailed list of gluten-free ingredients available on their menu. The list even goes so far as to point out differences that may exist between stores. Subway and Sonic provide similar lists. In order to always be prepared, print out these lists and keep them in your car&apos;s glove compartment. It is also important to update your copies frequently in case there are changes to the menu.

For a more filling meal, Boston Market has several gluten free offerings, including their rotisserie chicken and roasted turkey breast. Their website provides detailed information about its products including whether they contain soy , eggs, and shellfish in addition to gluten. The site does have a disclaimer that it cannot guarantee no cross-contamination.

Other fast food salad options are available. Chipotle Mexican Grill&apos;s burrito bowls are gluten free as are the chargrilled chicken garden salads available at Chick-fil-A 

Restaurants That Do Not Serve Gluten Free Products

Other restaurants unfortunately, are not so gluten-free friendly. Diners will find few good choices at Taco Bell, Kentucky Fried Chicken, and Jack-in-the-Box. Shared fryers contaminate products with gluten. Even products you may think are gluten-free such as salads may not be so if croutons are served on the salad or if dressings contain gluten.

Gluten Free Treats

When it is time for a treat, Dairy Queen offers several gluten-free products including soft serve ice cream, Blizzards made with Reese&apos;s peanut butter cups, Snickers, Heath, or Butterfingers. Several sundae toppings are gluten free, including chocolate, butterscotch, marshmallow, strawberry, and caramel. Likewise, you can still enjoy a chocolate Frosty or Strawberry Frosty Shake at Wendy&apos;s.

When you go out to eat at a fast food restaurant, take time to ask the manager about food preparation techniques even if items are listed as gluten free. Most people will be more than willing to change gloves or use a clean utensil if you ask. Just because you or a loved one has a wheat allergy or intolerance doesn&apos;t mean you cannot enjoy a juicy burger once in awhile.
 
Related Topics
 Gluten-Free Oatmeal Cookies Gluten-Free Brown Rice Cooking Directions 
 Gluten-Free Fast Food Restaurants List of Gluten-Free Fast Food Gluten-Free Restaurants Gluten-Free in San Antonio Eating Out Gluten-Free 

 Does Subway Have a Gluten-Free Menu? Restaurants Serving Gluten-Free Food Complete List of Gluten-Free Foods Gluten-Free Foods Health&amp;Fitness 
 Browse Gluten Categories 
 About Gluten Celiac Disease Gluten Sensitivity Gluten Slideshows Gluten-Free Breads 

 Gluten-Free Foods Gluten-Free Interviews Gluten-Free Recipes 
 Gluten Slideshows Gluten-Free Kids Lunch and Snack Ideas Gluten-Free Pumpkin Bread LoveToKnow Expert Interview Doc Popcorn Interview with Rob and Renee Israel 
Rob and Renee Isreal, founders of Doc Popcorn, share the inside scoop on this tasty gluten-free snack.
 New in Gluten 
 Gluten-Free Chickpea Flour How to Make Brown Rice Flour Is Spelt Flour Gluten-Free? Gluten Free Chocolate Cherry Bars Recipe Best Wheat Free Pumpkin Pie 
 Follow Us 
 Home Beauty&amp;Style Entertainment&amp;Hobbies Health&amp;Fitness Home, Garden&amp;Events Internet&amp;Technology Money&amp;Business Parenting&amp;Lifestyle Travel&amp;Vacations 
 Help About LoveToKnow Gluten Free Careers Privacy Policy Editorial Policy Terms of Service ©2006-2012 LoveToKnow Corp.
	</body>
</document>
