<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007497" url="http://www.fourwinds10.net/siterun_data/health/crime_hate_crimes/news.php?q=1321460133" time="2012-07-13-00:28" support="1" score="0.0015219338195121726" bingtitle="22 Signs That The Thin Veneer Of Civilization That We All Take For ..." webtitle="22 Signs That The Thin Veneer Of Civilization That We All Take For Granted Is Starting To Disappear &gt;&gt; Four Winds 10 - Truth Winds">
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>That’s when the cashier can be seen on the video disappearing into the back of the fast-food restaurant. ... those reporting their Social Security numbers ...</description>
	<body>
		Four Winds 10 - News 
 
22 Signs That The Thin Veneer Of Civilization That We All Take For Granted Is Starting To Disappear
 
 Home 
 About Four Winds Our Mission 
 Phoenix Archives 
 Phoenix Journals Unpublished Journals The Spectrum Newspapers The Law of the Creation and the Laws of God THE LAWS OF GOD AND THE CREATION by Patrick H. Bellringer 
 Bellringer&apos;s Corner 
 Hello Central People of the Lie Vital Articles Writings Meditation Poetry Songs Prayers Anne Bellringer 
 Nesara 
 News/Casper Updates History 
 Government 
 Banking Homeland Security Fraud 9/11 U.S. Gov. Israel NWO U.S. Constitution War Judicial Corporate US Obama Gov. Law Enforcement Immigration 
 History 
 Zionism American European World Middle East Africa Asia Cosmic 
 Health 
 Aleternative Medicine Harmful Products Disease Vaccinations Food Drugs Crime Morality Racism Prisons Abuse Fraud Mind Control Safety More» 
 Spiritual 
 Inspirational Hatonn Sananda Germain General Channelings Earth/Transition Prayer Thoughts 
 Environment 
 Humans Chemtrails Nuclear Pollution Plants/Animals Earth Changes Weather/Climate Disaster Relief Agriculture 
 Business 
 Economy Currency Corp. Fraud Corp. Growth 
 Science 
 Energy/Free Energy DNA/GMO Computers New Technologies/Inventions Cloning 
 More 
 Business Education Entertainment Environment Media Peace Freedom Projects Religion Cults Science Technology Space Spectrum Spiritual Valley Of Radiance 
 
 Custom Search 
22 Signs That The Thin Veneer Of Civilization That We All Take For Granted Is Starting To Disappear
 
More Recent Stories

 A PRAYER FOR AMERICA SOLTEC: WHAT IS YOUR ROLE IN MOTHER EARTH&apos;S RETURN TO BALALNCE?/(with Italian Translation) CASPER OPINION: JULY 11, 2012 WHITE HATS REPORT #44 - JULY 10, 2012 ~ALTERNATIVE HEALTH CARE~ THE ART WORK OF MOTHER EARTH ~WHAT THE FRACK? URGENT: THE UNITED STATES REVERSES POLICY TO REGULATE ARMS HOUSE VOTES TO REPEAL OBAMACARE &apos;PHOENIX OPERATOR-OWNER MANUAL&apos; - PHOENIX JOURNAL #27 - RECOGNIZING AND DEFINING THE MOST &apos;DEADLY&apos; SINS OF HU-MAN 7. SLOTH HATONN: OUR PLEIADES ROOTS AND ROLE OF WISDOM BOB WARD - INTERNATIONAL HEALER OUR MONEY IS DYING HILARION: LETTING GROW BY LETTING GO OBAMA SEIZES CONTROL OF ALL COMMUNICATIONS SYSTEMS WITH EXECUTIVE ORDER [!]- AMERICA THE BEAUTIFUL: A FIRE SALE FOR FOREIGN CORPORATIONS Government Will Soon Be Able to Know Your Adrenaline Level, What You Ate Breakfast and What Youre Thinking from 164 Feet 14 Incredibly Creepy Surveillance Technologies That Big Brother Will Be Using To Spy On You &apos;Super Event&apos; Warned Near As Weather Chaos Pounds Planet The Corn Is Dying All Over America 
 
Most Emailed
 
 ILLULMINATI CABAL FLEE BY THE HUNDREDS AS MASS ARESTS AWAIT THEM FROM STATES BECOMING FREE FROM THE FED.... ANOTHER HIDDEN SECRET IN OBAMACARE &apos;RFID CHIP IMPLANTS&apos; CONFESSIONS OF A FORMER WHITE HAT OPERATIVE - THE SAGA OF NESARA - with Comment by PHB Can a Land Patent SAVE YOUR HOME? - Even if you are NOT in foreclosure? THE PLANNED RE-ELECTION OF OBAMA, REVOLUTIONARY STYLE -- [READ!]
	</body>
</document>
