<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007043" url="http://dinehere.ca/surrey/gulberg-tandoor-donair" time="2012-07-13-00:02" support="6" score="0.010340891314522673" bingtitle="Gulberg Tandoor &amp; Donair | Surrey - Dine Here | Restaurant guide ..." webtitle="Gulberg Tandoor&amp;Donair | Surrey">
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>Excellent Pakistani fast food restaurant with Greek Food. ... An order of naan was the size of a pizza! Of ... They have a variety of items on the menu board, including ...</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt;&gt; Metro Vancouver Login or Register 
 Metro Vancouver Bowen Island Burnaby Coquitlam Delta Langley Maple Ridge New Westminster North Vancouver 

 Pitt Meadows Port Coquitlam Port Moody Richmond Surrey Vancouver West Vancouver White Rock 

 Abbotsford Brampton Burlington Calgary Chilliwack Duncan Edmonton Halifax Hamilton Kamloops Kelowna Kitchener Ladysmith 

 London Mission Mississauga Montreal Nanaimo Niagara Falls Oakville Oshawa Ottawa Parksville Saskatoon Scarborough Squamish 

 St. Catharines Tofino Toronto Vaughan Waterloo Welland Whistler Whitby Windsor 

 Greater Victoria Sidney Sooke Victoria 
 Do a search below using the city or postal code search box if your city is not listed above. 
 
 Follow us on Facebook and Twitter 

 Get dining news including restaurant closures and qualify for giveaways.
 Search: Location: Locations Locations: 
 Vancouver Burnaby Coquitlam Maple Ridge White Rock Pitt Meadows Richmond North Vancouver New Westminster West Vancouver Port Moody Bowen Island Surrey Langley Delta Port Coquitlam     
 Tip: To view neighbourhoods, click on a city above or change the default location to a specific city (top left of website). Cuisines Cuisines: 
 Afghan Cambodian European International Pakistani Soup African Canadian Family Irish Pasta Southern American Caribbean Fast food Israeli Persian Southwestern Asian Chicken Filipino Italian Peruvian Spanish Australian Chilean Fish&amp;chips Izakaya Pho Steaks Austrian Chinese French Jamaican Pita Sushi Bagels Coffee Fusion Japanese Pizza Swiss Bakery Contemporary Game Juice Polish Szechuan Bar Continental Gelato Korean Portuguese Taiwanese Barbeque Creole German Kosher Poutine Tapas Belgian Crepes Greek Latin American Pub Tea house Bistro Cuban Halal Lebanese Ramen Tex-Mex Brazilian Deli Hawaiian Malaysian Regional Thai Brewery Dessert Healthy Mediterranean Romanian Tibetan British Dim sum Hot dogs Mexican Russian Tunisian Bubble tea Diner Hot pot Middle Eastern Salad Turkish Burgers Doughnuts Hungarian Mongolian Sandwiches Ukrainian Cafe Dutch Ice cream Moroccan Seafood Vegetarian Cafeteria Eastern European Indian Organic Shanghainese Vietnamese Cajun Eclectic Indigenous Pacific northwest Singaporean Wine bar California Ethiopian Indonesian Pacific rim     
 Options Price: $ ($15 or less) $$ ($15 - $30) $$$ ($30 - $45) $$$$ ($45 or more) Features: 
 Ocean Wise View Dinner Banquet Wheelchair accessible Patio Lunch Delivery Live entertainment All day breakfast Breakfast Takeout Romantic Catering Weekend brunch Cheap eats Television Late night Buffet Fine dining 
 Sort: A-Z Popularity Rating - Food - Service - Value - Ambiance Z-A # Reviews Created Updated Min: 0 Reviews 1 Reviews 2 Reviews 3 Reviews 5 Reviews 10 Reviews 15 Reviews 20 Reviews 25 Reviews Results: 10 20 50 Offer: None Deals -- Group buys -- Coupons Order online Reserve online Gift cards Status: Open Opening soon Renovation Closed Fast food 
 Coupon Enjoy one complimentary menu item when a second menu item of equal or greater value is purchased Ends: Dec 31, 2012 
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance Reviews 4 
   Add to favourites Add to try 
 Surrey › Greek Surrey › Halal Surrey › Indian Surrey › Pakistani 

Gulberg Tandoor&amp;Donair
 7181 126 Street, #119 
 Surrey , BC V3W2M6 Tel: (604) 543-2080 

 Cuisine: Greek , Halal , Indian , Pakistani Price: $ ($15 or less) 
Excellent Pakistani fast food restaurant with Greek Food.
 

 Web site Inspection reports 
 
 Submit review Upload image Edit restaurant 
 
 Reviews 
 
Reviews
 Displaying 1 - 4 of 4 Reviews Found Sort: Useful | Helpful | Reviews | Date excellent value By robatsea of Maple Ridge (5 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, August 20, 2009 - 11:28pm [Dine in] 
While visiting Surrey I was prompted to visit Gulberg Tandoor&amp;Donair after reading reviews on this website. I was not disappointed. The interior is cafeteria in nature, though there is seating upstairs reserved for parties and that area may have more elaborate decor. Everything on the menu is very reasonably priced, and portions are enormous. I visited three times in two weeks for take-out service, and each meal allowed plenty for two dinners. An order of naan was the size of a pizza! Of the food I tried I found the Chana Curry - ordered with rice - to be one of the best I&apos;ve had - delicious in texture and just the right amount of spice.

They have a variety of items on the menu board, including several variations of Donair (I saw one being prepared, and it looked huge!), some burgers and other Greek items but the main attraction are the South Asian dishes - Tandoori Chicken, Chicken Tikka, Karachi Chicken, Malai Tikka, the curries and so on. It all looked fabulous and I frankly wish I had more time to visit and sample other menu items. Evidently they have a weekend breakfast buffet of Pakistani dishes for $7.50, and I&apos;m sorry that I missed out on that too. There was a steady stream of customers, and the kitchen / counter staff were being kept plenty busy. The next time I&apos;m in the area I&apos;ll definitely be stopping by again.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 3 / 4 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 best donairs&amp;indian food that is cheap yet tasty By sadeater of Sadville (13 Reviews) Submitted Wednesday, September 9, 2009 - 10:32pm [Dine in] 
I am now a happy eater as I&apos;ve been feasting on Gulberg&apos;s offerings. The hunt for a good donair is now over. They stuff the donairs here with meat doused generously in sauce and lettuce. The pita is sturdy enough to hold it all together. Don&apos;t shy away from their chili sauce, it&apos;s bright red but tastes more of tomato and has an addictive sweet undertone, it&apos;s like a spicier ketchup without being hot. Their biryani&apos;s are flavourful and full of the sticks and twigs that are the hallmark of true indian food made with spices that aren&apos;t all ground up. The biryani chicken consists of 2 plump, meaty chicken legs and it&apos;s more like a leg and a half as they cut the chicken leg farther up the joint. All of their menu items are cheap, with generous portions and it tastes good to boot. The restaurant itself is welcoming with a decent decor. Run, don&apos;t walk to this place. The best value Indian food and donairs in BC. You&apos;ll be able to feed your family and have change left over.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 1 / 3 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
&lt; More reviews below advertisement &gt;
 Authentic Pakistani Style Food for Dirt Cheap! By solidape of Vancouver (6 Reviews) Submitted Saturday, April 25, 2009 - 3:14pm [Dine in] 
I live in North Vancouver, but have made many weekend road trips to Surrey just to go eat there. What they serve there is pretty authentic Pakistani style food (yes I know), not Indian. There are some slight differences between Pakistani and Indian (then there are lots of regional differences within Pakistani and Indian but thats another story).

Anyway, the food: They have Nihari (spicy beef curry?)for $5.99 for a decent size serving, along with a $1.50 (i think) naan and you will be full and it will be very tasty. They have chicken Biryani (rice dish) for $5.50 and its a giant serving, you can feed almost 2 people with it or one hungry teenager.

One particular thing from Pakistan that is very hard to find here is something called Chicken TIkka. This is not the chicken tikka you get at Indian restaurants, its Karachi style chicken Tikka and it is very tasty. I think the boneless chicken tikka with rice or naan is only $5.99 while the leg quarter chicken tikka with salad is $3.99.

The ambiance is so so, it looks like a cafeteria, you order your food upfront and pay, then you sit and they yell out your order and you pick it up. Its clean but not the cleanest. Don&apos;t go there for a hot date, but do go there for a hot meal. I just wish they didnt microwave the nihari.

Lots of south Asian customers are there, which you will see if you go there. They also have some donair dishes but I have never tried them so I cannot comment on them. They have other Pakistani dishes there too but I have not tried them all.

If you want hot spicy Pakistani food that is pretty damn good and pretty damn cheap I highly recommend this place.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 3 / 5 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Best Nihari in town By rozinar of burnaby (2 Reviews) Submitted Monday, June 30, 2008 - 1:58pm [Dine in] 
Wow..the nihari was the real deal. First time since I have moved to
Vancouver, I tasted pakistani food that felt like home. The naan is the best you will find. Service was great. Nice homey place. Limited menu though. We had nihari, bihari kebab&amp;chai. Bihari kebab was ok. We can&apos;t wait to go back and try the other items on the menu but will definitely order nihari.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 4 / 6 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
   Map and directions 
 Vancouver Entertainment Book 
 Up to $26 off when you buy the new 2012 Vancouver Entertainment Book. Free Shipping. 
Nearby Restaurants
 
 1. Great Pizza Co. (57 m) 2. Urban Masala Grill&amp;Restaurant (59 m) 3. Grassroots (119 m) 4. Tim Hortons (143 m) 5. Prabu Sweets (424 m) 6. Prime Hut Pizza (429 m) 7. Lovely Sweet Shop Restaurant (429 m) 8. Punjab Sweet House (440 m) 9. Sohi&apos;s Incredible Indian Cuisine (440 m) 10. Bombay Palki (440 m) 
   
 Restaurants Opening Soon New Restaurants Updated Restaurants 

 Support Review Guide FAQ News 

 Socialize Facebook Twitter Google + 

 Corporate Contact Advertise 
 Copyright©2004-2011
	</body>
</document>
