<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007817" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/fuller-dog-park-denver" time="2012-07-13-00:46" support="2" score="0.0028862965663322667" bingtitle="Fuller Dog Park - Northeast - Denver, CO" webtitle="Fuller Dog Park - Northeast - Denver, CO">
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>As a rule of thumb I keep one eye on my dog and one eye on my car ... Would it kill Denver parks n rec to put in a few picnic tables? Word of advice...don&apos;t wear flip-flops.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Fuller Dog Park
 24 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Active Life Parks Dog Parks Dog Parks   [Edit] 
 Denver , CO 80205 
 http://www.dogparkusa.com/colorado… 
 
 Add Photos Good for Kids: No
 First to Review MAt L. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
24 reviews for Fuller Dog Park
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
24 reviews in English

 
Review from Michael S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 9 friends 38 reviews 

 Michael S. 
 
Denver, CO
 1/21/2012 
I was there this morning...my dogs had a blast, lots of different dogs were in and out...they had a great time running around as per usual. The general area of the park isn&apos;t the nicest ever, but it&apos;s nothing even CLOSE to sketch. Sounds like some people are too sensitive...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Catherine C. 
 
 0 friends 2 reviews 

 Catherine C. 
 
Denver, CO
 12/1/2011 
Fuller is NOT a ghetto dog park! It is a small-space dog park that has just been renovated, It now has benches for sitting, new clay-mix that won&apos;t turn to mud when wet and beautiful berms your dogs can run over and around.

It also has a new small/puppy/old dog area so special dogs can socialize in a safer environment than with ALL the dogs at the park.

This summer a water jug spigot will be added to the drinking fountain located in the playground nearby and shade structures will be installed. AND new trees are being planted around the park.

This dog park is a little gem in the middle of a great neighborhood with houses over 100 years old filled with friendly neighbors.

Bring you doggy out to play!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (3) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from misha P. 
 
 18 friends 34 reviews 

 misha P. 
 
Denver, CO
 4/21/2008 
Not at all good for little dogs!
Hey all you cell phone users with your coffee and head up your asses....why don&apos;t you pay attention to what your dog is doing!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (13) Funny (9) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from mark k. 
 
 15 friends 46 reviews 

 mark k. 
 
Denver, CO
 11/10/2007 
I&apos;ve gone to Fuller dog park with Barney a few times and overall it&apos;s ok but there have been a couple of times where some pretty aggressive dogs have been there.  Those are always the ones with the most oblivious owners.  I think people who go to these places need to understand that they still need to supervise.  I also think cell phones should not be allowed.
Poor barney drags his ears in the mud at Fuller and comes home filthy!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (10) Funny (1) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Elizabeth K. 
 
 76 friends 23 reviews 

 Elizabeth K. 
 
Basalt, CO
 9/22/2007 
I am a sucker of convenience.  I go to the Fuller Dog Park periodically because of it&apos;s location, location, location.  Located in five points, this park has an interesting dynamic.  The class differential is always apparent with the more affluent dog owners caged in the interior while the five point crowd plays hoops and scrambles around in the playground on the exterior.  As a rule of thumb I keep one eye on my dog and one eye on my car.  Occasionally a motherless child will wander in the park to check out the dogs with dreams of becoming a veterinarian.  I always enjoy a child&apos;s enthusiasm for a furry friend.

Pretty close to a fenced in dirt parking lot, Fuller is one of the closest off least dog parks to Downtown Denver.  I have found this dog park crowd to be much more engaging than the Boulder dog park variety.  I enjoy friendly conversations and the occasional recognition.  I always catch the dog&apos;s name and somehow space the human&apos;s.  The dogs tend to be friendly here as well with only the random skirmish, usually with the un-cut canine.  There are usually a few valiant men on hand to break up any fight and I have never seen permanent damage.

Tips on the park and for the park::

It needs more shade and water for the dogs.  It gets so hot out that the dogs won&apos;t play and just sloth around near their owners legs.

A bench or two for the owners to sit on would be delightful.

P and R took away the free poop bags which encourages the failing hygiene of the park.  Stick to the middle.  Dogs like to poop in the few weeds that line the fence.  Also, remember to bring bags with you and left over plastic grocery bags if you can spare.

I have no suggestions about the dust and mud problem.  These are seasonal conditions that can&apos;t be solved without AstroTurf.  There is obviously little funding for improvements.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (1) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Chirag C. 
 
 15 friends 56 reviews 

 Chirag C. 
 
Philadelphia, PA
 5/4/2011 
Meh...on one hand, I&apos;m glad this exists. To my knowledge, this is one of the very few dog parks in a city full of dogs, so its a much needed asset.

On the other hand, the location is a bit &quot;off the beaten path&quot; and the facilities are non-existent.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Cynthia G. 
 
 18 friends 17 reviews 

 Cynthia G. 
 
Denver, CO
 12/7/2008 3 photos 
The only reason I went a second time to this dog park is because it&apos;s the closest park to my house.

Although my first experience there wasn&apos;t all that bad, I don&apos;t like the fact that it&apos;s just dirt, no water unless you bring your own, and no seating or shaded areas.

So I went again a second time knowing the drawbacks. Our visit lasted approximately 2 minutes because my dog was instantly harassed by several big and aggressive dogs. She is smaller and very submissive, so she doesn&apos;t mind playing rough, but this time she got scared - I had never seen her bare her teeth before this encounter.

The owners of the aggressive dogs didn&apos;t do anything to stop the behavior. All they did was tell me &quot;Geez, I don&apos;t know why he&apos;s like this today.&quot;

So we immediately left the park and I will probably never go there again.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Greg K. 
 
 11 friends 51 reviews 

 Greg K. 
 
Denver, CO
 Updated - 3/13/2009 
I was too harsh on my last review, but seriously, this place is pretty cool.

The folks are always laid back, the dogs play around and I&apos;ve never seen one hurt.  They are just all behaving like dogs.

All these parks are just sand pits, but we should be writing to out local reps for that (Carla Madison 2713 Welton Street Denver, CO 80205) not to each other.

Actually, bollocks to the review, if you care, old fashion mail this lady with the unfortunate PR picture (seriously check out the site) .  Denver likes its dogs and parks, let&apos;s complain up and not to each other.

PS.
To the semi-cute chick in the Uggs, I&apos;m sorry I laughed when my neutered dog got a boner after play mounting your *Much* bigger and *Much* better groomed dog and you felt like you had to leave, it really was funny from where I was watching.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (3) 
 
1 Previous Review: Show all» 

 2/1/2009 
It&apos;s the closest park to our house and my wife and me visit this park usually every week.  Is it an… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kyla A. 
 
 119 friends 100 reviews 

 Kyla A. 
 
Denver, CO
 4/3/2009 
When I don&apos;t have the time to make the drive to Stapleton dog park, I go here.  It is by no means my favorite dog park but it serves a great purpose: to help the dog owners who live down town.

It is uber convenient and for that plus it comes with the negative of being in a somewhat sketch neighborhood.  The fenced up area is pretty small, and the surface is totally dirt, but most people who go here are friendly and I haven&apos;t seen that many problems between different dogs.

I do have to say stay out the middle.  I literally saw this middle-aged woman got toppled over by a group of dogs chasing each other.  They totally bowled her over, both legs were up in the air and we thought she might have broken something.  Thank goodness she ended up being fine, but lesson learned for those who watched.

Certainly do not make a trek to visit this park, but if you live downtown, it is a good resource if you need it, but it can get quite crowded.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from MAt L. 
 
 10 friends 4 reviews 

 MAt L. 
 
Denver, CO
 2/14/2006 
Fuller Dog Park is a great place to take your furry friend! While it may not be all that beautiful, (pretty much just a big dirt yard) it is enclosed, and equipped with dootie-bags and trash. What else do you need? Dogs run freely within the fenced area, playing and pooping. Good stuff! The only drawback is there is no provided water for your exahusted pal after a long day of sniffing butt, digging holes and tearing around with his newfound K9 buddies.

Chewie the dog gives it 5 stars!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Davian H. 
 
 17 friends 63 reviews 

 Davian H. 
 
New York, NY
 4/16/2009 
I&apos;m psyched to have a dog park just a few minutes drive from Uptown.

It&apos;s large enough for some running, and chasing, and general canine hi-jinks. The people are friendly, and the assortment of dogs is great...there are always a few interesting breeds. I love seeing a crazed poodle clinging to a running Rhodesian Ridgeback&apos;s leg.

That said...there is room for serious improvement, most notably:
1) Water for the dogs. There is no water fountain or water station in the vicinity, and the dog owners have to bring their own, which on a hot day can run out quickly.

2) seating. Would it kill Denver parks n rec to put in a few picnic tables?

Word of advice...don&apos;t wear flip-flops. When the dirt kicks up, due to a carousing pack of dogs, or the wind, your feet will be so dirty.

See you at the Dog Park!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nicholas O. 
 
 11 friends 72 reviews 

 Nicholas O. 
 
Denver, CO
 3/12/2009 
Denver could really use some upgrades to their dog parks. As I understand it, their system is still in &quot;beta&quot; mode and doesn&apos;t seem to be getting much better any time soon. A little water fountain, some obstacles, maybe a small-dog area would be nice.

Anyway, this and the other Denver dog parks I&apos;ve been to are bare bones -- just dirt and a fence. Two stars for wide-open space and plenty of plastic bags stocked. But my big furry four-legged friend gets bored very easily here. He burns off more energy running around in my backyard.
 
 Listed in: My Neighborhood 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jelena W. 
 
 42 friends 240 reviews 

 Jelena W. 
 
Lakewood, CO
 8/11/2007 
This dog park is basically a big fenced square of dirt, with poo bags as the only amenity. No shade or benches are provided for humans, and the dogs will have to bring their own water dishes- doggie backpack time!

I&apos;ll still give it a fat four stars, though, because the people are VERY friendly and a variety of dogs are always romping free at Fuller. If you have a pup like mine that&apos;s impossible to wear out, this is the spot to find playful people who&apos;ll throw a ball even for a dog that&apos;s not theirs, and similarly friendly dogs that love to wrestle and bounce around all over the park. Dogs don&apos;t seem to mind the lack of grass- all the better to get filthy in, then jump on you, especially if you&apos;re wearing light colored clothes!
 
 Listed in: Spoil That Pooch! 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Dawn O. 
 
 2 friends 14 reviews 

 Dawn O. 
 
Denver, CO
 5/7/2008 
What happens when you put a large group of dogs into a small fenced area?  A dog fight.  One always gets mad eventually. Maybe one dog sniffed anothers butt a little too long, or had their tennis ball stolen - either way, there&apos;s going to be a tiff at some point.
But as a dog owner, it should be understood that normally it&apos;s not severe and I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve ever seen a dog get hurt there.
So is this the best dog park? No - but it&apos;s better than nothing.  So therefore I give it 3 stars.  For those of us in the city, our pups need the energy release and Cherry Creek State park is great but the drive stinks!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jeremy H. 
 
 11 friends 37 reviews 

 Jeremy H. 
 
Denver, CO
 4/2/2009 
I&apos;ve read over the other reviews of this place, and I mean seriously, what do you people except of a busy dog park in the middle of Five Points. It&apos;s a big yard, and the entertainment from the neighborhood is excellent. Middle school fights between fifth graders, the police driving through the basketball court, and then there was the lady under the gazebo that called the cops on my friend for a vicious dog. My friend&apos;s dog weighs 10 pounds.

But, most of the people are really friendly and all the dogs are just happy to escape their urban houses. Except for that one lady that kept letting her dog hump my dog until I said &quot;You know, she&apos;s going to get pissed and kick his ass.&quot; And then my dog gets pissed and kicks your dogs ass. Sorry your dogs a sissy and you were too busy on the phone.

But really, this place is awesome if your dog is fixed and you realize you live in the middle of the city.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Christopher B. 
 
 29 friends 77 reviews 

 Christopher B. 
 
Denver, CO
 8/22/2010 22 Check-ins Here 
Fuller Park is the dog&apos;s meow.  Mostly because it&apos;s within walking distance for me. I&apos;m glad to have such amenities nearby.

I don&apos;t know how much it has to do with the new Denver Dogs group, but the park now enjoys one bench, and a Wall Of Water for the four-legged ones.

So ultimately, bring your own bags because they&apos;re frequently out; don&apos;t bring your kids; and pick off-peak times like weeknights and early weekend mornings unless you want to get stuck in a park with a bunch of panicky weird dog-owners.
 
 Listed in: Parks and rec ,
	</body>
</document>
