<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007893" url="http://www.sodahead.com/united-states/berg-reponse-in-opposition-to-obamadnc-protective-order/blog-19988/" time="2012-07-13-00:51" support="8" score="0.009696794920728466" bingtitle="Berg Reponse In Opposition To Obama/DNC protective Order" webtitle="Berg Reponse In Opposition To Obama/DNC protective Order">
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>... in oppostion to Obama / DNC protective order ... in one case, the name of a fast-food restaurant, Jimmy Johns. ... for the Little Rock, Ark., City Council, a seat on ...</description>
	<body>
		SodaHeadlines Entertainment Living Fun&amp;Humor games sports music fashion News&amp;Politics Leaderboard 
Berg Reponse In Opposition To Obama/DNC protective Order

 Posted October 11, 2008 03:36:10 Read all 3 opinions 
 
 Rave this Rave share this Share 
 Is Obama a Natural Born Citizen?

Berg response in oppostion to Obama / DNC protective order
Thursday, 09 October 2008 21:38 administrator Attached is Philip J. Berg&apos;s Opposition to Defendants, the DNC and Obama&apos;s Motion for Protective Order Staying Discovery pending Decision on their Motion to Dismiss. If the Protective Order were granted, discovery could not occur until the standing issue has been resolved and only if it is in favor of the plaintiff.

Following is an excerpt fromthe response:

PLAINTIFF’S RESPONSE IN OPPOSITION TO DEFENDANTS BARACK H. OBAMA AND THE DEMOCRATIC NATIONAL COMMITTEE’S MOTION FOR A PROTECTIVE ORDER STAYING DISCOVERY PENDING DECISION ON DISPOSITVE MOTION
Plaintiff, Philip J. Berg, Esquire [hereinafter “Plaintiff”] files the within Response in Opposition to Defendants, Barack H. Obama [hereinafter “Obama”] and the Democratic National Committee [hereinafter “DNC’] Motion for Protective Order Staying Discovery Pending Decision on Defendants Dispositive Motion on the following grounds:
1. Defendants’ pending Motion to Dismiss does not entitle them to a Protective Order under Federal Rule of Civil Procedure 26(c) [hereinafter F.R.C.P. 26(c];
2. Defendants have failed to show “good cause” and are therefore not entitled to a protective order under F.R.C.P. 26(c);
3. Defendants have not pointed to any legitimate privacy concerns. Defendants have failed to point out any substantiated specific examples demonstrating that disclosure will cause a defined and serious injury;

4. Plaintiff does not seek access to the requested information for any improper purpose;
5. Defendants have not shown any risk that particularly serious embarrassment will result from the requested documents;
6. The requested information is extremely important for public safety; and “Good Cause” requires a particular need for the protection sought;
7. The sharing of information will promote fairness and efficiency so as not to delay this action;
8. Barack Obama, as U.S. Senator of Illinois and the Democratic Nominee for President of the United States, is a public person, and his citizenship status is a matter of significant public concern and is subject to legitimate public scrutiny. The Democratic National Committee is a public entity and is also subject to public scrutiny; and 9. The public interest in access to the requested information under the Freedom of Information Act 5 U.S.C. § 552 is a strong factor in favor of not granting a protective order which would prevent disclosure of such information.
Attachments: File Description File size
Response in opposition to Obama&apos;s protective order which would delay discovery 127 Kb


Set as favorite Bookmark Email This Hits: 946
Trackback(0)
TrackBack URI for this entry
Comments (197)
Subscribe to this comment&apos;s feed
Test after crash
written by Webmaster, October 09, 2008

We had a website crash due to a problem with our software. In researching it, this is an occasional software glitch with the software.

It&apos;s fixed now and I&apos;m testing the comment system.
+1 ...
written by jeremy, October 09, 2008

does this judge realize the election is in 3 weeks!
+2 Questions
written by Ben, October 09, 2008

Does the judge HAVE to rule on ANY of the motions that have been filed? If the judge does not rule is Obama and the DNC required to provide the items of discovery by 10/15?

Thanks
+3 What happens if...
written by Patriot, October 09, 2008

the judge does not rule until after 11/4? If Obama cannot produce the vault version of the BC, but is already elected, what happens? Impeachment? Does Biden become president? Is the entire election cancelled after the fact? If so, what happens then?
+2 Best focus for your frustration, time, energy
written by sdallas, October 09, 2008

Folks:
If you want to channel your frustrations, energy, and time into something that will have an immediate impact to making MSM get interested in Berg&apos;s lawsuit, I highly recommend getting the word out via email and any/all means possible and hitting the streets (literally) with what Jerome Corsi is going to publish on worldnetdaily.com tomorrow Fri 10/13. Listen to his radio interview he did today via following link.
 http://www.audioacrobat.com/playweb? audioid=Pb2fca120155f68b55a2f95f93896c43bZVp+RH9uY2N0Vg


He is also going to reveal his Kenyan evidence on Hannity and Colmes Mon 10/13 9PM Eastern, 8PM central. This is hard evidence, not hearsay and not conspiracy stuff. This is the real deal. Once he goes public with this, particularly on Fox News, all hell is going to break loose and MSM is going to not have a choice but to start reporting this stuff and hopefully by then the judge will have a ruling on Mr. Berg&apos;s motions.

And don&apos;t forget Jerome Corsi is scheduled to be on MommaE&apos;s program http://blogtalkradio.com/mommaeradiorebels Mon 10/13 I believe.

+1 ...
written by TMAN, October 09, 2008

I wish something would happen, my nerves are on edge for days now...
+1 Class Action Citizen Signature Petition
written by Victoria, October 09, 2008

Mr. Berg,
Could a&quot;We the American People&quot;(movant) submit a Petition of Signatures in&apos;Class Action&apos;mass, in support of your case, right to be heard, demanding justice in the name of the people? This procedure has worked in public cases before, to prompt the Court to act, expressing the Publics Interest in the People&apos;s Court. This had a profound effect in Children&apos;s Advocacy Cases. Each time judges realized the public was watching, paying attention and cared about the outcome. Judges received a massive amount of postal mail (pre internet) and helped to change the de facto practice of deny and delay. We could collect thousands of signatures by email in a short period of time. In the State of Virginia Animal Rights Advocates used Electronic Petitions. A company set it up for them, acted as the legal collector. Public Clicked on a link, filled out the form to prove you agree, signed it, filed with the collector of signatures, with an automatic email sent to signer to confirm they in fact signed the petition. The mass signature Petition changed the law.
+7 ...
written by Ken T, October 09, 2008

I am having problems. I registered but did not get a confirmation email to use to fully register the account. So I now get blocked. It asks me if I did not get the confirmation but no way to answer the question. I have tried saying I forgot my password and forgot my log in name. neither help me. Although the forgot password refuses anything. the forgot name says it sent me an emaill but again nothing arrives.

can you help me.

my attempt to register was under the user handle name of Ken

since now the computer broke down maybe you can help me out.

thanks

Ken
+0 ...
written by Ken T, October 09, 2008

 http://rumormillnews.com/MEDIA_EMAIL_ADDRESSES.htm 

email addys to use to get the word out.

remember to copy and past them into the BCC. Blind Carbon Copy so they do not print out on the email.
+2 ...
written by Slick, October 09, 2008

Can someone that has the writing skills draft an effective but generic email/letter that we can all use to get the ball rolling? I emailed Berg asking for something of the sort but he&apos;s been too busy to reply. Just something where each one of us can fill in the blanks, and attach any pertinent .pdf docs or whatever, and then fire off to our local media contacts. If everyone works in concert together, this may be very effective but we will only know if we try.
+3 ALERT: WASH TIMES Friday: Obama secretly tried to sway Iraqi government...
written by sdallas, October 09, 2008

On http://www.drudgereport.com/ 
WASH TIMES Friday: Obama secretly tried to sway Iraqi government to ignore Bush deal on keeping troops in Iraq... Developing...

Watch the Obama campaign implode! With the Jerome Corsi evidence being published and now the Washington Times article coming out. His huge team of legal staff are going to be busy, busy, busy!

And...Mr. Berg motions to have to deal with on top of all that! I bet Obama is up to least a couple a packs of cigs a day he&apos;s smoking!
+1 ...
written by Sarah&apos;s #1 Fan, October 09, 2008

We need something to bring this guy down and fast. we are running out of time, the media will never report on anything bad regarding their messiahm, I hope that Corsi has the actual birth certificate of obama to prove that he was actually born in kenya
+2 ...
written by Chad, October 09, 2008

Mr. Berg,

Thanks so much for your hard work and labor! I&apos;m impressed with the arguments in your response. Continue on the fight for freedom and from a Constitutional Crisis!




+1 Mr. Berg and Berg Assistant: Excellent Work and Stay the Course!!
written by sdallas, October 09, 2008

Mr. Berg and Berg Assistant:
Wanted to convey to each of you: Excellent Work! I’m not an attorney, but your latest filings appear to me to be better prepared than your original filing. Your response to Defense’s motion for Delay in Discovery particularly looks very well prepared.

It is very apparent this is taking considerable amount of time and effort and likely taking its toll on your lives. Keeping our country’s constitutional integrity intact is no easy task and with the Obama machine as the foe, the task at hand requires considerable fortitude and courage. Stay the course! You have literally thousands, if not millions, of us out here who are right behind you, saying prayers for your success and safety, and ready to be your electronic and physical foot soldiers in this battle.

Let us know how we can be of assistance!

+1 ...
written by Daniel Smith, October 09, 2008

YOU CAN SIGN A PETITION THAT WILL BE SENT TO THE OFFICIALS OF YOUR STATE
FREE FREE FREE
Stop the Obama Constitutional Crisis | Concerned American Voter | Concerned American Voter

 http://www.rallycongress.com/constitutional-qualification/124... 

THIS CASE SHOULD BE COVERED BY THE MSM..........
+1 ...
written by Ken T, October 09, 2008

You can help by writing an email and sending it to as many people as possible to get the word out.

written by Ken T, October 09, 2008

 http://rumormillnews.com/MEDIA_EMAIL_ADDRESSES.htm 

email addys to use to get the word out.

remember to copy and past them into the BCC. Blind Carbon Copy so they do not print out on the email.

And also please make a donation to the cause. There are huge expenses. This is not a for profit undertaking. Phil Berg is basically paying all the bills. But getting the word out by sending emails is extremely helpful. You might get 1000 more people to recognize the truth who can then get more to see the truth. We need a growth of truth. spread the truth to everyone.
+2 Jerome Corsi Kenya Evidence Posted
written by sdallas, October 09, 2008

Jerome Corsi Kenya Evidence Posted

 http://www.worldnetdaily.com/index.php?fa=PAGE.view&amp;pageId;=7... 
+0 ...
written by Val from MA, October 10, 2008

Sarah&apos;s #1 Fan I think you should come down a bit. Perhaps comments like yours prevent the main stream media from taking this lawsuit seriously. Perhaps the media think we are all crazies here. We are all in this together - we all want Obama to be exposed for what he really is, but please be professional. You can be angry and still be professional - there is no reason to get personal though. Just a little piece of advice.

I also want to take this opportunity to thank Mr. Berg for everything that he has done and continues to do on behalf of all of us - those that are sick and tired of Obama&apos;s dark secrets, and he has way too many of them for someone that wants to be our president. I hope the ruling will be in your favor, Mr. Berg - you deserve it.
+0 ...
written by steph3, October 10, 2008

Getting the truth out there has become a full time job. Post on every blog and email, email, email, and donate. This is what is needed.
+3 ...
written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

his was on Jeremy&apos;s blog
Obama is Indonesian.

“My sources claim that he was adopted and that the Indonesian government is aware of this - so are Obama’s people who cut a deal with the Indonesian government to have the records suppressed.”

And he referred me to this Sept. 18 post, Obama Throwing Papua Under the Bus, which apparently was not read by enough people. He instructed me to read it carefully. So I did, and here’s the upshot.

According to Martin’s post, U.S. Congressman Eni Faleomavaega, an outspoken critic of Indonesia’s oppression of Papua and a Barack Obama supporter (and Superdelegate), visited Indonesia in July 2007, with the purpose of “acquiring any and all documentation or photographs of a young Barry Soetoro.” Martin claims that a substantial sum of money was exchanged. He writes:

The challenge of course was securing Indonesian government records potentially damaging to Barack Obama’s candidacy for the US presidency as well as other records pertaining to a young Barry Soetoro and his family wouldn’t be so easy to acquire and secure..


“In the end,” according to Martin, “everyone got what they wanted, all to the detriment of the West Papuans”:

…In a show of faith, Barack Obama’s childhood school would be one of the very first beneficiaries of this outpouring, receiving thousands of dollars to upgrade the school and for the purchase of computer equipment…

..The only issue of contention Faleomavaega would face from the Indonesian government would be the issue of West Papua. In the end, it was simply a give and take situation. The Obama campaign needed assistance from the Indonesian government and the Indonesian government wanted a free hand in Papua.

Later concerning Faleomavaega’s meeting, Indonesian presidential spokesman Dino Patti Djalal would have this to say: “One thing that is sure is that Faleomevaega’s visit here has changed his views about Indonesia. It has made him realize this country is so vast and complex it cannot be reduced by the Papua issue…” Dino said Faleomavaega was known as a US Congress member who often commented on the Papuan issue but now he had changed his views. “He now sees that Papua is inalienable part of the Unitary State of the Republic of Indonesia.”

Faleomevaega’s and meeting with Indonesia’s president regarding West Papua and his subsequent flipflop on supporting West Papau’s right to self-determination is something that you might think would warrant at least a press release on the congressman’s website, but there is nothing, nor is there any mention on the House Subcommittee’s site. No press release, nothing, not even a mere mention of his trip to Indonesia.

+0 ...
written by Mark Andrew, October 10, 2008

I started hearing about this Obama citizenship problem this week. Several people told me and one gave me the URL to this site. So this vital information is getting out without help of the so-called mainstream media. I&apos;ve told a dozen people about this too. Most of them were not planning to vote (we&apos;re mostly Democrats&amp;independents stuck in a McCain stronghold) but they all said they will vote for John McCain, if anything, just as a protest as to what&apos;s going on and give McCain some more of the popular vote.

I keep hearing about the disappointment over Hillary Clinton and the primary and learned that Hillary Clinton WON the vote in Texas, then lost it in&quot;the middle of the night&quot;to the&quot;powers in the party.&quot;With her stolen Texas win, she would have had the primary in the bag and be the next President I&apos;m quite sure.

You know, I didn&apos;t really believe any of this at first. It seemed totally absurd. But after looking at Obama&apos;s web sites (including fightthesmears) and also looking at what&apos;s on factcheck.org, snopes.com, and the lawsuit with responses from both sides, I have absoutely no doubt whatsoever that Obama and his campaign have engaged in a massive coverup on par with Watergate and Iran-Contra. These websites that I checked to verify the claims should have tons of supporting documents to show Obama&apos;s story (including educational records) to show a history of where this guy came from.

Obama is virtually unknown. I didn&apos;t know anything about him at all until the infamous&quot;1984&quot;ad came out in February of 2007. This is the ad that made Mrs. Clinton look like a dictator preaching to the masses. I thought Obama was born and raised in Kansas. I had no idea he lived in Indonesia. I also had no idea he used cocaine, and I have a copy of a page from HIS book where he said he did this.

A friend of mine works in law enforcement. He made the comment that Obama could NEVER pass a background check for a law enforcement job with his admissions (drug use) and omissions (sealed or hidden documents, lack of or sealed educational records, no official birth record). How can someone who couldn&apos;t pass a background check possibly even be a U.S. senator or be running for President of the United States?
+9 Problems registering?
written by Webmaster, October 10, 2008

If you registered and never received your confirmation email, request a password reset with the&quot;forgot your password&quot;link.

There seem to be some continuing side-effects to the crash earlier tonight.
+0 Thanks for the information
written by Ben_, October 10, 2008

I think I&apos;m registered now.
+0 Heroes
written by richardsh, October 10, 2008

To Mr. Berg and his Assistant:

I&apos;m not a lawyer, but from my lay person&apos;s perspective, I thought your response in opposition to the Obama/DNC protective order was excellent. You both are nothing less than Heroes in my book for taking a stand to protect our country. Godspeed to both of you!
+3 ...
written by Slick, October 10, 2008

In response to Mark Andrew;

I understand your sentiments exactly. I recently applied for a government position and was turned down because of prior drug use. It was literally the 2nd question I was asked during the telephone interview, and they immediately ended the interview after that. I sat there perplexed, and knowing what I know about obama&apos;s past, this presidential race suddenly came to mind. If he is elected, he will essentially be the commander in chief for many public and secret government agencies that he would never even be able to apply to if he was starting from an entry-level position. To think that the higher you go, the less they care, is absolutely absurd. I cannot believe that he will have control of these organizations which have a direct impact on our national security...Not to mention if the interviewer had found out that I had radical or terrorist or muslim ties, not only would I be disqualified, but I would be investigated!! Someone help me understand how this is possible?
+3 ...
written by Tony Stark, October 10, 2008

I just sent in my contribution via Paypal. It&apos;s important that we continue to support Berg in his quest to wring the truth out of Obama regarding his true origins.
+1 ...
written by Concerned Citizen 08, October 10, 2008

It&apos;s possible because many people in high places believe they are above the law, particularly if they are lawyers and Congressmen. They make laws, or interpret existing law, in ways to benefit themselves. The Founding Fathers attempted to make things simple and straightforward, but folks like Obama change the definition of words and use legal-wrangling to get the loopholes they want.

Just watch, when the proof is brought to light he will have already have put a plan in place to change something in the lawbooks to get him qualified and elected.
+1 ...
written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

The requirement&apos;s in Hawaii list that you must be a Resident for at least&quot;one&quot;year.
I would check to see the Eact Date that the Dunham&apos;s Moved to Hawaii. It&apos;s very close.
If they moved their after August 04, 1960 , Ann Dunham would not of qualified to register a live Birth Certificate. (Unless, maybe if Obama Sr. was there longer???)
Worth checking into!
+2 ...
written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

Did Ann Dunham finish her first year at Univ. Hawaii, and did start her second year in Sept. 1961?
+1 The Big Whopper Lie Buried in Sea of Rumors
written by Marie , October 10, 2008

I believe that the Obama campaign has planned to use this technique to address the eligibility issue all along. They&apos;ve almost encouraged people to put out crazy rumors so they can put on the dismissive air and prove them wrong and then the real whopper lies (like this BC forgery) are quietly lumped into the&quot;internet rumors and smears&quot;category. This approach is really rather ingenious if you think about it. It puts the mainstream media on the defensive--so afraid that they will get the story wrong that they just avoid iinvestigating anything that sounds too sensational. This is, ironically, the only way they were able to pull off this gargantuan con of the American electorate.

They know that only internet savvy skeptics will dig around enough for the real truth and the true believers and the low-information voters will never know what hit them. It&apos;s all a waiting game designed to overload the system and create chaos so the ineligible candidate can slide in under the cover of confusion. It&apos;s exactly the same MO used in the illegal caucus fraud during the primaries and the ACORN voter registration and early voting strategy. They know most of these fake registrations will be kicked out, but it overwhelms the system and allows them to slide some of them through.

And it&apos;s working. I have several friends who are Obama supporters and I can&apos;t even get them to look at this website. They all immediately dismiss it and say,&quot;It&apos;s obvious a website ginned up by Karl Rove. There is no lawsuit.&quot;It&apos;s like a huge case of mass denial and mind control...

I sure hope the Dept of Justice gets involved at some point.


+4 Thousands of voter registration forms faked, officials say
written by Philly, October 10, 2008

CROWN POINT, Indiana (CNN) -- More than 2,000 voter registration forms filed
in northern Indiana&apos;s Lake County by a liberal activist group this week
have turned out to be bogus, election officials said Thursday.

The group -- the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now, or
ACORN -- already faces allegations of filing fraudulent voter registrations
in Nevada and faces investigations in other states.

And in Lake County, home to the long-depressed steel town of Gary, the
bipartisan Elections Board has stopped processing a stack of about 5,000
applications delivered just before the October 6 registration deadline after
the first 2,100 turned out to be phony.

&quot;All the signatures looked exactly the same,&quot;Ruthann Hoagland, a Republican
on the board.&quot;Everything on the card filled out looks exactly the same.&quot;

The forms included registrations submitted in the names of the dead -- and
in one case, the name of a fast-food restaurant, Jimmy Johns. Sally LaSota,
a Democrat on the board, called the forms fraudulent and said whoever filed
them broke the law.

&quot;ACORN, with its intent, perhaps was good in the beginning, but went awry
somewhere,&quot;LaSota said.

Over the past four years, a dozen states have investigated complaints of
fraudulent registrations filed by ACORN. On Tuesday, Nevada authorities
raided an ACORN office in Las Vegas, Nevada, where workers are accused of
registering members of the Dallas Cowboys football team. And the group has
become the target of Republican attacks on voter fraud, a perennial GOP
issue.

A subsidiary of the group was paid $800,000 by Democratic presidential
candidate Barack Obama&apos;s campaign to register voters for the 2008 primaries,
and ACORN&apos;s political wing endorsed Obama back in February. But Obama&apos;s
campaign told CNN that it&quot;is committed to protecting the integrity of the
voting process,&quot;and said it has not worked with ACORN during the general
election.

Brian Mellor, an ACORN attorney in Boston, said the group has its own
quality-control process and has fired workers in the past -- including
workers in Gary. But he said allegations that his organization committed
fraud is a government attempt to keep people disenfranchised.
&quot;We believe their purpose is to attack ACORN and suppress votes,&quot;Mellor
said.&quot;We believe that by attacking ACORN, they are going to discourage
people that have registered to vote with ACORN from voting.&quot;

CNN was unable to reach ACORN officials in Gary and in Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
where the group&apos;s Indiana operation is based. Offices in both cities were
empty when reporters visited.

Lake County elections officials have set aside all 5,000 of the ACORN-
submitted applications in what Hoagland called the&quot;fake pile&quot;for later
review. But she said every one will be reviewed before the election to make
sure no legitimate voters are skipped.

There has been no evidence of voter fraud yet, because voters have yet to go
to the polls. But elections officials say they will be sending their
information to prosecutors, who will determine whether any investigation
will begin.

&quot;We have no idea what the motive behind it is,&quot;she said.&quot;It&apos;s just
overwhelming to us.&quot;
+1 Berg is a sharp guy
written by American Value2, October 10, 2008

I must admit that Berg is a sharp guy who knows his case law. He has laid out a very extensive case, enumerating each point that Obama could be eligible for a Protective order, and then shooting each of them down concisely and legally, citing numerous case law precedents along the way

It continues to boil down to this: All Barack Obama has to do is to produce a legal, verifiable, and original Hawaiian vault birth certificate, and ALL OF THIS WILL PROBABLY GO AWAY

Just DO IT, Mr. Obama, if you can

The chilling thing about this is that Mr. Berg finally enumerates in this latest response that once Obama is sworn in as POTUS, the protections that surround that office might make it impossible to REMOVE him from office

And don&apos;t bother talking about Impeachment - does any rational thinking person really believe that the Democratically-controlled Congress would bring Articles of Impeachment against a sitting Democrat President?

LOL - I need some of what YOU are smoking if that is true

Bloody fascinating and scary case - it has my attention


+1 Great Foreign Policy Experience
written by Marie , October 10, 2008

I was just following up on the Jerome Corsi Kenyan trip story and got curious so I looked at the Wikipedia entry for Raila Odinga. For those who don&apos;t know, this is supposedly a cousin of Obama&apos;s and Obama actively campaigned for him during a&quot;fact finding&quot;trip to Kenya. Corsi now has emails between Obama and Odinga showing Obama was a consultant of sorts to his cousin&apos;s campaign. It says that he is an Anglican but then I opened the memorandum of understanding (MOU) between Raila Odinga and the Kenyan National Muslim Leaders and the first Whereas states

&quot;Whereas The Candidate(that&apos;s Odinga) - who recognizes Islam as the only true religion - is seeking to become the next President of the Republic of Kenya&quot;.

Seems like Obama&apos;s favorite cousin is having a religious identity crisis!!

But then, I was flabbergasted when I read what all he agreed to do if elected! He basically said he would institute Shariah law and nationalize Islam. He also agreed that his Kenyan government would not allow other countries to extradite and put on trial Muslim extremist terroists and, instead, the Kenyan government would try them and pay for a lawyer for them. Given Shariah law, I&apos;m sure THAT would get those terrorists shaking in their boots!!

Read it here at this link and just remember, this is a guy that Obama CAMPAIGNED FOR!!! It&apos;s bad enough what havoc Obama is wreaking in the world as a candidate--just imagine what will go on with him in the Whitehouse!

 http://www.eakenya.org/AAEAKUpdate/RAILA_MUSLIM_MOU.pdf 
+1 This election has me very worried. So many things to consider.
written by J. Hansen, October 10, 2008

This election has me very worried. So many things to consider.
I watch all the news channels, jumping from one to another. I must say this drives my husband crazy. But, I feel if you view MSNBC, CNN, and Fox News, you might get some middle ground to work with. About six months ago, I started thinking---&quot;where did the money come from for Obama&quot;. I have four daughters who went to College, and we were middle class, and money was tight. We (including my girls) worked hard and there were lots of student loans.
I started looking into Obama&apos;s life.
Around 1979 Obama started college at Occidental in California. He is very open about his two years at Occidental; he tried all kinds of drugs and was wasting his time but, even though he had a brilliant mind, did not apply himself to his studies.
&quot;Barry&quot;(that was the name he used all his life) during this time had two roommates, Muhammad Hasan Chandoo and Wahid Hamid, both from Pakistan.
During the summer of 1981, after his second year in college, he made a&quot;round the world&quot;trip. Stopping to see his mother in Indonesia, next Hyderabad in India, three weeks in Karachi, Pakistan where he stayed with his roommate&apos;s family, then off to Africa to visit his father&apos;s family.
My question - Where did he get the money for this trip? Nether I, nor any one of my children would have had money for a trip like this when they where in college. When he came back he started school at Columbia University in New York. It is at this time he wants everyone to call him Barack - not Barry.
Do you know what the tuition is at Columbia? It&apos;s not cheap! to say the least. Where did he get money for tuition? Student Loans? Maybe. After Columbia, he went to Chicago to work as a Community Organizer for $12,000. a year. Why Chicago? Why not New York? He was already living in New York.
By&quot;chance&quot;he met Antoin&quot;Tony&quot;Rezko, born in Aleppo Syria, and a real estate developer in Chicago. Rezko has been convicted of fraud and bribery this year. Rezko, was named&quot;Entrepreneur of the Decade&quot;by the Arab-American Business and Professional Association&quot;.
About two years later, Obama entered Harvard Law School. Do you have any idea what tuition is for Harvard Law School? Where did he get the money for Law School? More student loans? After Law school, he went back to Chicago. Rezko offered him a job, which he turned down. But, he did take a job with Davis, Miner, Barnhill&amp;Galland. Guess what? They represented&quot;Rezar&quot;which is Rezko&apos;s firm. Rezko was one of Obama&apos;s first major financial contributors when he ran for office in Chicago. In 2003, Rezko threw an early fundraiser for Obama which Chicago Tribune reporter David Mendelland claims was instrumental in providing Obama with&quot;seed money&quot;for his U.S. Senate race.
In 2005, Obama purchased a new home in Kenwood District of Chicago for $1.65 million (less than asking price). With ALL those Student Loans - Where did he get the money for the property? On the same day Rezko&apos;s wife, Rita, purchased the adjoining empty lot for full price. The London Times reported that Nadhmi Auchi, an Iraqi-born Billionaire loaned Rezko $3.5 million three weeks before Obama&apos;s new home was purchased. Obama met Nadhmi Auchi many times with Rezko.
Now, we have Obama running for President. Valerie Jarrett, was Michele Obama&apos;s boss. She is now Obama&apos;s chief advisor and he does not make any major decisions without talking to her first. Where was Jarrett born? Ready for this? Shiraz, Iran. Do we see a pattern here? Or, am I going crazy?On May 10, 2008 The Times reported, Robert Malley advisor to Obama was&quot;sacked&quot;after the press found out he was having regular contacts with&quot;Hamas&quot;, which controls Gaza and is connected with Iran. This past week, buried in the back part of the papers, Iraqi newspapers reported that during Obama&apos;s visit to Iraq, he asked their leaders to do nothing about the war until after he is elected, and he will&quot;Take care of things&quot;.Oh, and by the way, remember the college roommates that where born in Pakistan? They are in charge of all those&quot;small&quot;Internet campaign contributions for Obama. Where is that money coming from? The poor and middle class in this country? Or could it be from the Middle East?And the final bit of news. On September 7, 2008, The Washington Times posted a verbal slip that was made on&quot;This Week&quot;with George Stephanapoulos. Obama on talking about his religion said,&quot;My Muslim faith&quot;. When questioned,&quot;he made a mistake&quot;. Some mistake!
All of the above information I got on line. If you would like to check it - Wikipedia, encyclopedia, Barack Obama; Tony Rezko; Valerie Jarrett: Daily Times - Obama visited Pakistan in 1981; The Washington Times - September 7, 2008; The Times May 10, 2008.Now the BIG question - If I found out all this information on my own, why haven&apos;t all of our&quot;intelligent&quot;members of the press been reporting this?A phrase that keeps ringing in my ear -&quot;Beware of the enemy from within.&quot;
+12 Civil Rights Movement&amp;the use of&quot;Civil disobedience&quot;-activley refusing to obey certain laws, demands and commands of a government
written by Another American for TRUTH!, October 10, 2008

Holy cow! Obama mentions being greatly influenced by the Civil Rights movement. But I had NO IDEA of just how much!

During the Civil Rights Movement people were encouraged to use **Civil Disobedience*** in order to accomplish their goals. This is what he&apos;s doing by not showing his COLB. He&apos;s using civil disobedience by refusing to comply with our constitution and laws!

I really had no idea of the similarities between the CRM and the Obama campaign... right on down to using the MSM as part of their strategy. Below I pasted just a bit of what I read;

Civil Rights Movenment and Civil disobedience

Civil disobedience, or&quot;Resistance to Civil Government&quot;is the active refusal to obey certain laws, demands and commands of a government, or of an occupying power, without resorting to physical violence.

Mainstream exposure

Some of the success of the Civil Rights Movement can be attributed to television coverage. Such coverage wakened the conscience of mainstream or middle America. In&quot;Television News and the Civil Rights Struggle&quot;Television news coverage had immediate and significant effects&quot;on perceptions of social equality and segregation.[2]

One of Martin Luther King&apos;s strategies was to challenge mainstream America on moral grounds. The medium of television was particularly effective at conveying the news about the conditions of the quality of life for African Americans. The news broadcasts and documentary film making were the first forms for presenting these stories.

Voter Registration Organizing

Black leaders helped register black voters and build community organizations that could win a share of political power, because the intent to stop blacks from voting had become part of the culture of white supremacy. Their efforts were met with violent repression from state and local lawmen.

Mass action replacing litigation

The strategy of mass action within the court system shifted to tactics that relied on mass mobilization, nonviolent resistance and civil disobedience.

Churches, the centers of their communities, and local grassroots organizations mobilized volunteers (i.e.&quot;Community Organizers!!!!) to participate in broad-based actions. This was a more direct and potentially more rapid means of creating ***change*** than the traditional approach of mounting court challenges.

The Communist Party and African-Americans

The Communist Party USA played a significant role in defending the rights of African-Americans during its heyday in the 1930s and 1940s. Even in its years of greatest influence, however, the party&apos;s relations with the black community, black organizations and their leaders were complicated by sharp turns in policy at the top that often alienated many allies and supporters. The party&apos;s civil rights work largely ended when it was driven out of mainstream politics during the early days of the Cold War.





+3 OH MY GOSH!!
written by Kay Buckels, October 10, 2008

JAMES CARVELLE HINT AT POSSIBLE RIOTS IF OBAMA DOES NOT WIN ELECTION!!!

 http://www.americansagainstobama.com/ 
+1 Unclean hands
written by sandyulmer, October 10, 2008

To: T J Berg. This among other things being plead is fraud, fraud is&quot;equity&quot;, why is not the doctrine of unclean hands being plead??? this would limit defendants&apos;ability to obtain certain affirmative relief from the Court.

I&apos;m not an attorney but have been litigating pro se enforcement of a criminal restitution order in state court, the doctrine should apply.

Food for thought.
+0&quot;Clear and Present Danger - ENEMY FROM WITHIN&quot;
written by Kay Buckels, October 10, 2008

Everyone, please watch the following youtube.com video. You can go here and see it. I think you will again be shocked! This can and will probably happen IF this man is elected PRESIDENT!

Watch the video here:

 http://www.audacityofhypocrisy.com/2008/05/24/now-playing-cle... 

UNREAL! Scary to say the least!
+0 ...
written by KH, October 10, 2008

 http://www.worldnetdaily.com/i...geId=77508 

Proof Obama backed ruthless, foreign thug
Set up direct Senate contact for Kenyan opposition leader

+0 Patriot
written by Brad Meador, October 10, 2008

If the judge does not rule by November 4th, but after that date, no Obama will not be impeached. He won&apos;t be impeached unless he&apos;s in the oval office and that won&apos;t happen until January 20th (I doubt a decision will be made that far down the road). I&apos;m not sure of who would take over; I would think Biden would automatically become President and he would choose a VP of his choosing or Obama&apos;s victory will be null and McCain will take office.

Ben, I&apos;m not sure of the answers to your questions; sorry I&apos;m not really good at the judicial system.

Maybe Philadelphia Roof Doctor can help you there. He&apos;s not an attorney, but he seems to know this stuff.
+0 ...
written by Dobe, October 10, 2008

Please don&apos;t crucify me for saying, but please share your energy and outrage on other forums, and internet outlets as well.
The stats here are saying that almost 30 million hits so far, but just in case if this is a set up, dead end bay, to keep most vocal opponents away from youtube, and molesting MSM etc. or maybe we got here isolated by some means of internet technology.
Go everywhere you can, and express your opinions.
Even Levinstin or whoever, from National Enquirer sticked a finger up to our pleads.
This is just not looking right.
dobe
+0 President elect
written by Terry Day, October 10, 2008

Patriot,
Section 3 of the 20th Amendment explains what happens when a President-elect cannot serve. If Obama is elected, but disqualified before he is sworn in, Section 3 would be invoked. Here is what it says:

3. If, at the time fixed for the beginning of the term of the President, the President elect shall have died, the Vice President elect shall become President. If a President shall not have been chosen before the time fixed for the beginning of his term, or if the President elect shall have failed to qualify, then the Vice President elect shall act as President until a President shall have qualified; and the Congress may by law provide for the case wherein neither a President elect nor a Vice President elect shall have qualified, declaring who shall then act as President, or the manner in which one who is to act shall be selected, and such person shall act accordingly until a President or Vice President shall have qualified.
+0 ...
written by Greg2You, October 10, 2008

Can someone that has the writing skills draft an effective but generic email/letter that we can all use to get the ball rolling?


I&apos;ll give it a shot:


Dear Fellow American:

Amidst the economic crisis that has befallen our country has arisen an even greater crisis, the likes of which America has not seen since the Civil War.

On November 4th, millions of Americans will flock to the polls to elect a new President in what is already a historic event. Yet, the choice that Americans will face this November goes way beyond selecting the most-qualified person to lead our country, or even one who offers the greater promise of change.

In fact, Americans have never had to make this choice in a Presidential election:

&quot;Will we elect a candidate who is not even qualified to be President? A candidate who has lied about citizenship, lied about being born in America, lied about his allegiances to other countries, and lied about upholding the Constitution of the United States?&quot;

Barach Hussein Obama, if that is even his real name now, and the Democratic Party who nominated him, are being sued in federal court by a lifelong Democrat for refusing to provide any real evidence of where or when Obama was born.

All that Obama would have had to do to prove his qualuifications, is to produce a copy of his certified, original birth certificate. Yet, unbelievably, Obama and the Democratic National Committee are manipulating our legal system to block or delay every attempt to verify Obama&apos;s basic qualifications to run for President.

Obama has also resorted to posting a forged image of his birth certificate on the Internet in a blatant attempt to fool the American public into thinking that he is a natural-born US citizen,

Below is a link to the lawsuit that was filed. This is not some wild conspiracy or an effort to smear a Presidential canadiate. This is real. This is serious. This is happening s you read this letter.

Our country is headed for a Constitutional crisis if nothing is done to prevent it. That&apos;s why I&apos;m asking you, on behalf of Americans everywhere, to make your voice heard and make your vote count, that we will never allow anyone to run for President who subverts our country&apos;s Constitution and who violates our laws and our trust.

Please read the lawsuit, and add your name below, to a fast-growing list of others like you who desire to preserve our Nation.
+4 Barack Obama&apos;s Involvement with ACORN Unearthed, Missing Articles Recovered
written by King, October 10, 2008

Barack Obama&apos;s Involvement with ACORN Unearthed, Missing Articles Recovered

 http://www.clevelandleader.com/node/7203 

+0 Radio and Riots
written by BlueWater1949, October 10, 2008

1) I heard Phil Berg interviewed on the radio in Toledo, Ohio yesterday and he was well received. He was scheduled to be on TV for the 6 o&apos;clock news on the Fox affiliate. Let&apos;s pray that this has national legs now.

2) Riots will be bad if Obama loses, but imagine how bad they will be if he is removed from the process early for any reason. This is probably the reason troops are being deployed stateside for the first time in decades. Pray for peace in the streets.
+0 ..., Lowly rated comment [Show]
Black Paper, White Type, No Borders.
written by Jim Johnston, October 10, 2008

This needs further verification.

Made a phone call to the Hawaii Health Department to purchase a copy of Barack Obama&apos;s birth certificate - but states laws prohibit public access. So asked some generic questions that did not violate state laws, such as&quot;Have Birth Certificate changed over time?&quot;and&quot;What did a 1960&apos;s Birth Certificate look like?&quot;

The answer was&quot;Black Paper with white type - and no borders&quot;.

Asking then,&quot;Are you sure?

The answer back was&quot;I was born in 1965 and this is what birth certificates looked like back then&quot;.

I then asked about the Certificate number and the answer was,&quot;It starts with 151, then the year, then the sequence&quot;. - So why the black bar?

Does anyone have a friend who was born in the 1960 in Hawaii? This would help Phillip Berg hit the ball out of the park most assuredly.

+0 If Obama stiffs court on discovery Oct 15
written by Old Atlantic, October 10, 2008

Ask judge to issue judgment for Berg:

Obama has withheld information from the court in a timely manner as required by the rules of civil procedure to prevent the court being able to act. Judgment is entered for plaintiff. The name of Barack Obama shall be removed from all ballots for president, and no elector pledged to Obama shall be elected.
+1 What about Obama&apos;s wife?
written by Robert Francis, October 10, 2008

If Obama is an illegal alien but marries an American wife, does he not get to stay in this country?
I don&apos;t think this changes his citizenship though. He needs to be a man about this and face the legal naturalization issue himself. We are all required to pay the fees, file the forms, go through the waiting periods, go to the interviews, etc. He is no exception.
If he is an illegal alien he is subject to being arrested and deported.
+1 ...
written by steph3, October 10, 2008

Tolstoy, it is obvious over, and over that you support Obama. I respect your right to do so. However, when anyone can overlook all the very dangerous connections, relationships, and almost demonic mentors of his, his very shady past, and his support of some Marxist man who incited riots in his own country simply because he wanted to win and did not, and to top that off his marxist views and associations with organizations such as Acorn that are questionable and dishonest, you seem too intelligent to not be able to see a clear pattern of deception and lies that span his whole life. The man is one continual lie, a lie to anyone who will listen, inexperienced and whose value system is not only not American, but as socialistic as it can be.

But as I heard one person say, our votes will count in heaven, and let me tell you something, God cannot and will not honor any man in the white house, or any nation who elects a president who when a baby is born despite being aborted, it is still alive, he votes four times for that baby to die, that, Sir, is murder. A fetus can survive at a pound and half in an incubator, but Obama does not know when life begins, it is&quot;above his paygrade.&quot;Well guess what, it is not above God&apos;s paygrade because He creates life at the moment of conception, and John McCain knew that one as well. God will judge this nation severely for electing this liar. So just continue to spout your excuses for Obama&apos;s dark past, lies, and associations and socialism, and vote your conscious if you have one, we on the other hand will do everything we can to get the word out, and guess what, God is on our side.
+3 ...
written by angela, October 10, 2008

What&apos;s this about Hillary really winning Texas?
+0 BAR Questions
written by SLF, October 10, 2008

Hi Everyone,
If an atty on here can answer this question, or anyone who knows-- my daughter is an attorney, and I know when she applied to law school and to the BAR she had to supply so much information, about family and friends--basically anything and everything she had ever done. She had to give the names of numerous people who then had to fill out in-depth reference forms and interviews about my daughter. I would be interested to see Obama&apos;s BAR applications! Who were his&quot;references&quot;and what came out in his BAR application. Someone is surely looking into all of this. This process is a snake slithering through our country and someone needs to cut it&apos;s head off. I&apos;m not talking about any type of physical altercation, so don&apos;t get me wrong! I&apos;m talking about everything that is happening, the process that is going on. Someone needs to bring this thing before the American people, and expose Obama and his cohorts. Someone somewhere has actual experience with this guy-- information that could expose him. I think it&apos;s time that we quit worrying about being politically correct! Pollitical correctness is just another word for censorship of thoughts and the freedom of speech and expression! I feel like I&apos;m watching a freight train wrecking and can&apos;t do anything about it-- or like watching 9/11 happen all over again and knowing we are under an attack of the most destructive kind, and there is no way to stop it.

+1 Obama lies again
written by Josee, October 10, 2008

Obama&apos;s campaign website states:

Fact: Barack was never an ACORN trainer and never worked for ACORN in any other capacity.

Is that really a FACT, or just another lie? Let&apos;s take a look at a quote from a 2004 article - Case Study: Chicago- The Barack Obama Campaign - written Toni Foulkes, a Chicago ACORN Leader, which was published in the journal Social Policy. Did we mention that Social Policy recently pulled this particular article from their website, while leaving links to all articles up?

&quot;Obama took the case, known as ACORN vs. Edgar (the name of the Republican governor at the time) and we won. Obama then went on to run a voter registration project with Project VOTE in 1992 that made it possible for Carol Moseley Braun to win the Senate that year. Project VOTE delivered 50,000 newly registered voters in that campaign (ACORN delivered about 5,000 of them).

Since then, we have invited Obama to our leadership training sessions to run the session on power every year, and, as a result, many of our newly developing leaders got to know him before he ever ran for office. Thus it was natural for many of us to be active volunteers in his first campaign for STate Senate and then his failed bid for U.S. Congress in 1996. By the time he ran for U.S. Senate, we were old friends.&quot;

Not only does Foulkes boast of Obama&apos;s ACORN leadership training, but also makes it clear that Obama&apos;s post-law school organizing of&quot;Project VOTE&quot;in 1992 was undertaken in direct partnership with ACORN. The tie between Project VOTE and ACORN is also something that Obama and others have attempted to disprove in recent weeks as ACORN has come under fire for allegations of voter registration fraud.

As recently as March 2008, the Los Angeles Times also made reference to Barack Obama&apos;s involvement with ACORN:

&quot;At the time, Talbot worked at the social action group ACORN and initially considered Obama a competitor. But she became so impressed with his work that she invited him to help train her staff.&quot;(LA Times, March 2, 200

All this information was easily pulled up with minimal time investment. It took less than thirty minutes to find, despite attempts by some to bury the truth. If I could find this with little effort, imagine what could be dug up with a serious, in-depth investigation. Scary, isn&apos;t it?

Nevertheless, Barack Obama&apos;s campaign website continues to lie and deny the truth about his involvement and association with ACORN. No matter how many times you say it, it does not make it true. The facts do not lie, Senator Obama. It&apos;s time to come clean and tell the truth, and it&apos;s time for the American people to demand it.


+1 ...
written by Josee, October 10, 2008

Obama is bought and is buying prime time slots with his buddies for a half hour supposed Ross Perot style presnetation with the major news networks.

I&apos;ll bet my house he&apos;ll try to pull another Philadelphia speech to get teh media people to say how great he is and how his connection to Ayers and ACORN are&quot;dstractions&quot;and a&quot;smear campaign.&quot;

Or maybe he&apos;ll try to explain his birth certificate away realizing the impending lawsuit?
+0 More on ACORN
written by Josee, October 10, 2008

Investors Business Daily asks what Obama knows about the epidemic of voter fraud in ACORN, and it’s not an unfair question. Not only has he publicly endorsed ACORN, Obama has paid them at least $800,000 for their voter fraud services, an amount that he didn’t immediately disclose until pressed. ACORN has responded in kind, with their voter-registration efforts that have resulted in criminal investigations in more than a dozen states:

For starters, Obama paid ACORN, which has endorsed him for president, $800,000 to register new voters, payments his campaign failed to accurately report. They were disguised in his FEC disclosure as payments to a front group called Citizen Services Inc. for&quot;advance work.&quot;

What’s more, Obama worked as executive director of ACORN’s voter-registration arm, Project Vote, in 1992. Joined by two other community organizers on Chicago’s South Side, Obama conducted the voter-registration drive that helped elect Carol Moseley-Braun to the Senate that year.

The next year, 1993, Obama joined the civil-rights law firm Davis Miner Barnhill&amp;Galland, where he sued the state of Illinois on behalf of ACORN to implement the federal&quot;Motor Voter&quot;law, which the GOP governor at the time refused to do. Then-Gov. Jim Edgar argued, presciently, that the Clinton law would invite voter fraud.

Obama downplays his ties to ACORN, and his campaign denies coordinating with ACORN to register voters.

For a man with a short track record, Barack Obama spends a lot of time disassociating himself from political partners. He spent most of the campaign misrepresenting his years-long working relationship with William Ayers, the unrepentant domestic terrorist of the Weather Underground and a man who still wants the overthrow of the capitalist economic system in the US. Now he wants to hide his work over two decades with an organization that should be looking at the business end of a federal RICO prosecution.
+0 Steph3, Lowly rated comment [Show]
and the ACORN kicker to boot!
written by Josee, October 10, 2008

08 ACORN voter fraud is so flagrant, that even ABC News has to report what Obama&apos;s old associates are up to, and when Obama denies this relationship, or calls it a distraction, which he will, remember this quote:

&quot;I’ve been fighting alongside ACORN on issues you care about my entire career. Even before I was an elected official, when I ran Project Vote voter registration drive in Illinois, ACORN was smack dab in the middle of it, and we appreciate your work.&quot;-- Barack Obama, Speech to ACORN, November 2007

+0 ...
written by Paige, October 10, 2008

Obama forgot about this speech.

 http://my.barackobama.com/page/community/post/samgrahamfelsen... 

Can anyone get a copy of his registration at the school in Jakarta? Word has it that he was registered as Barry Soetoro, registered as Indonesian, and religion was listed as Islam.
+0 ...
written by Josee, October 10, 2008

Beyond a reasonable doubt -- Obama is a socialist -- at best!

In 1995, Obama, as part of his first run for the Illinois State Senate, began seeking the endorsement of the New Party. The New Party&apos;s objective was to push forth the socialist principles of the Democratic Socialists of America (DSA), that claimed Obama as a member, by focusing on winnable elections at a local level and spreading the Socialist movement upwards.

Obama had been running in a four way primary against his former boss, Senator Alice Palmer, an executive board member of the U.S. Peace Council, which the FBI identified as a communist front group, and an affiliate of the World Peace Council, a Soviet front group.

The New Party required candidates who received the endorsement sign a pledge of support for the party. Obama signed that pledge, choosing to support a party that was, in effect, a front group for communists. The July issue of the New Ground noted that 15% of the New Party consisted of DSA members and a good number of members of the Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism, a democratic socialist group in the United States which originated in 1991 as the Committees of Correspondence, a moderate, dissenting wing of the Communist Party USA.

When allegations surfaced early this summer of the New Party&apos;s endorsement of Obama, the Obama campaign along with the remnants of the New Party and Democratic Socialists of America claimed that Obama was never a member of either organization. The DSA and New Party then systematically attempted to cover up any ties between Obama and the Socialist Organizations. However, it now appears that Barack Obama was indeed a certified and acknowledged member of the DSA&apos;s New Party.

On Tuesday, John Hinderaker of the PowerLine blog discovered a web page that had been scrubbed from the New Party&apos;s website. The web page which was published in October 1996, was an internet newsletter update on that years congressional races. Although the web page was deleted from the New Party&apos;s website, the non-profit Internet Archive Organization had archived the page.

GOTO http://www.theobamafile.com/ObamaLatest.htm and scroll a little down for it (sorry, my firewall does not alllow for me to transfer images).

So the New Party claimed Obama as a member as of 1996. Progressive Populist magazine agreed in this editorial:


New Party members and supported candidates won 16 of 23 races, including an at-large race for the Little Rock, Ark., City Council, a seat on the county board for Little Rock and the school board for Prince George&apos;s County, Md. Chicago is sending the first New Party member to Congress, as Danny Davis, who ran as a Democrat, won an overwhelming 85% victory. New Party member Barack Obama was uncontested for a State Senate seat from Chicago.


Barack Obama chose to affiliate himself with this band of quasi-communists. As the nation moves closer to the election, it is clear that Obama chose to affiliate with assorted anti-American radicals. Machiavelli once noted that we can know a leader by the people he surrounds himself with. What does it say about Barack Obama, that he chooses to surround himself with people committed to overthrowing the United States and capitalism?Sorry for blogging all of this, but I am FIRED UP!

WAKE UP AMERICA!

+2 ...
written by Ken Trainer, October 10, 2008

Hillary won the popular vote in Texas but they gave more delegates to Obama. Well he got more delegates because of voter fraud in the caucuses in Texas.

Obama is a marxist communist. All this voter fraud is simple communist corruption. All this is to be expected from Obama. His mother was also communist. His mother hated America. Obama hates the white american establishment. Black Liberation Theology is all about a black god and a black jesus who hate white people and want all white people dead. Obama is an Islamic infiltrator trying to take over America. He is backed up by big Islamic oil money. These are super dangerous people who care nothing about your life and only care about their power. they want an entire world of Islam and death to all other religions and people. This is pure coup d&apos;etat of America. Very little time left to save America. Obama wants financial crises so he can declare martial law and take over as a dictator and dump our constitution. This is incredibly important.
+6 ...
written by Ken Trainer, October 10, 2008

I did some editing of the above proposed email. here is my result for comments.


Dear Fellow American:

Barack Obama refuses to show a birth certificate to a Federal judge to prove he is a natural born citizen of the USA and thereby qualified to run for the Presidency.

 http://www.obamacrimes.com 

 http://www.obamacrimes.com/index.php/component/content/articl... 


Barack Obama and the Democratic Party are being sued in federal court by a lifelong Democrat for refusing to provide any real evidence of where or when Obama was born.

All that Obama would have had to do to prove his qualifications, is to produce a copy of his certified, original birth certificate. Yet, unbelievably, Obama and the Democratic National Committee are manipulating our legal system to block or delay every attempt to verify Obama&apos;s basic qualification to run for President.

There seems to be no other reason to refuse to show a birth certificate then the fact that Obama is not a citizen of the United States.

Obama has also resorted to posting a forged image of a certificate of birth on the Internet in a blatant attempt to fool the American public into thinking that he is a natural-born US citizen.

Below is a link to the lawsuit that was filed. This is not some wild conspiracy or an effort to smear a Presidential candidate. This is real. This is serious. This is happening as you read this letter.

Our country is headed for a Constitutional crisis if nothing is done to prevent it. That&apos;s why I&apos;m asking you, on behalf of Americans everywhere, to make your voice heard and make your vote count, that we will never allow anyone to run for President who subverts our country&apos;s Constitution and who violates our laws and our trust.

Please read the lawsuit, and add your name below, to a fast-growing list of others like you who desire to preserve our Nation.

 http://www.rallycongress.com/constitutional-qualification/124... 

+6 No fear.
written by BlueWater1949, October 10, 2008

As I have said before, Obama will never be our president - call me a wacko, but I don&apos;t have a single bone in my body that believes that God will let this happen. Corsi, Hannity and Berg are assigned to the case! Obama he will be lucky to avoid prison. Have no fear!
+1 BlueWater1949
written by Tolstoy, October 10, 2008

God isn&apos;t registered to vote.
-1 Tolstoy
written by Alexander, October 10, 2008

God isn&apos;t registered to vote? Sounds like ACORN needs to see him and get him registered 20 times ...stay classy Obama.
-1 Barack = Blessed
written by james, October 10, 2008

The Republicans are having a problem with using Barack Obama&apos;s middle name. Mr. Obama&apos;s grandmother (Sarah Onyango Obama), says his first name Barack is translated in Arablic as&quot;blessed&quot;.

Interesting.....

&quot;Mr Onyango, who died in 1975 at the age of 105, toyed with Christianity, and briefly changed his name to Johnson – would Barack Hussein Obama be more, or less electable as “Barry Johnson”? He rejected Christianity later as “foolish sentiment” and converted to Islam. Although the family still takes Arabic names (Barack means blessed), their faith is so lightly worn as to be invisible.&quot;

See the article at (http://www.timesonline.co.uk/t...902476.ece)
-1 Tolstoy
written by BlueWater1949, October 10, 2008

Mock me now - apologize later. I won&apos;t rub it in.


-1 Podcast of Berg interview in Toledo
written by BlueWater1949, October 10, 2008

 http://www.wspd.com/pages/brianstop10.html 
+0 The Enemy Within!
written by Steve , October 10, 2008

J Hanson,

If true, all the things you say are exactly what I fear with this man!! He is a fake and a phoney!! You can be a great speaker and dupe everyone to think you come with&quot;change&quot;but it is all an act!! It is obvious that Barack Obama, Barry Soetoro, or whatever his name is, spreads blatent lies like wildfire.. He is a very dangerous man and hopefully the american people see through this communist madman... He is tied to Acorn, voter fraud, homegrown terrorists, and I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if he has something or part to do with this failing economy. I wouldn&apos;t doubt he is disguised as a christian when in reality he is actually a extreme Islamic fascist!!! Wkae up people are country is under attack from within!!

I commend Philip Berg for doing what he is doing and everyone please don&apos;t give up the hard fight!!
+0 Honest answers only
written by Kenny, October 10, 2008

I have been praying and hoping that something would cause Obama to tank in this election but as the days go by I am not seeing anything that will stop him. Even with the investigation into ACORN doesn&apos;t seem to affect the people when it comes to this man. What is the drawing power of this man?? You have Louis calling him the Messiah and I honestly believe people are accepting him just as that. It really makes me sick. I was also praying that Mr. Berg&apos;s case would end his bid for President but I don&apos;t see that happening as well because Obama has too many friends that are playing games with peoples lives. I will never, ever vote for this man because I think he is dangerous to our country.
+4 Dont give up!!
written by Steve, October 10, 2008

Kenny, please don&apos;t give up!! You can&apos;t have a defeatest attitude or you will let them win! I feel in my heart that in the end, even if he is elected, he will not be our sitting president!! I still think an October surprise about this man is coming and I wouldnt doubt if the Clintons are involved.. So don&apos;t give up hope!

Btw, is it me or does anyone else ever see hate in Obama&apos;s eyes when he speaks at rallys?? I think there is a load of hate and evil in that man!!
+1 ...
written by Steve, October 10, 2008

Here is the podcast Peter Boyles did on KHOW in Denver yesterday. Interview with Berg.

 http://a1135.g.akamai.net/f/11...plete_Pete 
+0 ...
written by Ken Trainer, October 10, 2008

 http://archive.patriotpost.us/...oonid=1627 

this one is good with obama as the squirrel and the acorns.
+0 ...
written by Ken T, October 10, 2008

Kenney

if you get the list of emails I posted a couple of time and send a million copies. you will feel better.

 http://rumormillnews.com/MEDIA_EMAIL_ADDRESSES.htm 

if you need ideas on what to email out you can get all kinds of ideas at www.blog.pumapac.org they are all set up to help all members do active things to defeat obama.

Do not just sit there do something. convince another voter to vote against obama and that person might do the same and it grows fast.

email the msm and get them to start reporting. support fox on their efforts to keep pounding on obama. etc. lots of things to do. just do not sit there doing nothing.

Ken
+0 ...
written by Ken T, October 10, 2008

and I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if he has something or part to do with this failing economy.

Of course he does. As a community organizer he was the TEACHER to all the people on how to&quot;get in their face&quot;or have audacity and force the banks to make bad loans to the poor black people. the banks complained they would get into trouble if they made the loans. Obama forced the bad loans down the throats of the white peoples banks. He started this a very long time ago and of course once it got off the ground it kept growing. Obama now benefits as people turn to him. He wants total collapse of the economy. then he moves in as the riots start and declared martial law and suspends the constitution.

His friends who promoted him like Ayers and Alinsky have studied how to take power and this is all been planned out for decades. It has been worked on in more secrecy but now we see it playing out in front of our eyes. This is super dangerous. They will stop at nothing to gain power. Lies are like nothing. killing people is nothing. power is everything to these people.

They never have plans for change because the real plan for change is to make american an islamic country under communism. with them in total control.
+0 How Long the Wait?
written by Red, October 10, 2008

When does the Judge HAVE to make a ruling? I know that there are time limits involved. Is it 10/24/08? There are so many petitions and rebuttals and extra people wanting to be a part of this sui juris, it&apos;s getting ridiculous.

Can someone from the Berg Office please update us on what timetable we are looking at?

Thanks!
+0 Motion to stop Obama fundraising after Oct 15
written by Old Atlantic, October 10, 2008

If Obama fails to turn over discovery materials, a motion should be made for him to stop raising money for his campaign. If the judge declares for plaintiff, then part of the order should be Obama stops fundraising, stops spending, and starts repaying. This is in addition to being taken off ballots.

If this comes late in the process, money could be used on advertising that Obama is not eligible or signs at polling places that Obama is not eligible.
+1 At first I thought you were kidding . . ., Lowly rated comment [Show]
Does Anybody
written by James, October 10, 2008

Does anyone on this board have the contact numbers for people who work for Oreilly, Hannity or Greta. If they do, please post them so people can start calling these parties&apos;subordinates and try to convince them to report on this pending issue.
What are the contact numbers for the following parties (Actually get you live people)
Hannity
Greta
Oreilly

Please Post.
+0 To All
written by Brad Meador, October 10, 2008

I have a question that I probably have asked somewhere else on this board but it just keeps bugging me.

Now, I and all you on here and many other Americans that have NOT seen this site or know anything about this lawsuit know Obama is a liar. However, despite that, why is he pulling away in the polls? How can anybody believe his talk when all he does is lie, lie, lie; not only him but his whole campaign.
+0 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

I then asked about the Certificate number and the answer was,&quot;It starts with 151, then the year, then the sequence&quot;. - So why the black bar?

To hide the fact that the Obama was not born in Hawaii in 1961. Plus, the genius who made the forgery, made the sequence number on Obama&apos;s bogus COLB way too high for the month of June -- one of the things I brought out.
+0 HAWAII LAW GRANTS BIRTH CERTIFICATES TO THOSE NOT BORN IN HAWAII
written by NewGuy, October 10, 2008

In Mr. Berg&apos;s next brief, it might be helpful to explicitly include the information that Mike C mentioned in another comment that there is a Hawaii law which authorizes birth certificates to be issued for those who were born out of the state (or out of the country). (The L1982 at the end of this may indicate that this statute was passed or amended in 1982, so if that is the case the question would be what was the law or the policy in effect prior to that time.) This is a killer argument against all those who assume that if Obama has a&quot;certificate of live birth&quot;from Hawaii that that proves he was born in Hawaii. Oh well, when BHO is elected president, his big brother Orwellian regime will rewrite history to make it true because BHO&apos;s&quot;Newspeak&quot;will&quot;make lies sound truthful and murder respectable&quot;as Orwell said.

 http://www.capitol.hawaii.gov/hrscurrent/Vol06_Ch0321-0344/HR... 

[§338-17.8] Certificates for children born out of State. (a) Upon application of an adult or the legal parents of a minor child, the director of health shall issue a birth certificate for such adult or minor, provided that proof has been submitted to the director of health that the legal parents of such individual while living without the Territory or State of Hawaii had declared the Territory or State of Hawaii as their legal residence for at least one year immediately preceding the birth or adoption of such child.

(b) Proof of legal residency shall be submitted to the director of health in any manner that the director shall deem appropriate. The director of health may also adopt any rules pursuant to chapter 91 that he or she may deem necessary or proper to prevent fraudulent applications for birth certificates and to require any further information or proof of events necessary for completion of a birth certificate.

(c) The fee for each application for registration shall be established by rule adopted pursuant to chapter 91. [L 1982, c 182, §1]

Thanks for all that Mr. Berg is doing!!
+0 ..., Lowly rated comment [Show]
...
written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

I wonder if Mr. Berg could supeona the Congressman to testify.
According to Martin’s post, U.S. Congressman Eni Faleomavaega, an outspoken critic of Indonesia’s oppression of Papua and a Barack Obama supporter (and Superdelegate), visited Indonesia in July 2007, with the purpose of “acquiring any and all documentation or photographs of a young Barry Soetoro.” Martin claims that a substantial sum of money was exchanged. He writes:

The challenge of course was securing Indonesian government records potentially damaging to Barack Obama’s candidacy for the US presidency as well as other records pertaining to a young Barry Soetoro and his family wouldn’t be so easy to acquire and secure..
+1 The Rise and Fall of the Third Reich by William L Shirer
written by Michelle, October 10, 2008

Years ago when I was 12 I read this book because I was just trying to understand how a person like Hitler could become the Chancellor of Germany. We saw him giving speeches on documentaries on TV. With hindsight to an American he just looked like a lunatic but he had the power to sway the people of Germany with his rhetoric and style and really weird symbols and much etc. repreresenting Tueton power and various omens chants hand gestures. He was a big believer in symbols. I remember him saying all you had to do was start with one big lie and all the rest would easily follow. Why does this case remind me so much of how the Nazi&apos;s were able to steal power. If I remember correctly Hitler never won a public office. He was only put near power so that they could&quot;control&quot;him, until he seized power by then it was too late. Until I hear different I assume our Constitution works for all of us. President on down forever.
+0 Who is paying you to do this?, Lowly rated comment [Show]
...
written by steph3, October 10, 2008

No, Tolstoy, or perhaps I should call you Karl as in Marx, but He is bigger than any evil behind Barry, aka Barrack, aka, the downfall of America. He is still in charge, and going back to 1976 the pollsters have been wrong every time, and Christians and Jews who are concerned about America and Israel have risen up and voted for the one who was meant to be in office despite your liberal marxist views and support of evil and deceit. He is still in charge no matter what you think. We have a great God and He loves this country.
+2 Candidates and Their Eligibility To Appear On The Ballot
written by Jeff Wahlen, October 10, 2008

Who ultimately determines the eligibility of each presidential candidate? The State of Florida responded with the following:

Dear Mr. Wahlen:

The Florida Department of State does not have investigative or enforcement authority to ensure that major parties’ Presidential candidates are properly qualified to be President of the United States. The U.S. Constitution establishes the qualifying requirements for President. Under Florida law, the way a major party’s candidate is placed on the ballot is that the state executive committee of each political party submits its slate of presidential electors for its candidate before September 1st of each presidential election year; then, by law, the names of the actual candidates (not the slate of presidential electors) for President and Vice-President for whom the presidential electors will vote if elected are printed on the ballot. Those candidates are not required to provide any documents to the State that they meet the qualifications for office.

Any challenge to the qualifications of a U.S. Presidential candidate would be appropriate in a court of competent jurisdiction (such as that occurring in Pennsylvania). The Department of Justice in Washington, D.C., may also be a resource for information or inquiry on this matter. Contact information for the Department of Justice is: \n This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it&apos;&gt;AskDOJ@usdoj.govThis e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it .; phone: 202-514-2000; and U.S. Department of Justice, 950 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW. Washington, DC 20530-0001.



Sincerely,



Gary J. Holland

Assistant General Counsel

Florida Department of State

R.A. Gray Building, 500 S. Bronough Street

Tallahassee, FL 32399-0250


Note: This response is provided for reference only and does not constitute a formal legal opinion or representation from the Department of State or the Division of Elections. As applied to a particular set of facts or circumstances, interested parties should refer to the Florida Statutes and applicable case law, and/or consult an attorney to represent their interests before drawing any legal conclusions or relying upon the information provided.
Also, Florida has a very broad public records law. Written communications to or from state officials regarding state business constitute public records and are available to the public and media upon request unless the information is subject to a specific statutory exemption. Therefore, this email and any that you sent that generated this response may be subject to public disclosure.


Topic: Candidate Qualifying


Questions or Comments: It is the responsibility of each Secretary of State to determine the eligibility of each candidate which appears on that state ballot. I&apos;ve got a call into ----- office in Tallahassee asking&quot;what criteria did Florida use which determined that Barry Obama was a natural born citizen of the United States?&quot;The challenge going on up in Pennsylvania addressing that very issue could use some discovery from Florida if Barry&apos;s natural born citizenship is authentic and proven by the Sec of State in Tallahassee. So, please tell me your undeniable proof.

 http://obamacrimes.com/ 

This&quot;delaying discovery until after the elections&quot;is rather elusive and irresponsible, don&apos;t you agree? Please advise what convinced the State of Florida of each candidate&apos;s eligibility to qualify to appear on the ballot?

Jeff Wahlen

Orlando Florida


+2 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

cat callahan,

Put on your tin foil hat and go back to the Daily KOS you troll.
+0 Let your voice be heard
written by To All, October 10, 2008

Please help Mr. Berg get the word out.

 http://www.gop.com/connect/contactus.htm 

This link provides contacts to the Republican National Committee.

Send professional emails/letters/telephone calls to them demanding action. Wake them up!


+0 New Guy&amp;Hawaii law
written by Breshloch, October 10, 2008

New Guy:
Check out that quote - at the end:
(c) The fee for each application for registration shall be established by rule adopted pursuant to chapter 91. [L 1982, c 182, §1]

The law you&apos;re referencing was passed in 1982. Berg has consistently said that the law in effect at the time the particular events occurred is controlling. Therefore, Berg is NOT basing his complaint on that law - and he doesn&apos;t cite that law in his papers.
+1 ...
written by WB, October 10, 2008

Investigations into Obama&apos;s connections to ACORN and now Rezko chirping like a bird must be keeping Obama&apos;s lawyers very busy. You wonder how much energy they will have to defend him on this case when the other two more serious allegations could put him into jail.

Obama should just avoid embarrassment and his party&apos;s destruction by taking himself off the ballet.
+2 steph3
written by Peter, October 10, 2008

Tolstoy (Leo of War and Peace etc.) was very much like the Obama liberal of today. Lots of money, but somehow appeals to people who feel disenfranchised.

Our Tolstoy has probably chosen his handle well; a socialist at heart no doubt.
+1 ...
written by Bob, October 10, 2008

To BreslocH:
Reading that statute -Upon application of an adult --the director of health shall issue a birth certificate for such adult---provided that proof has been submitted to the director of health that the legal parents of such individual while living without the Territory or State of Hawaii had declared the Territory or State of Hawaii as their legal residence for at least one year immediately preceding the birth or adoption of such child.

It makes no mention of when the birth took place. So, technically someone born in 1961 could walk in today and get a BC provided they had the right documentation. Could they have done this prior to 1982 ? I don&apos;t know. The 1982 doesn&apos;t indicate that people born prior to that year are not eligible for a certif. It just indicates when this statute was passed
+1 Kilgore
written by Scalia, October 10, 2008

Hello, Kilgore!

Thank you for your observations, but I must disagree with your analysis. I initially thought this lawsuit was misguided due to a misreading of our citizenship laws. I failed to realize that the&apos;86 amendment was not retroactive.

If Obama was born outside of the United States, he is *not* a U.S. citizen and he is not qualified to serve as president, if elected. You insist we should ignore the law and allow him to be president anyway. As justification for that, you cite the will of the people. What if the&quot;will of the people&quot;is to elect Arnold Schwarzenegger as president? How about the head of the U.N.? You cannot ignore our laws because you don&apos;t like them. If Congress decides to change the law, that&apos;s fine. They will be accountable to the people who elect them and if the people go along, that&apos;s representative government. Once you allow a&quot;ignore the laws you don&apos;t like&quot;mentality, you get anarchy.

If this election is close, you&apos;ll only have half, or perhaps less than half of the electorate&quot;outraged&quot;over legal technicalities. I would say there would be just as much outrage over a man who refused to settle the matter by providing his birth certificate. I have my birth certificate and would not hesitate to give it to the judge if there were ever a question of my citizenship. If he&apos;s so confident his birth certificate is genuine, he would not hesitate to turn it over. If his certificate is phony, then his character is immediately suspect. Did he knowingly withhold relevant information about his citizenship? I have no doubt most Americans would be upset at a man who ran for an office he knew he wasn&apos;t qualified to hold.
+1 RE-Kilgore
written by ICEMAN, October 10, 2008

To many people like me it would not be his status, but rather his deception and fraud of a document. If he had been open from the get go you assumption may have been correct. But after 8 years of lies and deception i think America is looking for truth above all else. Further wouldent even one lie ruin his image as the Change we need.
+1 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Killgore wrote:
As long as we are parsing every jot and tittle of the US Constitution, It is interesting to note that, while the Constitution lists qualifications for President, it does not list qualifications for a presidential candidate, or for a president-elect. It appears that, as long as Obama could gain natural-born citizenship by Inauguration Day, there would be no constitutional crisis at all.

When the courts (especially the Supreme Court) interpret the constitution, they are supposed to interpret it in accordance with what the framers had in mind. It would be totally ludicrous to think that they would have desired to allow a non-natural born citizen to run for the presidency and then be disqualified. Obviously, their intention was to not allow this to happen.

Unfortunately, as wise as the framers were, they could not foresee everything and did not foresee the current situation. They were, however, wise enough to set up the court system to be able to deal with this and the amendment procedure to prevent a re-occurrence in the future.

The courts, particularly the Supreme Court in its role of interpreting the constitution definitely have the jurisdiction in the instant case.
+1 ..., Lowly rated comment [Show]
...
written by Merriweather, October 10, 2008

Is the judge planning to respond sometime this year? Sheesh.
-1 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Alex,

In case you don&apos;t know it (apparently you don&apos;t) U.S. District Court for Northern CA in the ruling dismissing a similar case against McCain, stated in the opinion that McCain met the requirements of being natural born.

Until some higher court makes overrules that decision, or a higher court comes to a different conclusion, that case will be the law.
+1 ...
written by Val in MA, October 10, 2008

Kilgore,

I beg to differ with your well written opinion. You seem to inject this lawsuit has no merit and that it should be dismissed. Suppose you are right and then answer this: why hasn’t judge thrown this case out as frivolous from its very inception if he or she thought there was no merit to it at all?

American people deserve to know the truth and Mr. Obama has been very good at hiding it. Mr. Obama always preaches about transparency in his “will be” administration, but how can we trust him if we don’t even know who he really is? How can we elect him our president if we know nothing or so very little about him? Why doesn’t he come clean in regards to his associations with individuals like Ayers, Wright, Rezko, Farakhan, etc? Don’t you want to know the truth? Never in American history had we had a President who was at least somehow associated with unrepeated terrorists or had at least some connections to such high profile criminals as Obama does. Doesn’t it bother you as an American citizen? And I don’t buy your argument that Americans don’t care about our next president’s character – we always have and we always will. We want our next President to be straightforward with us, free from all his dark secrets. We just want to know simple truth.

And that’s basically what Atty. Berg is looking for in this lawsuit – proof that Obama is qualified to serve as our next President. If Obama didn’t have anything to hide, why is it then it’s so difficult for him to produce the requested documents? Obama’s actions towards this lawsuit alone make him a suspect in my mind.

Lastly, I believe Berg’s lawsuit has standing in the court of law and that the court should order the defendants to produce the requested documents. This will serve our nation’s people well and Obama himself if he’s got nothing to hid.

+2 Alex
written by Peter, October 10, 2008

adding to PRD&apos;s response, this is NOT being&quot;pursued by the Republican community.&quot;Attorney Berg is a Democrat.

Actually, I wish the Republicans WOULD pursue this because it is a very real concern, and every American; Republican or Democrat should be outraged.
+2 Alex
written by Scalia, October 10, 2008

Alex, what are you talking about? Phil Berg is a DEMOCRAT. This isn&apos;t a Republican issue. McCain is not responsible for this lawsuit.
+1 Your Party??
written by Terry136, October 10, 2008

Alex,
You might want to gert a few of your facts straight. You mentioned the Republicans, and&quot;your party&quot;. F.Y.I. the Plaintiff in this case is a life-long Democrat. The judge hearing the case is a Democrat, and a Clinton appointee. This isn&apos;t about Democrats or Republicans, it&apos;s about the US Constitution. Now, what were you saying about the Republicans?

You apparently missed the 2000 election where McCain&apos;s citizenship was established once and for all. Google it and find out what happened. I don&apos;t want you to take my word for it.

&quot;It shows extremely poorly on both your character and intelligence if the republican community pursues this,&quot;


It shows extremely poor patriotism for any American that DOESN&apos;T pursue this. What American would want an illegal alien to be President?
+4 ...
written by Paige, October 10, 2008

Judging by the fact that it&apos;s 2:30 in the afternoon here on the East Coast, I&apos;m guessing we&apos;re not going to hear anything today.

I&apos;m starting to get the sinking feeling we won&apos;t get a ruling before the Nov. 4th election.
+0 Roof Doctor
written by ICEMAN, October 10, 2008

The case against McCain was simple, McCain showed the documents. Obama has not. Candidates have a legal right to challenge a voters eligibility, and thus voters have the right to challenge the Candidates eligibility. I was a Candidate for US Congress and produced any and all documents I was asked to. I don’t understand what obama is thinking. If this is true it will destroy the Democratic party
+1 Dr. Feel Good
written by Charles Rich, October 10, 2008

As a Canadian viewing this entire American election fiasco, my thoughts about why the Democratic Party deliberately torpedoed Hillary Clinton in favour of Barack Obama is Obama has this allure, which is equivalent to a Dr. Feel Good! A Dr. Feel Good is a nickname for any doctor that is known to easily prescribe narcotics to the famous and wealthy. But with Barack Obama the Democratic Party deliberately backed Obama over Clinton because they felt Obama had this kind of psychological allure to the ordinary person to be seen as a Dr. Feel Good for the nation! And they were right, for some unfathomable reason Americans became hooked to Obama like a narcotic. I as an outside observer can’t understand the rationale of people who have injected Obama’s campaign in their veins and who’ve been hooked onto the insipid slogan ‘Change You Can Believe In’ it’s meaningless, unless you’re a junkie.

It’s no different than people who get high and think they’re talking about something profound but if you video tape this conversation of drugged out people and then play it back to them when they’re sober, they realize how foolish they sound! Unfortunately all these Obama junkies need to get sober to realize how completely idiotic they sound by having all these deep conversations of what ‘Change’ means! It’s meaningless; it’s watching like a group of people high on marijuana talking about objects that they can hold and touch, they look ridiculous! Somebody high on marijuana can be talking about how a particular object feels and its curves and he/she can look through it and see life in a different perspective when all along this person was just holding a glass ashtray!

Barack Obama is a like a pet rock, he’s nothing—he’s just a rock in your hand unless you’re an Obama junkie then you’re like someone high on drugs! Who feels and touches Obama, puts all their hopes into him and feels he’ll make all the things every single politician did wrong for America and suddenly reverse it. As a sober outsider, I don’t see any credibility in Barack Obama that shows he’ll be good for Americans! I judge a person by his/her’s character first and then secondly by the people he/she associates with. Obamamites (people who are hooked on Obama as a Dr. Feel Good) have either willingly turned a blind eye to the people Obama has a friends or as a junkie, they vainly attempt to justify why who their Dr. Feel Good associates with and say it’s meaningless. But to me, all I’ve seen are 1960’s extremist radicals, black extremists (“hate the white man” crowd), not even mild Jew haters but ultra extreme Anti-Semites who have agendas to destroy Israel and all sorts of Muslims (from American who are not associated and are not funded by Saudi Arabia all they way to real Arabs from the Middle East who belong to well known Islamic terrorist groups).

And finally as a man of character, he has no real ‘Change’ agenda, he’s just another lying, cheating and self-serving politician! The proof being his questionable status of being born in the United States, his blatant obfuscation to delay justice in order to bring about a swift conclusion to his country of birth optimizes Obama’s genuine lack of character! Not only that but this answer to his country of birth could put at jeopardy America’s national election and even worse, America’s economy recovery! If Obama were never born in United States, all those Obamamites would suddenly get out of their stupor; anger would sweep the nation as well as even more uncertainty, which could make the stock market tank even further! All this is riding on Obama’s character but rather than tackle this question of his country of birth head on, Obama has chosen to hide behind a legal team in order to prevent the truth from coming out—that shows he’s no leader for change, in fact he’s lying Uncle Tom!

+9 ...
written by captbruce, October 10, 2008

The riddle to ask the radio pundits.....
What do Arnold Schwarzenegger and Barackobama have in common?

Answer: Both are ineligible to be President of the United States according to Article II, Section 1 of the Constitution of the United States. Both are entitled to fully live the American dream, except for holding its highest office. As Berg pointed out, this requirement goes all the way back to the first Constitutional Convention.

The difference--Arnold accepts it. Barack hides it, and in the process has defrauded the DNC out of over $400M plus creating a Constitutional crisis? If he prevails, what else of the Constitution will he not defend as his Oath expressly states? What else is&quot;That One&quot;hiding? Not even Obama deserves a pass on the Constitution.

“My mom told me I was born in Hawaii&quot;tells us a lot in the context of this lawsuit. He knows. We have to stop the one who would steal the election through violation of the Constitution and the rampant voter fraud being reported.

My take on Newguy was this. He was pointing out was how easy it is to get a Certificate of Live Birth in Hawaii and that in no way does it document a natural born citizen. It is odd to produce a certificate with no signature from an attending physician, or any other official. I wish someone could produce a copy of Obama&apos;s birth record in Mombassa, Kenya. Then put the burden once again on Obama to prove that the Kenyan cert is invalid and the Hawaiian one is correct.

If Obama is thrown out, it will definitely be rough, but the reason our forefathers made us a democratic republic under the rule of law and not a pure democracy is to assure that our country is not ruled by the whims of a mob. THAT is worth preserving whatever the cost.


+2 ...
written by james, October 10, 2008

Mr. Walen (Orlando, Florida)
Is it possible to file a freedom of information act request to obtain the “Form of candidate oath” for all the candidates on the ballet?

If there is a copy of the oath, can a state court case be initiated to have all candidates verify their eligibility? Can those oaths be challenged in court to establish whether fraud was committed when they signed the oath?

From the Florida Statutes 99.021 Form of candidate oath, all candidates (including those for a federal office) should have submitted the oath.

The 2008 Florida Statutes
99.021 Form of candidate oath.--
(1)(a)1. Each candidate, whether a party candidate, a candidate with no party affiliation, or a write-in candidate, in order to qualify for nomination or election to any office other than a judicial office as defined in chapter 105 or a federal office, shall take and subscribe to an oath or affirmation in writing. A printed copy of the oath or affirmation shall be furnished to the candidate by the officer before whom such candidate seeks to qualify and shall be substantially in the following form:


State of Florida
County of_____
Before me, an officer authorized to administer oaths, personally appeared (please print name as you wish it to appear on the ballot) , to me well known, who, being sworn, says that he or she is a candidate for the office of _____; that he or she is a qualified elector of _____ County, Florida; that he or she is qualified under the Constitution and the laws of Florida to hold the office to which he or she desires to be nominated or elected; that he or she has taken the oath required by ss. 876.05-876.10, Florida Statutes; that he or she has qualified for no other public office in the state, the term of which office or any part thereof runs concurrent with that of the office he or she seeks; and that he or she has resigned from any office from which he or she is required to resign pursuant to s. 99.012, Florida Statutes.


+0 ...
written by Gail, October 10, 2008

This could have such a simple solution, Obama like Mc Cain have done in the past should simply show his birthcertificate that is all people want. Obama adds one more question to who he really is. Years of his life are totally deprived of information, even the texts of his essais during his Unversity years, what he really did while member of two boards the Annenberg and the Woods, etc etc. this is so unamerican. Transparency is a must for someone that wishes to be the President of the land.
Up to know I believe he is a natural US citizen but it is his actitude that is really disgusting.
One has to think in Saul Alinsky and his shady ways to take over and impose a socialist way of life on a democracy. One has to wonder, the more I wait for this birthcertificate the more troubled I am.
+0 OBAMA IS NOT ELIGIBLE
written by BettySueLA, October 10, 2008

The bottom line...What kind of a moron would vote for Obama? He won&apos;t produce a lousy BIRTH CERTIFICATE. This is not someone you trust with the biggest job in the WORLD. Period. If the creep has nothing to hide, then go show the BC. Since he refuses, he knows he has a problem. I pray to God this is resolved soon so we can get him out of the race. He didn&apos;t belong in this race in the first place. He committed fraud and stole Hillary&apos;s nomination. Now, he pays.
+3 ..., Lowly rated comment [Show]
Obama leads now and may win BECAUSE he is Hiding his INFO
written by ZerObama, October 10, 2008

If he was FORTHCOMING and it is true that he is not a Natural Born Citizen and has held citizenship of other countries he would not EVEN be in the race never mind almsot winning.
+1 ...
written by Me2, October 10, 2008

Kilgore, the birth certificate is just a part of the suit. Would you like to take a shot at the Indonesian and Kenya citizenship issues since that documentation is also part of the lawsuit?
+0 When will the judge actually DO something? And when will the MSM actually REPORT something?
written by PoliticalSleuth, October 10, 2008

This has been out there for so long, with NO coverage by the main stream media. It&apos;s been discouraging to me to see the very fiber of our constitution at risk with this mess. It&apos;s inconceivable that the Obamans felt they could slide this by. If indeed he IS a valid citizen and has a US birth certificate and citizenship documentation, then hey, why is it such a big deal for him to PRODUCE the necessary documentation?


+0 ...
written by james, October 10, 2008

Mr. Wahlen,

Complaints to Florida Department of Elections.

 http://election.dos.state.fl.us/complaints/index.shtml 

See the form&quot;Fraud in Candidate Petition Issues&quot;.....
&quot;Under section 97.012(15), Florida Statutes, the Division of Elections has authority to conduct preliminary investigations into any allegations of irregularities or fraud involving voter registration or voting, or candidate or issue petition activities. The Division shall then report its findings to the Office of Statewide Prosecution or to the State Attorney for the judicial circuit in which the alleged violation occurred for prosecution, where warranted.&quot;

The 2008 Florida Statutes
97.012(15) Conduct preliminary investigations into any irregularities or fraud involving voter registration, voting, candidate petition, or issue petition activities and report his or her findings to the statewide prosecutor or the state attorney for the judicial circuit in which the alleged violation occurred for prosecution, if warranted. The Department of State may prescribe by rule requirements for filing an elections-fraud complaint and for investigating any such complaint.

Link to the state of Florida Candidate Petition: http://election.dos.state.fl.u...SDE104.pdf 

It would seem to me that if there was a candidate petition filed to have Mr. Obama placed on the ballet, then it is within the Florida statute to be able to challenge the candidate petition.



+0 Kilgore&apos;s analysis
written by Brad, October 10, 2008

... and THAT&apos;S why this thing has to move before the election. As a society we have become such moral relativists that a lot of people will say exactly this: we don&apos;t care what&apos;s legal or constitutional or right, we just want our way.

The only parts of the Constitution most people care about is the 1st Amendment, at least the part that says they&apos;re allowed to spew whatever non-truths they care to, and the separation of church and state that says they don&apos;t have to witness other people&apos;s Christianity. (Yeah, I know the second one isn&apos;t even in there. But they think it is...)

The founding founders must be spinning in their graves.
+0 Hello, Kilgore
written by Terry136, October 10, 2008

Congress can&apos;t&quot;pass a law retroactively granting Obama natural-born citizenship&quot;. To do that, would require a Constitutional Amendment. All Constitutional Amendments have to be ratified by 3/4 of the states within a 7 year period. As you can see, there&apos;s NO WAY an Amendment could be ratified in time to help Obama at all.

Then, there&apos;s still the issue of dual / multiple citizenship. According to Article 3, Section 1 of the Constitution the Commander-In-Chief can have allegiance to only ONE country, and that country shall be the US. Dual / multiple citizenship would knock Obama out of the race even if the&quot;natural born&quot;thing didn&apos;t knock him out of the race.

Obama has lost this legal battle. He just won&apos;t admit it.
+0 ...
written by Jeff, October 10, 2008

Mr. Berg needs to setup a Facebook page for this issue - it would be a great way to spread the facts. I know that anyone could do this, but from him it would be much more credible.
+1 ...
written by Patrick, October 10, 2008

Great idea, Daniel! That would be incredible! I hope Berg thought of that. Does anyone know if Berg would question the Congressman if this case moves forward?
_______________________________________________

written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

I wonder if Mr. Berg could supeona the Congressman to testify.
According to Martin’s post, U.S. Congressman Eni Faleomavaega, an outspoken critic of Indonesia’s oppression of Papua and a Barack Obama supporter (and Superdelegate), visited Indonesia in July 2007, with the purpose of “acquiring any and all documentation or photographs of a young Barry Soetoro.” Martin claims that a substantial sum of money was exchanged. He writes:

The challenge of course was securing Indonesian government records potentially damaging to Barack Obama’s candidacy for the US presidency as well as other records pertaining to a young Barry Soetoro and his family wouldn’t be so easy to acquire and secure..

+0 Obama is a United States citizen , Lowly rated comment [Show]
...
written by brownnpride, October 10, 2008

Dear Brad, I agree that WE have become moral relativists!

Kilgore brings up a great point. Thankfully, there&apos;s the issue of INDONESIAN citizenship which is equally devastating to B. HUSSEIN OBAMA.

I&apos;ve asked a hypothetical situation of my friends and acquaintances and although they would NOT ALLOW a pilot to fly a 747 if he refuses to show ID; nor be President.

For Obama, about half let him slide. It&apos;s a testament to the effectiveness/prowess of the CONFIDENCE MAN.

Obama is effective in APPEALING TO THE DREAMER in all of us!

The economic downturn is helping him EXPLOIT our FEARS of paying for medical bills and mortgages.

Never mind feeling good about voting for someone who LOOKS BLACK .

I never thought myself a conspiracist, but OBAMA makes it easy with his actions (i.e. no flag pin, no hand over heart like hillary and edwards), his words (i.e.&apos;my muslim faith..er christian, 57 states of US (NO THAT&apos;s ISLAM), etc), and his associations (Ayers, Rezko, Mansour, Davis, CAIR, Sandler, ACORN, etc).

If he was WHITE, we would not have let him slide. I know my words sound racist. Thankfully I have a healthy amount of&quot;protective&quot;melanin pigment in my skin.
+1 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Lisa,

If the Obamasiah wasn&apos;t hiding anything, he would have produced a certified copy of his birth certificate long ago.

Take your trolling back where it belongs, the Daily KOS.
+1 How about you go to school
written by J.Tims, October 10, 2008

Lisa,
Maybe you should go to school. The fact that Obama&apos;s team is is spending thousands of dollars and wasting hours upon hours of time defending this&quot;non issue&quot;goes to show that there is something not right. It would take far less money, and far less time to just prove that he is qualified to be the president of the United States. And what is important Lisa? Listening to a man lie to America, not so much for me.
+4 ...
written by Ken T, October 10, 2008

I need to talk to someone about my registration on this web site. It will not send me an email. it refuses everything I try to do. It probably would be best to start over. It has my email addy and will not allow me to do anything because it says my email is being used already.

I need an email addy of a person to talk to about my problem. I doubt I should use the email posted for Berg as he has more important things to do and read about then getting me registered.

you can email me at habs2u at yahoo dot, com

thanks
Ken

+0 Lisa
written by WB, October 10, 2008

Considering Obama&apos;s lawyers have so much work to do defending him against ACORN allegations, Rezko exposing him, his secret negotiations with Iraq, and God only knows what else, wouldn&apos;t it be easier just to prove his eligibility and get this case done and over with?
+2 Kilgore
written by Scalia, October 10, 2008

Hi, Kilgore! Thanks for your reply. I think your latest is markedly better than your first. Regrettably, I must again disagree with you.

First,&quot;outrage&quot;is irrelevant. You&apos;ve stated you think this lawsuit should be dismissed. Perhaps you elucidated elsewhere your reasons for thinking so, but your post is devoid of supporting argumentation. You later state that the law should be followed. If that is the case, and if it is the case that Obama is not a U.S. citizen, then consistency would dictate that this case *should not* be dismissed. If you believe in the rule of law, then you, as a law-abiding citizen, cannot turn a blind eye to a man who is not qualified to run.

It is not so cut and dried with Schwarzenegger. He is a U.S. citizen and many people (perhaps not the majority) believe he should be able to run. But...there&apos;s a little technicality called the law. Regardless his qualifications, he will never be able to serve as president, unless the Constitution is amended. Your&quot;arbitrary technicality,&quot;insofar as the law is concerned, puts both individuals in the same category: NOT QUALIFIED.

It is questionable whether Congress would retroactively qualify an unqualified candidate. A host of questions would have to be answered. A Democrat majority would not guarantee passage of such a law. It is not a matter of doing Berg&apos;s bidding that prevents Obama from submitting his birth certificate. Unless Obama believes that the Democrat-appointed judge in this case is a conspiracy theorist, it is irrelevant what wackos think. This is a federal court of law and as I&apos;ve previously stated, I wouldn&apos;t hesitate to submit my bc if that&apos;s all I need to prove my citizenship. If Obama&apos;s bc is proved a forgery, every honest Democrat would want to know *who* forged it and why. Obama would naturally be asked what he knew and when he knew it; and as his recent comments about Ayers indicate, he clearly rope-a-dopes when it comes to political convenience (&quot;I thought he had been rehabilitated.&quot;) Retroactive citizenship via Congress is no slam dunk.

You clearly don&apos;t like the law when it comes to this issue. That is, of course, your right. It is also your right to change what you think are inappropriate or unjust laws. However, I must get off the train when it comes to excusing Obama in this regard. Remember, Obama&apos;s citizenship has been on the table for some time now. His defenders have even produced&quot;proof&quot;on websites in the attempt to deflect this issue. To feign post-election ignorance would be laughable. He knows the requirements to run for office, it is very easy to prove this allegation false. The fact he doesn&apos;t want to produce that proof, at the very least, raises legitimate questions. Only those looking through their own&quot;prism&quot;can fail to see that.

Best wishes,
Scalia





+2 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Ken T,

Click on the forgot password link on the homepage (left side) to get it to resend.
+0 ...
written by Heidi Nickell, October 10, 2008

Hello to All,

I have been watching for news from the judge and I have to tell you this is scaring me. Why won&apos;t he rule? I mean, how long could this take? Like the rest of you have said, we are running out of time here. I think it is terrible that the media is not reporting on this. Why not?

Thank you.


+0 Obama Muslim Outreach Coordinator
written by Pam, October 10, 2008

On FOX NEWS: Barack Obama&apos;s newly appointed Muslim outreach adviser is coming under fire for meeting with Islamic groups with extremist views, just two months after her predecessor resigned over links to a radical cleric.

 http://elections.foxnews.com/2008/10/10/obamas-muslim-outreac... 
+0 ...
written by Dangling, October 10, 2008

My brother is a Priest in KY and is voting for Obama no matter what. I just can&apos;t believe that people, including my brother, are so gullible as to believe what Ovomit has to say about anything. I am retired from being a Registrar with Vital Records in Georgia and all you have to do to get a Birth Cert. is to write for it, send the money, and it will be returned to you. What is the problem with Ovomit doing this and stop being so stupid unless he has no BC in the US. I am sure the same rules stand in Hawaii. We are going to be in a dangerous situation if Ovomit gets in. Like several have said, it will be dangerous if he doesn&apos;t get in also. I say so be it.
If he allows ACORN to do fraudulent registering for voters, he must be a crook so why do people think he will do a decent job as President. This whole election system is a joke. His motto&quot;CHANGE&quot;means&quot;Come help a Negro get elected&quot;.
+0 ...
written by RMinNC, October 10, 2008

OUT OF TIME

It&apos;s now 3pm EST and still no word from the judge expected to rule on this case.....HAS THE JUDGE GONE TO SLEEP AT THE SWITCH?

Has it also occurred to anyone on this website, other than me, that just maybe this judge has no intentions of ruling on this SIMPLE case!

What can be soooooooo difficult here?
Either obama has a VALID birth certificate, or he doesn&apos;t.
Either the judge will make him present it, or he won&apos;t.

Looking at it from these two points of view.

If the judge rules for Mr. Berg then it&apos;s checkmate for obama because he can not produce something that does not exist. Then civil war will break in out America because that too has been built into obama&apos;s plans. From the jack-boot attitude the Obats and obama zombies have displayed up till now, is there doubt in anyone&apos;s mind big trouble will come following such a ruling?

From the other point of view, if the judge throws out Mr. Bergs case at the last minute of the last hour on the last day(which he damn well may do), what can the good citizens of this country realistically expect? The law abiding conservative citizens of America will do NOTHING because theres nothing they can do!

I&apos;m sure these points have been reviewed over and over in obama&apos;s war room by Hier Axlerod and his Chicago gang of thieves . THAT&apos;S WHY THEY DELAY, STALL, EVADE AND LIE about the massiah&apos;s place of birth, and all the other things necessary to PROVE he legally exist and not just an empty suit.

As for the MSM, those rats jumped on the obama train long before it left the station. Now they have backed themselves into a corner finding themselves in the awkward position of supporting an ILLEGAL ALIEN for President.

Poor Main stream media followed the Pied Piper right to the cliff. Now they too must show their continued loyalty by jumping over the edge.

One damn way or the other, NBC,CBS,ABC, and perhaps FOX to some degree will have poop in their pants, and egg all over those nicely pressed fifth Ave suits when this train wreck ends.

The American public now has about as much confidence in the media as they do in Nancy P&apos;s congress or George Bush&apos;s cabinet....about 9 percent!

My friends, our country is like a run away train with no brakes going ninety miles an hour on a downhill grade with a sharp curve at the bottom.

The Engineer and Brakeman (you and me) know when we bottom out at curve there will be one hell-of-a-mess to clean up, but the Company men (our government) sitting in an air conditioned office is telling us not to worry because their Train Expert and respected ACORN Community Organizer from Harvard (barack hussain obama) tells them there is no problem, just trust in his opinion and the company train will make it safely around the corner and back into the station.

Now just who in hell would you believe in this situation; the Engineer and Brakeman; the Company man; or the self made Community Organizer and Train Expert from Harvard?

If anyone reading this blog says trust the Company men, and by all means, trust the Train Expert, please give me a call as soon as possible
I HAVE A BRIDGE I WOULD LIKE TO SALE.

I suggest WE THE PEOPLE make the Company men and the self made Train Expert from Harvard ride the train down this hill with us just to restore our confidence in their abilities.

That can be done with something called the VOTE. We voted them in, by the grace of God, we can vote them OUT!



+2 Farrakhan note
written by SLF, October 10, 2008

Hi,
Someone made note that L. Farrakhan has named, (in front of a crowd that was in the hundreds if not thousands), Obama as Messiah. Please take note, all of you--think about this. The arguments have been made that Obama is a Christian. Farrakhan is MUSLIM! The MUSLIMS are not going to name a&quot;Christian&quot;as Messiah. Farrakhan is not talking about the Judeo-Christian Messiah, but rather the Muslim Messiah. Don&apos;t get confused about that. Farrakhan would only name a KNOWN and ACCEPTED Muslim as Messiah!
Please also realize that President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad truly believes that he will usher in the Shiite Islamic messiah figure – the Mahdi in the very near future, and the Mahdi will serve for 7 years before the judgement and end of the world.

Now, if the Islamic people buy into Farrakhan&apos;s sell of Obama as the Muslim Mahdi, Messiah, and then if he doesn&apos;t win the elections, we can only imagine what their reaction will be. I think it is important to world stability that the Judge immediately act on Berg&apos;s complaints and require that Obama produce the requested documentation. This is something that will only grow more volatile as time goes on. People have gone ga-gah over this guy.

It kind of telling to that when Ahmadinajad spoke at the UN he and one of his aids said that a&quot;green Light&quot;surrounded him, a light that was from Allah. and, when Obama spoke in New Hampshire he said something like this,&quot;a beam of light will come down through that window and when it falls upon you, you will have an epiphany, and you will go out and vote for Obama.&quot;So, it seems they are both on the same&quot;wave length&quot;or&quot;light wave&quot;!


+1 ...
written by Ken T, October 10, 2008

written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Ken T,

Click on the forgot password link on the homepage (left side) to get it to resend.
++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

Of course I tried this many times. I tried both the forgot password and the forgot name. On the password it does nothing and on the name it says it sends an email but it never arrives.

On the right where it discusses problems there needs to be an email addy to write to to get things working correctly. I suspect my password is different from what I used. but it will not respond on password.

For awhile today it had me sort of registered but it included my last name as the handle name. I do not want my last name on all my posts. just my first name is ok. If I try to use only my first name it says it is already used. if I include my last name it says wrong password now.

One idea is to erase all my info in the computer and start over.
+0 ...
written by Daniel Smith, October 10, 2008

I was just reading about the&quot;Unclean Hand&apos;s Doctrine&quot;for use against
&quot;Plaintiff&apos;s&quot;.
I would wonder if it can be used against&quot;Defendant&apos;s&quot;
involvement with&quot;Factcheck&quot;, and Moveon. org concerning the alledgely&quot;Fraudulent Birth Certificate!
or, the Congressman Eni...Dan
+1 ..., Lowly rated comment [Show]
Candidates meet&apos;natural-born&apos;test despite rumors (The Associated Press)
written by King, October 10, 2008

 http://ap.google.com/article/A...AD93NRJE00 
-1 A challenge to Mr. Berg, Lowly rated comment [Show]
Associated Press
written by King, October 10, 2008

Even Associated Press is in tank with BARACK HUSSAIN OBAMA
+0 Matthew
written by Terry136, October 10, 2008

Your case isn&apos;t like Obama&apos;s case at all. Was one of your parents a citizen of another country? Were you adopted by a foreign citizen at an early age, thus becoming a foreign national? Was your American citizenship renounced as a minor when your mother became a citizen of another country?

There are more differences, but I think the ones I mentioned will keep you busy for now. I think you need to do more research before you start comparing your case to Obama&apos;s case.
+1 Matthew
written by Scalia, October 10, 2008

Matthew, if you are 25 now, you were born in 1983. How old was your mother when you were born, and how many years did she physically reside in the United States? Also, was your mother a government employee?
+0 ...
written by Paige, October 10, 2008

We have to find a way to get all these Obama stories, including the most recent one on Fox News about his Muslim outreach coordinator to the MSM. I have many liberal&quot;friends&quot;who are voting Obama and will not believe any story that comes from Fox and is not reported by the MSM. I know they are in the tank for him, but there has to be a way.
+0 AP reporting about Fake Obama Birth Certificate rumors in internet
written by King, October 10, 2008

Candidates meet&apos;natural-born&apos;test despite rumors

 http://ap.google.com/article/ALeqM5gcwFmRs78Gz6-31o50qhACm-Y2... 


+0 Young Padawan..........
written by J.Tims, October 10, 2008

Matthew,

I believe that in your short life you should have learned to do some research before you open your mouth. What does 2018 have to do with anything? It is 2008 Matthew, are you from the future? I don&apos;t have the time to write what everyone else has written in the hundreds of blogs on this website that disprove your ignorant comment, but do a little research Mr Cochran, spend a little time on a&quot;learn to type&quot;software program and then maybe, just maybe you will get someone that wants to debate you. Until then..............good luck in your run for president.
+1 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

If Obama is an illegal alien but marries an American wife, does he not get to stay in this country?

There are forms to fill out, copies of birth certificates to be made, fees to be paid, medical exams to be taken, hands to be fingerprinted, background checks to ne performed, and THEN having to wait endlessly for the INS (now USCIS) to process everything.

If he wasn&apos;t a natural-born citizen, he would have his citizenship imputed to him through his mother, PROVIDED that he actually was born here.

Or....in other words, FAT CHANCE.
+0 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

Even Associated Press is in tank with BARACK HUSSAIN OBAMA

Notice how they snuck in on the last line of the story:

Even so, a lawsuit challenging Obama&apos;s candidacy was filed in August in a U.S. District Court in Pennsylvania and is still pending.

AP is the worst offender of the truth.

+4 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

As a natural-born United States citizen, born in Blacktown, NSW, Australia, I challenge you to prove, in a court of law, that I cannot be President of the United States of America, beginning in the year 2018.


Oxymoron, anyone?
+0 osama obama
written by Pam, October 10, 2008

NY election mix-up:&apos;Osama&apos;on the ballot
 http://news.yahoo.com/s/ap/20081010/ap_on_el_pr/osama_ballot 
+0 ...
written by RON IN LAS VEGAS, October 10, 2008

MATTHEW, YOU ARE BRAINLESS /TAKE TOUR GARBAGE SOMEWARE ELSE./ MR BERG HAS BETTER THINGS TO DO THEN LISTEN TO YOUR GARBAGE. YOU AIR HEAD
+0 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

Big sign on Berg&apos;s office:

IT&apos;S THE FRAUD, STUPID!

Forget about the vagaries of the Constitution for a moment. There are so many counts of felony fraud just waiting to come down on Obama like a ton of bricks. All it takes is one, solid piece of evidence that irrefutably proves that Obama not only committed felony fraud but also conspired to commit felony fraud.

He could be charged with violating the Logan Act for trying to influence the Iraqi government while the US is at war in that country.

He could be charged with massive voter fraud, campaign finance fraud, RICO acts, and even be subject to the Patriot Act once his ties to hostile foreign countries and terrorists are indelibly linked.

But, even if the American public at large does not understand the ramifications of all these potential charges, the failure to produce a valid birth certificate coupled with the act of using a fraudulent document image to disenfranchise the America voter.

Everyone thinks that he has a valid BC. What if John McCain turns to Obama in the final debate, and ask him, point blank,&quot;Why won&apos;y you show
+4 ...
written by Polarik, October 10, 2008

your birth certificate to the American public? Why are you showing a forged image instead? Why would you prove who you really are?
+1 Obama can&apos;t add:(
written by SLF, October 10, 2008

Obama has said that he was only 8 years old when Ayers was a&quot;terrorist&quot;, and I believe he reiterated that during the last Presidential debate on Tuesday evening--well, once a terrorist always a terrorist. However, Ayers particpated in bombing the Pentagon in 1972. I believe Obama would have been 11 years old at that time. Mr. Obama, please learn to add, right after you learn to tell the truth. In the meantime, I won&apos;t hold my breath. Also, the very fact that Mr. Ayers said he&quot;..would not discount the possiblity&quot;when asked if he would do it all again.

There is a big difference between an 8 year old and an 11 year old!
+0 James and Berg Assistant: Believe James is onto something with the State Statutes
written by sdallas, October 10, 2008

I believe James is onto something with the individual State Statutes. I have done some research and thus far found 14 states that specifically have statutes that require candidates submitting applications/petitions to be on state ballot for Federal positions that they be qualified under the applicable federal statutes and constitutional article(s) (U.S. Constitution, Article II, section 1 for US President) for the specific Federal office they are submitting for. The states I have found thus far include PA, TX, FL, OH, VA, IN, NC, TN, MA, NJ, MD, MN, WI, IL, NY. For total of 261 electoral votes.

Berg Assistant:
Wouldn&apos;t it be prudent to include the other states with these specific statutes in Mr. Berg&apos;s suite, not just Pennsylvania (http://www.dos.state.pa.us/ele...office.pdf) , as Obama&apos;s fraud would be violating those specific state statutes and would involve crossing state lines with applications sent via US mail, FEDEX/UPS, email, etc, which the fraud would be then violating federal laws and qualifying for consideration within US District Courts? Or would individual filings have to be made in each individual state?

Also Berg Assistant: Has Mr. Berg received any offers of legal assistance from any legal foundations? If this is a sensitive question, you may also respond directly to my email address on file - also look for dallasinsat (thanks to the site crash prob)

+0 James and Berg Assistant: Correction: 15 states with specific statutes on qualifications
written by dallasinsat, October 10, 2008

James and Berg Assistant: Correction: 15 states with specific statutes on qualifications
+0 ...
written by Philadelphia Roof Doctor, October 10, 2008

Ken T.

When I registered, it took my real name and used it as my username also. I tried to reregister and it brought the info I had used to register. I changed the real name to Philadelphia Roof Doctor and submitted it. I never received another email, but I&apos;ve been registered as the roof doctor ever since.

I don&apos;t think the system will allow 2 people to have the same name and I believe there is another Ken, so you may not be able to be just Ken.

For emails, check any spam filters to see if the email was blocked.
+0 Alex
written by Brad Meador, October 10, 2008

At the time McCain was born the Panama canal was part of the US. he was also born on a military base. However, your natural born point is completely moot. You obviously don&apos;t know the laws of the constitution. Even if McCain was born in Mexico, Jamaica or somewhere he would still be a Natural Born citizen because both of his parents were US citizens.


+0 Kilgore
written by Brad Meador, October 10, 2008

According to the Constitution a natural born citizen is a citizen of the United States. The Framers made it that way because the constitution was developed after we broke apart from England and they decided on&quot;natural born&quot;or being born/citizen here because if one was born in England then moved to the US and became president if anything bad came up in England down the road where would the President&apos;s allegiance be, here or in England.

That&apos;s why it also states you can&apos;t be a citizen of ANY other country. Obama&apos;s Indonesian and Kenyan citizenships in his past automatically disqualify him from the Presidency.

It&apos;s your opinion, but I&apos;m curious to know: why don&apos;t you think this suit will succeed?


+1 He is unaware!
written by Mario, October 10, 2008

It is possible Obama does not know that he was born somewhere else besides the US.
I work for DHS and there is always cases like this one where the parents lie to their kids that they were born here, but in reality they were born some where else and brought in the US as infants.
Therefore living their entire lives in the US as a noncitizen, and suddenly being deported. It is harsh but that is the law.
+0 ...
written by dneal, October 10, 2008

sdallas --- I think you have an excellent idea. I wonder what Mr. Berg would charge to file the same suit in Ohio for me and my son? How could one find that out?
+0 ...
written by Ken T, October 10, 2008

It was reported that Obama used to ask lots of questions all the time about his birth and citizenship while a student at Harvard Law School. He was very interested in the details. He is will aware of his situation.
+1 ...
written by Kilgore, October 10, 2008

Hello Scalia,

I think that we agree on more than you might think. We certainly agree on the rule of law. I imagine that we agree that the law gives judges the power to dismiss frivolous lawsuits. Our major disagreement is over whether Berg’s lawsuit is frivolous or not. I think that the suit is a baseless conspiracy theory that has been debunked. You think that the lawsuit has merit. From your point of view I can understand why you think the judge should not dismiss the case. (As the details of Berg’s allegations have been discussed to death already, I won’t get into them here. We will have to agree to disagree.)

Because we both agree that the law should rule, we agree that IF Obama was born outside the US, he would be ineligible to serve as President UNLESS Congress granted him retroactive natural-born citizenship. This would all be consistent with the rule of law. We disagree on the probability that this would actually happen.

Such an act by Congress would probably not be the slam dunk I would like it to be. But I think it would stand a good chance for many reasons. No Democrat would dare to vote against it for fear of the 100% chance of getting savaged in the next primary -- this would be enough to secure a majority in both houses. Republicans from states/districts that voted for Obama would come under pressure to vote with the Dems (obvious attack ad in the next election: “How can we trust Senator X to represent our interests? He can’t even get our presidential vote right.”). Would this be enough to gain a veto-proof majority? Hard to say.

As for popular opinion: you said that “’outrage’ is irrelevant.” It’s true that outrage does not trump the rule of law. But outraged citizens can force their elected representatives to change the law to their liking.

More subtly, would the Republicans want the Pyrrhic victory of McCain taking office under these circumstances? He would be a 4-year lame duck, with a zero mandate, fighting an enlarged and enraged Congressional Democratic majority. The GOP is in deep decline these days, and they need to find ways to expand their appeal the American public. The last thing they need is to be seen, correctly, as thwarting the clearly expressed will of the American electorate. Slaughter would follow in the 2010 midterms and beyond. (I am probably underestimating the amount of support Obama would lose if it came out that he was born outside the US. But, as I mentioned before, this seems like small potatoes given what is already common knowledge about his parentage and childhood.)

You say that you would supply your BC if asked. Okay, fine. But I’m sure you can see why, for tactical reasons, Obama is not. Why should he? Nobody is taking this lawsuit seriously and it has not lost him a single vote so far. If it becomes a damaging issue then he will provide the documents to make it go away, but at the moment it is far easier to bog the suit down in legal muck. Also, it is worth pointing out that Obama has already posted a copy of his BC. It was immediately denounced as a fake and repackaged as evidence for his guilt, because this is how conspiracy theories work. Obama is understandably not motivated to provide more documents to be immediately denounced as fakes.

(I agree, by the way, that Obama plays the rope-a-dope on controversial issues… which makes him exactly typical for an American politician. He&apos;s not a saint, despite what his most ardent followers want to believe about him.)

Cheers,
Kilgore

+0 ...
written by Tommy T, October 10, 2008

I am personally very disappointed that another complete week has gone by without a word from the judge.

The judge could at minimum give a statement of something such as that Obama will be required to begin answering some questions on the 15th or something similar.

What happens if the judge tries to stonewall it by holding on to the issues without ever answering any questions. Can he stonewall forever. What can be done to force him to move forward.

I would like to see more filings in all the states to stop this farce on our constitution. Above were listed 15 key states. Are there any lawyers who could file in one of those states. Where is some big contributor of money who will support the efforts to save America.
+0 THE JUDGE
written by ICEMAN, October 10, 2008

He will make a ruling when Bill and Hillary are ready.... I think it will be next friday.
+0 ...
written by Dahli Bama, October 10, 2008

From one Hillary`s Blog s ----------- You have to hand it to these girls, They work hard to defeat Obama. Never let up. The repubs in here need to get bust doing what these girls are doing instead of arguing with the obama idiots in here ---------------------- Okay, so, following your advice from the RICO article about contacting our governors and other state officials about ACORN and voter fraud, I found every possible number for PA officials and dialed them up.I called the State Election Bureau, which gave me one of those “Press 1 for…, Press 2 for…” options for the different divisions. I first tried the Division for Voter Registration, but no one answered so I left a message. Then I tried the division for the Help America Vote Act. The lady who picked up sounded slightly confused, so she told me to hold one for a sec. After above five minutes of mind-numbing elevator music, she returned and said that they had been getting a number of calls concerning ACORN. She told me to give her my contact info, and that they would get back to me.When I called Governor Rendell and Secretary Cortes’s offices, they non-surprisingly transferred me to the State Election Bureau.Finally, I live in Delaware County so I also called the county’s Election Bureau, who told me to send them a fax and that they would get back to me after they received it.No real concrete answers yet, but I’ll keep you updated.
+0 ...
written by Tommy T, October 10, 2008

written by dneal, October 10, 2008

sdallas --- I think you have an excellent idea. I wonder what Mr. Berg would charge to file the same suit in Ohio for me and my son? How could one find that out?
+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

Berg&apos;s email addy is listed on the first page. you can email him or phone him.

Philip J. Berg, Esquire
555 Andorra Glen Court, Suite 12
Lafayette Hill, PA 19444-2531
Cell (610) 662-3005
(610) 825-3134
(800) 993-PHIL [7445]
Fax (610) 834-7659
philjberg@obamacrimes.comThis e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it

+0 I am worried
written by Lawman, October 10, 2008

I have read through all of the docs, and here is my concern.

#1 There is no evidence that Obama was not born in the US.

#2 The argument that his citizenship changed is interesting, but there would be records within the government that Berg could get to proove this. As I have read through, there is nothing.

#3 Corsi is a terrible ally in this fight, the guy has been prooven wrong over and over again. I know what he writes is makes people who dislike Obama excited, but the guy has got nothing to back his stuff up.

#4 Obama has produced an actual certified copy of his COLB and it can be found here.

 http://www.factcheck.org/elections-2008/born_in_the_usa.html 

There are several links on the left hand side of the page that have photographs of the document with the raised seal and the stamp from Hawaii.



I want to believe, and you want to believe. At what point are we simply believing to believe?
-1 ...
written by Butch, October 10, 2008

He is unaware!
written by Mario, October 10, 2008

It is possible Obama does not know that he was born somewhere else besides the US.
I work for DHS and there is always cases like this one where the parents lie to their kids that they were born here, but in reality they were born some where else and brought in the US as infants.
Therefore living their entire lives in the US as a noncitizen, and suddenly being deported. It is harsh but that is the law.


*****************************
Lame excuse, he&apos;s a constutional lawyer running for POTUS for God&apos;s sake.


+0 ...
written by dneal, October 10, 2008

Tom ----------- What do you think about that idea? Dont want waste Mr. Bergs time. He may not be licensed in Ohio. I wonder what that would cost? Have any idea?

I have seen where they are taking donations for the PA suit, I thought maybe the amount needed had mentioned.
+0 To Lawman
written by pam, October 10, 2008

Are you aware that factcheck.org is run by the Annenburg foundation? Sound familiar? It should! That&apos;s the foundation Obama worked on with Ayers.
+0 ...
written by dneal, October 10, 2008

Lawman ------ I know for a fact the Israeli`s found that document to a fraud. I then read that 7 other forensics had declared it a fraud. Every forensic lab that looked at that document have found the exact same problems.

Disclaimer: Thats what I have read. Doesnt make me a expert.
+0 Where are the Clintons in all of this???
written by stpeh3, October 10, 2008

Surely, they must know of this case and I agree with my whole heart, Hillary was robbed. I can only hope they are in support of this effort.
+0 ...
written by Jury?, October 10, 2008

I am confused. Is Mr. Berg demanding a jury trial for this?

I would think a determination by a Federal judge would be preferable.
+0 ...
written by OBAMA&amp;AYERS WILL DESTROY AMERICA, October 10, 2008

We have been told by the leaders of Islam, (the likes of Louis Farrakhan and Osama) ‘the United States will collapse from inside itself.
We also know the terrorists plan years and years ahead on what they will do to complete one of their acts of terror. The destruction of the World Trade Center Twin Towers was the culmination of plans made after the first attempt at destruction failed.
This plan involved the training of pilots to fly the airplanes into the towers, the Pentagon and possibly the White House. Coordination between the terrorists had to be planned far in advance and it appears to me there were probably rehearsals and refining of the overall plan. Billy Ayers the American terrorist MAGICALLY had his prewritten article about his love of blowing up all things American published in the New York Times exactly on 9-11-01. He knew.
The plan took years to bring it to fruition. It didn’t happen overnight; it didn’t become the plan over a cup of coffee at Starbucks.
How better to bring about the collapse of the United States from within than to bring about the destruction from the top down. Remember the terrorists are patient, methodical and determined to do it right the first time. Now let’s examine this scenario.
We know about the uproar over Mitt Romney’s religious affiliation with the Mormon church and the opposition to electing a Mormon to the Presidency. Knowing this, can you even imagine what an uproar would come about if a candidate was affiliated with the Muslim faith?
There has been no President of the United States, to my knowledge, who been elected that didn’t claim to be a Christian. If I am wrong, please correct me.
HIDE RELIGION: The question now arises, How does Islam get one of their own elected. Answer; pass him off as a Christian. How do they do that? Answer, plan years ahead and carefully choose the right person for the job. Choose someone who is born on American soil, (though now it appears Obama&apos;s mother lied about this and she could not return from Kenya fast enough to not deliver him there) because that is a requirement for qualifying for the office. Even this is questionable from his fake birth certificate. Seems like Mom outscoundreled the scoundrels in this regard; she was able to finagle a Certificate of Live Birth for both Barry and Maya, though neither one was born in Hawaii.
FUND HIS EDUCATION: Then, send that someone to the best schools available even though his parents divorce when he is a toddler and neither has the money to send him to the highly expensive schools he attends. Take him out of public Indonesian schools and start him at an expensive private Catholic school though neither parent is Catholic, a school which he attends after he has been chosen and the refining begins. (Note it must be a male because women are not allowed to rule in Islam).


+1 ...
written by OBAMA&amp;AYERS WILL DESTROY AMERICA, October 10, 2008

Although his father is a Muslim, his mother an atheist and his step-father also a Muslim, he is sent to a private Catholic school after being removed from a public and free Muslim school--free because the boy is an Indonesian citizen. Why would either of his parents choose Catholicism over Islam or Atheism for his education? Remember, there has never been a President of the United States of America that was not at least claiming to be a Christian. Americans liked Kennedy, and he was a Catholic. The boy catches wind that he is something special, and writes not one but two essays that teachers remember vividly and attribute to him while in grade school in Indonesia:&quot;I Want To Be President&quot;by Barry Soetoro. Obama&apos;s sister Maya says that his mother often jokes that she knows Barack would be the first black president. Shakespeare wrote,&quot;Many a Truth is Spoken in Gest&quot;.

After the candidate for the job of saboteur has been chosen and the refinement process has begun the polishing must begin also. He must be sent to an outstanding private prep high school, one that his divorced struggling mother and grandparents living in a humble apartment building could never afford (Punahau today costs $17,000 per year tuition). It was at Punahau that Obama scrawls&quot;King Obama&quot;into the concrete (http://www.theobamafile.com/_images/ObamaKing.jpg). He needs proper mentoring during his youth to engage his black rage amidst all of his privilege: Enter Frank Marshall Davis, the bisexual perverted pornographer communist who was Obama&apos;s one-on-one teacher in all things black and hateful and Marxist in his youth. Davis is a friend of Bill Ayers.
He attended public schools in Jakarta, Indonesia where his step father returned after marrying Barack’s mother. At age 10 Barack entered Punahou School, a private school, in Hawaii until graduation from High School. He then moved to Los Angeles where he attended Occidental College.
And he must attend private expensive universities (with no record of a job, grant or student loan to pay for them--the only student loan records for college were for Michelle). Obama attends Occidental for 2 years, and it is during this time he fulfills another requirement: Travel to Pakistan for Jihad training, using his Indonesian passport. It is 1981 and Obama&apos;s mentoring shifts from Davis to Ayers.

Ayers accompanies Obama to NYC where he ostensibly attends Columbia in 1983 University, only nobody remembers him. To this day Obama refuses to release his Columbia transcripts. It is likely he lived in NYC with his former Pakistani roomie some of the time, and he lived in a rent-controlled area that even professional full-time employed individuals had difficulty affording. He lived close to Ayers. He probably traveled to Pakistan or other countries during this time. He ostensibly graduates with a degree in Political Science from Columbia but again, Obama lacks basic knowledge of politics, history which give away his real educational state, saying later that his nonexistent uncle liberated Auschwitz (the Russians did) and that one bomb dropped on Pearl Harbor and that Truman was a great peace negotiator. It appears that Ayers either hired a surrogate to take Obama&apos;s courses or simply bought him a diploma, while he was otherwise trained in Jihad and community agitating.

Ayers obtains funding through Khalid al Mansour a radical black American with wealthy Wahabist links for Obama to go to Harvard La school. Again, Obama lacks the income to live in the places where he lives without outside assistance. He gets no scholarships nor grants nor loans to go to Harvard. OBama fails the LSAT until he finally gain admission to Harvard (&apos;91) for the political and affirmative action climate encourages minorites despite low grades. Ayers gets a letter of reference from Percy Sutton for Obama&apos;s Harvard admission.

ACT THE PART: As with all politicians he must begin his career in politics at the bottom and work his way up by using his charisma and good looks that rock stars possess. He must run his campaign for the nomination of his party for President by attracting some special interest groups like ethnic, gender and age groups.

This process of selecting someone to fill all these qualifications will take more than a decade, it will require a generation, but remember, Islam is patient.

Do we know anyone who fits this mold? Yes, I think we do.

We know someone running for the nomination of his party for President of the United States of America who was born on American soil. Or so his mentors and funder think.

Somehow along the way he joined the Trinity United Church of Christ in 1988 and thus became a Christian. (It is interesting to note that he was at either Columbia University or Harvard Law School, far removed from the Trinity United Church of Christ in Chicago, when he became a member).



+2 Lawman
written by Ben_, October 10, 2008

I guess you are new to this. At this point I would ask you to read all the portions of this site, especially the part about the so called COLB from Hawaii. Funny you can&apos;t read a single word on the&quot;raised seal&quot;. Why was it taken at such a sharp angle where nothing can be read?

I&apos;m not going to rehash all the information that exists just on his site but if you want to know more, grab a cold one and jump in.

One last thought, shouldn&apos;t the person running for President have already presented his&quot;vault&quot;copy of his Birth Certificate to someone a bit more official than some website? Just because they have an official sounding name like factcheck does not mean much to me. I&apos;m of the Reagan school of&quot;trust but verify&quot;and there are soooo many problems with that proported&quot;certificate of live birth&quot;that I can&apos;t even start going through them. Just read the analysis of it on this site and join the rest of us waiting for the Judge to rule.

I&apos;l stop believing when I see a birth certificate and get the answers to the Indonesian citizenship issue. I won&apos;t sop until then.

Good Luck
+0 ...
written by OBAMA&amp;AYERS WILL DESTROY AMERICA, October 10, 2008

Who is this young man who gained all of this higher education and accomplished all that he has claimed while the son of a single parent, grandson of a middle class couple and son of a Muslim in Kenya, Africa, step-son of a Muslim in Indonesia?

I believe Barack Hussein Obama (Barry Soetoro), Indonesian, and candidate for the Democratic Party nomination as President of the United States of America, fits the mold exactly.

I ask you to think about this.

 http://www.blogatroid.com 
theobamafile.com
obamacrimes.com
texasdarlin.wordpress.com
noquarterusa.net/blog
obambi.wordpress.com

+1 Everything I have read
written by Lawman, October 10, 2008

about the&quot;fake&quot;documents has been based on an electronic image, not the actual paper document. Also from the Texasdarling site it was discovered that the image they were using was in a fact a fake that was put in play by some nutball from Daily KOS. So yes when you get a fake document created by some liberal idiot, it will be a fake.

As for the Annenberg foundation, it once hosted my hero Ronald Regan. It has a history of being a very strong organization despite having a jackass like Ayers associated with it.

Folks if you look through a microscope all the time, you miss a great deal of the big picture. I am just saying that I joined Mr. Berg in his fight to expose the truth about 9/11. We believed then that it was an inside job, we believed that the government was involved. Mr. Berg fought the fight to bring the truth to the front, but now I am not sure that we were right.
+0 ...
written by NANCYJOE, October 10, 2008

ONE MORE TIME...

OBAMA CAN MAKE THIS ALL GO AWAY AND JUST SHOW THE DOCUMENTS. ANYONE WITH A BRAIN KNOWS THAT HE IS HIDING SOMETHING OR HE WOULD DO SO. ENUFF SAID. IT&apos;S BAD NEWS FOR OBAMA. PERIOD. AND ALL OF US SHOULD BE ON OUR KNEES THANKING BERG AND SENDING HIM MONEY TO CONTINUE.
+0 Lawman -
written by Terry136, October 10, 2008

&quot;There are several links on the left hand side of the page that have photographs of the document with the raised seal and the stamp from Hawaii.&quot;

Note that the pics of the raised seal and stamp show NOTHING else. They could be from anyone&apos;s birth certificate, or simply a blank sheet of paper with the seal and stamp. That is the reason Mr. Berg is demanding a certified VAULT copy of the birth certificate -- to remove any doubt.
+0 ...
written by Paige, October 10, 2008

We know that... but unless the judge rules in Berg&apos;s favor, none of his followers are going to believe it. I&apos;m not sure they would believe it even after that, but Obama would be rightfully disqualified since we know he can&apos;t produce the documents in question.
+0 Is holding a fake Federal document as real a crime?
written by Project BCAD , October 10, 2008

Obama has held several versions of Birth Certificates on his website to the public as Real. With all of these different versions it is obvious that Obama did in fact forge a Federal Document at one point or another. Isn&apos;t this offense alone enough?
+0 lawman - you are late in the game
written by josee, October 10, 2008

The birth certificate on ko&apos;s and factcheck is not his long birth cerificate. You say you read through the entire case so you either did not or you missed this in the court papers.
+0 Lawman
written by Kenny, October 10, 2008

I had heard about Phil&apos;s suit about the 9/11 conspiracy and I have already told him how I felt about that. I really thought that was a crazy suit and I didn&apos;t appreciate it. However, I am backing him with regards to this case because I firmly believe that Obama has too many radical friends that can cause the country great harm. I am afraid though that no one is even paying attention to anything that Obama stands for because they hate the Republicans that much. All of us had better hope something breaks between now and Nov. 4th to derail the Obama machine.
+0 Whatever happened to the big news from NBC
written by Kenny, October 10, 2008

Was Josh just pulling our leg about this??
+1 ...
written by dneal, October 10, 2008

Israel Insider is reporting that analysts working separately have determined the birth certificate posted on the Daily Kos website and later on Sen. Barack Obama&apos;s&quot;Fight the Smears&quot;campaign website is fraudulent, and now two different actions have been launched to try and obtain the truth about the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee&apos;s birth.

The Israel Insider report said the two analysts it interviewed both have been&quot;able to independently discern the name&apos;Maya Kassandra Soetoro&apos;from artifacts left behind in the process of forging a new fake document for Barack from an image of Maya&apos;s original document.&quot;Maya is Obama&apos;s younger half-sister.

The report follows a posting from another researcher, identified by the news publication as Techdude, that the birth certificate is a forgery because it originally documented the birth of a woman in the 1970s.

Blogger Mitchell Langbert now has launched an online petition to the Federal Election Commission in which signers are asking the agency to&quot;take responsibility to verify the eligibility of Mr. Barack H. Obama to be president of the United States.&quot;

+0 Project BCAD
written by Terry136, October 10, 2008

&quot;Obama has held several versions of Birth Certificates on his website to the public as Real. With all of these different versions it is obvious that Obama did in fact forge a Federal Document at one point or another. Isn&apos;t this offense alone enough?&quot;

Biirth certificates are NOT Federal documents. They are STATE documents issued by the state the birth took place in. Each state has its own requirements as to what info birth certificates issued by it should contain.
+0 Fox is trying to keep the news low key.....wonder why
written by ICEMAN, October 10, 2008

 http://www.foxnews.com/video2/...index.html 
+0 Josee
written by Lawman, October 10, 2008

I understand that a COLB is not the same as his actual birth certificate. I also understand that a COLB is a valid document.

As for the photographs. These photos are the ones that made me wonder if the case holds water.

 

 

 

Could I be wrong? Of course.

Could Mr. Berg be wrong?

I know I was wrong about 9/11 and that would mean so was Mr. Berg.

There is being right, and then there is wanting to be right. I learned this the hard way after the 9/11 commission.
+1 ...
written by james, October 10, 2008

Tommy T, dneal, and sdallas.

I can be reasonably certain that Mr. Berg is pretty consumed by the case against Obama and the DNC in the District Court of Eastern Pennsylvania.

A lot of people are anxiously waiting for the case to get into the MSM and also waiting for the judge to issue a ruling in Berg v. Obama.

If you have firm belief in the lawsuit, hiring an Attorney in your state and filing a case in your state is within your right as a taxpayer, citizen and voter.

A RIGHT NOT EXERCISED CEASES TO BECOME A RIGHT. -unk

+1 Very scary stuff!
written by Pam, October 10, 2008

Farrakhan calls Obama the Messiah... Where is the mainstream media on this? The only one saying anything is Fox News. Very scary stuff!

 http://www.americanthinker.com/blog/2008/10/farrakhan_calls_o... 
+0 IMPORTANT POIINTS FOR PHILIP BERG TO READ.
written by Tom, October 10, 2008

Hello Philip Berg,


Thanks for your information on this site.

Today I read the following&quot;BERG v OBAMA UPDATE - OCT. 9&quot;at http://glnnflwrs.blogtownhall....ct_9.thtml :
-----------
In my study of possibilities I have learned that the responsibility to determine eligibility of a candidate for the presidency lies with two congressional entities. First is the Senate Ethics and Rules Committee chaired by Diane Feinstein. They are responsible for all election operations including the certification of a candidates compliance with constitutional requirements. Second is the Speaker of the House of Representitves. They have the responsibility to insure that the president elect can effectively be sworn in and assume the office and duties of the president. As far as national elections are concerned there is no eligibilty requirements to run for office, only to hold office. So, if the court does not rule before the election and Obama is the winner, he can still be banned from office by the house speaker and his VP would become president protem until a decision to hold a new election is made.

And, Sen. Feinstein could prevent any possible constitutional conflicts by immediately investigating Obama&apos;s background as to eligibilty prior to the election.


Glenn Flowers
----------------------
Here is what I think and I ask Philip Berg to read this posting carefully because I think it is important.
Here is what I think could, might happen with the case Berg vs. Obama in relation to what I have just posted above.
The judge will know the points explained in the extract that I have given just above (and I assume they are accurate and valid) BUT what he will do is the following. Assuming the judge is likely to vote Democrat (many judges are Democrat), he will delay his decision for AFTER the election!! And then he will say that the responsibility to decide on the eligibility of the President of the USA was not his responsibility but it was, as the extract above says, on the Senate Ethics and Rules Committee chaired by Diane Feinstein and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.
In such a scenario, Berg&apos;s current legal efforts would have been done for nothing!! And he would have been manipulated by the judge into believing that his case would taken into account by the judge when, in fact, the judge (a Democrat) would simply wait the elections to be held before telling Berg that he knocked at the wrong door I could say.

Therefore, Berg should also contact both the Senate Ethics and Rules Committee chaired by Diane Feinstein and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and explain to them that they have a legal obligation to assess Obama&apos;s eligibility to be President of the USA.
Berg must do this request in the open I believe and also at the same time than he does his current legal case only to cover himself for the eventuality that I have just explained where the judge would say&quot;it is not my business&quot;basically and refers the case to both the Senate Ethics and Rules Committee chaired by Diane Feinstein and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.

I want to warn Berg of this possible trap so that he covers himself fully against it.



Another problem. Even if Obama would give the documents requested, they could even be unreliable documents even if they are fully legitimate documents!! For instance, if Obama was born in Kenya, it is likely that he asked Kenyans to destroy the evidence of his birth in Kenya! Now, if he would be recorded on this full birth certificate as having been born in Hawaii, it is also possible that this fact is false. Therefore, there would then need to have a full double-checking at the hospital he is mentioned to have been born in Hawaii to make sure that the records at this hospital have not been tampered to create a false proof of birth in Hawaii on USA soil when, in fact, he was born in Kenya.
In other words, if Obama would produce a full birth certificate that is fully legitimate and that claims that Obama was born in Hawaii, there would still need to have a thorough investigation to double-check that this supposed birth in a hospital was not a fact that was created falsely to allow him to have a birth shown in the USA.
Conclusion: even in the case Obama would provide the documents requested, that would only be the beginning of the search for the truth on this matter!! And that is where it is very scary I must say.



Thanks for all your efforts and quest for truth, Philip Berg. You deserve the praises of every American, Democrat and Republicans alike. Keep fighting until you know for sure the truth fully. And it will not be easy with the kind of dishonest fanatics that are involved in this story.

Regards
Anonymous as usual.
-1 ...
written by OBAMA&amp;AYERS WILL DESTROY AMERICA, October 10, 2008

Why is it when I search google.com/search?q=philip+berg+attorney+at+law+lafayette+hil...
I get:
Philip J Berg Law Office
votepower.com

555 Andorra Glen Ct # 12
Lafayette Hill, PA 19444
(610) 825-3134

and votepower.com is a voter registration site owned by:
Registrant:
Global Soft Inc.
Global Soft Inc. Global Soft Inc.
9018 Balboa Blvd Unit 534
Northridge, CA 91325
US
Email: \n This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it&apos;&gt;ishaikh@hremedy.comThis e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it

Registrar Name....: REGISTER.COM, INC.
Registrar Whois...: whois.register.com
Registrar Homepage: www.register.com

Domain Name: votepower.com

Created on..............: Thu, Jul 17, 2003
Expires on..............: Sun, Jul 17, 2011
Record last updated on..: Sun, Jul 01, 2007

Administrative Contact:
Vote Power Corp.
Inti Shaikh
9018 Balboa Blvd Unit 534
Northridge, CA 91325

Phone: +1.8184261858
Email: \n This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it&apos;&gt;ishaikh@hremedy.comThis e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it

Technical Contact:
Register.Com
Domain Registrar
575 8th Avenue 11th Floor
New York, NY 10018
US
Phone: 1-902-7492701
Email: \n This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it&apos;&gt;domain-registrar@register.comThis e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it

DNS Servers:

ns1.ehostingbiz.com
ns2.ehostingbiz.com

and on greasy.com/texastar/philip_berg_continues_law_suit.html

&quot;And you&apos;ll never guess who is backing him(BERG)???&quot;Bill Clinton&quot;. I have seen some blogs and comments on here of folks thinking that this election is all wrapped up and Obama has it in the bag. Well, it isn&apos;t over yet and don&apos;t be too sure of that. Who knows it may be Hillary who will be the democrats choice come election day. Very interesting!! I came across this in another blog but, have seen this posted on several blogs over the past month or so.&quot;


??? any insight?

-1 ...
written by Karen Bracken, October 10, 2008

I am not sure what this document means. Does this mean Obama MUST produce proof of citizenship by October 15th??
+0 To Tom
written by Linda Starr in TX, October 10, 2008

In the amended petition, Phil added as co-defendents&apos;s the Senate Rules Committee, Diane Feinstein for failure to perform due diligence in investigating Obama&apos;s legal citizenship status, and also the Pennsyvania Secretary of State. Plus, never fear, we have a few surprises in store for the DNC and Obama.
+1 Linda Starr
written by Ben_, October 10, 2008

Greetings,

Can you explain to me what happens if the Judge decides to make NO ruling next week? Is Obama/DNC required to furnish the discovery items? The Judge has not instructed them to not comply. Does his silence on the Motions mean they have no impact on the case? I&apos;m a bit confused about whether discovery still continues unless he rules for Discovery to be stayed.

Any information you could provide would be appreciated.
+0 Individual State Lawsuits
written by dallasinsat, October 10, 2008

Tommy T, dneal, and James:
My instinct tells me James is correct. Mr. Berg has all he can handle. Individual citizens have just as much standing and rights as Mr. Berg. If we are truly committed to this endeavor, to the very end, then it is time for us to&quot;walk the talk&quot;. I&apos;m for it and willing to track down an attorney or firm with the right background, experience, and is willing to take on the filing for Texas - like yesterday.

I sent Mr. Berg an email requesting his advice regarding filing in the indivdual states vs adding them to his current lawsuit and if he has some time available to assist other attorneys filing on behalf of voters in the other 14 states.

Tommy T.: Can you take OH?

Who else out there is willing and ready to make the same commitment here as Mr. Berg? How serious are you about seeing this all the way to the end, no matter the cost, time, or effort? The remaining states (assuming Tommy T. takes OH), are: FL, VA, IN, NC, TN, MA, NJ, MD, MN, WI, IL, NY.

Time is of the essence - therefore each taking this on need to turn their emotions, anger, and frustrations into a&quot;presence of calm and relentless determination&quot;and leave any ranting and raving behind. Otherwise you will be written off immediately as&quot;crazy, rumor-mongering, internet conspiracy, nut-case” and you will only find incompetent attorneys that will take your money and do nothing. Not just any attorney will do for this issue. Considerable research and referrals will be needed to find the right one. And you will need to present credible information and data without verbs that reflect emotion. Referencing the most recent filings by Mr. Berg on http://dockets.justia.com/dock...id-281573/ is probably best approach.

+0 Be careful, guys
written by SL Baur, October 10, 2008

This is mainly at the poster who called Obama&apos;s mother an atheist. She most certainly is not. There is a word for a woman married to a Muslim man and that is&quot;Muslim&quot;. There is also a word for the children born of such parents, and that&apos;s&quot;Muslim&quot;.

Regardless of the true nature of Obama&apos;s birth, the probability that young Barry Soetoro in Indonesia has documentation listing his religion as&quot;Islam&quot;is 100%.

The US has done away with official government paperwork requiring public statement of religion. That&apos;s not true once you get outside of a handful of 1st world countries.

At a minimum, that is what they are trying to cover up. He may or not be Muslim now, I do not particularly care. But I guarantee you, being born and raised (by a different) Muslim father and not having his religion claimed to be Islam on paperwork in Indonesia is exactly 0.
+0 Stanley
written by Dr. bobbi , October 10, 2008

Stanley Anne Dunham and her parents were most certainly atheists. I&apos;m not sure why she married Lolo soetoro, but I doubt that it made her any less an atheist.
She just didn&apos;t like American men and wanted to date only foreigners is what I understood.
I did hear that she didn&apos;t force her opinion on Barry, but nonetheless, when a person is an atheist, they certainly act differently.
It has been documented that she was an atheist from a very young age.
the links are here
 http://hubpages.com/hub/Obamas-Mother-Stanley-Anne-Durham 
+0

Write comment
Name

Email

Website

Title

Comment

smaller | bigger

Subscribe via email (Registered users only)
I have read and agree to the Terms of Usage.

Write the displayed characters


Add CommentPreview



Last Updated ( Thursday, 09 October 2008 21:52 ) Make a donation to help us with the costs to pursue this case. Donate $2.08, $20.08. $200.80. or any amount you choose. Thank you for your generous support.




Main Menu
Home
Media&amp;Press Contacts
Phil&apos;s Blog
Login
Username


Password


Remember Me


Forgot your password?
Forgot your username?
Create an account

Philip J. Berg, Esquire
555 Andorra Glen Court, Suite 12
Lafayette Hill, PA 19444-2531
Cell (610) 662-3005
(610) 825-3134
(800) 993-PHIL [7445]
Fax (610) 834-7659
philjberg@obamacrimes.com

Please Help
Berg vs. Obama is expensive to pursue. Please read Phil J. Berg&apos;s request for donations and take action.When Making Comments
Low rated comments are concealed so that you must click a link to read the comment. Vote using the&quot;+&quot;and&quot;-&quot;buttons by each comment.

Use the&quot;!&quot;button to report abusive comments. If a comment receives enough complaints, it will be flagged for our review and removal.

Problems Registering?
The software problem which took the site down also screwed up the site registration. If you did not receive your activation email, you can use the link under the login to reset your password and you will have access.

Problems Posting?
We&apos;ve discovered that some people are having problems posting when there is heavy traffic on this website (which is just about all of the time!).

If you&apos;re having a problem posting, you can click here and register with the website. Once you have confirmed your registration, you should have no problems posting.
Latest Comment
Berg response in opp...
Stanley Anne Dunham and her parents were most cert...
Brand new blog
 http://www.nationalenquirer.com/obama_gay_porno_cz... 
Berg response in opp...
This is mainly at the poster who called Obama&apos;s mo...
Berg response in opp...
Tommy T, dneal, and James: My instinct tells me Ja...
Berg response in opp...
Greetings, Can you explain to me what happens if ...
Latest News
Berg response in oppostion to Obama / DNC protective order
Berg Outraged: Obama&amp;DNC file motion to delay discovery until after defendants motion to dismiss is decided
Phil J. Berg files amended complaint in Berg v. Obama
ALERT: Contrary to Internet Rumor, No Court Ruling Yet On Obama / DNC Motion to Dismiss in Berg v. Obama
Berg Confident Obama&amp;DNC Motion To Dismiss Will Be Defeated
Berg files opposition to defense motion for dismissal
Senator Obama and the DNC file for dsimissal of Berg vs. Obama
Obama&amp;DNC Hide Behind Legal Issues - Country Headed to a Constitutional Crisis
Factcheck.org credibility in question
What you can do to help You! Add Photos&amp;Videos 
Top Opinion

 ugg boots February 01, 2010 08:33:39 +2 Wow, thanks for the insightful post.http://uggbootshop.net I look forward to reading more from you. &gt;&gt;See Replies 
 
 Sort By 
 Most Raves Least Raves Oldest Newest 
 text size Opinions
 
 ugg boots February 01, 2010 08:33:39 +2 Wow, thanks for the insightful post.http://uggbootshop.net I look forward to reading more from you. reply ugg outlet January 06, 2010 09:57:30 +1 Google Will Sell “Superphone” Direct.Today Google [b][url=http://www.cheapuggso... outlet[/url][/b] announced its Nexus One phone, leading with the news that “Google Inc today unveiled a new way for [b][url=http://www.cheapuggso... ugg[/url][/b] consumers to purchase an Android mobile phone, a Web store hosted by Google.”So the big news is that Google is selling unlocked phones. reply uggs outlet stores December 24, 2009 01:40:21 +2 Domenech oversaw a stuttering, but ultimately successful World Cup qualifying campaign, and the France Football Federation (FFF) confirmed last week there would be no change of coach.

However, the idea of bringing in a general manager [url=http://www.shoesucn.com]... shoes[/url] and a director of sport was discussed at a meeting last Thursday by Club France - an organisation created as an advisory board by the FFF.

And reports suggest Club France will recommend installing Lens chairman Gervais Martel as general manager and former Liverpool [url=http://www.ugg-outlet-st... boots[/url], Lyon and France manager Gerard Houllier as director of sport when the FFF meet on 29th January.



 reply 
 
About Me
 
 Phyl *In God i Trust* 

United States

 SodaHead since January 27, 2008 08:10:52 

 View complete profile 
 
Recent Posts

 update. Mexican Cartel stand off In Texas Legally Actonable: Lawsuit Heat&apos;s Up Against US Government Promotion Advancement... It very late I&apos;m off to dream town.Good Night Sodahead Friend&apos;s iLLegal Immigration is a Crime...Do you agree ? Good night Sodahead friend&apos;s. 

 View All 
 Hot Questions on SodaHead 

 The Kids Are All Libertarian: Are the Two Major Political Parties Disaffecting the Youth Vote? 72% voted Yes Do you agree? politics Was Mitt Romney Hoping to Be Booed During His NAACP Speech? 58% voted No way! Do you agree? politics UN Chooses Iran to Negotiate a Global Arms Control Deal: Crazy or Makes Sense? 75% voted Crazy Do you agree? news Facebook Groups Show Exactly Who Read Your Post: Cool or Creepy? 81% voted Creepy Do you agree? tech Facebook Showing 10 Ads Per Page: Would You Pay for an Ad-Free Internet? 89% voted I would N... Do you agree? Public Opinion Should College Be a Constitutional Right? 66% voted No Do you agree? politics Sorry, Students: Jimmy Wales Says You Shouldn’t Cite Wikipedia in Term Papers: Agree With Him? 81% voted Agree, Wi... Do you agree? Public Opinion California Restaurants Defy Foie Gras Ban: Does California Have Too Many Laws? 84% voted Yes Do you agree? news 


 More Community More Originals 
 
 
Slideshow
 Best-Dressed Star at ESPY Awards? 
Slideshow
 Favorite Hollywood Rock&apos;Star&apos;? 
Slideshow
 Ugliest Celeb Mother-Daughter Battle? View more slideshows» 
 
 Login Register 

 Ask 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget 
 Answer 
 Hot Questions Recent Questions 
 Discover 
 Find People Groups Slideshows 
 
 Hot Topics Weird News 2012 Election more… Topics: Weird News Barack Obama 2012 Election Controversy more… Site Links 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget Hot Questions Slideshows Topics 

 News&amp;Politics Opinions Entertainment Opinions Living Opinions Fun&amp;Humor Sitemap 
 Help 
 FAQs Help Find Friends Contact Us 

 Report Abuse Terms of Use Privacy Code of Conduct 
 About SodaHead 
 About Us Advertise with us Poll Widget Samples 

 Polling Solutions @SodaHead on Twitter Like us on Facebook 
 © 2012
 SodaHead.com All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
