<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007745" url="http://www.food.com/recipe/Low-fat-Heavy-Cream-Substitute-113203" time="2012-07-13-00:42" support="2" score="0.008206207116729385" bingtitle="Low-fat Heavy Cream Substitute Recipe - Food.com - 113203" webtitle="Low-fat Heavy Cream Substitute Recipe - Food.com - 113203">
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>... Cooking mixes Condiments, etc. ... It took nowhere near 5 minutes (more like 1 minute ) to get thick and fluffy. ... javascript&quot;&gt; SNI.Food ...</description>
	<body>
		Food.com: The most complete collection of free recipes on the Internet, trusted by home chefs throughout the world. Search I&apos;m looking for: Recipes Ingredients Members Grilling Central 
 Join Food.com for Free 
 Take the Tour | SIGN IN 
 
 User at Food.com 

 Inbox (0) 
 
 
 
 My Profile My Settings My Cookbooks My Menus My Shopping List My Favorites Sign Out 
 
 Season&apos;s Best: Zucchini Recipes 

Whether you&apos;re craving something sweet, savory, hearty or light, versatile zucchini fits the bill.
 
More Summer Favorites:

 Juicy Strawberry Desserts , Fresh Corn Recipes , Tomato Sides 
 
 
Browse by Ingredient

 Beef Recipes Chicken Recipes Chocolate Recipes Fruit Recipes Pasta Recipes Pork Recipes Seafood Recipes Rice Recipes Tofu Recipes Vegetable Recipes 
 
Explore 400,000+ Recipes

 Newest Recipes Newest Photos Our Most Popular Recipes Easy Recipes Healthy Recipes 
 
 
Join the Food.com community to rate and review recipes and save and share your own—all for free!
 Join Food.com 
 
My Recipes

 My Public Recipes 99 My Private Recipes 99 My Reviews 99 My Private Notes 99 My Photos 99 My Shopping List 99 I Want To… Submit a Recipe 
 
 Season&apos;s Best: Zucchini Recipes 

Whether you&apos;re craving something sweet, savory, hearty or light, versatile zucchini fits the bill.
 
More Summer Favorites:

 Juicy Strawberry Desserts , Fresh Corn Recipes , Tomato Sides 
 
Browse by Ingredient

 Beef Recipes Chicken Recipes Chocolate Recipes Fruit Recipes Pasta Recipes 
 
Explore 400,000+ Recipes

 Newest Recipes Newest Photos Our Most Popular Recipes Easy Recipes 
 
 
 Copycat Recipes 

Why go out to eat? Find a new favorite for tonight from this collection of 300+ copycat restaurant recipes and more.
 
Similar Cookbooks:

 Clones&amp;Copycats , Grocery Store Food Copies 
 
 
Popular Member Cookbooks

 Restaurant Copycats Dessert Cookbooks Chicken Dishes 400-Calorie Meals Vegetarian Cookbooks Cookies Cookbooks Mexican Cookbook Low-Fat Cookbooks Rice Cooker Recipes Appetizer Cookbooks 
 
Explore More Cookbooks

 Newest Cookbooks All Cookbooks Healthy Cookbooks Cookbooks Forum Cookbooks FAQs 
 
 
Our free online cookbooks are like a recipe box, but better. Create as many as you want to help save, sort and share your recipes.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Cookbooks

 My Main Cookbook 

 All of My Cookbooks 99 
 
 Copycat Recipes 

Why go out to eat? Find a new favorite for tonight from this collection of 300+ copycat restaurant recipes and more.
 
Similar Cookbooks:

 Clones&amp;Copycats , Grocery Store Food Copies 
 
Popular Member Cookbooks

 Restaurant Copycats Dessert Cookbooks Chicken Dishes 400-Calorie Meals Vegetarian Cookbooks 
 
Explore More Cookbooks

 Newest Cookbooks All Cookbooks Healthy Cookbooks Cookbooks Forum 
 
 
 Summer Picnic 

Wow a big group of your friends with these 20+ creative backyard party picks.
 
Similar Menus

 Summer Dinner Party , Summer Lunch Al Fresco 
 
 
Popular Member Menus

 Chicken Dinners Seafood Meals Gluten-Free Menus Dinner Party Easy Menus Brunch Menus Vegetarian Menus Mexican Menus Italian Menus Winter Meals 
 
Explore More Menus

 Newest Menus All Menus Healthy Menus Menu Planning Forum 
 
 
Organize your weekly meals, parties or holiday events with our easy (and free!) online menu tool.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Menus

 All of My Menus 99 
 
 Summer Picnic 

Wow a big group of your friends with these 20+ creative backyard party picks.
 
Similar Menus

 Summer Dinner Party , Summer Lunch Al Fresco 
 
Popular Member Menus

 Chicken Dinners Seafood Meals Gluten-Free Menus Dinner Party Easy Menus 
 
Explore More Menus

 Newest Menus All Menus Healthy Menus Menu Planning Forum 
 
 
 Photo Contest: Win a Dream Trip to NYC! 

Give your next party a little French chic with wine, cocktails, cheese or hors d&apos;oeuvres from France. Submit a photo of your French Cocktail Hour and you could win.
 
More on the contest:

 All the Great Prizes , See the Full Rules 
 
 
Popular Forums

 Topic of the Month Contests&amp;Events Cooking Q&amp;A Food Photos Cooking for Kids Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Mexican Cooking Asian Cooking Dieting Breads&amp;Baking 
 
Explore the Community

 Food.com Blog Member of the Month Customer Support All Forums Contact Us 
 
 
Our community forums are the place to hang out, meet other members, trade tips and even play games.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Community

 All Community Forums My Favorite Topics 99 Chefs I Like 99 

More

 My Profile My Settings My Inbox 
 
 Photo Contest: Win a Dream Trip to NYC! 

Give your next party a little French chic with wine, cocktails, cheese or hors d&apos;oeuvres from France. Submit a photo of your French Cocktail Hour and you could win.
 
More on the contest:

 All the Great Prizes , See the Full Rules 
 
Popular Forums

 Topic of the Month Contests&amp;Events Cooking Q&amp;A Food Photos Cooking for Kids 
 
Explore the Community

 Food.com Blog Member of the Month Customer Support All Forums 
 
 
 
Popular Products

 Cookware Bakeware Cutlery Cooking Tools Small Appliances Cookbooks Shop All Categories 
 
Popular Brands

 Calphalon KitchenAid Cuisinart Le Creuset Shop All Brands 
 
 
 
Popular Products

 Cookware Bakeware Cutlery Cooking Tools Small Appliances Cookbooks Shop All Categories 
 
Popular Brands

 Calphalon KitchenAid Cuisinart Le Creuset Shop All Brands 
 
 
 
 Recipes 
 Recipes Navigation 
 Cookbooks 
 Cookbooks Navigation 
 Meal Planning 
 Meal Planning Navigation 
 Community 
 Community Navigation 
 Shop 
 Shopping Navigation Recipe Sifter 
 
 
Start Here

 Course Main Ingredient Cuisine Preparation Occasion Diet Filter by Ingredient Nutrition 
 
 1 
Select ( ) or exclude ( ) categories to narrow your recipe search.
 2 
As you select categories, the number of matching recipes will update.
 
 Make some selections to begin narrowing your results. 
 

 Get   Recipes Calories Amount per serving 
 Total Fat Saturated Fat Polyunsat. Fat Monounsat. Fat Trans Fat 
 Cholesterol Sodium Potassium Total Carbohydrates 
 Dietary Fiber Sugars 
 Protein Vitamin A Vitamin B6 Vitamin B12 Vitamin C Calcium Iron Vitamin E Magnesium Alcohol Caffeine 
Find exactly what you&apos;re looking for with the web&apos;s most powerful recipe filtering tool.
 You are in: Home / Recipes / 

 Low-fat Heavy Cream Substitute Recipe Lost? Site Map http://www.food.com/recipe/Low-fat-Heavy-Cream-Substitute-113203 
Low-fat Heavy Cream Substitute
 
By Dancer^ 
 
Select One

 Contact This Chef Chef&apos;s Page Chef&apos;s Recipes Chef&apos;s Photos Chef&apos;s Reviews Chef&apos;s Cookbooks Chef&apos;s Menus Add to Favorites 
 
Added March 11, 2005 | Recipe #113203
 
Categories: Sauces Cooking mixes Condiments, etc. 
 More 
 Eggs/dairy Ontario Canadian North american Low fat Low cholesterol Low sat. fat Low calorie Low carb Healthy 2 Healthy Low in... Food processor/blender &lt;15 mins 5 ingredients or less No Cook Small appliance 3 steps or less Time to make Easy Inexpensive Equipment Technique 
 
 Recipe Ratings&amp;Reviews (20) Photos (0) 
 Sponsored by: 
This recipe has no photos
 Add Your Photos 5.0 
 
 
 Rate it! | Read 20 Reviews 
 
Total Time:

Prep Time:

Cook Time:
 
 5 mins 

 5 mins 

 0 mins 
 
 Dancer^ &apos;s Note:

I have used this a few times and you can&apos;t tell the difference.
 
RECIPE TOOLS

 Print Recipe View Full Screen 
Full-Page View expands the recipe ingredients and directions for easy viewing in the kitchen.
 Add a Private Note Add Your Photos Ask a Question 
Get answers about this recipe in our Cooking Q&amp;A forum.
 Submit a Correction 
Spot a typo or missing ingredient? Submit your correction for review.
 
 
SAVE THIS RECIPE

 Add to Cookbook 
Save this recipe in your online cookbook to access when you need it.
 Add to Shopping List 
Add this recipe&apos;s ingredients to your weekly shopping list.
 Add to Menu 
Create a new menu and save this recipe for easy meal planning.
 
 
SHARE THIS RECIPE

 Send to Mobile 
Text a link of this recipe to your web-enabled cell phone.
 Email Share 
 
Ingredients:
 
Yield:
 1 1 
c.
 
Units: US | Metric 
 
 8 ounces low fat cottage cheese 3 tablespoons non-fat powdered milk 
 
Directions:
 
 1 Combine and in a blender. 2 puree for 5 minutes. 
 Add to Meal Planner Print Recipe 
Browse Our Top Sauces Recipes

 
 Very Diet Friendly Low Fat Low Cal Substitute for... 
 By Mama&apos;s Kitchen (Hope)... 
 
 
 Heavy Cream Substitute 
 By Rb85 
 
 
 Heavy Cream Substitute 
 By Chef #379453 
 
 
 Low Sodium/Low Fat Cream of Soup Mix Substitute 
 By WindLass 
 
 
 
Recipe Collections
 
 Low-Fat Salad Dressing Low-Fat Shrimp 

 Low-Fat Vegetarian Low-Fat Potatoes 

 Ice Cream Cake Chocolate Pudding 
 
 View all Recipe Collections 
 
Ratings&amp;Reviews:

 
By SusieQusie 
 
Select One

 Contact This Chef Chef&apos;s Page Chef&apos;s Recipes Chef&apos;s Photos Chef&apos;s Reviews Chef&apos;s Cookbooks Chef&apos;s Menus Add to Favorites 
 
on March 10, 2008
 
 4 5 

 I made Â½ batch of this to use in Southwest Chicken with Chipotle Cream . As others have said, it works beautifully in a cream sauce! It took nowhere near 5 minutes (more like 1 minute ) to get thick and fluffy. It blended into the sauce quickly with no graininess. That said, the uncooked taste was not like heavy cream. The powdered milk whang was very predominant. I would not hesitate to use this again in a cooked dish but would be skeptical of using it an uncooked dish where the taste would be more evident. Thanks for posting a recipe that I am sure to use time and time again! 
 1 person found this review Helpful. Was this review helpful to you? Yes | No We don&apos;t know who you are. Sign in or create an account 
By Wendy-Bob 
 
Select One

 Contact This Chef Chef&apos;s Page Chef&apos;s Recipes Chef&apos;s Photos Chef&apos;s Reviews Chef&apos;s Cookbooks Chef&apos;s Menus Add to Favorites 
 
on January 27, 2007
 
 I&apos;m not gonna rate this because I think something went wrong when I made it. Everything went ok until I added it to my pasta dish (which I had cooled somewhat) when it curdled and went rather disgusting! Clearly I&apos;ve made a grievous error somewhere as noone else has had that problem, so I will have to try again at some point. 
 1 person found this review Helpful. Was this review helpful to you? Yes | No We don&apos;t know who you are. Sign in or create an account 
By Chef #512461 
 
Select One

 Contact This Chef Chef&apos;s Page Chef&apos;s Recipes Chef&apos;s Photos Chef&apos;s Reviews Chef&apos;s Cookbooks Chef&apos;s Menus Add to Favorites 
 
on March 25, 2012
 
 5 5 

 Love this! Worked well in my recipe. Thank you for this great recipe. 
 0 people found this review Helpful. Was this review helpful to you? Yes | No We don&apos;t know who you are. Sign in or create an account 

 Read All Reviews (20) 
 
You Might Also Like...
 
 Low-Fat Coconut Cream (Or Milk) Substitute 
 By Nyteglori 
 
 View All Sauces Recipes 
Advertisement
 
Nutritional Facts for Low-fat Heavy Cream Substitute
 
Serving Size: 1 (248 g) 

Servings Per Recipe: 1
 Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 275.8   Calories from Fat 51 18% Total Fat 5.7 g 8% Saturated Fat 2.3 g 11% Cholesterol 27.1 mg 9% Sodium 866.1 mg 36% Total Carbohydrate 19.9 g 6% Dietary Fiber 0.0 g 0% Sugars 19.9 g 79% Protein 34.8 g 69% Detailed Nutrition Values About Nutrition Info 
More Ideas from Food.com
 
 Zucchini Recipes 

This versatile veggie works in fresh salads, zucchini bread, casseroles, cupcakes and more.
 
 Photo Contest: Win a Dream Trip! Essential Summer Sides Quick Summer Pies Easy Snacks 
 
More Recipes Like This From Food Network
 
 Healthy Recipes Heart Healthy Low-Fat Recipes Low-Calorie Recipes Low-Carb Recipes 
 &lt;div id=&quot;search-store&quot; class=&quot;promo pod hummus promo-pod-with-body&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;hd&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;fns-head&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/foodcom/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Food.com Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bd clrfix&quot;&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;list-store-item&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;first store-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;fns-1&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/products/shprodde.asp?SKU=193639&amp;CCAID=CBFO193639&quot; title=&quot;Paula Deen Fig Balsamic Grilling Sauce&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ifeed.cooking.com/images/products/shprodde/193639.jpg&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; alt=&quot;Paula Deen Fig Balsamic Grilling Sauce&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;item-info&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;item-description&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Paula Deen Fig Balsamic Grilling Sauce&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/products/shprodde.asp?SKU=193639&amp;CCAID=CBFO193639&quot; rel=&quot;fns-1&quot;&gt;Paula Deen Fig Balsamic Grilling Sauce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;$5.99&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;last store-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;fns-2&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/products/shprodde.asp?SKU=604704&amp;CCAID=CBFO604704&quot; title=&quot;Paula Deen Sauce and Marinade Set&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ifeed.cooking.com/images/products/shprodde/604704.jpg&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; alt=&quot;Paula Deen Sauce and Marinade Set&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;item-info&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;item-description&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Paula Deen Sauce and Marinade Set&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/products/shprodde.asp?SKU=604704&amp;CCAID=CBFO604704&quot; rel=&quot;fns-2&quot;&gt;Paula Deen Sauce and Marinade Set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;$28.95&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;browse-more&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;fns-products&quot; class=&quot;store-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cooking.com/foodcom/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Browse More Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ft&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;SNI.Food.Omniture.ClickTrack(&quot;#search-store&quot;, &quot;Food:Site: In Our Store&quot;, &quot;In_Our_Store&quot;);&lt;/script&gt; 
Advertisement
 
Over 400,000 Recipes

 All Recipes All Collections Get a Random Recipe Kitchen Dictionary Measurement Converter Request a Recipe 
 
Food.com Network of Sites

 Baking Recipes Blue Recipes Breakfast Recipes Cheese Recipes Chinese Recipes Christmas Recipes Dessert Recipes Healthy Recipes Indian Recipes Italian Recipes Mexican Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Recipes Red Recipes Restaurant Recipes Southern Recipes Thai Recipes Thanksgiving Recipes Unique Recipes Soul Recipes Dairy-Free Recipes Greek Recipes Deep-Fried Recipes Australian Recipes Low-Cholesterol Recipes MyRecipeBox.Food.com 
 
Ideas from Food.com

 How-To Videos Get Our Newsletter Carb-Free Cloud Bread Lemon-Baked Cod Creamy Cajun Chicken Pasta Microwave Caramels Banana Bread Recipe Crock-Pot Macaroni and Cheese Old-Fashioned Banana Cream Pie Whole Chicken Crock Pot Recipe 
More from Food.com

 Chef Directory Cooking Contests Cooking Q&amp;A RSS Site Tour The Food.com Blog 
 
Food.com Family
 
 
 
 Food Network 
 
 Catch Star this Week to Decide Who You Will Vote For 
 
 Cooking Channel 

 Healthy Summer Recipes Top Summer Side Dishes Best Burger Recipes 
 
 HGTV 

 Stunning Kitchen Ideas Join Us on Pinterest Design Star, Tuesdays 9/8c 
 
 Travel Channel 

 Best Sandwich in America 50 States, 50 Landmarks Best of the Road 
 
 
 Food.com: The most complete collection of free recipes on the Internet, trusted by home chefs throughout the world. 
 Recipes Cookbooks Menus Community Shop 
 Search I&apos;m looking for: Recipes Ingredients Members   See All of Scripps Networks Digital 
 Food Network Cooking Channel CityEats.com HGTV DIY Network FrontDoor.com HGTVRemodels.com Travel Channel GAC 
 
©2012 Scripps Networks , LLC. All Rights Reserved

 Sitemap | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Ad Choices | Infringements | About us | Help | Contact us
	</body>
</document>
