<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007177" url="http://www.nationalgunforum.com/showthread.php?25001-Lessons-learned-from-an-off-duty-officer/page2" time="2012-07-13-00:09" support="9" score="0.009625692723908865" bingtitle="Lessons learned from an off-duty officer - National Gun Forum" webtitle="Lessons learned from an off-duty officer">
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="156"/>
	<description>As I was standing near the front counter trying ... destruction and I think good cops die because we are taught to place ... being the setting rather than a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		{vb.raw vboptions.bbtitle} 
 
 Home Register Log In Today&apos;s Posts FAQ Search Community 
 Member List 
 
 Advertise with us Click for Rates 
 

 
 
 Forum General Discussions Concealed Carry Lessons learned from an off-duty officer 
 Reply to Thread Page 2 of 3 First 1 2 3 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 11 to 20 of 22 
Thread: Lessons learned from an off-duty officer 
 
 
 LinkBack 

 LinkBack URL About LinkBacks 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 12-01-2010  08:07 AM #11 AFPVet Senior Member Join Date Dec 2009 Posts 368 
 
 Originally Posted by dbm8301 A KFC was being robbed in my hometown in Indiana when a patron (not law enforcement) drew his weapon and held the suspect at gunpoint until police could arrive. He was criticized by law enforcement for stepping in because of the safety of everyone involved but he got the job done! If at least two or three other patrons joined in.... Going one man ninja for a robbery may not be the best move unless you believe that the robber is going to start picking people off IMO. Reply With Quote 12-01-2010  10:58 AM #12 Wag Super Moderator Join Date Sep 2010 Location New Mexico Posts 3,074 
 
 So the real question is, how do you know if the bad guy is actually going to start shooting people? Do you have to wait until he actually does shoot? In that case, someone is dead or critically injured at worst.

It&apos;s easy enough for the police/judges/juries to look at a situation an hour later or a month later and say that it wasn&apos;t necessary to shoot the guy.

What&apos;s most abhorrent are those who say that John Q. Citizen endangered the lives of other people in the establishment when in fact, it was the burglar who endangered everyone by stepping up to the counter with a gun in his hand.

Bottom line is, NOBODY can tell what the bad guy is thinking when he&apos;s standing there with his gun in his hand, pointed at the cashier. Except the bad guy, of course, and does anyone really think he&apos;s going to tell the truth about it after he&apos;s in cuffs? Not a chance.

So, having vented that off my chest, the question is, what to do? Seriously, do you wait until he fires the first shot and kills someone?

--Wag-- &quot;Great genius will always encounter fierce opposition from mediocre minds.&quot;--Albert Einstein. Reply With Quote 12-01-2010  02:53 PM #13 Rikk101 Member Join Date Aug 2010 Posts 93 
 
 This thread and the&quot;shoot or lay low&quot;thread gives me a lot to think about. I have been considering applying for a concealed carry permit. It just goes to show how much responsibility goes long with carrying a firearm..........not to be taken lightly. Nothing here to change my mind.........just a lot to think about. Reply With Quote 12-01-2010  09:46 PM #14 Wag Super Moderator Join Date Sep 2010 Location New Mexico Posts 3,074 
 
 Whatever you do, make sure you carry with a great deal of thought given to your situation. Preparing in advance for as many possible, conceivable scenarios as possible should be mandatory. All too often, I hear of people who get a gun, put some bullets in it and leave it in the nightstand for the next 12 years without ever firing a gun. Not a good thing at all.

If you&apos;re thinking, you should be reading everything you can get your hands on at least to get started.

Carry on! :-)

--Wag-- &quot;Great genius will always encounter fierce opposition from mediocre minds.&quot;--Albert Einstein. Reply With Quote 12-01-2010  09:52 PM #15 AFPVet Senior Member Join Date Dec 2009 Posts 368 
 
 I don&apos;t think any of us will know what we will do if the situation presented itself. Most likely, I would react in accordance with my military and law enforcement training. Perceptions of demeanor, how the subject holds the weapon [is he shaking] ...his voice and visual cues. Are there accomplices among the patrons? A million thoughts would probably enter my mind before I took action. Reply With Quote 01-14-2011  09:32 AM #16 Model520Fan Junior Member Join Date Jan 2011 Location PDR of MA Posts 5 
 
 Originally Posted by Wag So the real question is, how do you know if the bad guy is actually going to start shooting people? Do you have to wait until he actually does shoot? In that case, someone is dead or critically injured at worst.

It&apos;s easy enough for the police/judges/juries to look at a situation an hour later or a month later and say that it wasn&apos;t necessary to shoot the guy.

What&apos;s most abhorrent are those who say that John Q. Citizen endangered the lives of other people in the establishment when in fact, it was the burglar who endangered everyone by stepping up to the counter with a gun in his hand.

Bottom line is, NOBODY can tell what the bad guy is thinking when he&apos;s standing there with his gun in his hand, pointed at the cashier. Except the bad guy, of course, and does anyone really think he&apos;s going to tell the truth about it after he&apos;s in cuffs? Not a chance.

So, having vented that off my chest, the question is, what to do? Seriously, do you wait until he fires the first shot and kills someone?

--Wag-- Good question. I don&apos;t know whether my info is up to date, but when I took Massad Ayoob&apos;s LFI-1 over twenty years ago, a VERY high percentage of armed robberies ended with no injuries. I&apos;m not sure, but I think that most police will wait until the perp is outside the store before challenging, to avoid creating a hostage situation. Mas&apos;s rule of thumb back then was that a non-LEO should do nothing unless the perp or perps started herding people into a back room. Then it would probably be best to pick the most opportune time to incapacitate him/them.

I doubt that the odds have changed enough, if at all, to justify a different response, but you have to guess the best you can with the situation that confronts YOU. Even if you&apos;re sure that you can drop the guilty party, do you know who in the store is his seeded backup? No Monday morning QBing here, but just a suggestion in case you&apos;re not sure. Reply With Quote 01-14-2011  11:42 AM #17 coach1299 Senior Member NGF Addict! Join Date May 2008 Location NJ Posts 2,307 
 
 Originally Posted by Luvs2Play A lesson for all of us that carry.

P1 Special Report: Blood Lessons: Lessons learned from an off-duty officer involved in fatal shootout at a McDonald&apos;s by Police One Contributor Scott Buhrmaster:

Article submitted by PoliceOne member who would like to remain anonymous In response to a recent Force Science News article ( Have Gun, Will Travel? ) discussing the issue of off-duty/concealed carry, a sergeant in California shared the following account of a horrific off-duty engagement he and his family unexpectedly fell into. The hard-earned lessons he shares may save your life in an off-duty encounter, so we hope you will take them to heart.[Editors note: Because of the impact this incident has had on his family, this sergeant has asked for anonymity.]



He writes:
I had taken my family to a McDonalds Restaurant on our way to a pool party. I was off-duty, in civilian clothes, and armed.
I was standing in line and oblivious (like all the other patrons) to the fact that an armed suspect had taken the manager hostage and was forcing her to open the safe in the restaurants office. One of the cashiers had seen this and I overheard her telling another employee that the business was being robbed.
At that time, I had approximately 15 years of experience and was a SWAT team member and use-of-force/firearms instructor. I had talked to my wife about such an occurrence and we had a preplanned response. When I told her to take the children and leave the building, she did not hesitate. I began quietly telling employees and patrons to leave. My thinking was to remove as many innocent bystanders as possible and then leave myself.
I thought that because I did not see the suspect enter he must have come in from a side door or employee entrance and I assumed (wrongly) that he would go out the same way. As I was standing near the front counter trying to get some of the kitchen help to get out, the suspect came from the office area and began running in my direction.
I immediately noted the large semi-automatic pistol in his hand. The distance was about 15 to 20 yards. I drew my weapon, announced myself and took a kneeling position behind the counter. Unfortunately, the suspect raised his weapon at me and the gunfight erupted. The suspect fired a total of 2 rounds in my direction. I fired 11, striking him 10 times.
My weapon was now empty and I ran from the line of fire to reload my spare magazine. I then approached the downed suspect and could tell that he was seriously wounded. It was right then that I considered that there might be more than one&quot;bad guy&quot;(the thought had not crossed my mind before this) and I began to scan the 360 to check.
I immediately noticed a small child lying behind me. I saw blood pooling under her head and knew at a glance she was dead. One of the bullets fired at me had struck this child. Unbeknownst to me, my family had tried to exit out the fire door, which was locked. My wife was still trying to get out when the shooting started and she pushed my kids under a table where they all witnessed the gunfight.
The end result was that the suspect died, I survived, but a 9-year-old girl did not.
I tell you this story because I think that this topic is of utmost importance. It is largely ignored in mainstream police training. I want to tell you some of the lessons I learned from this incident:
1. If you are going to carry a firearm off-duty, you should carry
extra ammo. Security camera video of this incident revealed that I fired all 11 rounds from my Glock 26 in about 2 seconds. My extra mag held 17 rounds. Words cannot describe the emotion I felt when I slammed that mag into my weapon and was able to still be in the fight.
Mostly because of circumstances (distance) and my training, my rounds were on target. It could have happened differently and the reality is that most of us miss more than we hit when involved in a gun battle.
2. You cannot have the typical police mind-set in an off-duty
situation. I ended up in this incident without a radio, without backup, without body armor, handcuffs, other force options and without taking the time to think it through. I was truly most frightened when the gunfight was over and I was standing there covering the suspect with my weapon in my T-shirt and shorts.
I was really worried that one of my own guys might not recognize me. I was worried too that there might be some other off-duty copper around who would think I was the bad guy.
The smartest, most responsible thing I could have done would have been to take care of my family first. I should have seen personally to their safety. If I had grabbed them and gone outside, I would have spared them this entire experience and that little girl would probably still be alive today.
Again, words cannot describe the emotions that we all went through after this incident. I recognized afterward that it could have been one of my children lying dead because of my actions. When you are off-duty your first responsibility is to your family. You should never forget this.
3. I survived this incident. Partly due to my training and tactics.
Partly due to God&apos;s grace and blind luck. But the other side of the coin is that I got into this incident because of my training. I switched immediately into cop mode without stopping to consider that I was at a great tactical disadvantage. Most of us are driven and dedicated to the point of self destruction and I think good cops die because we are taught to place our personal safety second when others are in danger.
Because I had never trained realistically for a situation like this, I was unprepared. Most of the guys I worked with then and now carry off-duty weapons. But few of them, if any, have really taken the time to engage in realistic training and preparation for how to handle an off-duty incident.
Training can be as simple as discussing these types of situations with your coworkers. Since this shooting, I have devoted at least one quarterly range session with my students to off-duty encounters and the associated considerations.
4. The responsibility of carrying a firearm is huge. I had devoted
countless hours to training for the fight, but was not fully prepared for the aftermath. None of the training scenarios, books, films, etc.
that I learned from touched upon the fact that when you take that gun out and decide to take action, 9-year-old kids can get killed. Even if you do everything by the book, use good tactics, and are within policy and the law, the outcome can still be negative.
You have to remember that the suspect does not go to the range and he does not practice rules of weapons safety. He does not care about what&apos;s in his line of fire. If its you or him, you gotta do what you gotta do, but whether youre on-duty or off-duty we need to train to look at the totality of the incident.
Letting the bad guy go because doing otherwise would place innocent people in grave danger needs to be more socially acceptable
amongst our ranks. I think we&apos;re starting to see more of this in the pursuit policies of most agencies and I have tried to carry this message over into my training and teaching.
I guess the bottom line here is that its good to be on auto pilot when it comes to tactics in these situations, but we cant go on auto pilot in our assessment and examination of the environment and circumstances leading up to and during the event. On-duty mind-set and off-duty mind-set need to be strongly separated and the boundaries clear.
- A California Sergeant Interesting and very sad! I had a course/lesson in the NYPD academy almost 30 years ago that was called&quot;Avoiding Reflective Response&quot;and was for situations just like this. I thought that it was very helpful because it basically taught us that having a gun (especially while off duty) doesn&apos;t mean that you have to use it, but rather that you should only use it when it is absolutely a last resort, and rather remain anonymous and blend in, don&apos;t get involved without back up, but rather be more inclined to let a robbery happen as long as no violence has been initiated. It&apos;s better to obtain as much as info as possible in hopes of catching the suspect/s later under better circumstances. This is not always a given that this will be always be the best of course of action, but stats compiled over long periods of time support that you&apos;re better off avoiding a shooting at all costs. Yeah, one could argue that if the officer or armed person doesn&apos;t act that the suspect could be free to do harm elsewhere, but history shows that the chances of a peaceful apprehension later is a much better course of action than contributing to provoking a shooting, as happened in this case. The Academy course used a similar scenario with a bank lobby being the setting rather than a fast food restaurant but the situation is quite similar. Basically it was&quot;to lay low and let it go&quot;rather than draw a weapon if nothing violent had erupted. I think that this is good advice for all cops and CCW&apos;s The big exception to this is that you can use deadly force against a suspect if they have already used deadly force and is escaping, and still armed, and it&apos;s reasonably believed that they will to continue to use of deadly force if they avoid being physically stopped or apprehended. That&apos;s a situation that you can legally use deadly force where I&apos;m from. If you shoot them before they use deadly force, you&apos;re unfortunately going to be in a legal review which might consider criminal and civil sanctions against you if you can&apos;t convince the investigators that you had a legitimate reason to believe that they were going to seriously hurt or kill somebody if you didn&apos;t intervene. That&apos;s often difficult to prove, and just one more reason that&quot;Avoiding Reflective Response&quot;is the better course of action in most situations like this IMO. On the other hand I&apos;m not suggesting that if you really believe that you or someone else is going to get seriously hurt or killed if you don&apos;t intervene, then by all means do what you&apos;ve got to do, and be alive to deal with whatever the courts do. Reply With Quote 01-14-2011  05:17 PM #18 Go99 XD45 Join Date Jan 2011 Location Kearney, Nebraska Posts 42 
 
 This is a great discussion, I&apos;m new to this site but I can see I&apos;m going to enjoy the people and their posts. Thanks! Reply With Quote 01-14-2011  09:14 PM #19 Mears Senior Member Join Date Jul 2010 Posts 796 
 
 Well, I&apos;ve seen security videos where it was just more than once or twice where the robber shot the hostage even AFTER the robber got what he wanted.

Can&apos;t open the safe by himself, so he needs someone who can. Once the safe is open, the opener is no longer needed *boom*. 
Why carry an automatic rifle, a sniper rifle, and a 20mm airburst cannon when you can have all 3 in 1? Reply With Quote 01-15-2011  08:56 AM #20 Wag Super Moderator Join Date Sep 2010 Location New Mexico Posts 3,074 
 
 It&apos;s impossible to armchair quarterback all situations from the comfort of our keyboards. No one answer is always right or always wrong. The only thing you can do is assess each situation for what it is an act as best you can as you can. If we constantly worry what the jury is going to think or whether or not we&apos;re doing the right thing, we are going to make mistakes that get people killed.

What&apos;s critical is to learn to keep our brains running in a high stress situation. That, I think, is the real challenge here. If we know how to resist the unthinking, instinctive, dangerous act.

All that said, however, I also believe that if a criminal is waving a gun around in a public place, we have ample justification to shoot on the belief that his intent is apparent and the threat is imminent.

Carrying is a helluva responsibility.

--Wag-- &quot;Great genius will always encounter fierce opposition from mediocre minds.&quot;--Albert Einstein. Reply With Quote 
 Reply to Thread Page 2 of 3 First 1 2 3 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 Thread Information 
 
Users Browsing this Thread
 
There are currently 1 users browsing this thread. (0 members and 1 guests) 

 
 
 Bookmarks 
 
Bookmarks

 del.icio.us Digg StumbleUpon Google 
 
 Posting Permissions 
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts 
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On 
 
 Forum Rules 
 
 Gun Sites 
 Colt 1911 Forum Colt Forum Conceal Carry Forum Defensive Carry FN Forum Glock Forum Glock Forums Gun Forum H&amp;K;Forum Hand Gun Forum Kel Tec Forum Marlin Firearms Forum Prepper Forum Ruger Forum Smith&amp;Wesson Forum Survival Forum Taurus Forum Walther Forum XD Forum 
 Other 
 Dodge Dart Forum Evoque Forum Paintball Forum Surface Tablet Forum Treasure Forum Veloster Turbo Forum 
 
 Loading links... 
 National Gun Forum 
 
 Contact Us - National Gun Forum - Archive - Top 
Powered by vBulletin™ Version 4.0.8
Copyright©2012 vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
SEO by vBSEO©2011, Crawlability, Inc.Any use of material from this site MUST have a source link pointing to NGF.
	</body>
</document>
