<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007440" url="http://en.softonic.com/free-software-downloads/23" time="2012-07-13-00:24" support="15" score="0.01518904028329239" bingtitle="Download free software (page 23)" webtitle="Download free software (page 23)">
			<query id="000335" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001276" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000993" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000210" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001024" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000773" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000398" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000304" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000805" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000522" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001338" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000710" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000679" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>Software for Windows BioWare&apos;s return to the realm ... You may think that running a fast-food restaurant is easy...well ... If foreign languages are not your cup of tea ...</description>
	<body>
		Login Facebook Connect Create an account 
 You are here: 
 Softonic.com &gt;
 All our software downloads 
 
 
All our software downloads 
 
 Programs 

 Calibre 

 Software for Windows If you own an ebook (electronic book) reader, or just feel like reading ebooks on your desktop or netbook, Calibre will help keep them organized.Calibre is a library for eBooks. It has a big, bold...

 FIFA Online 

 Software for Windows This beta of FIFA Online has now closed, and the service is no longer available to play. However, you can download FIFA Online 2, which is a different game altogether but with similar gameplay....

 Martview 

 Software for Windows Martview is an original ebook reader that includes an extensive catalog of books and magazines.The most outstanding element in Martview is its interface, featuring an original design that lets you...

 FiNCK 

 Software for Windows FiNCK is an earie, atmospheric platformer that plays like a dark version of the classic Super Mario Bros. 2.FiNCK stands for Fire Nuclear Crocodile Killer, which doesn&apos;t seem to have much to do...

 Need For Speed World 

 Software for Windows Need For Speed World is the new online version of the extremely popular racing game franchise. It&apos;s a massively multiplayer open world game (MMO), with RPG style leveling up.Huge Open worldNeed...

 TV 

 Software for Windows This popular web tv player allows you to watch TV programs in English, Spanish, German, French, Italian, Arabic and many other languages. The live channel guide is divided by thematic categories...

 SUPER 

 Software for Windows SUPER is a useful media tool that both encodes and renders media files into a variety of different formats.The evolution of computers reveals a trend toward multimedia desktop apps where users can...

 PDF Create! 

 Software for Windows PDF Create! is a simple application that allows you to create PDFs on the fly. You won&apos;t be able to edit or modify the contents of the files, but you will be able to combine different file types,...

 Split/Second: Velocity 

 Software for Windows Split/Second: Velocity is an intense arcade racing game that drops reality for a crazy fantasy TV game show of explosions, destruction, and then more explosions.This one-race demo is pretty hefty...

 Nitro PDF Reader 

 Software for Windows Nitro PDF Reader is a handy PDF editor that covers all the basic tasks most people perform on a daily basis with PDF documents.With Nitro PDF Reader you can not only read PDF files on your...

 YouRecorder 

 Software for Windows YouRecorder Free is a simple screen recording tool that lets you save any on-screen activity on video in just a couple of clicks.With YouRecorder Free you can record images from your screen,...

 YouRecorder 

 Software for Windows YouRecorder is a simple screen recording tool that lets you save any on-screen activity on video in just a couple of clicks.With YouRecorder you can record images from your screen, either in...

 Shufflr 

 Software for Windows Shufflr is a video browser with highly integrated social features, that allows you to share what you&apos;re watching and find like-minded people and get personalized recommendations.Running through...

 MyPaint 

 Software for Windows MyPaint is a quick, easy-to-use application for digital painters. It enables you to create quick sketches or complex artistic drawings right on your computer.The best thing about MyPaint is that...

 AVG Identity Protection 

 Software for Windows AVG Identity Protection keeps your computer – and all the relevant information stored in it – safe from prying eyes.AVG Identity Protection is like an additional layer of protection that sits on...

 Subsonic 

 Software for Windows Subsonic is a 2D stealth puzzle game, that mixes retro visuals with a Portal-like dark humor.This game is the work of students at DigiPen University, and like many projects from there, Subsonic is...

 Electric Sheep 

 Software for Windows 

 Tab Utilities 

 Software for Windows Tab Utilities is a great Firefox add-on that brings new functionality to tabs in your browser.With Tab Utilities you can customize almost every single aspect of your tabs, from their appearance –...

 Cryogenic FileSplitter 

 Software for Windows Cryogenic FileSplitter is a free application to split large files, and join them up again. It&apos;s ideal for anyone who wants to email large files.No installation is required for this tiny EXE file,...

 LinkAssistant 

 Software for Windows LinkAssistant attempts to help you improve your search engine ranking by generating links for your site.It&apos;s no big secret that in order to get a top search engine placement, you need other...

 DeepBurner Portable 

 Software for Windows DeepBurner Portable works straight from your removable media, whether it&apos;s a USB flash drive, compact flash card, or even a good old floppy.
DeepBurner is an advanced and extremely powerful CD and...

 PaperPort 

 Software for Windows PaperPort is an application for organizing and sharing your documents, and helping you to digitize your paperwork.PaperPort has a very visual approach to organizing documents, which sit in the...

 Call Firewall 

 Apps for Windows Mobile Call Firewall is designed to block certain numbers from calling your phone.  Don&apos;t get me wrong, mobile phones are great and everything, but there are times when they can ruin your life a bit.You...

 Dragon NaturallySpeaking 

 Software for Windows Dragon NaturallySpeaking is amazing voice recognition software that lets you control the computer with your voice.It almost sounds like science fiction, but the truth is that Dragon...

 PaperPort 

 Software for Windows PaperPort is an application for organizing and sharing your documents, and helping you to digitize your paperwork.PaperPort has a very visual approach to organizing documents, which sit in the...

 England Football Team Fans Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows The England Football Team Fans Wallpaper is dedicated to all those supporters who will be cheering on England at the World Cup 2010.The 1024x768 desktop background is a montage of images of...

 Brazil Team Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Install the Brazil Team Wallpaper on your desktop PC and no one will be in doubt about which team you&apos;re following at the 2010 World Cup.The free Brazil Team Wallpaper features an image of the...

 PDF Converter 

 Software for Windows PDF Converter Standard is a high-spec PDF suite that will allow you to do almost anything with your PDFs - and then some!The main PDF Converter Standard interface is accessible but sleek. There...

 Dragon NaturallySpeaking 

 Software for Windows Dragon NaturallySpeaking is amazing voice recognition software that lets you control the computer with your voice.It almost sounds like science fiction, but Dragon NaturallySpeaking totally...

 Guitar Pro 

 Software for Windows Guitar Pro is a tool that aids in learning to both play and compose music for the guitar.Finding suitable software to help learn to play a musical instrument can sometimes prove to be more...

 PowerPointImageExtractor 

 Software for Windows PowerPointImageExtractor does exactly what the name says: extract images from PowerPoint – and sound - files.If you ever received a PowerPoint presentation with images and background music you’d...

 MKTwitter 

 Software for Windows MKTwitter is a simple tool that enables you to back up messages on Twitter.With MKTwitter you can not only download a copy of your own tweets to the hard drive, but also back up messages published...

 Jumplist Extender 

 Software for Windows Jumplist Extender is a handy app that lets you create custom jumplists for any application on Windows 7.Jumplists are a great feature in Windows 7 that let you access commonly used tasks and files...

 England Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re supporting the English team in the 2010 World Cup, then make sure you install this England Wallpaper.England Wallpaper has a very minimalist design, based around the England football...

 Listary 

 Software for Windows Listary is a system-embedded search tool for Windows PCsListary is very similar to Mac’s Spotlight that lets you instantly search for files, folders and apps.Listary runs in the background and...

 Max and the Magic Marker 

 Software for Windows Max and the Magic Marker is a mixture of traditional 2D platformer, and physics-based puzzles similar to Crayon Physics.You control Max, owner of a magic marker, who draws a monster which then...

 USA World Cup 2010 Widescreen Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows With this USA World Cup 2010 Widescreen Wallpaper you can show your affection for the US national team at this year&apos;s FIFA World Cup in South Africa.The 1920 x 1200-pixel image in USA World Cup...

 Apache OpenOffice 

 Software for Windows OpenOffice.org 3.0 has at last hit the shelves – but is it a viable alternative to Microsoft Word?Well, the answer is yes. OpenOffice.org 3.0 reveals itself as a very decent competitor: it&apos;s light...

 AceMoney Lite 

 Software for Windows AceMoney Lite is a freeware personal finance manager. It has all the features of its big brother except multiple accounts management. As AceMoney, AceMoney Lite helps people organize and manage...

 Ashampoo WinOptimizer 

 Software for Windows Ashampoo WinOptimizer helps you keep your system perfectly optimized for full performance in a very easy way.This Windows tweaker and optimizer is designed to provide you with professional results...

 FinalBurner 

 Software for Windows Good solid free CD and DVD burning software is often hard to find. Just when you&apos;ve got a problem with your default software or need something in a hurry, you&apos;ll find that most only burn a few...

 Sweet Home 3D 

 Software for Windows Sweet Home 3D is a sophisticated tool for creating your own interior designs.Sweet Home 3D allows your imagination to run wild without you having to lift a finger or costing you a cent. Apart from...

 StuffIt Deluxe 

 Software for Windows StuffIt Deluxe is a complete compression tool that can zip and unzip files into archives for better management and sharing.With StuffIt Deluxe you can easily compress data so that it takes less...

 MakeDisc 

 Software for Windows MakeDisc is an all-in-one disc burning application for your audio, video, image and data files. Make CDs or DVDs with a simple step-by-step process.The MakeDisc interface is simple, with four big...

 Pano2VR 

 Software for Windows Have you ever wanted to take your panoramic photos turn them into video that can be played in a player such as QuickTime or Flash? Pano2VR allows you by converting panoramic images into QuickTime...

 Xilisoft PowerPoint to Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft PowerPoint to Video Converter is a handy tool which lets you convert PowerPoint files (PPT or PPS) to a wide array of video formats.The reasons you may need to do this can be varied: you...

 Xilisoft ISO Burner 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft ISO Burner is an easy-to-use program that will allow you to burn ISO format files - as well as BIN/CUE, IMG, MDF, NRG, CDI, B5i, B6i, and DMG and some image and movie files - to disk....

 Xilisoft ISO Maker 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft ISO Maker is an easy-to-use program that will allow you to rip your CDs and DVDs to ISO format, perfect for storing on your computer, backing up your whole collection in case disaster...

 Xilisoft PowerPoint to Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft PowerPoint to Video Converter is a handy tool which lets you convert PowerPoint files (PPT or PPS) to a wide array of video formats.The reasons you may need to do this can be very varied:...

 MetaX 

 Software for Windows MetaX saves you a lot of time and typing by tagging your movie collection in a completely automated way, so that they’re easier to manage and look great in your movie manager.Using MetaX is piece...

 Office 2010 Trial Extender 

 Software for Windows The trial version for Microsoft Office 2010 must be activated after 30 days of use. But if you use Office 2010 Trial Extender, you can multiply the 30-day trial period by 5, having up to 180 days...

 Command&amp;Conquer Red Alert 3: Uprising 

 Software for Windows Command&amp;Conquer Red Alert 3: Uprising is a download-only standalone expansion to the real time strategy franchise, which doesn&apos;t require the original game.There are four mini campaigns in...

 NHL 09 

 Software for Windows NHL 09 is EA&apos;s NHL ice hockey sports game, which introduces some innovations to the long running franchise.The big change in NHL 09 is the Be A Pro mode, which like a role playing game, lets you...

 MaxBulk Mailer 

 Software for Windows If you have a business that requires contacting large numbers of clients and customers or other contacts, you need someway of contacting them and keeping in contact with them regularly.MaxBulk...

 Defraggler 

 Software for Windows Defraggler is a powerful defragmentation tool developed by the same people as Recuva and the almighty CCleaner.Defraggler is easy to install and gets straight to the point. One of the features we...

 Portable Defraggler 

 Software for Windows Portable Defraggler is a powerful defragmentation tool developed by the same people as Recuva and the almighty CCleaner.Portable Defraggler is easy to install and gets straight to the point. One...

 Microsoft Office 2010 

 Software for Windows Microsoft Office 2010 Professional Plus is a special version of the popular productivity suite aimed at developers, IT managers and other professionals.I tested the Technical Preview released a...

 Xilisoft DVD to iPhone Converter 

 Software for Windows If you don&apos;t have a portable DVD player but do have an iPhone, then you can have your cake and eat it when it comes to watching DVD movies on the move with Xilisoft DVD to iPhone Converter ....

 Taskbar Eliminator 

 Software for Windows Taskbar Eliminator is a highly simple application that will let you hide your Windows taskbar with a shortcut.Once you have installed Taskbar Eliminator, your taskbar will disappear immediately,...

 Red Dead Redemption Screensaver 

 Software for Windows Red Dead Redemption is one of the most eagerly anticipated games this year, and here’s the official screensaver to make the wait a bit easier.The People of the West is the actual name of the Red...

 FRAPS 

 Software for Windows FRAPS is a utility for taking screenshots and video of your PC. Run it in the background while you play games, and check the frame rate, make gameplay videos and take screenshots with ease.In the...

 Free YouTube Download 

 Software for Windows Free YouTube Download is a simple tool that downloads YouTube videos to your hard drive, featuring several formats namely AVI, 3GP, MP4 and the online native Flash video format, FLV.Using Free...

 Xilisoft MKV Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft MKV Converter is a multi-format app that will help you convert your MKV (Matroska) files into various formats for use on mobile devices such as iPod, Zune and Xbox.The Xilisoft MKV...

 FIFA 2010 World Cup Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows The FIFA World Cup begins on June 11 2010 and all eyes will be on South Africa to see who the best team national team on Earth is.The first World Cup to be held in Africa promises to be a...

 Poser 

 Software for Windows Poser is a nice tool to get started in computer-assisted 3D animations, as it’s fairly easy to use and includes a lot of pre-made material.With Poser you can easily create 3D characters, animate...

 Zotero 

 Software for Windows Zotero is a Firefox add-on designed to manage research sources. It ¡s perfect for students, researchers and anyone else who needs to detail, record and share where their information is coming from....

 YoWindow 

 Software for Windows YoWindow is a weather forecast app that stands out from the crowd.Instead of displaying data as a desktop notification, YoWindow features a colorful, fully-animated window that displays a nice...

 vReveal 

 Software for Windows vReveal is an excellent video editor with which you can easily enhance the quality of your videos, and also add some special effects to them.vReveal features a nicely designed interface with three...

 Starter Background Changer 

 Software for Windows Starter Background Changer is the solution to one of the most annoying limitations in Windows 7 Starter Edition: not being able to customize the desktop wallpaper.Once you install Starter...

 After the Deadline 

 Software for Windows After the Deadline is a neat add-on to check and proofread your spelling and grammar while writing online.Whether you&apos;re filling in forms, writing email or even just updating your status on...

 Iji 

 Software for Windows Iji is an action packed indie platform game, set in a future where Earth has been overrun by aliens.Your character, Iji, awakes six months after the alien attack, to find she has been turned into...

 Xilisoft Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft Video Converter Ultimate is a simple, straightforward tool that enables you to convert video files.Xilisoft Video Converter Ultimate supports a wide array of formats, with special...

 Aquazone Classic Reef Fish 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Reef Fish Pack adds new fish and coralline reefs to your Aquazone Desktop Garden virtual aquarium.With Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Reef Fish, you&apos;ll be able to...

 CloneDVD 

 Software for Windows If you are hoping to transfer your DVDs to a digital format, you could do much worse than CloneDVD. This app will allow you to both copy (rip) and write (burn) your movies to your computer or disk....

 Rising Antivirus 

 Software for Windows Rising Antivirus is complete Windows security center suite. Impressively, it has a 90 day trial period, so you can really get an idea if it&apos;s for you before you buy.Rising Antivirus provides disk...

 Universal Theme Patcher 

 Software for Windows Universal Theme Patcher applies changes to Windows XP, Vista or 7 that allow you to use unofficial themes and change the way Windows looks.This is a portable application, which means Universal...

 TweetOBox 

 Software for Windows TweetOBox joins the almost endless list of Twitter desktop clients with an AIR-based app that looks quite promising – but still needs some work.You can configure multiple Twitter accounts in...

 CyberLink PowerBackup 

 Software for Windows CyberLink PowerBackup is one of the easiest backup copy tools we’ve seen – and believe us, here at Softonic, we’ve tested a few.To use CyberLink PowerBackup you only need to follow four simple...

 CyberLink MediaEspresso 

 Software for Windows CyberLink MediaEspresso is a powerful media converter that lets you convert images, videos and music to share online or store on any portable device.Converting media with CyberLink MediaEspresso...

 Windows Error Code Lookup Tool 

 Software for Windows Windows Error Code Lookup Tool is a standalone app that can help you identify those mysterious codes you get in applications and Windows error messages.Windows Error Code Lookup Tool, also known...

 CloneDVD 

 Software for Windows If you are hoping to transfer your DVDs to a digital format, you could do much worse than CloneDVD5. This app will allow you to transfer your DVDs to a wide variety of formats, perfect for viewing...

 Xmarks 

 Software for Windows Xmarks, previously Foxmarks, is an extension for Firefox that syncs your bookmarks and other data anywhere you have it installed. It’s perfect for all those of us who work on two or more computers....

 Brave Plane 

 Software for Windows Take the the skies and free the world from invaders in Brave Plane. Your plane is equipped for the most difficult of missions - to eliminate all enemy raiders and land invaders. The detachments of...

 Windows 7 Theme 

 Software for Windows The Windows 7 Theme turns your Vista system into a Windows 7 lookalike. Windows 7 has been released and is a great success, but if you&apos;re stuck with a Vista PC for now, you can at least get the...

 TCPMP 

 Software for Windows TCPMP may remind you of the internet protocol’s name TCPIP, but it’s got nothing to do with that: it’s a simple, lightweight video player, perfect for old machines or low-spec computers.Everything...

 CreaWriter 

 Software for Windows CreaWriter is a full-screen text editor designed to provide an Ommwriter-like alternative for PC users. It&apos;s especially intended for writers and authors, or anybody who needs 100% concentration...

 Aquazone Desktop Garden 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Desktop Garden is the perfect alternative for those of you who love fish but don’t have the time – or the money – to have a real aquarium.This 3D virtual aquarium lets you enjoy a highly...

 Xilisoft DVD Copy Express 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft DVD Copy Express is a simple, efficient program that will allow you to backup your DVDs. It&apos;s basic, but very easy to use and perfect for users who want to make occasional, no-fuss copies....

 Fast Mail Server 

 Software for Windows Fast Mail Server is a fast and secure SMTP/POP3 server program. It runs as an unattended Windows NT service and can be easily configured using an accompanying Graphical User interface. It has lots...

 IP Address Shield 

 Software for Windows Hides your IP address while you are browsing the Internet and protects your identity. Whenever you surf the Web or do something else on the Internet, this program will totally protect you.Freely...

 VDownloader 

 Software for Windows VDownloader is more than just a YouTube downloader: it&apos;s a popular tool that allows you to quickly and easily download videos from a range of popular sites (including YouTube and Facebook).Using...

 StarCraft II Logo Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Its been 12 long years for StarCraft fans but on July 27 2010 (except China), the full official version of StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty will be released and for the first time, Mac owners will be...

 Travian 

 Software for Windows Travian is a free to play online multiplayer strategy game. The goal is to manage your resources well enough to expand your territory while fending off other attacking players.Travian is not an...

 USA FIFA World Cup 2010 Fan Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re supporting the USA national team in this summer&apos;s World Cup then install the USA FIFA World Cup 2010 Fan Wallpaper on your desktop.USA FIFA World Cup 2010 Fan Wallpaper features a...

 Ribbon Hero 

 Software for Windows Ribbon Hero 2 is a game that teaches you how to use Office 2007 and 2010, which introduced a new interface to the suite of apps.Many people find moving to the newer versions of Office daunting, as...

 TextPipe Pro 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a big fan of Wordpad but wish it was a little more advanced, then without doubt, TextPipe Pro is for you.With TextPipe Pro you can specify all your text processing needs through one...

 Click&apos;n View 

 Software for Windows Click&apos;n View is a fast and easy to use image viewer for WinXP/Win2000 that supports lossless editing , most popular image and video formats.
You can store thousands of images either on local disk...

 1Password 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re looking for a way of managing multiple passwords, take a look at 1Password, a rock-solid application to record your logins and, most importantly, keep them encrypted and totally safe....

 Hotkey Resolution Changer 

 Software for Windows Hotkey Resolution Changer is a handy tool that enables you to switch between different screens resolutions in just one click.Whether you’re a web designer or a software developer, you know that...

 Hero Core 

 Software for Windows Hero Core is a 2D, retro shoot&apos;em up exploration game, featuring monochrome graphics and an 80s-style soundtrack.The 8-bit-style Hero Core lets you battles as Flip Hero in the final battle...

 Sam&amp;Max The Devil&apos;s Playhouse 

 Software for Windows Sam&amp;Max The Devil&apos;s Playhouse sees the crime-fighting duo saving the universe from the power-crazed Space Gorilla General Skun-ka&apos;pe.This demo lets you play the opening sequence, where you&apos;ll...

 TimeSheet 

 Software for Windows TimeSheet is a handy tool to automatically record the time you spend on different tasks.As a time recording tool, TimeSheet will keep track of the exact amount of hours you spend on each task and...

 Xilisoft Blu-Ray to DVD Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft Blu-Ray to DVD Converter allows you to take Blu-Ray discs, and convert them into DVDs, or other more usable formats.Instead of an all in one solution, Xilisoft Blu-Ray to DVD Converter...

 Aquazone OpenWater Deep Sea Pack 

 Software for Windows Aquazone OpenWater Deep Sea Pack will give you a privileged view of the weird and wonderful sea life that dwells in the inky depths of the Marianas Trench. This expansion pack for Aquazone...

 Genetos 

 Software for Windows Genetos is a free vertical 2D shooter that takes players through the evolution of the genre, from Space Invaders to the present day.The iPhone game Space Invaders Infinity Gene took a similar...

 Granola 

 Software for Windows Granola is a small app that claims to manage your computer&apos;s power to make it as environmentally-friendly as possible - in fact, it shows you exactly how much energy you have saved.The Granola...

 Pavtube MTS M2TS Converter 

 Software for Windows Pavtube MTS M2TS Converter is an application for converting MTS, M2TS and AVCHD video formats. It&apos;s ideal for people who use HD camcorders or BluRay discs, and want to convert their movies for use...

 YouMemo 

 Software for Windows YouMemo is a note-taking tool that can be used on any computer, but which has been especially developed for those with a touch screen.With that special feature in mind, YouMemo offers a simple yet...

 Xilisoft iPad Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft iPad Video Converter lets you convert any videos from your PC to an iPad-compatible format.The user interface in Xilisoft iPad Video Converter is very easy to get to grips with. To...

 TrueTheater Enhancer 

 Software for Windows TrueTheater Enhancer is a browser plug-in especially developed to improve image quality in online videos.Once installed on your system, TrueTheater Enhancer displays a small icon over the video....

 CyberLink YouPaint 

 Software for Windows CyberLink YouPaint is the perfect tool to keep young kids entertained in front of the computer – without any risks.CyberLink YouPaint is a fun, colorful painting program where children can not...

 Task Coach 

 Software for Windows Task Coach will take care of all your pending tasks, as well as important dates and meetings, so that you never forget any of them again and you can also prepare them ahead of time. By organizing...

 Warhammer Online 

 Software for Windows Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning, or WAR, sees the cult tabletop game move to the realm of MMORPGs (Massively Multiplayer Role Playing Games). World of Warcraft rules that world, so what does...

 BrownRecluse 

 Software for Windows BrownRecluse is a web crawler, or spider, that browses the web to pull out specific information the user has defined. It can be used for tasks like email harvesting, and downloading source code....

 Xilisoft iPhone Software Suite 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft iPhone Software Suite contains just about everything you need to manage your iPhone! In fact, it&apos;s 4 tools in one namely: DVD to iPhone Converter, iPhone Video Converter, iPhone Ringtone...

 AutoSoft Online 

 Software for Windows AutoSoft Online is a complete repair shop management tool that enables you to have full control over your business.The AutoSoft Online interface is quite easy to use thanks to a graphic tool menu...

 PDFtoMusic 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a musician and have downloaded a musical score in PDF format, then PDFtoMusic cleverly reads and plays music sheets automatically.It&apos;s useful for anyone that receives or edits musical...

 MKVToolnix 

 Software for Windows MKVToolnix is a free tool for examining, inspecting and modifying the Matroska video file format.Matroska is one of the most advanced Container Formats being able to support subtitles, multiple...

 ListDJ 

 Software for Windows ListDJ displays the lyrics to the song you’re currently listening to on Spotify in a separate window, so that you can sing along with your favorite bands.You don&apos;t have to make up the words to...

 Norton PC Checkup 

 Software for Windows Norton PC Checkup is a very simple, low-effort application to keep various aspects of your PC in perfect condition.While most of us have a PC these days, not everyone is actually interested in how...

 Nero Vision Xtra 

 Software for Windows Nero Vision Xtra is a handy app for creating and editing videos and presentations. Although it doesn’t actually let you burn your creations, it&apos;s perfect for capturing and editing them before you...

 Xilisoft Blu-ray Creator Express 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft Blu-ray Creator Express helps you convert and record your favorite videos to DVD and Blu-Ray in a few easy steps.The interface in Xilisoft Blu-ray Creator Express is clear and intuitive....

 Norton Online Family 

 Software for Windows Norton Online Family allows you to monitor what different users on a computer are doing in browsers and instant messengers. Receive reports on what kids are searching for, and create rules and set...

 Xilisoft Movie Maker 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft Movie Maker is a simple but effective app to edit your movies and video files. The program is easy to use, but has a nice selection of effects and editing capabilities and should appeal to...

 PNotes 

 Software for Windows PNotes is highly customizable, flexible and free sticky note software that will allow you to keep your tasks and to-dos visible and on-schedule.If you have ever used a real Post-it note, you&apos;ll...

 ClipGrab 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re looking for a free, fast and easy to use video downloader that works independently of your browser, then ClipGrab is an interesting solution.ClipGrab download and converts videos and...

 Utilu Mozilla Firefox Collection 

 Software for Windows Testing a website in different browser versions is a must for all web designers and developers. This is where Utilu Mozilla Firefox Collection comes in handy.Utilu Mozilla Firefox Collection is a...

 iTuner 

 Software for Windows iTuner is the perfect iTunes companion: a handy desktop app that lets you manage the player with customizable keyboard hotkeys and gives you access to various other functions.With iTuner you’ll be...

 Xilisoft iPod Magic 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft iPod Magic allows you to transfer DVDs, music and video to your iPod or iPhone, without the need for iTunes.Billed as a three-in-one device management app, Xilisoft iPod Magic lets you...

 Norton Online Backup 

 Software for Windows Norton Online Backup is a great way to prevent data loss due to a virus attack, system breakdown or any other computer problem.You never know when disaster will strike, so you’d better be...

 Xilisoft Zune Converter Suite 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft Zune Converter Suite is a pack of two applications, a DVD to Zune and Zune Video Converter.While the applications are separate, they have almost identical interfaces. These are clean, and...

 iTunes 

 Software for Windows iTunes is one of the most popular media players and managers, and with good reason. Seamless integration with iPods, iPhones and iPads, one-click purchasing in the iTunes Store and an excellent...

 Transaction Generator 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve ever been suspicious that your Oracle or MySQL database is not functioning correctly, then one way of verifying it is to test the load capacity. That&apos;s exactly what Transaction Generator...

 IObit Advanced SystemCare 

 Software for Windows IObit Advanced SystemCare is a comprehensive program that aims to manage the aspects of your system that may need maintenance to keep them functioning perfectly.It has to be said that not everyone...

 IObit Security 360 

 Software for Windows IObit Security 360 Pro is a complete anti-spyware security application. It can be used to protect your computer from all types of malware, like dialers, tracking cookies, bots and trojans. It won&apos;t...

 Format Factory 

 Software for Windows Format Factory is a free, fully-featured, converter that enables you to convert audio, video, and even images, between the most popular formats.Format Factory&apos;s supported formats include WMV, AVI,...

 Gold Fish Pack 

 Software for Windows The Gold Fish Pack is an expansion set for the Aquazone Desktop Garden. This is an animated, realistic screensaver, that turns your monitor into a virtual aquarium.If you&apos;re bored of your basic...

 CyberLink PowerDirector 

 Software for Windows CyberLink PowerDirector Ultra is a complete video editor with which you can create colorful video presentations, mixing all sorts of multimedia elements: videos, images, transition effects,...

 SmartFTP 

 Software for Windows SmartFTP is a file transfer protocol that lets you transfer files from your computer to a location on the internet.SmartFPT is a free FTP client for Windows that houses all of the features...

 SkinCrafter 

 Software for Windows SkinCrafter Installer is a developer tool that performs a fresh idea in the sphere of GUI skinning. It&apos;s available for everyone who wants to be unique, express individuality and create corporate...

 4WomenOnly 

 Software for Windows Software that calculates the date of ovulation. One of the most power systems for monitoring women&apos;s health. Detect the period most propitious for conception or preventing a pregnancy.Get detailed...

 ExplorerView 

 Software for Windows How much time do you spend in Windows Explorer looking for the right file only to open it and find out that it is the wrong one?
Would you like to see and hear documents, movies, graphics and...

 Mobile Master 

 Apps for Symbian The data on my mobile phone is in a right state and I can never be bothered to sort through everything in order to manage it more effectively. Using Mobile Master finally brought some order to my...

 Lotto Pro 

 Software for Windows Winning the lottery isn´t the easiest thing in the world to do, but you can certainly improve your chances by installing this device. Lotto Pro 2005 uses mathematical calculations to analyse...

 PasswordsPro 

 Software for Windows PasswordsPro is a multifunctional and easy-to-use program to work with passwords. The application contains a number of features designed to help you manage your passwords more effectively....

 CyberLink LabelPrint 

 Software for Windows CyberLink LabelPrint is a simple application that will allow you to create personalized covers for CDs, DVDs and minidiscs and print them for immediate use.The CyberLink LabelPrint process is...

 Mobile Master 

 Software for Windows The data on my mobile phone is in a right state and I can never be bothered to sort through everything in order to manage it more effectively.Using Mobile Master finally brought some order to my...

 Sex and the City 

 Software for Windows We all know Sex and the City, the multiple Emmy Award and Golden Globe award-winning TV series that ran for six seasons - from 1998 to 2004.Noted as a very influential television show, especially...

 Xilisoft HD Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Xilisoft HD Video Converter is a simple, straightforward tool that enables you to convert video files in a very easy way.For those of us with a large video collection on our computers, Xilisoft HD...

 Random Password Generator 

 Software for Windows Random Password Generator helps you with the always annoying task of coming up with a new password every time you subscribe to a new online service.You can choose the password’s length (from 6 to...

 Picture Frame Manager 

 Software for Windows ACDSee Picture Frame Manager is a simple, easy-to-use image manager for digital picture frames.Importing images into ACDSee Picture Frame Manager is really simple, and they are all converted to...

 Smart Defrag Server 

 Software for Windows Smart Defrag Server is a defragmentation app with various options for the organization and optimization of your computer, especially designed for use with Windows Server.Smart Defrag Server is...

 NameWiz 

 Software for Windows NameWiz is a handy, straightforward application that can lend you a hand in the boring task of renaming multiple files at the same time.With NameWiz you can easily rename multiple files...

 Genie Backup Manager 

 Software for Windows Genie Backup Manager Home is a complete backup, restore and recovery utility, designed to protect your data from accidental deletion, drive failure and even natural disasters.When installed, you...

 AVS Audio Converter 

 Software for Windows AVS Audio Converter is a simple-to-use program that stands out of the crowd thanks to a clear interface, its support for all popular formats, and a handful of extra features you usually don&apos;t find...

 gedit 

 Software for Windows Linux fans will already be familiar with the world of GNOME but gedit has brought it to a wider audience by providing the default GNOME editor on Windows.gedit provides a simple interface from...

 GiliSoft Private Disk 

 Software for Windows GiliSoft Private Disk is a very basic program that will allow you to create a hidden, password protected compartment on a pendrive or HDD disk. It&apos;s an excellent way to keep sensitive material safe...

 Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Jellyfish Pack 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Jellyfish Pack is a pack with extra backgrounds and fish for your virtual aquarium.If you have Aquazone Desktop Garden installed on your computer, download Aquazone...

 Aquazone 2: Open Water 

 Software for Windows Aquazone 2: Open Water is a beautiful screensaver that lets you take a virtual snorkeling trip to the bottom of the sea.With Aquazone 2: Open Water you can transform your monitor into a relaxing...

 Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Bass Pack 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack Bass Pack is a pack with extra backgrounds and fish for your virtual aquarium.If you have Aquazone Desktop Garden installed on your computer, download Aquazone...

 DuckCapture 

 Software for Windows DuckCapture is a flexible - and free - screen capture tool that should easily meet the needs of most home users.Apart from a cute name, DuckCapture has lots going for it. Light on resources and...

 BlackWidow 

 Software for Windows BlackWidow is an internet tool that will allow you to carry out various functions, among them&quot;sniffing&quot;a website for downloadable content, scanning for email addresses, creating site maps and...

 Ares 

 Software for Windows Ares is a successful P2P application that will give you free, direct access to a huge file sharing community. It was spun-off from Gnutella in 2002, and since then has been building a strong and...

 NASA Hidden Universe 

 Software for Windows NASA Hidden Universe is a desktop theme for Windows 7 that features cool images from space.Like any other Windows 7 theme, NASA Hidden Universe is very easy to install. Simply double click the...

 Aquazone 2: Oceans of the World 

 Software for Windows Aquazone 2: Oceans of the World is an interactive ocean screensaver that features amazing 3D fish and sea life for you to explore and admire.Aquazone 2: Oceans of the World gives you a spectator&apos;s...

 Microsoft Fix It Center 

 Software for Windows PLEASE NOTE: THIS BETA IS NOW CLOSED TO WINDOWS 7 USERS.Microsoft Fix It Center is an application that scans your Windows PC for problems, and fixes those it can. It will download the latest...

 Genie Timeline 

 Software for Windows Genie Timeline is an extremely easy-to-use backup tool, that will monitor your computer and keep copies of all the files you want. This free utility has some limitations, but will cover most users&apos;...

 VidCoder 

 Software for Windows Vidcoder is a video ripper and transcoder that works with both DVDs and video files. It&apos;s light, packed full of configuration options and in all, a pleasure to use.Vidcoder is the ideal tool if...

 IObit Uninstaller 

 Software for Windows IObit Uninstaller is an uninstaller app to give you extra help when removing programs that are difficult to remove.The app opens displaying a list of all the software installed on your computer....

 Doro PDF Writer 

 Software for Windows Doro PDF Writer installs a virtual printer on your system with which you can create PDF documents for free from any Windows app.With Doro PDF Writer you don’t need an expensive PDF editor to...

 PhraseExpress 

 Software for Windows Do you write similar sentences and expressions all the time? Do you have to write almost identical email messages on a daily basis? Then PhraseExpress is going to save you loads of time....

 EssentialPIM Portable 

 Software for Windows EssentialPIM Portable manages your personal information without leaving any traces on your system, as you can run it directly from your USB memory device.EssentialPIM Portable can securely...

 Google Email Uploader 

 Software for Windows NOTE: THIS TOOL IS NO LONGER SUPPORTED BY GOOGLE.If you’re planning to migrate to Gmail there’s one thing you’ll need to do for sure: import all the messages in your old desktop client to the new...

 EssentialPIM 

 Software for Windows When Elena reviewed EssentialPIM, her only complaint was that some of the best tools were only available in the Pro version. I think that gives you a pretty good idea of what I&apos;m going to say about...

 Aquazone Bass Edition 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Bass Edition is a screensaver that turns your monitor into a virtual desktop aquarium. Like other virtual fish tanks, it never needs cleaning, and it&apos;s filled with fish who never need...

 Aquazone Seven Seas Deluxe 

 Software for Windows Aquazone Seven Seas Deluxe features an amazing array of 40 stunning Fish, Sharks, Turtles, and Jellyfish making it one of the most complete aquarium solutions out there. The colors and swimming...

 ComparatorPro 

 Software for Windows When you have your documents scattered across several computers (desktop and laptop, home and office) it’s hard to keep track of them all. Luckily ComparatorPro can now lend you a hand....

 Nero BackItUp&amp;Burn 

 Software for Windows So you&apos;ve finally decided to create backup copies on a regular basis. Good for you! Now the only thing left is to find the right app for the task.Nero BackItUp&amp;Burn, included as part of Nero...

 Windows 7 Start Button Changer 

 Software for Windows This application really does exactly what it says. If you&apos;re bored of Windows 7&apos;s Start button, this little app will allow you to change it!Windows 7 Start Button Changer is a simple application,...

 Fruix 

 Software for Windows Fruix is a match-3 game with a fruity theme that like many games of this genre, is maddeningly addictive.Fruix requires you to match fruits with a focus on planning ahead so you don&apos;t get...

 Unity 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve got the expertise to create high-end games, then Unity is a powerful application to help you design them.Unity sports a stylish GUI and is strictly for professionals in high-end game...

 Nero Burning ROM 

 Software for Windows Nero Burning ROM is a classic program that allows you to burn to disk. Anything goes, from data disks to audio CDs and HD DVDs. The program offers a range of options that is practically unmatched,...

 The Sims 2: Bon Voyage 

 Software for Windows What can you do with your sims when you grow tired of staying at home? Exactly: take them on a fantastic trip with The Sims 2: Bon Voyage!The Sims 2: Bon Voyage is a new expansion set for The Sims...

 Jc Net Meter 

 Software for Windows Is your internet connection fast enough? Are you sure you’re getting what you paid for when you bought your data plan? Now you can check with Jc Net Meter.Jc Net Meter is a useful, easy-to-use...

 VMware Player 

 Software for Windows Virtual machines are a handy way to avoid having to install real software on your computer that could potentially damage your system. If you’ve never used virtual machines before, VMware Player is...

 QT TabBar 

 Software for Windows As anybody who spends serious time on a computer knows, any help navigating your file and folder structure is very welcome.QTTabBar is a small and slightly mysterious application to do just that....

 VIPRE Antivirus 

 Software for Windows VIPRE Antivirus is a security suite designed to be lightweight and easy on resources, so you can be protected while maintaining PC performance.This application protects your PC from viruses and...

 TVRename 

 Software for Windows When you follow a dozen different TV shows, you really need some organization in your hard drive so that you don&apos;t get dates, stories and characters all mixed up.And TVRename is the perfect app for...

 Aquazone Classic Expansion Pack 

 Software for Windows The Aquazone screensaver is one of the most realistic of its kind on PCs.The Aquazone Arowana Classic Expansion Pack adds even more depth and realism to the Aquazone screensaver. The pack adds...

 Uniblue PowerSuite 

 Software for Windows Uniblue PowerSuite is a 3-part optimization app that aims to speed up your computer by offering you all 3 Uniblue optimization tools in one - RegistryBooster, SpeedUpMyPc and DriverScanner....

 MySims 

 Software for Windows MySims is a special adaptation of the original Sims game to play on Nintendo consoles (DS and Wii), which was later on ported to the PC as well. Being primarily a game aimed at children, MySims...

 GPL MPEG-1/2 DirectShow Decoder Filter 

 Software for Windows GPL MPEG-1/2 DirectShow Decoder Filter allows you to play MPEG 1 and MPEG 2 streams in any media player based on DirectShow, such as Media Player Classic.This won&apos;t be necessary for most PC users,...

 WebDrive 

 Software for Windows Imagine if you could mount an FTP server on your desktop so you could access it like any other local drive.You can with WebDrive which integrates SFTP, WebDAV, FTP, FTPS, or GroupDrive servers...

 TorrentSpy 

 Software for Windows The intent behind TorrentSpy is to give the BitTorrent power-user all the information they can get in one place. The primary motivating feature is the ability to see in real time the current number...

 Download Accelerator Manager 

 Software for Windows Download Accelerator Manager (also known as DAM) is a free internet download manager that will help manage and speed up your downloads.If you download frequently but don&apos;t use a download...

 Lotto Sorcerer 

 Software for Windows Lotto Sorcerer is the premier, state-of-the-art, multi-threaded lottery number analysis and lottery prediction software. Originally based on the advanced statistical theories of Deming and Juran,...

 Total Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Total Video Converter is a multi-format video converter, editor and player.As video apps go, Total Video Converter handles bunches of formats. Not only can it convert between various file formats,...

 SweetIM 

 Software for Windows Smileys are a cool way of making your emails and instant messages more fun. Most communication applications have some built-in, but they can be boring - after all, everyone&apos;s got them. Spice things...

 Peggle Nights 

 Software for Windows PopCap Games are probably the kings of casual gaming, and Peggle is one of the jewels in their crown. Peggle Nights, sequel to Deluxe, gives us more ball bouncing, peg clearing action.Because the...

 Mipony 

 Software for Windows File hosting sites are a great way to share large files online, but they are also a pain to browse: extra clicks, waiting times, checking back to see if the download is finished and start another...

 Excel Soccer World Cup 2010 Planner 

 Software for Windows Excel Soccer World Cup 2010 Planner lets you track the latest scores and standings in the FIFA World Cup in South Africa.Excel Soccer World Cup 2010 Planner is a highly advanced Excel spreadsheet...

 File Grinder 

 Software for Windows Renaming files is always a long, boring task. So why not take advantage of meta-tags to automate the whole process?This is precisely what you can do with File Grinder, a handy tool that helps you...

 Red Dead Redemption 

 Software for Windows Few games are as hotly anticipated as Rockstar&apos;s Red Dead Redemption. The Grand Theft Auto publisher knows better than anyone else how to make open world games that people love to play in, and this...

 Videolan Movie Creator 

 Software for Windows The developers of one of the most popular video players in the world, VLC Media Player, have started a new, promising project: Videolan Movie Creator.We say “promising” because Videolan Movie...

 Eraser 

 Software for Windows When you empty files from the recycle bin, they are not securely deleted from your hard drive. It&apos;s possible to retrieve data that has been&apos;erased&apos;in that way. Eraser deletes files properly and...

 Web Site Maestro 

 Software for Windows The bigger your website grows, the longer it can take to load in a browser. This is especially true if your site is rich in mutlmedia content.Web Site Maestro is designed as an optimizer to...

 SunlitGreen BatchBlitz 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve ever wanted to convert or edit lots of photos, you&apos;ll be aware it can really take time.BatchBlitz can speed up the process by performing certain tasks on as many photos as you want...

 Justin Bieber 

 Software for Windows Teenage superstar Justin Bieber is a bit of a phenomenon. Discovered on YouTube and skyrocketed to fame, he is one of the most popular R&amp;B artists around. Songs such as Baby are major hits, and...

 Microsoft .NET Framework 

 Software for Windows Microsoft .NET is a special platform aimed at helping developers create new applications for Windows.Microsoft .NET Framework 4 features all the necessary components to develop and run .NET-based...

 toDoo 

 Software for Windows To-do lists are a handy way to keep track of all your pending tasks, and toDoo is a good example of a small, useful app to do just this.With toDoo you can easily manage tasks, both professional...

 EverNote 

 Software for Windows EverNote is an application that works together with an online service to let you capture, store and sync anything on multiple devices.The EverNote utility features versions for many different...

 Artistic Font Collection 

 Software for Windows Bored of the typical Times New Roman or Comic Sans? Try one of the original fonts included in Artistic Font Collection and see the difference it makes.Artistic Font Collection is a free pack of...

 The Saboteur 

 Software for Windows The Saboteur is a stylish open world action game. Set in a stylized, over-the-top 1940s Paris, your undercover saboteur has to run, fight, climb and chase his way around the city to avenge your...

 The Sims 2: Apartment Life 

 Software for Windows With The Sims 2: Apartment Life you&apos;ll give your sims the opportunity to leave their peaceful towns and move to an apartment in a large city.The Sims 2: Apartment Life adds a new neighborhood to...

 Uploadr 

 Software for Windows Do you often need to share large files online? It can get really complicated, unless you have a handy tool such as Uploadr.Sharing files online with Uploadr is dead simple. All you need to do is...

 The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-Earth II, The Rise of the Witch-King 

 Software for Windows The Lord Of The Rings: Battle For Middle Earth II was a sequel that improved a lot on the original Tolkien-themed real time strategy game.This expansion pack centers on the Witch King, Sauron&apos;s...

 The Sims 2: Free Time 

 Software for Windows The Sims 2: Free Time helps you manage a slight problem all we sim players deal with in our games: how to spend your sims&apos;spare time.With The Sims 2: Free Time, your sims can choose a hobby from...

 Bejeweled Blitz 

 Software for Windows Bejeweled Blitz is a frantic, quickfire version of PopCap&apos;s classic matching puzzle game, which forces you to think fast to rack up huge multipliers before the time runs out. Hugely popular online,...

 FIXIO PC Cleaner 

 Software for Windows Sometimes I think that if I have to review another PC cleaning application, I&apos;ll scream. Why? The vast majority are at best average, and at worst, completely useless. So how did Fixio PC Cleaner...

 WW Points Calculator 

 Software for Windows If you favor the Weight Watchers method of keeping your weight under control, you might appreciate this WW Points Calculator.WW Points Calculator is a simple app in the extreme - there are no...

 Nero Multimedia Suite 

 Software for Windows Nero Multimedia Suite is a result of Nero&apos;s evolution over the last few years. It has evolved from a simple CD burning application to a full-featured multimedia suite. It has as many critics as it...

 Access Password 

 Software for Windows MS Access uses underlying Jet Database Engine. Using AccessPassword you can recover passwords for any Jet database, not only Access databases. Access password supports user passwords (most...

 The Sims 2: Pets 

 Software for Windows Do you miss anything in your Sim family? Of course.. pets! Having a dog or a cat is now possible with The Sims 2: Pets.The Sims 2: Pets is an expansion set that allows your sims to have a pet at...

 Gilisoft DVD Region CSS Decryption 

 Software for Windows When you own a DVD, there&apos;s nothing more irritating than realizing that you can&apos;t make a copy of it because it has copy protection. DVDs are delicate things, and if you value your movies, you may...

 Mirror&apos;s Edge 

 Software for Windows Set in an authoritarian future, Mirror&apos;s Edge is a unique 3D platform game where you play a free-running courier delivering secret and sensitive messages around the city.The runner, Faith, is...

 ZuluPad 

 Software for Windows There are a lot of notepad apps out there, and some of them have really cool functions. If you are craving simplicity, however, take a look at ZuluPad, a crisp, clean notepad application with a...

 Ad-Aware 

 Software for Windows Most users will be familiar with Ad-Aware, the antispyware app that’s been around the block a few times. What you might not know, however, is that with version 10, developers Lavasoft have made the...

 yBook 

 Software for Windows If you want the ease of ebooks with the feel of an old-style paperback, take a look at yBook.This free, lightweight ebook reader takes ebooks from various sources - including straight from a web...

 Photo Magician 

 Software for Windows Photo Magician is a batch photo editor that lets you resize many photos all at once.OverviewIf you&apos;ve ever needed to convert or resize multiple photos at the same time, you know how long and...

 Need For Speed: Undercover 

 Software for Windows Need For Speed is one of the best know franchises in racing games, and this installment, Need for Speed: Undercover, features the same mix of high octane arcade-style driving.Need for Speed:...

 The Sims 2: University 

 Software for Windows College years were by far the best time of my life. This is probably why The Sims 2: University is my favorite Sims expansion pack!The Sims 2: University is the first expansion set for The Sims 2....

 Dragon Age Origins 

 Software for Windows Dragon Age Origins is the huge, Dungeons and Dragons-like Role Playing game from Bioware. After the epic futuristic role players like Fallout 3, does this return to a classic fantasy setting mark a...

 Glint 

 Software for Windows Are you the kind of user who like to be in control of everything? Then Glint is for you.Glint is a small yet effective system monitoring tool that doesn’t require installation and with which you...

 The Sims 3: World Adventures 

 Software for Windows The Sims 3: World Adventures is the first expansion set for the popular life simulator The Sims 3, but it&apos;s not the first holiday-themed pack released by EA (remember The Sims: Vacation and The...

 Antenna 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re tired of iTunes, Winamp, Spotify or whatever you use to listen to music, why not trying online radio for a change?Antenna lets you browse thousands of online radio stations worldwide....

 The Half-Life 2: Episode Pack 

 Software for Windows The Half-Life 2: Episode Pack includes the two episodes released after Half-Life 2, as well as an online death-match game.The episodes are the biggest draw, expanding and continuing the fantastic...

 Nuance PDF Reader 

 Software for Windows When thinking about PDF editors, Adobe Acrobat Reader is probably the one that comes to mind first. But that doesn&apos;t mean there aren&apos;t alternative tools that can do the job just as well – such as...

 Battlefield Bad Company 2 

 Software for Windows Battlefield Bad Company 2 is the latest in the venerable and popular FPS series. Playing in a team of four war-weary, cynical soldiers in a gripping story that takes them all over the globe,...

 SLOW-PCfighter 

 Software for Windows Tools designed to speed up your PC are ten a penny, and with good reason - nobody likes a slow computer!SLOW-PCfighter aims to cure your PC of sluggishness by checking out and repairing a...

 Mass Effect 

 Software for Windows Mass Effect is an action role playing game, set in a universe populated by many intelligent species, of which Humanity is only one, and for once perhaps not the most noble.Even for science fiction...

 Nitro PDF Professional 

 Software for Windows If there is one thing that no computer user will ever be stuck for, it&apos;s a PDF application. From viewing to converting and creating to printing, there are literally hundreds of programs that claim...

 M.U.G.E.N 

 Software for Windows Chances are, you’ve probably played on several games created by the M.U.G.E.N graphics engine.2D fighting classics such as Street Fighter and Paws of Fury were originally developed on it. Today,...

 HDClone Free Edition 

 Software for Windows 

 SecondShell 

 Software for Windows SecondShell is a pack of small features and enhancements that can make window managing and browsing much more comfortable on your Windows computer, especially if you use a laptop.When you launch...

 Mass Effect 2 

 Software for Windows The second part of the trilogy, Mass Effect 2 sees the return of protagonist Commander Shepard in a huge role playing action space opera.It&apos;s well designed for new players, as well as people who...

 onOne Plug-In Suite 

 Software for Windows Photoshop is certainly the best photo editor out there, but that doesn&apos;t mean it can&apos;t be enhanced with add-ons.This is the case of onOne Plug-In Suite, an excellent set of plug-ins for Photoshop...

 IM ToolPack 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve ever wanted a quick and easy way of sharing images and screenshots with your friends, take a look at IM ToolPack. This simple but effective tool combines a simple screenshot feature,...

 Arena Online 

 Software for Windows Arena Online is a massively multiplayer online role playing game, set in a land with a fairly typical fantasy cast of races, monsters, castles and environments.Starting out with few abilities and...

 RDesc Portable 

 Software for Windows File hosting sites are a handy tool to share files, especially if they&apos;re of considerable size. But browsing those pages is also a pain: banners and ads everywhere, queues, waiting times...Luckily...

 HoDoKu 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ve tested lots of sudoku apps, but none of them were as detailed and feature rich as HoDoKu.With HoDoKu you can generate as many sudokus as you want and solve them straight away. You can also...

 Aplus Total DVD Ripper 

 Software for Windows With the number of mobile devices out there, you may want to convert your DVDs to a format that&apos;s suitable for your iPod or phone. That&apos;s precisely what Aplus Total DVD Ripper will let you do - rip...

 RecipeMaster 

 Software for Windows RecipeMaster is a comprehensive, easy-to-use recipe manager that manages to outdo most of the competition - while also being free.Recipe software doesn&apos;t always have the best reputation - it can...

 3D Flying Easter Eggs Screensaver 

 Software for Windows Easter is right here, so what about start celebrating with a bit of computer decoration?3D Flying Easter Eggs Screen Saver is a colorful screensaver that will spice up your computer while you&apos;re...

 RDesc 

 Software for Windows File hosting sites are a handy tool to share files, especially if they&apos;re of considerable size. But browsing those pages is also a pain: banners and ads everywhere, queues, waiting times...Luckily...

 Spore Creepy&amp;Cute Parts Pack 

 Software for Windows The Sims creator Will Wright&apos;s Spore divided reviewers and players alike. Was it creation genius, taking you on a fantastic evolutionary journey from single celled life to futuristic space...

 iScreensaver Designer 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s easy to create your own personalized screensavers if you know how and iScreensaver Designer is an excellent tool for doing so. Screensaver Designer 4 is a cross-platform screensaver editor...

 Ashampoo Snap 

 Software for Windows Ashampoo Snap is a feature rich screen capturing tool, for taking screenshots and screencasts.Like most screen capture tools, you can set hot keys for many of the capture features with Ashampoo...

 Ashampoo Anti-Malware 

 Software for Windows The all-new Ashamapoo Anti-Malware is a rewritten version of their previous security tool Ashampoo AntiSpyware, and includes a bunch of improvements and new features.The first thing that caught my...

 Cave Story 

 Software for Windows Cave Story is a 2D adventure platform game, a little like the original Caslevania and Metroid series from Nintendo, but released much later, in 2004. The work of a single Japanese programmer,...

 WipeFile 

 Software for Windows With WipeFile, you can rest assured the files and folders you delete from your computer won’t be recovered by any means.This simple yet powerful deletion tool supports more than a dozen different...

 MenuMaid 

 Software for Windows Context menus – the ones you open with a right click – are a handy way of accessing many tools and functions. The problem comes when they are ridden with options that you don&apos;t really use that...

 DriverEasy 

 Software for Windows Do you keep all your drivers up to date? Yes, it&apos;s a long, boring task, so why don&apos;t you let DriverEasy do it for you?DriverEasy scans your system in search of all missing or outdated drivers, and...

 Unify 

 Software for Windows If you have an extensive iTunes library but also like listening to music on Spotify, why not blend the two of them together?This is precisely what you can do with Unify, a simple AIR-based app...

 FileZilla Portable 

 Software for Windows FileZilla has become one of the most popular FTP clients on the net and with good reason - it&apos;s fast, reliable and packed with lots of cool features.Now things just got better with the...

 VirtualBox 

 Software for Windows VirtualBox is a free, open source solution for running other operating systems virtually on your PC.With VirtualBox, you can install any version of an operating system, such as Linux, Solaris, and...

 Wyzo 

 Software for Windows I like reviewing browsers. It&apos;s interesting to see what&apos;s out there in a market dominated by one or two giants.Wyzo is based on Firefox, so most users will have little or no problems using it....

 Eufloria 

 Software for Windows Eufloria is a relaxing, abstract strategy game set in a universe where strange plant lifeforms battle, quietly, for supremacy. This IGF Finalist game has become a little less abstract since its...

 Colorful egg wallpaper 

 Software for Windows This sweet wallpaper of delicate eggs in a wicker basket is bound to get you thinking of springtime and Easter. As the days begin to warm up and greenery sprouts, this wallpaper captures the whole...

 Sweet Easter Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows I&apos;d be lying if I said that Easter eggs weren&apos;t one of my favorite parts of the holiday, but so close to summer, I don&apos;t really need the extra calories!If you want all the fun of chocolate, but not...

 Windows Theme Installer 

 Software for Windows Windows can be easily customized with different wallpapers, window skins and other eyecandy contained in visual themes. Unfortunately these themes often come from third-party developers and won&apos;t...

 DamnVid 

 Software for Windows There are a dozen video converters out there, but a few of them stand out for their special features. One that does is DamnVid.Unlike many other similar tools I&apos;ve tested, DamnVid makes it...

 Flotilla 

 Software for Windows Blendo Games may not be a household name, but since the creation of Gravity Bone the fantastic first-person experience it&apos;s become a name worth following.Flotilla is a stylish 3D strategy game....

 MakeMKV 

 Software for Windows With MakeMKV you&apos;ll be able to convert your collection of DVD and Blu-Ray movies to a video format that can be played almost everywhere: MKV.MakeMKV is a video converter, also known as transcoder,...

 Windows Leopard XP OS X 

 Software for Windows I use Mac at home and I miss it a lot when I work with Windows at Softonic. That&apos;s why I thought about getting a Mac-inspired theme to cheer my computer up.Windows Leopard XP OS X is a basic...

 Feedling 

 Software for Windows Is your desktop working for you? It may be a mess of icons, a pretty wallpaper or just empty space. Feedling will embed any RSS feed over your wallpaper, so you can fill it with interesting news...

 Super MP3 Download 

 Software for Windows Super MP3 Download is both an MP3 search engine and a tool for downloading these files.With an interface similar in nature to iTunes, Super MP3 Download is really easy to navigate and use. The...

 C64 Commando Remake 

 Software for Windows C64 Commando Remake is a retro arcade game; a new version of a 1980s home port of an arcade game. Does that make sense? The important information is that this is a fast, one player vertical shoot...

 Flotilla 

 Software for Windows Blendo Gamesmay not be a household name, but since the creation of Gravity Bone the fantastic first person experience it&apos;s become a name worth following.Flotilla is a stylish 3D strategy game. You...

 Forewave Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Converting media formats is a necessary evil in today&apos;s multimedia world. It can get pretty complicated, with a plethora of formats, configuration settings and output parameters. If you&apos;d prefer to...

 Another World 

 Software for Windows Another World was one of the most memorable games of the 16-bit era. It was unique at the time, with it&apos;s lonely, stark atmosphere and cool polygonal graphical style.Another World is a 2D puzzle...

 MusicBee 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re tired of iTunes and looking for an alternative music player and organizer, MusicBee may be the perfect choice.MusicBee is a complete music manager and player with support for all popular...

 Easter Icons 

 Software for Windows With Easter just around the corner, it&apos;s time to start getting in the mood for the upcoming holiday. So what about downloading some new icons?The Easter Icons pack offers 15 fresh, new...

 Dream Desktop Agent 

 Software for Windows Are you bored of always having the same wallpaper? Give Dream Desktop Agent a try and you won&apos;t regret it!With Dream Desktop Agent you get access to a huge selection of high-quality images you can...

 AVS Image Converter 

 Software for Windows Are you looking for a way to convert and edit multiple image files? If so, AVS Image Converter is designed for doing just that.The interface in AVS Image Converter is really smooth and well...

 Heileen 2 

 Software for Windows Heileen 2 The Hands of Fate is a visual novel that you alter by making different choices as the story moves on. Follow the adventures of shipwrecked Heileen and her friends in this illustrated,...

 FastestChrome 

 Software for Windows FastestFox is a really popular - and useful - add-on for Firefox, so Chrome users will be glad to know that it&apos;s available for them too. Although it doesn&apos;t have exactly the same functionality (and...

 LittleRunner 

 Software for Windows Runners can be classified in two groups - the ones who are weighed down with MP3s, heart rate monitors and GPSs and the others, the low-tech types that don&apos;t need all the blinking and beeping. If...

 AVS Video Converter 

 Software for Windows With so many video formats available today, chances are you&apos;ll eventually need to convert a video file from one format to another.AVS Video Converter can give you a hand with this. This efficient,...

 KeyPass 

 Software for Windows KeyPass is a versatile password manager that types your passwords for you. Unlike other password managers that require tedious cut-and-paste or drag-and-drop operations to enter your passwords,...

 ALTools Easter Desktop Wallpapers 2006 

 Software for Windows White chocolate Easter bunnies and dark chocolate Easter eggs gather to brighten your desktop in these ALTools Easter wallpapers. The ALTools Easter bunny is a bit scared that you will eat him and...

 3D Desktop Bunny Rabbits 

 Software for Windows Well, spring is definitely in the air here at Softonic and what&apos;s more spring-like than cute rabbits?! This screensaver will bring multitudes of the furry little critters straight to your desktop,...

 Shotwell 

 Software for Windows Shotwell is a really simple photo viewer that lets you enjoy your pictures in seconds.All you need to do is connect your camera to the computer and transfer the images to Shotwell, either via the...

 TextSOAP 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re dealing with a text that&apos;s got the same error running all the way through it then it&apos;s incredibly tedious to go through it and remove the errors one by one.TextSoap is a very powerful...

 BatchRename 

 Software for Windows With BatchRename you have the power to create mass renaming rules and process multiple files quickly and easily.The menu item&quot;BatchRename files...&quot;is added to the windows shell context menu...

 Free Music Zilla 

 Software for Windows Want to download free music and video from web sites? Free Music Zilla is an automatic media downloader that monitors your web browser and grabs any music or video it finds.When it first appeared,...

 Predator 

 Software for Windows If you use a key to block access to your home or your car, why not do the same for the computer?Predator turns any USB memory device into a key that blocks access to your computer. How does it...

 myPortablePIM 

 Software for Windows For those who like to have everything planned, here&apos;s a handy portable agenda you&apos;ll be able to take anywhere with you.myPortablePIM is a surprisingly feature rich agenda that doesn&apos;t require...

 Kaspersky Internet Security 

 Software for Windows Kaspersky Internet Security 2012 is a complete security suite that offers all the advantages of Kaspersky Anti-Virus plus some extra tools that protect you from hacker attacks, identity theft, spam...

 GhostMyMail 

 Software for Windows Spam is an ever-present annoyance of modern life, and GhostMyMail has an interesting solution - fake addresses. Email is usually required to join services or access programs, but offering your...

 SIW Technician&apos;s Version 

 Software for Windows SIW stands for System Information for Windows, which perfectly describes what this app does. When running, you can get a report on almost any aspect of a computer you want.The interface is...

 iCopyExpert 

 Software for Windows The only thing I don&apos;t like about my iPod is the fact that I can&apos;t copy music from it to the computer. But you know what, this is about to change!With iCopyExpert you can read the contents of your...

 MagicCamera 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re only using your webcam for boring video chats with your mum on Skype, you&apos;re missing all the fun! With programs like MagicCamera you can now use your webcam in much more imaginative ways....

 ShutdownGuard 

 Software for Windows Accidentally shutting down, restarting or logging off your computer is a real pain in the neck. It tends to happen if you are installing new programs or working on a network where some wiseguy...

 Just Cause 2 

 Software for Windows Just Cause 2 is an excellent sandbox game, set on the huge island of Panau. You&apos;re there to overthrow the crazy dictator, using any means necessary, and luckily the Just Cause 2 gives you some...

 Battlefield: Bad Company 2 Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Battlefield: Bad Company 2 is the new pretender to Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2&apos;s first-person shooter crown? Many reviewers claim it&apos;s a smarter, more coherent game with much better gameplay,...

 Downloadr 

 Software for Windows Flickr is a great site to share photos, but sometimes it can be a bit tiring for browsing and downloading images. And this is where Downloadr comes in handy.Downloadr is a really simple app that...

 Internet Explorer 

 Software for Windows Internet Explorer 9 is the new edition of Microsoft&apos;s hugely popular web browser. Building on the success of previous editions of IE with new features and a new look, Microsoft has high hopes for...

 PCBoost 

 Software for Windows PCBoost increases computer performance by allocating higher portions of CPU power to active applications and games. PCBoost is a revolutionary product which enhances processor intensive software to...

 LookInMyPC 

 Software for Windows Whether you&apos;re a professional system admin or just a standard computer user, it&apos;s always a good idea to learn about the characteristics of your computer.LookInMyPC performs a complete system...

 Syncro Subversion (SVN) Client 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a developer or programmer working on a joint project, it&apos;s important to have someway of sharing code and documents.Syncro Subversion (SVN) Client makes it easier to share code and...

 BumpTop 

 Software for Windows PLEASE NOTE: BumpTop has been acquired by Google, and is no longer available for download. The developers have also stated that it will no longer be updated.If you&apos;re tired of your Windows desktop...

 Logosmartz Logo Maker Software 

 Software for Windows Do you want to make a logo but don&apos;t know where to start? LogoSmartz is a easy way to get started, and ideal if you&apos;re not confident with design.LogoSmartz comes with lots of example logos divided...

 Aide PDF to DXF Converter 

 Software for Windows Aide PDF to DXF Converter is a special tool developed with a very specific purpose: converting PDF documents to DXF, which is the format used by design programs such as AutoCAD.Using Aide PDF to...

 gDoc Fusion 

 Software for Windows If you have reports or multi-element documents to prepare and share, gDoc Fusion might be the perfect application for your needs.This interesting tool allows you to take various documents, such as...

 Tiny&amp;Big 

 Software for Windows Big has stolen Tiny&apos;s magic teleporting pants! Take control of Tiny with his grappling hook and rock-cutting laser, on his quest to take them back.Tiny&amp;Big is a 3D platform game with a twist: to...

 Ashampoo Home Designer 

 Software for Windows Decorating your new home – or giving your current one a facelift – can be tiring and difficult, unless you count on tools like Ashampoo Home Designer.With Ashampoo Home Designer you can easily...

 CyberScrub Privacy Suite 

 Software for Windows Have you ever worried about the information you are leaving behind when you surf the internet? Well, if you haven&apos;t before, you will do once you read CyberScrub Privacy Suite&apos;s scary warnings....

 Perfect PDF Reader 

 Software for Windows Whenever you think about PDF viewers, Adobe Acrobat is the one most likely to come to your mind. But that doesn&apos;t mean there aren&apos;t other choices.Perfect PDF Reader is one of them. This...

 Renault R30 Launch 2010 Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows The Renault F1 team may not be among the favorites for the 2010 constructors&apos;championship, but if there was a grand prix of wallpapers, the French outfit would definitely have a chance of getting...

 F1 2010 Wallpaper Pack 

 Software for Windows The 2010 Formula 1 season is upon us already and what an intriguing one it promises to be, with Michael Schumacher back in the driver&apos;s seat.This F1 2010 Wallpaper Pack contains high resolution...

 Audacity 

 Software for Windows For audio editing, look no further than open source wonder Audacity. You can record live, convert old records and tapes to digital, cut, copy and splice files and much more. This stable version is...

 Womble EasyDVD 

 Software for Windows If you are looking to make your own DVD, you&apos;re in luck. There are bunches of great tools around, with new products being added every day. Womble EasyDVD is the latest.Womble EasyDVD makes a good...

 Disk Doctors Data Sanitizer 

 Software for Windows Disk wiping or hard drive clearing can be necessary for a number of reasons such as to install a new operating system or to simply maintain your privacy.Disk Doctors Data Sanitizer is an ultra...

 Ferrari F10 2010 Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Add the Ferrari F10 2010 Wallpaper to your desktop and you can show everyone where your loyalties lie when it comes to F1.The gorgeous background features a promotional image of the new Ferrari...

 You Need a Budget (YNAB) 

 Software for Windows Any software that&apos;s based on Adobe AIR is a big hit with me because I think the platform lends itself to creating elegant interfaces.That&apos;s especially true with You Need A Budget (YNAB) which is...

 ABC Amber BlackBerry Converter 

 Software for Windows ABC Amber BlackBerry Converter is a handy tool too convert data stored on your BlackBerry into a format that&apos;s easier to view on a desktop computer.The program converts from IPD or BBB BlackBerry...

 Classic Menu Manager 

 Software for Windows Some people love the thrill of a new operating system and all the new changes it brings, but others like things the way they were and dread having to get to grips with new features.If you have...

 Paltalk 

 Software for Windows Paltalk is a desktop IM client that lets you chat with different people from around the world in hundreds of chat rooms – like in old-fashioned IRC channels.Paltalk includes access to hundreds of...

 ClearContext 

 Software for Windows Prioritize incoming email, assign categories to email conversations, and automate email filing with ClearContext Inbox Manager for Microsoft Outlook, the quick and easy way to take control of your...

 Macrium Reflect 

 Software for Windows Backups are not the only resource you have left when you&apos;re hit by computer disasters. Disk images are another alternative choice.With Macrium Reflect you now have access to a free disk imaging...

 Recipe Center 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s not very often that I can say this, but when I reviewed Recipe Center, I was really surprised to find that it was free. The reason? This app has all the features you would expect in a pay-for...

 G-Lock EasyMail 

 Software for Windows G-Lock EasyMail is a bulk email sending app, ideal for marketing campaigns or anyone who has to send out multiple mails to specific email lists.Tha application comes with its own Address Book,...

 Orbit Downloader 

 Software for Windows Orbit Downloader is a download manager that gives you powerful features and control, even if you have a broadband internet connection with unlimited data.With Orbit Downloader you can comfortably...

 Puzzle Quest: Challenge of the Warlords 

 Software for Windows Puzzle Quest: Challenge of the Warlords is a brand new, genre-bending title that ups the ante on traditional puzzle games by incorporating strategy, role-playing elements and a persistent...

 Parallels Desktop 

 Software for Windows Long gone are the days when your PC was restricted to running just one operating system.Nowadays, you can run several different editions of Windows plus others such as Linux simultaneously thanks...

 E-Zsoft iPod Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Want a dead simple way to play all your video files on your iPod? Look no further than E-Zsoft iPod Video Converter. The software provides a quick and easy solution for converting movies to MP4....

 SpreadsheetConverter to HTML / JavaScript 

 Software for Windows SpreadsheetConverter to HTML is an add-on for Excel that allows you to create forms for web pages without the need for professional help!The idea of SpreadsheetConverter to HTML is that you can...

 Hazard - The Journey Of Life 

 Software for Windows Hazard - The Journey Of Life is a first-person game with no shooting! There is also no one to kill, making this a really unusual 3D adventure!Hazard - The Journey Of Life is presented in really...

 Google Chrome Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve been convinced by Google&apos;s Chrome browser and want to spread the word then install this excellent Chrome wallpaper on your desktop.It&apos;s not an official Google wallpaper but the designer...

 RazorSQL 

 Software for Windows RazorSQL is a powerful SQL query tool, database browser, SQL editor, and database admin tool. It supports tabs, and allows you to open multiple database connections simultaneously. It also features...

 MeasureIt 

 Software for Windows If you have any interest in web design, understanding how pages are put together and how big different aspects of pages should be is important.MeasureIt is a tiny add-on for Firefox that adds an...

 WWE Raw 

 Software for Windows Are you a fan of WWE Raw? If you like the TV show, you&apos;re going to get a love the PC game, the WWE Raw game that’s sure to keep wrestling fans on the edge of their seats.The WWE Raw graphics are...

 Pidgin 

 Software for Windows Pidgin is an instant messenger client that is perfect for people who need to communicate with friends who use different applications, or for those who like a little more control over their...

 Wireshark 

 Software for Windows Analyzing data packets is one way to monitor for problems in your network traffic or to detect connection problems.Wireshark is a professional protocol analyzer aimed to help users in...

 UseNeXT 

 Software for Windows Usenet used to be a complicated file-sharing network that only experts could understand. Then came along UseNeXT and blew the doors right open to anyone who&apos;s familiar with clients such as eMule...

 Stylish 

 Software for Windows Changing interface styles can be a little difficult for people who haven&apos;t tried it before, as it generally involves messing around with scripts and other complicated-sounding things. With a bit of...

 RIOT 

 Software for Windows RIOT stands for Radical Image Optimization Tool, and this is precisely what it does: optimize your photos so that the file size is dramatically reduced, without skimping on image quality.When...

 Lingoversity 

 Software for Windows I love learning new languages, which is probably why I&apos;m a big fan of all language-related software tools like Lingoversity.With Lingoversity you can easily practice vocabulary and expressions in...

 SDExplorer Base 

 Software for Windows SDExplorer Base is a handy tool to manage Microsoft Live SkyDrive, an online storage service.Microsoft Live SkyDrive is a free 25GB online virtual drive you can access for free with your Windows...

 Notepad++ 

 Software for Windows Notepad++ is a free, open source application for writing text. A powerful editor full of options, Notepad++ is ideal for programming as well as normal text.Notepad++ works with tabs, so it&apos;s very...

 Towers Trap 

 Software for Windows If you fancy yourself as a bit of a military strategist then you might want to give Towers Trap a try. The aim of Towers Trap is to defend your land by preventing hoards of persistent alien...

 Logo Design Studio 

 Software for Windows Do you need a logo for your start-up but don&apos;t want to pay a fortune for it? Try creating it yourself with Logo Design Studio Pro!This app helps you create unique logos for your company, no matter...

 iGadget 

 Software for Windows iPods are excellent MP3 players, but now with iGadget you can make them even more useful.iGadget is an iPod manager that lets you transfer songs, videos and playlists from the iPod to your...

 Easy YouTube Video Downloader 

 Software for Windows Easy YouTube Video Downloader is an easy, fast and reliable add-on for Firefox that lets you download YouTube videos.The Easy YouTube Video Downloader instructions are easy: install it and open...

 Analysis Lotto 

 Software for Windows The Delta method is a statistical method that can be applied to games of chance such as lotteries. If you&apos;re a regular player and you&apos;re looking for a new way of picking your numbers, try Analysis...

 Cucusoft DVD to iPhone Converter Suite 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re sat at home looking at your DVD collection wondering how you get those movies onto your iPhone then it&apos;s high time you had a look at Cucusoft DVD to iPhone Converter Suite.This...

 Genieo 

 Software for Windows Are you looking for a fast, simple way to create a customized homepage? Let Genieo lend you a hand!Genieo is a small, simple tool that builds a custom homepage automatically in just a few minutes,...

 Puzzle Chronicles 

 Software for Windows Konami shook up the world of puzzles with Puzzle Quest, an ingenious and addictive mix of puzzle and role playing gameplay. Puzzle Chronicles continues this concept, but can it maintain the charm...

 Zipeg 

 Software for Windows If you have to decompress files regularly, especially image files, you may find Zipeg interesting. It&apos;s definitely one of the nicest image decompressors we&apos;ve used in a while.The key feature of...

 OJOsoft Audio Converter 

 Software for Windows OJOsoft Audio Converter is a simple, user friendly tool for converting your audio files so they work on different devices.This is a incredibly basic tool, but if you want a quick conversion it...

 Disk Space Fan 

 Software for Windows How is it possible that the 1TB hard drive you bought a few months ago is already running out of free space? Find the answer with Disk Space Fan!This simple tool analyzes your hard drive in just a...

 TubeHunter Media Center 

 Software for Windows TubeHunter Media Center is a complete media suite that meets all your conversion needs. It supports all popular formats and can also work with DVD and iPod.When launching TubeHunter Media Center...

 NFL Forecaster 

 Software for Windows If you follow football, you might be interested in NFL Forecaster, a application that allows you to predict winners and spreads and keep track of team performance and ranking.NFL Forecaster is a...

 Auto DWG to PDF Converter 

 Software for Windows If you use CAD (Computer Aided Design) programs, showing others your designs or drawings can be a pain if they don&apos;t have the AutoCAD application.DWG to PDF Converter takes CAD files, in DWG...

 Air Pressure 

 Software for Windows Air Pressure is a short visual novel about a relationship and its outcomes.Like adventure games, a visual novel allows players some control over their destiny. At various points you can choose...

 NTRsupport 

 Software for Windows When you&apos;re trying to help someone with a computer problem, whether it&apos;s your father, a friend or a customer, having a clear description of the situation is very important. And this is where...

 ACDSee Photo Manager 

 Software for Windows ACDSee Photo Manager lets you take full control of your photo collection from start to finish; it helps you import them to your PC from various sources, organize them in folders, fix any that need...

 Adobe Acrobat 

 Software for Windows There are several options for reading and editing PDF documents nowadays but Adobe Acrobat X was the first. This Professional version of the software gives you the power to create, read and modify...

 BattleForge 

 Software for Windows Battleforge is an interesting concept - an online massively multiplayer real time strategy (RTS) game mixed with card collecting. Set in a fantasy, Tolkien-like world, players battle each other...

 HouseShare 

 Software for Windows HouseShare is a billing tool, but with a different approach; it has been specifically designed to track bills in shared flats.If you&apos;ve ever shared a flat, you how difficult monitoring and...

 Rocketbirds: Revolution! 

 Software for Windows Rocketbirds: Revolution! is a bird-based espionage platformer. Take control of a Rambo-like chicken - HardBoiled - then infiltrate and destroy the evil Penguin dictator!This a Flash-based game,...

 Collegio Football 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a college football fan, you&apos;re going to love Collegio Football, an awesomely comprehensive guide to the sport.Collegio Football works via a main interface in which all the teams...

 Virtual Villagers - The Tree of Life 

 Software for Windows Virtual Villagers - The Tree of Life is a real time, casual sim and the fourth installment in the Virtual Villagers series. The game starts with a brief story recap - after a volcanic eruption, a...

 Abacre Restaurant Point of Sale 

 Software for Windows If you own a restaurant and need a program to manage it to the smallest detail, Abacre Restaurant Point of Sale is a good starting point.With Abacre Restaurant Point of Sale you can control every...

 StickyNote 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ve tried many virtual post-it apps, but I never found one as feature-rich and easy-to-use as StickyNote.With StickyNote you can create as many virtual notes as you need and stick them to your...

 CA Internet Security Suite Plus 

 Software for Windows CA Internet Security Suite is a complete application for protecting your system from internet threats. It also carries out file backups, system scans and regulates kids&apos;use of the web.CA Internet...

 CA PC Tune-Up 

 Software for Windows Your computer&apos;s stability and performance depends on several different factors: possible presence of virus or malware, a fragmented hard disk, outdated drivers or too many junk files.CA PC Tune-Up...

 Supreme Commander 2 

 Software for Windows Supreme Commander 2 is a real time strategy game which focuses on huge scale. You control and manage massive armies, in a future where humanity has split into three factions at war with each other....

 Electronic Recipe Manager 

 Software for Windows One thing there doesn&apos;t seem to be a shortage of is programs to manage your recipes. Electronic Recipe Manager is another contender to the throne, claiming to be a low-key, efficient way of...

 Now You&apos;re Cooking 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re an avid recipe collector like me, you&apos;ll reach a point where magazine clippings, scraps of paper and saved webpages just don&apos;t cut it any more. If your recipes seem to be getting a little...

 Dress Assistant 

 Software for Windows I&apos;m no Giorgio Armani, and as the years go by I find that buying clothes that look good on me is an increasingly challenging task.Dress Assistant is made for wannabe designers or those that want...

 E-Zsoft DVD to iPod Converter 

 Software for Windows Want to watch your DVD movies on your iPod or iPod Touch? Then you need a program such as E-Zsoft DVD to iPod Converter.As you can probably guess from the name this application fulfills one simple...

 Invoicer 

 Software for Windows With Invoicer you can easily create and print all sort of invoices, no matter what kind of company you run.Invoicer lets you create a custom list of items – your inventory – that will be...

 Business Card Studio 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re starting up a company and don&apos;t have your business cards ready yet, here&apos;s an app that can lend you a hand. Business Card Studio helps you create your own business cards, without having...

 PDFCreator 

 Software for Windows PDFCreator lets you easily create PDF documents from Windows applications - for free!PDFCreator works as a virtual printer that, instead of sending your documents to a physical device that prints...

 Moneydance 

 Software for Windows Any help you can get managing your finances is always useful in these troubled times. Moneydance offers an intelligent and comprehensive alternative which allows you to organize your finances,...

 Power Data Recovery 

 Software for Windows We&apos;ve all deleted files by accident at some point in our lives, so it&apos;s only natural that there are specific tools to recover them like Power Data Recovery. This simple tool scans your hard drive...

 Stream Torrent 

 Software for Windows Note: this app no longer seems to be supported and the developer website is down.Stream Torrent brings the best of internet video streaming and P2P technology together; it&apos;s a free app lets you...

 Paper Dreams 

 Software for Windows Early arcade games are best described as punishingly hard. Because players fed coins in machines to continue, these often simple games would never make progress easy. Despite this, many of them...

 A-PDF Merger 

 Software for Windows PDFs are useful documents, but sometimes managing and editing them can be a bit complicated. A-PDF Merger is a handy little tool that will lend you a hand, merging PDF documents without requiring a...

 Cucusoft Zune Video Converter Suite 

 Software for Windows If you have a Microsoft Zune you might be looking for a converter to make sure you can watch your favorite videos on your device. Cucusoft Zune Video Converter Suite is a program that may be able...

 Cucusoft Ultimate DVD + Video Converter Suite 

 Software for Windows If you have a lot of DVD movies and video files you&apos;d like to watch on the move, you should give Cucusoft Ultimate DVD + Video Converter Suite a try.This program can convert many popular video...

 PC Tools Antivirus 

 Software for Windows Forget about any prejudices, ditch any preconceived ideas: free anti-viruses can be as reliable and secure as any paid app! But in case of emergencies, you can now buy added support from PC Tools,...

 Hide Your IP Address 

 Software for Windows Your IP address is like your personal identification number on the web. But sometimes it&apos;s necessary to hide it – to access a certain IP-restricted web service, see a website in another language or...

 Pinnacle Studio HD 

 Software for Windows Pinnacle Studio HD is a massive video editor that includes all the tools and features you need to create your own movies.As soon as you view the example project provided for users of Pinnacle...

 OJOsoft Total Video Converter 

 Software for Windows The market for video converters is extremely full, so OJOsoft Total Video Converter has a lot of company. It offers ease of use and speed, but is extremely basic in some respects and missing common...

 Panda USB Vaccine 

 Software for Windows Email attachments and suspicious websites are not the only way to get a virus on your computer. USB memory devices are equally dangerous!With Panda USB Vaccine you can protect both your system and...

 CheckIt Registry Cleaner 

 Software for Windows The Registry is one of those key elements in your system that you need to keep in perfect shape to ensure proper performance. And CheckIt Registry Cleaner is the right tool for the job.CheckIt...

 MediaWidget - Easy iPod Transfer 

 Software for Windows I love my iPod Touch, but I always find iTunes&apos;s limitations for transferring music from the iPod to the PC quite irritating.If you&apos;re also annoyed by this ridiculous limitation, I have some good...

 Yugma 

 Software for Windows One of the problems with teleconferencing software is that it either performs poorly, costs a lot of money, or only works on one platform.I&apos;m pleased to say that isn&apos;t the case with Yugma which is...

 Station Spacewalk Game 

 Software for Windows Ever wanted to experience space? The world of video games isn&apos;t short of space experiences, but they&apos;re nearly all science fiction, and usually involve blasting some kind of aliens. NASA has...

 CA PC Tune-Up 

 Software for Windows PC tune-up programs are a bit of a Pandora&apos;s box - everybody is interested in what they might do to speed up your computer, but sometimes you&apos;re just not prepared for the amount of&apos;problems&apos;...

 GentleMouse 

 Software for Windows I can&apos;t even begin to guess how many times a day I use my mouse to click on things. What I can guess, however, is how painful it would be if I had some hand or arm injury, such as Repetitive Strain...

 AutoDWG DWGSee 

 Software for Windows If you need to open CAD files in multiple formats and can&apos;t afford to pay for AutoCAD, then AutoDWG DWGSee will do the trick. AutoDWG DWGSee allows you to view CAD files in multiple formats...

 Daniusoft Media Converter Pro 

 Software for Windows Daniusoft Media Converter Pro is designed for both audio/video format conversion and DRM (digital rights management) removal. Sometimes media has DRM included, which often means you cannot use it...

 Trend Micro Titanium Antivirus+ 

 Software for Windows Trend Micro Titanium Antivirus+ locates and protects your Windows PC from viral threats.Of all the things you don&apos;t want on your computer, a virus is probably number one. The best way to deal with...

 Norman Personal Firewall 

 Software for Windows Looking for a simple, reliable and no-nonsense personal firewall? Then Norman Personal Firewall is well worth a try.The app is designed to make your computer invisible to hackers, combining a...

 Picasa Album Downloader 

 Software for Windows Picasa Album Downloader, as you can infer from its name, is a simple tool with which you can download complete albums from the Picasa Web Albums photo sharing service.All you need to do is run the...

 VNC Scan Enterprise Console 

 Software for Windows If you have a network of computers, it may be useful to be able to manage them all from one place, and VNC Scan Enterprise Console is designed to help administrators do just that.VNC (Virtual...

 Norman Parental Control 

 Software for Windows If your children, younger siblings or any other kids in your household have access to the internet, you should keep an eye on their activities online.Norman Parental Control makes this task easier...

 Auto Loan Calculator 

 Software for Windows Thinking about buying a new car? Then you&apos;ll find this Excel workbook really helpful!With Auto Loan Calculator you can easily plan your next car purchase, taking into account every single detail....

 Mixero 

 Software for Windows There are probably enough Twitter desktop clients already, but Mixero shows there are still more ways to use the popular social media&apos;s API in inventive and useful ways.Unlike most clients, Mixero...

 Eggberts Easter Wish 

 Software for Windows As many of you will have already discovered, it&apos;s sometimes hard to find a good game with a seasonal twist. Eggberts Easter Wish is obviously designed with the Spring festival in mind, but will it...

 SoundTaxi Pro+Video Rip 

 Software for Windows As first impressions go, SoundTaxi Pro+Video Rip made a bad one. No sooner had the app installed when seven new icons appeared on my desktop and I realized that not one, but two new programs had...

 TuneUp 

 Software for Windows TuneUp is a tool that helps organize several aspects of iTunes for you.If your iTunes library is a mess, full of badly labeled tracks, TuneUp is a great way to get your library organized again....

 CyberLink Media Suite 

 Software for Windows Do you find yourself often looking for a program to burn videos, manage photos, create music compilations or print disc labels? Then look no further, because CyberLink Media Suite has all those...

 Tansee iPhone Transfer 

 Software for Windows Tansee iPhone Transfer allows you to copy music and video from your iPhone onto your PC. I know what you&apos;re thinking: you can already do this in iTunes, right? True, but Tansee iPhone Transfer...

 Cucusoft iPhone/iTouch/iPod to Computer Transfer 

 Software for Windows Cucusoft iPhone/iTouch/iPod to Computer Transfer is an application that allows you to directly access all the songs, video and photos stored on your iPod, then download them to your PC.After...

 An eggstremely 3D Easter Screensaver 

 Software for Windows There&apos;s nothing like a cute bunny on an Easter egg hunt to get you into the Easter spirit. This cute 3D screensaver is a real blast of spring cheer. The star of An eggstremely 3D Easter...

 Probability Zero 

 Software for Windows In Probability Zero you play a character who has to keep traveling down, doing all he can to stay alive. It&apos;s a downward scrolling platform game, and the platforms are procedurally generated, so...

 Norman Security Suite 

 Software for Windows Norman Security Suite is one of a bunch of tools out there that promises to rid your computer of a multitude of different threats. The suite contains three separate Norman utilities designed to...

 Norman Antivirus&amp;Antispyware 

 Software for Windows There are all manner of dangerous viruses out there that can damage your PC. By the same token, there are all manner of antivirus applications out there designed to destroy these threats.Norman...

 FLV to AVI MPEG WMV 3GP MP4 iPod Converter 

 Software for Windows Having such a descriptive name, it&apos;s difficult not to guess what the main function of this program is, isn&apos;t it?Yes: FLV to AVI MPEG WMV 3GP MP4 iPod Converter is a multi-format video converter...

 ePreserver 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re still using AOL email and would like to migrate to a different system, this is just the tool you need.ePreserver is an east way to backup your existing AOL email account. It works with...

 EMC Retrospect Express HD 

 Software for Windows You only realize the importance of backups when you really need one – but haven&apos;t done it. So before disaster strikes your computer, you better be ready!EMC Retrospect Express HD helps you create...

 Acronis Backup and Security 

 Software for Windows Acronis Backup and Security 2011 is a powerful backup utility thanks to which your most important information will always be safe.No matter how careful you are when using your computer, you can...

 Exterminate It! 

 Software for Windows Exterminate It! is an app that searches for and removes various types of malware, like trojans, rootkits and worms.After a brief installation, Exterminate It! will then look for updates to its...

 CA Anti-Virus Plus 

 Software for Windows CA Anti-Virus Plus Anti-Spyware 2010 is a very user friendly and clearly designed security solution for your PC, but one that uses a lot of your PC&apos;s system resources.Installation of CA Anti-Virus...

 Trend Micro Titanium Maximum Security 

 Software for Windows Trend Micro Titanium Maximum Security is a PC security suite that covers a variety of security concerns, including the standard firewall and spyware/virus controls, as well as a few more advanced...

 Uchuusen 

 Software for Windows Thrust has been used in video games almost since the beginning, and Uchuusen, or Spaceship, uses the idea of thrust again. However, where normally you would turn your ship and use a single thrust,...

 Logo Design Studio 

 Software for Windows Do you need a logo for your start-up but don&apos;t want to pay a fortune for it? Try creating it yourself with Logo Design Studio!This app helps you create unique logos for your company, no matter...

 AVCWare Video Converter 

 Software for Windows With so many media formats and media converters available, which one should you use? AVCWare Video Converter may be the answer.This multi-format audio and video converter proves to be a fast,...

 DRMBuster 

 Software for Windows DRMBuster is a tool for Windows PC users that removes the digital restrictions management (DRM) on certain files.Even if you legally acquire and download media files on certain websites and online...

 PDFIn PDF to DWG Converter 

 Software for Windows As anybody who uses AutoCad will know, there comes a time when you&apos;ll need to convert to .DWG or DXF. PDFIn PDF to DWG Converter does precisely this, converting PDFs or scanned documents to the...

 FotoSlate 

 Software for Windows Have you ever wanted to create a collage, a calendar or a greeting card with your own photos? FotoSlate is the right tool for the job!This incredibly easy app helps you create personalized...

 ACDSee Pro Photo Manager 

 Software for Windows ACDSee Pro Photo Manager helps you organize and keep track of all of the photographs and other images you have on your PC.ACDSee Pro Photo Manager includes a useful set of tools that allow you to...

 DAMN NFO Viewer 

 Software for Windows DAMN NFO Viewer is a handy app that allows you to view NFO files.NFO files are text-based documents that one usually finds as attachment to other files that contain extended information or...

 Easy Poster Printer 

 Software for Windows Do you have a nice photo you&apos;d like to see hanging on your wall? You can now make a poster out of it with Easy Poster Printer.True to its name, Easy Poster Printer lets you create custom,...

 Axara Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Axara Video Converter is an all-in-one video converter, downloader, editor and DVD ripper. It&apos;s compatible with most formats, so pretty much any video you have can be made to work on any device you...

 Jaksta Streaming Media Recorder 

 Software for Windows Jaksta Streaming Media Recorder is a media recorder for your PC that supports a variety of different video formats.Similar to aTube Catcher, which lets you download your favorite online videos to...

 Aimersoft Media Converter 

 Software for Windows There are so many media converters on the market these days that new programs have to be really something to make their mark. Will Aimersoft Media Converter have what it takes to impress us?Well,...

 1Click DVD Copy Pro 

 Software for Windows Would you like to be able to make perfect backup copies of your DVDs? 1Click DVD Copy Pro lets you do just that, and sports a number of options allowing you to customize what appears on your backup...

 BZFlag 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a fan of Quake 3 then you may well find yourself quickly addicted to the multi-player tank shoot-em-up BZFlag.The developers describe BZFlag as like a mix between&apos;Battlezone&apos;and&apos;Tank...

 Logitech Touch Mouse Server 

 Software for Windows Since you can just about anything with an iPhone or iPod Touch nowadays, why not control your PC with one?Logitech Touch Mouse Server allows you to control a PC with your iPhone or iPod Touch. The...

 Canvas 

 Software for Windows From the developers of popular photo tool ADCSee, here comes Canvas, a powerful tool to work on presentations, illustrations, publications and other kinds of graphical creations.Canvas is a...

 ACDSee Photo Editor 

 Software for Windows The photo viewer created by ACDsee was one of the first tools of its kind. Now the same developers offer ACDSee Photo Editor, a excellent app to edit, retouch and enhance your images.Unlike other...

 Style XP 

 Software for Windows Style XP allows you to expand the customization features of Windows XP and gives you the power to install new themes that break the mold of the existing XP shell.If you’re one of those people who...

 DVD Shrink 

 Software for Windows DVD Shrink compresses your DVDs to save space when backing them up.DVD Shrink you can easily create backup copies of media you own. Even if you have never used backup software, you&apos;ll find DVD...

 Bing Maps 

 Software for Windows While Google Earth remains the undisputed navigational heavyweight master of global mapping, Microsoft have weighed in with a reasonable effort.Bing Maps (previously known as Microsoft Virtual...

 Wallpaper Slideshow LT 

 Software for Windows If you grow tired of your wallpaper quite often but can&apos;t be bothered to change it for yourself, you need a program like Wallpaper Slideshow LT.Wallpaper Slideshow LT is a simple wallpaper changer...

 Food and Calorie Finder 

 Software for Windows If you like to keep an eye on your nutrition, an add-on like Food and Calorie Finder is just the tool you need.This Firefox extension place two small icons in your browser, a larger one on the...

 KidsMouse 

 Software for Windows You might have forgotten how hard it was to learn to use a mouse at first but it can be quite daunting the first time, especially for kids. KidsMouse is a simple collection of educational software...

 RDown Rapidshare Downloader 

 Software for Windows Do you often use RapidShare to download large files from the web? Then RDown Rapidshare Downloader is the perfect tool for you.RDown Rapidshare Downloader is a simple Firefox add-on where you can...

 Chit Chat for Facebook 

 Software for Windows If the little Facebook chat window is not enough for your communicative needs, try Chit Chat for Facebook instead.Chit Chat for Facebook is a simple desktop app that lets you use the Facebook chat...

 3D Love Clock 

 Software for Windows Would you like to be reminded of your loved ones and the time while your PC is idle? 3D Love Clock is an animated screensaver that serves as a clock and a photo frame.Once installed, you can...

 Valentine Windows 7 Theme 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s only a few days left for Valentine&apos;s. Are you ready yet? And most importantly, is your computer ready as well?If not, you can start by downloading Valentine Windows 7 Theme, a desktop visual...

 A Valentine Wish Screensaver 

 Software for Windows A Valentine Wish Screensaver is a themed set of images, poems and quotes that will rotate when your PC is idle.If you&apos;re mad about Valentine&apos;s Day, there&apos;s enough sugary variety in the images, but...

 3D Valentine Fairies 

 Software for Windows The good thing about special dates and celebrations like Valentine&apos;s is that you can decorate your computer accordingly with thematic wallpapers, screensavers, icons and more.3D Valentine Fairies...

 TotalMedia Theatre 

 Software for Windows TotalMedia Theatre is a slick, professional-looking media player that specializes in rendering your videos in the highest quality possible.For all its intimidating appearance, TotalMedia Theatre...

 UltraDefrag 

 Software for Windows In order to ensure optimal system performance, you need you keep your hard drive as organized as possible – something you can easily achieve with a defrag tool like UltraDefrag.UltraDefrag...

 Fishdom - Frosty Splash 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re after some fish-themed seasonal fun, then Fishdom - Frosty Splash is the app for you! This super cute game comprises of three parts, a virtual aquarium, puzzle and screensaver. You...

 Totally Free Teacher Tools 

 Software for Windows I wasn&apos;t entirely sure what to expect when I saw Totally Free Teacher Tools. Once I installed it, however, I could see why the developers think it might be good for teachers or other people who...

 QuickBooks Simple Start 

 Software for Windows Preparing taxes is something you shouldn&apos;t leave until the last moment – particularly since you have software tools to help you with it.  One of these tool is Qu¡ckbooks Simple Start 2010, a...

 Barra de Español 

 Software for Windows If you are learning a new language, you need all the practice you can get. I can tell you from personal experience that the easiest way to get this practice is by seeing the language in real-life...

 German Truck Simulator 

 Software for Windows From the makers of Euro Truck Simulator comes German Truck Simulator, and the title tells you all you should need to know about it. Take control of a number of realistic trucks, including licensed...

 UltraDefrag Portable 

 Software for Windows In order to ensure optimal system performance, you need you keep your hard drive as organized as possible – something you can easily achieve with a defrag tool like UltraDefrag Portable....

 Backworld 

 Software for Windows In Backworld, you can paint the world around you to expose an alternative reality. This allows you to do what looks impossible, in this charming puzzle platformer.Your character is a silent...

 C:Medieval 

 Software for Windows C:Medieval is a very basic multiplayer online slash&apos;em up, for up to a hundred players at a time. It also allows up to four players to play from the same PC.When you start the game, you&apos;ll see...

 Attack of the Paper Zombies !!! 

 Software for Windows Attack of the Paper Zombies !!! is a pretty simple real time strategy game with cute hand-drawn, top-down graphics. Take control of a group of marines, and fight of the spawning hordes of alien...

 Aliens vs. Predator 

 Software for Windows Aliens Vs Predator is an updated version of the classic 1999 horror shooter, bringing the violent terror up to date with todays powerful PCs.
The full game will feature the three-part single...

 Desert Blitz 

 Software for Windows Desert Blitz is an online strategy game based in a fictional future, where countries unable to develop alternative energy are increasingly hostile to each other. Huge oil deposits have been...

 Mission Cobra 

 Software for Windows Mission Cobra is an online strategy game, based on the world of espionage. You can be a spy for any of the most famous spy organizations in the world, like the KGB and MI6.Presented with a variety...

 Stupid Cupid Screensaver 

 Software for Windows Whether you like it or not, Valentine&apos;s Day is just around the corner, so you&apos;d better start getting into the mood! A nice way to do it is by installing Stupid Cupid.
Despite a somewhat aggressive...

 ToDoList 

 Software for Windows If you never seem to have enough time to complete your tasks, maybe you need a program like ToDoList.ToDoList can be a great help to organize your work and become more productive. This tool...

 MUkoTE 

 Software for Windows MUkoTE is a very specific app for a very concrete function: mute the sound of selected apps or windows temporarily.Before you start wondering about the purpose of this action, remember Spotify....

 SharedMinds Desktop 

 Software for Windows When you have multiple Twitter accounts, loads of followers and a ton of people following you, Twitter becomes difficult to manage. This is when you need a program like SharedMinds Desktop.
With...

 Cupid&apos;s 3D Valentine&apos;s Day Screensaver 

 Software for Windows Cupid&apos;s 3D Valentine&apos;s Day Screensaver is a great 3D screensaver and a sure way to get a Valentines vibe on your monitor.Ok, so the cynics among you might argue that St. Valentine&apos;s Day is a...

 SortPlaces 

 Software for Windows Do you feel your Firefox bookmarks are getting a little out of control? If you&apos;re having problems, download a program like SortPlaces and regain the upper hand.This Firefox add-on allows you to...

 Easy Duplicate Finder Portable 

 Software for Windows Duplicates - ugh! Clogging up your iPod, confusing your media player and generally messing up your computer, they are a major pain in the neck. Easy Duplicate Finder Portable is a portable tool to...

 ePub Maker 

 Software for Windows ePub Maker is a handy tool that lets you convert DOC and HTML documents to the ePub format, so that you can carry it around in your ebook reader.The ePub format is supported by many ebook readers,...

 Icepine Free 3GP Video Converter 

 Software for Windows Mobile phones are more than just a device to call people. Nowadays most of them offer advanced media capabilities, like support for video playback.
If you want to make the most of your phone&apos;s...

 WinMend Folder Hidden 

 Software for Windows Do you have sensitive information on your computer that shouldn&apos;t be seen by other people? Then you need a program like WinMend Folder Hidden.With WinMend Folder Hidden you can easily hide...

 CloudPad 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re looking for a simple, hassle-free note taking tool, you&apos;ve come to the right place.
CloudPad is exactly what you need: a dead simple notepad to jot down and store all those small notes...

 Super Space Rogues 

 Software for Windows Super Space Rogues is a fun 2D trading/shoot&apos;em up game. It begins with your character owing a lot of money to an angry alien overlord, then deciding to try and pay up rather than face the...

 Cut&amp;Paste 

 Software for Windows Cut&amp;Paste is an animated puzzle game based on a flip book cartoon idea. Your job is to keep the main character from danger as he goes on a journey into a city. 
The flip book is the key to Cut&amp;...

 MindManager 

 Software for Windows MindManager is a comprehensive organizer for PC users who want to keep track of just about anything in their daily lives.Sometimes complicated project management tasks can be made easier by...

 Audials Tunebite 

 Software for Windows Audials Tunebite is an all-in-one program that will let you copy and convert DRM-protected files so you can use them wherever you want.This slick-looking app performs two main functions – it...

 DocFetcher 

 Software for Windows When it comes to searching for files on your computer, there are several options. But if you need to search inside documents, then you need a very specific tool such as DocFetcher.With DocFetcher...

 Hope 

 Software for Windows Hope is a short indie point-and-click adventure game. It tells the story of a boy who wakes up unsure of who he is, and a girl he sees.
This futuristic adventure is very short, but has an unusual...

 Yasst 

 Software for Windows Twitter has become a great tool to communicate, and its increasing popularity has encouraged developers from around the globe to create all sorts of Twitter clients.Yasst is the latest one to join...

 gVim 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re serious about your editing, then gVim might well be the tool for you. This comprehensive portable app is a modified version of the Vi editor that comes with UNIX and is perfect for most...

 Cook&apos;n Recipe Organizer 

 Software for Windows There seems to be loads of cookery software landing on my desk these days. Cook&apos;n Recipe Organizer is the latest contender.Cook&apos;n Recipe Organizer has a large online community, so I was hoping...

 Screenshot Uploader 

 Software for Windows With Screenshot Uploader, you can make images of your desktop and instantly share them over the web.
To begin, you need to register an account so your images can be stored on the Screenshot...

 JDContextMenu 

 Software for Windows JDContextMenu adds some tools to the menu that appears when you right click on files or folders. There are already many functions on the right-click context menu, but if you feel there are some...

 Lock-UnMatic 

 Software for Mac Have you ever tried to empty your recycle bin only to find one file is apparently still being used, and is stopping the process? Unfortunately OSX Finder doesn&apos;t tell you what&apos;s using the file....

 Puran Defrag 

 Software for Windows Puran Defrag Free Edition is the free version of Puran Defrag, an alternative defrag tool that helps you keep your hard drive in perfect shape.Like its older brother, Puran Defrag Free Edition...

 Tumblweed 

 Software for Mac Tumblweed is a tiny Adobe Air-based desktop Tumblr app for Mac and PC.
Tumble exists somewhere between blogging and Twitter, encouraging short messages like Twitter, but also supporting so called...

 depict1 

 Software for Windows Games like Bioshock and Portal asked players some interesting questions about instructions in games - do we ever think about what we&apos;re asked to do? Depict1 is a low-fi platform game that takes the...

 Mass Effect 2 Wallpapers 

 Software for Windows Mass Effect 2 could be the game of the decade, and it&apos;s only just begun! This is a selection of 24 official wallpapers for your desktop.
Set in 2183, just after the end of the first Mass Effect,...

 DriverCure 

 Software for Windows Keeping all your drivers up to date is essential for a good, reliable performance. But checking for new versions of each and every one of your drivers can be boring!
Luckily you can now count on...

 SimpleDiagrams 

 Software for Windows A diagram is often the best way to explain certain concepts or plan a complicated step-by-step process. Now with SimpleDiagrams, they&apos;re easier than ever.SimpleDiagrams is the kind of tool that is...

 Tumblr Post 

 Software for Windows Tumblr Post is an add-on for Firefox that allows you to quickly post to your Tumblr account.Sitting in the status bar, Tumblr Post&apos;s icon won&apos;t bother you unless you want to use it. Right clicking...

 WeatherEye 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a frequent traveler then one of the most important things you&apos;ll need to check before you travel is the weather.Chances are that wherever you are going, WeatherEye has it covered with...

 YouTube HD Transfer 

 Software for Windows Watching videos on YouTube is fun, but sometimes you wish you could save the videos to your hard drive – something you can do with YouTube HD Transfer.YouTube HD Transfer is an easy-to-use free...

 Tumblr Post 

 Software for Mac Tumblr Post is an add-on for Firefox that allows you to quickly post to your Tumblr account.
Sitting in the status bar, Tumblr Post&apos;s icon won&apos;t bother you unless you want to use it. Right...

 Ask.com Toolbar 

 Software for Windows When toolbars are done badly, they can be very annoying. When they&apos;re done right, however, they can bring easily-accessed extra functionality to your browsing experience.Luckily for us, the Ask....

 avast! Internet Security 

 Software for Windows avast! Internet Security is the latest offering from avast! and offers users a chance to see how far this excellent security app has come.Visually appealingTraditionally here at Softonic we have...

 SuperAntiSpyware Portable Scanner 

 Software for Windows Viruses are not the only threat for your computer. Spyware is also a dangerous elements that you should avoid at all costs!Luckily there are tools like SuperAntiSpyware Portable Scanner that make...

 Zombie Driver 

 Software for Windows Do you like cars? Do you hate zombies? Zombie Driver is the game for you. In a pseudo 3D overhead game set in a zombie apocalypse, you have to drive around the city saving survivors, while...

 PdaNet 

 Software for Windows PdaNet lets you tether your computer to your phone&apos;s Internet connection using your USB cable, and it&apos;s really simple to set up.Trying to find a WiFi hotspot to connect your laptop or netbook can...

 Flash Video Downloader 

 Software for Windows Between dodgy files and dropped connections, getting videos from the internet can be a frustrating experience. Make things a little easier with a program like Flash Video Downloader, a low-effort...

 Circle Dock 

 Software for Windows If the Start menu in Windows is not enough for you, you can try an alternative menu like Circle Dock to access your favorite programs.
Circle Dock is a circle-shaped menu that can be easily...

 Utilu Internet Explorer Collection 

 Software for Windows Testing a website in different web browser versions is a must for all web designers and developers. This is where Utilu Internet Explorer Collection comes in handy.Just like the Mozilla Firefox...

 Vanity Remover 

 Software for Windows Vanity Remover is a simple cleaning application that searches for empty folders and deletes them.
Although it has an unusual name, this is actually a really useful tool - lots of programs and...

 Auto Mute 

 Software for Windows Have you ever been embarrassed by an accidental wake-up chime when you switch on your laptop? Maybe you want to turn on your computer at night without disturbing people in your house.Auto Mute is...

 Bloom 

 Software for Windows Are you an avid photo uploader on Facebook? If so, Bloom is going to save you loads of time.
Bloom is an easy-to-use app that connects with your Facebook account and enables you to upload photos...

 Lethal Application 

 Software for Windows Lethal Application is a vertical shoot&apos;em up with a difference - your hero can&apos;t fly, but uses her extremely powerful gun to propel herself around, while also using it to kill.
Each stage of...

 Ainvo Copy 

 Software for Windows Backup copies are the kind of thing you always leave for later and then regret you didn&apos;t create before. Don&apos;t you think it&apos;s time to put an end to this situation?
Ainvo Copy makes it easy for...

 Seesmic Look 

 Software for Windows Seesmic is a popular Twitter desktop client, and Seesmic Look aims to build on that, and introduce newcomers to the joys of Twitter.Built especially for Windows 7, although it runs on XP and...

 TunePrompter 

 Software for Windows In contrast to more complicated programs like kJams, TunePrompter makes creating your own Karaoke videos an absolute cinch.
Best of all, its absolutely free and a pleasure to use. It is supposed...

 BitWorld 

 Software for Windows BitWorld is a semi-3D dungeon exploration game. Take a wizard, knight or an archer on a journey to save your dwarf colony from an onslaught of monsters.This simple, yet unusual game is presented...

 recipefox 

 Software for Windows If you love cooking, you probably enjoy browsing the net for new recipes. If you do, then Recipefox is the app for you!
Recipefox is a Firefox add-on that allows you to&apos;grab&apos;recipes from various...

 3D Desktop Zombies! Screen Saver 

 Software for Windows Now that Christmas is out of the way, you can get rid of all those Santa screensavers and go for something a bit edgier. 
3D Desktop Zombies! Screen Saver sees zombies walk and crawl around your...

 What&apos;s my computer doing? 

 Software for Windows Not sure what that strange active process is doing on your computer? You can find more information about it with this simple tool.
What&apos;s my computer doing? is the self-explanatory name of an app...

 Tile Massacre SHMUP 

 Software for Windows Tile Massacre SHMUP is a little vertical shoot&apos;em up with a twist. There are no aliens attacking your ship - just flying tiles!
Your job is to shoot tiles in the right order to recreate the image...

 PC Tools Internet Security 

 Software for Windows Sometimes it feels like a new antivirus is released every day. PC Tools Internet Security is the latest offering on the market, a complete security suite that covers all aspect of online safety,...

 What&apos;s Running 

 Software for Windows If the standard Task Manager in Windows is not enough for you, try What&apos;s Running instead.
What&apos;s Running is a highly detailed task management app that scans your system and lists all currently...

 AeroSnap 

 Software for Windows AeroSnap gives XP/Vista users the Aero Snap capabilities of Windows 7, allowing you to&apos;snap&apos;windows to the top or sides of your screen or minimize or maximize them in just a click.If you&apos;ve...

 iWisoft Free Video Downloader 

 Software for Windows There are more and more videos being published online, on different websites and in different formats, so if you want to save them to your hard drive you need a program like iWisoft Free Video...

 Spyware Doctor with AntiVirus 

 Software for Windows Sometimes it feels like programs that promise to protect your system are as malicious as the viruses and spyware they warn about. PC Tool&apos;s Spyware Doctor with AntiVirus is an excellent security...

 Puddle 

 Software for Windows Puddle is a physics-based puzzle game, that looks similar to World of Goo, but plays completely differently.Every level of this short game requires you to tilt the world, so that a puddle of...

 radiotic 

 Software for Windows Radiotic is a Firefox add-on that allows you to browse a selection of online radio stations and listen to them from right inside your browser.The radiotic interface is clean and clear. Largely...

 SimpleSysInfo 

 Software for Windows What processor does your computer have? How much RAM memory? What about hard drive capacity? These can all be tricky questions if you don&apos;t know where to look for answers.SimpleSysInfo can lend...

 Default Programs Editor 

 Software for Windows File associations are what allows Windows to know which programs should be used to open each file type. But what if you&apos;d like to change those associations?
Here&apos;s where Default Programs Editor...

 Muso 

 Software for Windows Muso is a tool that lets users browse and sort through their music library.It&apos;s difficult to define a program like Muso. It&apos;s not a music player, nor is it a playlist manager. Instead, it can be...

 TimeStill 

 Software for Windows Time is becoming the fourth dimension for gaming, and like Braid, TimeStill requires you to manipulate time intelligently to solve puzzles and climb platforms.
Unlike Braid, TimeStill is presented...

 Spectre 

 Software for Windows Spectre is about an old man, who is trying to recall his life. The game can be played multiple times, and each time you can find and recall nine of Joseph&apos;s memories.As you move between the ages...

 Webroot Internet Security Essentials 

 Software for Windows Are you worried about security on your computer? Then you need a comprehensive security suite like Webroot Internet Security Essentials.With Webroot Internet Security Essentials you can protect...

 Ultracopier 

 Software for Windows Ultracopier is a very simple application that will help you manage moving and copying operations.Moving files isn&apos;t normally a complicated process, but when you are dealing with large volumes of...

 ShareThis 

 Software for Windows Sharing is pretty much the lifeblood of modern news, information and entertainment, with one person finding a link of interest and passing it on to their friends and peers. Most of us use so many...

 EditRocket 

 Software for Windows If you are a programmer or developer, editing is second nature. Make sure you have the right tools for the job with an editor like EditRocket.Source code-focused users are going to appreciate...

 Dark Void 

 Software for Windows Dark Void is a bold and bright third-person shoot&apos;em up set in an alien dimension in the 1930s. Cargo pilot Will, on Earth makes a detour through the Bermuda Triangle, and ends up in a dimension...

 Clipple 

 Software for Windows Some of the best applications are the ones that help you do a very simple job better. Clipple is a Firefox add-on that allows you to store multiple texts in the clipboard. When you want to use text...

 System Explorer 

 Software for Windows System Explorer is a complete tool that could be described as the standard Windows Task Manager on steroids.This full-featured system analyzing tool lets you take a sneak peek at everything that&apos;s...

 Snippage 

 Software for Windows You may have considered creating your own widget for Windows, but I&apos;m sure you never thought it would be as easy as creating them with Snippage.
Snippage is a simple AIR-based app that lets you...

 Spotify Tweaks 

 Software for Windows Spotify is a great music app, but that doesn&apos;t mean it can&apos;t be improved with extra functionality.
This is precisely what Spotify Tweaks does: add a bunch of new functions to Spotify to make it...

 Back4Sure 

 Software for Windows If your only excuse not to make backup copies of important data is that you can&apos;t find a backup tool that&apos;s easy enough for you, try Back4Sure.Back4Sure is a simple backup application with which...

 Jumper 3 

 Software for Windows Jumper 3 is a platforming brainchild of indie developer Matt Thorson, who has again created an innovative and challenging experience with this game.
You control Ogmo, a creature fabricated in a...

 CyberLink PowerProducer 

 Software for Windows Do you want to create a DVD or Blu-ray, but don&apos;t have any technical know how? Cyberlink PowerProducer 5 is designed especially for you, and anyone who wants to use their DV/HDV camcorders to...

 League of Legends 

 Software for Windows Tower Defense games have been big this year, probably reaching their purest peak with PopCap&apos;s Plants Vs Zombies. Combine the basic defense idea with fantasy and MMORPGs (Massively multiplayer...

 7 Quick Fix 

 Software for Windows The presence of malware on your system, or the installation of certain new programs can result in the deactivation of some features and services in Windows 7 that you&apos;ll surely want to repair....

 Kodu 

 Software for Windows What if you – or your kids – could create your own games? With Kodu now you can, and you don&apos;t even need any programming skills!Kodu is a Microsoft experiment that&apos;s still in development. This...

 Super Vampire Ninja Zero 

 Software for Windows Super Vampire Ninja Zero is a one-player arcade fighting game, with 90s, 16-bit styling reminiscent of Double Dragon. You play Mina, a martial arts expert with a ton of undead and demons to take...

 SubDiv 

 Software for Windows SubDiv is a smart little app that you can put in any folder you use a lot, to keep your files organized.
If you have folders that house all of your downloads or images, they can quickly become...

 RAR File Open Knife 

 Software for Windows RAR File Open Knife is a little tool that only extracts the RAR format of compressed files. The developer explains that this specialization allow it to be faster and more efficient than the...

 Love+ 

 Software for Windows Love was a tiny, brutal retro platform game, and developer Fred Wood has created a slightly friendlier version, in the shape of Love+. this version is more stable, has features that make it a...

 Rarmonkey 

 Software for Windows Not much utility-focused software can be described as cute, so Rarmonkey makes a nice change. This free application is designed to extract RAR files so you can use the documents they contain. It...

 Antiy Ghostbusters 

 Software for Windows Antiy Ghostbusters is a complete security tool that protects your system in real time and scans it in search of viruses, Trojans, spyware, rootkits and all sorts of malware.The program features a...

 MPEG Video Wizard DVD 

 Software for Windows If video editing sounds too complicated for you, try starting out with a simple video editor like MPEG Video Wizard DVD.With MPEG Video Wizard DVD you’ll be able to edit your own videos in a very...

 FreeOTFE Explorer 

 Software for Windows We all have private data on our computers that we wouldn’t want anyone to see. In these cases, the best option is to use an encryption tool like FreeOTFE Explorer.
With FreeOTFE Explorer you can...

 Cameo 

 Software for Windows Cameo is a new Windows desktop environment that&apos;s based on Linux – but don&apos;t worry, you don&apos;t need to be a Linux geek.Cameo is very easy to install: all you need to do is unzip the contents of the...

 LightShot 

 Software for Windows Sometimes simpler is better. This is probably the motto that inspired the developers of LightShot, a really simple yet handy screen capturing tool.LightShot replaces the standard PrtScr...

 QuickWayToFolders 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re like most computer users, you have more files on your computer than you realistically know how to handle. This can pose difficulties when you need to access them quickly....

 Flashnote Portable 

 Software for Windows How often do you need to take simple, quick notes? An email address, a phone number, maybe something important you need to remember or something interesting you saw online…This is where Flashnote...

 Foxit PhantomPDF 

 Software for Windows Foxit PhantomPDF is a full-featured PDF creator, editor and reader for 64-bit Windows PCs.Like Foxit’s other PDF apps, Foxit PhantomPDF is a lovely program to use. It’s light on resources and...

 The Camelizer 

 Software for Windows I love shopping online, and if you do too, you&apos;re going to like The Camelizer. I know, it&apos;s a bizarre name, but don&apos;t worry - it doesn&apos;t have anything to do with camels, unless you want to buy one....

 SplashID 

 Software for Windows If you have the dangerous habit of using the same password everywhere, or you&apos;re tired of having to turn to the password recovery service every time, you should seriously consider using a password...

 Digital Janitor 

 Software for Windows Digital Janitor is one of those small handy apps with a very specific purpose. In this case, helping you sort different file types. Imagine you have a folder with all sorts of files, where you...

 VVVVVV 

 Software for Windows Retro platform games are nothing new, but with VVVVVV, developer Terry Cavanagh has created a game that is truly special, and that easily stands alongside any of the early gaming greats.There is a...

 PhotoBook 

 Software for Mac If you&apos;d like a nicer way of viewing yours and your friends&apos;photos on Facebook, PhotoBook is for you. When Photobook is started, it&apos;s necessary to log in to Facebook, to give the application...

 Squid And Let Die 

 Software for Windows Squid And Let Die is an arcade game of survival - Your task is to collect dots, while avoiding fire from the sentry bots that patrol the perimeter.
By the author of Squid Yes, Not So Octopus...

 MAGIX Mobile Movie Creator 

 Software for Windows Modern mobile devices have so many cool features that it would be a real pity to miss out on any of them. Make sure you can watch your videos when you&apos;re on the go with a converter like MAGIX...

 Calme 

 Software for Windows One of the first things you need to take care of when starting a new year is getting a new calendar. But instead of buying a standard calendar like everyone else, why not create one by yourself?...

 Screenpresso 

 Software for Windows They say the first impression is what counts, but in the case of Screenpresso this could be a bit misleading. At first sight, Screenpresso seems to be the standard, simple screen capturing tool...

 ClipTrap 

 Software for Windows When working on your PC, the clipboard is undoubtedly one of the most used features in Windows. It&apos;s a shame then, that it&apos;s pretty limited! 
ClipTrap is a fantastic, portable little application...

 Sparkbooth 

 Software for Windows Sparkbooth (formerly known as Party Booth) is the closest thing you&apos;ll ever have to a photo booth on a PC.Photo booths are great fun and Sparkbooth adds a new dimension as it uses your webcam to...

 Pixel Force: Left 4 Dead 

 Software for Windows Left 4 Dead and its sequel are maybe the best Zombie shooters, and cooperative multiplayer games ever made. What if it was released on the original Nintendo Entertainment System? That&apos;s what...

 Photograbber 

 Software for Windows Photograbber allows you to download all tagged photos of yourself or your friends on Facebook.If you&apos;ve ever wanted to have copies of all the photos people tag of you on Facebook, you can download...

 ZFactura 

 Software for Windows ZFactura is a complete invoicing application, suitable for self-employed workers or small companies that don&apos;t need a complete finance and accounting management.
ZFactura includes everything you...

 ZGestion 

 Software for Windows ZGestion is an accounting and invoicing application with which you can easily manage stock, sales and customers in your small or middle-sized company.
The program features a friendly interface...

 EagleMailer 

 Software for Windows EagleMailer is a useful tool designed specifically for mass emailing of all sorts.Sending mass emails is a classic marketing tool, but it&apos;s awkward to do it from a traditional mail client. With...

 Comica 

 Software for Windows Comica, previously known as Comical, is a free, open source app with which you can read comics on your computer.Comica is stable and effective. It is compatible with ZIP and RAR compressed files,...

 SearchMyFiles 

 Software for Windows Have you sometimes found the Windows search imprecise or lacking in options? SearchMyFiles is a lightweight freeware app that offers you detailed parameters for performing searches in amongst your...

 TimeGT 

 Software for Windows If improving productivity is among your New Year resolutions, TimeGT can lend you a hand!
TimeGT is a complete task management application that supports popular productivity improvement methods...

 System Explorer Portable 

 Software for Windows System Explorer Portable is a complete tool that could be described as the standard Windows Task Manager on steroids.This full-featured system analyzing tool lets you take a sneak peek at...

 Elementals: The Magic Key 

 Software for Windows Save your sister from the evil wizard Sibelius and recover the Eiron key to return the world Elementals: The Magic Key to harmony. You are young magician Albert, who with his guide and aide Felly...

 Umbrella Adventure - The Castle of Cake 

 Software for Windows Umbrella Adventure - The Castle of Cake is a hand-drawn platformer, where you control an umbrella qielding monkey on a quest to find his stolen confectionary.This freeware title looks great, with...

 Krento 

 Software for Windows Some people don&apos;t have enough with the Start menu or the Quick Launch bar, and need something else to access their apps. This is where Krento may come in handy.Krento is an application launcher...

 Migratr 

 Software for Windows There are dozens of photo storage services out there, but is there an easy way to transfer photos between them? The answer is Migratr.
With Migratr you can easily move your photo collection...

 Any DWG to PDF Converter 

 Software for Windows If you work with CAD, you might find that one day you need to convert a .DWG or .DXF file to .PDF. If you don&apos;t actually have AutoCAD or a similar program, you&apos;ll need an app to do the conversion...

 WinRAR 

 Software for Windows WinRAR a file compression application that is a must-have in any modern-day PC toolkit.This application not only includes support for extracting virtually any kind of file compression format, it...

 Azada 

 Software for Windows Azada is a refreshing and unusual take on the puzzle genre. If you&apos;re tired of the same old stuff or repetitive challenges, then this is worth your time.There is an enormous number of puzzles...

 New Year Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;ve decided to stay inside this New Year&apos;s Eve there are plenty of ways to experience the thrill of the party without having to brave hoards of drunks and pay extortionate prices for entry...

 EASEUS Todo Backup 

 Software for Windows What is the most valuable part of your computer? Not the screen, or the keyboard, or the mouse. Exactly: the most important thing in your computer is the data you store on your hard drive, which...

 ORF-Ski Challenge 

 Software for Windows Just as it is every winter season, ORF-Ski Challenge is back with the new 2010 version to deliver all the excitement of mountain ski competition.ORF-Ski Challenge 2010 is a free online ski...

 T3Desk 

 Software for Windows Who said your Windows desktop was limited to two dimensions? With T3Desk you can turn it into a fully three-dimensional space to manage apps and windows more comfortably.T3Desk is very easy to...

 tunesBag Desktop Radio 

 Software for Windows What if you could have your favorite music available anywhere, anytime? This is what tunesBag offers you: an online free storage service for your music, and a desktop app to listen to it.
tunesBag...

 CyberSearch 

 Software for Windows CyberSearch is a Firefox add-on that turbo-charges your searches with a combination of keyword sensitive searching and result previews.When we first installed CyberSearch to test, we were pretty...

 EyeDefender 

 Software for Windows While we&apos;re all worrying about viruses, trojans and spyware, there might be another type of danger that is going unnoticed as we use our computers - our eyes. All those hours staring at a screen...

 Anki 

 Software for Windows Anki is a memorization system designed to help students - of anything - strengthen their long-term retention of facts. You&apos;ll still have to do the learning yourself, but Anki&apos;s method of drilling...

 RIOT Portable 

 Software for Windows When uploading images to your personal webpage, online gallery or blog, it&apos;s important to resize them and ensure a decent loading speed. But it&apos;s also important to keep quality as high as possible....

 Yet Another (remote) Process Monitor 

 Software for Windows The Windows Task Manager can be a useful tool, but it falls too short of expectations for the most tech-savvy users. If you&apos;re among them, you should consider taking a look at Yet Another Process...

 Open With 

 Software for Windows If you spend enough time on the internet, you&apos;ll realize that sooner or later your default browser is not always the best for the job. There&apos;s no easy answer, though, because the browser that is...

 Zbang 

 Software for Windows Picasa, Flickr, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Google Docs... most of us use these services on a daily basis, which means we waste a lot of time browsing from one website to another, logging in, doing...

 RarmaRadio 

 Software for Windows RarmaRadio is a complete audio and video streaming app that lets you tune in to radio and TV stations from all over the world.The program includes thousands of stations, all conveniently organized...

 Cryptomite 

 Software for Windows When you are dealing with sensitive information, you might want multiple methods of keeping it safe. One layer of security you can apply is to encrypt the files or emails in question. With a...

 Folder Shield 

 Software for Windows Sometimes you have a folder on your computer that needs a little more protection than usual. You have various options - passwords, encryption - but sometimes you wish that nobody even knew the...

 SpellBound 

 Software for Windows There are plenty of dictionary add-ons for Firefox, but users who spend a lot of time online might be looking for more comprehensive help. If you are, SpellBound is a great option. This add-on...

 Rikaichan 

 Software for Windows One of the great things about the Internet is the way it gives us access to other cultures. If you are a language learner, this gives you an incredible chance to practice what you are learning....

 Heiko Tietze Scrabble 

 Software for Windows Heiko Tietze Scrabble is an open source version of the table top classic. Play with up to four players, human or computer, on a single PC or over a network.
This game doesn&apos;t require installation,...

 You Be The Driver Screensaver 

 Software for Windows You be the Driver Screensaver is a simple short video screensaver of the BMW Sauber F1 team.
Installation is really easy, and it finishes by asking to open up the display manager so you can set it...

 TextRoom 

 Software for Windows TextRoom is a quiet place to write, free of all the distractions of modern word processors. If you need to get writing but you can&apos;t stop checking emails, reading Twitter and gazing at your...

 PING PONG! 

 Software for Windows Cactus is one of the most interesting indie developers around at the moment, and PING PONG! is one of the best offerings yet.
PING PONG! is obviously very retro, featuring graphics and music that...

 Free Screen To Video 

 Software for Windows Sometimes the best way to explain something to someone who&apos;s not very skillful with computer is showing them a video. And Free Screen to Video is one of the easiest ways to record your screen.Free...

 Songbird Portable 

 Software for Windows When it comes to audio players, most people choose between the three or four most popular apps: iTunes, Winamp, VLC, AIMP Player… but there are many other interesting choices like Songbird...

 Bing4free 

 Software for Windows Need a fresh source of wallpapers? The search engine Bing has lots of attractive photos everyday, and Bing4Free will find, download at set them as your wallpaper for you.
The simple interface...

 Irukandji 

 Software for Windows Do you enjoy chasing high scores? Irukandji, the new flashy shoot&apos;em up from Charlie&apos;s Games is made just for that reason.
The game consists of one vertically scrolling level, which ends in a...

 Serif 3D Plus 

 Software for Windows Nobody could blame someone starting out in graphic design for being a little bit overwhelmed. Even though applications like AutoDesk Maya are incredibly powerful, they can be a little difficult to...

 MPlayer Portable 

 Software for Windows MPlayer Portable may not be the most attractive player in the world, but like in VLC Media Player, this little app hides a great potential under its dull design.
With MPlayer Portable you won&apos;t...

 UltraVPN 

 Software for Windows Make sure your surfing is safe and anonymous with a VPN solution like UltraVPN.This virtual private network (VPN) is based on OpenVPN and, like other VPN clients, your network connection so that...

 Jumpman 

 Software for Windows Little known fact - Jumpman was Mario&apos;s original title! This indie game is just as exciting as the early platform games, and its blocky graphics makes it decidedly retro.
You control a man... who...

 Device Doctor 

 Software for Windows If you want to make the most of your hardware you should have your drivers updated to the latest version. Device Doctor can help!
Device Doctor is a small simple app that scans your hardware...

 Pale Moon Portable 

 Software for Windows If you love Firefox but still think it&apos;s a bit too slow, try Pale Moon Portable instead!The aim behind Pale Moon Portable is to build a completely customized version of Firefox that&apos;s tailored to...

 Easy Calendar 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s always handy to have a calendar at hand, but unfortunately the default Windows calendar is lacking in tools and options. Easy Calendar is a better choice!
With Easy Calendar you&apos;ll be able to...

 Pimpzilla 

 Software for Windows You have the car, the cash, the bling and the record contract, but you&apos;re still no competition for 50 Cent. What could be missing? PimpZilla, of course!
PimpZilla is a pimptastic Firefox theme...

 PasswordFox 

 Software for Windows There is nothing more irritating than realizing that Firefox knows your passwords, but you don&apos;t. When you&apos;re entering log-in details, Firefox will offer to remember them for you. That&apos;s great as...

 Tropico 3 

 Software for Windows If you like management games like the Tycoon series or the world famous SimCity, you should definitely give Tropico 3 a try.
Tropico 3 is the latest installment of a popular strategy saga that...

 Google Shortcuts 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ll bet there&apos;s more than one Google-addict reading this review, right? Well, if you&apos;re a fan of the Internet giant, I have the perfect app for you - a Firefox add-on that gives you quick and easy...

 madnessMadnessmadness 

 Software for Windows madnessMadnessmadness is an endless, circular platform where your sole aim is to survive as long as possible, escaping the wall of death.
This was created for a Game Jolt contest to create minimal...

 Santa&apos;s Workshop 

 Software for Windows Santa&apos;s elves have to get all the gifts ready and wrapped before Christmas, and in Santa&apos;s Workshop you help them do this by solving lots of block-sliding puzzles that will really get you thinking....

 Santa&apos;s Workshop 

 Software for Mac Santa&apos;s elves have to get all the gifts ready and wrapped before Christmas, and in Santa&apos;s Workshop you help them do this by solving lots of block-sliding puzzles that will really get you thinking....

 Christmas Wallpaper 33 

 Software for Windows Christmas Wallpaper 33 brings Santa Claus to your desktop in the shape of a fun background image.The picture in Christmas Wallpaper 33 depicts a merry Father Christmas ready for work, armed with...

 Screen Capture Utility 

 Software for Windows One screen capture tool looks much like the next, and at first glance, there&apos;s no reason to believe that Screen Capture Utility is going to be any different. Appearances can be deceiving, however,...

 Munky&apos;s Block 

 Software for Windows The indie game community is now the place to look for game innovation. Sometimes the experiences might be too experimental, but other times, you&apos;ll find new game mechanics that are just really cool...

 Graabr 

 Software for Windows Have you ever needed a tool to share your screen online? Either for technical reasons – capturing an error message for Customer Support – or simply to show off your new wallpaper, I&apos;m sure you&apos;ve...

 18 Wheels of Steel Extreme Trucker 

 Software for Windows Is there anything about truck driving that&apos;s romantic? Difficult to say, but there&apos;s certainly an attraction to the open road, and long journeys. In 18 Wheels of Steel Extreme Trucker, you&apos;ll take...

 Unlocker Portable 

 Software for Windows Deleting a file from your computer may not be as easy as it seems. Sometimes you get an error message telling you that the file is being used by another application and can&apos;t be erased. What&apos;s the...

 AddOrSubtract 

 Software for Windows In the eternal fight to teach math, teachers and parents need every trick in the book to keep kids interested. AddOrSubtract is a program that will help in the battle, with the added bonus that...

 Conceal 

 Software for Windows Encryption is an excellent form of protection against prying eyes, but sometimes the tools needed can be complex and inaccessible to the majority of users. With all the talk of algorithms, AES and...

 IcoFX Portable 

 Software for Windows I love programs with nice, colorful icons; they make apps easier to locate in the hard drive, they look great on the desktop and – especially for us Softonic editors – they make gorgeous program...

 Insectoid 

 Software for Windows Galaga is a videogame classic, a title that took Space Invaders and gave it speed and wow factor. With Insectoid, indie developers Actionsoft have taken that template and polished it up for today&apos;s...

 20 Dual-Monitor Wallpapers 

 Software for Windows More and more people work with dual monitor PCs today, and while this can help productivity, it&apos;s not always easy to find nice wallpapers wide enough to stretch between them.
This pack of 20...

 Product Key Finder 

 Software for Windows Sometimes simple is best, and that&apos;s definitely the case with Product Key Finder. This free and portable product key tool runs straight from the download file, so there&apos;s no need to install. Simply...

 Cleeki 

 Software for Windows As our online lives get busier and busier, we&apos;re always on the lookout for programs that will make us more efficient. There are lots of tools that can do this, from helping us get organized to...

 PassworG 

 Software for Windows Tired of having to come up with new, strong passwords every time you sign up for a new online service? It&apos;s time to start using PassworG.PassworG (it&apos;s not a typo, there&apos;s no d) is a simple...

 Speedy Shopper 

 Software for Windows One of the most irritating domestic pitfalls is coming home from the supermarket and discovering that you forgot to include the most important item on your shopping list.Prevent such misfortunes in...

 Jubilee 

 Software for Windows Christmas is back again, and though I&apos;m not particularly a very Christmassy person, I do like to decorate my computer accordingly.
Jubilee is a nice addition to those computer holiday decorations....

 NoSquint 

 Software for Windows Some people may have trouble reading certain websites, due to their choice of text size, color combination and background images. If you&apos;re among them, you should try NoSquint.
NoSquint is a...

 Free Screensavers Package 

 Software for Windows If you love screensavers but have a hard time deciding which one to download, here&apos;s the perfect solution: a whole collection of 50 free screensavers!
Free Screensavers Package includes 50 varied...

 Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures 

 Software for Windows Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures is a massively multiplayer online role playing game. Set in the fantasy realm of Conan the Barbarian, this massive game is being offered for free until January 1st...

 Awesome Soccer 

 Software for Windows FIFA and Pro Evolution have well and truly cornered the football simulation market. So much so, in fact, that the thought of choosing to play a different soccer game seems a bit absurd.
Awesome...

 Free Studio 

 Software for Windows Free Studio (previously known as Free Studio Manager) is an excellent conversion app that bundles multiple converters into one handy program so that when it comes to converting files from one...

 Adobe Digital Editions 

 Software for Windows Ebook readers are becoming more and more and popular these days, and this gives developers a good reason to create ebook-related software like Adobe Digital Editions.
With Adobe Digital Editions...

 EZ Photo Creations 

 Software for Windows Have you run out of ideas for presents? Are you searching for something special for your significant ones? Try EZ Photo Creations!
EZ Photo Creations lets you create customized calendars, posters,...

 Visions&amp;Voices 

 Software for Windows Something strange has happened in Montfort village - many have been wiped out, and those remaining are going insane! You play&apos;the wanderer&apos;, a man with a strange past, and and a lot of curiosity,...

 HijackThis 

 Software for Windows HijackThis is a no-frills tool to detect and remove suspicious elements from your web browsers.This tool works by scanning your browsers to see what might be lurking in them. It gives you a clear...

 VirusTotal Uploader 

 Software for Windows Here at Softonic, we&apos;re big fans of file scanning service VirusTotal. If you&apos;re like us, and serious about security, then VirusTotal Uploader is the perfect accompaniment.VirusTotal Uploader lets...

 TweakXPlorer 

 Software for Windows Tired of the traditional blue title bar and yellow folders in Windows File Explorer? Make the change with TweakXPlorer!
This little app lets you customize some basic features in File Explorer, the...

 G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows The popular action figure makes a big screen appearance this summer, with G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra. From the producer of The Mummy films, this will no doubt be a roller coaster action...

 USBDriveFresher 

 Software for Windows Every time you plug a USB drive to a computer, the system leaves some junk files in it (like thumbs.db, .trashes, .ds_store or .Spotlight-V100) that are not really necessary and can get really...

 MP3 Diags 

 Software for Windows Unless you&apos;re the extremely organized type, having a massive collection of music means having a bunch of messy folders and files. Luckily you can now use MP3 Diags to fix everything!
MP3 Diags is...

 Signo 

 Software for Windows Sometimes, working with the computer means performing a lot of repetitive tasks: always opening the same websites, launching the same apps, writing the same words and sentences… what if you could...

 Multiget 

 Software for Windows When your internet connection is a little on the slow side, large files take ages to download. In these cases, using a download manager is highly recommended!
MultiGet is a good example of a...

 Windows Access Panel 

 Software for Windows If there&apos;s one characteristic that defines both Windows Vista and Windows 7, it is a redesigned Control Panel. The problem is that this redesign doesn&apos;t necessarily make it easier to use.
Windows...

 DeskDuster 

 Software for Windows Is your beautiful wallpaper strewn with a mess of icons? It seems a shame to bother having one at all when it looks so untidy! DeskDuster is a tiny application that will magic your icons away if...

 Monitor Off Utility 

 Software for Windows Monitor Off Utility is a tiny utility that allows you to turn off your monitor using hot key commands or a double click.
Once installed, you can run Monitor Off Utility in the system tray, so it...

 namebench 

 Software for Windows You may not know it, but you can choose which service changes the address you put in your browser to IP numbers, the authentic coordinates of the internet.It&apos;s not something most users will think...

 STAR TREK: D-A-C 

 Software for Windows &apos;Inspired&apos;by the fantastic 2009 movie, Star Trek: D-A-C is a top down arcade shoot&apos;em up, like Asteroids with a multiplayer mode.
This demo gives you a good feel for the game, featuring a one...

 Memory Improve Master 

 Software for Windows No matter how much RAM memory and processor power you have, you may eventually run out of system resources... and this is where Memory Improve Master comes in handy.
Memory Improve Master takes...

 Ainvo Registry Defrag 

 Software for Windows Windows Registry can be fragmented as any other system file, and that can seriously affect the computer&apos;s performance. In these cases, what you need to do is defrag your Registry with a tool like...

 Visual Explorer 

 Software for Windows The web browser market is continuously increasing its offer with more alternatives to big shots like Internet Explorer or Firefox. One of the latest additions to the menu is Visual Explorer....

 Fren-ze 

 Software for Windows Fren-ze is an arcade shoot&apos;em up visually reminiscent of Geometry Wars, though it&apos;s a scrolling game.
There are two features of fren-ze that set it apart from other shooters. The first is that...

 Free Process Freezer 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s a sad fact of computing - sometimes programs get stuck. While in many cases simply opening the task manager and killing a process is enough, in other cases you may lose work as a result. It is...

 Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror 

 Software for Windows Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror is like a Where&apos;s Wally? book, mixed with a mysterious story.
The basic mechanic of Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror are like all games of this genre - you can play...

 Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror 

 Software for Mac Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror is like a Where&apos;s Wally? book, mixed with a mysterious story.
The basic mechanic of Hidden in Time: Mirror Mirror are like all games of this genre - you can play...

 Flickr Wallpaper Rotator 

 Software for Windows Flickr Wallpaper Rotator is a Windows wallpaper rotator that takes its wallpaper feed from Flickr.With this Flickr wallpaper changer, you&apos;ll never get bored with your desktop again. When you...

 Scenegrabber.NET 

 Software for Windows They say an image is worth a thousand words. In the case of movie frames, a certain image can perfectly describe the whole movie – if you choose it carefully.With Scenegrabber.NET you can select...

 Shadow Defender 

 Software for Windows There are as many computer security programs out there are there are computers, and sometimes it&apos;s hard to tell them apart. Shadow Defender is an application that has decided to take an original...

 Pipette 

 Software for Windows If you want to know the exact color of something on your screen, you need a color pipette, which is exactly what Pipette is. This little tool allows you to see exact values for any color on your...

 EZ Open 

 Software for Windows EZ Open is a weather application, that brings together 10 weather sources and a calendar in a browser like application. It is designed for people who like to check lots of sources for weather...

 EARTH 

 Software for Windows Developed for the experimental gameplay project, EARTH is an art game that will be instantly recognizable to anyone who&apos;s every played a video game.
As EARTH starts, the set up is obvious - you...

 Tunngle 

 Software for Windows Tunngle is a p2p VPN especially designed for online gaming.Do you like playing games like Call of Duty, Minecraft and Portal 2 online? Well, you’re in luck, because this is precisely what Tunngle...

 ImageShack Uploader 

 Software for Windows ImageShack is a popular free photo hosting service that comes in really handy to share photos on the spot. And now with ImageShack Uploader it&apos;s even easier to use!
ImageShack Uploader is a simple...

 Saezuri 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re hooked on Twitter you should give Saezuri a try!Saezuri is an AIR-based Twitter client that lets you interact with this revolutionary communication tool from your desktop. No more...

 Restaurant Savant 

 Software for Windows When you like eating out as much as I do, it&apos;s not unusual to have problems remembering where you&apos;ve been, what you thought and - most importantly - if you&apos;d go there again.Some people are happy...

 Christmas Eve Crisis 

 Software for Windows When he decides to leave the reindeer at home, in favor of a new motor powered Sleigh, Santa thinks he&apos;s doing Rudolph and the gang a favor. Unfortunately, the new system doesn&apos;t work so well, and...

 NeonPlat 

 Software for Windows Programmer Jayenkai describes NeonPlat as&quot;It&apos;s a bit Bubble Bobble, except it&apos;s not!&quot;If you remember the eighties game featuring cute jumping dinosaurs and fruit, you&apos;ll notice NeonPlat features...

 Hard Paint 

 Software for Windows Hard Paint is an original image editor that creates artwork based on selected photos, and using any other image as virtual brush.
Strange as it sounds, the truth is that Hard Paint is very easy to...

 Zoom 

 Software for Mac Interactive Fiction, the genre of text-based adventures that has existed pretty much since the beginning of home computing, is a little obscure. That&apos;s a shame as while it lacks graphics or sound,...

 Rover&apos;s Day Out 

 Software for Windows Rover&apos;s Day Out is a strange piece of interactive fiction, that you can play using an interpreter program like Gargoyle.
For newcomers, there is nothing graphical about interactive fiction - the...

 Watermark Image 

 Software for Windows Watermark Images is an easy-to-use image editor that&apos;s been especially designed to apply personalized watermarks to your photos. The program can watermark complete folders and subfolders in one...

 MangaMeeya 

 Software for Windows MangaMeeya is an easy-to-use comic reader that puts a special emphasis on manga.MangaMeeya also features all the tools and utilities you need to enjoy your comics on the PC. That means you&apos;ll be...

 PhiTodo 

 Software for Windows The best way to increase your productivity is to organize your tasks as neatly as possible. And the easiest way to do it is a task manager like PhiTodo.
With PhiTodo you can manage and organize...

 Igneous 

 Software for Windows In Igneous, you control a rolling Totem which you must guide through a fire and brimstone world being destroyed by an angry and powerful idol.
Best played with an Xbox controller, but keyboard and...

 Episode Encoder 

 Software for Windows Episode Encoder (formerly known as simply Episode and Compression Master) is a superb tool for compressing and encoding video.
In terms of speed, it&apos;s one of the quickest encoders you&apos;ll ever use...

 Irukandji 

 Software for Mac Do you enjoy chasing high scores? Irukandji, the new flashy shoot&apos;em up from Charlie&apos;s Games is made just for that reason.
The game consists of one vertically scrolling level, which ends in a...

 WinFontsView 

 Software for Windows Have you ever wondered how many text fonts you have on your system? Windows doesn&apos;t have a proper tool to list them, and here&apos;s where WinFontsView comes in handy.WinFontsView is a small utility...

 Free Language Translator 

 Software for Windows I don&apos;t know about you, but I need to use dictionaries and translators almost on a daily basis. And in cases like these, a tool like Free Language Translator is a real time saver!
Free Language...

 ImageConverter 

 Software for Windows Are you looking for a quick, easy way to convert or resize batches of images? ImageConverter is a neat little application that gets that job done quickly, without any additional fuss....

 Sonic Ironstorm: Fatal Attack 

 Software for Windows Sonic Ironstorm: Fatal Attack is a Japanese top down shoot&apos;em up. There may be a story, but it&apos;s not clear what it is - all you know is that cursor keys move your fighter, the Z fires weapons, and...

 Dreamside Maroon 

 Software for Windows Dreamside Maroon tells the story of Aster, who wants to go to the moon. He exists in a strange world of floating islands, and travels around by a vine that grows in whatever direction he wishes....

 Attack of the 50ft Robot! 

 Software for Windows Attack of the 50ft Robot! is a free game by students at DigiPen Institute of Technology, but don&apos;t think that there&apos;s anything amateurish about it! The title is fairly self explanatory - you...

 GOM Video Converter 

 Software for Windows GOM Encoder is a comprehensive video conversion tool that comes from the creators of the excellent GOM Player.The main interface of GOM Encoder is slick and clearly designed. Just drag and drop a...

 eBoostr 

 Software for Windows eBoostr is an application for Windows computers that helps you optimize the speed of your PC.In the ever-present battle to speed up your computer, eBoostr could turn out to be a formidable weapon....

 K-Lite Codec Pack 64-bit Edition 

 Software for Windows While most media players, even in 64-bit operating systems, use 32-bit media players by default, there are a few 64-bit players around. To make use of every media format out there, you&apos;ll need a...

 MouseExtender 

 Software for Windows There are many ways to access your favorite programs: a desktop shortcut, the Start menu, the Quick Launch bar... but the easiest would be to have them right on your mouse cursor, wouldn&apos;t it?Now...

 We Want YOU 

 Software for Windows &quot;Listen up maggot. Your country is a war. You will be entering enemy territory soon.&quot;So begin the instructions to We Want YOU, a randomly generated platform shoot&apos;em up.
This game is played top...

 Dooble 

 Software for Windows Dooble is an open source web browser, which aims to facilitate quick and secure internet surfing.Based on WebKit, the powerful engine that both Safari and Google Chrome also use, Dooble&apos;s main...

 Sumotori Dreams 

 Software for Windows Sumotori Dream is a Windows sumo wrestling game starring giant robots. Sumo wrestling isn&apos;t a sport that many combat games developers choose to make simulations of. Based on the gameplay in...

 MWAV Toolkit Utility 

 Software for Windows Are you worried about security on your computer? Do you think you need something more than just an antivirus? Try MWAV Toolkit Utility!
With MWAV Toolkit Utility you can scan the whole system for...

 CovArt Ops 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re anything like me, you probably like to have your music collection perfectly organized. And an important part of that organization is album covers.
CovArt Ops can lend you a hand with the...

 Colin McRae: DiRT 2 

 Software for Windows Colin McRae: DiRT 2 is an intense, visceral rally experience that updates the series by injecting a more American approach to off-road racing to the detailed realism series fans will be used to....

 sobees 

 Software for Windows Desktop apps that draw together all the social media streams that people follow are becoming extremely common, and the alpha release or this app adds Sobees to that list.This is an Beta release,...

 SPlayer 

 Software for Windows In the world of software sometimes simple is better, and SPlayer is a good example of it.SPlayer is a really lightweight audio and video player that joins the media player category ready to...

 Cave 

 Software for Windows Cave is a platform exploration game, like you may never have played before.
Starting in a darkened cave, you are shown a girl and a boy, with their controls. You control both of them, flicking...

 Cave 

 Software for Mac Cave is a platform exploration game, like you may never have played before.
Starting in a darkened cave, you are shown a girl and a boy, with their controls. You control both of them, flicking...

 Christmas Time 

 Software for Windows Christmas Time is a colorful theme for Windows XP that will bring the spirit of Christmas to your desktop. It&apos;s perfect for those who&apos;d like to decorate their desks but don&apos;t want the hassle of...

 GTDInbox 

 Software for Windows With GTDInbox you can easily apply the Getting Things Done philosophy to your Gmail inbox.
As you may already know, Getthing Things Done is a popular productivity method that helps you deal with...

 A Small Gift For Christmas 

 Software for Windows Well, Christmas is right around the corner, so it&apos;s about time we started getting into a festive mood. If this adorable penguin wallpaper from the ever-fantastic Vladstudio doesn&apos;t help, nothing...

 Twilight New Moon Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ve never known anything like the Twlight phenomenon. Well, not since Harry Potter anyway. Twilight, if you&apos;ve never heard of it, is a film based on a series of books by Stephanie Meyer that...

 Twilight New Moon IM Icons 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ve never known anything like the Twlight phenomenon. Well, not since Harry Potter anyway. Twilight, if you&apos;ve never heard of it, is a film based on a series of books by Stephanie Meyer that...

 Driver Robot 

 Software for Windows Drivers probably aren&apos;t most people&apos;s favorite software subject, but they are important. That&apos;s why it&apos;s a relief when you find a driver management program that is so easy to navigate and simple to...

 iPuissance 4D 

 Software for Windows You probably played Connect Four as a child. Now you have the opportunity to play it again in your computer with iPuissance 4D.
Despìte its misleading name, iPuissance 4D is a three-dimensional...

 Spelunky 

 Software for Windows Spelunky is a retro platform game with a difference - every new game the map is randomly created, no no game will be the same each time you play!The point of Spelunky is simply to find treasure,...

 Fishbowl 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re hooked on to Facebook but don&apos;t want to waste time opening the browser and loading up the website all the time, try Fishbowl instead.
Fishbowl is an eye-catching Facebook client for your...

 QuickFox Notes 

 Software for Windows If you use the internet for research (and let&apos;s face it who doesn&apos;t?), wouldn&apos;t it be useful to be able to take notes in your browser while you&apos;re doing it? With the Firefox extension QuickFox...

 Cute Knight Kingdom 

 Software for Windows Cute Knight Kingdom is an anime role playing game (RPG), set in a mystical kingdom. You play a young girl who sets out to find her way in life.The game starts after you choose a name, on your...

 Q10 

 Software for Windows Q 10 is a text editor designed to be a zen/like space where you can concentrate on your writing, free from the other distractions on your PC. 
Like most minimalist writing apps, you can choose the...

 JDarkRoom 

 Software for Windows JDarkroom is a basic text editor for people who find more complex word processors distracting. It has very few features but runs in full screen mode, so nothing else can disturb you.Of all the...

 Monitor Off Utility 

 Software for Windows Monitor Off Utility is a tiny utility that allows you to turn off your monitor using hot key commands or a double click.
Once installed, you can run Monitor Off Utility in the system tray, so it...

 WriteMonkey 

 Software for Windows Write Monkey is a writing app that takes the clutter from your desktop, giving you a distraction free space where you can write. If you&apos;re trying to finish a book, or just write an email or blog...

 Xara Web Designer 

 Software for Windows Xara Web Designer is a web design app created specifically to avoid the more technical side of website creation.Xara Web Designer works on the WYSIWYG principle, so that what you see on the screen...

 Q10 Portable 

 Software for Windows Q 10 Portable is a text editor designed to be a zen/like space where you can concentrate on your writing, free from the other distractions on your PC. 
Like most minimalist writing apps, you can...

 JaSFtp 

 Software for Windows JaSFtp is designed for those who want to automate their FTP transfer tasks so they do not have to spend time interactively transferring files.
JaSFtp has a simple user interface that helps you...

 MKV Player 

 Software for Windows MKV Player is a free video player that lets you watch MKV files on your computer - as well as other audio and video formats.The program is meant to be really simple in appearance and...

 WinMount 

 Software for Windows WinMount is an interesting application that gives you the functionality of several programs in one, a handy attribute when it comes to file compression, decompression, mounting and management.The...

 Devil&apos;s Tuning Fork 

 Software for Windows Devil&apos;s Tuning Fork is a creepy first person adventure. The world has been hit by an epidemic of children falling into a coma. And you play one of these children, who awakes in a bizarre alternate...

 Metronome 

 Software for Windows If you can&apos;t put your hands on a metronome to keep your musical tempo in check, then why not use your PC to do the job for you?
It&apos;s a darned-sight cheaper than buying your own and is just as easy...

 Adobe Camera Raw 

 Software for Windows Professional and mid-range photo cameras offer support for RAW format, a kind of digital negative that lets you tweak the images with great control and flexibility in order to obtain the perfect...

 Secret Disk 

 Software for Windows Do you have sensitive files or data you want to keep away from prying eyes? Secret Disk will create a space on your hard drive, only accessible with a password, and invisible to Windows explorer....

 FotoMix 

 Software for Windows FotoMix helps you create original photo compositions by adding people from another picture onto a different background.This is usually a trick for Photoshop experts, but now with FotoMix you can...

 War of Titans 

 Software for Windows War of Titans is an multiplayer online role playing game based around gladiators. Create a Gladiator of your own, and guide them through battles, gaining experience and money to improve your...

 Fishdom: Spooky Splash 

 Software for Windows Fishdom: Spooky Splash is a puzzle game where you have to build an aquarium, and fund your purchases with treasure from the bottom of the sea, which you do by playing a kind of Bejeweled clone...

 Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising 

 Software for Windows Tired of high octane, Hollywood shooters like Modern Warfare? Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising is the antidote.
Like almost any war shooter you&apos;d care to mention, Operation Flashpoint: Dragon...

 Assassin&apos;s Creed II Official Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows After the adventures of Altaïr across several capital cities in the Holy Land, back in the 12th century, Ubisoft presents us now with the second installment of their successful Assassin&apos;s Creed....

 Sothink SWF Easy 

 Software for Windows Many online services, websites and games use Flash technology these days. With Sothink SWF Easy you&apos;ll be able to create those animations as well, even if you have no Flash knowledge at all....

 Enigeo 

 Software for Windows They say the best way to learn something is making it fun, and Enigeo tries to prove this theory with a bunch of quizzes.Enigeo lets you create customizable quizzes about Geography, including...

 Google Chromium OS 

 Software for Windows After weeks of rumors, comments, headlines and an official presentation in San Francisco, Google Chromium OS is finally here.Chromium OS is currently only available as source code, which you can...

 Fetus 

 Software for Windows Fetus is a strange, dark little platform/puzzle game. No story is complained, but what you have to do is introduced to you during the first few levels.
Each level ends when you hit the big TV,...

 Windows Password Unlocker 

 Software for Windows Windows Password Unlocker is a useful tool for password retrieval if you&apos;ve lost or forgotten yours.If you&apos;ve forgotten your password for Windows, the situation can seem pretty desperate....

 Stickies 

 Software for Windows Everyone knows post-its, those yellow notes we use everyday to remind us of tasks, missed calls and other important things? You can now use them in their digital version with Stickies!With...

 Bugzilla 

 Software for Windows All developers will tell you that using an efficient, easy-to-use and reliable bug-tracking tool is one of the most important parts of their job.Bugzilla is Mozilla&apos;s system for reporting and...

 Hello Kitty Icons 

 Software for Windows Don&apos;t ask me why but Hello Kitty is massively popular brand even though it looks like it&apos;s based on some kind of kids cartoon.
If you&apos;re a Windows user and a fan of the cute cartoon cat, you will...

 PepSky All-in-One 

 Software for Windows PepSky All-in-One is a multimedia center, a collection of programs under one roof that aim to be all you need in terms of copying, converting and burning discs. The front interface splits the...

 Mad Skills Motocross 

 Software for Mac Mad Skills Motocross is a 2D racing and stunt game that brings 80s style bike action to your Mac. 
This demo introduces you to the action with ten levels, teaching you the basics and letting you...

 Focus 

 Software for Windows Focus is a 50 stage platformer, which requires jumping, teleportation, lightening fast reactions, and pin-point accuracy.
With it&apos;s basic ball-shaped character and black background with brown...

 rComplex 

 Software for Windows rComplex is a short, simple game in which you try to escape a giant&apos;thing&apos;that&apos;s chasing you.
The game starts with the silhouette protagonist running, closely followed by tentacles. You control...

 7stacks 

 Software for Windows One of the major problems with operating systems is that you can get bored of staring at the same interface, day in and day out. Spice things up a little with 7Stacks, a small program that gives...

 James Cameron&apos;s Avatar: The Game 

 Software for Windows James Cameron&apos;s Avatar is one of the year&apos;s most hotly anticipated movies, promising to be a visual feast. Ubisoft have been charged with taking the lush visuals of the movie, and translating them...

 K Sketch 

 Software for Windows Flash animations look really nice on websites, games and online apps, but what if you could create your own?
K-Sketch is a easy-to-use drawing editor that enables you to create simple Flash...

 Osmo 

 Software for Windows Sometimes simple is better, and Osmo is a good example of that: a simple, lightweight personal information manager that lets you handle all important tasks and events in an easier way.
Osmo has a...

 Canabalt 

 Software for Windows Canabalt has been this years viral online game for those in the know. Now Portable Apps have made it available for your USB stick, so you can play offline too!
What makes Canabalt so special is...

 Nikon Camera Control Pro 

 Software for Windows Nikons are highly regarded as the creme-de-la-creme of digital SLR cameras, but to get the most out of them, you need the right software.
Nikon Camera Control Pro remotely controls most functions...

 Password Workbook 

 Software for Windows Ah, passwords! So useful and so annoying at the same time. They help us keep our data safe, but at the same time it&apos;s hard to come up with good passwords and, even worse, remember all of them....

 Vitamin D 

 Software for Windows Webcams are fun to use: you can have video chats with people all over the world, record videos of yourself to become a YouTube superstar and use special software to add hilarious effects to the...

 Featherweight 

 Software for Windows &apos;Point and Click&apos;adventures are really coming back into fashion, and Featherweight is another addition to the genre. It&apos;s pretty short, so would make a good introduction to this type of game.
You...

 QQ Messenger 

 Software for Windows QQ Messenger may not sound familiar, but it&apos;s the most popular IM client in China.When you think about IM clients, the first names that come to your head are Windows Live Messenger, Yahoo!...

 New Super Mario Bros. Wii Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows After the success of the DS&apos;s New Super Mario Bros, Nintendo is making another return to 2D platforming on the Wii console.
This promises to be the Wii game of the year, and if you&apos;re mad about...

 New Super Mario Bros. Wii Wallpaper 

 Software for Mac After the success of the DS&apos;s New Super Mario Bros, Nintendo is making another return to 2D platforming on the Wii console.
This promises to be the Wii game of the year, and if you&apos;re mad about...

 GiliSoft RAMDisk 

 Software for Windows GiliSoft RAMDisk is a simple, straightforward partition creation utility for Windows PC users.GiliSoft, a software developer that seems to be determined to bring the world handy, low-key tools to...

 Mail Man 

 Software for Windows Do you regularly send out mass emails? Mail Man is designed just for that purpose.
Of course, you can send mass email with any email client, but Mail Man allows you to import email lists and group...

 Registry Reviver 

 Software for Windows The Registry is one of the most important elements in Windows. The moment it starts to fail, you&apos;re doomed!Luckily there are tools like Registry Reviver with which you can keep your Windows...

 Santa and the City 3D Christmas Screen Saver 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re looking for something to get you in the mood for Christmas, what better than a visit to your computer from Saint Nick? 
Santa and the City 3D Christmas Screen Saver sees Father Christmas...

 Contenta RAW Converter 

 Software for Windows Contenta RAW Converter allows you to convert batches of RAW photos to other formats in a few simple clicks.Photo converters always win points with me when they allow you to preview the final...

 Gili USB Stick Encryption 

 Software for Windows Pendrives (USB sticks) are really handy tools, allowing you to roam far and wide while bringing all your important documents with you. They are easy to carry and easy to use, which is great for...

 Gili Privacy Protector 

 Software for Windows We all have secrets to hide, especially in our computers. But with a program like Gili Privacy Protector you can make sure nobody accesses your private files and folders!
Gili Privacy Protector is...

 MouseWrangler 

 Software for Windows I&apos;m a sucker for keyboard shortcuts, but if you prefer to use the mouse, here&apos;s the perfect app for you: MouseWrangler.
With MouseWrangler you can configure custom mouse movements and make them...

 Gili File Lock 

 Software for Windows If you share your computer with other people and don&apos;t want them to run certain programs or access specific folders, Gili File Lock is the program you need.
With Gili File Lock you can easily hide...

 Frobot 

 Software for Windows Frobot is a pseudo 3D top down action puzzle game, with a futuristic blaxploitation theme.
Movement is done via the keyboard, while aiming and most actions are handled by the mouse. The first...

 Frobot 

 Software for Mac Frobot is a pseudo 3D top down action puzzle game, with a futuristic blaxploitation theme.
Movement is done via the keyboard, while aiming and most actions are handled by the mouse. The first...

 Siotra Watermark 

 Software for Windows If anyone wants to use the photos you have on your website, there&apos;s little you can do about it except for trusting people&apos;s good will. But you can at least discourage them from stealing copyrighted...

 Microsoft Reader 

 Software for Windows Microsoft Reader is a desktop application for reading eBooks. It allows you to organize, annotate and bookmark your eBook collection. However, there are some major reservations!
While it has very...

 Mobipocket Reader Desktop 

 Software for Windows Whether you want to read eBooks on your mobile device or from your desktop, Mobipocket Reader Desktop is the application for you.
Organize your eBook library, collect RSS feeds and your personal...

 Nemo Excel To PDF 

 Software for Windows Here&apos;s the situation: you&apos;re working on an important document in Microsoft Excel and you need to share it with your collaborators. But you want to make sure they receive the document exactly as you...

 Nemo Word To PDF 

 Software for Windows Here&apos;s the situation: you&apos;re working on an important document in Microsoft Word and you need to share it with your collaborators. But you want to make sure they receive the document exactly as you...

 Speccy 

 Software for Windows If I asked you about your computer&apos;s characteristics, most of you would be able to name the processor, and maybe the amount of RAM memory and hard drive capacity it has. But what about the rest?...

 Kindle 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a Kindle reader owner, or just want to get an idea what all the e-book fuss is about, Amazon&apos;s Kindle for PC allows you to experience it from your desktop.Installation is easy, and it...

 Nemo All to PDF 

 Software for Windows Here&apos;s the situation: you&apos;re working on an important document and you need to share it with your collaborators. But you want to make sure they receive the document exactly as you created it. What&apos;s...

 Celestia Portable 

 Software for Windows Unless you are a millionaire or an astronaut, space travel is probably out of reach. Luckily you can now bring it a little closer with Celestia Portable.
Celestia Portable is the standalone...

 Gratuitous Space Battles 

 Software for Windows Gratuitious Space Battles is an excellently titles game, as it describes exactly what you get! This demo allows you to play three missions of this large scale strategy game.
This is a one-turn...

 The Black Heart 

 Software for Windows The Black Heart is a macabre and dark beat&apos;em up. Created over 7 years by one developer, it has almost all the options you&apos;ll find in a commercial beat&apos;em up, presented in a completely unique...

 CuteRank 

 Software for Windows If you have a blog or website, you&apos;ll know how important it is to make sure it is performing well in keyword rankings. There are lots of ways to do this, but sometimes you want a simple tool that...

 QT Lite 

 Software for Windows There is nothing more annoying when you&apos;re surfing the web than clicking on a link only to be told that you need plug-ins you don&apos;t have to view the content. One of the biggest offenders in this...

 Tetris 

 Apps for Symbian I&apos;m old enough to remember when the Tetris phenomenon first swept the World. Factories shut down, traffic came to a standstill and planes remained grounded as the whole planet sat, transfixed with...

 STDU Viewer 

 Software for Windows STDU Viewer is a free file viewer that deals specifically with the most important scientific and technical documentation formats – namely TIFF, PDF, DjVu, XPS, JBIG2, and WWF.This app also...

 Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Official Wallpaper is a desktop background image designed by Infinity Ward, the developers of the latest installment of this glorious FPS franchise.
Call of Duty:...

 Dragon Age: Origins Character Creator 

 Software for Windows As any MMORPG player knows, the perfect character is key to enjoying the game. The same is absolutely true for Dragon Age, so the developers have produced an excellent tool to help you achieve this...

 Nemo PDF to Word 

 Software for Windows PDF files are great to share documents on the Web. The problem comes when you&apos;d like to edit them and all you have around is a text processor with no PDF support?Here&apos;s when Nemo PDF to Word comes...

 Breevy 

 Software for Windows As anybody who works with words knows, having to type the same word over and over can become a bit of a chore. There are some set phrases that you just know you&apos;ll have to use multiple times in one...

 Gridrunner Revolution 

 Software for Windows Retro shoot&apos;em ups have had some serious adrenaline shots in recent years, with the well known Geometry Wars and Space Invaders Extreme proving there&apos;s lots of life left in intense but simple...

 The Marionette 

 Software for Windows The Marionette is a spooky point and click adventure. It has all the advantages of independent development, and a few of the drawbacks too.
The story begins with you in an artist&apos;s studio, at the...

 dupeGuru Music Edition 

 Software for Windows Going through huge numbers of music files one by one to see which ones have been duplicated can be a complete pain and very time consuming.dupeGuru Music Edition is a tool to find duplicate files...

 dupeGuru Picture Edition 

 Software for Windows dupeGuru Picture Edition (PE for short) can help automatically find duplicate pictures on your computer and save both headaches and valuable hard drive space.dupeGuru Picture Edition is actually a...

 Kite Player 

 Software for Windows There are many apps to watch online TV for free, and KitePlayer is just another on to add to the list.This basic Internet TV app lets you tune in to hundreds of TV channels from all over the...

 jDownloader Portable 

 Software for Windows Do you use jDownloader to download from free file sharing sites like Rapidshare, and Megaupload? Well, now you can use this excellent download manager on any computer, without leaving any traces...

 Kabloom 

 Software for Windows Floating islands, trees, water, elephants. Put them all together and you have the wonderfully relaxing Kabloom. You play an elephant who awakes in a fairly desolate world, with a dying tree.Water...

 Dragon Age: Origins Wallpapers 

 Software for Windows BioWare&apos;s return to the realm of pure fantasy role playing has got fans really excited, and it&apos;s sure to soak up hours and hours of people&apos;s lives. But what about those times you have to work?...

 YL Mail Verifier 

 Software for Windows How do you know if an email address is valid? YL Mail Verifier can check emails before you send. Whether you&apos;re checking big lists of emails or just want to be sure an address is honest, YL Mail...

 Argente Utilities 

 Software for Windows No matter how careful you are as computer user, your system will eventually require maintenance and optimization tasks in order to keep its performance at the top. Luckily you can trust Argente...

 Luckhan Matrix Calculator 

 Software for Windows Matrix Calculator pro is a calculator of matrices! Very much aimed at mathematicians this calculator comes with absolutely no explanation of what it&apos;s for!
There is a manual included, but it&apos;s...

 Easy CurveFit 

 Software for Windows Easy CurveFit is a small application designed to allow you to easily plot a curve through any graph of results that you enter into the application.
When first opened, Easy CurveFit is a complete...

 Pale Moon 

 Software for Windows If you love Firefox but still think it&apos;s a bit too slow, try Pale Moon instead!The aim behind Pale Moon is to build a completely customized version of Firefox that&apos;s tailored to make the most of...

 Nemo PDF Converter 

 Software for Windows When it comes to sharing documents online, PDF is usually the format of choice because they provide an excellent viewing quality and keep the same layout on all platforms. But we all know they&apos;re...

 NirLauncher 

 Software for Windows NirSoft apps are a bunch of handy small tools that you can download separately and use for the most varied purposes: clean Registry values, show information about blue screens of death, list all...

 Video Surveillance Monitor 

 Software for Windows Sure, we all use our webcams for chatting to friends and family, but have you ever considered that it could be used for other, more serious pursuits? Well, there are various alternatives for your...

 Rubber Ninjas 

 Software for Windows Rubber Ninjas is a one or two player fighting game. It features easy to learn controls, ragdoll physics and some spectacular Matrix-like bullet time camera effects.
This demo allows you to play...

 Rubber Ninjas 

 Software for Mac Rubber Ninjas is a one or two player fighting game. It features easy to learn controls, ragdoll physics and some spectacular Matrix-like bullet time camera effects.
This demo allows you to play...

 Feedly 

 Software for Windows Whatever your homepage is, the chances are it&apos;s not a very personalized thing. Make things a bit more&apos;Web 2.0&apos;and install Feedly on Firefox to give yourself a completely new homepage experience....

 VLC Skin Editor 

 Software for Windows VLC Player is the most popular open source media player for a reason - it&apos;s excellent! It isn&apos;t the most attractive program though, and the online community has been hard at work creating lots of...

 Portal 

 Software for Windows Portal is a fantastic 3D puzzle game set in the strange and frightening laboratories of Aperture Science.Available on Mac and PC through Steam, now there is little excuse not to play one of the...

 Windows 7 Visual Themes Pack 

 Software for Windows So now that you&apos;ve got a brand new copy of Windows 7 installed on your computer, it&apos;s time for some personalization, isn&apos;t it? And changing your theme is the perfect way to start!
Windows 7 Visual...

 Backup&amp;Recovery 

 Software for Windows Backup copies are the only thing that can prevent you from losing important data in the event of a computer disaster. And Paragon Backup&amp;Recovery is a great tool to create and manage your...

 Livebrush 

 Software for Windows Drawing editors are all very similar: a working area, a pack of tools and a few configuration and editing options. But LiveBrush is different from any other drawing tool I&apos;ve seen. LiveBrush uses...

 Drench 

 Software for Windows Drench is PC version of a flash game of the same way. It&apos;s a puzzle game that&apos;s wonderfully simple to grasp, but difficult to explain!
The game starts with a big grid of colored blocks. Beginning...

 Left 4 Dead 2 

 Software for Windows Left 4 Dead 2 is a single and multiplayer action-packed first person shooter, where you have to survive a zombie apocalypse in a series of movie-like episodes.For the uninitiated, the first Left 4...

 GeneRally 

 Software for Windows GeneRally is an old school top-down racing game that features basic retro graphics but great competitive gameplay.
The interface is a bit clunky, but works well enough. You can choose from lots of...

 AVS Video ReMaker 

 Software for Windows Video editors can help you customize your recordings in many ways. But unlike those general purpose tools, AVS Video ReMaker is dedicated to just one thing: cutting unwanted scenes out.AVS Video...

 USB Flash Security 

 Software for Windows USB sticks are pretty much ubiquitous, and there have been many examples of people losing them and releasing sensitive data. USB Flash Security creates a password protected USB drive that will help...

 Metal Drift 

 Software for Windows Metal Drift is a futuristic multiplayer motorsport game. You play in two teams of up to 6 players, and the idea is to collect a metal ball with your hover tank, and take it to the opposition&apos;s...

 Tidy Favorites 

 Software for Windows Bookmarks and favorites are a great way to take care of your top websites and pages, but as anybody with more than a few dozen will know, they can quickly get unmanageable.
Tidy Favorites is a...

 i2sm 

 Software for Windows In the world of software you find apps that are handy, apps that are interesting and apps that are... well, a bit pointless, but attractive nonetheless!
This is the case of i2sm, one of the...

 Torchlight 

 Software for Windows Torchlight is an action-RPG, much like the classic genre defining game Diablo.
Unlike that grim, dark game, Torchlight has a comic-like style and while the gameplay itself is very similar, the...

 GunFu Deadlands 

 Software for Windows GunFu Deadlands is a super hard retro styled indie game. You play a wild west guy, and have to kill all the bad guys on each of 10 levels. 
This is a stealth game, so running out guns blazing will...

 Pimp My Zombie 

 Software for Windows This weekend is Halloween, so you probably have pretty much everything ready by now: costume, candy, home decoration.. wait: did you send Halloween cards to your friends?
Well, now you don&apos;t need...

 Oxelon Media Converter 

 Software for Windows High quality media converters are hard to find. Either they don&apos;t support the format you need, or they don&apos;t work as expected. But Oxelon Media Converter is a totally different thing.Oxelon Media...

 Free Fun Halloween Screensaver 

 Software for Windows If you already have a Halloween desktop background, Halloween icons and even Halloween sound effects, the only thing left is a screensaver.
With Free Fun Halloween Screensaver you&apos;ll give the...

 The Left 4 Dead HUD Desktop 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a Left 4 Dead fan, or simply love zombies and machine guns, this HUD will suit you down to the ground. Using the Rainmeter application, convert your desktop into a likeness of the...

 Boo-tiful Halloween Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows Halloween is just around the corner, so it&apos;s time to get started with celebrations! And what better way to get into the mood than decorating your computer with a Halloween wallpaper?
Boo-tiful...

 Diet Sleuth 

 Software for Windows Sitting behind your computer all day is a surefire way to put on weight. Diet Sleuth aims to stop the rot by using your PC as a tool in the fight against weight gain.
Diet Sleuth allows you to...

 Skype Portable 

 Software for Windows Skype Portable is the standalone version of the popular VOIP (Voice over Internet Protocol) program that allows you call and talk to other Skype users, video chat and more for free over the...

 Think Halloween Wallpaper 

 Software for Windows &apos;Think Different&apos;was the slogan of a popular advertising campaign for Apple. It was happily adopted by Apple fans and recreated on posters, photo collages and wallpapers... like this one.
The...

 OpinionCloud 

 Software for Windows Popular Flickr photos and YouTube videos have hundreds of comments, and if you&apos;re interested in what the crowd thinks that&apos;s a lot to read. OpinionCloud, a Firefox extension, adds a useful cloud to...

 Fatty Bum Bum 

 Software for Windows Fatty Bum Bum is not the protagonist of this game, but a strange God creature who you have to feed. Your baby character flies through a world of dreams and nightmares, collecting food to make Fatty...

 Pure CSS Menu Maker 

 Software for Windows If you like CSS-based menus but have no idea about CSS – or HTML for that matter – you need a tool like Pure CSS Menu Maker.
With Pure CSS Menu Maker you can easily generate purely CSS menus...

 Simple Shutdown Timer 

 Software for Windows Simple Shutdown Timer provides an uncomplicated countdown timer for your computer.You specify the hours, minutes and seconds and chose the action you want the program to perform – Log off, Reboot,...

 My Daily Planner 

 Software for Windows The more tasks you have to complete, the more stressed you feel about it, and the less productive you are. What&apos;s the solution then? Simply organizing your tasks so that you can focus on one thing...

 Google Maps Saver 

 Software for Windows Having a natural tendency to get lost anywhere, Google Maps has saved my life many times. I guess that&apos;s why I&apos;m a big fan of this tool, and with Google Maps Saver, I even like it more!Google Maps...

 Waver 

 Software for Windows Google Wave is a fascinating communication service, and Waver is an Adobe Air based desktop client. It&apos;s cross-platform, as are all Air applications, and allows you to access the service without a...

 Waver 

 Software for Mac Google Wave is a fascinating communication service, and Waver is an Adobe Air based desktop client. It&apos;s cross-platform, as are all Air applications, and allows you to access the service without a...

 CrystalWolf Audio Player 

 Software for Windows Sometimes simpler is better. That&apos;s probably the motto behind CrystalWolf Audio Player, a minimalist audio player that works with all major formats.
CrystalWolf Audio Player supports 20 formats,...

 SecurAble 

 Software for Windows Ever wanted to get up close and personal with your processor? Well, no, neither have I, but sometimes it’s a good idea. If you are thinking about upgrading or changing your operating system, for...

 Unified Search 

 Software for Windows Unified Search is a Firefox add-on that allows you to view various search engine alternatives in the right-hand side of your usual results. The alternative engines are configurable in the options...

 On-Screen Keyboard Portable 

 Software for Windows A virtual keyboard is an app that works like a keyboard, but appears onscreen, that you type into with the mouse.
This On-Screen Keyboard is a virtual keyboard that you can install on a USB drive,...

 goot 

 Software for Windows Google Translate now covers a huge range of languages, so for anyone working in a multi-lingual environment it&apos;s become a trusty tool.
goot is a cross platform translation tool that aims to...

 DMS Clarity Metrics Tracker 

 Software for Windows Before shelling out on Windows 7, you&apos;ll want to know if you computer is compatible. DMS Clarity Metrics Tracker is a small multi-part application that will help you make sure that your machine is...

 EraserDrop Portable 

 Software for Windows EraserDrop Portable puts a secure data deletion tool in your USB toolkit. If you often work on different terminals, and want to make sure you haven&apos;t left anything there, EraserDrop Portable is at...

 Doit.im 

 Software for Windows GTD – which stands for Getting Things Done – is a very popular method to manage tasks and boost your productivity in a very easy way. Based on the main principles of this method, Doit.im lets you...

 uTorrent Portable 

 Software for Windows uTorrent has quickly become a favorite among torrent users worldwide thanks to an innovative interface, minute CPU usage and extensive download details. And now, with this Portable version, you can...

 Grappling Hook 

 Software for Windows Grappling hooks have often played a big part in comic book fiction and games like Bionic Commando, but they have never caught on in real life. For anyone upset about this tragic state of affairs,...

 Grappling Hook 

 Software for Mac Grappling hooks have often played a big part in comic book fiction and games like Bionic Commando, but they have never caught on in real life. For anyone upset about this tragic state of affairs,...

 New Tab Page 

 Software for Windows How many times a day do you open a new tab in Firefox? Wouldn&apos;t it be nice to have a more useful page instead of the usual blank space?
New Tab Page is a simple Firefox add-on that replaces the...

 Dropresize 

 Software for Windows If you constantly post your photos on the web, resizing them can be a bit time consuming. Some websites now do this during the upload process, but this does seem to slow it down. 
DropResize is a...

 FolderSize.WPF 

 Software for Windows After using the computer for a while, one day you suddenly realize there are only a few MB left in your hard drive. Now, where did all that space go?
A quick, easy way to find out is FolderSize....

 Windows 7 USB DVD Download Tool 

 Software for Windows Windows 7 is already available for purchase, also as an installation ISO file from Microsoft&apos;s website. But once you&apos;ve paid for the file and downloaded it, how do you install it on your computer?...

 You Can&apos;t Possibly Expect Me To Do That 

 Software for Windows You Can&apos;t Possibly Expect Me To Do That is a platform/puzzle game with an odd idea - to beat levels you have to die!
This is a strange game. It&apos;s graphically stark and basic, but that actually...

 Windows 7 Manager 

 Software for Windows Windows 7 offers dozens of configuration and customization settings, but sometimes the most interesting tweaks are way too hidden for the average user.Windows 7 Manager brings all those hidden...

 Sublime Text 

 Software for Windows Sublime Text 2 is a minimalist coding editor that will let you focus completely on your code.Sublime Text works by focusing on what it really important - the code - and leaves the other types of...

 Windows 7 Easy Transfer 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re planning to get a new computer and install the brand new Windows 7 on it, there&apos;s one important question: how do you transfer all your data from the old system to the new one?
Luckily...

 Windows 7 Easy Transfer 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re planning to get a new computer and install the brand new Windows 7 on it, there&apos;s one important question: how do you transfer all your data from the old system to the new one?
Luckily...

 History Killer 

 Software for Windows Lots of programs build up their own history, cache and temporary files taking up HDD space and slowing down your system. Cleaning all of your applications one by one is time consuming, but there...

 Death Rally 

 Software for Windows Remedy Entertainment have recently made a name for themselves with the Max Payne games and Alan Wake, but back in 1996 they made a significantly less serious game: Death Rally.
This top down racer...

 RunMan: Race Around the World 

 Software for Windows Platform games were introduced to speed by Sega&apos;s Sonic, but while he&apos;s away from the 2D arena, Tom Sennet and Matt Thorson have introduced RunMan: Race Around the World.Runman is a little yellow...

 Boulder Dash - ROCKS! 

 Apps for iPhone Boulder Dash is one of the oldest franchises around, and surprisingly the basic format hasn&apos;t changed for 25 years! Boulder Dash - ROCKS! is the latest addition to the family, this time on your...

 Aero 7 Windows Seven Wallpapers 

 Software for Windows Looking forward to Windows 7? You can already get yourself into the mood with these beautiful wallpapers for your background.
Aero 7 Windows Seven Wallpapers is a pack of high resolution...

 Sothink Photo Album Maker 

 Software for Windows Here&apos;s the situation: you have a bunch of photos you&apos;d like to share with family and friends, but you don&apos;t want to send them as simple email attachments. You&apos;d like to do something creative with...

 Windows 7 Wallpaper Pack 

 Software for Windows The launch of Windows 7 is the most important software-related news we&apos;ve had in the last few weeks. It&apos;s only natural then that we celebrate it in any possible way, such as this huge pack of...

 Subvein 

 Software for Windows Subvein is a free online multiplayer shooter. What makes it unusual is that it&apos;s a top-down 2D game!
Like many online shooters, you have some control over your player - you can buy and upgrade...

 Bullets of a Revolver 

 Software for Windows Bullets of a Revolver is a little freeware Wild West beat&apos;em up. It tells the story of two bandits on their journey to discover a secret cave filled with gold.
The journey is told through a...

 FIFA Manager 10 

 Software for Windows Football Manager is generally regarded as the best soccer management game out there. In recent years though, FIFA Manager has made up some ground on its rival, and this latest incarnation is the...

 Scott&apos;s Gmail Alert 

 Software for Windows Checking your email can be become such an automated action that you don&apos;t realize how much time you really waste on it. Luckily you can use applications that take care of this task for you, like...

 Splashup Light 

 Software for Windows Most users don&apos;t need a massive graphic suite like Photoshop to work on their images. A smaller, more simple solution like Splashup Light will do the trick.
Splashup Light is actually a...

 Zuma&apos;s Revenge! 

 Software for Mac Zuma&apos;s Revenge is the addictive sequel to Zuma, the bubble bursting puzzler where you control a lost frog which has found itself up against angry island god Zuma.
The story is just decoration for...

 Foxit PhantomPDF 

 Software for Windows Foxit PhantomPDF is a full-featured PDF creator, editor and reader that’s got all of the tools, but none of the bloat.Like Foxit’s other PDF apps, Foxit PhantomPDF is a lovely program to use. It’s...

 ImTranslator 

 Software for Windows ImTranslator is a Firefox add-on that translates between 1640 language combinations, right from within your browser.The internet is great for making new friends. The only problem is that even...

 SE-ScreenSavers 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re tired of the traditional 3D Pipes, Marquee or Starfield screensavers that come shipped with Windows, it&apos;s time for a change!
SE-Screensavers is a pack of ten free screensavers with...

 Star Guard 

 Software for Windows 2D gaming seems to be coming back into fashion, and developer Sparky&apos;s Star Guard is a neat minimal reminder about what makes it great.
Available for Mac and Windows, this little game offers...

 Star Guard 

 Software for Mac 2D gaming seems to be coming back into fashion, and developer Sparky&apos;s Star Guard is a neat minimal reminder about what makes it great.
Available for Mac and Windows, this little game offers...

 CPick 

 Software for Windows Have you ever wanted to copy that exact color you&apos;ve seen somewhere on your screen? If so, you&apos;re going to love Cpick.
Cpick is one of those small apps that can make a difference in your day to...

 Secure FTP 

 Software for Windows Most FTP clients support connections over Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connections but few are designed specifically for them.
Secure FTP, however, is designed to provide maximum security when...

 TomTom Home 

 Software for Windows In my opinion SatNav is the greatest motoring innovation since the steering wheel. All that money that goes into defense spending finally produced something useful for the average citizen (that and...

 Football Manager 2010 

 Software for Windows Football Manager 2010 is a highly realistic soccer management sim that proves to be very addictive.One of the areas that&apos;s most improved in Football Manager 2010 is the match engine. The 3D view...

 3GP Player 

 Software for Windows Many mobile devices use 3GP as the default video format, but sometimes it&apos;s difficult to find also a desktop video player that opens it. This is where 3GP Player comes in handy.
With 3GP Player...

 FlipOut 

 Software for Windows Breakout and its successor Arkanoid are maybe the most copied and emulated video game ever. Most of them are more or less the same, but FlipOut takes the block breaking ball in a new direction.
In...

 b2 Gmail Notifier 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re the kind of person who needs to be check their email quite frequently, this program is going to save you loads of time.
B2 Gmail Notifier checks your Gmail account automatically...

 XeIMG Image Editor 

 Software for Windows If you work for a website or maintain a personal blog you probably need to edit a few images everyday, and XeIMG Image Editor will help you with that.
This simple, AIR-based application lets you...

 Wolfenstein 

 Software for Windows ID Software&apos;s Wolfenstein is where 3D shooters began, and while the 1993 game looks seriously dated, it pretty much set the format for the genre for years to come.
Raven Software have developed...

 Falling Autumn Leaves Screensaver 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a fan of the fall then you might want to check out the Falling Autumn Leaves Screensaver.
This animated screensaver will bring a taste of autumn to your desktop, as the leaves pile up on...

 PhotoJoy 

 Software for Windows No matter how many wallpapers you have, you&apos;ll eventually grow tired of them... and this is where PhotoJoy comes in handy!
This fun app creates fresh desktop images based on a variety of...

 About Battery 

 Apps for iPhone The default battery indicator on the iPhone looks pretty, but it doesn&apos;t really give you much information other than a general idea of how much juice you have left.
About Battery delivers a more...

 Race On 

 Software for Windows Race On aims to bring the excitement of the World Touring Car Championship, Swedish Touring Car Championship, US muscle cars and more to your PC.
This demo lets you race one circuit in either the...

 IMDB Ripper 

 Software for Windows Most of you will already be familiar with IMDB, a great Internet resource that provides the details of almost every film ever made. The website is great to consult when you are looking up a...

 Manga Studio Debut 

 Software for Windows Manga Studio Debut is a complex - but hugely powerful - solution for stunning, ready-to-publish manga and comics.The main Manga Studio Debut interface is a little reminiscent of Photoshop - it...

 Foxit Reader Portable 

 Software for Windows Foxit Reader Portable is the lightweight and portable version of Foxit Reader. PDF (Portable Document Format) is now one of the most ubiquitous document formats on the net. The problem is that...

 Photo Labeler 

 Software for Windows One of the risks of publishing your photos online is having them&apos;taken&apos;by someone else without any credit to the original author – you. Photo Labeler can help you prevent that.
This simple tool...

 DTweak Free 

 Software for Windows If you want your system to run in perfect conditions, you need to be on top of many different issues. Luckily DTweak can now lend you a hand with this difficult task.
DTweak is some sort of...

 Blockman Gets 

 Software for Windows There are lots of PacMan-like games and clones out there, but it&apos;s a rare thing to find an original take on the idea.
Blockman Gets takes the ghosts out, and makes the game a kind of logic puzzle...

 My Notes Keeper 

 Software for Windows With a name like My Notes Keeper, it&apos;s not too hard to guess what this program is intended for. The developer, however, has ambitious plans for the little application and lists a whole world of...

 Miner 2049er Again 

 Software for Windows Miner 2049er Again is a free arcade platform game, based on the 80s Atari 800 game Miner 2049er.
You guide Bob around dangerous polluted mines, cleaning them up and collecting any valuable objects...

 eDoc Organizer 

 Software for Windows eDoc Organizer is a document management application, ideal for anyone who has a large collection of documents on their PC.One of the biggest flaws in Windows is the weak search engine that makes...

 MidiPiano 

 Software for Windows MidiPiano is a little application that turns your keyboard into a piano. Play and record music in Midi format.When you open MidiPiano, you&apos;ll see a&apos;virtual keyboard&apos;with a Piano Roll window that...

 PDF Studio 

 Software for Windows PDFs are the best way to distribute documents on the Net, particularly if you&apos;ve scanned one. It&apos;s way better than sending a generic JPEG scan.PDF Studio is easy to use, yet powerful enough to...

 RidNacs 

 Software for Windows No matter how big your hard drive, there comes a moment when you suddenly realize there are only a few megabytes left. Now where did all that space go?
The answer to this question is offered by...

 Arora 

 Software for Windows Most people use popular web browsers like Internet Explorer, Firefox or Opera, but you should know there are other&apos;minority&apos;alternatives, such as Arora.
Arora is based on the Webkit rendering...

 Imagine Picture Viewer 

 Software for Windows Imagine Picture Viewer is a lightweight alternative to the default Image Viewer in Windows, that adds a few basic editing tools.
With Imagine Picture Viewer you can browse images on your computer...

 Memoriser 

 Software for Windows Some things just have to be learned off by heart. Pin numbers, phone numbers and exam data are some of the things you may have to commit to memory, and there&apos;s no easy way to get around it. There...

 Berokyo 

 Software for Windows If your computer is so messy that it takes you ages to find any file on it, you probably need an application like Berokyo.
With Berokyo you can create a kind-of virtual cabinet to manage all your...

 Carambis Driver Updater 

 Software for Windows Drivers - the mysterious things that instruct your hardware how to interact with your computer. Without them, your mouse, audio card and other hardware items like modems and printers, wouldn&apos;t know...

 ArcSoft Magic-i Visual Effects 

 Software for Windows If you often use a webcam in your favorite IM client to chat with friends and family, you&apos;re going to love this application. ArcSoft Magic-i Visual Effects lets you not only make the most of your...

 Ashampoo Slideshow Studio HD 

 Software for Windows One of the most eye-catching ways to share your photos with family and friends is turning them into a video slideshow. And with Ashampoo Slideshow Studio HD this task is fun and easy!Ashampoo...

 ZapBing 

 Software for Windows It may not be as popular as Google, but Bing does have some amazing background images that many people would like to use as wallpaper. If you&apos;re among them, ZapBing is the tool you&apos;re looking for....

 ProCon Latte 

 Software for Windows Everybody knows that along with all the cool things on the Internet, there&apos;s also a whole lot of unpleasant stuff. It&apos;s only natural, then, that parents and guardians want to protect their children...

 Auslogics Task Manager Portable 

 Software for Windows Auslogics Task Manager Portable is a simple, streamlined task manager that will give you all the information you need about what&apos;s going on on your computer.The Auslogics Task Manager Portable...

 Sisma 

 Software for Windows I must admit I&apos;ve had to use the password recovery utility on several different online services a dozen times – a tricky situation you can easily avoid with Sisma.
Sisma is a handy password...

 Aristotle Virtuousness Test 

 Apps for Symbian If you had to choose anyone from history to psychoanalyze you, Aristotle would be a wise option. Of course, that will never happen, but now you can at least set a virtual Greek philosopher to work...

 PhotoFilmStrip 

 Software for Windows If you want to share a few hundred pictures from your last vacation with your friends, don&apos;t torture them with an endless session of photo browsing; use video instead!PhotoFilmStrip enables you to...

 PDF Suite 

 Software for Windows PDF Suite is a very user-friendly PDF editor that can be used to view, create and edit PDFs, and has a huge range of easy-to-use features that will help you to get the most from your documents.PDF...

 Magix PC Check&amp;Tuning 

 Software for Windows Magix PC Check&amp;Tuning is a computer optimization program that will let you fine-tune your PC for optimum performance.Magix PC Check&amp;Tuning is a great program that really does attempt to...

 TVTrigger 

 Software for Windows When you&apos;re following a dozen different TV shows at the same time, keeping track of all the episodes, characters and stories can be tricky. Here&apos;s where TVTrigger comes in handy.
With this...

 Modi 

 Software for Windows Do you want to edit several photos in a row? Forget about having to work on them one by one, and let Modi do the hard work for you.
This simple photo editor lets you apply the same effects and...

 Risen 

 Software for Windows Risen falls into a very traditional gaming genre (role-playing) but starts off in a quite unusual setting: a deserted island.
Playing as the main characters of this adventure, you&apos;re stranded on...

 TooManyTabs 

 Software for Windows TooManyTabs is a Firefox add-on that allows you to deal efficiently with multiple tabs.Are you the kind of person who always has a million tabs open at once? If you are, they you&apos;ll know how...

 Windows Medkit 

 Software for Windows In the search for the meanest, leanest computer around, dedicated techies are always looking for better ways to optimize their machines. There are often several parts to this optimization, however,...

 ArcSoft PhotoStudio Darkroom 

 Software for Windows RAW formats have evolved from being a professional-only feature to being supported by most digital cameras nowadays. The only problem is that they need specific image editors, capable of working...

 McDonald&apos;s Videogame 

 Software for Windows You may think that running a fast-food restaurant is easy...well, here&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Videogame to prove you wrong.
McDonald&apos;s Videogame is a simple and fun Flash-based game that doesn’t even...

 Machinarium 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s great when you find a game that is just so cool it&apos;s really hard to stop playing, but unfortunately that&apos;s not always the case. Luckily for us, Machinarium is one of these games, a program so...

 ArcSoft Print Creations 3 

 Software for Windows Have you ever thought about all the different things you can do with your photos, besides sharing them by email or uploading them to Flickr? ArcSoft Print Creations can help you get the idea.
This...

 Gmail Notifier 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re constantly checking your Gmail account for new messages, you need a program like Gmail Notifier.With Gmail Notifier you&apos;ll save the time of having to launch the browser, go to the Gmail...

 infoRSS 

 Software for Windows Everybody has their favorite way of monitoring RSS feeds, whether it&apos;s in Google Reader, via a desktop client such as FeedDemon or using some other application. If you still haven&apos;t found the...

 MAGIX Video easy 

 Software for Windows It&apos;s not too often I can say this, but when the folks at MAGIX called their video editor MAGIX Video easy, they weren&apos;t exaggerating.MAGIX Video easy is completely conceived for the video editing...

 Batch File Rename 

 Software for Windows Batch File Rename is a handy, flexible app that will allow you to rename your files with the least effort possible.File renaming can be a thankless task - even more if you have large batches of...

 MixVibes Cross DJ 

 Software for Windows I&apos;ve never been into the DJ world that much. If fact I&apos;ve always considered it a mysterious, confusing universe – judging from the usually complicated software DJs use.
MixVibes Cross DJ is one of...

 Auslogics Task Manager 

 Software for Windows Auslogics Task Manager is a simple, streamlined task manager that will give you all the information you need about what&apos;s going on on your computer.The Auslogics Task Manager layout is attractive...

 Ignis Fatui Screensaver 

 Software for Windows The intriguingly-named Ignis Fatui screensaver displays an impressive moving system of light particles to create a drifting effect across your screen.
There are a handful of options that allow you...

 Indian Radio 

 Software for Windows One of the best things about the Internet is the variety of radio stations that everybody has easy access to. What&apos;s not so hot is looking for those stations, finding ones you like, and switching...

 DictionarySearch 

 Software for Windows DictionarySearch is a simple Firefox add-on that gives you new context menu search options that will allow you to search for words and phrases without copying and pasting.DictionarySearch&apos;s...

 Screenbook Maker 

 Software for Windows If you need to make a tutorial, you have to make it interesting enough to stop your audience falling asleep. Screenbooks are a great way to achieve this, combining screenshots and other images with...

 AIMP Wallpaper Pack 

 Software for Windows AIMP is one of the most underrated audio players out there, but there&apos;s a small number of dedicated followers that produce wallpaper packs like these to celebrate it.
AIMP Wallpaper Pack features...

 SpeedyFox 

 Software for Windows SpeedyFox is a super-easy tool that will help speed up and refine Firefox.Simple is definitely one of the best ways to describe SpeedyFox, a one-window, no options tool to optimize the performance...

 Dictionary.NET 

 Software for Windows We all need to check the meaning of a word or a sentence in a foreign language from time-to-time. And for those quick translations, Dictionary.NET is a great tool.Dictionary.NET makes use of the...

 Viewer2 

 Software for Windows Viewer2 may not be the most full-featured photo viewer in the world, but is certainly an original one.
With Viewer2 you can browse your photo collection in thumbnails that can be freely rearranged...

 Foxit PhantomPDF 

 Software for Windows Foxit PhantomPDF is a PDF creator, editor and reader that’s got all of the tools, but none of the bloat.Like Foxit’s other PDF apps, Foxit PhantomPDF is a lovely program to use. It’s light on...

 Integrated Gmail 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a heavy Google user, you&apos;ll probably be willing to give apps that streamline a try. Integrated Gmail is a Firefox add-on that aims to do just this, combining the functionality of the...

 Tucan 

 Software for Windows If you frequently download files from free hosting services, Tucan can make your life easier.
Tucan is a simple, handy manager that helps you handle all your downloads from services such as...

 KUninstall 

 Software for Windows If Windows already features a tool to uninstall programs, why should you install a third-party tool for that same purpose? Easy: because with some of them, like KUninstall, you get extra features...

 Moo0 FileShredder 

 Software for Windows If you have private information that needs deleting, you shouldn&apos;t make do with just the Recycle Bin. You need to make more of an effort to ensure that your confidential details stay confidential....

 Printee 

 Software for Windows We should all avoid printing web pages unless it&apos;s absolutely necessary. But if you do have to print one, use Printee and try at least to save paper and ink.
Printee is an Internet Explorer...

 Cogs 

 Software for Windows Cogs is an independently developed 3D puzzle game that uses some classic puzzle ideas and puts them together in compelling new ways.
The first thing you will notice about Cogs is the gorgeous...

 Moody Desktop 

 Software for Windows Many of us spend so much time on the computer that&apos;s its easy to get bored with your wallpaper. When changing it once or twice a year isn&apos;t enough to keep the boredom at bay, you might want to look...

 ASCIIpOrtal 

 Software for Windows Valve software&apos;s Portal is one of the most influential and enigmatic titles of the last decade, and ASCIIpOrtal is a retro style game that takes it as a major influence.
The basis of both games is...

 ASCIIpOrtal 

 Software for Mac Valve software&apos;s Portal is one of the most influential and enigmatic titles of the last decade, and ASCIIpOrtal is a retro style game that takes it as a major influence.
The basis of both games is...

 Need for Speed Underground 2 

 Software for Windows Need for Speed Underground 2 is a demo version of a game in the popular street car racing series.Need for Speed fans have come to expect fantastic and intense racing from the Need for Speed line,...

 Express Scribe 

 Software for Windows If you have to transcribe an audio file to a text document, you might think about using your word processor and media player. You&apos;ll soon find out, however, that this isn&apos;t the best way, and might...

 FabTabs 

 Software for Windows I&apos;m a big fan of making Firefox look as pretty as possible, so when I realized that I could color my tabs, I grabbed the opportunity with both hands. After a while, however, I began to lament the...

 VistaSwitcher 

 Software for Windows When you have a dozen different applications running at the same time on your computer, you need something else than just a simple icon when using Alt-Tab to switch between them.With VistaSwitcher...

 Must Have Icons 

 Software for Windows Do you feel like brightening up your desktop? Changing the icons is an easy way of giving it a new look.
This icon set, Must Have Icons is a pretty comprehensive collection of 50 icons, each in...

 Particle 

 Software for Windows Particle is a relaxing experimental game, where you control a particle that can merge with other colored particles. This is a developmental demo, which is playable, but the setup options are...

 RapidReader 

 Software for Windows Over at OnSoftware we&apos;ve been looking at ways to speed up and improve your reading skills, and one program that we&apos;ve come across in the process is RapidReader. This application takes a&quot;speed it...

 NodeSoft Cover Printer 

 Software for Windows Printing CD and DVD covers can be a bit tricky: you need to calculate sizes, margins and proportions properly if you want them to come out right and fit the correspondent case.Luckily you can now...

 Must Have Icons 

 Software for Mac Do you feel like brightening up your desktop? Changing the icons is an easy way of giving it a new look.
This icon set, Must Have Icons is a pretty comprehensive collection of 50 icons, each in...

 Métamorphose 

 Software for Windows Renaming a file is no big deal; but when you have to rename a bunch of them simultaneously, it&apos;s a different story. In those cases, you need a tool like Métamorphose.With Métamorphose you can...

 Free Audio Converter 

 Software for Windows If you like to buy high quality music files, as many sites now offer files in lossless WAV format, you will probably need to convert them for use on a portable device.Free Audio Converter is a...

 iMule 

 Software for Windows If you&apos;re a P2P (peer to peer) user worried about the increasing regulation of file sharing, one solution is to use an&apos;anonymous&apos;network, which hides your IP address from anyone who cares to...

 Midori 

 Software for Windows Besides the web browsing big shots like Internet Explorer and Firefox, there are other minor, more experimental web browsers you can try out, like Midori.Midori is based on WebKit, the same layout...

 WLMUninstaller 

 Software for Windows Some programs are very easy to install, but a real pain to uninstall. A good example of this is Windows Live Messenger.
If you don&apos;t like it at all or prefer to use an older version- which...

 Open in IE 

 Software for Windows As pared-down add-ons go, Open in IE is very, very basic. Without multiple functions or configuration settings, it really only does one thing, but if it&apos;s the one thing you need, this add-on is the...

 Gljakal&apos;s To Do 

 Software for Windows Having things to do is one thing, but being organized enough to get them done is quite another. Let Gljakal give you a helping hand!I have reviewed lots of planners and one thing I have learned is...

 New Star Grand Prix 

 Software for Mac With the Formula 1 season underway, New Star Grand Prix is just in time to cash in. This is a top down arcade style racer, combined with a career mode more commonly associated with simulations....

 Transmute Portable 

 Software for Windows Transmute Portable is the standalone version of Transmute, a simple way to move your bookmarks from one web browser to another, especially if you don&apos;t want to mess around with the browser&apos;s...

 USB Disk Security 

 Software for Windows USB Disk Security is a program that aims to detect any virus before it has a chance to infect your memory stick.By their very nature, USB drives are prone to infection. You stick them in strange...

 Cuberok 

 Software for Windows Cuberok is a music player based on the popular Amarok application.
Cuberok allows you to listen to music stored locally on your hard disk plus with streaming services such as Magnatune and...

 Splunk 

 Software for Windows Splunk is a Web-based tool for IT administrators who need to search and navigate IT data from applications, servers, and network devices in real time.The tool allows you to log, configure systems,...

 OOo4Kids 

 Software for Windows Kids start using computers earlier and earlier these days, and it&apos;s a good idea for them to get used to office apps as soon as possible.With OOo4Kids you can make your kids start becoming familiar...

 WordReference Translator 

 Software for Windows As a native Spanish speaker who works for an English website, I use online dictionaries and translators quite often. And my favorite above all is WordReference. This is why I was excited to see a...

 Need for Speed Shift 

 Software for Windows Need For Speed Shift has arrived, and heralds a change of direction for the venerable racing series. Whereas in recent years it has found success in street racing, Need For Speed Shift goes for...

 Marble 

 Software for Windows When it comes to exploring the globe, there&apos;s usually only one choice on the table - Google Earth.
However, Google&apos;s groundbreaking Earth navigation application isn&apos;t the only option out there, as...

 RapidTyping Portable 

 Software for Windows Being fast and accurate at typing is becoming increasingly important in today&apos;s world of computers and devices. With RapidTyping Portable you can improve your typing easily.RapidTyping Portable...

 Disketch Disk Labeler 

 Software for Windows After creating a custom disk (CD, DVD) with your favorite photos or music, the final touch is designing also the cover and labels.
With Disketch Disk Labeler you can easily create your own...

 Kigo Video Converter 

 Software for Windows With so many video formats and video-capable devices available today, chances are you&apos;ll often need to convert video files from one format to another. But don&apos;t worry: with programs like Kigo Video...

 Perfect PDF Premium 

 Software for Windows PDF is often related to read-only documents, but the truth is that you can also create and edit PDF files if you have the right tool, like Perfect PDF Premium.With Perfect PDF Premium you can...

 K.O. Champs 

 Software for Windows K.O. Champs is an online game that takes you into the world of boxing management. Choose a fighter and take him to the top, by choosing fights well, promotion and training.
Like many similar...

 StuntMANIA Pro 

 Software for Windows StuntMANIA Pro is a 3D driving game, that puts you behind the wheel of indestructible vehicles in specially designed stunt arenas.This demo is limited to only one car and arena, although there are...

 Nuke Anything Enhanced 

 Software for Windows Some websites are prettier than others. Too many images, flashing ads and stupid banners all contribute to a really ugly website, but sometimes just closing the page isn&apos;t an option. Nuke Anything...

 K.O. Champs 

 Software for Mac K.O. Champs is an online game that takes you into the world of boxing management. Choose a fighter and take him to the top, by choosing fights well, promotion and training.
Like many similar...

 GearGrinder 

 Software for Windows Trucks, speed and guns sounds like the dream combination, and GearGrinder aims to give you all three in a ridiculously over the top racing game.
This GearGrinder demo is quite generous in what you...

 Whois 

 Software for Windows Ever wanted to know more about the company - or person - behind an IP address or domain name? If you have, Whois is the program for you, a small application that presents the information behind web...

 Mac OS X Snow Leopard Wallpapers 

 Software for Windows One of the new features in Snow Leopard, the latest version of Mac OS, is a bunch of new desktop wallpapers. And guess what: you can now use these images even if you don&apos;t have a Mac!
Mac OS X...

 Movienizer Portable 

 Software for Windows Is your movie collection so large that you can hardly manage it? Then it&apos;s time to use Movienizer Portable, a handy tool that doesn&apos;t need installation helps you organize your personal movie...

 Xilisoft DivX Converter 

 Software for Windows The problem with video today is that there are just so many formats, it&apos;s inevitable that sometimes you&apos;ll end up with the wrong one for your purpose. Given the risk, it&apos;s great to have a converter...

 KwiClick 

 Software for Windows Although it&apos;s not going to ruin your day, having to open a new tab every time you want to look something up when browsing the Internet can be a pain in the neck, especially if you have to do it...

 Write Attack! 

 Software for Windows Even the author of this program admits that some people will find it completely ridiculous, while others will discover a new source of literary inspiration. If you&apos;re a writer, why not give it a...

 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 
 
Searches:

 Popular searches Other searches A a a a a a l l videos A a a a a a l l software 
 
 
About us

 Softonic Info Help&amp;Support Jobs Softonic News Comment on Softonic Legal Information 
 
Developers

 Upload and Manage your Software Promote your Software Increase your downloads Monetize your downloads Softonic Ads 
 
Partners

 Advertising Opportunities Softonic API 
 
Users

 Become a fan of Softonic Follow us @Softonic Google+ LinkedIn Flickr Subscribe to our RSS feeds Softonic Answers Softonic Moba Softonic Newsletter OnSoftware 
 
 
Copyright SOFTONIC INTERNATIONAL S.L.©1997-2012 - All rights reserved
 Softonic logo
	</body>
</document>
