<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007619" url="http://www.wacktrap.com/people/stupid-people/beautiful-people-dating-website-disgracing-world-cup-players" time="2012-07-13-00:35" support="9" score="0.022976890214625328" bingtitle="Beautiful People Dating Website is Disgracing World Cup Players ..." webtitle="Beautiful People Dating Website is Disgracing World Cup Players | Wacktrap">
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>Any nastiness doesn’t end there--clicking the link to World Cup players will take users ... fries, and even punches were thrown at a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Log In | Sign Up Connect Search Wacktrap: 
 Primary links 
 
 Home Add Wack Top Rated Popular 
 Videos 
 Maps 
 Member Maps 
 Gear Shop About FAQs Contact Sign Up! 
   
What’s your story?

Share and find customer experiences

Connect with the people behind them

Wacktrap is
complaints made social

 Post Your Wack Now 
 
 Read Wacks 
 
 Advertising Autos Beauty Education Entertainment Entrepreneurship Environment Events Government Health Homes Insurance Legal Media Money Nightlife People Pets Rebates Recalls Religion Restaurants Scams Science Services Shopping Sports Technology Travel Warranties Work 
 Home » People » Stupid People » Beautiful People Dating Website is Disgracing World Cup Players 
Beautiful People Dating Website is Disgracing World Cup Players
 | Share Join To Wack 
 July 8, 2010 12:50am by hearit 
 Happened:  In The News 
The Beautiful People website turns ugly—promoting the beautiful World Cup players while disgracing those less blessed. Ugly people can now get at least a half-beautiful baby using the site’s new virtual sperm and egg bank, don’t count on a mix of beauty and brains—the founder suggests Mensa utilize its own database for those seeking intelligence in reproduction.

To become a website member of the Beautiful People community, the site’s existing members rate an applicant&apos;s looks (aka, beauty) to let you in—kind of like high school all over again. So, whoever missed out on the first round during teen years, can now live—or simply relive—the experience now.

After what was circulated as a PR stunt at the end of last year—when the Beautiful People site supposedly kicked off 5,000 members for being fat—any current spamming wouldn’t exactly serve as a surprise. The site seems to be gettin’ its spam on, with a bit of nastiness thrown in—and throwing any supposed ‘beauty’ into a nosedive:

The Beautiful People homepage encourages users to “Check out the most beautiful World Cup players”—better understood when it’s clarified that featured football player shown is named as part of the Beautiful People membership. But that doesn’t preclude the site from using (or abusing) the world’s specialized sports teams. What better way to spam search engines than by listing the name of every World Cup player and text which includes terms like “Beauty Score: Argentina” Looking for a World Cup “Score” for “Argentina” in Google?—then you just may be ‘accidentally’ run across the Beautiful People website instead.

Any nastiness doesn’t end there--clicking the link to World Cup players will take users straight to a second ‘homepage’ of sorts or sub-site—and, once there, users have the option to rank the football players. But if you’re not feeling the itch to rate the football players, Beautiful People will help prompt you—by featuring photos of the least ‘beautiful’ alongside those ranked most beautiful. A quick glance at the attached image exemplifies the poor souls who are fortunate to rank among the world’s best athletes—since Beautiful People makes it clear that they don’t rank among the most gorgeous.

After allegedly removing fat people—and the sudden interest garnered by that little stunt—the site seems to be at it again—only this time the stunt involves offering sperm in order to produce a bundle of beautiful kids. Started roughly 8 years ago, in 2002, the Beautiful People site wants to oblige the world’s plain and frumpy through offering a chance to produce beautiful kids. Dubbed its “fertility introduction service”, the website’s recent venture involves a &quot;virtual sperm and egg bank for people who want to have beautiful babies.”
By offering sperm to the general world, it seems the founder missed the fact that less-than-beautiful babes could still arrive—if the ‘ugly’ use beautiful sperm, there’s still that other part of the gene pool involved. But a half-full cup of beautiful is apparently better than none.

Beautiful People website founder Robert Hintze said: “Initially, we [Beautiful People] hesitated to widen the offering [of sperm] to non-beautiful people. But everyone--including ugly people --would like to bring good looking children in to the world and we can&apos;t be selfish with our attractive gene pool.”

Such a way with words—and what a formation of complex thoughts and expression. Following a virtual slam of Mensa, that the company could consider doing something similar with a sperm donor program utilizing the Mensa database, Hinze’s own words reflect that beauty and intelligence are well-separated in his world. And that may be the case--Mensa probably doesn’t need to worry about a missing member. The world should know now: apparently there is no such thing as beauty and brains, not according to Hinze’s words anyways.

The Beautiful People website--which claims to be a game reserve of &quot;leopards and gazelles&quot; compared to other dating sites (referring to competing sites as full of &quot;jungles of hippos and warthogs”) supposedly cut 5,000 website members over Christmas. The reason: supposedly a fat factor—however that ‘news’ has been called a PR stunt. Allegedly—and a big allegedly—5,000 website members awoke to find their accounts inactivated due to holiday weight gain, and after members posted photos in the post-holiday timeframe.

Want to know more about the Beautiful People website? Well, you probably won’t get that info so easily--clicking on the About Beautiful People link yields nothing but a refresh of the site’s homepage. But more importantly, how about some snapshots of the founder, managing director or any other staff. Considering all this beauty talk, how could such vital pics be missing—unless, of course, there’s another explanation. Hmmm…. Maybe the founder’s the dark-haired one on the homepage?—or are none of those people members of Beautiful People?

The Beautiful People website claims that 600 beautiful babies have been born to members who met while using its site, or through its services—it sounds like a somewhat interesting statistic (or more accurately, not totally boring)—until anyone considers that the number doesn’t really differ from other dating sites. More specifically, the number doesn’t really differ from life in general: people meet, and mate—that’s the pattern. It’s not exactly extraordinary that 600 babies have supposedly been born to members—but, since the website doesn’t seem to have a lot of stats, a number’s a number.

So now the Beautiful People website has set up the beautiful DNA bank—for members are married or in a relationship, but need an external sperm donor-- in order to accelerate the birthing process of ‘beauties’. That’d be PR stunt number two.

The ‘managing director’ for the Beautiful People website, Greg Hodge, issued the statement: “Attractiveness is one of the first qualities that people want in a child. We [human beings] are all more open and accommodating to attractive people, and anyone would want their child to have as many advantages as possible, so this is no different.”

Hodge added, “For a site with members who resemble Brad Pitt, George Clooney and Angelina Jolie you can imagine the demand.” Wow-that’s quite a statement: a claim of website members who look like Brad Pitt, George Clooney and Angelina Jolie—that would certainly make it odd that there is so many people that good looking who have found their way to the site. With site stats of 600,000 members, that’s a heck of a lot of Pitts, Clooneys and Jolies around the globe. While everyone’s been trying to find the perfect mate, apparently they’re all hiding out on the Beautiful People website—now that the tip is out, dating life will certainly be easier now—it’s just so weird and coincidental that all those insanely good-looking people are looking for dates online.

In reference to the new sperm donor program match-up, Hodge says, “Obviously it&apos;s going to be controversial, but it&apos;s human nature that people want to be with people they find attractive, and have babies with people they find attractive. Exclusion is present throughout society”

The “have babies with people they find attractive” part is a bit of an unusual add-on to a statement—a bit of a ‘cart before the horse’. People tend to “have babies with people they find attractive” because of sexual attraction.

Hodge apparently felt the need to cover every base, stating “We&apos;re [the Beautiful People site] not saying that beauty is the only important quality. Intellect is important as well, so maybe Mensa could do a similar thing with the people on their databases”

Whew—it’s good to know that “intellect is important as well”—for a moment it appeared intellect was going to be thrown out the window altogether. That means Mensa can start up its own site and dub it Ugly Smart People.

The most intriguing statement on behalf of Beautiful People is Hodge’s expression that, “There are no financial benefits for us [the Beautiful People website] in doing this [sperm donor service availability]--we are simply responding to a demand for attractive donors.”

Who knew the Beautiful People website is humanitarian, and just downright thoughtful—to supposedly provide a service that’s going to the company “no financial benefit” at all. The world certainly needs more businesses like that—who have no motivation, and not a thing to gain when offering a service that’s going to cost them in all the resources needed for implementation and management—and all for nothing in return. That good-hearted move on behalf of the Beautiful People site couldn’t have one thing to do with wack attempts to boost traffic in order to garner some serious ad revenue down the line.

In the meantime, where’s that photo of founder Hinze? Apparently he hasn’t chosen to bless the world with displays of his beauty—but we can all only hold out hope.

Maybe all of those ‘fat’ people shouldn’t have been kicked off—while February marked media exposure for the site, and a huge traffic boost that shot to 93,000, the month of May plummeted the company to a rough estimate of about 5,000. Maybe the beautiful people are shrinking with the economy.

Don’t gain weight people…or you might lose the remainder of your beautiful people—then what will the world do?
 Related Link:  http://www.beautifulpeople.com/about 
 Stupid People 
 
 Login or register to post comments 3713 reads Print 
 | Share Your rating: Select rating a bit wack kinda wack wack really wack totally wack Average: 5 ( 2 votes) Take The Tour or Join To Add A Wack 
 More Stupid People 
 The Cheese Will Kill You! 
So, today I am at a cool little grocery near my house waiting at the deli counter to to order up some Boar&apos;s Head meat and cheese for lunches this week. While I am waiting in line there is a sample plastic counter full of bagel slices that this short and rather chunky lady is munching on with glee.
 Police Force Bans Penis Enlargement Size Increase 
Forget about getting a job as a police officer in Indonesia if penis enlargement is top on your list. The Papua Police Chief bans jobs for police officers who aren&apos;t happy with organ size.
 Stamford Driver Lands on Office Building Roof 
Police in Stamford, Connecticut, say a man drove his car into a stone wall, driving the car airborne, to land on the roof of an accountant&apos;s office. The vehicle came to a stop in a residential yard.
 Body Stolen Along with Hearse Returned at Cleveland Intersection 
A corpse in Cleveland, Ohio, was taken for a &apos;ride&apos; by crooks, car thieves who got more than they bargained for while stealing a crematory&apos;s hearse: the genius crooks forgot to check the vehicle fo
 Man Loans Stolen Truck for Beer Run and Tells Police Carjacked 
Running out of beer might be stupid enough-but lending your vehicle to a total stranger stupider. Lying to Florida Police who check video cameras-stupidest, and priceless.
 
 121 People Drink Benadryl External Skin Lotion Medicine 
The federal FDA is urging consumers not to swallow the&quot;Benadryl Extra-Strength Itch-Stopping Gel&quot;medicine, after people reporting they&apos;ve been drinking the lotion medicine meant to be u
 Irritated Juror Sends Obscenities to Court for Jail Time 
A returned jury questionnaire-complete with obscenities-was returned to Arizona Court, where it promptly landed its author (aka, selected juror) a gig behind bars.He fought the law, and the jail (b
 600 Lb Woman Wants to Eat Her Way to Heaviest Living Female 
A 600-pound mother wants to gain 400 pounds and eat her way to title of the world&apos;s heaviest living woman, by topping 1000 pounds-she just might win, as the rest of the contenders are already dead.
 Wendys Drive-Thru Food Fight Ends in Customer Arrests 
Burgers, french fries, and even punches were thrown at a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant drive-thru window--in a fight involving customers and employees of Wendy&apos;s in Kalamazoo, MI, two people were ar
 Worker Empties IRS Building Over Eggs Mistaken as Grenade 
Apparently tax dollars are really going to use-2,000 people total and hundreds of IRS workers were evacuated needlessly from an Atlanta federal building that houses IRS offices.
 
 
 People 
 
 Relationships Celebrities Sports Stars Musicians Artists Stupid People Smart People Political Leaders Clerks Neighbors Social Networking 
 
 Author Information 
 hearit Offline Last seen: 5 weeks 1 day ago Joined: 01/16/2010 Wack Stats : 26403 
 
 
 How To Wack 
 Join Now! You won&apos;t get a discount, it&apos;s free.
A wack world awaits... Rate those wacks Give us your tired, your lame, your
ridiculous and outrageous... Wack comments Your personal soapbox that speaks volumes,
far safer than shouting from the rooftops... Add your wack Give us your tired, your lame, your ridiculous and outrageous... 
 

 Wacktrap Mens T-Shirt 

$24.77

 more 
 
Take the Tour

Click on any image to start
 
 
Share Instantly
 
Connect
 
Create Your Wack
 
Search Wacks
 
Rate Those Wacks
 
 About | FAQ | Terms | Privacy Policy | Copyright | Site Map | Contact Us | Archive | Press 
 Follow us on Twitter | Follow us on Facebook | Subscribe to our Feeds 
© 2011 wacktrap.com All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
