<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007732" url="http://forex-scam.com/corporate-scams/299332-watch-out-for-scentura-creations.html" time="2012-07-13-00:41" support="1" score="0.0013097382264320731" bingtitle="Watch Out For Scentura Creations - Forex Scam Reviews &amp; Ratings" webtitle="Watch Out For Scentura Creations - Forex Scam Reviews&amp;Ratings">
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... to say, Tuesday morning I returned to work, turned in my order and my money, and expected to ... Then work at a fast food restaurant just to pay the bills. Then go back to ...</description>
	<body>
		Publish Your Forex Reviews&amp;Testimonials Instantly! 
 Register FAQ Members List Today&apos;s Posts Search Calendar Search Today&apos;s Posts 
 
 Search Google 
 


 
   Forex Scam Reviews&amp;Ratings &gt; Online Scam&amp;Fraud Reviews &gt; Corporate Scams Watch Out For Scentura Creations 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register FAQ Members List Calendar Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 

 
   Tweet                 
 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 Sponsored Links 
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 

   LinkBack Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
  # 1 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Watch Out For Scentura Creations Sponsored Links I was recently taken in by a scam in sheep&apos;s clothing. I&apos;ll tell my story and then you guys can decide for yourselves. I&apos;m not going to outright call it a scam for the simple reason that everything they do is perfectly legal, but, it&apos;s shady enough that you definitely don&apos;t want to get mixed up in it.



About two weeks ago I answered an add in the Hammond newspaper that was seeking&quot;hard-working individuals to work in a fun, fast paced office in the Hammond area.&quot;I called to see exactly what it was they were looking for considering the add itself was rather vague. I have tons of experience in data entry and customer service, so I thought to myself that this might just be what I was looking for. I called the number and the phone was answered by a girl who sounded about 15 on the phone. I told her I had seen the add in the newspaper and was interested and asked what they were looking for. Her response, word for word, was this:&quot;She is looking for 18 to 25 sharp individuals to manage an office for an expanding fragrance company in the New Orleans/Hammond/Baton Rouge area.&quot;I told her that I was interested and she asked me to come in for an interview at 3:30 pm that evening. This was at 2pm.



I told her I would be there and she told me to&quot;dress professional&quot;and they would see me then. I excitedly got dressed and ran out the door. I arrived at the address she gave me and when I saw the number of people in the waiting area lost some of my zeal. There were about 10 other people in the office waiting to be interviewed. Regardless, I signed my name to the list of potential employees and sat in a chair in the front, planning to have a long wait.



Imagine my surprise when a girl almost immediately walks into the front of the office and motions for me and a man who was waiting to follow her. I think that now she is just going to go over basics, like what the company is about and give me at least the NAME of the company.



Instead, she conducts our&quot;first interview&quot;which consists mainly of what kind of car we drive and what our 1 year goal is. How would we describe ourselves in one word? Are we motivated? After a few moments of asking the same questions over and over in different phrasing, she then tells us we have both been selected for a second interview.



Excited, I thank her very much for the opportunity and immediately call my mom to tell her the good news. At this point, the only information she has given us is that it&apos;s a management position, they will train us so no experience is necessary, and our first year guaranteed salary is $30,000. I still don&apos;t have any idea what the name of the company is, but, who really cares? I was more interested in the&quot;salary&quot;than in the name of whoever was hiring me at that point. When you&apos;re broke, dollar signs are all you see when going to a job interview.



So, anyway, at this point, I think I&apos;m going to be rolling in cash, so on the day of my second interview I float into the office, confident in my ability to impress the&quot;owners&quot;I was told I would be meeting. When I walk through the door, again my heart plummets. There are at least 30 people standing in the room waiting for an interview. Again, we sign in and then we&apos;re all led into a conference room like lambs to slaughter, 5 at a time. I take my seat and pull out the notebook and pen we were told to bring with us, wanting to look my most professional and hopefully stand out above the rest.



Now here is where the tricky part comes in. One of the&quot;partners&quot;in the company comes in and tells us that we have to smile for the hour and a half interview in order to be chosen. Even if it&apos;s the corniest joke in the world, if we don&apos;t laugh, we won&apos;t be chosen. So, I glue on my best fake smile and grin like an idiot throughout the whole line of bull they feed us about how we&apos;re going to be managers, we&apos;re here for management positions, and eventually, we may even be given the opportunity to own our own business. Great! You mean I work for the company for a year and then if I like being a manager I&apos;ll get to own a piece of the action? Sounds like my dream job. Of course, we&apos;re guaranteed a salary of $30,000 in the first year after we complete our training, which will last 6 to 8 weeks. Awesome!



Now for the interesting part of the interview. Individual questioning. I still don&apos;t have the first idea what the name of the company is because it was never mentioned, but, I still want to be chosen. I WANT that $30,000. So, I listen as other people give answers to questions such as,&quot;Should a manager be likeable or feared?&quot;and etc. I critique them, prepare myself for how I would answer in my head, and then finally my turn comes. I stand up, goofy smile on my face, and answer that I think a manager should be likeable because if people like you, they will work harder for you, but at the same time, they should also respect your authority as their manager. Great answer, right?



Now, before the individual questioning began, we were told that some of us would stay in the room, and some would be allowed to leave, but not to read anything into it because it didn&apos;t mean anything. As I watched the others before me sit down in their chairs and others, with bad answers, leave the room, I assumed that I would be one of those sitting in my chair. Instead, the woman scribbled something on my&quot;application&quot;and then sent me from the room. My heart dropped then, because I just knew I hadn&apos;t been chosen.



So, imagine my surprise and gratitude when I walked into the office and was told that I had been selected to come back and work for them and to hide my blue paper in my notebook because others hadn&apos;t been selected. I covertly hid my paper in my notebook and with a wide grin walked out the door repeating over and over in my head that I had to be at the office on Monday at 8:30 am. I got to the car and called everyone I knew and told them I was going to be a MANAGER of a fragrance company making $30,000 in my first year. Great, right?



So, Monday morning I arrive at the office dressed&quot;sharp&quot;as instructed, pen and notebook in hand, and expecting to learn all the ins and outs of being a manager. Instead, the woman starts to teach us about perfume. I don&apos;t really understand why we need to know this exactly, but, at this point, I don&apos;t really care about the difference of eau de parfum and eau de toilette, if they think I need to know it, I will listen. I will learn. I will be the BEST manager ever.



At the end of our perfume lesson, we are told that in order to learn&quot;compassion&quot;for the people we will be overseeing, we must experience what they will go through ourselves by participating in FFARR. We must sell as much perfume as we can to our friends and family members. If we can sell fifty bottles by Tuesday morning, we are done with the first few weeks of training and will move into the&quot;hands on&quot;phase. Awesome! I&apos;m&quot;motivated&quot;to sell as much as possible. Where are the samples, right?



No, we&apos;re given a list with names like Aqua Di Gio and Paris Hilton. Still, I&apos;m motivated. I&apos;m going to sell 50 bottles. Class is dismissed and I rush home to start calling people. Before we left, we were all given a specific time to call in to the office and if we don&apos;t call in at that specified time we are all WPS which stands for&quot;Worthless Pieces of Shit.&quot;So, at my time I call in and I&apos;m told that I have to sell at least 5 bottles that night just to continue to move forward in this program and to recieve my&quot;promotion&quot;the following Saturday.



I&apos;m desperate at this point, calling everyone I know. Of course, no one wants to buy anything they can&apos;t smell so I make no sales. Finally, my father offers to buy five bottles just to get me through to the next phase. He asks if this is all the sales I have to make and I tell him of course, this is just part of my training to learn compassion for the people I will be managing, and I&apos;m sure that the next day will be dedicated to teaching me to be a better manager. Somehow, I managed to sell two more bottles that night and then turned in my order and money the next morning, excited that I had 7 whole sales.



Now I won&apos;t give you a play by play of each day I was there, but needless to say, Tuesday morning I returned to work, turned in my order and my money, and expected to be learning something about management. Instead, after another brief class on perfume, we are sent into the&quot;field&quot;to&quot;pitch&quot;people and&quot;drop&quot;bottles. After assigning various people to trainers, a small group is left in the classroom. We are told to close the door and then informed that we are&quot;sharper&quot;than the others and so we are going to go into the field by ourselves. The first thought that popped into my head was the day I was sent out of the room when the others were kept behind. Did that make me one of the&quot;stupid&quot;ones that day?



Needless to say, this turned out to be something that I didn&apos;t expect it to be. I didn&apos;t do all that great on my second day, so on the third I was sent out with a&quot;trainer.&quot;When we started going to Wal-Mart parking lots to pitch people, I knew something was wrong. EVERYONE knows that Wal-Mart does NOT allow soliciting in their parking lots. I felt like a fool walking around trying to sell bottles of fake perfume to people who, while my clothes might have said otherwise, probably believed I was trying to sell flea market perfume so I could buy crack or booze.



To add insult to injury, my&quot;trainer&quot;kept asking people who didn&apos;t buy bottles for&quot;donations&quot;so we could open our office. That&apos;s called PANHANDLING and it&apos;s ILLEGAL!! But in the office it was encouraged. The analysis was that if you were a waitress you would expect a tip, right? If I were a waitress, I would expect a CHECK. Since I wasn&apos;t expecting a check, why would I expect a tip?



I won&apos;t lie and say I didn&apos;t understand that I was working for commission. As soon as &apos;Independent Contractors&apos; was mentioned I knew that everything was commission based. HOWEVER, I expected it would only be for a few short weeks until I began to manage my own office. Instead, after researching Scentura Creations online, I have come to realize that it could be months or even a full YEAR before I get my office. I&apos;m not a good salesperson and told them that in my initial interview. I was then assured that I wasn&apos;t going to be a salesperson, I was going to be a MANAGER. That is a very huge difference on the totem pole.



All I can say is that I feel sorry for the poor fools who are still out there peddling for them. They make big promises, but can&apos;t follow through. It really caught my attention when my&quot;manager&quot;told me that&quot;all of her money is invested in the business&quot;when I questioned her about an article I had read of one of these&quot;offices&quot;packing up and leaving, never to be heard of again. It was meant to reassure me that she wasn&apos;t going anywhere, but instead it threw up a huge caution sign, because from the very beginning they have been promising that there will be NO start up costs for me to open my own business, they will pay for EVERYTHING until I get on my feet and am established.



A word to the wise: if it seems to be too good to be true, it probably is.




























var addthis_pub=&quot;scamdotcom&quot;;
 &apos;, &apos;[TITLE]&apos;)&quot;onmouseout=&quot;addthis_close()&quot;onclick=&quot;return addthis_sendto()&quot;&gt;[img]http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif&quot;width=&quot;125&quot;height=&quot;16&quot;alt=&quot;Bookmark and Share&quot;style=&quot;border:0&quot;/&gt; 



















 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























pdeamer


[url=member.php?u=115505&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=115505&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to pdeamer[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=115505&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by pdeamer[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=729073&amp;postcount=2&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount729073&quot;name=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post729073&quot;&gt; 
 
 Sponsored Links 
 
  # 2 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations I laugh at you because this is the exact same thing that happened to me back in 2003 but guess what? We live and learn Needless to say we young guys had fun because we stole the bottles of perfume, they never could get it back and we threw rocks and broke all the scam artists windows! WHAT A BLAST!



Thank you Scentura Creations for being our guide and teaching us great *pitches* (Into the window of course)




Quote:




&lt;div&gt;
Originally Posted by pdeamer
[url=showthread.php?p=711070#post711070&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;













BrianM


[url=member.php?u=83668&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=83668&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to BrianM[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=83668&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by BrianM[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=749309&amp;postcount=3&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount749309&quot;name=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post749309&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 3 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations I feel your pain. I think it was 1997 when I got sucked in to Scentura Creations. Though I was not initially classified as a WPS (I actually made it my own office), I saw after quite a bit of time and ****** invested, that that lifestyle was not for me. At least you found out after only a fews days. Everything that is told to you from the very beginning is meant to fool you. Like you said, you thought you were getting a salary. Well, if they told you what was really going on most people would walk out immediately. And they need the &apos;animals&apos; to go out there and sell that $h!t so they need most people to stick around long enough to make a little money off of you until they &apos;hire&apos; your replacement! I just couldn&apos;t lie to people everyday about the so-called management position I was offering them, so I left after about 6 months.



On a positive note I did meet one of my best friends there. Also I did get to see what my strengths and weaknesses are as far as direct marketing goes.





























 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























muziqlvr23


[url=member.php?u=125138&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=125138&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to muziqlvr23[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=125138&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by muziqlvr23[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=784372&amp;postcount=4&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount784372&quot;name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post784372&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 4 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations I want people to know about Scentura Creations, aka(Firebird) in Elmhurst, IL. I&apos;ve been unemployed for a year now and I have 13 years of managerial experience working for banks such as Bank of America, WaMU, etc... I was laid off so I am in the market for as managerial position, anywhere at this point. That&apos;s when I was suckered in at Firebird. It&apos;s the same story everywhere with these guys. They called fro an interview because they seen my resume on careerbuilder.com and said I would be great management material since I&apos;ve managed banks and if I was looking to change careers. I said, SURE, at this point in my life something new would be good for me since banking is on the fritz. So, I went to the first inteview and when I walked in the office the music was blaring and everybody was walking around happy as they can be and their was about 5 other people waiting to be interviewed also. Anyway, I said to myself maybe they&apos;re a easy going place to work for so I went through with the interview. I felt kind of reluctant because they really couldn&apos;t explain to me my position or what my duties included as a manager in training. Then I asked about salary during the training they said would take 6 to 8 weeks depending how good you were. They told me I would get paid at least 450 dollars a week and when my training was over they would give me my own location with 15 to 20 sales associates under me and after that my salary would be around 50,000 a year. I was happy with that so when the interviewer asked me if I was interested I said YES! So she said that they would be calling me back today for a second interview if I was chosen. Anyway, these people make you feel good about the first interview with all these promises you know damn well they&apos;re not going to keep but because I&apos;m desperate in need of a job I went to the second interview when they called me and told me I was chosen to come back. I was ecstatic, I told my wife, mother, sister that I finally think I found a job and that they called me back for a second interview. Everyone in my family was like don&apos;t worry you&apos;ll get it because you have a lot of banking and management experience and they need someone likie you. So I was confident I would get the job when I went to the second interview with all my knowledge. Anyway, when I get there, once again the music is blaring and they come to greet you with all the giddyness of a 5 year old. I was also very disappointed when there was 15 people there also to interview. I knew right away their was something fishy going on when we weren&apos;t even called in one by one for the interview. They told all of us to come into a raggedy room with a cheap white chalk board and a speaker with the music blasting still, with cheap fold up chairs that you could of bought in a second hand store for .50 each. The sad part about it was I sat through the whole 3 hours because I wanted to see what they were talking about but I knew it was crap. I&apos;ve been in the work force 25 years and all my interviews were one on ones not with 15 to 20 people in a room. After they tell you about the parent company Scentura Creations and how much money Larry Hahn makes they tell you about FFARR(Family, friends, associates, relatives, etc.), and much money you could make selling perfume bottles. Also, be careful because they prey on younger people because I was the oldest person in there in my 40&apos;s. I knew it was boggis because at the end of the seminar they call each one of us one by one in front of the whole room and ask us questions like, Are you married, have kids, are you happy, then they joke around so much with you that you start feeling this is too good to be true. Then they tell you were hired before leaving and to come back monday morning without discussing any job descriptions, benefits, salary, etc. Most people left so happy thinking they got a managerial job but in reality they got suckered in to be a perfume salesman. I got home that evening and I went online and found out other people saying the same things about this company. I called them up the next morning and told them thank you for the opportunity but I will not be there monday morning. Be careful, they prey on the unemployed, desperate, young, weak minded, kindhearted individuals and tell you that you&apos;re hired for management position when in actuality you&apos;re a run around with your car, walk around parking lots, malls, etc., perfume salesman.


































 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























GRocJr


[url=member.php?u=132228&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=132228&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to GRocJr[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=132228&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by GRocJr[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=869738&amp;postcount=5&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount869738&quot;name=&quot;5&quot;&gt;5[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post869738&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 5 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations So, I had my&quot;2nd interview&quot;today with this so called company. Everything sounds exactly the same as what happened to me. The only difference is that we got the whole business lesson about perfume at the 2nd interview and they&apos;re now calling themselves&quot;Genesis&quot;. They are located in Union City, Ca so people from that area, beware. As I was sitting through the lesson, I knew it wasn&apos;t adding up. It just made no sense that I was responding to an ad on *****slist that was titled&quot;Office Help&quot;and now you&apos;re selling me a dream that seems too good to be true minus the 6-9 week training program where you sell fragrances and make boo boo money. So I was skeptical the entire time and couldn&apos;t wait to get to a computer to do my research. The only thing I know is that everyone else in the room was eating up what was being told to them and are all probably really excited to report to work on Monday. It&apos;s unfortunate that some people prey on others the way they do.





























 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























sashonne16


[url=member.php?u=144825&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=144825&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to sashonne16[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=144825&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by sashonne16[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=873236&amp;postcount=6&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount873236&quot;name=&quot;6&quot;&gt;6[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post873236&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 6 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations 
Quote:




&lt;div&gt;
Originally Posted by sashonne16
[url=showthread.php?p=869738#post869738&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;













JustMe74


[url=member.php?u=83720&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=83720&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to JustMe74[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=83720&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by JustMe74[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=880716&amp;postcount=7&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount880716&quot;name=&quot;7&quot;&gt;7[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post880716&quot;&gt; 
 
  # 7 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations Can anyone PM me a location I can find for California? I want to steal their perfume again! LOL




















&lt;div&gt;
__________________

My Name is Brian, and I am a professional Internet Marketer/Business Man. I know ALL The legit business secrets and opportunities, just send me a private message on here to ask 
 I am ALSO joining the best MLM opportunity, if you are interested in becoming a member of my team, let me know. My teams are already winning teams, and those who make the transition to work with me will be winners too 


















 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























BrianM


[url=member.php?u=83668&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=83668&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to BrianM[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=83668&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by BrianM[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=885450&amp;postcount=8&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount885450&quot;name=&quot;8&quot;&gt;8[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post885450&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 8 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations Hey Guys!



I just went to their&quot;2nd interview&quot;yesterday. In Southern California area they are calling themselves Management Center Group.. Everything that was said about their from the original poster was true. I Knew something was fishy when they said they were the largest perfume distributor in the US and yet when i googled their names nothing came up! I still went to the interview just to see what it was all about. Now I will never get back those 2 hours of my life. The Manager of that branch Beatriz went on and on about money this money that. I get it.. people like money but damn some people just want to know more about the job they might be doing. So she goes on some more about how much money you will make but never really tells you how until way later. She explains the 5- 8 week course that you will be taking. 1. Marketing Basics, 2. Training new employees 3. Management 4 Admin Work. Well some more stuff she talked about yada yada nothing big then she mentions that when you finally graduate the course and you are given a branch of your own and if your branch stays open for 1 year she receives a check of 20,000 dollars. At this point i conclude this is a multilevel scheme. Not really worth my time. if anyone wanna check them out of for yourself heres the number 1 909 949 2361 as of Feb 24 2010 it still works. Hopefully people will catch on and not fall for this company.





























 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























MiamiScam


[url=member.php?u=147112&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=147112&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to MiamiScam[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=147112&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by MiamiScam[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=892942&amp;postcount=9&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount892942&quot;name=&quot;9&quot;&gt;9[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post892942&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 9 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations I am surprised of the ignorance I have read on this blog. All of you that have decided to talk crap about Scentura Creations needs to get a life. Is it so hard for you to understand that someone can get their own business with pure hard work. You keep saying Scentura Creations is a scam but yet they are constantly opening people from training in their very own office. I am one of them. I run an office with the company. I went through training and finished in 7 weeks. I now run an office of my own and I have people from training that I have opened. So I guess it&apos;s still a SCAM right. So people go to college for 4 years and get a degree but can&apos;t find anything in the field you worked so hard to get a degree in. Not to mention having to pay back thousands of student loans. Then work at a fast food restaurant just to pay the bills. Then go back to school because they don&apos;t have experience. I was one of those people. I also interview those people all the time. Every office with the company is independent. If you have a problem with 1 office try talking to them but it&apos;s not fair for hard working, dedicated, and fair offices. People like you ruin it for people that really need us. You would never have the strength to run your own business. Your better of making other people rich because you obviously have no problems taking orders. For those of you that listen to all the crap on here from people that no nothing about our business, grow a backbone and stop listening to broke people.

TAKE BUSINESS ADVICE FROM SUCCESSFUL BUSINESS OWNERS AND TAKE ALL THE REST OF THE ADVICE FROM YOUR FAMILY THAT LOVES YOU!!! Stop listening to people you don&apos;t know, and be open minded. The company has been around for 35 years. We&apos;re still opening people. I made $86,000 my first year in business. I used to manage a McDonald&apos;s for $28,000 a year. The company took me on a 13 day vacation to Maui, Hawaii. I&apos;m going to Vegas in July. I have never lied or cheated ANYONE. I hope you make your own choices and listen to people that actually know what the business is about. Hope to see you at a company rally soon



Ihaveprevailed





























 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























ihaveprevailed


[url=member.php?u=155914&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=155914&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to ihaveprevailed[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=155914&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by ihaveprevailed[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=951574&amp;postcount=17&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount951574&quot;name=&quot;17&quot;&gt;17[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post951574&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
  # 10 ( permalink )  09-01-2010, 11:27 PM 
 Anonymous Junior Member   Join Date: Jan 2010 Posts: 3,478,201 Tournaments Joined: 0
Tournament Wins: 0 
 Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations I was a former Regional Manager to Scentura Creations back in 1995 and 1996. I think I can give more real information then anyone else here.



For those of you who do not know what a Regional Manager is I will explain.

First level is Branch office. This is first level after training.

Next is Distribution center. a DC is where you had your 2nd interview. DC&apos;s monitor branch offices.

Next is Regional Office. Regional office is similar to DC&apos;s but also monitor DC&apos;s as well as their own branches.

Final stage is a Division.



I went up the rancks from a branch office to a DC and became a regional office when I promoted others to DC&apos;s.



Now to begin with YES they do open offices. The issue is can you survive the time it takes to get to that level with pretty much zero income.

Anyone telling you they are making money during the training phase is full of it. I was there longer then those posting. I knew many offices etc... and have had 1000&apos;s of people coming through my office.

Most making positive comments have not been there long enough to know the real deal and you are still in the brain washing phase.



While the fact offices will be opened is true the whole process is a lie.

Ads are clearly stating SALARY in them. During interviews people are being told SALARIES and BENEFITS.

This is also false. If it was honest then why not tell people the truth from the begining?

If the truth was told no one would stay PERIOD!!! This is why people are mislead at the begining. It is the only way to keep people.



Next we are taught to lie. Taught to lie about how much money we make, What cars we drive and homes we own. Even as office Owners truth be told we were broke.

Now for anyone who wants to comment we were weak etc...

I made it farther then you and knew many many many offices and all were struggling financially.



Everyday I saw people loosing everything. Especially those going through training. I once had a family (husband and wife) who were in our program. One day they pulled up in front of my office with a UHaul truck with everything they owned in it. They had two young children with them and no place to go because they believed in the oportunity. They lost their home.



My regional manager was robbed in his office at gun point by a former employee. I had just left his office minutes earlier or I would have been there as well. However that was not the worse for him. Another employee robbed him at his home. His wife and young daugther were outside in the car at the time and they tied them up and even shot his wife. The news story can even be found online to prove I am not lieing. It happened in cockeysville MD back in 1996.



Bottom line is YES they open offices. However this does not mean success. We were forced to buy bottle by the company to make numbers look better. There goes profit.



One person here said the company has been around for 35 years. While this is true it is amazing they are still trying to open new offices. After 35 years if the oportunity was so good offices would already be everywhere. No more room for growth. They can keep growing because offices are closing.

Should it not be easy for that person to see that a company 35 years old only has all new offices??? Where are the people who have been there for 35 years? 30 years? 25 years? 20 years? 15 years etc...

These people do not exist. Only a couple division managers (people at top) have been there this amount of time.



A few years ago a girlfriend ran into their office. It started fights with us because she was brain washed. Her manager was 21 years old and stated how he had expensive cars, owned a 6000 sq foot home etc... I went to the office and caled him out on it. He was driving a 13 year old ford exploer (in his parents name) and lived in an apartment with his parents.

To the person here who posted they made $86,000 in their first year. I call BS. In fact I will even pay you to produce your income tax record showing it.



It is all lies. Even I did it because I was taught and told to do it. Lieing is the way to success here. When in fact it is a way to financial ruins, death threats and being robbed.



When you piss off alot of people believe me some are coming for you.

Working for this company means you have to live your life hiding. Hiding from people. Hiding from thei police, hiding from the labor board, hiding from court cases, hiding from the local news etc....



Can you make it in this business? Yes you can. But you have to be a person with no soul period. You have to be a person who can lie and not bother them. You have to be a person who does not care about ruining peoples lives so you can succeed. You have to be a person who can deal with the hiding. If you can do that then it is perfect for you.

If you have any sour at all in you then you will never make it in this business period.

It was the biggest mistake of my life. even 15 years later I am still bothered by things that happened.



Also to comment . The person who stated they made $86,000 also said they went on trips with the company. First I will add that the company did not pay for you to go on the trips. They set up confrences and everyone attending has to pay their own way. Do not make it look like the company paid to take you on the trip. I went on many trips my self and paid for my own airfare and hotel everytime as well as all the other 1000&apos;s of people who went. When you paid for the trip it is not called a company trip. I could have went to those places anyways since I paid for it.

They do not pay for you to go on trips so lets get that cleared up right away.



However that person will one day be back on this forum also writing to others to stay away. It is only a matter of time. Once the brainwashing stops and reality kicks in they all change their tune.





























 /images/buttons/quote.gif&quot;alt=&quot;Reply With Quote[/img] 























FormerOwner


[url=member.php?u=158326&quot;&gt;View Public Profile[/url]


[url=private.php?do=newpm&amp;u=158326&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Send a private message to FormerOwner[/url]




[url=search.php?do=finduser&amp;u=158326&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Find all posts by FormerOwner[/url]

































*
#[url=showpost.php?p=954626&amp;postcount=18&quot;target=&quot;new&quot;rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;id=&quot;postcount954626&quot;name=&quot;18&quot;&gt;18[/url] *









&lt;a name=&quot;post954626&quot;&gt;












Re: Watch Out For Scentura Creations


 
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 

 « THe Cobra Group | Prosper Learning Inc.??? » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may post new threads You may post replies You may not post attachments You may edit your posts vB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Welcome To Forex Scam Forum   General Trading Discussions (Forex)   Newbie Town   Fundamental Trading Strategy   Trading Analyst Area   Free Forex Trading Systems and Signals   Live Real Time Daily Trading Ideas   General Trading Discussions - Forex - Stocks -Indices - Any   Show Me The Next Good Trade Today [Daytrading]   Post Your Performance Results Forex Signals Reviews   Forex Signals Review Forex Software Reviews   Forex Software Review Forex Education Review   Forex Education Reviews managed Forex Trading account reviews   Forex Money Manager Reviews Forex Reviews and Ratings   Forex broker ratings&amp;reviews   Best Forex Software ratings&amp;reviews   Best Professional Forex Trading Systems ratings&amp;reviews   Best Professional Forex Signals service Systems ratings&amp;reviews   Best Professional Money Managers ratings&amp;reviews   Best Forex Education ratings&amp;reviews   Forex Scam and Fraud Complaints   Other Investment Forums Financial Markets   Indices     Asia-Pacific Indices     UK Indices     US Indices     European Indices   Equities     US Stocks     UK Shares     Asia-Pacific Stocks   Commodities     Energy     Metals     Livestock     Grains     Soft   Money Markets   Options   Futures   Money&amp;Real Estate Investments Trading Platforms Trading For A living   General Career Advice     Taxation&amp;Accounting   Trading from Home   Trading Arcades   Trading for a Firm     Looking to Hire Trading Styles&amp;Strategies   Day Trading&amp;Scalping   Swing&amp;Position Trading   Spreads Trading   Technical Analysis - Price&amp;Volume   Technical Analysis -Candlesticks   Technical Analysis - Fibonacci   Technical Analysis - Indicators   Level II Tools&amp;Utilities   Trading Software     MetaStock - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks     TradeStation - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks     Sierra Chart - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks     Updata - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks   ShareScope - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks   Data Feeds - Reviews&amp;Tips&amp;Tricks     End-of-Day Data     Intraday Data   Trading Resources     Books&amp;Magazines     Web Sites     Seminars&amp;Tutors   Computer - Security - Networking     Hardware     Software     Internet/Network/Firewalls     Viruses/Spyware Main Stock Market Forum   SEC Filings&amp;Company Reviews and Ratings   General Stock Market Day Trading Discussion   International Stock Markets   Sub Penny Stocks - .0001 To .01   Small Market Capitalization - Penny Stocks   Large Market Capitalization   Rumors&amp;News Online Scam&amp;Fraud Reviews   Internet Scams   Multi Level Marketing - MLM - Pyramid Scams   Religious Scams   Nigerian Scams   Other Scams   Work at Home Scams   Medical Scams   Investment Scams   Boiler room scams, telemarketers, and money scams.   Corporate Scams   Mail Order Scams   Conspiracy Theory Zone   Contest Scams   Lottery Scams   Government Scams   Insurance Scams   Mortgage Scams   Charity Scams   Retail Scams   Used Car Scams   Auction Scams   Hotel Scams   Sports News   Banned Users&amp;SCAMMERS How To Make Money Online   I Am Looking For Forum   Exchangers   General Program Talk   E-Currencies - Liberty Reserve, PerfectMoney, AlertPay, Hd-Money, etc     Liberty Reserve     EuroGoldCash     E-Gold     WebMoney   WebMasters   Adult Businesses   Sports Betting   Get Paid To Do ?   Paying Auto&amp;Manual Surf Programs     Surf Payment Reports     No Longer Paying Surfs   Online Business Discussions   Need business , legal Or Tax advice? Discussion Forum   I Am Offering Forum   Special Offers! How To Make Money Online - Specific Programs   Current HYIP&apos;s - Discussion     HYIP Payment Reports     No Longer Paying HYIPs     HYIP Monitors   MLM / Matrix / Doublers&amp;Network Marketing Forum   Closed Programs and Scam Warnings   Network Marketing&amp;Money Cycling Programs     Closed&amp;Non Paying MLMs&amp;Cyclers   LYIP Black Hat SEO Professionals   Black Hat SEO Tools   Black Hat SEO   Blogging   Cloaking and Content Generators   Proxies     Proxies For Sale     Proxy Lists   Social Networking Sites     Myspace     FaceBook White Hat SEO Professionals   Domain Names&amp;Parking   Web Hosting   Link Building   White Hat SEO Black Hat SEO Making Money   Associated Content&amp;Writing Articles     Buy / Sell Phone-Verified AC Accounts     Sell Your Articles / Services   Affiliate Programs     KlikVIP     Clickbank     Commission Junction     Other Affiliate Programs   Craigslist&amp;Other Classified Ads Sites   Dropshipping&amp;Wholesale Hookups   Ebay   Email Marketing and Opt-In Lists   Joint Ventures   Making Money   Membership Sites   Offline Marketing   Pay Per Click     Adsense     Adwords     Yahoo - MSN - Bing     Other PPC Networks     General PPC Discussion   Pay Per View   Site Flipping   Torrents   YouTube Online Business Owners Market Place   Tech Talk   Looking To Hire   Internet Legal Issues   Sell, Buy&amp;Trade     Content     Links&amp;SEO     Design&amp;Development   Complete Web Sites For Sale! Marketing Forums   Google Forum     AdSense   General SEO   Marketing Forum   Writing For The Web   Social Network Marketing   Affiliate Marketing Forum   Webmaster Revenue     Contextual Networks   Dealing With Web Directory Issues     Directory Announcements&amp;Promotions   Traffic&amp;Content   Newbie Questions   E-Commerce&amp;Products   Automation   Webmaster Marketplace     Content     Design Contests     Domains     Joint Ventures     Links     Want To Buy Links     Want To Sell Links     Want To Exchange Links     Link Building Services     Services     Social Networking     Websites     Web Hosting     Templates and Themes   Ad networks cpa cpm cpl millionaire makers   Mind Set - Success, Power, Self-Improvement   The Copywriting Forum   Adsense PPC SEO   Internet Marketing Product Reviews&amp;Ratings Blogging   Blogging Forum   Blog Promotion Web Development   Coding Forum   Web Design Lobby     Web Usability     Website Review     Forum Management   Graphic Design Forum   Digital Photography Forum   Web Hosting Forum     Web Hosting Offers     Reseller Hosting     Dedicated Servers   Domain Name Forum     Buy and Sell Domains     Domain Name Appraisals Want To Buy Links Stock Market Daily Trade Set Ups   Members Watch List   US Penny Stock   US Stock Picks   Canadian Stock Picks   Euro / Uk Stock Picks   Austrailian / Asian Stock Picks Forex Broker Reviews   Forex Broker Reviews   Online Broker Discussion Full Time Forex Trader Popular Topics   Trade the News - Economic Indicator Definiations   Interactive Investment Trading   Documentation How too Tutorials   Spread Betting   Contracts for Difference (CFDs)   Fixed Odds&amp;Binary Betting   Risk&amp;Money Management , Planning   Psychology   Trading Systems   Trading Discussion   Commodities and Stocks   Programming Discussion   Trading Journals   Rookie Discussion Trading Systems&amp;Metatrader , EA , Indicators , auto trading , robots , black box   Metatrader brokers   Commercial Trading Systems and indicators   New Fresh Commercial Ideas   General Discussion Expert Advisors and Automated Trading Systems   Setup&amp;Configuration Settings   Meta Trader 3   Meta Trader 4   Meta Trader 5   Evaluate&amp;Review Commercial Ideas   Metatrader Programming Forex Forum Directory review   List for Other Forex Forums Hot American Disccussions   Alabama     Birmingham area     Huntsville-Madison-Decatur area     Mobile Area 
 

 
 Sponsored Links 
 

 
 Contact Us - Forex Scam | Reviews&amp;Ratings | Fraud Warnings! - Archive - Top 

 Powered by Blogger 9®
Copyright©2000 - 2012,Dynex Forum Ltd. Design by Forex Scam Forum Community 
 
 
 LinkBack LinkBack URL About LinkBacks
	</body>
</document>
