<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007883" url="http://perezhilton.com/?p=72018" time="2012-07-13-00:50" support="51" score="0.07518555365815674" bingtitle="Miley&apos;s A Bad Tipper! | PerezHilton.com - Celebrity gossip juicy ..." webtitle="Miley&apos;s A Bad Tipper! | PerezHilton.com">
			<query id="001117" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001306" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000131" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000271" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000960" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000114" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000177" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000991" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001179" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000646" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000457" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000146" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000582" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000147" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001383" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000645" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000020" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001194" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000551" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000240" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000426" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000021" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001211" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>... bonehead waiters that only got an evil note on my receipt ... If I don&apos;t want to tip 25% I should eat at McDonald&apos;s? ... is what you were paying for, when you go to a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Channing Tatum • Demi Lovato • Glee • Robert Pattinson • Andrew Garfield Perez Posse login | Sign up Home CocoPerez FitPerez TeddyHilton Perezitos Videos Photos Store Home Videos Photos     
 
 Glee &apos;s Kevin McHale Has A Date With Demi Lovato! 
 
 Katie Holmes Looks Lovely In Leather For A NYC Night Out! 
 
 Bryan Cranston On Breaking Bad &apos;s New Season: &apos;You Will Sh*t! Uncontrollably!&apos; 
 
 Kristin Chenoweth: Released From The Hospital&amp;Recovering! 
 
 Comic-Con: Robert Pattinson&amp;Kristen Stewart Ignite Breaking Dawn Frenzy! 
 
 Madonna Announces Turn Up The Radio Video Premiere! Stop Everything! 
 
 Jennifer Lopez Remains On The Idol Fence, But Thinks It&apos;s Time To Go! 
 
 Demi Lovato&amp;Her Pink Tips Surf Into Teen Choice! 
 
 Kirk Cameron Belittles Gay Families In Dying Homophobia Campaign 
 
 Are You Ready For ANOTHER New X Factor Promo?! 
 
 Celebrity Chef Cat Cora BUSTED For DUI! Check Out Her Mugshot HERE! 
 
 Celebrities Going Braless! 
 
 Kristin Chenoweth Rushed To The Hospital! 
 
 Tom Cruise Had His&amp;Katie&apos;s Security Cameras Duct-Taped! 
 
 Sofia Vergara&amp;Nick Loeb...Not Engaged Yet?! 
 
 Channing Tatum WILL Strip Again! Confirms Magic Mike Sequel In Development! 
 
 Katie Holmes&amp;Suri Cruise Spotted Day After Divorce Settlement! 
 
 Florence Welch Pulls A Little Mermaid, Forced To Cancel Gigs! 
 
 EXCLUSIVE! Kelly Osbourne Front Runner To Host X Factor ! 
 
 Britney Spears&amp;Demi Lovato: We Stormed Off X Factor Because... 
 
 Has Kris Humphries&apos; Bootycall Girl Screwed Kim Kardashian In Divorce Battle? 
 
 Listen To This: Oh, Lordy! 
 
 Demi Lovato Says NO To Bath Salt Bullsh*t! 
 
 One Direction: Before They Were Famous! 
 
 Watch Britney Spears Take No Prisoners During Critiques In New X Factor Promo! 
 
 Eugene McGuinness!! One Night In London!!! 
 
 EXCLUSIVE! Jenny McCarthy&apos;s Bad Habits Book Cover! Sinfully Sweet!! 
 
 Triple Stabbing Near The Set Of Sandra Bullock&apos;s New Movie! 
 
 Sofia Vergara Gets Engaged To Nick Loeb!! 
 
 Twilight Fan Struck And Killed By Car At Comic-Con 
 
 Snooki, Jon Stewart, Stephen Colbert... All Will Be Taken Away At Midnight! 
 
 Scary Movie 5 Just Got A Whole Lot Scarier! Lindsay Lohan In Talks To Join Cast! 
 
 50 Shades Of Grey Nails Producers In Place! 
 
 TomKat Settlement: Why It Happened So Fast 
 
 Listen To This: Swaggy! 
 
 Soaking Wet Celebrities! 
 
 Joe McElderry!! One Night In London!!!! 
 
 Listen To Justin Bieber&apos;s 911 Call After Paparazzi Harassment! 
 
 Adam Lambert Is Not Alone! American Idol Producers In Talks With Multiple Stars For Creative Overhaul Of Series! 
 
 Did Tom Cruise Have The Church Of Scientology Audition Potential Wives For Him? 
 
 Home &gt;&gt; Oops! , Miley Cyrus &gt;&gt; Miley&apos;s A Bad Tipper! 
 Miley&apos;s A Bad Tipper! 
 Filed under: Oops! &gt; Miley Cyrus 
 

You&apos;d think with as much ca$$$h as Miley Cyrus is raking in, she&apos;d have the decency to leave a tip. Not true!

After racking up a $70 bill on steak and mac and cheese at an Outback Steakhouse in Burbank last Sunday, the non-Twittering singer didn&apos;t leave a damn thing for the staff.

Seriously!? We know it&apos;s not Katsuya , but that doesn&apos;t mean you gotta be cheap!

According to a source Miley pulled out an envelope of $100 bills, paid with one and then kept the change.

How rude!

Word got to a rep of the lip-syncing rapper because they&apos;re already doing damage control by saying &quot;she didn&apos;t know she was supposed to tip unless she was eating inside.&quot;

Mama and Poppa Cyrus need to teach their childrenz about proper restaurant etiquette.

Too bad she doesn&apos;t have her Twitter to set the record straight! Ha!

P.S. CLICK HERE to &quot;follow&quot; Perez on Twitter!

[ Image via WENN .]
 Posted: Oct 12, 2009 at 12:15 pm
 / Email this   »
	</body>
</document>
