<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007463" url="http://www.frugalvillage.com/2010/03/25/frugal-replacements-for-household-items/" time="2012-07-13-00:26" support="14" score="0.034364035049855454" bingtitle="Frugal replacements for household items - Frugal Village | Frugal ..." webtitle="Frugal replacements for household items - Frugal Village | Frugal Village">
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="205"/>
	<description>Many of these items have cheaper alternatives, and some items you can completely ... to use cloth napkins, but you can save paper napkins from fast-food restaurant orders.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to our frugal living community!
Join the fun and save a ton! It&apos;s free!
 Login or Register or Sign in: 
 What&apos;s new | Real Time posts | Submit a frugal tip | Advertise 
 Home Frugal&amp;simple living Frugal Cooking Question&amp;Answer Home&amp;family Frugal Tips 
 
 About Contact Archives Forums What&apos;s New Contests Subscribe 
 Latest Posts in RSS 
 Contest Giveaways Contributors Featured Frugal&amp;simple living Frugal Cooking Frugal Gardening Frugal Holidays Frugal Tips General Green Living Home&amp;family Organization Question&amp;Answer Thrifting 
 Latest Comments in RSS Subscribe by e-mail Follow us on Twitter Connect on Facebook 
 
 Thursday, March 25th, 2010 | Posted by Sara Noel 
Frugal replacements for household items

 
photo by redspotted 

 F rugality teaches you that you have options. Everyone has their own idea of what is essential for comfortable daily living. Many of these items have cheaper alternatives, and some items you can completely eliminate buying. What frugal replacements have you made?
Here are a few easy ideas.

 PAPER NAPKINS: Maybe you don’t want to use cloth napkins, but you can save paper napkins from fast-food restaurant orders. Check your workplace if takeout is no longer in your budget. Put out the word that you’ll take them instead of them being thrown away.

 WAX PAPER: You can use cereal bag liners instead. If you don’t consume a lot of cereal, you can ask family or friends to save liners for you.

 FABRIC SOFTENER AND RINSE AID: Try vinegar in your washing machine and dishwasher. If you wash synthetic materials separate from your natural fiber clothing, you won’t use as much fabric softener because your natural fiber clothing won’t get static cling.

 MOISTURIZER: Vaseline, coconut oil and baby oil work wonders on dry skin. One reader, Cheryl from Michigan, shares:“I use Vaseline on my hands with gloves on when they get really dry and cracked, and also on my feet. I also use it on my eczema. Very soothing. I also use it on my lips for Chapstick. If I put cheap baby oil on my skin after a shower or bath (while still wet), it will stick with me (stay moisturized) longer than any creams I’ve used. And baby oil will take off eye makeup fast. Even waterproof! Gently rub a drop on each eye-lash-line. Tissue off or use a warm wet washcloth. It doesn’t burn my eye area, and it is moisturizing!”

 BROWN SUGAR: Make your own. For measurements, try 2 cups sugar to 1/3 cup molasses, and adjust (increase molasses) it to your own taste from there. If you don’t have a stand mixer or food processor, use a fork to combine the two ingredients. While this won’t always be cheaper than brown sugar you can buy at the store, if you’re out, it will save you time and money.

 COOKING SPRAY: Invest (or ask for one as a gift) in a refillable oil sprayer.
 Article continues below ↓ advertisement | your ad here 
 
 SALAD DRESSING: These are very easy to whip up. If you go through the trouble of making a wonderful meal, take a couple of minutes to make your own salad dressing.

 French Dressing 

1/3 cup sugar
1 teaspoon paprika
1 teaspoon onion powder
1/3 cup ketchup
1/2 cup salad oil
1/4 cup cider vinegar
1 squeeze of lemon

Combine all ingredients and blend until oil is incorporated. You can adjust the amount of sugar and lemon juice.—Skip, Kentucky

 CLEANERS: Many of your cleaning products can be replaced with vinegar, salt, dish liquid, essential oils, lemon juice, castile soap and baking soda. The exception will be for natural surfaces, such as granite countertops, but for most other surfaces, you can use your own homemade cleaners and even laundry soap. You can make your own laundry soap, too.

 Powdered Laundry Soap 

2 cups finely shredded Fels-Naptha or Zote grated soap
1 cup washing soda
1 cup borax

Combine ingredients, and store in an airtight plastic container. Use 2 tablespoons per laundry load.
If you have a hard time finding ingredients, visit www.soapsgonebuy.com for kits that include everything you need including pre-grated Fels-Naptha.
 If you enjoyed this post, make sure you subscribe to my RSS feed ! Posted by Sara Noel on March 25 2010. Filed under Home&amp;family .
Sara Noel owns Frugal Village, LLC and is a nationally syndicated columnist with Universal Uclick. Bio , Follow me on Twitter , Join us on Facebook «« Cook seasonal vegetables Just Eyewear contest giveaway »» 
 

3 Comments for “Frugal replacements for household items” 

 Lulu 3/25/2010 - 12:44 pm 
I also use Olive Oil to deep condition my hair. It sounds weird..but it works so well. On a Saturday morning I warm some olive oil for a few seconds in the microwave and apply to dry hair with my fingers. I put on a plastic shower cap and then blast my head with the hair drier for 5 minutes. Then take off the cap and shampoo my hair as normal…hair feels so soft after.
.-= Lulu´s last blog .. I Lost A Credit Card =-.
1 Reply Yasmine 3/27/2010 - 11:46 pm 
I use vinegar in my dishwasher for quite some time now and my dishes are still sparkling. I used to pay almost 8$ for a bottle of commercial product! I also make my own all purpose cleaner with vinegar, alcohol and a dash of dish detergent mixed with water. Non toxic and smells great!
.-= Yasmine´s last blog .. The Love Story About Two Dirty Socks =-.
2 Reply AngieP2B 3/30/2010 - 10:35 pm 
I love reading all of these little tips. I didn’t know about using vinegar in the dishwasher, I’m definitely going to try that one because the commercial products are so expensive. Vinegar is also great for cleaning windows. When I use regular window cleaner I water it down but I prefer to use vinegar because it is cheaper and works better.
.-= AngieP2B´s last blog .. Living On A Student Budget =-.
3 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
MOST RECENT
 
 Forums Blogs Articles 
 
 View RSS feed 

 View RSS feed 

 Uses for metal spoons Ways to clean and care for wooden bowls New uses for an old TV armoire Uses for silicone baking cups Dressing a tween on a budget Make saving money a game Create a plan for leftovers Storing ginger root New uses for baby wipes Prevent stale marshmallows 
 
You may also like
 
 Frugal&amp;simple living» 
 
 Lump-free gravy easy as a few shakes 
 
photo by talekinker Homemade gravy is far superior to what you can buy in the store. It’s cheaper, too. It’s oil, liquid, such as stock, and a thickener. Seems simple enough. Yet how often have you bought a can, jar or packet? The trick to making gravy without lumps is to make a slurry by [...]
 
 More Frugal&amp;simple living articles» 
 
 
 Frugal Cooking» 
 
 Berried treasures for summer 
 
photo by lissalou66 Raspberries are expensive to buy at the grocery store. It’s cheaper to pick them yourself at a U-pick farm, buy them at your local farmers’market or grow your own. They mold quickly, so you’ll want to use them up or freeze them as soon as possible. They’re healthy for you and [...]
 
 More Frugal Cooking articles» 
 
 
 Home&amp;family» 
 
 What’s a Mary Ann pan? 
 
DEAR SARA: I asked my mother-in-law what my sister-in-law might like for her upcoming birthday. She told me she wanted a Mary Ann pan. I was too embarrassed to ask what it is. What is it?—Becky Cody, Kansas DEAR BECKY CODY: It’s a round cake pan. They’re short compared to a Bundt pan. [...]
 
 More Home&amp;family articles» 
 
 
 Question&amp;Answer» 
 
 Refrigerate leftovers quickly 
 
photo by babyparentingguide DEAR SARA: Is it safe to put warm chicken in the fridge?—Linda S., e-mail DEAR LINDA: Often, you’ll hear advice to let food cool on the counter before placing it in the refrigerator. This can be helpful so your refrigerator doesn’t work harder to keep its temperature. However, according to [...]
 
 More Question&amp;Answer articles» 
 
 
 Frugal Tips» 
 
 How to buy souvenirs on a budget 
 
photo by henry bloomfield Souvenirs can be expensive. I suggest bringing home pieces of the scenery, such as rocks, sand or shells, to display in mason jars or in your garden. Or press flowers and leaves. Of course, check that there aren’t any rules against taking these items. You can take plenty of photos, and [...]
 
 More Frugal Tips articles» 
 
 
 Home | Frugal living forums | United Features | Contact | About | Terms of service | Privacy Statement | Entries (RSS) | Comments (RSS) | Editorial Calendar 
Copyright ©2001 - 2012, Frugal Village, LLC
	</body>
</document>
