<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007735" url="http://www.themedicalquestions.com/beauty/are-a-cups-or-b-cups-bigger.html" time="2012-07-13-00:41" support="1" score="0.0009092842791899615" bingtitle="Are a cups or b cups bigger-Beauty Health Questions answered" webtitle="Are a cups or b cups bigger-Beauty Health Questions answered">
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>Remember that cup size is determined by the number of inches around the breast, and proportionally ... It&apos;s all about proportion.When someone is below or near 5&apos; and below ...</description>
	<body>
		Health Questions Find Your Best Health Questions&amp;Answers Online Home &gt; Health &gt; Beauty Health &gt; 
Are a cups or b cups bigger
 Health related question in topics Style Beauty .We found some answers as below for this question &quot;Are a cups or b cups bigger&quot;,you can compare them. 
 A B cup bra is larger than an A cup bra. 15 percent of women in the United States wear an A cup, 44 percent wear a B cup. ChaCha! [ Source: http://www.chacha.com/question/are-a-cups-or-b-cups-bigger ] More Answers to &quot; Are a cups or b cups bigger &quot; Why do other people&apos;s B cups look bigger than my B cup?? http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090718102749AAEvtpZ well they could have push up bras and the ones with the gell stuff. and ive heard if u put like bronzer at the top and in the middle of ur breast it makes them look bigger Is a B cup *that* big? http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080423141547AABcrav You are average. That is a totally normal size. Even a C cup is pretty average, so no, you aren&apos;t big. How can i make my breasts bigger, naturally, from a AA cup, to B?? http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080616113859AAgkJL0&amp;=7 Suction bras are proven to work, but they probably hurt and there is some debate over whether they increase your risk of cancer or not. But really, why do you need bigger breasts? Of course guys like them, but that&apos;s not your responsibil... 
Related Questions Answered on Y!Answers
 Why do other people&apos;s B cups look bigger than my B cup? LOL? Q: I noticed in magazines, internet, and T.V. when they talk about celebrities breast sizes, the ones that are B cups..I would think are C cups.... I&apos;m a 34 B but I look smaller than them...I&apos;m 5&apos;3 and 115lbs...weight could have to do with it..But then again the celebs are skinny and have B cups that look prety big. A: its because boobs look different with all people it all depends on your height Is a B cup much bigger than an A cup? Q: I know A&apos;s are quite a bit bigger than AA cups. Are B cups quite a bit bigger than A&apos;s or is it not really much of difference? A: An&quot;A&quot;cup means your bust measurement is one inch more than your band measurement.A&quot;B&quot;cup is a two inch difference.A&quot;C&quot;cup is a three inch difference.Consequently, the cup size for a 34C is the same as the cup size for a 36B. Would you consider small c-cups (or even large b&apos;s) to be big breasts, if they are on a small frame? Q: My friend is 23 yrs. old, about 5&apos;1&quot;and about 110 lbs., so she has a pretty small frame, like me. However I have a-cups, and she has large b-cups and is always bragging about how huge her boobs are! Sure, they definitely look larger on her than they would a woman who was 5&apos;10&quot;, but I wouldn&apos;t consider them to be big.So, my question is, would large b-cups be considered&quot;big&quot;on a small frame like this? (Cuz I think only small c&apos;s on my/my friend&apos;s type of frame could be considered big.) So, what do you think the minimum cup size is, on a very petite body, to be considered as having&quot;big&quot;breasts? A: I&apos;ve definitely seen very petite women with medium-large b-cups that have a lot of the characteristics of&quot;big&quot;breasts. Remember that cup size is determined by the number of inches around the breast, and proportionally speaking, an inch is a lot more on a small body. It&apos;s all about proportion.When someone is below or near 5&apos;and below or near 100 lbs, and/or when you are in band sizes of 32 and below, a large b-cup can seem big. I&apos;ve seen breasts this size that form definite cleavage and that, in a bra, have the same general rounded shape as c-cups on medium-sized women. However, breasts this size often share the small-breast characteristics of being perky even when unsupported (because the absolute size is still small) and of looking&quot;pointy&quot;when braless.Don&apos;t worry about your a-cups; take advantage of what you&apos;ve got. A-cups on a very petite frame are about equivalent to b-cups on a medium frame, which is about average. And you can get away with low-cut tops, going braless, and even going topless at appropriate beaches/pools, all of which can attract attention if you want. A cute petite woman with small breasts who is confident in her body is just as attractive as a confident large-breasted woman. TOP 
 
 Prev Question: Is the Nike hyperize the lightest basketball shoe 
Next Question: 
 People also view Is the Nike hyperize the lightest basketball shoe Are a cups or b cups bigger How long does it take fingernails to grow Is it trashy to get your belly button pierced What is the most popular color for fall Who has the most tattoos in the world Do girls like sideburns Do guys think stretch marks are nasty How fast do eyelashes grow How much does it cost to get a piercing at Snake Bites 
 Health Questions Guide 

 Fitness Health Healthy Eating Beauty Health Psychological Health Illness Drugs Medicines Womens Health Diet Pregnant Health 

Advertising
 
Hot Questions Answered

 Who has the most tattoos in the world Is it trashy to get your belly button pierced How do you clean a cloth Coach purse How do I grow a beard if I don&apos;t grow facial hair Who is the hottest girl in world What kind of lotions and cream can I get to get rid of stretch marks How can you grow your hair really fast How can I not look preppy Which would hurt more - threading or waxing my eyebrows What color should i paint my toe nails, and finger nails 
 
QA Tags

 Conditions Illness Treatment Medicine Womens Health Style Beauty Nutrition Diet Addiction Drug Abuse Fitness Psychology Celebrities Drink Food Definitions Health Biology Conversational 
 

 Copyright©2009 Free medical questions answered online 
themedicalquestions.com 
 About Browse Contact Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
