<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007097" url="http://mynorthwest.com/216/441188/March-foreclosure-activity-down-to-near-5year-low" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="6" score="0.005715836295910354" bingtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low - Money News ..." webtitle="More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June  - Money News - MyNorthwest.com">
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>Bill Radke; Ross and Burbank; Dori Monson; Ron and Don ... March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low ... Vancouver&apos;s Biffle wins Texas Sprint Cup race; More Sports »</description>
	<body>
		Traffic alerts 
 74°fair 
 Connect 
 Login or Create an Account 
 
 Edit Profile Newsletters Contests Log Out 
 
 news 
Extras

 Weather Traffic Earthquake Tracker Seattle Police Blotter School Closings Podcasts 


Blogs

 Linda Thomas Bill Radke Ross and Burbank Dori Monson Ron and Don MyNorthwest.com 
 
 Local Eastern Washington Police Blotter National World Money Real Estate Home Improvement Technology Odd Politics Blogs 
 News Talk 97.3 KIRO FM: Listen Live» 
 radio 
710 ESPN Seattle

 Brock and Salk Bob and Groz Kevin Calabro 


Online

 tbtl w/ Luke Burbank the mixtape GeekWire 
 
97.3 KIRO FM

 Seattle&apos;s Morning News Ross and Burbank Dori Monson Ron and Don John Curley Weekends 


770 AM: The Truth

 Michael Medved David Boze 
 
 Podcasts 97.3 KIRO FM 770 AM: The Truth 710 ESPN Seattle Listen Live Heard on the Radio In the Community Contests and Events 
 97.3 KIRO FM: Listen»  |  710 ESPN Seattle: Listen»  |  770 AM: The Truth: Listen» sports 
Extras

 Podcasts 


Blogs

 Brock and Salk Bob and Groz Kevin Calabro The Outdoor Line Brady Henderson Mariners Blog Seahawks Blog 
 
 710 ESPN Seattle ESPN Shows Mariners Seahawks Sounders FC UW Huskies WSU Cougars Seattle U Thunderbirds Storm 
 710 ESPN Seattle: Listen Live» 
 get out 
Blogs

 Tom Tangney: Movies Gardening with Ciscoe Seattle Kitchen The Mixtape Seattle Fashionistas Life By The Pint 
 
 Calendar of Events Entertainment News Gardening w/ Ciscoe Tom Tangney Seattle Kitchen Movie Times Northwest Travel Contests 
 go local traffic deals 
 
Updated Jul 12, 2012 - 6:00 am

More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June
 Tweet Comments (0)  |  Print  |  E-mail 
 Source: Money News
Originally published: Jul 12, 2012 - 6:00 am AP Real Estate Writer

LOS ANGELES (AP) - Banks are increasingly placing homes with unpaid mortgages on a countdown that could deliver a swell of new foreclosed properties onto the market by early next year, potentially weighing further on home values.

June provided the latest evidence of this trend, as the number of U.S. homes entering the foreclosure process for the first time increased on an annual basis for the second month in a row, foreclosure listing firm RealtyTrac Inc. said Thursday.

California in particular saw a big spike in foreclosure starts, or homes placed on the foreclosure path for the first time. They increased 18 percent versus June last year, the firm said.

The increase in foreclosure starts comes as banks make up for time lost last year as the mortgage-lending industry grappled with allegations that it had processed foreclosures without verifying documents.

The nation&apos;s biggest mortgage lenders reached a $25 billion settlement in February with state officials. And that&apos;s cleared the way for banks to address their backlog of unpaid mortgages.

Lenders initiated foreclosure on 12 percent of the loans behind in payment in June _ the highest level since the first half of 2009, according to Fitch Ratings.

&quot;These properties that are starting the foreclosure process are mostly homeowners who likely have been missing their payments for a year or more and just now are officially starting the foreclosure process,&quot;said Daren Blomquist, a vice president at RealtyTrac.

That means the latest crop of homes entering the foreclosure process does not signal that there is a fresh wave of homeowners in distress and missing payments.

Still, the increase in foreclosure starts sets the stage for a potential increase in homes sold at a discount via short sale, when the lender agrees to accept less than what is owed on the seller&apos;s mortgage. Others could end up taken back by banks and placed on the market also at a sharp discount.

Either way, short of homeowners obtaining loan modifications or otherwise arranging to exit the foreclosure process, many of these properties could end up adding to the inventory of foreclosed homes on the market, dragging down the values of nearby homes.

Those homes may not hit the market for many months, however.

In the second quarter, it took an average of 378 days for a U.S. home to complete the foreclosure process, or the point when a bank takes over the property, RealtyTrac said. That&apos;s up from an average of 370 days in the first three months of the year and a record going back to the first quarter of 2007, the firm said.

In New York, it took an average of 1,001 days for the foreclosure process to run its course in the second quarter, down from 1,056 days in the first quarter.

Of the homes that entered the foreclosure process in June, those that end up as bank-owned properties would likely hit the market a year from now, Blomquist said.

&quot;However, if they take the short sale route, it may be sooner,&quot;he said.

Short sales take, on average, 319 days to sell from the time they enter foreclosure.

A stronger housing market could mitigate the impact of future foreclosures on home prices, and home sales are expected to end up ahead of last year. But many economists still say the market is years away from a full recovery.

There are some 3 million U.S. homes behind on their mortgages, according to the Mortgage Bankers Association.

An additional 629,000 homes were on banks&apos; books as of June, but not yet sold. That translates into a 15-month supply, at the current pace of sales, according to RealtyTrac.

And nearly 13 million home loans are underwater, or owing more than the house is worth. Those properties could be at higher risk for entering the foreclosure process.

Even so, the backlog in foreclosures that banks are still dealing with has slowed the pace of home repossessions.

RealtyTrac forecasts some 700,000 homes will be repossessed by lenders this year, down from about 1 million last year.

(Copyright 2012 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.) 

 share this story: Tweet 
 0 Comments | Join the conversation» 



 
 Local News 
 
 United Airlines orders 150 Boeing 737s 
 United Airlines ordered 150 Boeing 737s on Thursday, a big win for the jet-maker and a clear sign that the world&apos;s largest airline is shifting increasingly toward Boeing planes. 
 Mom headed to Ethiopia to honor daughter&apos;s charity-water legacy 
 Fugitive in Wash. bunker recorded video of plans 
 President Obama wants WA to get more degrees 
 Wash. small town movie theaters struggling 
 Nordstrom to launch Topshop in 14 stores 
 3 sentenced in wolf poaching case 
 Crews working to meet target date for dam removal 
 More Local News» 
 
 

 
 Blogs and Opinion 
 Monson 

 The coolest video you&apos;ll watch all week 
 A dad caught a once-in-a-life-time moment while filming his 
daughter reeling in a red drum at Myrtle Beach, SC. 
 Monson: Local amputee defends &apos;Blade Runner&apos; Olympic bid 
 Monson: Coolest VIDEO you&apos;ll watch all week 
 Ross&amp;Burbank: Ask Dave and Luke: Why is blushing so serious? 
 Radke: Snoqualmie, Maybe 
 Dave Ross - tcti: When booing doesn&apos;t hurt 
 News Chick: Two Almost Live! stars are almost back 
 
 

 
 Photo Galleries 
 
 
 The day in photos 
July 12: Pretty cute security dog, drug tunnel 
 Retailer&apos;s mobile revolution 
Chris Sullivan visits to mobile retailers who are taking... 
 The 2012 ESPY Awards | July 11, 2012 
The ESPY Awards on Wednesday, July 11, 2012. 
 The day in photos 
June 11: Spanish swim fashion, health care debate 
 

 
 Sports 
 
 Penn State football deserves the death penalty 
 Mike Salk | The NCAA must punish PSU in the strongest way possible after an investigation revealed Joe Paterno and top university officials hushed up allegations of child sex abuse. 
 Listen: Mike Leach on Jeff Tuel&apos;s maturity 
 Photos: The 2012 ESPY Awards 
 7.5 over-under seem right for UW football? 
 Flynn, Baldwin getting to know each other 
 Mariners youth reaches break inconsistent 
 Venoy Overton&apos;s car at scene of shooting 
 Need a lawn? CenturyLink sod up for grabs 
 More Sports» 
 
 

 
 National News 
 
 Thousands fall victim to utility payment scam 
 As much as President Barack Obama wants your vote, he&apos;s not actually offering to pay your monthly bills. 
 2 sophisticated border drug tunnels discovered 
 New recordings show Zimmerman&apos;s many police calls 
 New blazes break out in Utah 
 Correction: ICE Agent Shot story 
 Ex-Calif. mayor to plead guilty in bribery case 
 More abortion restrictions anticipated in Miss. 
 Ga. woman gets 3 years for buttocks injections 
 More National News» 
 
 

 
 Odd News 
 
 Cop accused of stealing driver&apos;s iPhone from wreck 
A 27-year-old police officer in Louisiana has resigned after authorities say he stole an iPhone from the scene of a drunken-driving crash. 
 Court: Ore. police can seize $1M lottery prize 
 German town designates tricky parking &apos;men only&apos; 
 Oklahoma museum seeks superhero world record 
 SC funeral home to offer Starbucks coffee 
 Yoga teacher fired after glare at Facebook worker 
 Wash. man pleads not guilty in dead cat claim 
 &apos;Boared&apos; piggy goes to bank in Austria 
 More Odd News» 
 
 
most popular

 Esquire readers say Ezell&apos;s has most life-changing chicken 
In what could be considered a culinary upset of 
sorts, voters in a new Esquire magazine...
 Two Almost Live! stars are almost back 
News Chick: Ballard and Kent, beware. Two of the stars from Almost Live appear to...
 Tony Softli thinks Wilson will be Seahawks&apos; starter 
Bob Stelton and Dave Grosby discuss the possibility of rookie quarterback Russell...
 Raped in the military? They won&apos;t pay for the abortion 
Rachel Belle: The military will not cover abortion costs for women who have been...
 Will Washington state purge illegal voters? 
Laws designed to reduce voter fraud before the November have been causing controversy...
 
 
 west seattle 
 
 Photo by Page Level | Share your photo 


 West Seattle news and events» 

 KOMO TV 
 Junction festivities start tonight with West Seattle Art Walk 
 West Seattle Herald 
 Artwalk tonight then the big show this weekend 
 West Seattle Herald 
 Twelfth Night Productions presents Anything Goes, partners with West Seattle Food Bank 
 
 [set your neighborhood] 

 

 
 Contact Us 
 Employment 
 Contest Rules 
 RSS 
 Terms of Use 
 Privacy Statement 
 EEO Public File Report 
 Copyright Infringement 
 
 mynorthwest.com 
 Copyright©2012 Bonneville International. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
