<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007091" url="http://www.kathysfastfoodtoys.com/AandW.html" time="2012-07-13-00:04" support="1" score="0.0007332937735402915" bingtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - A&amp;W" webtitle="KATHY&apos;S FAST FOOD TOYS - A">
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>FAST FOOD CHAINS AND STORES ... web site, but will be promptly provided once we receive ... in the USA is shipped with a delivery confirmation number.</description>
	<body>
		Menu

TOYS FOR SALE

 


TV, MOVIE AND CHARACTER TOYS
 A to J K to R S to Z 


FAST FOOD CHAINS
AND STORES
 A &amp; W Arby&apos;s Big Boy Blockbuster Braum&apos;s Burger King Carls Jr. Chick Fil A Dairy Queen Denny&apos;s Domino&apos;s Pizza Hardee&apos;s Hungry Jack&apos;s IHOP Jack In The Box KFC K Mart Little Caesar&apos;s Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s 1 McDonald&apos;s 2 Pancho&apos;s Pizza Hut 7 Eleven Showbiz Pizza Place Sonic Subway Taco Bell Target Walmart Wendy&apos;s Whataburger White Castle Wienerschnitzel 


OUR PERSONAL COLLECTION
 Our Collection 1 Our Collection 2 Our Collection 3 
 
 


Need Help?
 Search our website 
 

 A &amp; W 


 Back To Home Page 


If you are interested in buying any of the items on this page, just email us at katriggs@tx.rr.com and please include your zip code (country if outside the USA) so we can include shipping cost when we reply.
For payment we accept PayPal, money orders, personal checks or cash.
Prices are not included here on the web site, but will be promptly provided once we receive your e-mail.
We mail very quickly by USPS--usually within 24 hours or less of receiving payment--and every package in the USA is shipped with a delivery confirmation number.

MIP = Mint in Package
NP = No Package
U3 = Rated Safe For Children Under The Age Of Three

 

 A&amp;W -Miscellaneous Toys- 

 
 
Click for larger image 
 A&amp;W -1997&amp;1998- MIPs 1997 Beanie Bear &quot;Orange Shirt&amp;Hat&quot;


1998 Beanie Bear &quot;Turquoise Shirt&amp;Hat&quot; (x3)
 Three Beanie Bears in turquoise shirts have sold. 
 COMMENT: All these Beanie Bears are approximately 6&quot; tall.  
 
 
Menu

REFERENCE ONLY

 


McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 

 


RESTAURANTS OTHER THAN McDONALD&apos;S CATALOGS
 2010 

 


RESTAURANT WEB SITE
 A &amp; W 
 


BOOKS


 

 

 ©2010 kathysfastfoodtoys.com - All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
