<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007098" url="http://productivity.artcony.com/2011/06/23/profit-strategy-raise-the-value-raise-your-profit/" time="2012-07-13-00:05" support="1" score="0.0013130362433120253" bingtitle="Profit Strategy – Raise the Value, Raise Your Profit « Rip ..." webtitle="Profit StrategyRaise the Value, Raise Your ProfitRip ProductionsIncreasing Workplace Productivitybusiness news">
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>Visit any fast food restaurant; you will notice the huge sign in front of the counter which say in a ... You can leave a response, or ... app store download (58) app store ...</description>
	<body>
		Increasing Workplace Productivity–business news 
 What is productivity, read comment and discuss through productivity business expert authors articles « Henry Ford’s Idea The Easiest Way to Double Your Productivity » 
 Profit Strategy–Raise the Value, Raise Your Profit 
 
Small businesses, due to their limited resources and capability, often do not pay much attention to expand and maintain their customers’base; they are more inclined to focus on how many sales they can close when ever they meet their customers. In doing so, they often lose the future business opportunity. 

As a small business owner, you have to realize that it costs to acquire customers. The acquisition cost is fixed for a particular campaign whether the campaign brought in one customer or one thousand customers. While the acquisition cost is fixed, the average cost varies, the more the customers, the lower will be the average cost per customer. Then again, since the promotion campaign had brought in a certain number of customers, you should focus on how best you can bring more value to your customers who in turn increase your income and then
profit. 

Visit any fast food restaurant; you will notice the huge sign in front of the counter which say in a bold letter,“Value Meal”. You were hungry and just wanted a big Mac perhaps, but when you saw the value meal, you might though to yourself, why not? It value for money. So you ended up spending a few dollars more just to save may be fifty cents. But you still believe it is worth your money. The restaurant just sell you more value for them by making you think that what you bought is value for you. 

As small business owner, you need to constantly asking yourself this, 

“How can I bring more value to my customers each time they response to my campaign? 

What you have given might not necessarily of more or higher value to your customers, but they must perceive to be of greater value as far as the customers is concern. For example, the value meal, if you really check the prices of all the content, you probably saved
about fifty cents. But it save the embarrassment hassle of you standing in front of a long queue to decide what you wanted. 

By increasing the value to your customers, you will inevitably bring more sales and income to your business; while strategize to bring more value you should never forget to increase your customers base. You must always have a system to obtain your customers information, at least their contact number and name for future business dealing. 

Keep focusing on increasing your base and when your customers response to your campaign, think of a way to bring more value to them, which in turn bring more income to your business.
 
 This entry was posted
 
 on Thursday, June 23rd, 2011 at 5:46 pm and is filed under rip productions .
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 
 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 
Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Categories

 app store download (60) app store downloads (76) apps store download (74) business consultants (67) c-line products (94) dog products (81) employee productivity (90) garmin.com products (65) GENERAL (2) health products (82) increasing workplace productivity (87) labor productivity (72) natural products (77) new product (84) new products (66) pet products (73) productivity (75) productivity definition (85) productivity software (71) remington-products.com (83) rip productions (69) skin products (72) the cloud (70) what is crm (77) what is productivity (80) worker productivity definition (57) yoga products (84) zellers.ca products (90) 
 
 
 
 June 2011 M T W T F S S «May   Jul»   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30   
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 
 
Recent Posts

 Gross Weight? Tare Weight? Wait! Which Weight? The Timesheet Deathnell Well Designed Office Spaces Boost Employee Morale It is Time to Do the Right Things Selecting the Right Letter Folder 
 
Tags
 business business productivity business success career Communication document management document scanning effectiveness efficiency email employee motivation energy entrepreneur focus goals increase productivity leadership lean Management Marketing Meggin McIntosh Motivation office office supplies organization organize Performance personal productivity plan planning process improvement procrastination production productivity Project Management Sales Selling Six Sigma small business stress success time time management training work 
Contact

 Contact 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
 
 Copyright©2010 Increasing Workplace Productivity–business news - Powered by WordPress ARTs by Top Arts
	</body>
</document>
