<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0007909" url="http://www.job-applications.com/applebees-application/" time="2012-07-13-00:53" support="4" score="0.007710800445059727" bingtitle="Applebee&apos;s Application Online - Print Job Employment Form" webtitle="Applebees Application Online - Print Job Employment Form">
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>Apply online to receive Applebee’s hiring consideration immediately. Complete the ... Entry-level waitstaff job duties include serving food, taking orders, greeting ...</description>
	<body>
		The #1 Independent Online Job Application Resource Website 
 
 
 
 
 Home » bar »Applebee&apos;s

Applebee&apos;s Application
 
 
 
Applebee’s Application Online–Print Job Employment Form 

 
 
 
 
 Apply for Jobs at Applebee’s Online 

 Application for Applebee’s: Applebee’s does not provide a printable job application. If you want to get a job at Applebee’s, you must apply for employment on the website by following the link above. Full-time or part-time positions may vary depending on the location.

 Interview Tips: Go to the Applebee’s job interview questions&amp;tips page.

 Available Positions at Applebee’s: Host, Hostess, Server, Bartender, Dish Washer, Carside To Go Specialist, Line Cook, Prep Cook, Broiler Cook, International Chef, Kitchen Manager, General Utility Worker, Food Expeditor, Busser, Assistant Manager, Manager, Waiter, Waitress, Customer Sales Assistant, Delivery Driver, Produce Analyst

 Minimum Age to Work at Applebee’s : 18 years old (How old do you have to be to work at Applebee’s?)

 Applebee’s Hours of Operation: Sun-Thurs: 11:00am-12:00am; Fri-Sat: 11:00am-1:00am

 More Information: Applebee’s Job Info 
 
Applebee&apos;s Employee Videos
 

Completion of the Applebee’s application opens up a wide range of employment opportunities. Entry-level kitchen jobs and full-time management careers offer Applebee’s applicants an exciting array of job openings. Apply online to make Applebee’s your next place of employment.

 Applebee’s Job Opportunities 
The Applebee’s online application form aids prospective employees seeking a new foodservice career. Apply online to receive Applebee’s hiring consideration immediately. Complete the online Applebee’s job application to discover available restaurant industry employment opportunities.

Whether you seek an entry-level restaurant job or hope to begin a lasting foodservice career, Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar may need to begin work now. Applebee’s restaurant chain needs to fill part-time vacancies and full-time jobs and must hire entry-level workers and professional associates at many locations today. Prospective employees over 18 years of age may apply online with Applebee’s restaurants immediately. Fill out the Applebee’s employment application to find a new restaurant career.

Entry-level Applebee’s employees often begin in kitchen worker or waitstaff associate jobs. Entry-level duties include serving customers, cooking food, and completing other jobs as necessary. Professional Applebee’s workers often find managerial or administrative careers. Professional duties change according to job title, experience, and department. Professional applicants may need to meet certain education or work history requirements to receive hiring consideration.

If you start the Applebee’s online job application, you might begin earning the competitive salary and comprehensive job benefits you seek in a new restaurant career. Apply online to receive immediate Applebee’s employment consideration. Finish the Applebee’s application form to find restaurant industry jobs today.

 Job Titles and Salary Information for Applebee’s 
Applebee’s often hire entry-level workers and professional employees as restaurant associates. The restaurant chain must fill part-time vacancies and full-time jobs across the globe. Apply online to receive Applebee’s employment consideration now. Fill out an Applebee’s job application form to find foodservice career opportunities. Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar locations must often fill the following restaurant jobs:

 Waitstaff – Applebee’s needs waitresses, waiters, hosts , hostesses, and bartenders . Entry-level waitstaff job duties include serving food, taking orders, greeting guests, mixing drinks, and completing other jobs as assigned. An Applebee’s server typically earns a starting salary at or below minimum wage, but many workers receive tips, as well. Read the Applebee’s host job description to discover job duties and pay scales for Applebee’s hosting staff members. Browse the Applebee’s bartender job description to learn about bartending opportunities with the quick-casual restaurant chain. Consult the Applebee’s server job description to find out more about waiting openings with Applebee’s.

 Kitchen – Kitchen jobs at Applebee’s may include chef, prep cook, line cook, dishwasher, and busser positions. Kitchen duties include preparing food, cooking, washing dishes, bussing tables, and completing other assigned tasks. Kitchen employees at Applebee’s often earn starting pay rates between minimum wage and $10 per hour, according to job title and previous experience. Take a look at the Applebee’s kitchen crew member job description .

 Management – Supervisor jobs at Applebee’s include restaurant general manager, assistant manager, kitchen manager, and shift lead jobs. Applebee’s managers hire new employees, schedule workers, train associates, and oversee daily operations. An Applebee’s supervisor may receive a starting salary between $20,000 and $50,000 per year, depending on position, previous management experience, work history, and department of operations. Read the Applebee’s manager job description .

Applebee’s often needs to hire standard restaurant workers, but the company frequently needs to staff further restaurant jobs as well as corporate careers. Some Applebee’s location hire employees to fill Carside To-Go, broiler cook, food expeditor, general utility worker jobs. Applebee’s corporate offices may need to staff customer service associate, administrative assistant, or other professional jobs. Regardless of the work you seek, Applebee’s restaurants and offices may need you to begin work immediately. Apply online with Applebee’s to discover locations hiring workers today.

 Applebee’s Work Benefits 
Applebee’s restaurants offer even a new-hire employee job benefits, like flexible scheduling, paid job training, and industry-competitive pay rates. Eligible Applebee’s workers may enjoy further employee benefits. Qualified workers with Applebee’s restaurant chain may access future planning perks, health and wellness bonuses, and further employment benefits .

Eligible Applebee’s workers receive health and wellness benefits, like healthcare options and various insurance plans. The future planning benefits offered to qualified Applebee’s employees include 401(k) retirement plan access and life insurance options. Additional Applebee’s employment benefits offer eligible associates paid time off and meal discounts. As a franchised business, Applebee’s benefits program may vary drastically between franchises. Apply online to find Applebee’s employee benefits information now.

Read more about Applebee’s benefits .

Applebee’s Application Video: 

 History 
Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar restaurants began with a single location in 1980 in Decatur, GA. Founders Bill and T.J. Palmer sold T.J. Applebee’s Rx for Edibles&amp;Elixirs in 1983. Applebee’s began franchising shortly after the sale and changed names in 1986. Applebee’s opened a series of franchised locations. Between the early-1990s and the mid-2000s, Applebee’s opened roughly 100 new locations every year. Applebee’s operates more than 1,900 locations across the globe.

 Menu 
Applebee’s offers a selection of American fare and a full bar at most locations. Applebee’s menu includes burgers, pasta, seafood, chicken, ribs, steak, sandwiches, soups, and salads. Applebee’s also sells dessert items and specialty coffee drinks. The drink menu at Applebee’s offers beer, wine, margaritas, sangrias, martinis, and other classic cocktails, like the Hurricane, the Mud Slide, and the Bahama Mama. Whatever you crave, Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar menu satisfies.

 Community Involvement 
Applebee’s restaurant chain works with several national and local charitable organizations across the globe. The business supports programs caring for children and improving education. Since 2005, Applebee’s raised over $1 million for the Alex’s Lemonade Stand charity. The company donated $300,000 to Make-A-Wish Foundation and $120,000 to V Foundation for Cancer Research in 2008 alone. Applebee’s strive to give back to the communities supporting the business, and many Applebee’s franchisees work with local charities.

 Environmental 
Applebee’s cares for the environment and works to reduce waste and energy consumption in several ways. Applebee’s recycled over 49 tons of paper products from 2007 to 2010. Applebee’s also pioneers green initiatives across the chain of restaurants. Many Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar locations utilize automatic faucets and low-flow fixtures to reduce water consumption, coordinated heat, ventilation, and air conditioning controls, energy-saving products like reduced usage light fixtures and automatic lights, and solar reflective windows.

 International 
Applebee’s International Inc. operates both U.S. and international Applebee’s franchises. Applebee’s runs a large international business. The restaurant chain maintains hundreds of international locations in countries like Canada, Mexico, Saudi Arabia, Chile, Brazil, Singapore, Qatar, Greece, and the United Arab Emirates. Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar restaurants operate in more than 15 countries outside the U.S..

 Financial 
Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar restaurants operates under Applebee’s International Inc. Applebee’s International exists as a wholly owned subsidiary of DineEquity Inc. DineEquity trades publicly on the NYSE under ticker symbol DIN. In addition to Applebee’s, DineEquity operates IHOP, formally International House of Pancakes, restaurants. DineEquity maintains corporate headquarters in Glendale, CA and employs more than 60,000 workers worldwide. Applebee’s pulls in average yearly revenues near $1 billion and maintains company headquarters in Lenexa, KS.
 19 comments: 
 Michelle: 



 Top Comment 
 
You can work at Applebees at age 16. I know two people aged 16-17 that work at an Applebees and I personally was called in for an interview when I was 16
 

 
 Jennel: 





I love applebees, I am thinking about applying for a job there, but I’m also thiking about applying for outback. does anyone knows which one is better?


 
 Justine: 





I like Applebees a little bit better. But there aren’t any Outbacks where I’m from so I can’t really even apply there too sadly :/


 
 Joe: 





I thought they hired teenagers 16+?? =(


 
 petter: 





I think that depends on the place you live, because I know people that are not 18 yet and the work at Applebees, so it probably depends on the location.


 
 Titus GrahamSr.: 





Cook Job or Line Prep seem like really great jobs. I will apply online tonight!


 
 Tamara: 





I am interested to work for Applebee’s and be a good server. Right now I am trying to get any position that’s open at Applebee’s. I am a good people person.


 
 maryannvargas: 





I would like to work at applebee’s i think it would be great. they got some great food there .


 
 amanda: 





Do you have applications that you can print out?


 
 Yvette Zuniga: 





I want an applebees job and I’m an excellent worker. Do I need past experience?


 
 Jannat Verser: 





I want to do server and cook for applebees. I want this to be my first job ever so I will apply right away.


 
 James Killinger: 





I would like for you all to graduate from high school, so you will know how to write a sentence correctly, then graduate from college or a tech school, so you won’t have to work in restaurants for the rest of your lives, so you can purchase for your children shoes that last longer than the time it takes to get another pair from the Salvation Army. Nothing can stop you, and anyone with bad influence or anyone who gets in the way of you achieving your goals is not your friend. It’s your choice. The brushes are all at your fingertips and the world is your canvas. Paint a good picture!


 
 kamesha neal: 





I love applebees and I would choose applebees any day. And I love the fact that they have 2 for $20.00. I know that I would make a very good waitress for applebees, so now I’m going to apply today and submit my resume….


 
 Na&apos;Tisha Roberts: 





I’m interested in working at Applebee’s as a server. I was trying to find the printable application, so I can return it to Applebee’s. Is it more effective to apply online or turn in a printed application?


 
 Clifford Perry: 





Hey, my name is clifford and I am looking to apply for a job with applebee’s. I have 10 yrs experience in fast food. I have also worked for applebee’s before.


 
 Giomar bynum: 





My name is Giomar and I would like to apply for the hostesses position . My only question is do I need a lot of exspierence for this position?


 
 Teairra: 





I want to apply for a job there. What are your store hours?


 
 Jennifer Owen: 





I am interested in working in Applebee’s I would like to work as a Utility Worker, or a dish washer,


 
 kayy: 





how old do you have to be in order to apply online and work for Applebee’s?


 
 
 Most Popular Jobs Retail Store Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Career Research Employee Benefits 
 En Espanol 
 Interview Tips 
 Interview Questions 
 Job Descriptions 
 Job Finding Tips 
 Salary Info 
 Job Newsletter We&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name: Email: Zip Code: Select Category: Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery 

 Sign Up Job Categories Airline Jobs 
 Amusement Park Jobs 
 Armed Forces Jobs 
 Automotive Store Jobs 
 Banking Jobs 
 Book Store Jobs 
 Casino Jobs 
 Childcare Daycare Jobs 
 Coffee Shop Jobs 
 Computer Store Jobs 
 Cruise Ship Jobs 
 Delivery Driver Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Fashion Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Fitness Health Jobs 
 Furniture Store Jobs 
 Gas Station Jobs 
 Grocery Store Jobs 
 Hardware Store Jobs 
 Healthcare Jobs 
 Home Decor Jobs 
 Hospital Jobs 
 Hotel Jobs 
 Ice Cream Shop Jobs 
 Insurance Jobs 
 Mechanic Jobs 
 Movie Theater Jobs 
 Office Supply Jobs 
 Pet Store Jobs 
 Pharmacy Tech Jobs 
 Pharmacist Jobs 
 Pizza Delivery Jobs 
 Rental Truck Jobs 
 Rental Car Jobs 
 Restaurant Jobs 
 Retail Management Jobs 
 Retail Store Jobs 
 Shoe Store Jobs 
 Smoothie Maker Jobs 
 Specialty Foods Jobs 
 Sporting Goods Jobs 
 Telecommunications Jobs 
 Temp Agency Jobs 
 Tools Jobs 
 Tutoring Jobs 

 All Job Categories 
 
   

 
 Sign up - we&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name:
 Email:
 Zip:
 Select Category:
 Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery Sign Up 
 
 disclaimer 

 privacy policy 

 terms of use 
 
 
Copyright © 2011, 2012 Job-Applications.com
	</body>
</document>
