<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008362" url="http://www.olx.com.pk/restaurant-jobs-food-service-jobs-cat-385" time="2012-07-13-01:50" support="3" score="0.0047794506659382474" bingtitle="Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs Pakistan" webtitle="Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs Pakistan">
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="118"/>
	<description>... SALARY PACKAGE 15000 TO 25000 LIMITED JOBS AND PICK ... now i back ti pakistan and i am experienced in fast food ... jobs cashier; jobs for lahore; hotel jobs; cooks in lahore</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Pakistan 
 
 Search 
 Post a Free Ad  |
English 
Category: Home &gt; Jobs &gt; Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs 
 
Selected Location
 
 Pakistan 
 
Refine your search

 Enter a City Accept 
 
 Category: 
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs   unselect 
 Type: 
 Chef Managers Supervisors Cashiers Delivery Boys Helpers Kitchen Assistants Waiters Bartender Captains Catering Waitress Stewards 
 Ads: 
 With Photos 
 Type: 
 All Wanted Offering 
 Position Type: 
 All Full-time Part-time 
 Location: 
 Karachi Lahore Islamabad Rawalpindi Faisalabad Peshawar Multan Sialkot Hyderabad Abbottabad Gujranwala Sahiwal Sargodha Jhelum Gilgit Gujrat Attock Bahawalpur Kamoke Khanewal Larkana Bagh Bahawalnagar Haripur Mardan Mirpur Okara Sukkur Toba Tek singh 
 
 Results for Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Pakistan 1 - 50 of 1,127 List | Picture Gallery How do I buy a sponsored link? 

 
 anything 
 
Hi this is asif ahmed i have done inter.i need job in showbize or night clubs. any kind of job if u have plz contact 03462227344 asif ahmed from korangi karachi...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
July 10   
 Required a Female Operating Manager 
 
Required a female operating manager for a brand new restaurant near the Port Area Must have some experience in operating a restaurant should be young , good loo...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
July 10   
 staff requierd in restaurant in uk 
 
we need a staff witch chefs helpers manegar acounting staff house keeper store keeper waiterz and labour for hotel salary 1500 pound leave after 6 manth bonus a...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
July 9   
 helper job for kitchen 
 
NEED HELPER WHO HELP IN KITCHEN, PAY BE WILL FINE, INTRESTED PERSON CONTACT ME. IMRAN 03008616997
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Sialkot 
July 8   
 job required For Chef (Cook) 
 
job required For Chef (Cook) All Kind Of Western Food, sweet dishes, Cakes Biscuits Making, 26 years working experience Worked with German Embassy, American Emb...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
July 7   
 Accountant 
 
We seek IT savvy (even) fresh B.Com accountant, residing near Askari X Lahore. Send your cvs at 3bfoods.mexicano@gmail.com
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
July 6   
 pizza and fas food chef 
 
i need a fast food chef for my new take away fast food restaurent
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
July 3   
 Steno, Assistant Library&amp;Draftsman required - School of Army Defence Cantt Karachi 
 
School of Army Defence Cantt Karachi are invited the following staff: Steno, Assistant Library&amp;Draftsman required: Last date : 20-07-2012 Ad provided by: For ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Punjab 
July 2   
 Order Taker 
 
A Young and Professional order taker is required for a fine dinning restaurant. A candidate must previous professional experience in find dinning restaurant.
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
July 2   
 Job - Urgently Required for Saudi Arabia 
 
Urgently Required for Saudi Arabia Tell: 0300-9711284 Ad provided by: For more details about this ad please check this link http://www.papers.com.pk/ad/Job-Urge...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Punjab 
July 2   
 I need job 
 
This is mohsin Raasheed of 21 year old from Islamabad. I need job urgently. qualification Matric Icom Bcom Mcom (under progress ) last year i am decent and well...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
July 1   
 AL-MA`IDAH fast food, continental, chinesc restaurant&amp;out door caters 
 
2: Chef Type: Chinese / fast food, continental male/ female Vacancy for 1 gm, mg male/ female 4 sale&amp;marketing;male / female 6 waiters male / female 4 cooks mal...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 30   
 catering food service manager 
 
I am MBA,I have an experience of catering/food managment /guest management/housekeeping/mess systems.I am also qualified HACCP from TUV (UAE).my last appointmen...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
June 29   
 Manager Assistant 
 
I have (10) years experience for Customer Services, Operations and Administration Department in Renowned Bakers, Fast-food Centers, Pizza’s&amp;Different organiza...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Rawalpindi 
June 29   
 Customer Service Officer 
 
I have (10) years experience for Customer Services, Operations and Administration Department in Renowned Bakers, Fast-food Centers, Pizza’s&amp;Different organiza...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Rawalpindi 
June 29   
 need partner for restuerent 
 
need partner for established resteurent . we need honest and dedicating partner forour restuerent with small investment contact 03222227603
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 29   
 online business 
 
Need someone who has experience of online businss , ecommerce, affiliate marketing, marketing through social media or has some new ideas of online business , wa...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Mithi 
June 28   
 Required cook only for Pakistani dishes 
 
Required Cook for preparation of Pakistani dishes like biryani, nihari, daal, vegetable, curry, shami kabab kofta, etc. preference given to the residence of akh...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 28   
 Restaurant Staff Required 
 
Nawaab Tandoori Restaurant Opening DATE 12 June 2012 Traditional Pakistani Dishes and Introducing Tandoori Meats and Dishes to Pakistan 230 Seating Hall Separa...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 28   
 mr mehtab ali 
 
my name is mehtab and i am expert in cashier , table work , accountant , peti cash, office work , balancing sheet, and i also work in hbl for 33 years ............
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 27   
 U regent required - Jobs In Bharian - 
 
Regards, Ishrat Ali Education International Promoters (Pvt)Ltd. 92-300-2078526 2 M,Block 6, P.E.C.H.S, Near Dahli Sweet. Shahrah-e-Faisal, Karachi. ishratoep@ho...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 26   
 Cook / Handyman wanted 
 
Cook/Kitchen Help required for a new fast food place in F-10, Islamabad Pay 7000 Rupees per month Tips. Timings, 4:30 pm - 1:00 am Contact at 03335344911
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
June 26   
 Looking for a cook! 
 
Looking for a cook who can manage to prepare pakistani and bangladeshi cuisines, for a resturant situated in Ajman, UAE. Salary offered 1100 Dhs. Food and accom...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 25   
 Fast Food Chef Required 
 
Responsible for achieving Company&apos;s objectives with respect to the particular Business unit. Oversee and coordinate planning, organizing and training necessary ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Sahiwal 
June 25   
 NEED A COOK 
 
we need a cook for small bbq point for pizza stuff and biryani person who have experience in this feild plz call us 0347202 7713
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 25   
 jobs in bahrain 
 
Search International karachi pakistn urgantly requaired =For Macdonals restuaent 5 yang boy deuty 9 hours. 4 hours daily over taim - position * crew/rider- Sala...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 25   
 Female Manager 
 
We want female manager for restourant basic salary 35000 to 40000 mail ur cv on hina_khan5019@hotmail.com
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 24   
 cafe 
 
i want to part time job in this plz contact me my mobile 03034045160
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Multan 
June 24   
 Chef wanted Malaysia 
 
I&apos;m looking for 2 professional chefs for malaysia 1 who can make all Pakistani dishes 2nd who can make all BBQ dishes urgent if any 1 interested plx contact me ...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 24   
 Female manager 
 
We want female manager for our restaurant basic salary 35000 to 40000 u can send ur cv on nisha_khan83@yahoo.com
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 24   
 Wanted Production Incharge Food Products 
 
We are a Karachi based company looking for experienced Production Incharge with experience in the manufacture of Food Sauces, Food Pastes, Pickles&amp;Chutneys. S...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 23   
 female staff for a restuarant in malaysia 
 
i need female staff for malaysia its a fully aircondition family restuarant can offer u good salary plus handsome tips should be energetic and confident.plz con...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 23   
 cook or chef 
 
i am looking for a cook/ chef for my home kitchen, reasonable salary along with residence.
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Sargodha 
June 23   
 cleric , cashier, billing dept 
 
my name is sajjad , i am lookng a suitable job in these category. cleric, cashier , billing dept, my age is 40,gender male, qualification b.a with previous expe...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 22   
 CONTINENTAL CHEF 
 
I,m Robert Khokhar lived in lahore pakistan, i,m specialist in continental ,Italian,chinese,indian ,paksitani and fast food ,I Had worked in UAE (Dubai ,Abu dha...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 22   
 Cook / Chef Available in Islamabad for Full or Part time work 
 
Chef / Cook available for full time or partime work in Islamabad Rawalpindi. Hard working, dedicated&amp;honest individuals who are looking to work with sincerity...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
June 22   
 Continental Chef 
 
My name is Robert Khokhar i lived in lahore. I had worked in UAE (Dubai,Abu dhabi) as a head chef In ROYAL MARIDIAN Elite Restaurant . I have 15 years experienc...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 22   
 Customer Sales Mixologist Required 
 
Job Title: Customer Sales Mixologist Job Description: You will be joining our team and our new venture into a new product. We are bringing a world renowned prod...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 22   
 SUPERVISOR 
 
I NEED ANY SUITABLE JOB: I have (10) years experience for Customer Services, Operations and Administration Department in Renowned Bakers, Fast-food Centers, Piz...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Rawalpindi 
June 21   
 MANAGER ASSISTANT 
 
I NEED ANY SUITABLE JOB: I have (10) years experience for Customer Services, Operations and Administration Department in Renowned Bakers, Fast-food Centers, Piz...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Rawalpindi 
June 21   
 Vacancy for experience restaurant staff 
 
Vacancy for 3 waiters 2 cooks 1 lady Receptionist 1 BBQ specialist 1 Tandoor nan/roti specialist
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 21   
 Staff Required for Fast Food Restaurant. 
 
The following positions are available for jobs at a restaurant in Bahria Town, Islamabad. Pizza Chef Helper Waiter Rider For more information, please contact 03...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad 
June 20   
 Chef Required for a Restaurant... 
 
A very good trained chef who is an expert in italian, french, continental and Pakistani cuisines is required for an upscale restaurant in Islamabad. The chef sh...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Islamabad - italian restaurants 
June 19   
 Manager 
 
I NEED ANY SUITABLE JOB: I have done Bachelor of Commerce (B.com)&amp;I am Certified Computer Operator. I have (10) years experience for Customer Services, Operat...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Rawalpindi 
June 18   
 Rider Required 
 
We r going to open a Turkish Food chain in Pakistan with name &quot;CHEZ SULTAN&quot;.We need experienced Riders for delivery.If any one wants to apply contact Azhar Baig...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Lahore 
June 17   
 Required French Fries Chef 
 
Asalamoaliakum.... required a responsible person for saleing french fries... its easy to cock... selery 5000 per month... timing 4pm to 11pm .... Area : north n...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 16   
 Servers, Bar Person&amp;Delivery Boy 
 
A renowned Restaurant at Zamzama Urgently requires Experienced Servers, Bar Person and Deliver Boy. Experience of this market is a must. Market Competitive Pack...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 16   
 Need Rider for delivery base restaurant setup 
 
I Need Rider For Delivery Base Restaurant at karachi administetor society experience minimum 3 years must be obedient&amp;hard working salary plus commission expe...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 16   
 lady staff require for Restaurant 
 
we need 2 girls for our restaurant and must have working experience 2 years in hotel line, its located at Zamzama D.H.A. on urgent basis plz contact me @ 030023...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 16   
 I Need Rider 
 
I Need Rider For Delivery Base Restaurant at karachi administetor society experience minimum 3 years must be obedient&amp;hard working salary plus commission expe...
 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs - Karachi 
June 16   

 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next 
 Create Alert. Get emails for Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Pakistan 
 
 Can&apos;t find what you are looking for? Ask for it! 
 
Popular Searches: Culinary arts jobs 

Popular Searches
 
 Hospitality jobs Restaurant management jobs 

 Restaurant manager Jobs in catering 

 Waiter jobs Culinary arts jobs 
 
Related Ads

 hotel jobs in pakistan lahore jobs in hotel cooking jobs in punjab dairy industries Dairy 

 restaurants jobs in lahore jobs in restaurants in lahore pizza hut peshawar jobs resturents jobs in islamabad leaders inn hotel 

 HOTEL MANAGEMENT JOBS IN RAWALPINDI cook job in lahore hotels jobs LAHORE waiter job objective jobs cashier 

 jobs for lahore hotel jobs cooks in lahore cashier jobs restaurent 
 
Location: Pakistan 

 Free classifieds in Pakistan &gt; Jobs in Pakistan 

 Restaurant Jobs - Food Service Jobs in Pakistan 
 close 
Useful Information

 Help About OLX Terms Of Use Contact OLX 
 
OLX Features

 Sponsored Links How to Partner with OLX Tools&amp;Widgets Post a Free Classified Ad 
 
OLX Close to you

 Browse Cities Sitemap 
 
Stay Connected

 OLX Mobile Facebook 
 Pakistan Free classifieds  -  Copyright © 2006-2012 OLX, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
