<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008422" url="http://www.citizendia.org/KFC" time="2012-07-13-01:53" support="2" score="0.004198517420149896" bingtitle="KFC - Citizendia" webtitle="KFC - Citizendia">
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="001069" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>... the Proper noun World Wide Web) is a collection of Web pages A fast food restaurant ... Knife and Fork, Chopsticks, or other utensils ... single restaurant, offering a single menu ...</description>
	<body>
		Your Ad Here consolidate student loan debt Cheap Tramadol no Prescription A Rumor of War 

 For other uses, see KFC (disambiguation) . 
 KFC Type Wholly owned subsidiary Founded 1952 ( North Corbin, Kentucky ) Founder Harland Sanders Headquarters Louisville, Kentucky Key people Gregg R. North Corbin is a Census-designated place (CDP in Knox and Laurel counties in the U An entrepreneur is a person who has possession over a company enterprise, or Venture, and assumes significant accountability for the inherent risks and the outcome Harland David Sanders, better known as Colonel Sanders ( September 9, 1890–December 16, 1980) was an American entrepreneur Derrick President 
Harvey R. President is a Title leaders of Organizations companies, Trade unions universities, and countries. Brownlea COO 
James O&apos;Reilly VP for Marketing Industry Fast food Products Chicken and related Southern foods Revenue $520. A chief operating officer or chief operations officer ( COO) is a Corporate officer responsible for managing the day-to-day activities of the Corporation __FORCETOC__ For the Vice President of the United States, their roles and other information see Vice President of the United States. In popular usage&amp;quotmarketing;&quot;is the promotion of products especially Advertising and Branding However in professional usage the term has a wider meaning of For other uses of this term see Industry (disambiguation An industry (from Latin industrius,&amp;quotdiligent;industrious&quot; Fast food is the term given to food that can be prepared and served very quickly In Marketing, a product is anything that can be offered to a Market that might satisfy a want or need See also List of foods of the Southern United States The Cuisine of the Southern United States is defined as the regional culinary form of states In business revenue or revenues is Income that a company receives from its normal business activities usually from the sale of goods and services 3 million USD (2007) [1] Employees 24,000 (2007) [1] Parent Yum! Brands Website http://www.kfc.com/ 

 KFC , originally Kentucky Fried Chicken , is a chain of fast food restaurants based in Louisville, Kentucky . The United States dollar ( sign: $; code: USD) is the unit of Currency of the United States; it has also been Employment is a Contract between two parties, one being the employer and the other being the employee. A holding company is a company that owns part all or a majority of other companies&apos; outstanding Stock. Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and A website (alternatively web site or Web site, a back-construction from the Proper noun World Wide Web) is a collection of Web pages A fast food restaurant, sometimes known as a quick service restaurant or QSR, is a specific type of Restaurant characterized both by its Fast food KFC has been a wholly owned subsidiary of Yum! Brands since 2002. Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and 

The company was founded as Kentucky Fried Chicken by Colonel Harland Sanders in 1952. Harland David Sanders, better known as Colonel Sanders ( September 9, 1890–December 16, 1980) was an American entrepreneur The company adopted the abbreviated form of its name in 1991. For the HTML tag see HTML element. An abbreviation (from Latin brevis&amp;quotshort;&quot; [2] Starting in April 2007, the company began using its original appellation of Kentucky Fried Chicken again for its signage, packaging and advertisements in the United States as part of a new corporate re-branding program; [3] [4] newer and remodeled restaurants will have the new logo and name while older stores will continue to use the 1991 signage. The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Additionally, the company continues to use the abbreviation KFC freely in its advertising. Internationally the company is still known as KFC .

KFC primarily sells chicken in form of pieces, wraps , salads and sandwiches . Salad is a mixture of cold foods usually including vegetables and/or fruits often with a dressing occasionally nuts or Croutons, and sometimes with the addition of A sandwich is a food item made of two or more slices of Bread with one or more layers of a filling While its primary focus is fried chicken KFC also offers a line of roasted chicken products, sides and desserts . Fried chicken (also referred to as Southern Fried chicken) is chicken which is dipped in a Breading mixture and then deep fried, pan Dessert is a course that typically comes at the end of a meal usually consisting of sweet Food but sometimes of a strongly-flavored one such as some Cheeses The Outside of North America , KFC offers beef based products such as burgers or kebabs, pork based products such as ribs and other regional fare. The popularity and novelty of KFC has led to the general formula of the fried chicken fast-food restaurant being copied by restaurant owners worldwide.

 
Contents
 
 1 History 2 Products 
 2.1 Packaging 2.2 Menu items 
 2.2.1 Chicken 2.2.2 Other products 2.2.3 Sides 2.2.4 Discontinued products 2.2.5 Nutritional value 
 
 3 Advertising 4 International operations 
 4.1 Global locations 
 5 Criticisms 
 5.1 Environmental concerns 5.2 Trademark disputes 5.3 Wages and working conditions 5.4 Animal rights 5.5 Urban legends 
 6 See also 7 References 8 External links 
 

 

 History 
 The restaurant in North Corbin, KY where Colonel Sanders developed Kentucky Fried Chicken World&apos;s first KFC in South Salt Lake, Utah , since replaced by a new KFC on the same site 
Born and raised in Henryville, Indiana , Sanders passed through several professions in his lifetime. South Salt Lake is a city in Salt Lake County, Utah, United States. Henryville is a Census-designated place (CDP in Clark County, Indiana, United States. [5] Sanders first served his fried chicken in 1930 in the midst of the Great Depression at a gas station he owned in North Corbin, Kentucky . A filling station, fueling station, gas station, service station, petrol station, or gasbar, Retail Outlet North Corbin is a Census-designated place (CDP in Knox and Laurel counties in the U The dining area was named &quot;Sanders Court&amp;Café&quot; and was so successful that in 1936 Kentucky Governor Ruby Laffoon granted Sanders the title of honorary Kentucky Colonel , in recognition of his contribution to the state&apos;s cuisine. Governors Kentucky was initially Kentucky County in Virginia. Ruby Laffoon ( January 15, 1869 March 1, 1941) was the forty-third Governor of Kentucky, serving from 1931 to 1935 Kentucky colonel is an honorary title bestowed upon individuals by approval of the Governor of Kentucky. The following year Sanders expanded his restaurant to 142 seats, and added a motel he bought across the street. Entering dictionaries after World War II, the word motel, a Portmanteau of motor and hotel or motorists&apos; hotel, referred [6] When Sanders prepared his chicken in his original restaurant in North Corbin, he prepared the chicken in an iron skillet, which took about 30 minutes to do, too long for a restaurant operation. In 1939 , Sanders altered the cooking process for his fried chicken to use a pressure fryer , resulting in a greatly reduced cooking time comparable to that of deep frying . Year 1939 ( MCMXXXIX) was a Common year starting on Sunday (link will display the full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. In Cooking, pressure frying is a variation on Pressure cooking where Meat and Cooking oil are brought to high temperatures while pressure is Deep frying is a Cooking method in which food is submerged in hot oil or Fat. [7] In 1940 Sanders devised what came to be known as his Original Recipe. Year 1940 ( MCMXL) was a Leap year starting on Monday (link will display the full 1940 calendar of the Gregorian calendar. [8] 

The Sanders Court&amp;Café generally served travelers, often those headed to Florida , so when the route planned in the 1950s for what would become Interstate 75 bypassed Corbin , he sold his properties and traveled the U. Florida ( is a state located in the southeastern region of the United States, bordering Alabama to the northwest and Georgia to the Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. Corbin is a City in Whitley and Knox counties in the southeastern portion of the U S. to sell his chicken to restaurant owners. Sanders entered into franchise agreements paying him five cents for each piece of chicken sold. In many national currencies, the cent is a monetary unit that equals 1/100 of the basic monetary unit The first to take him up on the offer was Pete Harman in South Salt Lake, Utah ; together, they opened the first &quot;Kentucky Fried Chicken&quot; outlet in 1952. Leon W or&amp;quotPete;&quot;Harman (born 1919 is best known for having struck a deal with Colonel Harland Sanders to open the first KFC franchise South Salt Lake is a city in Salt Lake County, Utah, United States. [9] By the early 1960s Kentucky Fried Chicken was sold in over 600 franchised outlets in both the United States and Canada. One of the longest-lived franchisees of the older Col. Sanders&apos; chicken concept, as opposed to the KFC chain, was the Kenny Kings chain. The company owned many Northern Ohio diner-style restaurants, the last of which closed in 2004 . &amp;quotMMIV;&quot;redirects here For the Modest Mouse album see&quot;Baron von Bullshit Rides Again&quot; Sanders sold the entire KFC franchising operation in 1964 for $2 million USD [10] Since that time, the chain has been sold three more times, most recently to PepsiCo , which made it part of its Tricon Global Restaurants division, which in turn was spun off in 1997 , and has now been renamed to Yum! Brands . Franchising refers to the methods of practicing and using another person&apos;s Philosophy of business. The United States dollar ( sign: $; code: USD) is the unit of Currency of the United States; it has also been PepsiCo Incorporated (Short for Pepsi Company ( is a large conglomerate with interests in manufacturing marketing and selling a wide variety of carbonated and non- carbonated Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and Year 1997 ( MCMXCVII) was a Common year starting on Wednesday (link will display full 1997 Gregorian calendar Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and Additionally, Colonel Sanders&apos; nephew, Lee Cummings, took his own Kentucky Fried Chicken franchises (and a chicken recipe of his own) and converted them to his own &quot;spin-off&quot; restaurant chain , Lee&apos;s Famous Recipe Chicken . Chain stores are Retail outlets that share a Brand and central management and usually have standardized business methods and practices Lee&apos;s Famous Recipe Chicken is a Fast food Restaurant in the Southern and Midwestern United States which specializes in Fried 

Today, some of the older KFC restaurants have become famous in their own right. One such restaurant is located in Marietta, Georgia . Marietta is a City located in central Cobb County Georgia, and is its County seat. This store is notable for a 56-foot (17 m) tall sign that looks like a chicken. The sign, known locally as the Big Chicken , was built for an earlier fast-food restaurant on the site called Johnny Reb&apos;s Chick, Chuck and Shake. The Big Chicken is a KFC restaurant in Marietta Georgia, which features a large steel-sided structure designed in the appearance of a chicken rising up from the top It is often used as a travel reference point in the Atlanta area by locals and pilots. [11] 

 

 Products 

 

 Packaging 

The famous paper bucket that KFC uses for its larger sized orders of chicken and has come to signify the company was originally created by Wendy&apos;s restaurants founder Dave Thomas . Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. David&amp;quotDave;&quot;Thomas ( July 2, 1932 January 8, 2002) was an American restaurateur and Philanthropist. Thomas was originally a franchisee of the original Kentucky Fried Chicken and operated several outlets in the Columbus, Ohio area. Columbus is the Capital and the largest city of the US state of Ohio. His reasoning behind using the paper packaging was that it helped keep the chicken crispy by wicking away excess moisture. The rotating bucket sign was designed by Leonard Goldstein to advertise the availability of Kentucky Fried Chicken at his Lendy&apos;s Restaurants in Roanoke and Salem, VA. Lendy&apos;s was a restaurant chain that was opened in Salem Virginia on November 2 1955 by Leonard Goldstein. The signs first appeared in 1961, a year before Dave Thomas took over 4 Kentucky Fried Chicken stores in Columbus, OH.

 

 Menu items 

 

 Chicken 
 KFC&apos;s Original Recipe fried chicken and French fries 
 KFC&apos;s specialty is fried chicken served in various forms. KFC&apos;s primary product is pressure-fried pieces of chicken made with one of two types of breading: original recipe or extra crispy . KFC has two lines of sandwiches: its &quot;regular&quot; chicken sandwiches and its Snackers line. The regular sandwiches are served on either a sesame seed or corn dusted roll and are made from either whole breast fillets (fried or roasted), chopped chicken in a sauce or fried chicken strips. Sesame ( Sesamum indicum) is a Flowering plant in the genus Sesamum. Maize (ˈmeɪz ( Zea mays L. ssp mays) known as corn in some countries is a cereal grain domesticated in Mesoamerica The Snackers line are value priced items that consist of chicken strips and various toppings. In the UK the main sandwiches are chicken fillet burger (a chicken breast fillet coated in an original-recipe coating with salad garnish and mayonnaise) and a Zinger Burger (as with the former but with a spicier coating and salsa). The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom, the UK or Britain,is a Sovereign state located Both of these are available as &quot;tower&quot; variants, which include a slice of cheese and a hash brown. A variety of smaller finger food products are available at KFC including chicken strips, wings, nuggets and popcorn chicken. Finger food is Food eaten with the Hands in contrast to food eaten with a Knife and Fork, Chopsticks, or other utensils These products can be ordered plain or with various sauces, including several types of barbecue sauces and buffalo sauce . Barbecue sauce (also abbreviated BBQ sauce) is a Liquid flavoring Sauce or Condiment ranging from watery to quite thick consistency Buffalo wings, chicken wings, hot wings or wings are Chicken wing sections (called Wings or&amp;quotflats;&quot;and drummettes Several pies have been made available from KFC. The Pot Pie is a savory pie made with chicken, gravy and vegetables. A pot pie is a type of baked savory Pie with a bottom and top completely encased by flakey crusts and baked inside a pie tin to support its shape In the second quarter of 2006, KFC introduced its variation on Shepherd&apos;s pie called the Famous Bowl . Cottage pie is a traditional English dish made with minced meat covered with a Mashed potato crust Served in a plastic bowl, it is layered with mashed potatoes or rice, gravy, corn, popcorn chicken, and cheese. The bowl had been available at KFC&apos;s special test market store in Louisville since the third quarter of 2005. A test market, in the field of business and marketing is a geographic region or Demographic group used to gauge the viability of a product or service in the Mass market The KFC Twister is a wrap that consists of either chicken strips or roasted chicken, tomato, lettuce and (pepper) mayonnaise wrapped in a tortilla . In Mexico, Central America, the Caribbean, the United States, and Canada, a tortilla is a type of thin unleavened Shish kebab - in several markets KFC sells kebabs. Kebab (also transliterated as kabab, kabob, kibob, kebhav, kephav) refers to a variety of meat dishes in Middle Eastern 

 

 Other products 
 Coleslaw 
 In some international locations, KFC may sell hamburgers , pork ribs or fish. A hamburger (or burger) is a Sandwich consisting of a cooked ground Meat Patty, usually Beef, placed in a sliced bun or between Pork ribs are a type of Food dish popular in North America and Asian cuisine In the U. S. , KFC began offering the Fish Snacker sandwich during Lent in 2006. Lent, in some Christian denominations, is the forty-day-long liturgical season of fasting and prayer before Easter. The Fish Snacker consists of a rectangular patty of Alaskan Pollock on a small bun, and is the fifth KFC menu item in the Snacker category. Pollock (or pollack, pronounced the same and listed first in most UK and US dictionaries is the common name used for either of the two Species of marine [12] Three types of salads (which can be topped with roasted or fried chicken) are available at KFC: Caesar, house, and BLT salads (in the US). Zinger Burger - A regular sized burger which regularly consists of a boneless fillet of hot and spicy chicken, lettuce and mayonnaise in a burger bun. Cheese, tomato, bacon and pineapple can be added upon request. Barbecue sauce can also replace/join the mayonnaise. Parfait deserts - &quot;Little Bucket Parfaits&quot; in varieties such as Fudge Brownie, Chocolate Crème (once called the Colonel&apos;s Little Fudge Bucket), Lemon Crème and Strawberry Shortcake are available at most locations in the US. [13] Sara Lee Desserts - Available in either Cookies and Cream Cheesecake or Choc Caramel Mousse. &quot;Variety Bucket&quot;: This has chicken, popcorn chicken, two sides, biscuit. 

 

 Sides 

 Other than fried chicken, many KFC restaurants serve side dishes like coleslaw , various potato -based items (including potato wedges, french fries and mashed potatoes with gravy ), biscuits , baked beans , macaroni and cheese , rice , steamed vegetables and corn on the cob . A side dish, sometimes referred to as a side order or simply a side, is a food item that accompanies the Entrée or Main course at a Meal Coleslaw (or cole slaw) is a Salad consisting primarily of shredded raw Cabbage. The potato is a Starchy Tuberous crop Vegetable from the perennial Solanum tuberosum of the Solanaceae French fries ( North American English; sometimes not capitalized chips ( British English) fries or French-fried potatoes (formal Mashed Potato or mashed potatoes is a common way of serving Potato in many countries worldwide Gravy is an English Sauce made often from the juices that run naturally from meat or vegetables during cooking A biscuit (ˈbɪskɨt is a small baked product the exact meaning varies markedly in different parts of the world Baked beans is a dish consisting of Beans baked (or despite the name usually stewed) in a Sauce. Macaroni and cheese (sometimes referred to as macaroni cheese or mac &apos;n&apos; cheese in parts of the United States and Rice is a Cereal foodstuff which forms an important part of the diet of many people worldwide and as such it is a staple food for many Corn on the cob (known regionally as&amp;quotpole;corn&quot;&amp;quotcornstick;&quot;&amp;quotsweet;pole&quot;and&amp;quotlong;maize&quot;is the Culinary term for a 

 

 Discontinued products 

 The Colonel&apos;s Rotisserie Gold - This product was introduced in the 1990s as a response to the Boston Market chain&apos;s roasted chicken products, and a healthier mindset of the general public avoiding fried food. Boston Market (known before 1995 as Boston Chicken) headquartered in Golden Colorado, is a chain of American Fast casual restaurants Purportedly made from a &quot;lost&quot; Col. Sanders recipe, it was sold as a whole roaster or a half bird. [14] Tender Roast Chicken - This product was an off-shoot of &apos;The Colonel&apos;s Rotisserie Gold&apos;. Instead of whole and half birds, customers were given quarter roasted chicken pieces. For a time, customers could request chicken &quot;original&quot;, &quot;Extra Tasty Crispy&quot;, or &quot;Tender Roast&quot;. Chicken Little sandwich - a value oriented sandwich that sold for $0. 39( USD ) [15] in the U. The United States dollar ( sign: $; code: USD) is the unit of Currency of the United States; it has also been S. during the late 1980s and early 1990s. It was a small chicken patty with mayonnaise on a small roll, similar to White Castle &apos;s mini chicken sandwich. White Castle is the oldest American Hamburger fast food restaurant chain [16] Extra Tasty Crispy (ETC) - Chicken much like the Extra Crispy served today, except ETC was prepared using chicken that had been soaking for at least a day in special marinade. There is some speculation that the marinade may have been made with trans-fats, and KFC boasts to no longer use trans-fats in their chicken. In the summer of 2007, KFC started marketing the chicken just as &quot;Extra Crispy&quot; without the marinade. Kentucky Nuggets were a chicken nugget product available at KFC until 1996. No reason has been given for their discontinuation. Fillers - A promotional item for a Cricket team, the filler was a nine inch (22cm) sub available in four different varieties from November 2007-Mid January 2008, only in Australia. Cricket is a bat-and-ball team Sport that originated in England and is now played in more than 100 countries 

 

 Nutritional value 

KFC formerly used partially hydrogenated oil in its fried foods. This oil contains relatively high levels of trans fat , which increases the risk of heart disease . Trans fat is the common name for a type of Unsaturated fat with trans - isomer Fatty acid (s Heart disease is an Umbrella term for a variety for different diseases affecting the Heart. The Center for Science in the Public Interest (CSPI) filed a court case against KFC, with the aim of making it use other types of oils or make sure customers know about trans fat content immediately before they buy food. The Center for Science in the Public Interest ( CSPI) is a non-profit watchdog and Consumer advocacy group headquartered in Washington D 

In October 2006, KFC announced that it would begin frying its chicken in trans fat-free oil. This would also apply to their potato wedges and other fried foods, however, the biscuits, macaroni and cheese , and mashed potatoes would still contain trans fat. Macaroni and cheese (sometimes referred to as macaroni cheese or mac &apos;n&apos; cheese in parts of the United States and Trans fat-free soybean oil was introduced in all KFC restaurants in the U. S. by 30 April 2007 . Events 313 - Roman emperor Licinius unifies the entire Eastern Roman Empire under his rule Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. CSPI announced that it would immediately drop its lawsuit against KFC and was hopeful that this would create a ripple effect on other restaurants or fast food chains that prepare food rich in trans fat. The ripple effect is an education-related term associated with the studies of Jacob Kounin. &quot;If KFC, which deep-fries almost everything, can get the artificial trans fat out of its frying oil, anyone can,&quot; CSPI Executive Director Michael Jacobson said in a statement. An executive director is the senior manager or Executive officer of an Organization, company, or Corporation. Michael F Jacobson, who holds a PhD in microbiology co-founded the Center for Science in the Public Interest in 1971 along with two fellow scientists he met while [17] 

 

 Advertising 
 KFC&apos;s logo from 1997 until November 2006 
Early television advertisements for KFC regularly featured Colonel Sanders licking his fingers and talking to the viewer about his secret recipe and the importance of a family joining one another for a meal. A television advertisement or television commercial (often just commercial or advert (US or ad (UK is a span of television programming produced Despite his death in 1980, this angle was quite common through the 1980s and up until the early-mid 1990s.

Throughout the mid 1980s, KFC called on Will Vinton Studios to produce a series of humorous, claymation ads. Will Vinton (born 1948 is an American director and producer of animated films Clay animation is one of many forms of Stop motion animation Each animated piece either character or background is&amp;quotdeformable;&quot;&amp;mdashmade;of a malleable substance These most often featured a cartoon-like chicken illustrating the poor food quality of competing food chains, mentioning prolonged freezing and other negative aspects. Food quality is the quality characteristics of food that is acceptable to consumers [18] TV ads also featured Foghorn Leghorn advising Henery Hawk to visit the restaurant for better chicken. Henery Hawk (sometimes misspelled Henry) is a cartoon character from the American Looney Tunes series who appeared in twelve cartoons 

In the 80s, KFC was an associate sponsor for Junior Johnson &apos;s NASCAR Winston Cup Series cars, with such drivers as Darrell Waltrip , Neil Bonnett , and Terry Labonte . Robert Glen Johnson Jr (born June 28, 1931 in Wilkes County North Carolina) known as Junior Johnson, was a Moonshiner in the The National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing ( NASCAR) is the largest sanctioning body of Stock cars in the United States. Darrell Lee Waltrip (born February 5, 1947 in Owensboro Kentucky) is a three-time former NASCAR Winston Cup champion the 1989 Daytona Lawrence Neil Bonnett ( July 30, 1946 - February 11, 1994) was a NASCAR driver who compiled 18 victories and 20 poles over Terrance Lee Labonte (born November 16, 1956, in Corpus Christi Texas) is a NASCAR driver who now races part-time in the Sprint Cup Series 

In 1997 KFC briefly re-entered the NASCAR Winston Cup Series as sponsor of the #26 Darrell Waltrip Motorsports Chevrolet with driver Rich Bickle at the Brickyard 400 . Darrell Waltrip Motorsports was a NASCAR team owned by three-time Winston Cup champion Darrell Waltrip. Chevrolet (ˌʃɛvroʊˈleɪ - French origin (also known as Chevy) is a Brand of Automobile, produced by General Motors (GM Rich Bickle Jr (born May 13, 1961 in Edgerton Wisconsin) is a journeyman NASCAR driver The Allstate 400 at The Brickyard, introduced as the Brickyard 400 in 1994, is an annual 400-mile (644&amp;nbspkm;NASCAR Sprint Cup points race 
 A co-branded Long John Silvers and KFC 
By the late 1990s, the stylized likeness of Colonel Sanders as the KFC logo had been modified. Long John Silver&apos;s Inc is a United States -based Fast-food restaurant that specializes in Seafood and Fish and chips. KFC ads began featuring an animated version of &quot;the Colonel&quot; with a lively and enthusiastic attitude. The bouncing ball animation (below consists of these 6 frames He would often start out saying &quot;The Colonel here!&quot; and moved across the screen with a cane in hand. The Colonel was often shown dancing, singing, and knocking on the TV screen as he spoke to the viewer about the product. In reference to these ads, William Shatner shouted &quot;The Colonel is breakdancing ! Give me a break!&quot; in the song &quot; I Can&apos;t Get Behind That &quot; [19] 

KFC claims that its 87500 sq. William Alan Shatner (born March 22, 1931) is a Canadian double Emmy - Golden Globe - and Saturn Award -winning Breakdance, breaking, b-boying or b-girling is a Street dance style that evolved as part of the hip hop movement among Has Been (2004 is William Shatner &apos;s second musical album after 1968&apos;s The Transformed Man. ft. Logo created in the Nevada desert is the first to be visible from outer space.

The animated Colonel is uncommon today. Still using a humorous slant, the current KFC campaign revolves mostly around customers enjoying the food. It also features a modified version of Lynyrd Skynyrd &apos;s &quot; Sweet Home Alabama &quot; as the theme song for practically all its commercials, though the restaurant hails from Kentucky. Lynyrd Skynyrd (ˌlɛnɚdˈskɪnɝd is an American Southern rock band &quot;Sweet Home Alabama&quot;is a song by Southern rock band Lynyrd Skynyrd that first appeared in 1974 on their second album Second Helping The phrase theme music usually refers to that of a radio program, Television program, or Movie. 

In 2006 , KFC claimed to have made the first logo visible from outer space , though Readymix has had one since 1965. Year 2006 ( MMVI) was a Common year starting on Sunday of the Gregorian calendar. Outer space, often simply called space, comprises the relatively empty regions of the Universe outside the escape velocities of Celestial bodies. The Rinker Group is an Australian headquartered multinational building products company [20] [21] KFC says &quot;[It] marked the official debut of a massive global re-image campaign that will contemporize 14,000-plus KFC restaurants in over 80 countries over the next few years. &quot; The logo was built from 65,000 one-foot-square tiles, and it took six days on site to construct in early November. The logo measured a record-breaking 87,500 square feet (8,130 m²), and was placed in the Mojave Desert near Rachel, Nevada . For the indigenous American tribe see Mohave. The Mojave Desert (moʊˈhɑːvi or /məˈhɑːvi/ ( Hayikwiir Mat&apos;aar in Mojave [22] 

Many KFC locations are co-located with one or more of Yum! Brands restaurants, Long John Silvers , Taco Bell , Pizza Hut , or A&amp;W Restaurants . For the business term see Colocation (business. For collocation methods for the solution of differential equations see Collocation method. Long John Silver&apos;s Inc is a United States -based Fast-food restaurant that specializes in Seafood and Fish and chips. Taco Bell Corp, a subsidiary of Yum! Brands Inc, is a restaurant chain based in Irvine California specializing in Tex-Mex -inspired A&amp;W;Restaurants Inc is a chain of Fast-food restaurants, distinguished by its draft Root beer and Root beer floats. Many of these locations behave like a single restaurant, offering a single menu with food items from both restaurants. [23] 

One of KFC&apos;s latest advertisements is a commercial advertising its &quot;wicked crunch box meal&quot;. The commercial features a fictional black metal band called &quot;Hellvetica&quot; performing live, the lead singer then swallows fire. Black metal is an extreme subgenre of heavy metal. It often employs fast tempos shrieked vocals highly distorted guitars played with Tremolo picking, The commercial then shows the lead singer at a KFC eating the &quot;wicked crunch box meal&quot; and saying &quot;Oh man that is hot&quot;.

 

 International operations 
 Examples of Kentucky Fried Chicken&apos;s international operations 

 (Listed alphabetically by county) 

 Keihan Moriguchi City station,
 Osaka, Japan Kuwait City ,
 Kuwait Bangkok, Thailand Singapore 

 Countries with KFC restaurants: Countries with KFC restaurants
 Key :
Blue: Countries currently with KFC restaurants 

 

 Global locations 

 
   Andorra   Antigua and Barbuda   Australia   Austria   Bahamas   Bahrain   Bangladesh   Barbados   Botswana   Brazil   Bulgaria   Cambodia   Canada   Chile   People&apos;s Republic of China 
   Hong Kong   Macau 
   Colombia   Costa Rica   Curaçao   Cyprus   Czech Republic   Denmark   Dominica   Dominican Republic   Ecuador 
 
   El Salvador   Egypt   Fiji   France   Germany   Greece   Grenada   Guyana   Honduras   Hungary   Iceland   India   Indonesia   Ireland   Israel   Italy   Jamaica   Japan   Jordan   Kuwait   Lebanon   Lithuania   Malaysia   Malta   Mauritius 
 
   Mexico   Morocco   Namibia   Netherlands 
   Aruba   Netherlands Antilles 
   Curaçao   Sint Maarten 
 
   New Zealand   Nicaragua   Oman   Pakistan   Panama   Peru   Philippines   Poland   Portugal   Qatar   Romania   Russia   Saint Lucia   Saint Vincent and the Grenadines   Saudi Arabia   Serbia (No data on Kosovo or Montenegro ) 
 
   Singapore   Suriname   Slovakia   South Africa   South Korea   Spain   Sri Lanka   Syria   Republic of China   Thailand   Trinidad and Tobago   Turkey   United Arab Emirates   United Kingdom 
   Bermuda   Cayman Islands 
   United States 
   Guam   Puerto Rico   United States Virgin Islands 
   Venezuela   Vietnam   Yemen   Zimbabwe 
 

 Canada 

In Quebec , KFC was officially renamed as PFK ( Poulet Frit Kentucky ) in the late 1970s after the Parti Québécois was elected to power. is a city in Japan, located at the mouth of the Yodo River on Osaka Bay, in the Kansai region of the main island of Honshū Kuwait City ( Arabic: مدينة الكويت Transliteration: Madīnat al-Kūwait) is the Capital and largest The State of Kuwait ( دولة الكويت IPA [dawlatt̪ alkuwajt̪]) is a sovereign Arab Emirate on the coast of the Persian Gulf, enclosed Bangkok, known in Thai as Krung Thep Maha Nakhon (krūŋtʰêːp máhǎːnákʰɔn) or Krung Thep ( for short is the Capital, largest Singapore Andorra, officially the Principality of Andorra ( Catalan: Principat d&apos;Andorra) is a small Landlocked country in western Antigua and Barbuda ( Spanish for&amp;quotAncient;&quot;and&amp;quotBearded;&quot;is an Island nation located on the eastern boundary of the Caribbean Sea For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Australia topics. Austria (Österreich ( officially the Republic of Austria (Republik Österreich The Bahamas, officially the Commonwealth of The Bahamas, is an independent sovereign English -speaking country consisting of two thousand Cays and The Kingdom of Bahrain (in مملكة البحرين,, literally Kingdom of the Two Seas) is an Island country in the Persian Gulf ( Bengali: বাংলাদেশ inc-Latn Bangladesh) officially Barbados ( Portuguese word for bearded-ones, bɑrˈbeɪdoʊz -dɒs situated just east of the Caribbean Sea, is an independent Island nation The Republic of Botswana (Lefatshe la Botswana is a Landlocked nation in Southern Africa. |utc_offset = -2 to -4 |time_zone_DST = BRST |utc_offset_DST = -2 to -5 |cctld The state of Bulgaria (България transliterated bg-Latn &apos;&apos;Balgaria&apos;&apos; The country preserves the traditions (in ethnic name language and alphabet of the First Bulgarian The Kingdom of Cambodia ( formerly known as Kampuchea (, transliterated: Preăh Réachéanachâkr Kâmpŭchea) is a country in South East Country to&amp;quotDominion;of Canada&quot;or&amp;quotCanadian;Federation&quot;or anything else please read the Talk Page Chile, officially the Republic of Chile ( Spanish:) is a country in South America occupying a long and narrow Coastal strip wedged between the Talk People&apos;s Republic of China) PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF CHINA ARTICLE GUIDELINES Hong Kong ( officially the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, is a territory located on China &apos;s south coast on the Pearl River Delta, and borders For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Macau topics. Colombia (kəˈlʌmbɪə officially the Republic of Colombia () is a country in northwestern South America. Costa Rica, officially the Republic of Costa Rica ( Spanish: Costa Rica or República de Costa Rica,) is a Country in Curaçao (ˈkjuːrəsaʊ in English Dutch: Curaçao, Papiamento: Kòrsou) is an Island in the southern Caribbean Sea, Cyprus (Κύπρος transliterated: Kýpros,; Kıbrıs officially the Republic of Cyprus (Κυπριακή Δημοκρατία Kypriakī́ Dīmokratía The Czech Republic ( ˈt͡ʃɛskaː ˈrɛpuˌblɪka short form in Česko ˈt͡ʃɛskɔ also called Czechia, The Kingdom of Denmark ( ˈd̥ænmɑɡ̊ (archaic ˈd̥anmɑːɡ̊ commonly known as Denmark, is a country in the Scandinavian region of northern Europe The Commonwealth of Dominica, commonly known as Dominica, is an Island nation in the Caribbean Sea. The Dominican Republic ( Spanish: República Dominicana;) is a nation located in the Caribbean region and shares the island of Hispaniola with For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Ecuador topics. El Salvador ( República de El Salvador,) is a country in Central America. This article is about the country of Egypt For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Egypt topics. Fiji (Matanitu ko Viti फ़िजी officially the Republic of the Fiji Islands (Matanitu Tu-Vaka-i-koya ko Viti फ़िजी द्वीप समूह गणराज्य This article is about the country For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic France topics. Germany, officially the Federal Republic of Germany ( ˈbʊndəsʁepuˌbliːk ˈdɔʏtʃlant is a Country in Central Europe. Greece (Ελλάδα transliterated: Elláda, historically, Ellás,) officially the Hellenic Republic (Ελληνική Δημοκρατία Grenada (grɪˈneɪdə is an Island nation that includes the southern Grenadines in the southeastern Caribbean Sea. Guyana (ɡaɪˈænə or /ɡiːˈɑːnə/ officially the Co-operative Republic of Guyana and previously known as British Guiana, is the only Nation state Honduras in Spanish, República de Honduras) is a democratic republic in Central America. Hungary (Magyarország &apos;mɔɟɔrorsaːg) officially in English the Republic of Hungary ( Magyar Köztársaság, literally Magyar (Hungarian Republic Iceland, officially the Republic of Iceland ( ( Ísland or Lýðveldið Ísland ( India, officially the Republic of India (भारत गणराज्य inc-Latn Bhārat Gaṇarājya; see also other Indian languages) is a country The Republic of Indonesia ( (Republik Indonesia is a Country in Southeast Asia. Ireland ( Irish: Éire, ˈeːrʲə is a country in north-western Europe. For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Israel topics. Italy (Italia officially the Italian Republic, (Repubblica Italiana is located on the Italian Peninsula in Southern Europe, and on the two largest Jamaica (ˈdʒəˈmeɪkə} is an Island nation of the Greater Antilles, in length and as much as in width situated in the Caribbean Sea. For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Japan topics. Jordan, officially the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan (الأردنّ al-Urdunn) is an Arab country in Southwest Asia spanning the southern The State of Kuwait ( دولة الكويت IPA [dawlatt̪ alkuwajt̪]) is a sovereign Arab Emirate on the coast of the Persian Gulf, enclosed Lebanon (ˈlɛbənɒn Arabic: ar لبنان Lubnān) officially the Republic of Lebanon or Lebanese Republic (ar الجمهورية اللبنانية Lithuania, officially the Republic of Lithuania (Lietuvos Respublika is a Country in Eastern often referred to as Northern Europe or in the For the biogeographical region see Malesia Malaysia (məˈleɪʒə or /məˈleɪziə/ is a country that consists of thirteen states and Malta, officially the Republic of Malta (Repubblika ta&apos; Malta is a European Microstate, comprising an Archipelago of three islands Mauritius (pronounced məˈrɪʃəs L’île Maurice /il mɔ&apos;ʁis/ Mauritian Creole: Maurice) officially the Republic of Mauritius, République The United Mexican States ( or commonly Mexico (ˈmɛksɪkoʊ () is a federal constitutional Republic in North America. Morocco (المغرب&amp;quotal-Maghrib;&quot;officially the Kingdom of Morocco (المملكة المغربية is a country located in North Africa Namibia, officially the Republic of Namibia, is a country in Southern Africa on the Atlantic coast The Netherlands ( Dutch:, ˈnedərlɑnt is the European part of the Kingdom of the Netherlands, which consists of the Netherlands the Netherlands Aruba is a -long island of the Lesser Antilles in the southern Caribbean Sea, north of the Paraguaná Peninsula, Falcón State, Venezuela The Netherlands Antilles ( Dutch:) previously known as the Netherlands West Indies or Dutch Antilles/West Indies, is part of the Lesser Antilles Curaçao (ˈkjuːrəsaʊ in English Dutch: Curaçao, Papiamento: Kòrsou) is an Island in the southern Caribbean Sea, For the island of St Martin on the whole see Saint Martin, for the French side see Saint Martin (France and for other uses see Saint Martin (disambiguation New Zealand is an Island country in the south-western Pacific Ocean comprising two main landmasses (the North Island and the South Island Nicaragua (ˌnɪkəˈrɑgwə officially the Republic of Nicaragua () is a representative democratic republic and the largest nation in Central America Oman, officially the Sultanate of Oman ( Arabic: سلطنة عُمان) is an Arab Country in Southwest Asia on the southeast Pakistan () officially the Islamic Republic of Pakistan, is a country located in South Asia, Southwest Asia, Middle East and Panama, officially the Republic of Panama (República de Panamá) is the southernmost country of Central America. Peru (Perú Piruw Piruw officially the Republic of Peru ( reˈpuβlika del peˈɾu is a country in western South America. The Philippines ( Filipino: Pilipinas, officially known as the Republic of the Philippines (fil &apos;&apos;Republika ng Pilipinas&apos;&apos; RP Poland (Polska officially the Republic of Poland Portugal, officially the Portuguese Republic (República Portuguesa is a country on the Iberian Peninsula. Qatar ( قطر; ˈqɑtˁɑr local pronunciation giṭar officially the State of Qatar (Arabic دولة قطر transliterated Romania ( dated: Rumania, Roumania Russia (Россия Rossiya) or the Russian Federation ( Rossiyskaya Federatsiya) is a transcontinental Country extending Saint Lucia (ˌseɪnt ˈluːʃɪə is an Island nation in the eastern Caribbean Sea on the boundary with the Atlantic Ocean. Saint Vincent and the Grenadines is an island nation in the Lesser Antilles chain of the Caribbean Sea. The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, KSA ( المملكة العربية السعودية, al-Mamlaka al-ʻArabiyya as-Suʻūdiyya) or Suudi Serbia (Србија Srbija) officially the Republic of Serbia (Република Србија Republika Srbija) is a Landlocked Country Montenegro ( British English) Montenegrin / Serbian: PLEASE DO NOT CHANGE THE LANGUAGES WITHOUT CONSENSUS ON THE TALK PAGE! Singapore Suriname ( Dutch: Suriname; Sranan Tongo: Sranan) officially the Republic of Suriname (traditionally spelled Surinam by Slovakia (long form Slovak Republic; Slovak:, long form, is a Landlocked country in Central Europe with a population of over five million The Republic of South Africa (also known by other official names) is a country located at the southern tip of the continent of Africa South Korea, officially the Republic of Korea and often referred to as Korea ( Korean: 대한민국 tɛː Spain () or the Kingdom of Spain (Reino de España is a country located mostly in southwestern Europe on the Iberian Peninsula. Sri Lanka, officially the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka ( Sinhalese:, இலங்கை known as Ceylon before 1972 is an Island Syria ( سوريّة or) officially the Syrian Arab Republic (Arabic ar الجمهورية العربية السورية REPUBLIC OF CHINA ARTICLE GUIDELINES The Kingdom of Thailand (ˈtaɪlænd ราชอาณาจักรไทย, râːtɕʰa-ʔaːnaːtɕɑ̀k-tʰɑj The Republic of Trinidad and Tobago (ˈtrɪnɪdæd ən təˈbeɪgoʊ is an archipelagic state in the southern Caribbean, lying northeast of the South American Turkey (Türkiye known officially as the Republic of Turkey ( is a Eurasian Country that stretches The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom, the UK or Britain,is a Sovereign state located Ba (officially The Bermuda Islands or The Somers Isles) is a British overseas territory in the North Atlantic Ocean. The Cayman Islands are a British overseas territory located in the western Caribbean Sea, comprising the islands of Grand Cayman, Cayman Brac The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Guam ( Chamorro: cha Guåhån) officially the Territory of Guam, is an island in the western Pacific Ocean and is an organized unincorporated Puerto Rico (ˌpwertoˈriko officially the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico (&amp;quotEstado;Libre Asociado de Puerto Rico&quot;{{lang-en|&amp;quotAssociated;Free State of Puerto Rico&quot;}} The United States Virgin Islands is a group of Islands in the Caribbean that are an Insular area of the United States. Venezuela (ˌvɛnəˈzweɪlə) officially the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela (Spanish República Bolivariana de Venezuela) is a country on the Vietnam (ˌviːɛtˈnɑːm Việt Nam) officially Yemen ( Arabic: اليَمَن al-Yaman officially the Republic of Yemen ( Arabic: الجمهورية اليمنية al-Jumhuuriyya See also Great Zimbabwe National Monument. For information about the March and June 2008 presidential elections see Zimbabwean presidential election Quebec (kwɨˈbɛk The Parti Québécois &apos; is a Sovereignist Political party that advocates national sovereignty for the Canadian province of Quebec and This was due to the province&apos;s language laws on commercial signs, and part of law prohibiting the specific use of only English. The Charter of the French Language ( La charte de la langue française, in French) also known as Bill 101 and Loi 101, In the early 1990s, these regulations were relaxed to allow national chains to use their familiar name in Quebec, but KFC/PFK continues to be one of the few non-Quebec companies to use a French name in the province.

 China 

KFC is known as 肯德基炸鸡 ( pinyin : Kěn Dé Jī Zhà Jī) in China . Pinyin, more formally Hanyu pinyin, is the most common Standard Mandarin Romanization system in use China ( Wade-Giles ( Mandarin) Chung¹kuo² is a cultural region, an ancient Civilization, and depending on perspective a National 

In 1987 , it opened its first store in Qianmen Beijing , the capital of China. Year 1987 ( MCMLXXXVII) was a Common year starting on Thursday (link displays 1987 Gregorian calendar) The Qianmen ( is the common name for the gateway known formally as Zhengyangmen ( Manchu: Tob šuni duka In 2007 , it has over 1800 restaurants in 402 cities in all Mainland China &apos;s provinces other than Tibet . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Mainland China, Continental China, the Chinese mainland or simply the mainland, is a geopolitical term synonymous with the area that is under the jurisdiction Definitions of Tibet See also Definitions of Tibet Name In English The English word Tibet, like the word for Tibet in most European [24] From 2000 to 2005, it was selected as the &quot;Best chain store brand. &quot; [25] 

KFC is the most popular Western fast-food chain in Taiwan . Taiwan ( Taiwanese: Tâi-oân/Tāi-oân (historically 大灣/台員/大員/台圓/大圓/台窩灣 is an Island in East Asia. [26] Local menu items include egg tarts , and lotus root salad. Egg tarts, custard tarts, or egg custard tarts are a kind of Pastry popular in many parts of the world but particularly in Chinese and Western European Nelumbo nucifera is known by a number of common names including Indian lotus, sacred lotus, bean of India, and sacred water-lily KFC in China also serves other poultry in addition to chicken. Poultry is the category of Domesticated Birds which some humans keep for the purpose of collecting their eggs, or kill for their Meat and/or 

 Germany 
 KFC restaurant in Munich at the &quot;Euro-Industie-Park&quot; 
The first KFC locations opened in Germany in the 1960s thus making it one of the first European countries where KFC established itself. Currently, there are 55 locations in Germany, with most located in major cities (mostly Berlin, Cologne, Munich, Frankfurt, Hamburg to name a few), with at least 1 new location planned in Munich [27] . Munich (München; Minga is the capital city of Bavaria, Germany. The new Dortmund location opened in April marking the end of a 3-year absence in that city. On May 13 , 2008 , KFC opened their largest restaurant worldwide in Munich at the &quot;Euro-Industie-Park&quot;. Events 1497 - Pope Alexander VI excommunicates Girolamo Savonarola. 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common [28] 

 India 

In India, KFC has not established itself in any large way as opposed to another Yum! brand-name restaurant, Pizza Hut , which is prevalent in most Indian cities. It has outlets in Chandigarh , Pune , New Delhi , Mumbai , Bangalore and Kolkata . Chandigarh ( ਚੰਡੀਗੜ੍ਹ, चंडीगढ़) also called The City Beautiful Pune (ˈpuːneɪ Marathi: पुणे Hindi: पूना formerly Poona, is the second largest city in the state of Maharashtra New Delhi (नई दिल्ली ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ نئی دلی is the Capital city of India. Mumbai ( Marathi:,, IPA: formerly Bombay, is the capital of the Indian state of Maharashtra and the financial Bangalore ( officially Bengaluru ( Kannada: ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು) is the capital of the Indian state of Karnataka. The success of the Mumbai restaurant led KFC to introduce the hot and spicy chicken flavour which is more acceptable to the Indian palate. More recently, KFC has opened outlets in Chennai , Tharamani and Mylapore . Tharamani (also called Taramani) is an important area in the south Indian city of Chennai. Mylapore ( Tamil:மயிலாப்பூர் is the cultural hub, and a bustling neighborhood just south of Chennai (formerly Madras 
 A life-sized statue of Colonel Sanders stands and greets customers outside a KFC in Tokyo , Japan. officially, is one of the 47 prefectures of Japan and located on the eastern side of the main island Honshū. 
 Japan 

A life size statue of the Colonel stands in front of most stores in Japan . For a topic outline on this subject see List of basic Japan topics. Fried chicken is an especially popular dish at Christmas time and on Christmas Eve many families, many of who have made reservations weeks in advance, have their traditional Christmas dinner of Kentucky Fried Chicken at home. Christmas Eve, December 24, is the day before Christmas Day, the celebrated birthday of Jesus. Christmas dinner is the primary meal traditionally eaten on Christmas Day. [29] 

 Philippines 

In the Philippines , the KFC name is turned into a tagline cum acronym to stand for &quot; K apag F ried C hicken. The Philippines ( Filipino: Pilipinas, officially known as the Republic of the Philippines (fil &apos;&apos;Republika ng Pilipinas&apos;&apos; RP . . mag-KFC&quot; to stand for &quot;If fried chicken. . . have KFC&quot;.

 Poland 

First KFC restaurant in Poland was opened in 1993 in Warsaw . Poland (Polska officially the Republic of Poland Year 1993 ( MCMXCIII) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full 1993 Gregorian calendar) Warsaw (Warszawa; also known by other names) is the Capital and Largest city of Poland. As of May 2008 KFC has 87 restaurants in Poland operated by AmRest company. International holidays May 1 - Labour Day ( Pakistan) May 1 - Labour Day ( Singapore) American Restaurants ( WSE: EAT is an international fast-food and Casual dining restaurant operator Many of those restaurants are drive-through. AmRest operates KFC also in the Czech Republic , Hungary , Russia , Bulgaria and Serbia . American Restaurants ( WSE: EAT is an international fast-food and Casual dining restaurant operator The Czech Republic ( ˈt͡ʃɛskaː ˈrɛpuˌblɪka short form in Česko ˈt͡ʃɛskɔ also called Czechia, Hungary (Magyarország &apos;mɔɟɔrorsaːg) officially in English the Republic of Hungary ( Magyar Köztársaság, literally Magyar (Hungarian Republic Russia (Россия Rossiya) or the Russian Federation ( Rossiyskaya Federatsiya) is a transcontinental Country extending The state of Bulgaria (България transliterated bg-Latn &apos;&apos;Balgaria&apos;&apos; The country preserves the traditions (in ethnic name language and alphabet of the First Bulgarian Serbia (Србија Srbija) officially the Republic of Serbia (Република Србија Republika Srbija) is a Landlocked Country 

 United Kingdom&amp;Ireland 

The first KFC outside of the US and Canada was opened in Preston , England in 1965, becoming the first American fast food chain to open in the UK , there are now over 700 locations across the UK and Ireland with many more planned. The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Country to&amp;quotDominion;of Canada&quot;or&amp;quotCanadian;Federation&quot;or anything else please read the Talk Page Preston ( ˈprɛstən is a city and local government district in Lancashire, England, located on the River Ribble. England is a Country which is part of the United Kingdom. Its inhabitants account for more than 83% of the total UK population whilst its mainland The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom, the UK or Britain,is a Sovereign state located Ireland ( Irish: Éire, ˈeːrʲə is a country in north-western Europe. The franchise was initially run by an independant company known as KFC GB Ltd. until 1986 when Pepsico purchased it as part of a joint venture with Trust house Forte, in 1997 when Tricon (now Yum! ) was spun off from Pepsico it gained full ownership of the UK&amp;Ireland operations. PepsiCo Incorporated (Short for Pepsi Company ( is a large conglomerate with interests in manufacturing marketing and selling a wide variety of carbonated and non- carbonated Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and The UK&amp;Ireland operation is seen as KFC&apos;s European base and is often used to train franchisees from across Europe due to its great success and restaurant quality. [30] 

 

 Criticisms 

 

 Environmental concerns 

KFC has been accused of a large destruction of the Amazon Rainforest , because the supply of soy used for chicken food KFC receives from Cargill has been traced back to the European KFC. The Amazon Rainforest (Brazilian Portuguese: Floresta Amazônica or Amazônia; Spanish: Selva Amazónica or Amazonía Cargill Incorporated is a privately held, Multinational corporation, and is based in the state of Minnesota in the United States. Cargill has reportedly been exporting soy illegally for several years. [31] The Greenpeace organization researched the issue and brought it to the attention of the parent company YUM! Brands, Inc. Greenpeace, originally known as the Greenpeace Foundation, was founded in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada in 1972 The parent company denied the illegal operation, and said that their supply of soy is grown in parts of Brazil. [31] Greenpeace has called on KFC to stop purchasing soy from Cargill, to avoid contributing to the destruction of the Amazon. [31] [32] 

 

 Trademark disputes 

In 1971 , Sanders sued Heublein Inc. Year 1971 ( MCMLXXI) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full calendar of the 1971 Gregorian calendar. , KFC&apos;s parent company at the time, over the alleged misuse of his image in promoting products he had not helped develop. In 1975 , Heublein Inc. Year 1975 ( MCMLXXV) was a Common year starting on Wednesday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. unsuccessfully sued Sanders for libel after he publicly referred to their gravy as &quot;sludge&quot; with a &quot;wallpaper taste&quot;. [33] 

In May 2007 KFC (Great Britain) requested that Tan Hill Inn , in the Yorkshire Dales , North Yorkshire, UK refrain from using the term &apos;Family Feast&apos; to describe its Christmas menu. May 2007 is the fifth month of that year It began on a Tuesday and 31 days later ended on a Thursday. The Yorkshire Dales (also known as The Dales) is the name given to an upland area in Northern England. [34] 
 Protesters demonstrating outside a KFC restaurant in Royal Oak, Michigan Balmoral KFC workers and allies picket the store 
 

 Wages and working conditions 

Like many fast food outlets, KFC employs a high proportion of young, unskilled workers, at or just above minimum wage , and its workers are not unionized. Royal Oak is a city in Oakland County of the US state of Michigan. Balmoral is a Suburb of Auckland, New Zealand that is bordered by Mt Eden, Epsom, Mount Roskill and Sandringham A minimum wage is the lowest hourly daily or monthly Wage that employers may legally pay to employees or workers In New Zealand , KFC youth workers earn NZ$ 10. New Zealand is an Island country in the south-western Pacific Ocean comprising two main landmasses (the North Island and the South Island The New Zealand dollar ( sign: $; code: NZD) is the Currency of New Zealand. 13 an hour. Staff at the Balmoral, Auckland store went on strike for two hours on December 3 , 2005 after Restaurant Brands , the franchise holder, offered no wage increase in contract negotiations. Balmoral is a Suburb of Auckland, New Zealand that is bordered by Mt Eden, Epsom, Mount Roskill and Sandringham Events 1800 - War of the Second Coalition: Battle of Hohenlinden, French Year 2005 ( MMV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Restaurant Brands is a Fast Food company based in New Zealand. [35] In March of 2006 , Restaurant Brands agreed to phase out youth rates in New Zealand, although no date was set. Events in March American Red Cross Month Fire Prevention month ( The Philippines) Women&apos;s History Month ( United Year 2006 ( MMVI) was a Common year starting on Sunday of the Gregorian calendar. 

Many stores in western Canada are unionized with the Canadian Auto Workers, and as a result many non-franchise stores in western Canada pay higher than minimum wage. Western Canada, commonly referred to as the West, is a region of Canada normally including all parts of Canada west of the province In British Columbia , where minimum wage is $8 an hour, KFC employees make between $10 and $11 an hour. British Columbia (ˌbrɪtɨʃ kəˈlʌmbiə ( BC) ( (la Colombie-Britannique C 

 

 Animal rights 

Since 2003 , animal rights and welfare organizations, led by People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), have been protesting KFC’s treatment of the animals used for its products. Year 2003 ( MMIII) was a Common year starting on Wednesday of the Gregorian calendar. &amp;quotAnimal;liberation&quot;redirects here for other uses see Animal liberation (disambiguation. These groups claim that the recommendations of the KFC Animal Welfare Advisory Council have been ignored. [36] Adele Douglass, a former member of the council, said in an SEC filing reported on by the Chicago Times , that KFC &quot;never had any meetings. The US Securities and Exchange Commission (commonly known as the SEC) is an independent agency of the United States government which holds primary responsibility The Chicago Times was a Newspaper in Chicago from 1854 to 1895 when it merged with the Chicago Herald. They never asked any advice, and then they touted to the press that they had this animal-welfare advisory committee. I felt like I was being used. &quot; [37] [38] 

KFC responded by saying the chickens used in its products are bought from suppliers like Perdue Farms , Tyson Foods , and Pilgrim&apos;s Pride , and that these suppliers are routinely monitored for animal welfare violations. Perdue Farms is a major chicken processing company based in Salisbury Maryland, United States. Tyson Foods Inc ( is an American Multinational corporation based in Springdale Arkansas, that operates in the Food Industry Pilgrim&apos;s Pride Corp, headquartered in Pittsburg Texas, is the largest chicken producer in the United States and Puerto Rico and the second-largest chicken producer in Mexico [39] Several PETA undercover investigations and videos of these and other KFC suppliers purport to show chickens being beaten, ripped apart, and thrown against walls contradict KFC’s claims. [40] There have been more than 12,000 demonstrations at KFC outlets since 2003 because of this alleged mistreatment of chickens by KFC suppliers. Year 2003 ( MMIII) was a Common year starting on Wednesday of the Gregorian calendar. 

In June 2008, KFC Canada agreed to PETA&apos;s demands for better welfare standards, including favoring suppliers who use controlled-atmosphere killing (CAK) of chickens, and other welfare standards as well as introducing a vegan sandwich at 65% of its outlets. PETA has called off its campaign against KFC Canada, but continues to demonstrate against KFC alsewhere in the world. [41] 

 

 Urban legends 

 Urban legends about KFC&apos;s rebranding from Kentucky Fried Chicken include the notion that the Commonwealth of Kentucky planned legal action against the chain due to a trademark on &quot;Kentucky. An urban legend or urban myth is a form of modern Folklore consisting of stories thought to be factual by those circulating them The Commonwealth of Kentucky ( is a state located in the East Central United States of America. A trademark or trade mark, represented by the symbols ™ and ®, or mark is a distinctive sign or indicator used by an individual &quot; Another popular tale is that the chain was forced to change its name from Kentucky Fried Chicken to KFC based on the assertion that the chain would be falsely advertising their products as being made from actual chickens. The corollary to the myth is that the chicken products came from highly genetically modified animals without feathers, beaks, or feet, which were easier to harvest. Genetic engineering, Recombinant DNA technology, genetic modification/manipulation (GM and gene splicing are terms that apply to the direct [42] Both such tales have been debunked.

The TLC program Mostly True Stories: Urban Legends Revealed had a segment called &quot;Kentucky Fried Rat,&quot; which aired on June 10, 2003. TLC (generally called as The Learning Channel) is a cable TV network in the US and Canada, that carries a variety of informational and Mostly True Stories Urban Legends Revealed is a Docu-drama about Urban legends and re-enacting them and researching their credibility The story described a woman who purchased a dinner from KFC as a shortcut in the evening preparations for her family, only for the dinner that was supposed to be chicken turn out to be rat [43] . According to the show, the story was not true.

 

 See also 

 List of fast-food restaurants Dixy Chicken Favorite Chicken Chicken Cottage Buffet - Some KFCs have these facilities in select locations 

 

 References 
 
 ^ a b Joe Bramhall. The following is a list of Fast food restaurant chains, as distinct from fast casual chains (see List of fast casual restaurants) casual chains (see List of Dixy Chicken is a Fast food Restaurant chain that specialises in Halal chicken and is owned by a company of Pakistani origin Favorite Chicken&amp;Ribs is a chain of franchised Fast food Restaurants throughout the United Kingdom and overseas Chicken Cottage International is a Halal Fast food chain It was founded in 1994 by Mohammed Khalid A buffet is a meal serving system where patrons serve themselves KFC . Hoovers . Hoover&apos;s Inc is a business research company that has provided information on U com. Retrieved on 2008 - 02-21 . 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common Events 362 - Athanasius returns to Alexandria. 1245 - Thomas, the first known Bishop of Finland ^ Peter O. Keegan ( 1991 - 02-21 ). Year 1991 ( MCMXCI) was a Common year starting on Tuesday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian Calendar. Events 362 - Athanasius returns to Alexandria. 1245 - Thomas, the first known Bishop of Finland KFC shuns &apos;fried&apos; image with new name - Kentucky Fried Chicken has changed its name to KFC . Nation&apos;s Restaurant News. Retrieved on 2007 - 08-24 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 49 BC - Julius Caesar &apos;s General Gaius Scribonius Curio is defeated in the Second Battle of the Bagradas River ^ KFC Resurrecting Old Kentucky Fried Chicken Name, With New Image . buzzle. com ( 2005 - 05-01 ). Year 2005 ( MMV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Events 305 - Diocletian and Maximian retire from the office of Roman Emperor. Retrieved on 2007 - 08-28 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 475 - The Roman General Orestes forces western Roman Emperor Julius Nepos to flee his Capital ^ Anne DiNardo. Kentucky Fried Chicken: Fast Food Makeover . VMSD. com date=2005-08-29. Retrieved on 2007 - 08-28 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 475 - The Roman General Orestes forces western Roman Emperor Julius Nepos to flee his Capital ^ Doug Bennett, Jr. . Kentucky’s Colonel Sanders . The Courier-Journal. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Kevin Beimers, Aimee Lingman. Doing Chicken Right Since 1932 . roadtrip. beimers. com. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ KFC (2007). The Pressure Cooker . KFC. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ KFC (2007). History . KFC. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Jenifer K. Nii (2004). Colonel&apos;s landmark KFC is mashed . Deseret Morning News. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ I&apos;ve Got A Secret interview, originally broadcast April 6, 1964 (rebroadcast by GSN March 30, 2008). For IGAS qua graphology organization see International Graphoanalysis Society I&apos;ve Got a Secret is a weekly panel Game show produced ^ Roadside America. The Big Chicken . Roadside America. Retrieved on 2007 - 04-16 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1178 BC - A Solar eclipse may have marked the return of Odysseus, legendary King of Ithaca, to his kingdom ^ Alex Davis for the Louisville Courier-Journal (2007). The Courier-Journal, nicknamed the&amp;quotC-J;&quot;, is the main Newspaper for the city of Louisville Kentucky, USA KFC tries Kentucky fried fish . Archive . Kentucky Community and Technical College System. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Little Bucket Parfaits - KFC.com ^ Peter O. Keegan (1993). Rotisserie Gold media blitz storms nation . Nations Restaurant News. Retrieved on 2007 - 08-21 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1192 - Minamoto Yoritomo becomes Seii Tai Shōgun and the De facto ruler of Japan. ^ YouTube - KFC Chicken Littles 1987 TV Commercial ^ Webb Howell, (2000). Power to the People . QSR Magazine. Retrieved on 2007 - 08-21 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1192 - Minamoto Yoritomo becomes Seii Tai Shōgun and the De facto ruler of Japan. ^ Todd Zwillich (2006). KFC to Fry Chicken Without Trans Fats . WebMD. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Animate Clay!. Vinton Studio Commercials . Animate Clay!. ^ [1] . ^ KFC (2006). KFC Creates World&apos;s First Brand Visible from Space . Press Release . KFC. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Stephen Hutcheon (2006). Giant Nullarbor logo zooms back into focus . The Sydney Morning Herald. Retrieved on 2007 - 10-28 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 306 - Maxentius is proclaimed Roman Emperor. 312 - Battle of Milvian Bridge: Constantine ^ Associated Press (2006). The Associated Press ( AP) is an American News agency. The AP is a Cooperative owned by its contributing Newspapers radio KFC Unveils New Logo with Giant Image in Nevada Desert . FOX News . Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Melanie Warner ( 2005 - 07-11 ). Year 2005 ( MMV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Events 911 - Signing of the Treaty of Saint-Clair-sur-Epte between Charles the Simple and Rollo of Normandy. Diners Walk Through One Door and Visit Two Restaurants . the New York Times . Retrieved on 2007 - 12-29 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1170 - Thomas Becket: Thomas Becket Archbishop of Canterbury is assassinated inside Canterbury Cathedral by followers of King Henry II  “Yum&apos;s multibranded stores have two illuminated logos, but they function as one restaurant. They have combined kitchens, a single line of cashiers and a staff trained to prepare both sets of menu items. ” ^ Yum! Brands . Yum! Brands Inc ( or Yum! is a Fortune 500 Corporation, that operates or licenses Taco Bell, KFC, Pizza Hut, and Yum! China Division . Retrieved on December 9, 2007. ^ People&apos;s Daily . The People&apos;s Daily ( a daily Newspaper, is the organ of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, published worldwide with a circulation China Grants Kentucky Best Franchise Brand . Retrieved on December 9, 2007. ^ Jack Marr, Alcinda Hatfield. Fast-Food Restaurants: Just What Eastern China&apos;s Consumers Ordered . USDA Foreign Agricultural Service. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ KFC Kentucky Fried Chicken | restaurants ^ According to the advertisements on the restaurant itself. ^ The Age (2005). The Age is a Broadsheet daily Newspaper, which has been published in Melbourne, Australia since 1854 Deck the malls, it&apos;s Yuletide in Japan . The Age Company Ltd. . Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ http://www.kfc.co.uk/about/about.aspx ^ a b c Greenpeace (2006). KFC exposed for trashing the Amazon rainforest for buckets of chicken . Greenpeace . Greenpeace, originally known as the Greenpeace Foundation, was founded in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada in 1972 Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Brazil Magazine (2006). KFC&apos;s Secret Ingredients Include Soy That&apos;s Destroying the Amazon, Says Greenpeace . Brazil Magazine. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Kleber, John E. ; Thomas D. Clark, Lowell H. Harrison, and James C. Klotter (June 1992). The Kentucky Encyclopedia . University Press of Kentucky , page 796. The University Press of Kentucky (UPK is the scholarly Publisher for the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and was organized in 1969 as successor to the University of Kentucky ISBN 0-81311-772-0.   ^ Pub Fights KFC for &apos;Family Feast&apos; . BBC (2007-05-10). Retrieved on 2008 - 04-29 . 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common Events 1429 - Joan of Arc arrives to relieve the Siege of Orleans. ^ The New Zealand Herald (2005). KFC staff to strike . The New Zealand Herald. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Dr. Temple Grandin, Dr. Johan Raj, Dr. Ian Duncan (2005). Animal welfare recommendations and proposed plan of action for implementation at KFC suppliers (. pdf). People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals . Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ Securities and Exchange Commission (2006). Relating to an Animal Welfare Standards Report - Shareholder Proposal . EDGAR Online, Inc. . Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ David Montgomery (2003). Small But Mighty Rights Group Tries Gentler Approach . Archived . Chicago Tribune . The Chicago Tribune is a major daily Newspaper based in Chicago, Illinois, United States, and owned by the Tribune Company Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ CNN (2003). Pamela Anderson takes on KFC . CNN . Cable News Network, usually referred to by its Initialism CNN, is a major English language Television network founded in 1980 by Ted Turner Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ PETA (2005). Undercover Investigations . PETA. Retrieved on October 28, 2007. ^ &apos;Kentucky Fried Cruelty&apos; comes to an end ^ Barbara and David Mikkelson. Tastes like Chicken . Urban Legends Reference Pages . Snopes (ˈsnoʊps also known as the Urban Legends Reference Pages, is a Web site that is the most widely-known resource for validating or debunking Urban legends ^ Mostly True Stories: Urban Legends Revealed Episodes | TVGuide.com 
 
 

 External links 

 Official site 
 ©2009 citizendia.org; parts available under the terms of GNU Free Documentation License, from http://en.wikipedia.org
 Dapyx Software network: MP3 Explorer | Ebook Manager | Zenithic
	</body>
</document>
