<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008000" url="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2007/03/results_of_the_/" time="2012-07-13-01:04" support="10" score="0.022825511757840335" bingtitle="Results of the ABC News ’20/20′ Undercover Pharmacy ..." webtitle="Results of the ABC News20/20Undercover Pharmacy Investigation - ABC News">
			<query id="000093" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000073" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000092" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001243" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... undercover field test of prescription dispensing ... to popular belief we DO NOT come to the counter ... wait times in the pharmacy. it is not a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		ABC News Blogs &gt; Headlines &gt; Investigative 
 Investigative 
 Headlines Politics Entertainment Health Lifestyle Business Technology 
 Previous
 Drugstores Respond to’20/20′ Next
 ABC Story Leads to Deluge of Pharmacy Error Reports Mar 30, 2007 10:17pm 
Results of the ABC News’20/20′Undercover Pharmacy Investigation
   Email 170 Smaller Font Text Larger Text | Print 
For the last two months, a team of&quot;20/20&quot;producers fanned out across four states to conduct an undercover field test of prescription dispensing at the country’s best known chain drug stores. They found that in more than one in five cases, chain pharmacies made some type of error in filling their prescriptions.&quot;The results confirm our worst fears,&quot;said Dr. Ken Barker of Auburn University School of Pharmacy, one of the country’s leading experts in studying pharmacy error rates.&quot;There really is a problem out there.&quot;The ABC test was designed and supervised by Auburn’s Dr. Betsy Flynn, a specialist in studying errors in neighborhood pharmacies who designed a similar undercover test for ABC News over a decade ago.&quot;The 22 percent error rate found in the study was unacceptable,&quot;said Flynn, who expressed her&quot;surprise and disappointment&quot;that&quot;despite all of the implementation of technology over the past 12 years, the error rate was similar to the previous study.&quot;While in no case were ABC’s producers given the wrong medication, there were a variety of dispensing errors found—too many or too few pills, faulty and missing instructions on the labeling, even a failure to put a child proof cap on a powerful medicine for bi-polar disorder. But perhaps the most important finding of the undercover test was a dramatic reduction in time spent on patient counseling by pharmacists. Despite federal and state laws that require pharmacists to provide counseling to customers picking up new medications, patient counseling was only offered in 27 out of 100 purchases of new prescriptions, less than a third, in the ABC-Auburn Study. Particularly alarming to the Auburn experts was the chain pharmacies’failure to warn patients of potentially harmful interactions when they purchased certain over-the-counter medications, such as adult strength aspirin with Coumadin, a blood thinner. In only eight cases out of 25 were the customers given a verbal warning. Finally, the study revealed that some pharmacies appear to be misleading customers into signing away their right to patient counseling. Although the ABC producers paid with cash and no insurance was involved, in most cases they were still asked to sign at the pharmacy counter to pick up their prescriptions. But with only a few exceptions, our producers were never told they were signing forms that also included language to waive the legal right to counseling with a pharmacist.&quot;They’re deceiving the patient about what they’re really signing,&quot;said Bruce Berger, a department head at Auburn’s pharmacy school who says the pharmacy personnel at the counter may not know it, but they are in effect, undercutting the law. You can read a full summary prepared by Dr. Betsy Flynn of the design and results of the Auburn University–ABC News Pharmacy Study by clicking here.
   Email 170 Smaller Font Text Larger Text | Print Previous
 Drugstores Respond to’20/20′ Next
 ABC Story Leads to Deluge of Pharmacy Error Reports 
 User Comments 
 
What about the errors doctors make that are caught by the pharmacist on a daily basis? There are two sides to the coin. Your piece of one-sided jounalism doesn’t show the positive impact that pharmacists make. One error is too much and we take our profession very seriously. It’s easier and more lucrative for your show to focus on the negative. I’m dissappointed in 20/20. I thought your standards were higher than that! Broadcast a show highlighting duties performed by a pharmacist that make a postive impact on patients and you’ll get me back as a viewer. Viewers, where else can you go to get free healthcare information when your doctor isn’t available? I’ve spent the last 25 plus years working nights and weekends and helped scores of people during that time. Your pharmacist will always be there for you.
 
Posted by: Candi | March 30, 2007, 10:53 pm 10:53 pm
 
I have seen customers yelling a pharmacy employees that they need to just put the pills in the bottle and how hard can it be. I think that there are many causes to these problems outlined in this report. Pharmacies are trying to keep up with the ever growing demand that their customers have to get their perscriptions right now. If everyone wants their perscription right now, that does not leave much time for anything else. You try telling someone to come back in an hour and see what response you get.
 
Posted by: Ryan | March 30, 2007, 11:02 pm 11:02 pm
 
this report only shows one side of the story. my friend is a pharmacy technician and she is ptcb certified. i think she is very well qualified. she works for a major chain in which they want you to fill a prescription in 15 min or less. while you have customers asking why does it take so long remember they just don’t sit at a computer and type they have to pick up the phone answer questions and deal with ringing up store merchandise all together. we have to minimize there work so that they can pay more attention to us when we are picking up. so they don’t have there mind on what’s on sale! and they will have more time for patients instead of customers that are not picking up rx’s!!!!
 
Posted by: sharen | March 30, 2007, 11:26 pm 11:26 pm
 
I thought your story was really informative. I think people don’t think twice and just take the pills with the assumption that they have been filled correctly.
I was thinking of an idea that may help to assure that each patient can do a“self-check”after receiving and before taking their medication. What if the pharmacy included in the literature that is printed out with the prescriptions, a color photo depicting the exact color, size and logo that should match-up to the pills they have been given! I think this would be a great tool in helping to ensure the patient is aware of what the pill should look like prior to taking it!
Kathy
 
Posted by: kathy | March 30, 2007, 11:38 pm 11:38 pm
 
The question arose“what about the good pharmacists have done?”This story was about the absence of said pharmacist and the bulk of the technical work being completed by“untrained”personnel. Pharmacists themselves are a very competent, respected, and well paid breed. I don’t think, no matter how much training“technicians”get, that they receive the knowledge of a 4, 6, or 8 year degreed program comparable to a pharmacist and, as such, should NEVER be responsible for filling prescriptions. They are perfect for duties such as fact checking, ordering of supplies, cashier work, assistant tasks, etc. A pharmacist should be onsite the entire time the pharmacy is open and should be the sole employee performing the skilled work, while the technicians assist–and only assist this process. If these chain stores have a quota for their pharmacy, they’ll need to rethink this strategy as if I had any clout in this industry, their CEOs would be putting some of their record profits back into the business to insure the pharmacy is staffed by proper personnel. Since when has this country switched paradigms so that which is good for the few (IE–the wealthy) outweighs the needs of the many?
 
Posted by: John M. | March 31, 2007, 12:01 am 12:01 am
 
I have been in management for 2 major pharmacy chains and I can tell you that one chain I worked for before put us through 6 classes and then we had to take the test to be certified by the company but not the state. They have now since changed that in the past 2 years, you get in store training and when you are ready you now sit at a computer at the store in the office and take your test to be certified. At this chain they do their best to keep costs down so there are minimum employees in the pharmacy and up front. The company I work for now has 3 or more employees in the pharmacy and 4 or more up front so that the pharmacy employees are not doing thing they shouldn’t have to do. This allows them to spend all their time doing what they should be doing. They put you through classes and then you go to take the certification test and we all have to be trained in store and in the class room. I have seen more mistakes by the doctors and our pharmasits catch them and call the doctor to fix them before we can fill these perscriptions. Then you have the customer who wants it now! Noone can wait, they have to have it now and they yell at you if they have to come back. All in all, I have never seen any mistakes made at either drug store chain I have worked for and the pharmasists whom I have worked with really pay attention to what they are doing and they care about the people they are filling perscriptions for. We also have new computer programs in place that alert us of mis fills, drug interactions and every perscription that goes out MUST be checked by the pharmasist or it can not be sold at the register. As for signing away your rights, we ask everyone if they have any questions for the pharasist about the medication or it’s effects, and 90% of the customers that we have at the pharmacy say no or they just don’t want to take the time to wait a few minutes to speak to the pharmasist.
 
Posted by: Lori | March 31, 2007, 12:15 am 12:15 am
 
After seeing your 20/20 story tonight I just had to respond…As a full-time 49-year-old pharmacy technician(&amp;a 4-year colon cancer survivor—after 3 major surgeries!!) at a major chain in the Northeast, I can only say that I am an intelligent, conscientious, competant mother of 2 college-aged students and am very concerned and disheartened by your story (of which it is)…The pharmacy that I work for (for 7&amp;1/2 years now) will ONLY employ anyone over 18 years old–but who wants to start at a starting salary of $6.50 an hour and then gradually progress to $8.00 after completing 6 months of computer training and 4 in-house workbook courses (in which you have to travel 30 miles both ways??)…Heck…you could walk across our parking lot to McDonald’s and start at $8 or $9 an hour&amp;flip burgers or be a manager…Where is the comparison or logic? Filling prescriptions correctly is worth a lot more money than getting your take-out order right at the drive-thru burger joint…don’t you think??…why don’t you ask the top execs why the starting salary is so low??…heck..i’ve been working my rear off and getting the scripts right but the pharmacists in my store change from month to month…they can’t keep them or they change them from store to store..the higher-ups don’t really care about the techs…just keep the pharmacists happy…not good business…customers don’t like it (they want consistency) and I don’t like it…I am great at what I do and think (hope) my customers appreciate me for that and if I ever wanted to sue my original doctor for malpractice (two botched surgeries) I could have (gee…maybe I should…I could be living the life I always dreamed of!)…you never even took a glimpse at the prescriptions that doctors’write and the pharmacy tech’s have to read them…come on…check out these doctors’handwriting while you criticize the tech’s job…just a thought!!! Bet you won’t follow up on that…got lot’s of doc’s who are guilty of VERY POOR HANDWRITING and still don’t use an e-script or e-fax (way better for us techs)…thanks for listening…P in PA
 
Posted by: pharmtech0304 | March 31, 2007, 12:19 am 12:19 am
 
Very important story…very important topic, especially considering that medication errors kill more people in the US than car accidents. However, I would like to propose to investigate the root cause of all this. Let’s focus for a minute on the EMPLOYER themselves, the working conditions of the personnel behind the counter.
I worked for Giant Eagle for a while. Did you know that:
1. Pharmacists do NOT get time off to (a) eat (have lunch), (b) go to the bathroom (basic needs!), or sit? Pharmacists may go for full 8 or 12 hours (depending on the schedule) on their feet for ALL those many hours. Could we investigate the degree of concentration of that pharmacist after 6 hours of non-stop work?
2. In addition to checking what technicians have filled, the pharmacist has to (a) call prescribers for mutiple clarifications AND refill authorizations. Who do we get? Only SECRETARIES!; with luck, a nurse, who sometimes decides on his/her own to“go ahead”and authorize one (or several) refills, or who says,“the patient says s/he is taking this or that…”. Right there there is a tremendous opportunity for error…but most physicians are NOT available EVER to talk to a pharmacist!; (b) make an infinite number of calls to TRANSFER prescriptions…from one pharmacy to the next, depending on WHO is offfering coupons or other rewards. I do not know HOW a pharmacist can provide counseling to these costumary“transfering patients”.
3. Most pharmacist (and technicians) work in a extremely noisy environment, which can and IS quite distracting. NOt only the phones ring constantly, the pharmacist has to make calls mostly non-stop, but a RADIO is blasting with non-stop nonsense“talk”, laud music, and plain stupidity.
All of the above is in addition to being subjected to a“store manager”who, if a costumer complains, interferes and try to manipulate pharmacy business (although Pharmacy BOards prohibit the presence of non-pharmacy personnel in the pharmacy area).
In summary, none of the above is to justify the errors made and lack of counseling given…it is just to point out that the problem is MUCH bigger. Big chains have a responsibility on this. For them, it is just“business”. Pharmacists are subjected to inhumane treatment and working conditions by the“Rite Aids”, the“Giant Eagles”, the“CVSs”, the“Walgreens”, etc, etc., with serious consequences to the pharmacists’health.
 
Posted by: Sophia | March 31, 2007, 12:25 am 12:25 am
 
Kathy…”fast checking”…what is that…??? I’m a tech and we need a cashier in the pharmacy…is this a“fast checker”??
 
Posted by: Peg | March 31, 2007, 12:26 am 12:26 am
 
I think Kathy’s idea is great.Patients should double check their own prescription before using it.May be people should stop comparing Chain drug stores to fast food restaurants. Drive-thrus are for convenience, but hey you have to realize that we are not dispensing fries or drinks. It’s a PHARMACY…learn to be patient when it comes to drugs that can either heal you or kill you!
 
Posted by: Future Pharmacist | March 31, 2007, 12:27 am 12:27 am
 
I listened to the report and it amazes me because I’m not sure that 20/20 even knows what the responsibility of the pharmacist is. Unfortunately, a pharmacist does not have time to do every single task in the pharmacy. there is usually only 1 pharmacist working at a time, the rest of the employees are usually technicians. I will begin by stating that even the possibility of errors, as a registered practicing retail pharmacist makes my skin crawl. It is an awful fact of life that pharmacists face because we are after all human. However, there is a perception that we cannot make mistakes no matter how understaffed or rushed we really are. And I agree–I strive to not make a single mistake in any day of my career–that is truly my goal. Is that realistic? It is the expectation. There is a huge responsibility that goes with the territory, and I face that everyday. I don’t think that the general public understands the consequences a mistake can have. I think that everyone needs to understand what it is exactly that the pharmacist does behind the counter in between being griped at by angry patients concerning insurance claims or longer than 15 minute wait times or just someone coming up that wants nothing from the pharmacy other than to be rung up. I think that the general public and evidently 20/20 does not understand that it is the pharmacist’s ultimate responsibility to make sure that your prescription is accurate (this includes multiple aspects of checking–right patient, right drug, right drug strength, right quantity, right directions, right refills, right doctor just to name a few). AND NOT ONLY IS IT ACCURATE, we check to make sure that there are no drug interactions or allergies. We also check that the dose is reasonable and will not harm the patient. This is our ultimate responsibility–our reason for being. Not to count by 5′s or explain why insurance/drugs cost so much. I think that it’s quite funny that 20/20 is trying to rile people up because a pharmacist is not counting your prescription. That is not our responsibility, simply put. However, it is our responsibility when something goes out wrong. Technicians are to be prudent and fill responsibility, but everything they do is to be double checked by the pharmacist. So is it the fault of the 16 year old technician? answer: mostly not. I am willing to bet there was a big law suit involving walgreen’s. And i imagine that the pharmacist is being held liable. It is extremely unfortunate that mistakes are made. I cannot imagine having that happen to a loved one in my family, nor could I imagine making a mistake like that. I think that I would not be able to practice as a pharmacist after that, knowing that a mistake caused that much harm. The disturbing fact is, however, pharmacists are human and thus capable of making mistakes even on a good day. And the environment of retail pharmacies are such that they create an environment where mistakes can happen. From the gimmicks of gift cards (that cause people to be“incentivised”to go from pharmacy to pharmacy leading to drug interactions left unchecked which may cause serious harm–something that we are promoting at chain pharmacies) to the idea that you can get your prescription in less than 15 minutes especially if you haggle with the pharmacy staff, retail pharmacy is very high stress. There are constant interruptions which I believe are a major source of errors. Not to mention being rushed by people who have no clue what consequence an error may have on their lives. Yet, as sure as the sun will come up tomorrow, I will have someone come into my pharmacy tomorrow and tell me about this news story, but in the same breath tell me that they need their Rx ASAP and they will have a cart full of groceries to ring up with it. Or even better, they’ll pick up their prescription and not pay a bit of attention because they’ll be too busy talking on their cell phone. I have actually counseled patients while they were talking on their cell phone. As one sided as this story is, it would be nice if just for one moment people would think about how important this process is that they would actually take it seriously. a lot of the problem, and this is a point of agreement with ABC actually, is due to corporate coming up with gimmicks and ways to fill more prescriptions with less people. I’ve also actually heard of schemes by certain corporations (luckily not my employer) concerning quotas for pharmacists in terms of what percentage they fill within 15 minutes. Unfortunately, this seems to be the image that the corporate world wants to burden the profession of pharmacy with, and they have done a damn good job at that. This is what the public really expects and wants from pharmacies and I think that it is very unfortunate. It truly is a disservice and an ill-use of skills by otherwise very capable pharmacists. But that is my opinion. Many pharmacists get burned out in retail and leave either because they get beaten down from being rushed checking literally hundreds of prescriptions without any break in sight for 14 hours a day, or from being harassed by patients that cannot find someone at the insurance company to yell at, or by news articles like this that demean the profession. But then again, 20/20 wouldn’t make it’s money or have nearly the response if the show highlighted the actual day of a pharmacist and what the responsibilities actually are and how pharmacists can help prevent errors. No scandals = no sales for news corporations. Sounds like your corporate and my corporate should do lunch sometime!
 
Posted by: KMS | March 31, 2007, 12:30 am 12:30 am
 
Mr“John”, Technicians are VERY WELL trained to count pills!! A pharmacist needs to check! and YES…a pharmacists is ALWAYS on duty when the pharmacy is open.
 
Posted by: Ron | March 31, 2007, 12:30 am 12:30 am
 
I noticed that you seemed to target Walgreens Rx in your story. I think that this is a bigger problem than you realize. Being an employee of The Kroger Co. based in Cincinatti, Ohio I am forced to use Kroger Rxs because they are self insured.
Having delt with Kroger Rxs after 12 years my wife and I have seen many stupid mistakes made by thier employees, too numerous to list.
I used to remodel and build pharmacies for Kroger and the HIPPA privacy law may well not exist. Rx employees discuss customers’medications and behaviors like a soap opera
Joe
 
Posted by: Joseph Schmitt | March 31, 2007, 1:03 am 1:03 am
 
The article misleads through omission: the article describes Flynn as being“disappointed”that the error rate in the current study was the same as the one conducted 10 years ago and thereby gives the probably false impression that process improvements and technology have done nothing to improve the accuracy of pharmacies. However, the article neglects to mention whether all other factors were the same or similar. For example, what about fill rates and pharmacist to rx ratios at the pharmacies that were visted. If the pharmacies visited 10 years ago filled 100 rx in a day and the ones in this study filled 300 rx in a day, then you can make the assertion that processes and technology HAVE improved the accuracy of the pharmacy. Apples&amp;oranges here with the article omitting that little item.
The article is just plain wrong:
1) Pharmacists are only LEGALLY required to counsel Medicaid patients with new prescriptions only (OBRA 1990). Any other counseling is a courtesy (either personal or encouraged by the company).
2) Signing the form is NOT a waiver of your right to counselling. It is merely an assertion by the patient that they want to take their medication out of their pharmacy without needing counseling. If you want it, you’ll get it every time.
3) Verbal indication of the aspirin/coumadin interaction would be nice to get from every pharmicist. However, AGAIN, there is no legal requirement to counsel anyone but medicaid patients. The labels and warning on the medication DO list those interactions and it is the PATIENT’s responsibity to read them. If there is a lack of understanding on the patient’s part, then for god’s sake ask for the counseling whether it’s at the pharmacy or by phone from home.
Junk science. It’s like saying that since the death rate from car accidents is the same as it was 20 years ago, all safety improvements due to technolgy must be ineffective. Of course, that would ignore the greater number of drivers on the road, increased congestion, DUI rates, etc.
Ignore the article&amp;do yourself a favor by simply taking an interest in what medication you’re taking.
 
Posted by: Mitch | March 31, 2007, 1:11 am 1:11 am
 
There are 2 sides to this story. While it is right to hold the pharmacist and the pharmacy accountable and responsible for prescription errors, the physicians who prescribe medications and the patients who are given the medications have similar acccountabilities and responsibilities on their end. Most prescribers do not write legibly or conscientiously or refuse to use technological tools to improve their communication to other healthcare providers causing the pharmacist precious time by calling to verify pertinent info about the medication. Most of the time pharmacists had to leave a voice message which most clinics or doctors’offices do not return till 24-48 hours or so later. Let situations like the video you just aired be a lesson to all patients/customers who are in a hurry to pick up their medications. The pharmacy is not a fastfood joint. A lot of people don’t understand the work environment inside a pharmacy. Each time a prescription is being processed,a life hangs in the balance. When customers yell at or argue with employees for whatever complaint they have, what they don’t realize is that they are unknowingly tipping the scale, not to their favor. My advice to patients,customers and caregivers is to always BE VIGILANT AND READ BACK TO YOUR DOCTORS THE MEDICATION INFORMATION THEY WRITE DOWN ON PAPER. ASK QUESTIONS WHILE FACE-TO-FACE WITH YOUR PHYSICIANS. FINALLY, REMEMBER TO TAKE FULL ADVANTAGE OF THE FREE COUNSELLING SERVICES THAT YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD PHARMACY PROVIDES BY COMING INTO THE PHARMACY AND REQUESTING CONSULTATION WITH YOUR PHARMACIST.
 
Posted by: Carol | March 31, 2007, 1:18 am 1:18 am
 
I just want to let you know that CVS is a mess too regarding filling medication, my daughter was at the pharmacy, lst month, filling up an antiobotic, they first could find the med, finaly they gave her my MED ; ACTONEL !!!
a bunch of kids were lost between the med, they gave their med to other client !….I dont understand I gave you my e-mail ok?
 
Posted by: yvonne soffer | March 31, 2007, 1:25 am 1:25 am
 
I am a nationally certified pharmacy technician (CPhT) and hope to be a pharmacist in the near future. There needs to be an emphasis put on formal, standardized training of pharmacy technicians. As it stands now, with a minimum of on-the-job training, one can apply for a license in most states. Standardized, mandatory, formal education would provide needed skills and knowledge for most technicians to do their jobs properly (and weed out those who can’t hack it). I have witnessed (and corrected) potential medication errors by techs who didn’t know better or were too stupid to be doing the job. Wages for technicians also need to go up to reflect and attract dedicated, career technicians. I have no desire to stay as a tech because I cannot live on $9.75/hr forever and support a mortgage at the same time. The gap between tech wages and pharmacist wages is too extreme; pharmacists rely on techs to provide them with a correct product to do a quality assurance check before it goes to the customer. Do you want your scripts interpreted, the meds chosen off the shelf, counted, and put into the bottle by someone who is barely exceeding minimum wage? Me either. Without support from the public, the chain stores have no impetus to change their practices. Unless people speak out, nothing will change and errors will continue to be made by uneducated, undedicated techs who should not be in the profession.
 
Posted by: Lori L. | March 31, 2007, 1:28 am 1:28 am
 
I dont care if you have a or a GED PhD, I think it is a miracle that any one can read my doctor’s hand writing. Why dont we hold the doctors responsible to printing the prestriptions or sending them electronically to the pharmacy so they can use computers and robots to fill them error proof. imho, conting 30 pills and pouring them into a vial is not rocket science. I dont care who does that. Oh BTW, I can READ the instructions on the label too. SO I dont need the pharmacist to waste my time by reading them to me.I want my pharmacist to watch for allergies/ drug interactions and answer mu questions.
 
Posted by: rk | March 31, 2007, 1:29 am 1:29 am
 
most Pharmacist at Retail chain pharcists are foreign pharmacy gruaduates, most of them are on some kind visas and they are all bound to follow the corporate policies of filling 300 to 350 prescriptions in hour shifts.there is extreme pressure on individuals of foreign pharmacists they bound to do it or they lose the job as well as visas to stay in united states. so pharmcists skip counseling and also time spending on drug interactions and questioning higher authorities about the work environment. this is the life of many bigger chain pharmacists. can they answer how pharmacist are from overseas??? its just a eye wash from bigger chains about customer service by bigger publicities
 
Posted by: kumar | March 31, 2007, 1:35 am 1:35 am
 
I am a 3rd year pharmacy student and although I did not get to view all of tonight’s broadcast, I can say with confidence that I would do everything in my power to ensure that the right medication is dispensed to my patients. I can only hope that your story will inspire patients to me more involved with their healthcare. I do feel that ABC misrepresented pharmacists and the value that they have in saving lives. Please consider for a moment all of those individuals that were saved by a pharmacist’s intervention. There is no excuse for mistakes, and my sincere apologies go out to anyone affected by a medication error. I urge patients to talk with their pharmacist and asked questions about their medications. Please understand that pharmacies are not fast food restaurants and that it takes time to review a patient’s medications
 
Posted by: ashleigh ritchie | March 31, 2007, 1:42 am 1:42 am
 
For those that think trained pharmacy technicians should NEVER fill a prescription you need to look at the facts: There is a pharmacist shortage in America. With billions of prescriptions being filled in the U.S. each year, there are simply not enough pharmacists to handle filling ALL of these prescriptions without trained assistance. The wait time to get your medication would be in hours or DAYS instead of 15-30 minutes. When you are ill, do you really want to wait a day or two to get your medication? The answer is to enhance the training and compliance of all pharmacy employees, NOT to quadruple the workload of already over-burdened pharmacists.
 
Posted by: Rick | March 31, 2007, 2:04 am 2:04 am
 
Once again I am disappointed in 20/20. This expose demonstrates the ability of the uneducated media to present a story that misleads the public. The main“hook”of this story appears to be the fact that you as the comsumer are“signing away”your right to counseling at your local pharmacy when you pick up your prescription. The real fact is that when picking up your rx the main, and most important question asked is“do you have any questions about your presciption”. When most consumers put down their cell phone long enough to actually listen to this important question asked at the point of sale they say“no just get me my rx as fast as you can”. In our fast paced 24 hour society the unfortunate reality is that people are too busy to get to their next appointment to slow down enough to listen to this important question. The job of a pharmicist is that of a gate keeper. The pharmacist performs the final check of safety for each rx filled and I find it hard to believe a pharmacist would knowingly dispense something that would harm anybody. Furthermore I am sure that far more people have been helped than harmed by our nation’s dedicated pharmacists and pharmacy technicians. What about all the mistakes made by the Dr, physician’s assistant or nurse that the pharmacist spots and prevents from going out to the patient. This attack on retail pharmacy is an unbalanced presentation of what really happens at your local pharmacy and should be discounted as such. Our nation’s pharmacists provide a valuable and in most cases free service to our population, and I challenge ABC to find a more dedicated group of profesionals with the fortitude and ability to provide such a service.
 
Posted by: Sheri | March 31, 2007, 2:06 am 2:06 am
 
in response to john…a pharmacist is always on duty when a pharmacy is open as required by law. a pharmacy can not open without a pharmacist present. in addition, an 6 year degree is frankly not required to“fill”a prescription. trained technicians are more than capable in typing up a script and counting out the medication. it is the duty of a pharmacist to make sure that the information is typed in correctly, that the right drug dispensed, to check for drug interactions, correct dosing, qty, etc. how can you expect one person to do it all? unless the public wanted to wait a week to receive their prescriptions, it would be impossible given the number of scripts the average pharmacy fills in a day. but i agree, something needs to give. i found that popping the lid at the check out counter has reduced a lot of errors. it gives the patient and the pharmacist an opportunity to do one final visual check together and opens up diaglogue. also, get rid of the drive thru. they are errors just waiting to happen.
 
Posted by: Gwen | March 31, 2007, 2:10 am 2:10 am
 
I am a pharmacy tech at one of these large chains and have been a tech for 13 years. Our store fills over 650 rxs per day. Our longest wait time is 30 minutes when we are busy,If I tell a customer 15min.sometimes the response is, that long,this not not a fast food rest.People today want there meds asap. The pharmacy i work at makes sure all employees get certified before being able to handle important tasks in the pharmacy. Another problem is that technicians are so underpaid that sometimes hiring quality employees is a difficult task. As I have been doing this 13 years and only make 14$ per hour.As computers do a lot of error checks people are human and will make mistakes just like the doctors writing the rxs do also.We do not want to cause harm to anybody abd this show makes it seem as thats what pharmacies are trying to do.Not all pharmacies are run this way!!
 
Posted by: Sammy | March 31, 2007, 2:13 am 2:13 am
 
Pharmacists are placed under an extreme amount of stress. I have been yelled at, threatened, have items thrown at me. In several cases I have had to call the police to have unruly customers removed.
In addition, most pharmacists are forced to work 8 to 10 hour shifts without meal breaks. Due to heavy workloads, many pharmacists do not even take restroom breaks.
And the public expects perfection under these conditions?
 
Posted by: Liza | March 31, 2007, 2:42 am 2:42 am
 
As a pharmacist, I found your report to be short-sighted not investigative. With 12 years of retail pharmacy experience, many times Doctor’s sloppily written prescriptions are a source of errors. I found it very interesting that Mr. Ross did not question why there are laws that require prescriptions to be typewritten rather than handwritten. Yes, pharmacists make mistakes, so do physicians. Sometimes a physician will have an unqualified staff member (no licensing involved) write a prescription and the physician will simply sign it, without reading what was written. It is the pharmacist who catches these errors and help to save the patient unnecessary harm. Mr. Ross if you are going to report on the subject, do not report half a story, but a whole one. I thought that this is what an objective journalist does.
 
Posted by: Jim S | March 31, 2007, 3:08 am 3:08 am
 
The entire reason pharmacies employ pharmacy technicians is to free up the pharmacists so that they can adequately perform tasks that require in-depth knowledge or training. A pharmacist is required to be present at all times and must check every prescription before it can be given to a patient—these laws are intended to prevent medication errors such as those described in the article. That the technician incorrectly transposed a prescription is unfortunate, and certainly more training could have helped prevent this from occurring, but I believe the real issue is that the pharmacist didn’t catch the mistake. I can’t speculate as to why s/he didn’t, but this highlights the problem that arises when prescriptions are treated as goods rather than the entire process being seen as a service. Whether a pharmacist spends 20 minutes discussing a medication with a patient or 5 seconds“checking”a prescription, the pharmacy makes the same amount of money. Consider how many 5-second checks could be performed in 20 minutes and it’s easy to see why some chains push quantity at the expense of quality. I would bet that if pharmacies could get reimbursed for patient services such as consultations, question research, etc, chains would again focus on patient care and not so heavily on volume.
 
Posted by: Jessica | March 31, 2007, 4:06 am 4:06 am
 
I am a nationally certified, educated, well trained tech with many years experience. Unfortunately, 20/20 didn’t bother to mention our side of the story. I don’t know of ANYONE who wants high school kids filling Rx’s. A lot of us have been pushing for mandatory certification and education in all fifty states.
There are requirements in some states and with some employers, but there is nothing on a national level. I would like to see that happen sooner rather than later.
This program, in my opinion, was designed to frighten the general public. National Boards of Pharmacy and legislators-are you paying attention now??
 
Posted by: RG, CPhT | March 31, 2007, 6:19 am 6:19 am
 
I am a small pharmacy chain owner who supports pharmacists with high quality technicians so they have the time to counsel patients. We are being forced out of business due to low reimbursement by the government and insurance companies. This situation demands that large numbers of prescriptions be filled to survive. The answer is to increase reimbursement and enforce laws already in place that require patient counseling. If the current low reimbursement is not changed I don’t think there will be any independent or small chain pharmacies left within two years. Patients will have no choice except the large pharmacy mills.
 
Posted by: Larry | March 31, 2007, 6:29 am 6:29 am
 
I am a PTCB certified tech that has worked in both a hospital and retail pharmacy. I am now in retail and work in a small family owned pharmacy that has one pharmacist. After reading the comments posted here I had to tell you about her! Our pharmacist always takes the time to counsel patients and will even stop what she’s doing to offer to counsel. It’s not always the technician or the cashier that offers it. We also double check behind each other to make sure that dosage, directions, count and even the correct doctor is on the prescription. We know and love all our patients and treat them like family even though some are not always so friendly to us. This story should just prove to the world why you should use a smaller drug store instead of the big chains. Some of the big chains (I’ve been told) will ask the pharmacies to take longer to fill a prescription so that the customer will have to spend time waiting and will possibly spend more money because they’ve shopped while they waited. Use the smaller, local stores and see if it doesn’t make a difference……..I know ours does!
 
Posted by: proud tech | March 31, 2007, 8:21 am 8:21 am
 
I just want to say first that I have a lot of respect for pharmacists. My issues have never been them, but their assistants are mostly incompetent, in my opinion. I’ve heard many complaints from friends and co-workers, and I’ve had some of my own as well. I can’t understand how a pharmacist has to go to school for years to be qualified to dispense medication, but these high school kids and other unqualified people can do their job as an assistant. I’ve wondered for years when something would be done about it. I have an idea: How about the pharmacies hire more than one pharmacist for each store? They make a ridiculous amount of money. I think maybe they can afford it. Because that’s what it really boils down to, isn’t it? It’s always about the money. Money is always more important to these companies than people’s lives. Shame on them!
 
Posted by: Kerry | March 31, 2007, 9:38 am 9:38 am
 
Four years ago, the night before leaving on vacation, I picked up a prescription at a local Rite Aid. I opened it early the next morning to check it and pack it in my bag. Yes, it was the drug the doctor had prescribed BUT it was the wrong dosage and it belonged to someone else–an elderly woman living in the same community. Her name was not even remotely similar to mine. I can’t imagine what might have happened if I had just thrown the medication in my suitcase without paying attention to it. When I called the pharmacy that morning to complain, I received a very lukewarm response.“Yeah, these things happen. Sorry about that.”I even spoke to the store manager, who while apologetic, was not surprised or outraged that this had happened. He promised me that he would refer this to the district pharmacy manager. I never heard from either one of them again. Needless to say, Rite Aid has lost my business and I tell everyone that story and my other endless complaints about Rite Aid.
Sadly, Rite Aid is not the only error prone pharmacy–Eckerd is a very close second. I picked up a prescription for my elderly mother there only to find it was filled with a much larger dose than was required. The bottom line is, when dealing with ANYONE–doctor, nurse, pharmacist, pharmacist assistant, pharmacy clerk–ultimately, it is up to the patient to be responsible for their own medication.Sad but true.Doesn’t anyone assume responsiblity for their own mistakes anymore??
 
Posted by: Judy | March 31, 2007, 9:41 am 9:41 am
 
I think this is a very informative story that adds substance to the position that everyone needs to be an advocate in their own health care. As an RN who works with pharmacies and patients on a daily basis, I have seen the good and the not so good on both sides. Pharmacies catch errors that are made on the clinic side at times and clinics also catch errors that the pharmacies have made. To me, the bottom line is that everyone in health care needs to be doing the right job at the right time for the right person so that expensive“re-work”(fixing mistakes) and any possible harm to our patients is avoided.
 
Posted by: Heidi | March 31, 2007, 10:05 am 10:05 am
 
I am a PTCB Certified Pharmacy Technician CPhT and have been for the last 6 years. I work for one of the large chains. And yes a pharmacist is required to be in the pharmacy at all times. A pharmacy cannot open without one. I am a college graduate who has decided to make this my career. I have taken numerous courses and taken a 3 hour long test to become certified. Just like pharmacists we are required to complete at least 20 hours of continuing education every 2 years to keep our certification. The continuing education we take is often times the same that the pharmacists take. Well trained and educated techs are extremely competent and a vital member of a pharmacy team.
And yet as several people have mentioned before, techs are paid extremely poorly. During a typical day my pharmacy fills 300 prescriptions all the while answering constantly ringing phones, having to answer the drive-up (which should be removed), ring purchases out for customers with no prescription, and being screamed at because someone thinks their medication is too expensive. Oh I forgot. when people come to pick up their prescriptions, there is often an issue with their insurance which needs to be resolved (resolving an insurance issue can take anywhere from 5 minutes to an hour depending on the issue), all the while a line is forming and the phone is still ringing.
My pharmacy wants us to have all prescriptions ready in 15 minutes or less. You tell me what the chance is of an error in the situation I described. The chance is there, however we send out all prescriptions most days without one error. And the errors that do get made are caught by the Pharmacist before it’s even filled. By the way, we report every single error as required by our state law.
 
Posted by: Kathleen | March 31, 2007, 10:30 am 10:30 am
 
I am a PTCB certified tech that has worked in one of the named chains for almost 7 years. Pharmacy errors due occur it is a fact. If there is anyone to blame it is at the corporate level. At the corporate level it seems to all be about money and wanting more. More stores, less paid staff equals higher profits for the big boys. At my store we must promise customers unreasonable time frames. It does not matter how busy we are, or that we are already one hour behind schedule. Some of the time when a customer drops off a prescription the tech is unable to get all the proper information from the patient usually because they have a phone to their ear and are in a hurry.
Many Pharmacists and techs must work long hours and with out lunches, breaks, or even bathroom breaks making them standing on their feet for 8 to 12 hours. The McDonaldisation has now spread to retail pharmacy, and is choking the life out of it. I believe that 20/20 should do an investigation regarding what goes on behind the counter to offer an explanation of pharmacy error. Then maybe we can then point the fingers and work together to fix the problem!!!
 
Posted by: A CVS Tech | March 31, 2007, 11:30 am 11:30 am
 
It is always wonderful to see how the media takes a negative and turns it into an epidemic. Pharmacist are under high pressure to fill medications at a fast pace because society is always in a rush to do something. What we do is life threating but people seem to think that our job is a joke. We are there to just put pills in a bottle and that is it. You forget to see that when a patient is rung up at the register the technicians also ask if you have any questions for the pharmacist. Your show happily skipped that part and only showed your under cover person signing a paper to waive that right. If it wasn’t for us, people would not be living as long as they are. We catch many critical drug errors and try our best to prevent any harm to occur to a patient. You made it see like it is a joke when an error is made. You should feel horrible for portraying this.
I am sure that the pharmacist involved felt horrible and that their life is ruined because of such a mistake. Just like when you guys make a mistake reporting a story you apologize to the world. You should really apologize to us because we do care about our patients and we do try to do our best to help them. We are not God and neither are you.
 
Posted by: Lou | March 31, 2007, 11:33 am 11:33 am
 
I have told our company that we have a pharmacist who makes 2 miss fills per month and they have not looked into this matter yet.I think the company is waiting until one of our patients dies before they will look into this problem we have.
sign great tech
 
Posted by: suzzie | March 31, 2007, 11:34 am 11:34 am
 
News or Entertainment?
I have been watching the coverage of this story and have to conlcude this has nothing to do with news. If it was news, why not address the issues raised by those in the industry that posted on this site? I am not a pharmacist or technician but they seem to raise valid concerns. Why didn’t we get to see the prescription with the doctor’s handwriting from that lady’s case? Why did we not see the written warnings given to the fake customers or the people suing the pharmacy? This“report”gave most of the time to the lawyers and union representative, not people who actually work in the industry. With that many lawyers helping them write the story/set the agenda you would think Brian Ross could correctly state the law!! Oops was that a mistake? I noted other inconsistencies in the various stories posted on this site (which have either been removed or edited since the story aired–nice touch). Guess Mr. Ross and his team are no better than 16 year olds, they just have better opportunity to cover their tracks. Could it just be a reality that everyone can make mistakes?
 
Posted by: Matt | March 31, 2007, 11:38 am 11:38 am
 
I have been a pharmacy tech for 12 years, and I have been certified for almost 8 years. I have worked in several areas of pharmacy including hospital, long-term care, and retail. The pharmacists depend a lot on techs and if a store hires someone that has no experience in pharmacy then it is the stores responsibility to properly train the tech. They can even send them to take the classes to become certified. I know a lot of stores will pay for this, but it may not be broadcasted. There are things an untrained tech can do in the pharmacy and learn about medication. Job experience is also education! (for the comment about Pharmacists having 6-8 yrs of schooling and have the“experience”needed for the job.)
I never took a pharmacy class. I learned everything I know through experience. I was trained properly then offered a chance from the company I was employed with to take the certification test. I have the confidence of every pharmacist I have ever worked with that I am very capable of filling prescriptions and much more. I always have them check behind me and am not shy about asking questions.
 
Posted by: proud tech 2 | March 31, 2007, 11:47 am 11:47 am
 
Thank you for doing the research on how pharmacy drugs are dispensed. I would like to see the same regarding hospitals dispensing prescriptions to sick patients, many of them unconscious and unable to ask the right questions or know what they are being given. When I was in the hospital after giving birth to my daughter the lady in my room (who also just gave birth) was given an injection. A few minutes later her husband came to visit (he happened to have been a pharmacist) saw the vial on the table and ran to get help. His wife had been given the medication that was meant for a man across the hall that had a terminal illness. Over the years, when I have repeated this incident, many people have come up with their own horror stories. I do believe that hospitals need to be held accountable, and perhaps a survey should be done there.
 
Posted by: Sharon | March 31, 2007, 12:47 pm 12:47 pm
 
Larry, I work at Rite Aid. I have been at one of the locations for 3 years now. I know every customer and love every customer. My pharmacist does stop every thing that she or he is doing to counsel. we do have floater pharmacist too, they would do they and done that too. it does not have to be a smaller independent pharmacy that would do the work better than we do. it depend on who is working in the pharmacy. And to Rite Aid, our Focus is the customer.“WITH US IS IT PERSONAL”. Just a question what would a patient that goes to a small independent do ir they need to get a script on a Sunday or a holiday, let me guess they would come to us. And how about if he ran out of the med while his pharmacy is close, he would come to us to give some tablets of no charge till his pharmacy opens for us to transfer the script.
And to all others, I am really enjoyed reading all the comments. It is funny to see how all of us go almost through the same pressure, and how little do people on the other side of the counter know what happens on our side.
I guess since by Law only pharmacy staff are allowed behind the counter, and I am sure 20/20 crew are not from this staff, so they are not able to know what actually goes on.
thank you
hitawi
 
Posted by: hitawi | March 31, 2007, 12:50 pm 12:50 pm
 
There’s not much I can say that hasn’t been already been said by the many pharmacists and techs that commented before me, but I feel I have to respond to the claims that you are“signing away your right to counseling.”As a third year pharmacy student and intern at a retail chain, everytime I ring out a customer I am required to ask if he or she has any questions. On most occasions the answer is“no”and the customer is asked to sign the line that says“I was offered and declined the opportunity to speak with a pharmacist.”It is my responsibility to ask but if the customer responds without really listening or signs without reading what he is signing, there is nothing I can do. Perhaps if patients would put down their cell phones, shush their screaming children, or stop talking to their friend long enough to listen to what the human being behind the counter was saying, they would know that what your program claimed was a flat out lie.
 
Posted by: amanda | March 31, 2007, 1:45 pm 1:45 pm
 
Interesting article and responses. I especially liked Yvonne Soffer’s comment. She might want to re-visit her pharmacy. After reading her comments, it sounds like she’s off her meds.
 
Posted by: Theodore Salmons | March 31, 2007, 1:47 pm 1:47 pm
 
John I would like to thank you for broadcasting this reports. Mistake is unfortunately an human thing because we are not perfect. I am a licensed pharmacist and has been practicing for almost 3 years. I confronted Doctors who refused to acknowledge mistakes that they made on prescriptions:frightened to report me to my“boss”,told customer to go to another pharmacy,ask if I was a legal worker because of my accent only because I questioned the content of their prescription. Unfortunately the health system became so into business that it will be another political debat. I took a oaf when I graduated from pharmacy school: to be concerned about the welfare of humanity and relief of human suffering my primary concerns.
 
Posted by: kiki | March 31, 2007, 2:29 pm 2:29 pm
 
I work for a major chain as a pharmacist. With the major changes that my company inplemented over the past 3 years, our error rate has been greatly reduced. Again all I see is one sided journalism. Must be a slow news week. What happen, no more news on the late Anna Nicole?
 
Posted by: Wilfred Broussard Jr | March 31, 2007, 2:29 pm 2:29 pm
 
My wife calls pharmacists at two local pharmacies and asks all sorts of questions about the medications that are prescribed for my family. Her constant calling would make any other profession block her calls or refuse to return them. However, they always take the time to answer all of her questions and provide recommendations free of charge. One of them even wrote, Happy Birthday! on a prescription of hers that I picked up that day.
The 20/20 report stated that there was no system in place to catch prescription filling errors. I believe this is totally false. There is software available and in use that prevents errors.
 
Posted by: Carl Williams | March 31, 2007, 3:07 pm 3:07 pm
 
I am a retail pharmacist. I work for one of the large chain stores. I’m sure I can help shed light on some of these issues.
Note: No Pharmacist ever wants to make an error in filling a prescription. Sadly, errors do occur.
Note: The verifying pharmacist is ultimately responsible for what is dispensed to the customer.
 
Posted by: Informed | March 31, 2007, 3:53 pm 3:53 pm
 
To Kerry:
I work at an independent pharmacy. We do not make lots and lots of money.
Insurance companies have cut pharmacies to nothing on alot of medicines. Sometimes we barely make cost on some prescriptions. At a chain I’m sure it’s different because they are
a big company. I hate the mindset that Pharmacists are getting rich. We are filling lots more prescriptions of alot less money.
 
Posted by: photozbykimberly | March 31, 2007, 4:48 pm 4:48 pm
 
I am forced to use a mail in rx by my ins co. After they sent the wrong strength rx for me (copd patient) it took 2 months of back and forth to get it corrected. I also was charged for both because it came in the mail. Someone needs to TAKE SOME GOOD LOOKS AT ALL HEALTH CARE. Ins has become such big business that everyone is suffering from the burden. I am alive and well no thanks to my ins co or mail in pharmacy. Ins refused to pay for correct dosage at local pharmacy. And you wonder why the people who work there get hardened or lax. MONEY IS THE BOTTOM LINE&gt;at Walgreens, cvs, eckerds or anywhere else. Corporate greed both from companys and ins co……we the comsumers need HELP
 
Posted by: Jim Brower | March 31, 2007, 5:15 pm 5:15 pm
 
I can’t believe so many in the Pharm. field are laying blame on patients. Most patients don’t have a medical degree.
If you take your car to the shop to be repaired do you think it’ll fly if the mechanic messed it up and then said,‘you should have checked to make sure I did it right.’
 
Posted by: amy | March 31, 2007, 5:41 pm 5:41 pm
 
Amy, If an auto shop were to fix a flat tire or broken window, you WOULD double check it before you left. The Pharm field is suggesting the same thing. Most pharmacies provide descriptions or pictures of the drug you should be taking. It is simply not that much trouble to look at the medicine.
 
Posted by: Rob | March 31, 2007, 7:21 pm 7:21 pm
 
THE BLAME GAME IS ALWAYS UNPRODUCTIVE. 20/20 may be responsible for having a bias story, but the real issue is how do we make this better for everyone. The patients deserve more and we as pharmacists deserve more to give them.
If this doesn’t change soon there is going to be a growing decline of pharmacists available to serve the population. I would NEVER recomend the study of pharmacy to young kids looking toward there future.
If you’re smart enough to get into pharmacy school be smart enough to go into something else. It’s not worth the money and NO RESPECT from the public, doctors, nurses, and the companies you work for. I plan on changing careers soon.
 
Posted by: Jacob | March 31, 2007, 7:56 pm 7:56 pm
 
Bravo 20/20!
The public has always been led to believe that their
prescription or Intravenous solutions that runs in their veins was filled by a practicing Pharmacist who went to school and earned their Doctor degree. The reality is that the Pharmacy Technician fills 95% of prescription and medication orders, including IV solutions. This
in itself would not be a sign for alarm, except that, Pharmacy Technicians, in several states, including Colorado, need have no prior educational or experience to work in the Pharmacy setting. In fact, the state of Colorado Board of Pharmacy currently does not even
recognize Pharmacy Technicians.
Personally if I were a consumer wanting all that could be done in the prevention of potential medication errors, I would question why this practice exists in which a Pharmacy Technician is filling my prescription order and not the Pharmacist of which I place my trust?
The answer is simply because there is a major shortage of Pharmacists nationwide and the roles of the Pharmacy Technician has changed to more of a dispensing function than simply one who works the cash register.
 
Posted by: Joe Medina | March 31, 2007, 8:08 pm 8:08 pm
 
No one likes to hear negative comments about their profession. I think everyone would agree there are good and bad in all professions. Yes, errors are made and one mistake is one too many! But to not be accountable and take responsibility for your actions is just not right!! It’s not professional. I can’t believe that errors aren’t even tracked. I’m a Registered Nurse who works as a Clincial Manager in home care. We’re always looking at performance improvement, tracking the outcomes of the services we’re providing and what we can do to improve our outcomes. We also look at service recovery for those cutomers who are unhappy for whatever reason.
Someone commented on what they called the“uneducated media.”I don’t think that’s a fair statement at all. The media is educated and are trying to educate not“frighten”the public. The consumer should be an educated consumer paying attention to what each prescription med looks like, the dosage, who the manufacturer is, read the label and the educational material that is provided with the script and ask questions.
I myself was on the receiving end of a Walgreen’s error twice. I received a call from a women who lived in the town next to mine and has the same first and last name as mine (the last name with one letter difference, but said the same way). An unlikely coincidence, but true. She called because the scripts she had just gotten from Walgreen’s had all my personal information on the label and were actually my prescriptions that I had just renewed. They never bothered to check the Date of Birth DOB or address to be sure they had the right patient. This was a violation of HIPPA, my privacy, my personal health information and could have been terrible for her had she not been an educated consumer.
 
Posted by: Cynthia | March 31, 2007, 8:19 pm 8:19 pm
 
All I have to say (being a tech) is“Let me go into anyone else’s place of employment and act as impatient and self rightious as alot of the patients (usually not regulars) who want their scripts yesterday and see how far it gets me”Some of these people actually want to wait in the drive thru for us to complete their orders while they wait.. Listen up people!! It is life or death we are dealing with on a daily basis.. HAVE SOME PATIENTS!! I’m sure you waited along time at the office to see your high cost doctor.. So don’t take it out on the pharmacy emplyees when you come to us for your scripts…Yes we do multitask but that is part of our job.. Not just to fill YOUR prescription in 15 minutes or less…Most of the job is basically STRESSFUL because of the DEMAND of the consumer.. NOT TO LEAVE OUT THE EMPLOYER.. Who doesn’t think a pharmacist working 14 hours should have a break.. Oh and about PAY.. The teenagers can be hired at minimum wage to fill scripts.. Being with a chain company for 9 yrs.. I only make $8.68.. PITYFUL.. But I love my job most days..
 
Posted by: Barb | March 31, 2007, 8:53 pm 8:53 pm
 
I can’t believe the the one-sided hit you delivered to Walgreens. Did someone on your staff have a bad experience there? The Walgreens where I have always received my prescriptions has never failed to ask me if I wanted a consult with the pharmacist. I have never seen the pharmacy open without a pharmacist. When my husband was dying, they delivered the prescriptions to the house. I know that pharmacy techs work in the pharmacy at Walgreens and everywhere else also, except perhaps the small pharmacy where you have one pharmacist and a small number of prescriptions.
I know for a fact that the techs have training and have to pass tests. Whatever they do has to be checked by the pharmacist. There is an extreme shortage of pharmacists. I’m sure that any drug chain would be thrilled to be able to find the pharmacists they needed to have those extra pharmacists available. I really think that your reporting was extrememly biased against Walgreens. I believe that the things you hit them with could have been the same in any pharmacy. The fact that mistakes were made isn’t good for Walgreens or any other pharmacy. I’m sure that Walgreens isn’t the only drug store to make a mistake.
 
Posted by: jan | March 31, 2007, 9:07 pm 9:07 pm
 
I went to college to become a pharmacy technician and recently became certified by the ptcb. I work for a major retailer and in the first three months of employement we have changed pharmacists twice and lost 3 technicians to other jobs. The cashiers are taking on more and more responsibility because we dont have enough hands to accomodate the customers needs. Yes I have seen errors and it is devastating to see it happen. These retailers better start paying better than 8 bucks an hour, and get more mature minded help and being ptcb certified should be made a law. I am going to reach out to my senator to get a law passed so these errors can be minimized. As for the pharmacists, there are some great ones out there that have a love for their patients and want to give them the best service. Its a shame that they have to work under such stress, long hours and screaming impatient customers. I urge all technicians to get ptcb certified and urge your local government to get a law passed in your state that mandates only certified personnel can dispense meds.
 
Posted by: Linda | March 31, 2007, 9:22 pm 9:22 pm
 
Rob, you’ve given painfully obvious examples akin to being handed an empty Rx bottle for comparision. I’m talking about something that requires the skill and education of a certified mechanic, like a transmission or motor rebuild that you can’t check unless you KNOW what to look for, to compare to the skill and education of a pharmacist. No reputable shop would try to blame the client for their mechanic’s mistake regardless of how impatient the client was to have their car back.
The customer bashing….
Make people wait if that’s what it takes. In such a postion of responsiblity there is a duty to insist the safety of the public. That’s kinda the realm of the health care profession. Profits over safety is disgusting and the chains should be ashamed of themselves. However the‘pass the buck’–whining about the customer (who is the reason you have a job) is just wrong. How about ranting to the employer who understaffs. That, and remaining polite and curteous, despite whatever the customer does will get you farther. Most people will chill out and respond in kind if you play nice, but if they sense attitude and a‘you’re a pain in my butt’aura about a worker, that is what you’ll get back.
 
Posted by: amy | March 31, 2007, 10:09 pm 10:09 pm
 
I too am a Pharmacy Technician in Washington State and have sent our President of the WSPA an email and how this program has done a disservice to Pharmacists and Technicians. I feel with the emails i have read the same way and want them to come and see the profession as it really is. I have worked with the best and feel this is a shame as we who work with them see what all they do..
 
Posted by: denise | March 31, 2007, 10:33 pm 10:33 pm
 
With all do respect to ABC and 20/20, you totally missed the ball on this so called“investigation”. I will be graduating from a major university in the coming months and have been nationally and state certified as a pharmacy tech. Do this make me an idiot? No!!! I’m well trained, highly motivated, and only have the patients interests in mind. I work at a major retail chain and my store does around 2500 rx a week. Add to that customers that want their rx filled 30 seconds after they drop it off while they’re talking on their phone, reading a MD’s trouble handwritting correctly, inputing the rx, filling the rx, fixing insurance problems, checking the rx, answering the phone between all these steps, ringing people up at the register. Yeah lets see the folks at ABC NEWS do this job. It’s true that mistakes do happen. I can only say that we are human and that we take every single precaution to assure the correct dispensing of medications. This story is just a punch line intended to get veiwers to watch. It in no way accuratly depicts a typical pharmacy. Why don’t you do a follow up at my store? Come and interview my customers and let’s see what they say about the service we provide. I can assure you ABC, that that investigation would be quite different than the one sided, highly biased trashed you aired on Friday. You say you want to inform the public. How about giving the public the complete picture and allowing them to make there own decisions. That’s reporting ABC, the whole facts and not just one side of the story. How about that, and I’ve never even taken a journalism class. I think if you take the time to read these blogs, you will see that most people agree with me.
 
Posted by: CPhT Tech | March 31, 2007, 10:47 pm 10:47 pm
 
as a pharmacist in retail for the last 23 years, I have worked for am indepent pharmacy, CVS, Eckerd and now a supermarket chain. I can agree with everything said above, and there is plenty of blame to go around, corporations who;s CEO bonus’rely on increased profits so what do they do cut the help that a high paying pharmacist is given and expect exemplary service with less and less help!
14 hr days with no lunch break, while the doctors work 9-5 with a 2 hr lunch…my wekkend shift once constisted of a 11 hr shift on friday, 14 hrs on staurday and 12 hours on sunday, no lunch!! I did not see the program last nite but someone told me that the patients were advised NOT to sign the log and that the fact it is used for insurance purposes as proof and rx was picked up is a LIE!!!….well i am routinely audited by insurance companies and the process includes having the last 2 yrs signature logs ready to show the auditor, why?! because part of his procedure is to check for signatures for EVERY rx he is auditing, and if it is NOT signed the money is taken back by the insurance company, of course they did not mention that on the show…i will be damned if any customer will get any meds from me without signing, no sign, no med!! I will refuse…so 20/20 there are 2 sides to every story so get your facts straight!!!and it is a FEDERAL LAW that every patient be asked at the counter if they have any questions for the pharmacist, no one is skirting that issue,,,and I understand that you did not mention PTCB or that most states now REQUIRE a tech to be certified!!!..you must have went to the George Bush school of investigation…GET THE FACTS for both sides of a story please!!!
 
Posted by: mark | March 31, 2007, 10:47 pm 10:47 pm
 
I enjoyed reading everyones comments, I didn’t watch the show but I work for a pharmacy that was named. I am all for electronic rx, it would help in forgery rx, who doesn’t deal with that.
Saving america 1 rx at a time.
 
Posted by: jd | March 31, 2007, 11:00 pm 11:00 pm
 
I agree completely with Cynthia about pharmacies and pharmacists needing to TAKE RESPONSIBILITY for their errors. I am also an RN and, concerning the poor, overworked, pharmacists who never get potty breaks and have to deal with nasty people all day, I can only say,“Welcome to my hell!”Nurses“get to enjoy”all that and more and ARE held accountable for their mistakes, those of the staff they supervise, remedying those of the doctors, pharmacists, dieticians, housekeeping staff…..and on…and on…RN’s DON’T get to illegally give their patients“a few (you name the drug..INCLUDING narcotics) to get through the weekend”to shut them up without a valid prescription. (I would LOVE to see a 20/20 on THAT!) It is just hideous how pharmacists and pharmacies just get away with this incompetence. Enough with the excuses, already!
 
Posted by: Karen, RN | March 31, 2007, 11:30 pm 11:30 pm
 
I cannot believe what I am reading. I knew people were easily swayed by the media, but to see some people say that they have loyally had their prescriptions filled at a particular pharmacy for 25 years and then after seeing this ridiculous investigative report are not going to go to that pharmacy anymore. That is just plain stupidity! This investigation completely rail-roaded the retail pharmacy industry. The fact that this investigation is trying to tell people that pharmacies are trying to deceive all of its patients is ludicrous!! Why must we always place the blame? You blame the pharmacy tech for filling it wrong, but what about the pharmacist who verifies the prescription? What about the doctors who have worse handwriting than a 2-year-old? Most of the time you need to have some sort of code to decipher what exactly the doctor is trying to communicate to you. I work for a retail pharmacy in a management aspect and every store that I have worked at does everything that it can for the patient. The comment that when you sign for your prescription means that you signing away your legal right to counselling is completely false. I GUARANTEE that if you ever have a question about your prescription, you will NOT find a pharmacist who won’t answer it for you. This whole investigation looked like a personal vendetta, only showing how much wrong happens at retail pharmacies. When you take into account how many prescriptions are actually filled every year in the United States, the percentage of errors pales in comparison, yet somehow, we are still considered the bad guy. You cannot walk into a pharmacy and not see a disgruntled customer screaming at a pharmacist or a pharmacy tech because their prescription couldn’t be filled instataneously or their insurance wouldn’t cover their prescription, which somehow always ends up being our fault even though we have nothing to do with insurance. It’s natural that people are going to make mistakes. There isn’t a single person in the entire world who can say that they have not made a mistake. Is it unfortunate? Yes. Should corrective action have been taken? Yes. I am just simply saying that because there are a few mistakes on occassion does not mean that every pharmacy in the United States is not out to deceive you. We are here to help. All you have to do is ask. It’s that simple. And please, do not base your decision on where to take your prescription based on this report. This is a horrible report by someone who obviously had a bad experience at a retail pharmacy.
 
Posted by: G | April 1, 2007, 12:04 am 12:04 am
 
In Wisconsin, pharmacist are required to and do consult on 100%…yes 100% of prescriptions. Did I mention the patient is consulted on 100% of all prescriptions filled? Please 20/20, if you’re going to investigate, look for the positives and ways for the rest of the country to improve on their dispensing of prescriptions. This takes place at EVERY Walgreens too! Please 20/20 learn how to“investigate.”I had been a 20/20 tivo watcher, but not anymore. To catch a….sounds better!
 
Posted by: jamie | April 1, 2007, 12:49 am 12:49 am
 
I think 20/20 should be ashamed. Yeah their intent was to give a stiry but they have created panic when there is no need for one.
When did it become a retailers resposiblity for a pts health? When did the pt become non responsible for asking questions and checking things.
They expect everything for nothing or next to nothing.
If the cost is to high they want you to call the doctor and change it, now, even ifs 2am.
They expect to get full medical adcvice through lane twos speaker and the patient being in the passinger seat.
They expect you to know their insurance policys copays and drug tiers. They want you to know the interactions of over 10,000 otc and rx items. They expect you to know their health and life style and any other“supplements they use”
Its called communication, patience and understanding. If you want your medicine at a fast food price and time then that is the quility you will get.
Also 20/20 but the blame on walgreens for allowing a 17 year old to fill rxs. The local states set up the laws and The Pharmacy board sets the ratio of Pharm to tech.
If people did not expect so much, instead of helping with their health care, all this bs would go away.
I will never watch another ABC program until its News againces research the stories they put on the air. Check the loacl and state laws. Dont you think if Walgreens was grossly neglagent in that womans case it would cost them less to settle out of court?
This program has created a panic directed toward walgreens, when the panic should be directed to the whole health field.
 
Posted by: Jennyfer 0 | April 1, 2007, 8:10 am 8:10 am
 
I went to Walgreens in Lady Lake, Florida the day after your disturbing report to pick up presciptions filled. The“technician”was having a difficult time explaining Humana’s prescription coverage to an elderly man in line in front of me. When my turn came, I understood why. Her nametag stated she was a Walgreen’s certified photo specialist!
 
Posted by: mary jo | April 1, 2007, 9:01 am 9:01 am
 
The problem isn’t with pharmacies or pharmacists. It’s with a nearly omnipotent“legal”drug cartel (i.e.; GlaxoSmithKline, AstraZeneca, Roche, etc.) that labels every human condition as a treatable illness so they can hawk their dangerous drugs to treat that“illness.”Note; A“cure”would negate the need for such drugs, whereas“treatment”is ongoing w/o end (can you say“cha-CHING!) These pharma companies are so deep in doctor’s pockets, as well, that we can be certain that your doctor does NOT have a your best interest at heart. These aren’t“doctors,”they’re“pharmaceutical company representatives.”This isn’t“medicine,”it’s“quackery.”It’s the same old snake-oil, run through all the legal loopholes.
My own“doctor”endangered my life through a prescription for something as innocuous as heartburn&amp;never corrected the problem, either. After getting fed up with the pointless multitude of tests he was putting me through (for the financial benefit of his company,) I merely stopped taking the prescription he’d given me&amp;by the end of the week, voila! The potentially deadly side-effect had stopped completely.
Open your eyes; we are little more than guinea pigs with wallets.
 
Posted by: Lana | April 1, 2007, 10:53 am 10:53 am
 
I am a Certified Pharmacy Technician in the State of Washington. Technicians in the state I live and work in must be at least 18 years old and have completed a formalized State Board of Pharmacy accredited training program in order to be licensed to perform non discretionary duties in the pharmacy. This type of sensational“investigative”reporting does speak volumes about way we practice pharmacy in the United States both from the professional side and the patient/customer perspective.
I would be excited to see some comments logged from customers willing to share their stories about how they contribute to the frustration felt by technician’s every day. Probably won’t happen…Contrary to popular belief we DO NOT come to the counter to tell you your insurance would not pay for your prescription just to“make your day horrible”. Trust me it makes doing our job just a bad.
AND Leave the 16 year old technicians alone! What states are we talking ablut here? I am disappointed in 20/20 that they did not interview any of the CEO’s that ultimately call the shots. Were they“unavailable for comment”. How unfortunate. You have effectively caused a sensationalized media event that will end up causing the Pharmacy Associations across the country to spend inordinate amounts of time and energy defending a profession that has as its purpose,“to serve the public with patient centered care”when their efforts should only be concerned with that same care.
 
Posted by: Becky S | April 1, 2007, 2:29 pm 2:29 pm
 
I want to challenge 20/20 to air a segment on reporting a solution to this problem. The market share may not be a big, but it would surely elevate your program above the rest. It would shout out incredible UNBIASED reporting. Come on Diane (Sawyer), help the pharmacy profession educate patients on how they can be part of“their own”total care. Interview the pharmacist who SAVED a life from counseling a patient about their medication. Interview the technicians who pass the PTCB exams and conduct themselves like the professionals that they are.
You can do this 20/20! Make a real difference!!
 
Posted by: Becky S | April 1, 2007, 2:52 pm 2:52 pm
 
First off my condolences to the families affected by these errors. My heart goes out to you. With that said I feel that the 20/20 piece was very one sided. It’s been pointed out in many comments here that pharmacists are making interventions everyday to prevent errors and that is so true.
Here are my feelings:
1.)I think all of these patients who come in and bitch at the pharmacist and the techs because they may have to wait a half hour for their script should watch the 20/20 piece so then maybe it will give them some perspective of why we shouldn’t be treatd like a fast food restaraunt.
2.) The companies (Wal-Greens, CVS, etc) may try and say that they care about the patient. That is BS! The bottom line (profit) is what they care about.
Techs are under paid, stores are understaffed. The corporations use # of scripts filled per hour as a measuring stick to determine how many tech hours a pharmacy will get (it is usually like 1 hour for every 10 perscriptions). This does not take into account time for answering phones, ringing up customers who may have purchased other non-pharmacy items, insurance issues, and counseling of patients.
The environment sucks in a retail pharmacy. Pharmacists are on their feet all day, phones ringing nonstop, people yelling about having to wait for their script, no lunch break so you have to eat while you work, and god forbid you need to hit the restroom.
 
Posted by: marc | April 1, 2007, 5:18 pm 5:18 pm
 
Dear investigative reporters;
As a licensed and practicing pjarmacist in the state of New York this topic is obviously of extreme importance to me, my family and my colleagues. The problem is solely dur to high volume of prescriptions being thrown at each and every practicing pharmacist.
In one day a pharmacist can be required, demanded, forced to fill several hundred prescriptions. That allows for only a couple of minutes per each prescription. My question to you is: Wouldn’t you want a pharmacist to spend more than just one or two minutes on your or your family members prescription. Just think, if you can imagine, a pharmacist is forced-in just a couple of minutes-to ensure all customer personal information is correct, check for interactions between all other medications the customer is already on, enter all information is typed in correctly from the doctors original prescription, pick the correct medicatin form a pharmacy stock of tens of thousands of medications, and then apply the most most time consuming part: insurace information, which is 9 out ten times a problem. Correting insurace information in iteslf takes several minutes-per customer.
The problem lies in staffing. How to correct this dangerous issue? Each and every state must create laws dictating the amount of prescriptions that a pharmacist can fill per hourly period. This shall certainly ensure accurate presription fills ensuring greater public safety. It comes down to state boards of pharmacy passing laws controling the number of prescriptions that a licensed pharmacist can fill per hourly period.
g in the trenches where the medication errors occur.
 
Posted by: Brian | April 1, 2007, 6:15 pm 6:15 pm
 
I have been a pharmacy technician for over four years. I have been certified for almost two. I am now a pharmacy student. First and for most it was, and in every case is always, the pharmacists responsibility to catch the medication errors. Pharmacists I have talked to on this matter agree with me completely on this. Pharmacists go to school for 6 years 4 of which are Pharmacy school. If it were not for technicians there would be far more errors than there are now. There are some pharmacies in my area that do over 300 prescriptions a day with just one pharmacist.
In some states the law is two uncertified technicians per pharmacist. That is very much needed in any pharmacy setting. A good pharmacist would have caught any errors that the technician might have made.
Patients themselves also need to be responsible for their own medication as well. Patients need to know the strength and name of the medication that they are on, as well as what it is for. If they cannot remember their medications then they need to have them written down to refer to them when needed. This would also help fatal errors from happening. If a patient knows what medication they are on and thinks it looks different than before….DONT TAKE IT and call your pharmacist for advise.
Also I hope everyone now knows that it takes longer than 10 minutes to fill prescriptions because unlike popular belief we just dont throw pills in a bottle and slap a lable on it. Which is a comment that is made everyday!
 
Posted by: Erica | April 1, 2007, 7:10 pm 7:10 pm
 
I am a pharmacist. I am glad you did the story. I feel that my profession has been robbed from me because of current way pharmacy is being conducted by the large chains. Your report is accurate. big bussiness is trying to get rid of pharmacists and replace us with pharmacy tech’s. As this continues to happen,and as pharmacists are bullied to keep working faster and faster, you can expect more of the same. All pharmacy chains value thier tech’s more than thier pharmacists because pharmacy tech’s work for less money therefore the CEO’s of these chains can make more profit’s for themselves at everyone else’s expense.
 
Posted by: CB | April 1, 2007, 8:59 pm 8:59 pm
 
As a pharmacist, I did feel the report was one-sided and did not focus on some of the truly life-saving interventions pharmacist make. However, it is a real eye-opener to us a profession and to our employers that the practices the public expects of us are not in play as required by our profession and state regulatory boards. I am also just amazed at my colleagues’comments on the patient should take responsilibilty. They are not the drug experts, we are! As medical professionals we ASSUME the lay public would know what to do and should not! I don’t a plumber come over and ask a million questions how to fix my toilet….I just want it fixed with out a problem. Same with most patients…they want their medical conditions treated without harm. For as good as drugs are to treat and cure disease, every pharmacist surely remembers lectures in school about the fine line between efficacy and toxicity. Drugs are recognized by our bodies as“toxins”…and if taken incorrectly or with contraindications or other drugs, foods, and herbal supplements, tragic outcomes can and do result.
Instead of whining about the reality of the feature, I think pharmacists should do some self reflection. Work at a pace that you feel provides safety and if the employers don’t like it, quit. As we all know, we can walk and find another $100,000 job tomorrow. Simple economics: supply and demand, and with united demands on more pharmacist versus technicians we can make a difference.
 
Posted by: Richard | April 1, 2007, 9:34 pm 9:34 pm
 
Regarding the issue of the cashier not catchinga drug interaction (Coumadin®/aspirin):
1) It is not a cashier’s or even a pharmacy technician’s responsibility to inspect OTC sales, in fact, many pharmacies don’t even have a cash register in the pharmacy department. 2) The pharmacist doesn’t come home with the patient and snoop through their medicine cabinet, so the patient needs to be completely forthcoming about any OTC products being used if they desire this level of service.
3) Under some circumstances, some patients do take Coumadin with aspirin, this just requires careful monitoring on the part of the patient’s doctor.
 
Posted by: - | April 1, 2007, 10:39 pm 10:39 pm
 
Yep, retail pharmacists are asked to perform an impossible job…they have to be 100% right all the time (including catching doctors’mistakes), dealing with no breaks, illegible scripts, medicaid and insurance issues, butt-insky managers, and cranky customers (not to mention being subjected to armed robbery).
Yep, there is a pharmacist shortage. (wonder why???)
Yep, I’m a pharmacist. I COULD make good money as a retail pharmacist.
Nope. I don’t. It’s not worth it, for all the reasons described above.
I’d like to correct one thing, tho. The techs don’t“dispense”prescriptions. They can put the pills in the bottle, but that’s not“dispensing.”The pharmacist whose initials appear on the label“dispensed”it, whether or not he or she actually touched the bottle or its contents.
 
Posted by: J | April 1, 2007, 10:43 pm 10:43 pm
 
THIS IS RIDICULOUS!
I’ve worked in many pharmacies for years. People don’t realize how much pressure there is in this job. And there is a lot more to it then just‘counting pills’. The people who say that should try working in a pharmacy. They probably couldn’t handle one day. Ignorant fools.
Many mistakes are from the doctor’s office,(which they never admit too).
Here’s the problem. There is a big shortage of health care in the U.S. and the owners of the hospitals and pharmacys keep the staffing down to try to make money. Most mistakes that I’ve seen have been due to slopply handwritting by the doctor. The other is when the person is yelling at the staff to get everything done. People are just too rude and demanding. That only makes mistakes more likely to happen.
Would you yell at someone cutting your hair stylist while they’re cutting your hair? Your dentist when he’s doing a root canal? Then why do people take everything out on the pharmacy staff? I’ve worked with a few staff memebers that have had heart attacks from the stress of the job. And many had nervous breakdowns. THIS IS NOT A JOKE. The stress put on pharmacy staff is unhuman. And believe me, the pharmacy staff knows how important it is not to make a mistake. It’s reinforced constantly. The real morons are the people that yell at innocent people without trying to understand the system. You have know idea how hard we try. I agree with everything‘Erica’said before me.
This whole thing is insulting to hard working ethical people. Aim it at the system or the people in charge.
 
Posted by: ryan | April 2, 2007, 12:15 am 12:15 am
 
I don’t know about other pharmacies but the log that you sign at my pharmacy is in no way related to patient rights…. it is an ins. log showing your medication was picked up….
 
Posted by: CM | April 2, 2007, 12:33 am 12:33 am
 
I have a suggestion that might alleviate this situation. Having recently visited a third world country I observed a low tech approach. I noticed my elderly parents were taking various medications for diabetes, high blood pressure, cholesterol etc. However there was very little chance for error since the pills were dispensed in their manufacturers original labelled bubble pack cards with the name and strength clearly marked. When it was time to take a pill they cut it from the card and took it. Also it was much easier to load a pill dispenser if used. Even with failing eye sight they were able to recognize which pill they were taking. There were no loose pills to deal with either at the pharmacy or at home. Since there were no pill boxes the pills remained moisture proof and uncontaminated until taken. Also it was much easier to count at the pharmacy since the pills came in cards containing ten or twenty pills. Why dont we try this over here–might actually save some money.
 
Posted by: cecil | April 2, 2007, 8:06 am 8:06 am
 
I have been a pharmacist for 5 years, i work in a hospital full time and for CVS part-time. IT is amazing how the same issues occur all over the country. We are treated as fast food joints, patients want the meds as fast as possible, putting pressure on workers including tech and ringers make workers angry, nervous, etc,, its just human nature to respond, and that’s when potiential errors can occur. Although i have learned to block out difficult customers and focus on whats at hand. Patients should check everyone including doctors, i cant tell you how many times i have caught prescription errors at CVS, and i dont even want to get into what happens in hospitals! Iam sure many of you know how some physicians prescribe antibiotics?Patients must ask questions, they must know what they are taking especially when they leave their doctors office. Everyone makes errors, it impossible to say that no one makes errors, we must check each other, doctors, nurses, pharmacists, tech’s–thats what healtcare is all about. I think retail will suffer in the next 10 years, pharamcists cannot work the way retail is set up now, if we didnt have to deal with insurance problems, like hospitals, retail would be a different world, but we all know that will never go away! Let just say drive-through is the down fall of our profession in retail!! we are treated nothing more than Mcdonalds when patients drive up, how can you discuss pharmacy issues over a microphone of through a window? iam lucky enough in NY many stores do not have drive up windows, i know many other places in the country do. I think they should be banned from ALL pharmacies!!
 
Posted by: Frank | April 2, 2007, 9:00 am 9:00 am
 
Everyone involved is hurt when reporters misundertand present events that they do not fully understand in a sensational expose. One of the more inflammatory comments made in the 20/20 report on pharmacies pertains to the pharmacist’s“Duty to Counsel.”
In reality, the law requires that the pharmacy make an OFFER to counsel a patient on the medications. There is no requirement that the pharmacist must counsel all patients, although the laws state that a registered pharmacist must be present and available to answer questions per the patient’s request. Furthermore, as a pharmacist, I have seen that the vast majority of patients answer“no”when asked wether they“have any questions for the pharmacist.”
By stating that a patient“signs away the right to counseling”is sensational journalism that misinforms patients. This is the type of reporting that creates public outcry and reactionary policy-making. Pharmacists are misrepresented to the public, Patients are misinformed, the journalists loose credibility (but sure make a buck when the ratings rise…scare tactics work!), and politicians make bad laws in response.
The journalists should have read the state and federal statutes regarding pharmacy. If you really want to inform patients, encourage them to anwer“yes”when asked if they have any questions for the pharmacist and to not increase demand for faster pharmacy services.
The pharmacy is not a candy store.
 
Posted by: MiamiPharmD | April 2, 2007, 10:01 am 10:01 am
 
This type of one sided journalism is doing much more of a disservice to patients and consumers than providing them with accurate and trustworthy information. You should go on air and show the positives and make a formal apology.
 
Posted by: Marie | April 2, 2007, 10:24 am 10:24 am
 
As a pharmacy tech for 3 years I must say that this really disappointed me because of the fact that on a daily basis I see customers screaming at us to fill their prescription and that 15 minutes and far too long to wait. I’ve tried to explain the process of entering the prescription and making sure we don’t screw it up on them and all they care about is catching the next flight to their vacation destination. Also, as stated by another viewer, I must agree that the pharmacist catches many mistakes made by the doctor. I am constantly calling the office and trying to speak with a doctor to confirm the directions and dosage of prescriptions given. Also, many times by the PATIENT I am told“oh I dont need those papers”(the ones with all the interaction information/warning packages) so they get tossed into the trashcan. I’m sorry but if the customer is refusing this information then they have no right to complain if something comes out of it. I agree with the viewer of suggesting a better look at what the pharmacist does FOR the patient…the pharmacy I work at is 24/7.. how many doctors can you call at 3am to find out if you can take over the counter cough meds for whatever you might be on for a prescription? I think none…or you have to wait 3 hours to get a call back when the doctor finally wakes up and punches into work. Before you do anymore harping I suggest you get the FULL story…….
dissapointed viewer…
 
Posted by: concerned pharm tech | April 2, 2007, 11:49 am 11:49 am
 
Cecil- that is an excellent idea. Sometimes the dose on the pill is printed so small or faintly many people can’t read it. So they can’t check strengthes.
We can come with other ways of child proofing. Those bottles are horrible and my kids can open them easier than I can.
—-
The paper I’ve been asked to sign at the phamacy counter has to do with HIPPA and to show the med was picked up by who. This helps catch errors, but after the fact when somone has time to enter the codes and check against inventory. The clipboard really should have a cover sheet, considering HIPPA but it doesn’t.
Sometimes I’m asked if I have Q’s, not always. About half the time I am asked there is a heavy implication that they really don’t want you to and they don’t have time.
I must live in a polite area because I have never seen anyone yelling or being huffy at the pharmacy. Just sitting in chairs waiting. Most people drop of or have it called in and come pick it up later on the home from work. I give 24 hours to fill our scripts so they aren’t rushed, hopefully. The people being jerky are probably being jerky to everyone else too. I doubt they singled the pharmacy out for their jerkiness. We all get the joy of dealing with them.
 
Posted by: amy | April 2, 2007, 11:52 am 11:52 am
 
I think it’s hilarious that people are saying that it’s the pharmicists and tech’s fault for the prescriptions being filled wrong. I can’t even begin to tell you how many times the pharmicists I work with have to call doctors to tell them that the dose they have prescribed is either the wrong dose or the wrong drug all together. How about you do an undercover report on how pharmacy personnel are treated that would open everyone’s eyes to how many people are addicts and junkies. I know there are many people out there that need these drugs and that’s fine but I have been called some of the worst names you could ever call someone all because I would not fill a FAKE prescription for a junkie. People need to start treating pharmacy employees with more respect and not hassle them when they are trying to fill your prescription because mistakes are made when someone is being loud and obnoxious because it’s taking 20 minutes to fill the prescription not because the pharmicist doesn’t know what they are doing.
 
Posted by: Brandon | April 2, 2007, 12:21 pm 12:21 pm
 
I am a pharmacy technician for a big chain store. i am certified which was required by my company and any cost concerning the certification is provided by my company. while there is a need for patient care there is a demand by the customers for unrealistic wait times in the pharmacy. it is not a fast food restaurant it is a place of health care. some customers when asked to come back in 15 minutes they yell and get upset that it could not be sooner. each script needs its own attention and when customers dont understand that it can lead to errors and stress on the pharmacy staff. i see someone else mentioned the drive thru. that again is another distraction for the staff with the window buzzing and the customers walking up to the window banging on it and the customers inside screaming. no one knows the stress and aggrivation until they are behind that counter!! Not for nothing they would not treat their doctors the way they treat their pharmacists.
 
Posted by: Ronnie | April 2, 2007, 1:44 pm 1:44 pm
 
I watched this episode on television the other night. Your story states not all people who wear lab coat behind the counter are Pharmacists. That is true. However, in Washington State, every Pharmacy Technician MUST pass a Washington State Board of Pharmacy approved training program before practicing. The person must be a minumum of 18 years old, have a High School Diploma or GED and pass an extensive criminal background check before a candidate may be considered for the program.
Additionally, Pharmacists are tremendously overworked and underpaid for their education and responsibilities. They are the second most educated individuals next to physicians (I bet no one knew you had to have a Doctorate degree in Pharmacy to practice here in WA). Large chain drugstores need to look at this story and heed it’s warning. Any person in any field who is forced to work 12 to 14 hour days with no relief, up to sometimes 7 days a week is going to make a mistake. I am not trying to make excuses; however, you must understand if Pharmacists are not given the breaks they need and are expected to 300 rx’s a shift, things can be overlooked due to stress.
 
Posted by: Kathryn Brown, CPhT | April 2, 2007, 1:52 pm 1:52 pm
 
This story was an appalling example of investigation and reporting. Using a few (admittedly devastating) examples of mistakes is misleading, millions of prescriptions are filled correctly. Mistakes happen in every field, and placing the blame on the technicians and pharmacists is wrong. They’re doing their job, and never intentionally setting out to hurt their patients. What does it matter if a technician worked at a fast-food job previously, I bet there’s people on the crack-team at 20/20 that worked jobs in high school to (and I bet some of them even were 16 before!). That doesn’t matter, it doesn’t make them incompetent.
The story implied that the pharmacy chains are to blame by expanding too quickly, and they need to hire more pharmacists. Our country is in a shortage of pharmacists, because of its insatiable appetite for drugs. If drugs were any less convenient to acquire, there would be public outrage and your story would, instead, be about why we need more pharmacies, and look at the devastating health problems caused by not being able to buy drugs.
 
Posted by: Scott | April 2, 2007, 1:55 pm 1:55 pm
 
A few points from a CPhT intending to enter Pharmacy school:
1) Catching an error is ultimately the pharmacist’s responsibility.
2) Pharmacy staff are required to be 18 years of age.
3) There simply are not enough registered pharmacists to fully staff all pharmacies.
4) Techs are NOT paid enough by chains. This results in high rate of turnover and lots of lesser trained associates behind the counter.
I have been yelled at, cursed out, even threatened with bodily harm because a script took too long to fill or a doctor denied refills. I have seen techs and even a pharmacist or two reduced to tears after the abuse they received from patients angry about insurance copays, wait times, etc. I have dealt with drug addicts acting up, patients that speak little or no English and even patients accusing ME of trying to KILL them because their insurance won’t cover their medication and they can’t afford the cost.
Would you endure all that for $8 an hour? Oh, wait…you have to pay $120 to take a certification exam in order to get a raise so that you can make THAT much. I started at $6.50 an hour. NO insurance or benefits for me, either.
I’m still there because I’m fascinated by the work. I consider pharmacy a respectable profession that I can be proud of joining upon completing my 6 years of school. It pays well, but if you work in retail there is a LOT of abuse you take, both at the hands of the corporations and the hands of the patients. What make that harder to bear in my opinion is that the patients often have legitimate complaints, despite the fact that they are often directed at the wrong person.
 
Posted by: Tech in NC | April 2, 2007, 2:40 pm 2:40 pm
 
I am a CPhT at a retail pharmacy. I do love my job, what i do is important. I worked hard to become certified. Our job isnt simply filling vials. The above statements somewhat explain the conditions we work under, not always pretty. However people are impatient. No, we cannot just‘go get the medicine off the shelf’and give it to you. No matter what the med is, it requires the same attention every other script gets. We WANT to get your meds asap to you. We know you need it, we know your in pain…but so are the other 300 people who just called in, dropped off or got faxed a new script in the last half hour! WE have to make sure you script is correct, your doctor is not perfect, we are not perfect, the nasty RNs who THINK their doctors, are not perfect. We do however try to work together as your TOTAL HEALTH CARE PROVIDERS to make you better. Have no meds left and no refills but you want them now? We have to get the ok from your dr! This can take 2 days to get back! Is it friday at 6 pm? You probably wont get your ok till mon or tues. You should have been prepared and called about the medicine YOU MUST TAKE EVERYDAY, yesterday for that approval! Take responsibility for yourself, people. Stop bitching at us! We are trying the best we can but you want it faster..faster…faster!! And the drive thru is helpful for those who have trouble getting around.. not for you lazy impatient people who think its a fast food drive thru. Sometimes we have to deal with insurance or a drug interaction in the drive, it may take a while but we would give you the exact same attention if you needed it. So have some patients with your local pharmacy, we are there to HELP YOU!
 
Posted by: CPhT | April 2, 2007, 4:30 pm 4:30 pm
 
I am a pharmacist with 34 years experience. My question is of a legal nature. Where did the“undercover producers”get the prescriptions they presensted to these pharmacies? Did those with Coumadin Rx’s obtain their Rx by explaining their“undercover operation”to a physician willing to write the Rx for this purpose? Under what rock did you find these physicians? Can you say“prescription fraud”? And who can justify obtaining fraudulent prescriptions for this purpose? What became of all those tablets, capsules, elixirs, etc. that were obtained during your“sting”operation? Into whose hands were they ultimately entrusted? Where are those meds now?
 
Posted by: K. Ray | April 2, 2007, 5:11 pm 5:11 pm
 
I applaude your story, and I work for one of the big chain Pharmacies named. I was hired as a Pharmacy technician because I was willing to work for the pay they offered. The mistakes I’ve seen made, are also caused by the fact that a shortage of Pharmasists means that our two registered pharmasists have to work 12 hour shifts, becauses the sore if open for 12 hours most days and 8 hours on weekends. When one of our Pharmasists got so sick he couldn’t even remain on his feet, the other pharmasist had to be called in to work seven days a week until the ill pharmasist was able to come back to work.
Yesterday we were e-mailed and told to pull all Zelnorm off the shelves, no reason why, just told to do it. Even the Pharmasists were unaware of the reason. I did a web search to learn the reason for the American recall. However, no mention of the patiests for whom I’ve filled Zelnorm scripts in the last week has been mentioned. Since I’ve asked what we were going to do, and no one at the store level has any idea. The District Manager will e-mail Corporate for instructions.
The corporate mentality of profit and listing things for the employee’s to‘sell’seems to have out stripped the emphasis on making sure all prescriptions are filled right!
 
Posted by: J. Christopher | April 2, 2007, 6:02 pm 6:02 pm
 
Karen, RN–
Illegally giving patients a few medicines to get them through the weekend? That just shows your ignorance of the law. Most states have an emergency supply law built in. It has been known since pharmacy was regulated that no doctor’s office bothers to call back. Therefore, we are allowed to dispense a supply to the patient of a medicine once we are able to obtain that the patient was taking that medicine, and that the medicine was meant to be continued by the doctor. Usually that means we have to read sloppy handwriting and discuss with the patient why they are taking the medicine and determine that on our own, because, yes we were trained in disease state management just like the docs. But you bring up a good point. In order for us to do this, we have to TALK TO THE PATIENT. But we don’t do that according to the story. Geez…conflicting information going on here.
 
Posted by: PharmD | April 2, 2007, 6:09 pm 6:09 pm
 
A couple of thoughts.
1)Counseling is important. Very. If you feel that you aren’t getting the offer, ask. If you aren’t answered in a way you like, go to a new pharmacy to a pharmacist who cares. I love getting to know the customers who ask questions. They are usually the ones who get better in their disease states because they care. Pharmacists get jaded over time, me included. No one wants to talk to you, they want you to shut up and give you their pills. You feel bad at night for thinking that way but it’s been reinforced over years of experience. You come out of school wanting to talk to everyone, then you get cussed out by not only the person you talk to, but others who see you aren’t at your computer screen. I mean thats exactly why I spent 7 years of my life to get Dr. in front of my name, so I could get cussed back into my little computer space. I miss talking to patients, but very few ever say yes they want to talk.
2)Why is it that“1-hour photo”never gets questioned, but“20 minute prescriptions”takes too long????
 
Posted by: Aaron | April 2, 2007, 6:23 pm 6:23 pm
 
What do you expect when people treat their pharmacy like it was fast food service? Or when we can’t keep pharmacy techs because of the low pay combined with constant abuse by customers?
Throw in the fact that the stores are more concerned about you ringing up Sudafed sales than they are in treating the pharmacy staff as professionals.
 
Posted by: Dezel | April 2, 2007, 6:41 pm 6:41 pm
 
This broadcast is concerning…. I have a quick question, why did the pediatrician write for a tablet to be dispensed to a 7 month old infant? An oral phenobarbital solution would have prevented this error. Why is that doctor not held accountable for his role in the error&gt;
 
Posted by: anonymous | April 2, 2007, 6:53 pm 6:53 pm
 
I have been a pharmacist for 15 years and I am very upset that so many people are trying to blame techs for things that are not correct or this or that. I feel that my operation does not work well without them. I am also upset that they are treated less than pharmacist when they are so important and 1/2 of you will agree that a percentage of all drug stores are ran with techs. If that is the case why do we pay them so much less and and treat them as if they are not educated at all. The next time you fill a prescription think about if you did not have a tech how much more you would have to do.
Derek
 
Posted by: derek | April 2, 2007, 6:57 pm 6:57 pm
 
It is a wonderful problem facing Americans. With so much more demand placed on an already overburdened health-care system it is little surprise that mistakes can be found. Granted that some mistakes may be blatent, I have worked in pharmacy for more than 7 years and yet to find a pharmacist or technician who was less than anxiously interested in seeking our patients best interest. Oftentimes their time and extra efforts to seek solutions to our customers go unheralded and unappreciated. How many times a day I as a pharmacist go above what would be considered my“duty”to save a customer money, headache, time, concern, worry, and also then give answers, help, a listening ear, good cheer, extra help, donations, calling the insurance company for them, billing medicare, accepting assignment, giving some meds to help“get buy”until the doctor gives refill OK’s, offer drug consulting, disease state modifications, pharmacotherapy recommendations, interaction checks. These are above and beyond all the rigorous demands of doctors, nurses, customers, employees, bosses, insurance companies, this is all when we as pharmacy personel feel good, great, or catch the miserable cold every customer brings in their prescription or seek help with over-the-counter remedies. Granted we are in a unique position to seek the best interest in assuring accurate medication for our customers. Every pharmacy personel I remember working with was keenly interested in that very fact. Additionally, if in the poor event there ever was a mistake made, that shook up the pharmacist or technician terribly. Not one pharmacist did I ever know who was arrogant, rude, uncaring, or without regard to the best care of the patient, whether or not we achieved great accuracy or misfilled. Pharmacist’s are not the embodiment of perfection. Human as you we carry with us a love of life and a desire to protect life, cure or prevent disease, protect patient privacy, encourage compliance, ease burdens, lift patients spirits and if possible provide a living while doing all of this. Please, recognize pharmacists are people like you, who go home to their families and friends everyday and then in the morning put on their coat saying they are a pharmacy professionals. No matter the size of a drug store, people work in it. Yes there are corporate people who are bean counters who may believe otherwise, whose interest is not in the patients happiness, but all in all pharmacists and technicians are caring people whose best and foremost interest is in helping people like you and me be healthy and happy, so we all can enjoy our families and our lives to the fullest.
 
Posted by: CJ | April 2, 2007, 6:59 pm 6:59 pm
 
i did not have the opportunity to view youre segment on pharmacy. however i am a pharmaceutical technician of over 23 years and am nationally certified through certified pharmacy technicians which requires a proctor test. i will tell you there is no extra incentive or pay when you take this test. you, the individual are required to pay for all of the upkeep of these fees and the test on youre own. what the retail situation is i do not know, but i do know because physicians are not required by law to be informed of pharmaceuticals, they only have to take one semester of pharmacology, they the physicians are the prescriber, if it werent for the pharmacists or the technicians, many of the errors are caught before they are dispensed. that is because the pharmacist calls the m.d. and clarifies the prescriptions. the pharmacy is youre second line of defense in the changing world of medicine. you can contact me at the above email address. ps, since i have been a pharmacy technician for these many years the pharmacists that i work with trust me for a double check. there are many checks in the hospital environment
 
Posted by: mary | April 2, 2007, 8:21 pm 8:21 pm
 
As a Doctor of Pharmacy student weeks away from graduation, I find your portrayal of the profession I am dedicating my life to pursuing incredibly one-sided and short-sighted. Not only did you include misleading information in your report, your“investigation”never reveals exactly what you feel constitutes a prescription error. Some issues in your report: 1. Under federal law (OBRA-90), the only patients I am legally required to provide consultation to are Medicaid patients with new prescriptions. Fortunately, I live in a state where the state law requires that I counsel ALL patients, Medicaid, insured and uninsured on EVERY prescription they pick up, both new AND refill. While this system catches many potential problems, including people taking medications incorrectly and potential drug interactions, I can’t even count the number of complaints I have heard from patients regarding the fact that they have to wait for the pharmacist. I often hear,“I’ve been taking this for years–I don’t have any questions”and yet when asked simply how they feel the medication has been working, I hear,“well, I don’t know.”If you are picking up a prescription, please pay attention to what the pharmacist is telling you! That cell phone call can wait–this is your health, so take an active interest! Pay attention to the appearance of your medication and if something doesn’t look right, call or stop in and ask. Pharmacists want you to be safe while taking medications that can be potentially life-saving and are available for questions–just ask! 2. The signature you are asked for at the register really is for proof of your receipt of HIPAA information or proof of purchase for your insurance. While many states do have a waiver for consultation, generally the offer to counsel must always be made. So when you hear,“Do you have any questions for the pharmacist?”and you do, say yes. If you say no, you have just declined consultation. 3. Pharmacy technicians serve this profession in more ways than I can name. They deserve more respect and better treatment than they got from your story and than they get from patients every day. Portraying them as uneducated high school students does a disservice to the highly trained and nationally certified technicians that work in pharmacies nationwide. Without pharmacy technicians, the seven years I just spent in school would guarantee me a job doing nothing more than counting, licking and sticking all day long and would leave me no time for the counseling your report so desperately desires. So please, when you stop into your pharmacy, pay attention to what the staff really does for you. Then, thank them. In closing, here are a few tips for people to improve their pharmacy experience:
1. Know your medications, know your pharmacist!–I do my best to make sure you know if a prescription has changed or if the medication looks different, but you can help if you know what you’re used to taking. Also, fill all your prescriptions at one pharamcy. That way, I can check your profile for potential drug interactions and know I am seeing everything. Remember, if I don’t know you’re taking it, I can’t make sure you are safe.
2. Know your insurance. The pharmacy did not set the price on your prescription, your insurance company did. If you’ve got an issue with the co-pay or price, take it up with them–don’t take it out on the pharmacy staff.
3. If you’ve got a pressing appointment, please just drop off your prescription and pick it up later. That way both it and you can get the attention you deserve, when you have more time.
4. Please pay attention to the number of refills you have remaining (printed on your bottle, usually on the lower left). If you come in and I need to contact your doctor, you WILL be waiting until I hear back. So save yourself the trip and call in advance when you see you are out of refills. Then I can have your renewal waiting for you when you do come in (at least 24 hours later).
5. Ask me when you have questions about your prescriptions or over-the-counter items. I am more than happy to help and will do my best to answer your questions. If I look busy, still ask! Helping patients is what I went to school for and honestly makes my day better.
6. Do me the courtesy of getting off your cell phone when you are picking up or dropping off your prescription. Do you have phone conversations during your doctor’s appointment?
7. If you want to learn more about how prescriptions are filled, ask at your local pharmacy. Discover how much education and training your pharmacy staff has and how much knowledge they have to share.
 
Posted by: Nicole, 2007 PharmD Candidate | April 3, 2007, 12:20 am 12:20 am
 
I would really like 20/20 to put a hidden camera in a busy pharmacy and see the abuse we get daily. I can’t understand why people think their prescriptions are like picking up a burger or a star bucks.They don’t need insurance for that
 
Posted by: carrie | April 3, 2007, 12:36 am 12:36 am
 
I wish that 20/20 would follow up this story by putting a camera in a busy pharmacy. I bet if your insurance had to ok that big mac you’re picking up they would have a problem too. This is not fast food people. I recently had to go to URGENT CARE for an injury and the sign said“your wait time is 2.5 hours”hmmm URGENT CARE. That’s when I decided I have to stop beating myself up to get people their rx’s in 15 minutes. We are under staffed and under paid but we do the best that we can because we do not like problems either. It makes it hard for the pharmacy staff as well. This is health care! Where else can you go for treatment in 15 minutes? I really like my customers
and have empathy for them but we have to do all the steps to get the right drug for you and deal with your insurance and drug interactions etc. I can’t tell you how many times I have had people ask me“how can you possibly read this”I don’t think that you want us to guess do you? So please try to understand and go do some errands and give us the time to fill your rx the way it is supposed to get you better. I am a cerified pharmacy technician and I have to do continuing education every year and I take pride in what I know, so please try to look at that side of it.
 
Posted by: kathy | April 3, 2007, 12:59 am 12:59 am
 
Amy–From a post way back–I never said that Pharmacists should be free of blame. When an error occurs, it is usually the pharmacy’s fault. Problems are bound to happen when humans are involved, and that won’t ever change in any profession. Having said that, the customer has the ability to double check the prescription WITHOUT a Pharmacy degree or advanced training. My examples given earlier (an auto shop fixing a window) are still valid. Most customers now have pictures and descriptions of the pills you’re supposed to take. Look at the pills in your hand and see if they’re the same.
The Auburn experts who did the study on 20/20 seem to agree:
The Auburn experts says patients can help avoid a prescription error by taking the following steps:
-Know what you’re taking and why. The information can help the pharmacist determine the medication in case of poor handwriting or difficulties reaching the doctor.
-Many prescriptions now come with a physical description written on the vial. Compare what’s in the bottle to the description.
Again, I’m not putting all the blame on the patients. Patients should simply exercise due diligence.
 
Posted by: Rob | April 3, 2007, 1:57 am 1:57 am
 
Pharmacists make 100,000+ a year and are under paid for the abuse they take from the uneducated public aid people bringing in their prescriptions at cost the state hundreds of dollars and they pay a 1 dollar copay or no copay.
 
Posted by: Christ | April 3, 2007, 11:12 am 11:12 am
 
While I disagree and am disappointed with the way this story was presented by ABC 20/20 I am glad the topic is being talked about. I would like to thank Nicole for her comments…this is not an issue for blame and pointing fingers, it is the safety and efficacy of the public’s medication and ultimately their health. I made a conscious decision to become a clinical community pharmacist to help the public with the challenging aspect of managing their disease states and medications. I think pharmacists are the public’s most accessible health care profession and should be given the respect as a Doctor of Pharmacy and the public should use this accessiblity and knowledge to their advantage. Nicole brings up very good points about how to make your pharmacy experience better. KNOW YOUR PHARMACIST!!! Then you WILL know your medication. If you do not have this type of relationship then find another pharmacist that gives you the attention you deserve! You see the same doctor, nurse, dentist, and yes often even use the same trusted mechanic, carry this mentality to your pharmacist as well. It is impossible to suceed at the career I was highly trained for if I don’t know the medication you get from Walgreens, Rite Aid or mail order. This is not the publics fault..corporate gives the incentive so it will naturally occur, however I urge the public not to take advantage of this so routinely that it jeopardizes your health!! PLEASE do not disregard the wonderful job that pharmacy technicians do everyday, without my technicians I would not be able to have the time to verify dosages, interactions, allergies and call doctors for clarifications, etc. These acts and counseling patients are what I am there to do 10-12 hours of the day! The safety of dispensing medication is too important to argue over, lets work together so the best possible outcome is assured based on a few prudent actions of the patient, the doctor and your pharmacist!
 
Posted by: PharmD2006 | April 3, 2007, 11:23 am 11:23 am
 
Very informative piece of one-sided sensationalism called investigational journalism. And it’s all absolutely true. It has been this way for the chains for years. Why do Pharmacists allow this to happen? It is the Pharmacist who is responsible for every Rx dispensed regrardless of who types the label or fills the bottle. So let’s not worry about the underage underpaid pharmacy technician. The final check is that of the Pharmacist. The Rx to the Label to the drug to the bottle.
So what are we going to do about this? This has been going on for decades as the chains have put out of business all the mom and pop pharmacies who actually spent time and cared for their patients.
Tha almighty dollar wins again. Chains want to make the money. Pharmacists want to earn it. The insurance companies don’t want to pay for medications. The chains cut corners by decreasing staffing. The chains lobby for increased Pharmacist to Technician ratios so more work can be done and expenses be kept low.
Pharmacists leave the chains in search of beter working professional conditions. Things only get worse. Let the government step in and require Pharmacists to only fill a maximum number of Rxs per shift. Heck the lobbyists for the chains will stop that. But the chains will fight to get a Tech check Tech program allowed.
Pharmacists are to blame as we let this happen to our profession.
 
Posted by: Pharmacist | April 3, 2007, 11:57 am 11:57 am
 
A lot of blame tossed around here. Patient, Doctors, The retail drug company, technicians, pharmacist…
Every situation is different, most situations are usually a result of compounded causes.
The customer has to have their prescription right“NOW”, but you can’t read the doctor’s handwritting on the prescription they droped off and you can not get them on the phone. The phone you are on has just stopped ringing for the first time in 5 hours, thanks to the 50 questions you are answering each hour about the 20/20 spcial that aired last night (but, in reality, no one watched 20/20, most questions concern a new drug Oprah is pushing). You are starving and really need to use the bathroom, but your relief is not due for another 5 hours because the term“overlap”is not used by your company. Your technician is keeping everyhting going; typing in prescriptions, counting pills, and answering the again ringing phone. All of this while she is angry about her pay, among other things.
 
Posted by: Mike | April 3, 2007, 12:32 pm 12:32 pm
 
I am a CPhT who works for a big name pharmacy. In viewing your report I came up with a few opinions of my own. Yes, it is the sole responsability of the pharmacist to make sure that the medication was correct before leaving his pharmacy. In the pharmacy that I work in, we use a system that checks the bottle before pouring it out to ensure we picked up the correct medication. As far as your statement that techs are 16 and untrained, I have the student loans&amp;license to proof otherwise.
Your report also targeted in my opinion an employee who didn’t like the corprate way of dispensing medications. As his view is well noted, i know plenty of pharmacists who can keep up with corprate’s way without jeopardizing the quality of the patients needs. He needs to open his own small mom&amp;pop pharmacy so he can do things his way. My guess is he’ll be out of buisness in less then a year.
I thought 20/20 could have done better in investigating its story by getting more facts from other resources then just a discruntal empolyee and a womens horror story brought on by a terrable error.
 
Posted by: jeff | April 3, 2007, 12:55 pm 12:55 pm
 
Your report is completely bias. you should weight the error’s doctors make every day and how all of them the Pharmacist have to fix. You should have a program where you can educate the public that they have to be PATIENT they have to respect the pharmacy work just like they respect an office visit to the doctor’s office.
Also, the public needs to understand that a pharmacy is NOT the same as McDonalds. Honestly I don’t think drive-thru pharmacies are a good idea is not convinient because how can a pharmacist counsel someone there where the car behind you can hear everything. To close this comment the Public needs to be responsible for their own prescriptions READ the label, before you leave the pharmacy The people working behind the counter are highly educated, but they are humans just like your doctor.
 
Posted by: Mary | April 3, 2007, 2:13 pm 2:13 pm
 
I have worked as a registered pharmacist for 24 years. All of my fellow pharmacists could list COUNTLESS times we have SAVED the patient by checking with the prescriber. I very rarely get thanked by the prescriber or patient. Your story is absolutely insane as an accurate representation of pharmacy. As usual, ABC presents the most negative situation hoping to improve your ratings.
I would welcome cameras in all pharmacies. Maybe that would get some attention as to how many prescriptions we fill correctly. How about the NUMEROUS calls we get every day asking…will my xanax,
hydrocodone, oxycodone go thru yet???? Until the public demands better conditions for all pharmacy employees, these situations will only get worse. I bet ABC news would love to cover the story if every pharmacist in America called in sick just one day! The entire medication distribution system would shut down. Think about that the next time you are upset it takes“about 15 minutes”to fill your child or her grandparents medication.
 
Posted by: RCM,RPH | April 3, 2007, 2:15 pm 2:15 pm
 
Where was this report when the state decided to increase the ratio of technicians and clerks to pharmacist-on-duty??? Where were all the voters when this bill passed to allow such increase? The old law allowed 1 pharmacist to 1 technician to 1 clerk. New law allow for 1 pharmacist to 1 technician and as many clerks as possible. If there are 2 pharmacist on-duty, the number of technicians can increase to 3 and the number of clerks can also be any number.
Since the new law came into effect, companies like Walgreens/Rite Aid/Eckard/CVS feel that it is justification to hire more techs and clerks while reducing the number of pharmacist to save money. Retail pharmacist are being forced by the state and companies to fill more prescriptions with help such as technicians and clerks when there really should be another pharmacist available.
I am very disappointed that 20/20 did not look into the reasoning behind such mistakes but instead put blame on highly respected professionals. 20/20 also did not look into the number of mistakes that pharmacists help to avoid on a daily basis,of course those mistakes are avoided so nobody really see that mistakes can also be made on the end of the doctors office, but yet the pharmacist bear the burden of the ones that get pointed out. Instead of airing such a biasis report, 20/20 should really do a much more thorough investigation.
 
Posted by: kate | April 3, 2007, 2:53 pm 2:53 pm
 
To Karen:
Quote:”I agree completely with Cynthia about pharmacies and pharmacists needing to TAKE RESPONSIBILITY for their errors. I am also an RN and, concerning the poor, overworked, pharmacists who never get potty breaks and have to deal with nasty people all day, I can only say,“Welcome to my hell!”Nurses“get to enjoy”all that and more and ARE held accountable for their mistakes, those of the staff they supervise, remedying those of the doctors, pharmacists, dieticians, housekeeping staff…..and on…and on…RN’s DON’T get to illegally give their patients“a few (you name the drug..INCLUDING narcotics) to get through the weekend”to shut them up without a valid prescription. (I would LOVE to see a 20/20 on THAT!) It is just hideous how pharmacists and pharmacies just get away with this incompetence. Enough with the excuses, already!”
My sister is a nurse, my neice is in nursing school, my ex gf is a nurse. i have worked in more than one 900 bed Ivy League teaching hospitals. There is no amount of money that would convince me to do that job. That said.. you seem to be in the minute minority of nurses I wouldn’t let near my dog, let alone a family member. You know why you wouldn’t give a patient med“to get them through the weekend”? Because you can’t. Thats the pharmacists job. I DO NOT give out controlled substances. However I was taught in pharmacy school that the abrupt discontinuation of beta blocker and many other medications would be BAD for a patients health. While quasi legal at certain times and in certain states, I never feared a visit from the Board of Pharmacy or a lawyer questioning the decision to give a patient three (3) atenolol pills or a couple lisinopril tablets so that they would not run out of medication while waiting on full refill authorizations from the equally overworked office or clinic
My professional life would be a living hell without the excellen techs I work with. They are the ones there every day. They know these patients better than I do. They know the fakes and seekers and doctor shoppers in town. I dread Sunday mornings because that is the one morning I do not have a tech. And I then have to“work at my worst”. Every single step is mine. It’s inefficient and takes longer. Not that I am not confident in my own abilities but two sets of eyes seeing the same thing is never bad.
 
Posted by: Craig | April 3, 2007, 6:14 pm 6:14 pm
 
I watched the show on Pharmacy errors. I did NOT appreciate the way that pharmacy technicians were being portrayed. I am a Nationally Certified and State Registered Pharmacy Technician. I take my job VERY seriously, whether I am ordering drugs, typing in scripts, filling meds , or ringing a customer up–my first priority is that patient. I have worked in big chain retail pharmacies as well as hospital settings and I have never worked with any of the kind of“dum dums’that were in your one sided story.Don’t think that every tech is some idiot working part time while in high school. Maybe next time you should focus on the positive things that are done in the pharmacies. Maybe the drug to drug interactions , wrong med/dosage , the allergies , the drug reactions/ side effects that our patients have that their doctors did’nt even bother to catch/notice/concern themselves with. The report made such a big hooplah about the mistakes that pharmacies make. Which some were huge but when you compare it to the hundreds of prescriptions–if not thousands that a pharmacy fills in a day (my pharmacy averages about 5000 per day–with very few,minute errors)the true amount of rx errors is truley miniscule. Whether large or small mistakes they are reported to MedMarx , an agency that looks at our mistakes and helps us better our procedures in oreder to avoid future mistakes.
 
Posted by: Rene In Texas | April 3, 2007, 6:44 pm 6:44 pm
 
I have been a chain store pharmacist and I am currently an independent pharmacist. One issue that this article did not address is the issue of REIMBURSING THE PHARMACIST FOR TIME. Doctors and lawyers get paid for time. If the pharmacist is not being reimbursed for TIME, then this issue will only become worse.
 
Posted by: Denzil | April 3, 2007, 10:12 pm 10:12 pm
 
I am a pharmacist for a major chain and don’t really feel this was a very well done“study”. Though it is unfortunate that the error rate is so high, it’s a product of the society we live in. People want to walk in and walk out with a prescription in under 10 minutes. When you look at the fact that there are usually only 1 or 2 pharmacists on duty (2 in the store I work in for about an hour when the shifts overlap) and we do about 500 prescriptions a day, that doesn’t leave much time for anything else.
The asa that was bought with the coumadin was probably sold by a technician that wasn’t aware of the interaction, and the pharmacist doesn’t always have time to look at everything a patient is buying. Should they? Absolutely.
This will become much less of a problem when people take a little more responsibility for their own healthcare and pay attention to what they are taking, and actually listen when the pharmacist is counseling them. The amount of time I spend calling insurance compaines because someone thinks their copay is too high could be much better spent preventing a possible medication safety issue.
Also, on top of the sheets we have patients sign, it says wehter you wanted to talk to a pharmacist or not. If people read what they are signing they would realize we aren’t trying to pull a fast one on them.
So, be patient, don’t expect pharmacists to baby you and deal with all your insurance issues, don’t scream and throw a fit if your prescription will take more than 5 minutes, and take an active role in your own healthcare, and we can make a big step in making the health care system safer for everyon.
 
Posted by: pharmd | April 3, 2007, 10:20 pm 10:20 pm
 
I am extremely disappointed in 20/20′s investigation. I am a pharmacist, and I spend many hours during the day trying to reach unavailable doctors concerning illegible, incorrect, and incomplete prescriptions. Many times they have their secretaries (many without high school diplomas) call in their prescriptions. They often mispronounce the medication or even phonetically pronounce sig. abbreviations. My favorite is when they say“bid”instead of“b.i.d.”(which means twice a day). Scripts are often dosed wrong by doctors. Time after time I get prescriptions for Wellbutrin XL“1 twice a day”when it is dosed once a day. The Wellbutrin SR is dosed twice a day. Sometimes they will even write for Wellbutrin SL, which does not even exist. With pushy customers, insurance problems, poor communication from doctor to nurse to (sometimes secretary) to the pharmacist messages can come out incorrect. There are guidelines now requiring doctors to print prescriptions but you do not see 20/20 investigating this. The solution is very clear 20/20. Look at the following:
1. Pass laws requiring doctors to type in prescriptions by computer and send the prescriptions electronically or fax directly to the pharmacist. This reduces the amount of people relaying the prescription. Absolutely no handwritten prescriptions!
2. Pass laws that require the minimum amount of time for a rx to be processed and filled to be 20 minutes unless of course it fits into an emergency situation. This reduces the pressure pharmacists receive from some customers to have their prescriptions yesterday.
3. Pass laws requiring that all pharmacists must have a minimum 30 minute lunch break. What do you expect will happen when a person’s blood glucose levels drop due to not eating?
This situation is more complex. The blame is on everyone involved in the prescription process–the medical doctor’s office, the impatient public, as well as the pharmacy corporations. That is why you need to get people to pressure their representatives regarding these issues, so that they can pass appropriate laws with enforcement.
Thank You and I hope this is helpful insight.
 
Posted by: Patrick | April 3, 2007, 11:00 pm 11:00 pm
 
I am a RN. Everytime I go into a CVS to get a perscription filled, they ask me to sign their book. Everytime they do I inform them that it is the law for them to tell me WHY I am signing this book. I have been doing this since the conception of this book signing, with the same people at the same drug store. Yet somehow, they still don’t ask me if I have any questions!!!!!! This is even after I had an arguement with the head Pharmacist, and she informed me that she would ask everytime from now on……Go Figure.
 
Posted by: Lori Wood | April 4, 2007, 8:15 am 8:15 am
 
I agree with some of the statements above in regards to Pharmacists not offering counseling for Rx’s. I am a pharmacist but I don’t work in a retail chain pharmacy–I work in home care. I have picked up my Rx’s from my local chain without being asked if I needed counseling and just told to sign. I have confronted the pharmacist about the responsibility that they have to offer counseling, since it is the law and part of our policy at work as well. I don’t condone this‘sign for your Rx’behavior, but you couldn’t pay me a million dollars a year to do what a chain pharmacist does for a living. Patients continue to yell and scream at the staff when the pharmacist tells them it will be about 20 minutes for their Rx and management is always on the side of the patient. Quotas, no lunch ( or bathroom breaks! ) and lack of staff make for a recipe for disaster! Let’s look at the CEO’s of these chains to make some much needed changes and you will see most of these problems disappear!
 
Posted by: Angie | April 4, 2007, 9:19 am 9:19 am
 
I am very disappointed in 20/20′s investigation about retail pharmacy. I used to trust the information and studies that 20/20 presented before I saw Fridays show. I will never again watch 20/20 or any news program on ABC. ABC and 20/20 must learn how to properly investigate a subject before presenting it to the public. I have never seen a more bias study. As a medical professional I know how to interpret journal articles and medical studies. The 20/20 pharmacy study is completely useless and it only confused the public and misrepresented retail pharmacy. I think somebody should do a study on ABC and 20/20 to find out how much INCORRECT, biased information they have on their shows. I will never again watch ABC and will tell friends, family and coworkers never to trust anything they hear or see on 20/20. I will also be submitting an article in my local newspaper enlightening the public about the lies and bad information provided by 20/20. ABC needs to take some lessons from CBS on how to perform a study. CBS’s news specialists are far superior to anything ABC has put out. Try to keep up ABC!!! Very sad ABC..very very sad!!!
 
Posted by: Jack Jones | April 4, 2007, 9:54 am 9:54 am
 
I agree, patients reserve the right to know if the medication they suppose to take is safe or not. there should be created a standard policy to reserve the right of a patient to excerise checks for medication verification through desired approach to identify a pill’s content and visible indicator to propceed or disallow the use of the product or pills.
 
Posted by: Jamal | April 4, 2007, 1:36 pm 1:36 pm
 
20/20, I think I speak for the thousands of technicians, who work retail and must say we are deeply disappointed in this extremely biased so-called investigation. Get the whole story next time. During the past five years alone, the big chain pharmacy I work for has invested millions upon millions of dollars in the pharmacy to upgrade equipment, technology and filling procedures. A label does not print out until the pharmacist verifies it correctly typed. Then we have barcode readers to double check the product, and then we count, and then weigh to double check again. Then the pharmacist checks to make sure everything is correct, and then we VERBALLY ask the customer to VERIFY their address to ensure we are selling to the correct patient. But when the patient is too busy having the most important conversation of their life on the cell phone, they don’t care, they mumble out an address, ignore us when we ask if they have any questions for the pharmacist and off they go. 20/20 quit pointing fingers, errors are an equal blame on the doctor (illegible handwriting), pharmacies (ignorant, impatient customers, and overworked pharmacists), and the patient (for rushing the pharmacy staff, ignoring us and not taking an active role in their medication management).
 
Posted by: Nick | April 4, 2007, 1:52 pm 1:52 pm
 
Last 2 prescriptions from Walgreens–ordered 30 rec’d. 28, ordered 90 rec’d. 87. I guess I’m lucky that was the only error.
 
Posted by: Jill | April 4, 2007, 8:25 pm 8:25 pm
 
by the way, lots of the counting errors could be coming from the automated counting machine. sometimes those machines are known to make errors too.
i have patients that request that we count pills in front of them. and i will do it if they ask.
 
Posted by: jenny | April 5, 2007, 7:10 am 7:10 am
 
To Nick:
I couldn’t have said it better myself. I think that report must have been done in the dark ages before our new technology. Also, how are we supposed to know if that aspirin the customer is purchasing is for them or someone else??
Leah, CPhT
 
Posted by: Leah | April 5, 2007, 9:00 am 9:00 am
 
Great work 20/20!! I recommend filling prescriptions not in busy pharmacy chains but in a small independent pharmacy with a more attentive staff. It is less convenient, but it beats being dead. Unless lawsuits put a dent in the bottom line, corporate managers will continue to push and patient will continue be harmed. That is the sad reality of pharmacy.
 
Posted by: chain pharmD | April 5, 2007, 9:31 am 9:31 am
 
I watched this program the other day, and I was appalled at all of the information that 20/20 left out. I am a pharmacy tech at a major chain, and I am 18 years old. It is a New Jersey law that techs be at least 18 years old, and I don’t work with one person who hasn’t graduated high school with a diploma, as have all of the other techs I work with. I am also very well trained and a pharmacy student at a well respected university. We fill approximatley 500 scripts per day, and there is always a pharmacist or two working during pharmacy hours, and these pharmacists are very overworked. They work 10-12 hour shifts without taking a single break or sitting down, and getting a chance to eat a meal is a luxury.
The job of a pharmacy tech is a very hard one, and we are very very underpaid. At this time I am only making $8.00 an hour. This small amount of money do what a tech does. We are expected to type in prescriptions (while trying to read the doctor’s scribble), scan the script into the computer system, file the hardcopy prescription correctly, find the medication, print the label (which does have a description of the correct pill on it), scan the barcode on the bottle to make sure it is the right medication, acknowledge and fix any insurance problems (which occur in about 50% of prescriptions), call the insurance company if the problem can not be fixed by the tech (this usually means being put on hold for a minimum of 10 minutes), count the pills, bottle them using the correct cap, and give them to the pharmacist.
The pharmacist then scans the barcode on the bottle and a screen comes up showing the scanned original script, a picture of the correct pill and all of the customer information. The pharmacist has to verify that all of the information is correct (this includes multiple things–right patient, right drug, right drug strength, right quantity, right directions, right refills, right doctor, etc. and also checking for potential drug interactions). This process is completed hundreds of times per day.
This process is different for a narcotic prescription. Only the pharmacist is allowed to fill these scripts. These medications are kept in a safe, and customers always want to wait for them. The pharmacist must fill out a narcotic book for each script. This process takes a long time, and customers don’t realize this.
Doctors make more mistakes than the average patient would expect. I cannot tell you how many prescriptions I have received that have a medication or a strength that doesn’t even exist. Doctors put refills on narcotic scripts, which is legally not allowed, just to name a couple of the common mistakes on the physician’s end. When the pharmacy attampts to call the doctor’s office, we never talk to the doctor, only a nurse who will ask the pharmacist what they recommend to give the patient, including the strength and the sig code. Isn’t this the doctor’s job?
All of this is expected to be done in under 15 minutes by the customer. If it is not, boy do we hear about it.
A tech then has to ring them up, and not only the prescription but a cartful of front store items. The customer will be talking on their cell phone, complaining about their copay and make us double check it, although the cost is set by the incurance company.
Another HUGE mistake made by 20/20, the log book at the register. This is NOT a waiver of your right to counselling. That is rediculous. You are signing that you have no questions for the pharmacist about your prescription. If the customer would actually read what they sign, they would know this. If you ask for counseling, you will always get it. If you have spoken to the pharmacist, you sign a different box in the book stating that you have.
Throughout the past week I have gotten in countless arguments with misinformed customers about the log books. Paitents now think that pharmacies are trying to pull a fast one on them, when they actually are not. The logbook also helps if we cannot find a script in the bin when a customer comes to the register. Many times a customer has gotten livid with me because I couldn’t find the prescription when their husband or wife picked up the script the day before, and they didn’t even know. We look in the log book and there is their signature. We spend so much time trying to please the customer and get little praise in return. We almost NEVER get an apology.
Through all of this, I still love my job. I feel that I am a vital part of the pharmacy and that the pharmacists respect me and need me to be there. I know that I could easily walk over to a fast food restaurant and get paid more, but I stay because I want to help the customers. There is no better feeling than when a customer comes in and truly values the service we provide to them. We have customers that will yell, scream and curse at us and make fools of themselves, and there are customers that are so greatful that they bring us home cooked dinners throughout the week. These are the customers I love to serve. Maybe if more people realize how much effort is put info filling their prescriptions they would have a greater respect for us.
I am very disappointed in this“investigation”and I think that 20/20 needs to do an investigation on the other side of this problem, the doctors, insurance companies and the misinformed customers.
 
Posted by: Gabrielle | April 5, 2007, 10:08 am 10:08 am
 
I watched this program the other day, and I was appalled at all of the information that 20/20 left out. I am a pharmacy tech at a major chain, and I am 18 years old. It is a New Jersey law that techs be at least 18 years old, and I don’t work with one person who hasn’t graduated high school with a diploma, as have all of the other techs I work with. I am also very well trained and a pharmacy student at a well respected university. We fill approximatley 500 scripts per day, and there is always a pharmacist or two working during pharmacy hours, and these pharmacists are very overworked. They work 10-12 hour shifts without taking a single break or sitting down, and getting a chance to eat a meal is a luxury.
The job of a pharmacy tech is a very hard one, and we are very very underpaid. At this time I am only making $8.00 an hour. This small amount of money do what a tech does. We are expected to type in prescriptions (while trying to read the doctor’s scribble), scan the script into the computer system, file the hardcopy prescription correctly, find the medication, print the label (which does have a description of the correct pill on it), scan the barcode on the bottle to make sure it is the right medication, acknowledge and fix any insurance problems (which occur in about 50% of prescriptions), call the insurance company if the problem can not be fixed by the tech (this usually means being put on hold for a minimum of 10 minutes), count the pills, bottle them using the correct cap, and give them to the pharmacist.
The pharmacist then scans the barcode on the bottle and a screen comes up showing the scanned original script, a picture of the correct pill and all of the customer information. The pharmacist has to verify that all of the information is correct (this includes multiple things–right patient, right drug, right drug strength, right quantity, right directions, right refills, right doctor, etc. and also checking for potential drug interactions). This process is completed hundreds of times per day.
 
Posted by: Gabrielle | April 5, 2007, 10:15 am 10:15 am
 
I was very upset about your program on pharmacy. i am a pharmacy tech. i have been since i was 16 years old. your program blamed pharmacy tech. for all of the mistakes in the pharmacy. you who have to Pharmacists who have to double check the scripts before they go out of the pharmacy. another thing that made me very angry is that we are not deciving the customer in anyway when they pick up the script most techs ask if they have any questions for the pharmacists. most patients say no. i dont think you guys did your job very good. it seems to me that you have no clue how a pharmacy is ran!
 
Posted by: jenny | April 5, 2007, 12:09 pm 12:09 pm
 
I work for a retail chain. I am a Certified Senior Pharmacy Technician. There have been many great points in previous comments. It is true that people do not know what is required of Pharmacy Technicans and Pharmacists. It is much more that just“slapping a label on the bottle”. It is much more involved that that! In the chain I work for, Technicians must be 18 years of age or older. They are required to take the certification exam, and be licensed. Also, there is an extensive 2 week training program for all new technicians. There are still some people who can just not handle the stress of the job or the job itself. The pharmacist must verify EVERYTHING, and a technician is never to advise the patient on ANYTHING. The patient is given the option to accept or refuse a counsel. I am surprised at the number of people who refuse a counsel on medication they have never taken before. It is the patient’s responsibility to know what they are taking, and ask questions and read the material that comes with the prescription. The pharmacist is there to adivse you, not get yelled at because being counseled is taking 2 extra minutes out of their day; 2 extra minutes that could potentially save their lives. There is a lot of stress placed on us and everyone wants their prescriptions now. A lot of the errors that happen occur because of Doctor error. What about the training of the Doctors nurses and staff? Many times I have had to call because a Doctor has written for a prescription that does not exist, or strength or dosage that is incorrect. Other errors do happen when the Pharmacist is not given enough time to verify. It is unfortunate that errors happen, but they do help improve our system and policies in the pharmacy. And I know it is hard to believe, but the majority of people who come in are not the most pleasant people to come into contact with. There is better things we have to do than call your insurance because you don’t know who you have coverage through, your ID number, or because your copay is too much. That is part of the patient’s personal responsibility. It is also not right that the insurance company is the deciding factor on if a patient gets the prescription they need. The doctor prescribed the prescription for a reason, but it is the insurance that can say NO, we want you to be on something cheaper. In addition, I am used to working 12+ hour days with no lunches, and no breaks because there are just not enough technicians to work at the growing number of retail stores. In our store, people have been hired who are not capable of doing the job. There is not enough stores to train technicians, and new technicians are being thrown into high volume stores and being expected to be trained there, which is not possible!
So if your local store is understaffed or there are not competent people working there, go to the district office or corporate. I know as technicians, we have all gone to our supperiors about these problems, and they don’t see it as a big enough problem coming from just us.
It would be great if you did a story on what actually goes on in the pharmacy, not just one or two unfortunate mistakes.
We are in a very under appreciated profession. The majority of us are in the profession because we truly care and want to help people.
 
Posted by: Brittany | April 5, 2007, 7:39 pm 7:39 pm
 
As a pharmacist, I am very offended by the comment made by Karen regarding us giving patients a few pills for the weekdend“to shut them up”. The reason we need to do this is because we are unable to reach a physician to refill a prescription, as doctors are seldom available on weekends. As a nurse, Karen should realise that it might be dangerous for patients to go off their medication for a few days. I have been yelled at by a doctor because I bothered him during his dinner to ask for a refill on his patient’s insulin. So, I guess Karen would rather see someone spend the weekend in pain or have a stroke because they didn’t pay attention and ran out of refills. Then 20/20 can blame the pharmacist for not giving them any medication.
I also think 20/20 should do a companion piece entitled“Who’s really working in you doctor’s office?”While the company I work for prohibits technicians from taking new prescriptions over the phone, I have received more than one call from office staff who can’t even pronunce the name of the medication, much less interpret the directions for use. Then there are the office staff (nurses, I hope)who approve refills without even checking a patient’s chart. Once when I asked for a doctor to call me back about a question, the nurse informed me that he probably wouldn’t, because“that’s what nurses are for”. If doctors need all this help to do do their jobs, why are we pharmacists expected to do everything ourselves?
 
Posted by: Susie | April 5, 2007, 7:42 pm 7:42 pm
 
Unfortunately there is some truth to the report that 20/20 released. I am a pharmacist, but I don’t work in retail, I work in home care. I don’t agree with the‘sign for your Rx’mentality that you see in the chain pharmacies and most patients don’t realize that when they are signing,they are refusing couseling. I often confront the pharmacist when told to sign for my Rx when counseling is NOT offered. I know it is the law to offer couseling and find it very disturbing that this‘signing a piece of paper’next to your Rx number is the‘way around’fulfilling that requirement. In my job as a home care pharmacist, it is our policy to counsel every patient.
On the other hand, you could not pay me a million dollars to work in a chain pharmacy. They have to deal with screaming, impatient customers, store managers that side with the customers ( often without a clue of the responsibilities that a pharmacist has ), limited staffing, no lunch breaks( or bathroom breaks! ) and 12-14 hour shifts on your feet. This is all a recipe for disaster. If you want to see change happen–then the focus needs to be on the CEO’s of these chain stores. If the appropriate changes were made–most of these problems would go away.
 
Posted by: Angie | April 5, 2007, 8:36 pm 8:36 pm
 
While i beleive that the information you were TRYING to portray to the public may have been beneficial, i do see several“ERRORS”that your reporters made as well. So should we assume that everything we hear from the media is contaminated. No. You portrayed prescription errors as being a large portion of the pharmacy world. I work for the Walgreens chain and have for years. I have been in pharmacy for 10 years, and i agree that while errors are horrible, they do sometimes happen. Just as things happen that are unfortunate to everyones jobs at some time in their career. I believe that you“targeted”Walgreens! You did not even it out with any other chain and customers are concerned that CVS, WAL-MART, PUBLIX, RITE AIDE ect are not prone to the errors! YOU misdirected YOUR information! Also, with the ASA (aspirin for you non-intellectual reporters) and Warfarin, you asked sales clerks NOT the pharmacist! Techs do not atend school and therefore are unaware of many of the reactions. However, when you go to WAL-MART and buy ciggarettes does the clerk ask if they are for you? NO! They ASSUME that if you are buying them that they must be for someone!
Also for you customers that believe a prescription being filled is equivalent to to the McDonalds drive through, maybe if you would be patient, we would be able to meet all of the demands as well as correct filling and verifying processes!
ABC YOU misconstrued information about the pharmacy profession and your“investigation”was bias at the LEAST! It is my opinion that ABC either needs to do another investigation and look at ALL the factors or offer a public apology to the Pharmacists that work hard to provide healthcare to the public!
YOU ARE ALSO TO BLAME FOR MISINFORMING THE PUBLIC! So what should we think about your profession?
 
Posted by: Renee&apos; FAMU pharmD, FL | April 5, 2007, 8:47 pm 8:47 pm
 
PHARMACY TECH I WORK AT AN INDEPENDENT PHARMACY AND I SEE THE DEMAND OF PEOPLE WHO WANT THEIR RXS TO BE FILLED IN MINUTES WHEN WE TELL THEM IT WILL TAKE ABOUT 15 TO 2O MINUTES THEY SAY YOU DONT HAVE TO MAKE THE PILLS ONLY PUT IN THE BOTTLE THEY DONT KNOW THE PROCESS AND THEY WANT TO TALK TO YOU AT THE SAME TIME WHEN WE ASK THEM TO LET AS FINISH THE RX THEY SAY YOUR SO RUDE AND MANY MORE STORIES I COULD TELL BUT MISTAKES ARE NOT THE EXCUSE, CERTIFIED AND REGISTERED PHARMACY TECH IN MASS. DOTTY
 
Posted by: DOTTY | April 6, 2007, 6:52 am 6:52 am
 
Watching this 20/20 investigation, my blood began to boil. As a 6th year PharmD candidate, I await graduation in less than 7 weeks. I have had the opportunity to work in retail pharmacy and I wonder. . .did you take the time to videotape the pharmacy at 5:30 pm when 35 people have lined up to YELL at the pharmacist and staff for not being quick enough? I have personally stopped errors from occuring, all while being on the phone for hours with YOUR insurance companies and having you scream at me over the phone why your copay went up one dollar. I believe that 20/20 owes the pharmacists of this country to right to show another side to this story. Yes, I agree that no pharmaceutical error is acceptable, but lets face it. We are human too. It will happen. While respecting this opinion, maybe your program should also show how many lives are saved each year by pharmacists. Or how absolutely horrible customers can be to a pharmacy staff. I do not want to graduate in less than two months and have to go to a work environment filled with scorn for me, when I have yet to make an error. So please do us a favor, and be better journalists.
 
Posted by: Katie | April 6, 2007, 2:24 pm 2:24 pm
 
That was the most ridiculous and outlandish piece of media I have ever seen. As a 2nd year pharmacy student/intern; I take it personally when others assume that we do not care. Most pharmacy students go to school so they can help people. That is our main goal and priority. Most pharmacists are perfectionists, obsessive compulsive people who worry about the possibility of making mistakes. Hearing the story about the 8 year old girl and the mother broke my heart and as enlightened me to never rush and rush again. And yes, it does happen, and yes it hurts deeply; but many professors have informed us that“we are a profession scrutinized to be perfect. If anything less than perfect, there goes our license.”I do work in a retail pharmacy and I do get griped at by customer after customer for numerous reasons. When at work, I often think to myself…“if people only knew how it really worked.”I am called incompetent on a regular basis by one customer in particular, when in reality I have never done anything less than my best for him or any of my patients. Doctors make mistakes, nurses make mistakes, McDonald’s workers make mistakes, teachers make mistakes and yet, you shed a negative light on a profession that is working so hard and so diligently towards improvement. It isn’t right 20/20. I did not write this comment to be completely negative and oppossed to your findings. So my constructive criticism begins here:
1. Patients/Customers: Please ask questions. Let your pharmacist/intern talk to even if it’s just long enough to understand how to take it and why. And listen carefully!
2. Don’t let a technician tell you a pharmacist is too busy to talk to you.
3. Be Patient. WE ARE NOT A PROFESSION DESIGNED TO WORK LIKE MCDONALD’S.
4. Pharmacists: Take your time to get it right. (but what do I know, I’m just a student)
5. Counseling in the retail enviornment is crucial to catching errors.
P.S. Electronic Prescribing will not change the world. Errors can still occur in the drug selection process on the other end. But it is a step in a positive direction.
Keep working hard technicians, interns and pharmacists not for the dollar but for the patient.
 
Posted by: Alexis | April 7, 2007, 1:41 am 1:41 am
 
Although some of the“facts”are wrong in these set of stories and is a bit one-sided, I think in the end, it will cause some debate for change. Humans will make errors. It’s how do we prevent errors is the question. One of the big factors as you can see from people experienced in the field is the lack of help. There simply isn’t enough pharmacists in the US to fill for the increasing number of prescriptions sold. Not only that, but corporate chain stores won’t provide enough staffing hours for pharmacists at these stores if they are available. Too many times a pharmacist is left by themselves. I feel at least two pharmacists should be present nearly all the time except during down times (which is vastly different from store to store). Although I’m not sure if there are enough pharmacists available for this. Technicians should have more than just a high school diploma or GED. Now if they are only going to get paid $8/hr, then nobody will want to be a tech. Techs need higher wages because if someone is going to be more than just a high school graduate and has taken the time to get board certified, I feel they should be paid in the $15+/hour range. I feel the good techs are underappreciated and this would give more incentive for quality people to become technicians. Good technicians are absolutely vital for a retail store (or hospital pharmacy) to run smoothly as they are doing most of the busy work that can easily cause a mistake. If a pharmacist has a bad tech that makes a mistake 1 out of 5 prescriptions, then it’s much more difficult to detect those errors. Plus good techs allow more time for pharmacists to do what they went to school for, to counsel and talk to patients and check for drug-drug/drug-disease interactions. All retail stores should allow for lunch breaks (at least a half hour). Breaks reduce stress which can prevent mental lapses. The large chain pharmacies need to realize this and try to do everything possible to make it about patient safety first and not about money. I’m living in a fantasy world though if I believe this to come true.
 
Posted by: Brett | April 7, 2007, 2:07 am 2:07 am
 
I did not watch all of the broadcast, but what I did see is what I would call“enterntainment”. News reporters only report what will attract people to watch. What you dont tell the public who are watching is that pharmacists are lucky to get a bathroom break, they are lucky to eat the lunch they bring. They are always interupted by phone calls, people screaming,“I want my meds now!”Many techs are not trained properly to ask people if they have questions, but there are many that are trained. It is ultimately the pharmacists responsibilty to catch mistakes and make sure none go out. Some mistakes are made, but it is also up to the patient to ask questions. Especially if the medication appears different than the last time. If they have not taken or given the medication before, they need to ask questions. You can’t blame the pharmacist because the patient did not ask questions. And, how did that lady get 7 weeks of phenobarbital?
1. you can only get 30 days for the med.
2. the baby should have shown some type of signs in the beginning, atleast I would think.
3. You are telling me they filled it wrong twice? Did the label say phenobarbital or“the diabetic drug”? Could she not read the label? If the label said phenobarbital, you are telling me they filled it wrong twice which is highly unlikely. I dont believe that ladies story. It sounds a little too fishy to me.
 
Posted by: Soccergirl | April 7, 2007, 10:07 am 10:07 am
 
I thought your broadcast was misleading and put blame on individual pharmacists. I could not believe that 20/20 targeted the pharmacist who gave the wrong medicine to the girl. Do you people not realize that this man is haunted by this, and yet ABC let their cameras ambush him? It was not his fault, I am sure he is intelligent and competent. The fact is, he is human and works for a horrible system, which is the medical system. The system as a whole needs to be blamed for this incidence not the individual. I wish ABC would put a hidden camera on a pharmacist who fills, by him or herself 50 prescriptions an hour. Imagine trying to counsel, decipher doctors handwriting, answer 20 calls an hour, not be able to eat, sit or use the rest room and still be 99.9% accurate! NOW THAT’S TV!
 
Posted by: MP | April 8, 2007, 9:58 am 9:58 am
 
Please do a broadcast on the physicians and their staff. Let’s see how accurate they are. This is where the source of most errors come from……the MD office. I’m glad the pharmacists are there to clean up the physicians messes!!
 
Posted by: RC | April 8, 2007, 4:20 pm 4:20 pm
 
As a pharmacist for 20 years, it has always amazed me how some patients will spend 5 hours in a doctors office, yet expect their rx’s filled in 15 minutes. Keep in mind that the physicians schedule these patients by appointment, pharmacists serve their patients as they walk thru the door. I work in and own an independent pharmacy. The amount of work we do could not be done without our trained and certified technicians. We are a team. The pharmacist is the only person that can check and release a prescription to the patient. We encourage our patients to look at and ask questions about their meds. It it looks different than last time, ask to speak to the pharmacist. It is preferable to correct an error on the front end than to treat the results on the back end. This specific incident was a worse case scenario, but 20/20 had errors in the story…and ABC had time to edit and correct. Did they? No. So while their is no excuse in misfilling a prescription, it may do investigative journalists some good to remember when they are pointing fingers, 3 more are pointing back at them. We should all strive to do better.
 
Posted by: Barry | April 8, 2007, 9:11 pm 9:11 pm
 
All this is great, I’ve read all the comments. I just wish something good would come out this for everyone involved pharmacist, technicians and our customers. The problem is real, its not only real it has hugh implications as a matter of public safety. Corporate, district managers, and big pharmacy chains need to re-direct their coroporate strategy.
Its a dis-service to pharmacists and consumers that our pharmacy profession takes a back seat to photo department for 1 hr photo, and allows for a pharmacist to be working a drive-thru as if he/she worked at a fast-food chain.
 
Posted by: rphmiami | April 9, 2007, 9:05 pm 9:05 pm
 
WORST EVER REPORT BY ABC
Not enough investigation at all. You should know that around billions of prescription are filled every month in US by US PHARMACISTS. If you have found few errors, that happened in last FEW YEARS, that does not relate anywhere to you conclusion of“epidemic”.
ABC should remember that, PHARMACY is still america’s most trusted profession. Pharmacists are not god, they are human. All humans are prone to errors. There are several issues that ABC failed to mention like the circumstances Pharmacists are forced to work in by CEO’s of big chains (CORPORATE AMERICA).
If any of these patients are saying that Pharmacist who makes 1 mistake should be fired, go and get your prescriptions filled in canada or somewhere else through internet.
Then you will know importance of US pharmacist.
God Bless America, with this new side of journalism.
 
Posted by: Vikram rao | April 10, 2007, 4:50 pm 4:50 pm
 
I took my daughters Rx to be filled, I waited over 1 hour. I did not mind…I just came back. I do mind waiting; I know I am not the only person living! However, I gave my daughter the med as told on the bottle. Sulfamethozaxole 50ml(generic for Septra) it said 1 tsp a day for 5 days until gone. Well, on the 5th day I called the pharmacy and asked why there was still half a bottle left, I gave her the med as directed. She said, hmm why did they give you 50ml..let me pull the original prescription. When she came back, she stated oh I am so sorry, they gave you the right amount but the directions are wrong. You should of been giving her 1 tsp twice a day for 5 days. She tried to get me to continue the rest of the meds as originally prescribed by my doctor. She was just sure my daughter needed it. She kept referring to they and them, we I could plainly see her name on the bottle as the Pharmacist!
When I told her that I would call my doctor to see what he wanted to do. She said oh.ok. Well, if you need more meds or a different med we will gladly fill it free. In addition, since it is a rainy night I will gladly have someone bring it to you. My daughter was on the med for a UTI and swallow Lymph nodes in her belly region. She is also autistic, so communication on whether or not the infections cleared or not was impossible. I had to take her back for more rounds of test because of this.
Thank goodness, another CT scan was not ordered. The head office called me to check on my daughter and told me the person making the report was so concerned about my daughter. She did not tell them in the report that it was her mistake nor that she tried to get me to complete the meds without calling my doctor. I did find out that she was suppose to call the doctor her self and speak with the doctor about the situation and find out what they wanted to do. I am not sure if this common practice or just this chains rules. If I had not been a concerned parent and called the pharmacy, my daughter’s infection could have got worse to whatever point. Since she lacks communication, I would not have known the infection did not clear. Now, I still have to take her back in a few weeks. Since the meds clear the infection now, it does not mean it took care of long term. Therefore, here the tech got the Rx wrong and so did the Pharmacist who checked their work!
 
Posted by: Tina | April 11, 2007, 10:10 am 10:10 am
 
Your story was biased and inaccurate, but the truth doesn’t always win ratings does it? We pharmacists are responsible for the safety and welfare of the public and some of us take our jobs very seriously. Yes, the girl who typed the prescription wrong was a teenager, however the pharmacist legally needs to check every prescription and whether a teenager or a noble-prize winning scientist types it, human nature dictates that sometimes mistakes will be made. Despite pressure from the chains to fill prescriptions fast, the real issue is public pressure. Do they want it fast or do they want it right? People moan and complain when you tell them there prescription will be 20 minutes. Then they proceed to ask you a thousand questions about which toothpaste would be best for their sensitive teeth or which antihistamine their dog should take. All the while, the prescriptions are backing up because the technicians may assemble them, but a pharmacist MUST check them before they go out. You get back in the pharmacy and another patient wants to chew your ear about how generics are not the same because they tried generic store-brand ice cream and it is nowhere near as good as Bluebell. Inside the pharmacy, line 1 has a prescription transfer, line 2 is a new prescription being called in, and line 3 is Mrs.Smith returning your call about a question you had regarding a potential drug interaction. In the meantime, the customer in the waiting room is complaining because they have been sitting there for 25 minutes and all we have to do is“put the pills in the bottle and slap a label on it”. When the prescription is done, the cashier calls for a counsel which is REQUIRED on all new prescriptions in the state of Texas. You go to the window where the customer proceeds to answer his cell phone in the middle of the consultation. How about showing all that is involved with the profession of pharmacy and maybe people will be a little more patient. And what about people taking a little time to make sure they have all the information and take a little responsibility for themselves?
 
Posted by: Michele | April 11, 2007, 12:39 pm 12:39 pm
 
Brian: You are the jewel in the crown at ABC! Bravo for your research on pharmacies. I always try to get Rx before 6am to get a pharmacist&amp;avoid the crowd&amp;tech. Still I have found errors. It is amazing that everyone is so worried about drugs from Canada! I feel that I have just as good a chance there as in US.
Keep up the investigations. Cynthia
 
Posted by: Cynthia | April 14, 2007, 9:19 pm 9:19 pm
 
pharmacist and pharm techs can and do make mistakes but they r under tremendous stress every day. They are expected to complete several tasks at once and this is what causes mistakes. The tech counts medication, answers phones, rings out customers answers questions for customers concerning where otc medications are located, and does several other misc. work around the pharmacy, yet the tech will only get paid 6.35 per hour. In addition to all this both pharmacist the techs have to deal with unruly customers who don’t want to understand why their medication will be filled late or why insurance companies wont pay for them. I work 12 hour shifts as a tech get paid 6.35 per hour and that wage can barely fill gas for my four cylinder car.
 
Posted by: philip | April 15, 2007, 4:49 pm 4:49 pm
 
The real issue here is that there isn’t enough time given to prevent from making a mistake. If the customer would just give the pharmacist/technician the respect and the time that they give their doctors, we would be more accurate in filling the prescriptions. But it’s not that way in most cases. 80% of the customers want to wait for the prescriptions and if they drop off more than 3 prescriptions, they want it in at least 15 minutes or less. They don’t realize that it takes time to get the information on the patient from the patient or the person dropping it off for the patient, it takes time to type in the prescription, pull the drug from the shelf, count out the drug, pour the drug into the bottle, put the label on the bottle, check to see if it’s a easy open cap or a child safety cap and then they have to stack it all together and pass it down the counter for the pharmacist to check. But they don’t realize that the pharmacy has other customers that they already have assisted that they told them that their medication would be ready before them and they don’t realize that sometimes the phone rings and you are on there for a while depending on if it’s Mrs. Smith calling to ask what drug interactions she should look for in a medicine that she just picked up. And sometimes you have more than one line ringing at a time that you have to answer and put on hold while they finish up the first phone call. We realize that our customers are sick and they don’t want to have to wait around to get their medication, but they also have to realize that it’s not a fast food joint and we aren’t short order cooks. Sometimes it takes time and the time you give your pharmacist and or technician may be all they need to assure that your prescription is right and ready for you to pick up. If you can come back to the pharmacy, do so. If you can’t, please just be patient. We aren’t only working on your prescription, we are working on other things too and we deserve the time that you give your doctors when you wait to be seen. Point being, just be patient and try not to rush us because it’s stressful enough making sure that it’s done in a timely manner, but making sure it’s DONE RIGHT, is the MOST IMPORTANT THING.
 
Posted by: singinrxtec72 | May 2, 2007, 12:39 am 12:39 am
 
I am a pharmacy technician of 9 years at a grocery store and this show really pissed me off. Here are some of the ways I spend a typical day: Babysitting the Vicodin addicts who are eating 20 tabs a day when they only should be taking 2. Taking 10+ calls from same person who is wondering if their Vicodin has been refilled yet or if they can get it early because they are going out of town(usually to the mall 15 min. up the road). Calling insurance to ask why medication was covered last month but not now and holding for 20 min. Calling insurance to ask why patient not covered, when it turns out they“forgot”they quit their job last month and no longer have insurance–just hoping Rx might go through. Calling insurance to get ID # for person who doesn’t have it on them but thinks they have the company with the blue and white cards. Calling Md to verify RX because refill came back all wrong and person entering information on the electronic script program at the
office has no medical or drug training and input everything wrong. Helping little old lady do her grocery shopping because the pharmacy staff are the only ones she can get to acknowlege her. Listening to customer cry about why Medicaid won’t pay for her baby’s tylenol and she can’t afford it but while she’s at the counter can I ring up her beer? Etc, etc, etc. Let someone from 20/20 spend a day doing my job and then we can talk.
 
Posted by: cr | May 21, 2007, 1:48 am 1:48 am
 
Let’s look into the causes of these pharmacy errors:
1. Most pharmacies are understaffed
2. Pharmacists are overworked
3. People think that a pharmacy is a fast-food joint and are rushing and pressuring the pharmacy staff to get the prescriptions out quickly.
4. Illegible prescriptions written by MD’s
5. Phones ringing 1000 times a day plus have to attend the drive-thru and do multiple tasks at once
6. Rude people disrespecting the pharmacy staff on a daily basis and getting them unfocused and nervous.
Of course you are going to have pharmacy errors, let’s correct these points above by educating the general public as to how tough working in a pharmacy really is and making it unlawful to rush, disrespect and pressure the pharmacy staff to do their jobs in a matter of nano-seconds.
 
Posted by: Richard | June 1, 2007, 7:41 pm 7:41 pm
 
I have worked in a well-known drugstore for 4 1/2 years. The pharmacy has always been my first love. I love helping customers; NEVER EVER have I thought about decieving them! The specific quote about the pharmacy personnel decieving customers without thier knowledge is garbage. Every customer is asked whether counseling from the pharmacist is needed, if not; they must sign to decline counseling. If counseling is their request, then they will still be asked to sign only once all of thier questions were asked to decline any FURTHER questions. Patients don’t realize this but signing that moniter is also helpful in determing any fradulent pick-ups by people who you did not authorize to do so. I don’t know how many times I have had to print off the signature from our computer database showing the patients own handwriting and signature after being screamed at that they didn’t pick it up.
Another point that I want to make is the fact that a pharmacy is NOT Burger King or McDonalds…Filling one script takes at LEAST 15 minutes. Patients must understand that while filling that SINGLE script the pharmacy staff is answering phone calls, correcting any mistakes that the doctor has made on your script, checking to make sure that everything on your script is written correctly and also typed correctly. Because not only do we have to answer to you, our customer, but we also have to answer to insurance companies if the quantity, days supply, etc. is incorrect!
Unfortunately, Most of the people that are believing this junk that 20/20 has pulled out of thier…are the people that come to my counter and tell me they want“all of thier scripts filled”…we don’t have crystal balls to tell us what scripts you are on and what ones you are not taking any longer. People NEED to read about thier medicine, make yourself aware!! It’s absolutely your right as a patient of our pharmacies!! Ask questions!! If you are that concerned about your drugs or your health, why are you waiting for us to ask you!! In the words of NIKE, just do it!!
 
Posted by: Jessica | July 5, 2007, 9:56 pm 9:56 pm
 
I have been a pharmacist for 24 years, and was a pharmacy technician/drug clerk for 8 years before that. I have worked with many pharmacists and even more technicians over the years, and most have been conscientious and good. A few, who stand out strongly, have been incompetent and just don’t care about the job they are supposed to be doing. Before the revolution of pharmacy techs, those who assisted the pharmacist were drug clerks. These clerks could count tablets and put in vials, waiting for the pharmacist to affix the label to the container. Clerks helps customers/patients to find items in the store, they answered the phone and wrote down refill requests, the performed chores such as cleaning, facing shelves, etc., and they operated the cash register. Those were the days. We did not have the insurance issues that we have today—we didn’t bill anything. Payment was the responsibility of the patient, and many pharmacies carried revolving charge accounts to help patients who mailed their receipts to their insurance company and were waiting to be reimbursed. The most that a“drug clerk”had to do regarding insurance was to pull a profile and write down what the patient had received and have the form signed by the pharmacist so that the patient could mail it in. There weren’t nearly as many drugs 20 years ago as there are now. More drugs means more potential for drug interactions and error. More drugs means more expensive meds, and more meds that are not covered by insurance plans. When things are“not covered”, typically the pharmacist now contacts the physician and assists the physician in prescribing a similar med that IS covered, or in obtaining authorization to fill a prescription in spite of the formulary. People, insurance companies have taken our healthcare system and they are bleeding us all dry.
 
Posted by: Marie | July 27, 2007, 6:47 pm 6:47 pm
 
people don’t understand the tremendous pressure the pharmasist is under, in addition to the techs…Working for a national chain pharmacy we’re expected to meet script quotas…Can you believe they gauge you on this and that if it’s somehow under what’s budgeted then they perceive that as not meeting expectations. There is no way you can control who goes to what pharmacy and at what time someone will be given a script to fill…it’s like these executives are banking on people to be constantly sick. Then there is the fact that more then 75% of the time customers who pick up their medication become highly argumentative with Rx personnel if their paticular medication isn’t covered or they’re actually trying to fill the script before it can actually be filled. there are federal mandates that prohibate certain medications from being dispensed prior to when they were originally filled.
mistakes are made on both sides of the gamate both by doctors and pharmacists…it’s human nature, no matter how highly trianed or educated you are it’s inevitable that a mistake will be made, especially is a high stress environment such as a pharmacy. Little do people know that the average chain pharmacy on any given week is filling between 2-3 thousand scripts in which all of these are 15 minutes or less…many times although you walk up the the rx counter and there is no line they’re always getting E-scripts and scripts being faxed in from doctors offices.. It’s also important that people who are taking medication educate themselves on what their medication looks like and the MG’s you’re taking…You should never assume anything and just pop something into your mouth without first checking out the medications characteristics.
 
Posted by: Ken | August 15, 2007, 4:07 pm 4:07 pm
 
Pointing the finger is not enough. Point out the problems and work on possible solutions. We should all feel fortunate that somebody is willing to do this job.
 
Posted by: pookie | September 16, 2007, 9:14 pm 9:14 pm
 
I went to a grocery store pharmacy. Dropped off a script for my daughters emergancy seizure medicine(diastat acudial)it is a rectial gel. Her dosage is 15mg. First I had to tell them how to order the medicine. It is like a big syringe and they set it at doctor ordered dosage. I had to explain to them they needed to order the 20mg. size and set the dial to 15mg.
Upon picking up the medicine Thankfully I Noticed that they never bothered to set the dial correctly!!?? Even if the pharmacy had never filled this before,there are so many recources that the pharmacy could have checked into before letting a coustomer walk out with a incorrect dose.The pharmaceutical company that makes the drug offers instructions on thier website…call the docotrs office that wrote the script…or maybe check with other pharmacys in thier chain.
As far as I am concerned they put my 11 yr. old daughters life at risk!!!
 
Posted by: Amy | September 22, 2007, 5:11 am 5:11 am
 
I just started working as a pharmacy tech at a large Grocery Store Chain.
I have been there two months and am quitting tomorrow!
I am 44 w/ a college degree and eager to learn. Well, there is no trainer available. That doesn’t stop the twenty line deep list of pateints waiting for the script in 15 minutes, or the drive thru, or the rude people wanting me to ring their groceries. On top of that I work with all kids in their 20′s who don’t want to answer any questions about the work, help me out, but leave me in these dire circumstances. all without lunch, break, or pee time, let along if there is a phone call to be made. I thought i would love working in a pharmacy, its my worst nightmare come true. Oh and the pay 7.85 an hour.
CIndy
 
Posted by: CIndy | October 8, 2007, 11:18 pm 11:18 pm
 
I am a 20 year old college student and I have been working for retail pharmacy for about 2 years. I am a pharmacy technician and I could not believe the things that were said in 20/20. Fist: technicians are not the way they portray them. We are required to be certified by the PTCB and I can honestly say that all my associates are very smart and take the job seriously. Second: a 6 year college degree is not required for the job technicians do (data entry, filling, ordering and cashiering), checking the final product is the reason why the pharmacist is there.
Third: 20/20 said misfills are not tracked, they are wrong. Misfills are reported and are tracked, that is how pharmacies know where the problems are and how to fix them. Fourth: The working conditions for pharmacy staff are horrible. Most patients expect a prescription to be filled instantaneously, phones are ringing constantly, there are always problems with insurances, doctors write horrible and cannot even identify themselves (sometimes all we get is an illegible signature), people are rude and ignorant (they do not know what medications they are on, cannot leave cell-phone conversations for later, do not listen to pharmacists when counseling, they can’t even identify or get mad if asked their own address to insure the prescription will be sold to the right patient…etc, etc…), and we have to watch out for fake prescriptions, which we get a lot. Fifth: we do not ask the patients for a counseling waiver, that is the most stupid thing I have ever heard of. Counseling is offered, and like a comment above said, if you want counseling all you have to do is get it, no one will say“no mam, the pharmacist is too busy to counsel you!”What frustrates me the most, though, is that people don’t take the initiative to check themselves what they are taking. All they read is“take 1 daily”and that is all they do, they dont look at the name, don’t read the literature and do not check the drug size, shape and color that is also included in the literature. We actually have people every day saying the want a refill on their“white round pill”but don’t know the name or what it is for and get mad if we tell them we don’t know either (there are millions of white, rounded pills). So the bottom line is that while error do occur, we try as hard as we can so that they do not, I think that the biggest challenges are patients themselves (because of their apathy and lack of understanding to what we do) and the doctors ambiguity on prescriptions. By the way I don’t want to sound like a people hater because I am not. I love people, and what I do is satisfactory and that both pharmacist and pharmacy technicians do the best to ensure patient safety.
 
Posted by: Walg Tech | October 29, 2007, 6:00 am 6:00 am
 
I understand the natural urge by some in the health care profession to become defensive, but the fact remains that there are gaping holes in our health care system that endanger peoples lives. Pharmacists, technicians and nurses are the gatekeepers to monitor errors. As a health care professional still practicing with prescriptive authority and a trial lawyer who has investigated these cases I can say two words: NO EXCUSES. Solve the probem.
 
Posted by: JOE FLORES RN,MSN,CCRN,FNP,JD | November 4, 2007, 10:12 pm 10:12 pm
 
There is no excuse for the lack of staff in a pharmacy, the inability for a pharmacist to take a bathroom break,
a lunch break. Then for all the nights, holidays and weekends worked management makes the pharmacist find coverage for their own weekend off or their own vacation.
Pharmacists are professionals who have gone to school 6-8 years. The chain drug stores treat them like marbles.
They are not treated as professionals. They are a number to make the most money for the chain stores with the least amount of help and the least amount of management skills to support their needs.
Pharmacists have to manage themselves. They have no support from the upper levels of management. It is a crime if 20/20 would like to research that.
There were so many mistakes made in a chain store in MA that the board of pharmacy had to force the chain to hire a consultant to review why this happened. The chain store was not fixing the problem.
Pharmacists are treated very poorly in the world of retail pharmacy. There is no union and no one is willing to take a stand against the many inequities and gross miscare they face in every work day.
If you have to worry about going to the bathroom, eating lunch and not being able to take a day off for anything unless you find your own coverage (management passes that on to the pharmacist) imagine how you would feel on a daily basis. Minor rights of the average individual are not provided for a retail pharmacist every day at work.
It is a crime and all for the american dollar. Hope those people at the top executive level enjoy their profits and realize the havoc they wreak on those out in the field. They probably have never spent a day in the field and are
clueless of the pharmacists quality of life,
 
Posted by: BXW | June 10, 2008, 10:28 am 10:28 am
 
This is the result of pure greed and capitalism without morality.
The bottom line is the profit, not the safety of the patient, the adequate staff or work enviornment for the pharmacist.
Corporate pharmacies treat pharmacists worse than those who work at Mcdonalds.
No lunc, no bathroom time, no days off, vacation time without finding your own
coverage.
Imagine trying to work in a profession where accuracy means so much yet you can not go to the bathroom, eat or take any time off without finding your own replacement. Pharmacists are not given respect by their employers.
Bottom line is profit. It is sad for the health care consumer and the individual who decided to work in the pharmacy profession.
Aren’t there laws about no breaks, no lunch, no time off in the 21 st century.
Try working under those conditions.
 
Posted by: BXW | June 10, 2008, 10:36 am 10:36 am
 
The problem needs to be solved at the executive level of these retail pharmacies.
They are putting their customers at risk and their employees for the sake of additional profit.
There really needs to be a 20/20 show done on the working conditions of those staff pharmacists. You would not believe how they are treated.
 
Posted by: BXW | June 10, 2008, 10:39 am 10:39 am
 
Great…I love this post, I got more info here, Thanks.Really happy to read this, I too interested in pharmacy blogs….I am looking for anyone who has had a successful experience with Any Pharmacy…
 
Posted by: Compound Pharmacy | July 18, 2008, 4:18 am 4:18 am
 
I can understand the defensiveness of the pharmacy staff to this report. Many have trained for years in their professions, have worked hard to get where they are. I also understand that we are human and fallible but the simple basic fact is the lack of quality control. I am a 48 year old quadriplegic and take several medications. I have made it my business to know what medications I take, what they look like, how they are dispensed, and what side effects and interactions they have. That knowledge is what kept me from taking Nitro that was placed in my prescription bottle instead of Baclofen. When I questioned the staff regarding the incorrect medication, I was told that they had probably changed companies they purchased from and it would be alright. I had to raise a “Stink” to get it corrected and am thankful they were able to contact the other patient before they took my Baclofen instead of their Nitro. If this were all, I maybe could forgive, but the same pharmacy chain recently filled a prescription for my mother of methylprednisolone to counteract allergic reactions prior to a testing procedure. Her script contained a quantity of 20 and instructed her to take 8 tonight and then 12 tomorrow. She called her doctor for verification only to find out that the script was for 3 pills and was giving the proper dosage. Had she taken the script as dispensed, it would have killed her. Now we have two family members placed in danger by the same pharmacy. It gets worse. My father was diagnosed with a CNS Lymphoma and was given methotrexate through IV in the hospital, dispensed over a 24 hour period. His third treatment was mislabeled to be dispensed over 2 hours and not 24. He died 3 weeks later without receiving the benefit of the estimated six months he would have had without any treatment. Like I said where is the quality control? Should we forgive these errors? NOWAY NO HOW!
 
Posted by: Nena H | July 22, 2008, 7:05 pm 7:05 pm
 
It really irks me in the media when I see pharmacies blasted for the mistakes they make. Ya know what? We do make mistakes. Usually we catch them, but occasionally one will get out. Of those that get out, 99% of them we realize what we did and rectify the situation in a timely manner. We are human after all and are not perfect.
Then you have exposes on Dateline and other‘news’outlets exposing such mistakes. Think about what we do in a day. For instance last week, during an eight hour shift, we filled 342 prescriptions. That’s one prescription being filled every 43 seconds all day long. On top of that, at last check, our accuracy rate was in the 98th percentile. Funny that these outlets often leave that part out.
What is even more irksome is the fact that they leave out to true culprits of errors, the doctor’s office.
How are we supposed to function with errors like this being sent to us? Do you know how often we’ll get a script for Amoxcillin only to have, right on the Rx, an allergy to Amoxicillin? Honestly we have to call one of the office’s at least a half dozen times a day just to clarify something which should not have been wrong anyway. It could just be the hospitals here, but I saw the same thing when I lived in another state. A lot of it has to do with e-prescribing and picking the wrong item from a drop down menu, but that’s no excuse to not double check. Hell we have to triple check things in the pharmacy before they even get out to the patient.
Yet we’re the one’s who are blamed for screwing up. One mistake out of thousands and thousands of prescriptions, and we’re chastised. Never mind the fact that we routinely fixed a dozen errors a day, that doesn’t matter.
To paraphrase the late Rodney Dangerfield“We don’t get no respect.”
 
Posted by: Debi | July 27, 2008, 2:42 pm 2:42 pm
 
This is only for the blog owner I just want to thanks this guy because of it I get lots of information from it ….
thanks for the info you provided
 
Posted by: Pharmacy | July 30, 2008, 2:42 am 2:42 am
 
I am a Nationally Certified Technician as well, and I am not stupid. I am also human.
On the whole, it is a societal problem, as most have underlined in their responses.
Relative to the fast-food analogies, one of the first pharmacist I ever worked with used to say,“this is not McDonalds”. No one at our store ever rushed to sacrafice the health of our patients.
If society doesn’t change now, we’ll never change. In the pharmacy there will still be filling errors because they are being rushed.
Even McDonalds is rushed; if someone tells them they are allergic to peanuts (and most things are cooked with something that has peanuts, or peanut oil), and it somehow contaminates their food, what then? Blame McDonalds instead of community/mail-order/hospital pharmacies?
Last note: HIPPA violations. I found it amusing how many posts–especially from patients on this article–posted what medications they were taking. Just simply saying the name or the color of someone’s shirt with their phone number or given name is a HIPPA violation.
 
Posted by: Alex | December 2, 2008, 9:31 pm 9:31 pm
 
I just love your writing! Very well written and nice thoughts of you. Thanks and hope to read more from you.
 
Posted by: Kosher Vitamins | June 16, 2010, 11:00 pm 11:00 pm
 
Great article, we like your blog post and we will pass it on and recommend your writing. We will save your blog to our social network favorites, so please approve our comment, thanks much,
 
Posted by: Canadian drugs | June 20, 2010, 9:50 pm 9:50 pm
 
You are really a great author of this article! Great writing! You are helping people to enlighten their minds in different aspects in life through your excellent writing skills! Thanks so much!
 
Posted by: Canada pharmacy | July 23, 2010, 9:39 pm 9:39 pm
 
I was wondering if some one have the Eye of Horus, do it mining that person is King Tutankhamen? I believe who have the Eye of Horus and can prov it he should be Crown King Tutankhamen. He Should be crowned with he’s crown The Wedjet Crown. Can you send me your answer to my Facebook message box.
 
Posted by: justin small | August 27, 2011, 3:19 am 3:19 am
 Top 
Leave a Reply

Do you have more information about this topic? If so, please click here to contact the editors of ABC News.

 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 
 About Investigative 
Exclusive and breaking news stories from Chief Investigative Correspondent Brian Ross and the investigative team.
 Categories 
 Crimes Against Christmas Investigative Middle East Nation Picture This: ABC News Press Release Religion World 
 Top Posts 
 ‘Top 100 Tollway Violators’Owe More Than $9 Million Today in Pictures: Olympic Torch, Manhattanhenge, Bankrupt City Photos: Bubbles In Motion Miami Purse Snatcher Drags Victim With His Car Window Washers Rescued from 42nd Floor of NYC High-Rise 
 Top Stories on ABC News 
 
 Watch: Sun Releases Strong Solar Flare 
 
 Photos: Best and Worst Olympic Team Uniforms 
 
 Penn State Board Unsure of Paterno&apos;s Legacy 
 
 Death, Greed at the Dentist: American Children at Risk 
 
 Israel Accused of Killing Arafat 
 
 Subscribe 
 RSS 
 
 Twitter Facebook
	</body>
</document>
