<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008924" url="http://grandtheftauto.ign.com/wiki/GTA_San_Andreas_Girlfriends" time="2012-07-13-02:21" support="3" score="0.002315984417895126" bingtitle="GTA San Andreas Girlfriends - IGN Grand Theft Auto Wiki" webtitle="GTA San Andreas Girlfriends - IGN Grand Theft Auto Wiki">
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>But pulling up in a car with ... She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is ... need to date her enough, in order to get ...</description>
	<body>
		Login | Register 
 Home 
 Home Page Articles Topics Index Poll Index News Index Submit News RSS Feed 
 GTA Map 
 Liberty City Map GTA IV Map Images GTA Map Help 
 Missions 
 Missions Home GTA 4 Missions List Add Missions Mission Help 
 Leaderboard 
 Top Contributors My Contributions About GTA Hood Points 
 Cheats/Guides 
 GTA IV Guide GTA IV FAQ GTA IV Cheats All GTA Guides 
 GTA Wiki Images/Videos 
 GTA IV Screenshots GTA IV Videos All GTA Screenshots All GTA Videos 
 Forums 
 IGN GTA Boards Hot Topics 
 About 
 Site FAQ Staff Contact Us 
 
 GTA Wiki Home    |    Ballad of Gay Tony    |    Chinatown Wars    |    Lost and Damned    |    GTA IV    |    Vice City    |    Liberty City    |    San Andreas    |    GTA: Vice City    |    GTA Hood » IGN Grand Theft Auto Wiki Read Wiki Page | Discussion | Edit Wiki Page | History | Upload Image 
GTA San Andreas Girlfriends

Girlfriend Overview
 
During the mission Burning Desire you will need to rescue a girl from a burning building. After you do this, she becomes your girlfriend whether you like it or not. This is CJ&apos;s first girlfriend, but not the last. You can date up to 6 girls in total all at the same time, if you want.

Each girl becomes available as you progress through the game but not all of them are aquired through missions. Some of them can be found around San Andreas and it is up to you to meet each girl&apos;s tastes. We&apos;ll go into that in more detail later in this guide.
 
Finding a Girlfriend
 
First off, you have to find them. Denise Robinson and Millie Perkins will pose no problem, because you meet these girls during missions. The others however take a bit more searching.

Below is the locations of each girlfriend, not found during missions. Each girl has a blue arrow above their heads and will be standing around doing various things, like talking to someone or shooting a gun.
 
Sex Appeal
 
Sex appeal is very important when getting a girlfriend and turning up to a date. Most of the sex appeal is achieved through the clothing, tattoos and haircut CJ has. But pulling up in a car with high sex appeal also contributes well (check out the vehicle images guide for sex appeal values of each car)
 
Dating Progress
 
Once you start dating a girl, your initial progress with her will be 15%. This will go up when you 
date her with a successful date. It will go down, if you dont date her, or a date goes badly. 
Each girl has their own unique favourite type of date (which we will go into later in the guide), but each girl likes flowers. Flowers add a tiny amount of progress to the date and can be found all over san andreas, but later in this guide i will show you the nearest flowers to the girlfriends home. (to give flowers, select them from your weapons and go up to her and press L1. You may need to press it several times) So why should you bother progressing with girlfriends? Well each girl offers rewards for higher dating progression, which will be detailed later.
 
Successful Dating
 
Successful dates depend on a number of factors. Firstly the condition in which CJ arrives on the date. Make sure CJ has high sex appeal and make sure your car isnt a wreck either.
There are several types of dates, depending on what girl you are dating. There are drinking dates, food dates, dancing dates and driving dates. When you meet your girl, she will tell you what she wants to do. If it&apos;s a drinking/food/dancing date, icons will appear on the map to show you where the locations of these places are. Driving dates depend on which girl you are dating, but can range from cruising about, driving fast as possible or driveby&apos;s.
Whatever date you take your girl on, DONT WASTE HER. You might expect her to appear again, but she doesnt. Once she&apos;s dead, she&apos;s dead.
 
The Girls
 
 Denise Robinson Helpful map: Denise&apos;s Map
Location: Do the mission Burning Desire and you will meet denise and become her girlfriend in that mission.
First Appearance: In the mission Burning Desire.
Tastes: She doesnt seem to be bothered about CJ&apos;s appearance as you meet this girl in a mission.
At Home: Come by her house after 16:00 hours.
Date she likes: If she asks to do a driveby, go into enemy gang territories and try to find some enemy gang members. She will lean out the window and shoot at them when you get close. Keep doing this until she wants to go home. If she asks for a food date, take her to the cluckin bell south of her house.
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: After 40-50% progress 
Rewards: After 50% progress with denise, the green hustler parked outside her house becomes unlocked, but if you get a tractor or tow truck, you can drag the hustler to your garage and unlock it that way. After 100% progress you will get a pimp suit. Seeing as you get one later in the game much more easily, there doesnt seem much point in dating this girl.

 Helena Wankstein Helpful map: Helena&apos;s Map
Location: Go to the small town of blueberry and find ammunation. If she is there at that time, you will here her firing a gun at a target range beside ammunation up some steps.
First Appearance: Because her pickup point is in the badlands, she doesnt come availabe for dating until you unlock San Fierro and the Badlands
Tastes: Doesnt like much muscle or fat. Make sure CJ has less than 25% muscle and as little fat as possible, but make sure he has alot of sex appeal at the same time. Get a nice bike and ride it up to her on the balcony and get off it to ask her for a date. This will give you a little bit extra sex appeal. 
At Home: Come by her house after 14:00 hours.
Date she likes: Helena likes to eat in restaurants and the closest place to take her is the reastaurant in Rodeo, Los Santos. If she wants a driving date, drive slowly because she doesnt like speed. 
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: After 70% progress 
Rewards: Right from the moment you start dating her, a Bandito appears at her farm. Alsoa flamethrower, chainsaw, molotov cocktails, and a pistol appear in a shed next to the farm building. At 50% progress with Helena, it is reported that you get the keys to the bandito, but actually, you can drive the bandito from the moment it spawns there. At 100% you get country style clothes (oooo how rewarding). Overall, there is not much point in dating her to 100%, but just going out with gives you a Bandito.

 Michelle Cannes Helpful map: Michelle&apos;s Map
Location: Enter the driving school and she can be found inside talking to someone.
First Appearance: As soon as you can get into the driving school
Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.)
At Home: Just after 00.00 hours. (it appears as though it&apos;s difficult to catch Michelle in. Lot&apos;s of people have reported her to be &apos;never in&apos; and I myself have had trouble catching her in. Keep trying though, she will eventually be at home). 
Date she likes: She really likes drinking dates so take her to one of those, if she wants that kind of date. Sometimes she&apos;ll want you to drive fast, so do that but try not to crash. There is also a special type of date that involves helena driving the car instead of CJ. When on this type of date, helena will drive and you can control the camera. Dont get out the car though otherwise it will fail the date. 
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: After 40% progress 
Rewards: As soon as you start dating her, you can use the garage next to her apartment, which acts as a pay n spray only it&apos;s free. After 50% progress, the monster truck that spawns next to her apartment becomes unlocked and at 100% you get the racing suit outfit. Overall, she&apos;s worth going out with for the monster truck and the free pay n spray, but as for the suit, it doesnt seem worth it.

 Katie Zhan Helpful map: Katie&apos;s Map
Location: At the north east corner of the golf course in San Fierro, katie is practicing Marital arts near some bushes. You should be able to see her easily from the road.
First Appearance: As soon as you have access to San Fierro
Tastes: Lot&apos;s of muscle and lots of sex appeal. Try to aim for about 75% muscle or more.
At Home: Just after 12.00 hours
Date she likes: If she requests a food date, take her to the diner just north of her house. If she requests a drive, then you&apos;ll have to cruise around. Take her to china town to increase her fun meter quicker.
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: about 50% progression in dating.
Rewards: Dating Katie allows you to come out of hospital with your weapons, which is cool enough reason to date her. At 50% you will be able to unlock the hearse outside her house (dont ask me why there is hearse outside her house) and at 100% you will unlock the Medic uniform.

 Barbara Schternvart Helpful map: Barbara&apos;s Map
Location: Find the sheriffs building in El Quebrados, The desert. She&apos;ll be outside talking to someone.
First Appearance: As soon as you get access to Las Venturas and the desert.
Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.)
At Home: Just after 00.00 hours
Date she likes: If she wants a food date, take her to the diner just south west of where you pick her up. Ocasionally she will ask to go dancing which is a real pain, because your pretty far from any dance clubs. On driving dates, she will want you to cruise and not speed.
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: After 60% progress 
Rewards: A very cool reward when you first start dating her. She is a cop, so when you get busted, you get to keep your weapons and no money is taken from you. At 50% you will get to drive her ranger that spawns outside the sheriffs office. At 100% you will recieve the police uniform in your wardrobe. However, the police uniform does not let you get in the military areas such as the Naval base or restricted area in the desert without getting a wanted level.

 Millie Perkins Helpful map: Millie&apos;s Map
Location: You will meet Millie in the mission &apos;Key to her heart&apos;. You will automatically become her girlfriend during this mission.
First Appearance: During the mission &apos;key to her heart&apos;
Tastes: Because it&apos;s for a mission, there is no special taste that you need to satisfy in order to go out with her.
At Home: Just after 12.00 hours
Date she likes: Take her to a restaurant if she wants a food date. She also likes driving dates that are just cruising around. Wear the gimp suit to a date and she&apos;ll just want to go indoors for some &apos;fiki fiki&apos; (if you dont know what im talking about, dont ask!).
Invites you in for &quot;coffee&quot;: Wear the gimp suit and you can do it anytime.
Rewards: Dating Millie is part of the main story. You need to date her enough, in order to get a key card to Caligula&apos;s casino. You will get this key card around 35%. At 50% you can drive her pink Club, which is parked outside her house when she is home. No reward for 100%.
 
 Spotted Around The Hood 1.) Out of the closet... - Brucie and Roman ...
 Updated by:
	</body>
</document>
