<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008841" url="http://boards.cruisecritic.com/archive/index.php/t-680346.html" time="2012-07-13-02:17" support="1" score="0.0012400993706072805" bingtitle="Food Poisoning?? [Archive] - Cruise Critic Message Boards" webtitle="Food Poisoning?? [Archive]  - Cruise Critic Message Boards">
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>... on Mariner than it would be getting it at a fast food ... I always make it a point to take a good look at my food ... bathroom door with a clean paper towel to avoid picking ...</description>
	<body>
		Cruise Critic Message Boards &gt; Cruise Lines&quot;P - Z&quot; &gt; Royal Caribbean International &gt;Food Poisoning?? PDA 
View Full Version : Food Poisoning?? 
 Mac777daddy December 27th, 2007, 09:56 PM I was reading this forum and noticed a few people state they got food poisoning the first or second night into their cruise. We were on Disney Magic a couple years ago and noticed there were waterless hand cleaners all over the ship. I do not think these will help with food poisoning though. I would hate to get food poisoning on my cruise or have one of my kids get food poison. Are there any foods to stay away from on a cruise? We are going on Marnier of the Sea 1/6/08. Thanks FL_Cruiser64 December 27th, 2007, 10:04 PM I was reading this forum and noticed a few people state they got food poisoning the first or second night into their cruise. We were on Disney Magic a couple years ago and noticed there were waterless hand cleaners all over the ship. I do not think these will help with food poisoning though. I would hate to get food poisoning on my cruise or have one of my kids get food poison. Are there any foods to stay away from on a cruise? We are going on Marnier of the Sea 1/6/08. Thanks

Food poisoning?

Are you talking about brother Noro, the virus? HeavySurf December 27th, 2007, 10:09 PM Food poisoning is quite different from the more common Norovirus outbreaks on ships. Noro is not passed through food, but through touching surfaces that have been touched by someone with the virus. Food poisoning comes from eating contaminated food or spoiled food.

The symptoms can seem the same, though. It can be confusing. A perfect example is what Hubby and I experienced on a summer cruise. He got really sick a couple of hours after we ate dinner in a premium restaurant. He was sick all night and much of the next day with a fever, exhaustion and stomach pain. I stayed in the room with him to keep him company and try to help, bring him water, etc. He was sure he had eaten bad food at the restaurant.

That next night I get what has to be called explosive vomiting, fever, jaw rattling chills, stomach pain, exhaustion, headache...I forget what all. Next day I went to the clinic and was diagnosed with Norovirus and given a Phenergan injection. The illness lasted almost four days. I am told that is very long for Norovirus.

Now the question is--did Hubby really have food poisoning as he believed or did he have Norovirus which he in turn gave to me or exactly what did happen? It is really hard to say.

One thing is true. A person can die with really severe food poisoning. My guess is that only people who already have greatly compromised health would die with the Norovirus, but I surely felt as if I was going to die. Mac777daddy December 27th, 2007, 10:14 PM I was talking of food posioning. Some guy stated he ate at Windjammer on Marnier of the Seas and soon after eating nachos he was sick and stayed sick for 4 days. This would not be good if my one year old son or four year old daughter came in contact with food poisoning. Just curious is there were some foods to stay away from? Like mayo or patato salad etc....... Jimmers December 27th, 2007, 10:15 PM Mariner is my favorite ship. I haven&apos;t heard of any reports of food poisoning on any ships. There are occasional reports of norovirus on various ships. Best defense is frequent washing of the hands and avoiding hand to mouth contact. At various times the ships will have the hand sanitizers at the dining room entrances but handwashing is your best defense.

Cases of norovirus do occur but but I wouldn&apos;t be too concerned with it. I&apos;ve been on 4 cruises, 3 with RCI and I haven&apos;t seen a sick passenger on any of them. The odds are you won&apos;t either.

Have fun.

Jimmers Sue L December 27th, 2007, 10:18 PM I was talking of food posioning. Some guy stated he ate at Windjammer on Marnier of the Seas and soon after eating nachos he was sick and stayed sick for 4 days. This would not be good if my one year old son or four year old daughter came in contact with food poisoning. Just curious is there were some foods to stay away from? Like mayo or patato salad etc.......


You are more likely to get something in your own town then on a cruise ship, whether it is a virus or improperly cooked or stored food. Jimmers December 27th, 2007, 10:19 PM I was talking of food posioning. Some guy stated he ate at Windjammer on Marnier of the Seas and soon after eating nachos he was sick and stayed sick for 4 days. This would not be good if my one year old son or four year old daughter came in contact with food poisoning. Just curious is there were some foods to stay away from? Like mayo or patato salad etc.......

Food is as safe as any you&apos;d eat at any restaurant.

Jimmers Mac777daddy December 27th, 2007, 10:22 PM Good to hear. This is my first cruise on Royal so I hope it is a nice as Disney. We had a great time on Disney Magic. Maybe I will back a bottle of the water free hand sanatizer with me. reallyitsmema December 27th, 2007, 10:28 PM I read that review too and was surprised that no one had commented before. Use your head, wash your hands often, if you see someone touch something that they shouldn&apos;t, choose another item. The Mariner is a beautiful ship, we loved it so much we are going again in June.

Some of what I read here before my cruise got me nervous too. I actually stopped reading here the week prior to my cruise so I wouldn&apos;t have to be sedated:eek: :p :D Sue L December 27th, 2007, 10:29 PM Good to hear. This is my first cruise on Royal so I hope it is a nice as Disney. We had a great time on Disney Magic. Maybe I will back a bottle of the water free hand sanatizer with me.


The best defense is THOROUGHLY washing your hands, the NORO is a virus and most of those hand sanitizer are anti-bacterials which do nothing. Jimmers December 27th, 2007, 10:53 PM Some of what I read here before my cruise got me nervous too. I actually stopped reading here the week prior to my cruise so I wouldn&apos;t have to be sedated:eek: :p :D

That&apos;s reallyitsmema funny. I&apos;m having multiple laughs and I didn&apos;t even know men could have those. Brad1185 December 27th, 2007, 10:56 PM After 40 something cruises, I have never got any food poisoning. Having gone on a lot of galley tours, the galleys look cleaner than any restaurant kitchen that I have ever seen (I have seen some bad ones).

They load new food each cruise, so I would think they dont have a lot of old food sitting around or going bad.

Anyone handling food always wears gloves, which is impressive.

I cannot think of anything food wise that I would stay away from.

Relax and enjoy. reallyitsmema December 27th, 2007, 10:57 PM .... Bakincakes December 28th, 2007, 08:01 AM Perhaps pax like to believe that they have food poisoning rather than admit that they have the Noro?

That may explain why they didn&apos;t quarantine themselves and left their cabin while still feeling ill.

Why ruin their cruise and miss the chance to infect other pax?:rolleyes: Mac777daddy December 28th, 2007, 08:16 AM I am more concerned about my 1 year old and my 4 year old then myself. You know how kids are. I would hate for one of them to get sick. Yes its just a likely to happen in my home town the only difference is I can rush them to a hospital if needed. I am not sure how health care is on a ship?? Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 08:17 AM I was talking of food posioning. Some guy stated he ate at Windjammer on Marnier of the Seas and soon after eating nachos he was sick and stayed sick for 4 days. This would not be good if my one year old son or four year old daughter came in contact with food poisoning. Just curious is there were some foods to stay away from? Like mayo or patato salad etc.......


Hey it&apos;s me,&quot;some guy&quot;. Yes I did have food poisoning on that cruise. It was not Noro Virus however, thier were 115 confirmed cases on our cruise per the medical staff. I&apos;ve been in the medical field for over 8 years. I know how to wash my hands and keep clean.
Another thing. If it had been determined that I was indeed infected with the Noro Virus I would not have been out and about the ship thank you very much. It amazes me how some people can take the little bit of information and assume so much more. I also did use my head and washed my hands often. I&apos;m not sure where that would help with food poisoning but hey, whatever makes you feel better reallyitsmema. Now if you will excuse me I have to go use my head.:mad: Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 08:22 AM Perhaps pax like to believe that they have food poisoning rather than admit that they have the Noro?

That may explain why they didn&apos;t quarantine themselves and left their cabin while still feeling ill.

Why ruin their cruise and miss the chance to infect other pax?:rolleyes:


Oh yeah that&apos;s it. I would much rather have Food Poisoning than the Noro. After all food poisoning feels sooo much better!! Of course I would also love nothing more than infecting the whole ship with the Noro Virus which encluded my two kids and girlfriend. Hell what I wouldn&apos;t give to get them sick on the only vacation they&apos;ve ever had.....you people...sheesh Mac777daddy December 28th, 2007, 08:39 AM Ronrocks...What was the boats excuse for the food poison? Bakincakes December 28th, 2007, 08:44 AM Oh yeah that&apos;s it. I would much rather have Food Poisoning than the Noro. After all food poisoning feels sooo much better!! Of course I would also love nothing more than infecting the whole ship with the Noro Virus which encluded my two kids and girlfriend. Hell what I wouldn&apos;t give to get them sick on the only vacation they&apos;ve ever had.....you people...sheesh


If you indeed in&quot;the medical field&quot;then you are aware the even washing your hands may not prevent the noro.

The point is that you assumed you had food poisoning and unless you were examined by a qualified medical officer and that was his/her diagnosis you may have had the Noro. Were you checked? Or were you concerned that if you were checked that you and your party may have been quarantined?

No one is questioning whether you were sick or not but the OP was wondering what foods to avoid on a cruise after your thread about being sick. Fact is that you may not have had food poisoning at all and his fears about his small children becoming sick from ill prepared food may be unfounded. Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 08:49 AM Ronrocks...What was the boats excuse for the food poison?

They never said. I told them what I had for dinner that day. They pulled the ground beef off the line. Don&apos;t get me wrong. I was not opset at RCCL. I was upset that this was our first vacation ever and I was the one who got it! I would not hesitate to eat at the WJ again. If you think about all the food they serve they do a great job. It could have been something as simple as the warmer under the pan not working..or turned on who knows. I know RCCL changes out the eating utencils every 4 hours and recleans them reguardless. Accidents happen I understand that. What I wont do is let people tell me it was my fault I got sick.
Mac777 I would not worry about the food on the ship. Have a great time and eat until you pop...just don&apos;t pop like I did!:eek: Mac777daddy December 28th, 2007, 08:53 AM Yeah I agree with ya. Its not your fault the last thing you want to do is get sick on a boat at sea. We didnt even think about getting sick on the disney boat, but I was not on a forum like I am now either. We will be cautious but not paranoid. Thanks for the info. Lionesss December 28th, 2007, 08:53 AM After reading every post on this thread, I would like to share what happenned to us.
The first day of our last (only) cruise we all eagerly got up and went to breakfast. We all ate the exact same thing except for my husband who went back to the breakfast bar and got cantelope. about 3 hours later his stomach started rumbling, and then he was very busy (Lower) in the library (bathroom) for about one hour off and on. He layed down, I made him have some tea, ginger ale and toast. He took a nap and then felt better. To this day I feel the cantelope was not cleaned properly. He said he tasted cantelope in his mouth for hours. So you never do really know for sure.
I feel if it was Noro, more people would have been sick, but, we did not here of any one else getting sick after breakfast either. Who really knows for sure. If it was sea sickness, I felt he would have been sick longer. Mac777daddy December 28th, 2007, 09:02 AM I guess we just say a prayer and hope for the best. Again I am not as worried about myself as I am about my young kids. Thanks Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 09:05 AM If you indeed in&quot;the medical field&quot;then you are aware the even washing your hands may not prevent the noro.

The point is that you assumed you had food poisoning and unless you were examined by a qualified medical officer and that was his/her diagnosis you may have had the Noro. Were you checked? Or were you concerned that if you were checked that you and your party may have been quarantined?

No one is questioning whether you were sick or not but the OP was wondering what foods to avoid on a cruise after your thread about being sick. Fact is that you may not have had food poisoning at all and his fears about his small children becoming sick from ill prepared food may be unfounded.

Some people amaze me. Here&apos;s what I did. I got sick on night two of the cruise. I figured heck I am sick but I&apos;m not going to let it ruin my cruise. As soon as I get done blowing my chow all over the sink and in the toilet I think I&apos;ll go down to the Promenade and have a drink. On the way there I will stop by and see my girls, because hey..if I have to be sick...so should you.
Or were you concerned that if you were checked that you and your party may have been quarantined? Oh you figured me out. I ALWAYS put the welfare and safety of myself before others. (it&apos;s a good trait to have in a firefighter)
Were you checked? Well you see I was going to get checked, but while I was sitting on the toilet throwing up in the sink I thought...hey this would make a fun excursion I hope it last!!:p Yes I was checked... Mac777daddy December 28th, 2007, 09:08 AM Maybe the key to this story is to just drink onboard and stay away from all food?? Liquid diet for 7 days? Hmm I would lose the weight I have been wanting to lose. Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 09:09 AM I guess we just say a prayer and hope for the best. Again I am not as worried about myself as I am about my young kids. Thanks

Again Mac,

As another poster said. You are much safer than eating the food on a cruise ship than at most of your local eating establishments. I would not hesitate to let me kids eat in the Windjammer again. Ronrocks! December 28th, 2007, 09:10 AM Maybe the key to this story is to just drink onboard and stay away from all food?? Liquid diet for 7 days? Hmm I would lose the weight I have been wanting to lose.

lol, very true!! depends on what kind of liquid your drinking!! You drink the right stuff it will kill the germs..:eek: katiel53 December 28th, 2007, 09:18 AM I was talking of food posioning. Some guy stated he ate at Windjammer on Marnier of the Seas and soon after eating nachos he was sick and stayed sick for 4 days. This would not be good if my one year old son or four year old daughter came in contact with food poisoning. Just curious is there were some foods to stay away from? Like mayo or patato salad etc.......

I read that too, but I really think, even though I have nothing to back it up, that the guy got noro. I think it was coincidental that it happened after eating Nachos. If he got food poisoning from the Nachos, lots of others would have had it too. He didn&apos;t mention that a lot of people on the ship were sick, so that&apos;s what makes me think it wasn&apos;t food poisoning.

It&apos;s not any more likely that your one year or four year old would get food poisoning on Mariner than it would be getting it at a fast food restaurant or a buffet. The food on the ship is probably safer than it is land side. Just be diligent in washing your hands and your children&apos;s hands and tell them, I know it&apos;s hard, to keep their hands away from their mouthes. Enjoy the cruise and don&apos;t panic. Newbcruiser1 December 29th, 2007, 04:15 PM Are there any foods to stay away from on a cruise? We are going on Marnier of the Sea 1/6/08. Thanks

I wouldn&apos;t say there&apos;s anything specific to avoid. I always make it a point to take a good look at my food and make sure it&apos;s cold if it&apos;s supposed to be cold (especially creamy foods), hot if it&apos;s supposed to be, and fully cooked. If anything looks weird or un-indentifiable, I don&apos;t eat it. And luckily I have yet to get sick from food while on vacation, or at home.

As far as picking up viruses goes, the best thing is to wash your hands PROPERLY and frequently, and avoid touching your mouth (often hard for kids). And while hand sanitizer doesn&apos;t kill every type of bug, it kills a lot of them, so I make it a point to Purell my hands frequently as well, particularly if I&apos;m on vacation, or in a public place touching a lot of things. Also if you can avoid touching railings, elevator buttons, and doorknobs, that&apos;s good as well. On our cruise, I made sure to open the bathroom door with a clean paper towel to avoid picking up new scum on my hands after washing them.

Most importantly, don&apos;t stress over it, and HAVE FUN! :) Ronrocks! December 29th, 2007, 05:16 PM I read that too, but I really think, even though I have nothing to back it up, that the guy got noro. I think it was coincidental that it happened after eating Nachos. If he got food poisoning from the Nachos, lots of others would have had it too. He didn&apos;t mention that a lot of people on the ship were sick, so that&apos;s what makes me think it wasn&apos;t food poisoning.

It&apos;s not any more likely that your one year or four year old would get food poisoning on Mariner than it would be getting it at a fast food restaurant or a buffet. The food on the ship is probably safer than it is land side. Just be diligent in washing your hands and your children&apos;s hands and tell them, I know it&apos;s hard, to keep their hands away from their mouthes. Enjoy the cruise and don&apos;t panic.

Well I think the guy had food poisoning. Simply because the guy was me and I have a doctor to back it up. katiel53 December 30th, 2007, 09:00 AM Well I think the guy had food poisoning. Simply because the guy was me and I have a doctor to back it up.


Sorry, I posted this when I only read about half of the posts. I had been reading other posts regarding Noro and what you had seemed to me to be the same. As I said, I had nothing to back it up. Hope you are feeling better now. Ronrocks! December 30th, 2007, 06:53 PM Sorry, I posted this when I only read about half of the posts. I had been reading other posts regarding Noro and what you had seemed to me to be the same. As I said, I had nothing to back it up. Hope you are feeling better now.

I am feeling much better now Katie thank you. I know everyone is quick to diagnose any illness on a ship Noro these days. We did have 115 confirmed cases on our cruise alone. Not that it matters...I was sick either way. HeavySurf December 30th, 2007, 07:53 PM RonRocks, I&apos;m asking out of ignorance and not disprespect. How does one know if vomiting and diarrhea are food poisoning and not Noro? Hubby was sure he had food poisoning on Liberty, but then I came down with Noro the next night, so we thought in retrospect he had Noro too, but how can one know for sure?

How does the doctor know for sure (unless a line of patients come to his office and say they ate bad nachos for lunch in the Windjammer and immediately fell ill, but no one else comes who is similarly ill.

Is there one specific symptom of food poisoning that clearly sets it apart from Noro? leftyrn December 30th, 2007, 08:19 PM RonRocks, I&apos;m asking out of ignorance and not disprespect. How does one know if vomiting and diarrhea are food poisoning and not Noro? Hubby was sure he had food poisoning on Liberty, but then I came down with Noro the next night, so we thought in retrospect he had Noro too, but how can one know for sure?

How does the doctor know for sure (unless a line of patients come to his office and say they ate bad nachos for lunch in the Windjammer and immediately fell ill, but no one else comes who is similarly ill.

Is there one specific symptom of food poisoning that clearly sets it apart from Noro?

A doctors diagnosis of food poisening is only as accurate as the history he is given and if the doctor confirms with lab testing which would consist of a stool sample that shows salmonella or other food born illness. Coralc December 30th, 2007, 08:35 PM I had land based Noro about 15 years ago, and thought I was going to die. I did end up in the ER 6 hours for dehydration/rehydration. I only found out later, that it was Noro/rotovirus because about half of the attendees came down with it Monday after a Saturday evening get together. One of the children had it (something), and it wasn&apos;t food borne because it was just cocktails and not shared food.. :o Shelli December 30th, 2007, 09:12 PM The best defense is THOROUGHLY washing your hands, the NORO is a virus and most of those hand sanitizer are anti-bacterials which do nothing.

Actually, most hand sanitizers are alcohol based, and therefore, they are effective against both bacteria and viruses. abridalmaven December 30th, 2007, 09:19 PM Thanksgiving evening on the ride home I felt nauseous. I did not throw up but felt like it. I felt better the next morning, but after I laid down, I could not lift my head off of the pillow I was so nauseous. My husband and I ate the same things except one low carb cake which others did also eat with no ill effects. I did not have noro, or food poisioning. I am highly sensitive to sugar alcohols in some sweetners and I was having an allergic reaction. My sis tried a new recipe with stevia mixed with sugar alcohols. I no longer eat things she makes with that combo. Not all reactions are caused by the same thing. And since I do have certain food allergies ( cottonseed oil is one) I avoid eating those things ( which ususally are in processed foods which I no longer eat).
In the past I have had noro/food poisoning type reactions from the trigger foods.Throwing up or eliminating it is a good thing for me, it takes the offending thing out of my system quicker. I know enough to take benadryl because it I do not not only do I have those reactions but I get hives or throat swelling. So if one person in a party is the only one affected by something, do not make assumptions.... oh and by the way food allergies as those who have peanut allergies know CAN be life threatening and we do not always know we are allergic to something until it builds up to a critical level in our bodies. So seeing a doctor is best. belles53 December 30th, 2007, 09:24 PM I was on the Voyager in May 2005- my first cruise. I got sick the last day as did many others with the norovirus. Glad it happened the last day, not earlier. It was a mess with so many sick and of course, the ship just turns around and heads out again. I knew someone on the next sailing and there were many sick then also. I am leaving on 1/6/08 on the Mariner and sure hope it doesn&apos;t happen again. Obviously, people get on board with the virus, not knowing it, and it spreads. Will wash my hands very frequently. Things like the slots and the elevator buttons can even spread the germs.
Dorothy Ronrocks! December 30th, 2007, 09:33 PM RonRocks, I&apos;m asking out of ignorance and not disprespect. How does one know if vomiting and diarrhea are food poisoning and not Noro? Hubby was sure he had food poisoning on Liberty, but then I came down with Noro the next night, so we thought in retrospect he had Noro too, but how can one know for sure?

How does the doctor know for sure (unless a line of patients come to his office and say they ate bad nachos for lunch in the Windjammer and immediately fell ill, but no one else comes who is similarly ill.

Is there one specific symptom of food poisoning that clearly sets it apart from Noro?

In my case I went to see the doctor on the ship. As far as one specific symptom that sets one apart from the other I don&apos;t know. I&apos;ve never had Noro. Until I got sick on the ship I had no idea that Noro caused vomiting and diarrhea. I will assume that the doctor on the ship has seen enough of Noro to be able to tell. As far as the nachos go, I can&apos;t say it was them. It could have been something I had earlier. It was the last thing I ate....and the first thing that...well you know. Funny thing is they tasted the same the second time.:eek: ;) Coralc December 30th, 2007, 10:37 PM I think it is very difficult to ascertain the difference. Cruisers are always upset that people board with Noro, but I think most people wouldn&apos;t necessarily know. I went to work Monday at 8AM, felt fine, did some paperwork, and went to the restroom at 9:30 and barfed. I was sick again about 10 AM. I went home. At about noon the explosive bowel problems started and the vomiting continued. By 1PM I was crawling to the home bathroom, and trying to decide which orfice was more urgent. At about 3PM my DH took me to the ER, because I was moaning and slightly delusional. I received a shot of Phengran and glucose for fluids. We hear a lot about Noro/food poisoning...and I wouldn&apos;t wish it on anybody. :p alicam December 30th, 2007, 10:39 PM Just curious about all of this....and maybe another plausible reason....NOT everyone washes their hands when they leave a washroom...and if they don&apos;t, and touch...for example...railings, elevator buttons, etc. about the ship, and someone else touches the same place, then it could be reasonable to assume that they have come down with something else and not acquired food poisoning (although it is easier to blame a cruise line than to admit not washing up after being in a washroom....believe me...I have seen it happen and it floors me to see people in this day and age doing it...either because they don&apos;t know better, don&apos;t care or think it won&apos;t matter) sagiv666 December 30th, 2007, 10:57 PM I was reading this forum and noticed a few people state they got food poisoning the first or second night into their cruise. We were on Disney Magic a couple years ago and noticed there were waterless hand cleaners all over the ship. I do not think these will help with food poisoning though. I would hate to get food poisoning on my cruise or have one of my kids get food poison. Are there any foods to stay away from on a cruise? We are going on Marnier of the Sea 1/6/08. Thanks

If one is afraid of food poisoning, the foods to avoid most are those served in the buffet, particularly open foods such as salads, etc. One should be careful when consuming dairy products (as well as salad dressings, etc.) which may be spoiled.:( Ronrocks! December 31st, 2007, 07:49 AM I think it is very difficult to ascertain the difference. Cruisers are always upset that people board with Noro, but I think most people wouldn&apos;t necessarily know. I went to work Monday at 8AM, felt fine, did some paperwork, and went to the restroom at 9:30 and barfed. I was sick again about 10 AM. I went home. At about noon the explosive bowel problems started and the vomiting continued. By 1PM I was crawling to the home bathroom, and trying to decide which orfice was more urgent. At about 3PM my DH took me to the ER, because I was moaning and slightly delusional. I received a shot of Phengran and glucose for fluids. We hear a lot about Noro/food poisoning...and I wouldn&apos;t wish it on anybody. :p

WOW!!! I did this excursion too!!! Isn&apos;t it great!! One of those&quot;once and a life time trips&quot;:eek: you hope Jovocrtt December 31st, 2007, 09:48 AM Well, I had an earthworm in my salad from the WJ! :lol

The chef explained that the salad was cleaned, they spray it with a bleach solution before they serve it. So I guess my worm was a clean one! I laughed at this for days.

I noted that there was no Purell hand sanitizer on board anymore. It is mostly made of alchohol and that does not kill Norovirus.

Poor Ron, sorry you got so sick .

I read somewhere that Melons if left out can go as bad a chopped meat does. Don&apos;t know where I read that.

I have been a nurse/Respiratory therapist for 37 years. Anyone can get Noro, and anyone can get food poisening. I dont&apos; think the ships do blood work to determine which is which, but perhaps by the numbers of people and the symptomology? Mac777daddy December 31st, 2007, 09:52 AM A worm? That salad would have gone back into the chiefs face as he came out to explain how clean and well prepared the salad was. That is something you do not miss while preparing a salad. I wanted to eat a lot of fruits on board but I think I will stay away from ground beef and melons. Sueny99 December 31st, 2007, 10:16 AM I got sick on Nov 27th on the explorer of the seas. And I am still not feeling 100% better yet. I was wondering if anyone else has had the same problem? Is it normal to still be sick a month after your trip? The doctor said it was gastritis from the trip but im still not better so im worried now. Mac777daddy December 31st, 2007, 11:23 AM Thats terrible. I guess people get food illnesses from all restaurants and this is the only setting for people to write about it. There is a&quot;golden corral&quot;restaurant in my home town that gave 15-30 people food poison one Friday night. A few of the older people actually died from it. Today the golden corral is open and packed every night. It only closed for a few days for health inspectors to go over the restaurant I guess. But this goes back to the person stating avoid certain foods on the buffet or avoid the buffet all together. Is WindJammer a buffet or cook to order? belles53 December 31st, 2007, 01:42 PM There is no way that you would be sick a month after the norovirus. I was better after 2 days. You must have another problem.
Dorothy sagiv666 January 2nd, 2008, 05:23 AM Thirty years ago, cruise ships would hire a Health and Sanitation Officer to watch over all parts of the ship relating to health; this was done as the US Federal Government was threatening to prohibit cruise ships -- almost all of which are not registered in the US -- from cruising in and out of US ports. This individual covered everything from checking the food and water, to checking the pool for proper amount of chlorine, to checking the air conditioning system (Legionnaire&apos;s Disease was the threat), to mention a few of his duties.
On a past cruise, I had the opportunity to have a drink with one. He told me the meat served had to be of a minimum temperature, and he was constantly arguing with the chefs, who thought the higher the temperature the worse the meat would taste. The dishware and eating utensils were cleaned at a high temperature, and when one picked up platers, etc., one was tempted to drop them because they were so hot.
Here the chefs would complain because they were so warm, salads would often wilt.
In recent cruises, I haven&apos;t noticed such an Officer on board. If they no longer hire such a person, perhaps they ought to bring him back.:(
	</body>
</document>
