<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008454" url="http://articles.mcall.com/keyword/burger-king-restaurant" time="2012-07-13-01:55" support="2" score="0.0016066993026821778" bingtitle="Articles about Burger King Restaurant - Morning Call" webtitle="Articles about Burger King Restaurant - Morning Call">
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="101"/>
	<description>... with a handgun robbed a Whitehall Township fast food restaurant ... A Palmer Township man involved in a four-car crash ... High School and has worked as the township&apos;s trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement Home → Collections → Burger King Restaurant IN THE NEWS 
Burger King Restaurant
 FIND MORE STORIES ABOUT: 
 Theft Burglary Zoning Bethlehem Police Traffic |   More 
 FEATURED ARTICLES NEWS 
 Woman&apos;s Purse Stolen Police 
 The Morning Call | March 29, 1986 Alice Iasiello, 1909-J Hoover Ave., Allentown, told Bethlehem police yesterday that her purse was taken while she was in the Burger King restaurant, 2141 Stefko Blvd. Police said the value of the stolen items was $130. ARTICLES BY DATE NEWS 
 Best Of The Week&apos;s Blogs 
 The Morning Call | December 21, 2008 QUOTE OF THE WEEK &quot;Making an investment in infrastructure is something tangible that you can see, much better than sending out a $300 [stimulus] check to taxpayers who go to Wal-Mart to buy flat-panel TVs made in China.&quot; BOB WENDT Lehigh Valley Economic Development Corp. research director, on president-elect Barack Obama&apos;s infrastructure improvement program. WE&apos;LL LEAVE THE FLASHY SUIT AND SPRAY-ON HAIR TO TV NEWS One of my many fans did my blogging work for me earlier this week with the following letter to the editor: &quot;Please tell Bill White to put on a clean, pressed shirt. Advertisement NEWS 
 Patriotic Washer 
 The Morning Call | April 29, 1987 An American flag waves in the background as window washer Jan Kraftician cleans the roof of the sun room at the Burger King restaurant on Stefko Boulevard in Bethlehem. The roof got wet again yesterday as rain fell off and on throughout the day. NEWS 
 Kidder tries new company for trash hauling work 
 By Christopher R. Mena Special to The Morning Call - Freelance | October 23, 2007 Kidder Township supervisors have awarded a contract to a new trash hauler after their last one caused a stink with residents. Supervisors chose a three-year contract with Waste Management of Pen Argyl rather than a five-year pact to make sure the township has the option to change sooner. Township residents have often complained about the service of the present hauler, Keystone Sanitation of Mifflinburg, Union County, whose contract will expire March 31. In recent months, residents complained about Keystone&apos;s infrequent collection, which they say led to eyesores and health hazards. NEWS 
 Hamburgers, Pies Stolen From L.v. Burger King Police 
 The Morning Call | December 28, 1987 The theft of 864 hamburgers and 48 cherry pies was reported Saturday by employees of the Burger King restaurant on Union Boulevard in Bethlehem, according to a police report. An employee told police that it was uncertain when the six cases of burgers and two cases of pies were taken. The items were found to be missing early Saturday, according to the report. NEWS 
 Sunny Side Up 
 The Morning Call | April 28, 1987 Window washer Jan Kraftician is a good man to have around this time of the year, when sunshine is especially welcome after a long winter. He&apos;s working to let plenty of light pour in at the Burger King restaurant on Stefko Boulevard, Bethlehem. NEWS 
 Burger King Aiding Hunger Relief Effort 
 The Morning Call | December 22, 1986 The Save the Children Federation will be gathering coupons donated by Burger King restaurants today and tomorrow to be distributed to needy children in the Lehigh Valley for free food. The regional volunteer for the organization will visit Burger Kings in the Lehigh Valley to collect the coupons, which are redeemable for food at those restaurants. The coupons then will be given to area child service organizations, which will be responsible for distributing them. NEWS 
 New Restaurant Around The County 
 The Morning Call | April 17, 1989 Good news, fast-food fans. There soon will be a new Burger King restaurant in Bethlehem Township. Township commissioners approved the plans April 10. The Burger King will be built in the Bethlehem Square Shopping Center on Nazareth Pike. The eatery was proposed last year but approval was delayed because of a dispute between the township and the shopping center&apos;s developer, Rosenshein Associates of New Rochelle, N.Y. NEWS 
 Hanging Holiday Wishes May Cause Traffic Delay 
 The Morning Call | December 14, 1989 MacArthur Road travelers may have a few minutes longer travel time this morning as Whitehall Township workers add a holiday greeting in the area of the Lehigh Valley Mall. Two police officers will assist traffic at the traffic light at the Burger King restaurant while workers erect a &quot;Merry Christmas&quot; banner across the six-lane highway about 9 a.m. NEWS 
 Cleaning Up For A Cause 
 The Morning Call | July 7, 1992 Angela Dean, 14, of Lehighton, cleans a table in the dining area of the Burger King restaurant near Lehighton. Burger King in a promotional program donated 20 percent of its receipts during a 5 p.m. to 8 p.m. period of business, netting $157 for the youth group of Trinity Lutheran Church, Lehighton. NEWS 
 Kidder Township planners advance motel project 
 By Christopher R. Mena Special to The Morning Call - Freelance | October 5, 2007 The Kidder Township Planning Commission has given conditional approval for a Holiday Inn Express motel at the former site of a fast food restaurant on Route 940. &quot;To get to this point has taken a long time,&quot; Shirish Shah, who will be the hotel&apos;s owner and project manager, said after getting the approval Wednesday. Planners gave approval on the conditions an emergency generator be built, that developers get National Pollutant Elimination System approval and the plans state that the on-site abandoned Burger King restaurant not be used unless plans are brought before the board and meet requirements, such as parking. SPORTS 
 Wakeup Call 
 The Morning Call | May 15, 2007 MONEY FIGHT Pennsylvania Gov. Edward Rendell has never been shy about voicing his opinion on the NFL draft as it pertains to the Philadelphia Eagles. In 1999, for example, the former mayor of the City of Brotherly Love wanted the team to draft running back Ricky Williams over quarterback Donovan McNabb. On Friday, during an interview on a political-themed television show, Rendell said the Eagles should have drafted USC receiver Dwayne Jarrett instead of quarterback Kevin Kolb with its first pick, the 36th overall. FEATURES 
 Culinary Calendar 
 The Morning Call | February 21, 2007 SPECIAL EVENTS Thursday -- Anniversary Bash -- Abruzzi&apos;s on Main, 212 N. Main St., Coopersburg, will celebrate its 10th anniversary by featuring Terry Balent from PA Wines, Troy Johnson from Lauber Imports, Jody Stahley and Ed Mac from Southern Wine and Spirits, Tom Holton from the Wine Merchant, Mark Wolfe from Barton, Eddie Stoudt from Stoudt&apos;s Brewery, Alan Edwards from Appalachian Brewing Co., Ron from Shangy&apos;s and Lee from Legacy Brewing Co.... BUSINESS 
 Over 50? Ask for senior discounts 
 By Gregory Karp Of The Morning Call | February 4, 2007 Age discrimination is running rampant in America, and people over 50 should take full advantage of it. Price discounts abound for the more mature crowd, but you have to know where to look. Joan Rattner Heilman knows. She has written the 2007-08 edition of &quot;Unbelievably Good Deals and Great Adventures That You Absolutely Can&apos;t Get Unless You&apos;re Over 50.&quot; It&apos;s important information for the nearly one in four Americans older than 50. Their ranks are swelling every day, and businesses have noticed this group and its huge buying power. NEWS 
 Hold the &quot;lettuce&apos; 
 Merge | October 18, 2006 Three workers at a Burger King restaurant in Los Lunas, N.M., were arrested last week after two Isleta police officers discovered the hamburgers they ordered were sprinkled with marijuana. According to the Associated Press, the officers ate about half of their burgers Sunday before discovering marijuana on the meat. The officers used a field test kit to confirm the substance was pot, then went to a hospital for a medical evaluation. The three Burger King employees -- Justin Armijo, 19; Robert Nuckols, 21; and manager Joseph Ledesma, 33 -- were arrested and charged with possession of marijuana and aggravated battery on an officer. NEWS 
 For The Record 
 The Morning Call | January 12, 2002 The movie &quot;In the Bedroom&quot; is not playing at General Cinema Lehigh Valley Mall, Whitehall Township. Information was incorrect in a Friday movie review. The American Lung Association&apos;s Valentine Fun Pac contains nine coupons that can be redeemed for a soft drink or french fries at Burger King restaurants. Also, Fun Pacs distributed in the greater Lehigh Valley do not contain coupons for Harrisburg Senators home games. A news brief in Wednesday&apos;s paper included some incorrect information. NEWS 
 Cressona 
 The Morning Call | August 4, 1993 Theft -- Reported by Burger King restaurant; state police, Schuylkill Haven, said a black man in his late 30s, wearing a red Phillies T-shirt, presented a $100 traveler&apos;s check for payment about 8:30 p.m. July 19 , then apparently switched checks, providing a counterfeit as payment; police said man left with food and change; he was reportedly accompanied by a black man in late 20s wearing dark shirt and brown pants. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next Index by Keyword | Index by Date | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service Please note the green-lined linked article text has been applied commercially without any involvement from our newsroom editors, reporters or any other editorial staff.
	</body>
</document>
