<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008974" url="http://nutrition4kids.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:23" support="1" score="0.0006485209812149131" bingtitle="Health &amp; Wellness for Your Child | tips to keep your child healthy ..." webtitle="HealthWellness for Your Child | tips to keep your child healthywell">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>... first off, it is important to note that eating a meal with the same amounts of fat in a fast food restaurant and ... up in their bellies rather than in the trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Health&amp;Wellness for Your Child 
 tips to keep your child healthy&amp;well Skip to content 
 Home About the Author Canada’s Food Guide Links Questions Recipes References 
 ← Older posts 
 Navigating your grocery store 
 Posted on November 18, 2010 by sarahgeb 
Grocery shopping is a key aspect in your children eating healthy so it is an important thing to mention here. First and foremost, be sure to eat before you go shopping and make sure your children have eaten as well. I fall victim to this almost every time I go out for groceries. I am so hungry that I buy everything in sight…and let’s just say the foods I choose when hungry aren’t always the healthiest options.

I am sure you have heard the age-old advice; shop around the perimeter of the grocery store. This is because most centre aisles of grocery stores are filled with highly processed foods that are higher in sodium, fats and sugars. They are the foods that aren’t really required in the diet…extras calories! The foods found in the centre aisles are most common to developing illnesses such as obesity, diabetes and cardiovascular disease.
 
1/2 of your plate should be covered by vegetables. 1/4 of the plate should be covered by protein, such as chicken, fish, or lean meat. The remaining 1/4 of your plate should be filled with starch.
 
I recommend making a list up of all the food items you require so that you are only buying what you need and you are avoiding unnecessary buys (most of which are junk foods). I find planning your meals for the week is easiest in finding out what you need so that you aren’t scrambling when trying to make a meal later on in the week. Remember that your meals should be balanced according to Canada’s Food Guide. The diagram to the right shows how you should divide your plate up to maintain a balanced diet.

When creating your list, order it so that you aren’t jumping around to each of the departments. List your milk, cheese and yogurt together; List your veggies and fruits together. Have your chicken and beef listed next together on your grocery list. This will make finding things easier and create less of a feeling of confusion and fatigue when going grocery shopping.

Try and use fresh or frozen fruits and vegetables in your meals rather than canned fruits and veggies, as canned ones tend to have higher amounts of sodium, fats and sugars. Frozen veggies tend to get a bad rap for some people which I don’t quite understand. The veggies you find in the frozen aisles are just as good (and full of vitamins and minerals) that your fresh veggies are. They are just blanched ( Blanching is a cooking term that describes a process of preparation wherein the food substance, usually a vegetable or fruit, is plunged into boiling water, removed after a brief, timed interval, and finally plunged into iced water or placed under cold running water (shocked) to halt the cooking process) to keep the nutrients in during freezing.
 
The Health Check logo (eatrightontario.ca)
 
To make things easier for you, and educational for your children, invite them to create the list and find the foods they need themselves with your supervision. Teach them that foods listed with the“Health Check”are better for maintaining a healthy diet. The Health Check program is a tool that you can use to make healthier choices when grocery shopping or dining out. Because it is a voluntary program and not all healthy foods will have a Health Check symbol, use it along with other healthy eating tools like Canada’s Food Guide and reading the Nutrition Facts table to compare products [6] . Yep, those nutrition facts I spoke of earlier this week…it comes in handy here too. Invite your child to compare two items to see how much more vitamins and minerals they can add to their diet; or how much bad fats they can cut out of their diet if they choose the healthy option rather than the other.

 References: 

 [6]    Find Out More about Health Check: Eat Right Ontario, retrieved from: http://www.eatrightontario.ca/en/ViewDocument.aspx?id=419 
 Posted in fruits , grocery store , nutrition labelling , snacks , vegetables | 2 Comments 
 Those nutrition labels… 
 Posted on November 15, 2010 by sarahgeb 
“Give a man a fish and you feed him for a day. Teach a man to fish and you feed him for a lifetime”–Chinese Proverb

Teaching your child how to read a nutrition label is probably one of the most important measures in ensuring that your child continues to maintain a healthy lifestyle well into their lives. There are a couple steps I have listed below to help introduce your child to the nutrition label.
 
A nutrition label can seem rather overwhelming for anyone, let alone a child. Teaching them to read one will help them be more health conscious.
 
You will need to have:

 a cereal box with a nutrition label, preferably something healthy! two measuring cups a child! 

1.   Have your child measure out the typical serving size. In the case of the label to the left, the serving size is 30 grams, or approximately 1 cup.

2.   Have them measure out milk in the listed serving size. In this case, 125 mL.

3.   Introduce them to calories. Calories tell you how much energy you get from one serving of a packaged food.

4.   Ask them to find the amount of carbohydrates. Here it is listed as 21 grams. Pay particular attention to the percent of the daily limit carbohydrates gives in this cereal with and without milk. A proper serving of cereal with milk will give you 10% of your daily intake.

Sugars are an important thing to note as well. There are sugars present in a lot of cereals, and some people even add more to it for more sweetness. Inform your child of the amounts and how much you actually take in when adding sugar.

5.   Have them look at the levels of calcium present. Without milk, the cereal accounts for only 4% of your daily intake. With milk and cereal, the calcium jumps to 20% of your daily intake. From here you can see that milk is a large source of calcium which is important for growing childrens’teeth and bones.

6.   Introduce your child to fats. As we can see here, there is 2 grams of total fats in the cereal. It is also listed that there are zero grams of trans fat. Let them know that fat is a healthy part of our diet, but to be weary of the levels of trans fats.

7.   Mix both the cereal and milk into a bowl and enjoy!

 Try to get less of these: 

 Fat, saturated fat, trans fat, sodium, cholesterol 

 Try to get more of these: 

 Fibre, vitamin A, vitamin C, iron, calcium 
 Posted in children , nutrition labelling | 4 Comments 
 Helping children help themselves 
 Posted on November 12, 2010 by sarahgeb 
So we offer our children healthy foods and snacks at home. Everything is good, right? Wrong. With one-third of childrens’caloric intake at school, they are eating outside of the home more and more and breaking all those good habits we have been forming at home. Seventy-eight percent of adolescents make their junk food purchases at school, and of those, 64% include a beverage, 32% include candy or gum, and 26% include salty snacks [5] . With twenty-six percent of Canadian children between the ages of two and seventeen listed as overweight or obese [2] , and considering our children eat 1/3 of their daily intakes outside the home, I think we should be more worried on what our children are eating at school.

These past couple days in my nutrition education class, we have been talking about marketing towards children, school policies, and more specifically vending machines in schools. Currently there are different standards on vending machines in Canadian schools as it is the responsibility of  the provinces and territories to maintain and enforce the policies. To look up to, we have British Columbia and Nova Scotia: they have regulations ensuring that only foods considered maximum- or moderate-nutrition choices are made available to students at schools. All other provinces and territories have either a voluntary approach to guidelines, or none exist at all.
 
Provincial Guidelines&amp;Policies on Vending Machines. Click to enlarge.
 
I think there should be restrictions on what can and cannot be filled in vending machines in schools today with the rates of obesity today. However, who says what’s good and who says what’s bad? What labels a food or drink a health item, and another a junk food? Should it be foods high in sugar, high in sodium, high in fat, or high in calories? Or a number of those things? Should a registered dietitian be going through all these products? Will this be Canada wide?

I think our only option here is to educate our children on the effects of junk foods and fizzy pops, and help them make the right choice themselves and hope for the best.

 What can we do to solve the problem? 

 References: 
[2]      Spence, J.C., Carson, V., Casey, L.,&amp;Boule, N. (2010). Examining behavioural susceptibility to obesity among Canadian pre-school children: the role of eating behaviours. International Journal of Pediatric Obesity, Early Online, 1-7 
 [5]     Finkelstein, P. (2009). School Nutrition: Are we failing Canada’s kids? Best Health. Retrieved from: http://www.besthealthmag.ca/eat-well/nutrition/school-nutrition-are-we-failing-canadas-kids 
 Posted in blood sugar , children , junk food , overweight , physical activity , pop , snacks | 3 Comments 
 Eating out… Healthy 
 Posted on November 3, 2010 by sarahgeb 
Eating out is a common practice among Canadian families today, especially with the busy lives we lead. In between work and school, heading to soccer practice and doing shopping, it is hard to eat well at home. I can attest to eating fast food three times last week (yikes!) because of the stresses of midterms and assignments. While it might not always be the best option for meals, eating out can be done healthy if you choose properly.

 Is eating out healthy even possible? Well first off, it is important to note that eating a meal with the same amounts of fat in a fast food restaurant and at home can have significant differences. Trans fats are more common in the fast food meal than in the home-cooked meal, as it is more prevalent in fried foods. A study found that eating foods with monounsaturated fats found in home-cooked meals versus eating a meal with the same amount of fats, but in the form of trans fats in fast food meals, lead to a increased chance of becoming overweight, which could lead to developing heart disease and diabetes. [3] We can still avoid trans fats in our fast food choices though with some simple guidelines.
 
Milk and apples with your child&apos;s Happy Meal, adds some health foods to the meal that would otherwise be fried. (mcdonalds.ca)
 
First off, avoid eating large portions . While it may only cost a few cents to upgrade to a large size fries and a large drink, the nutritional value and increased caloric intake is definitely not worth it. We also tend to try to finish everything in front of us although we may not need to eat any more, so keeping the portions small limits overindulging. If a child is eating a combo meal off a fast food menu, it’s almost always too large, so even go for a split between two for the fries and drink.

 Go for the healthy option . More and more restaurants are offering healthy choices such as salads and side dishes of rice, instead of fries. Take advantage by trying new things on a global taste. Get sauces and toppings on the side so that you can alter the amount of dressings you need. For children, a kid’s menu often has apples and cheese cubes, so go for that option rather than fries as a side.
 
Eating out on the go can be easy and healthy
 
 Think of preparation. How a food was prepared will often give you a clue to how healthy an item is. Something that is grilled, steamed, or baked is often free of the extra fats that frying, deep-frying or breaded foods add.

 Drink healthy . Drinking milk, water or 100% fruit juice instead of pop can reduce the calories you consume as well as rehydrate you better. In kid’s meals, the choice is often juice or milk, so avoiding soft drinks here is important. Pop also is a diuretic making you have to go to the bathroom more often leading to dehydration.

For more tips on eating out, visit Eat Right Ontario’s Top 10 Tips for Eating Out .

 How easy do you find it to find healthy eats while outside the home? 

 References:
[3]         Gosline, A. (2006, June 12). Why fast foods are bad, even in moderation . New Scientist: Health , Retrieved from http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn9318-why-fast-foods-are-bad-even-in-moderation.html 
 Posted in children , fast food , overweight , trans fats | 1 Comment 
 Picky Eaters! 
 Posted on October 28, 2010 by sarahgeb 
Picky eaters…sigh!
 
I’m sure a lot of parents can relate to this video, even though it’s a cartoon. And I’m hoping that it’s never restricted you from eating outside of your home (hopefully!).  It may have had you thinking about dinner preparations…and changing some ingredients, sometimes creating something completely different so that there are no problems during dinnertime. But if we did that everyday than we would never be getting essential nutrients!

If you are having issues with disguising those healthy vegetables, here are some tips [4] :

 1. Respect your child’s appetite — or lack of one. Young children tend to eat only when they’re hungry. If your child isn’t hungry, don’t force a meal or snack. Likewise, don’t bribe or force your child to clean his or her plate. This may only ignite — or reinforce — a power struggle over food.
 2. Stick to the routine. Serve meals and snacks at about the same times every day. If your child comes to the table hungry, he or she may be more motivated to eat, so avoid snacking before dinner.
 3. Be patient with new foods. Young children often touch or smell new foods, and may even put tiny bits in their mouths and then take them back out again. Your child may need repeated exposure to a new food before he or she takes the first bite (I’ve heard 21 times?). Encourage your child by talking about a food’s color, shape, aroma and texture — not whether it tastes good.
 4. Make it fun! Serve broccoli and other veggies with a favorite dip or sauce. Cut foods into various shapes with cookie cutters. Offer breakfast foods for dinner.
 5. Recruit your child’s help. At the grocery store, ask your child to help you select fruits, vegetables and other healthy foods.
 6. Set a good example. If you eat a variety of healthy foods, your child is more likely to follow suit.
 7. Be sneaky! Add chopped broccoli or green peppers to spaghetti sauce, top cereal with fruit slices, or mix grated zucchini and carrots into casseroles and soups.
 8. Minimize distractions. Turn off the television during meals, and don’t allow books or toys at the table.
 9. Don’t offer dessert as a reward. Withholding dessert sends the message that dessert is the best food, which may only increase your child’s desire for sweets. You might select one or two nights a week as dessert nights, and skip dessert the rest of the week — or redefine dessert as fruit, yogurt or other healthy choices.
 10. Don’t be a short order cook! Preparing a separate meal for your child after he or she rejects the original meal may encourage your child’s picky eating. Keep serving your child healthy choices until they become familiar and preferred.

If after all your stealth efforts, your child still sees what you are trying to do and refuses to take part, don’t worry and try again later. Did you like olives* when you were a child? Not likely.

*You can substitute this with anything…spinach, carrots, brocolli, green peppers, mushrooms, brussel sprouts, onions, cauliflower…the list goes on!

 References: 
[4]           MayoClinic.com: Children’s Nutrition: 10 Tips for picky eaters. http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/childrens-health/HQ01107 
 Posted in children , grocery store , picky eaters , vegetables | 4 Comments 
 Keeping Fit &amp;Staying Active 
 Posted on October 21, 2010 by sarahgeb 
With the increasing number of unhealthy foods being consumed in today’s society, many people of all ages are packing on a couple pounds here and there, and it is no different with our children. It is recommended that children engage in at least 60 minutes of of physical activity every day [1] but most barely hit this mark. Approximately 26% of Canadian children between the ages of 2 and 17 years are overweight. [2] Ultimately an energy imbalance is what is causing Canadian children to be overweight, as they are consuming a certain number of calories but they are not burning off those calories to the extent children were even a decade ago.

It is important to promote physical activity among the youth today as a childhood inactivity is usually a precursor to adult inactivity. Adults often find it more difficult to start exercising when older as they do not have as much drive or time to do so. Parents are encouraged to:
 
Keeping active with fun sports and activites can be as easy as playing a pick up game for 20 minutes.
 
 Set a good example by being physically active themselves and joining their children in physical activity Encourage children to be physically active at home, at school and with friends. Limit television watching, computer games, and other inactive forms of play by alternating with periods of physical activity. Encourage them to join an organized sport; a favourite sport or activity within the community to meet new friends and remain active while having fun. 

The 60 minutes of exercise a day does not need to be performed all at once. It can be broken up in to two or three smaller portions of activity. Younger children often play hide and seek or tag, which will give them the aerobic exercise they need. Exercise not only lessens the chance of being overweight. It also lowers the chances of developing Type II diabetes, it possibly lowers blood pressure and cholesterol levels too.

 What do you think of children’s level of activity today? 

 References: 
[1]     Brown, J. (2008). Nutrition through the life cycle . Toronto: Thomson Wadsworth.
[2]     Spence, J.C., Carson, V., Casey, L.,&amp;Boule, N. (2010). Examining behavioural susceptibility to obesity among Canadian pre-school children: the role of eating behaviours. International Journal of Pediatric Obesity , Early Online , 1-7 
 Posted in adolescent , children , exercise , overweight , physical activity | 3 Comments 
 Healthy Snacking 
 Posted on October 18, 2010 by sarahgeb 
Snacks keep your body going between meals as well as maintains your blood sugar levels so you don’t have any unwanted symptoms. Your brain requires glucose to maintain daily activity, otherwise your blood sugar level can get low.
 

Blood sugar levels spike after a meal, then drop significantly
 
Ideally the body requires 5 to 6 small meals a day to maintain the proper equilibrium. The body should be refueled every 2 to 3 hours to maintain this equilibrium of blood sugar levels. Diets in North America tend to be based around our school or work life, which is not really the best time line when it comes to eating right. So we are forced to eat 3 large meals, several hours apart. This causes our blood sugar level to spike for a couple hours, and then drop significantly causing feelings of hunger and tiredness.

Healthy snacks keep your body energized and limits the amount of up and down levels of blood sugar content. This reduces the cravings, hunger and tiredness after a large meal.
 
Children who eat healthy snacks have more energy to do their daily tasks
 
Finding healthy snacks is rather difficult because most of the easy and cheap ones are also high in sugar and salts. Snacks appropriate for you and your children are ones that are low in salts and sugars, and incorporate foods that are part of Canada’s Food Guide. Younger children at school prefer finger foods, that taste good and are easy to eat. Make healthy treats fun to eat by cutting them into different shapes, for instance:

 
 cutting cheese into small squares or triangles, served with whole wheat crackers 
 cutting carrots into coins rather than sticks cutting cucumbers into squares rather than circular slices slicing grapes into smaller half spheres 

For older children at school, include snacks that they pick. Snacks that they choose are more likely to end up in their bellies rather than in the trash. Include whole grains, fruits and vegetables that they like, and low sugar juices or milk to drink in between meals. [1] 

Adolescents lead busy lives. Between school, academic extra-curricular activities and after school sports, many skip meals. Unfortunately the food choices teens make while snacking tend to be high in sugar, sodium and fat, and relatively low in vitamins and minerals. Adolescents can be counselled to ask for juice, water or milk, instead of soft drinks, choosing a salad instead of a baked potato or fries, and avoiding“supersizing”the meal. [1] You cannot spend all your meals together as a family so just informing your adolescent the benefits of eating right can go a long way.

 Do you eat healthy snacks? How do you feel snacking affects you? 

 References: 
[1]          Brown, J. (2008). Nutrition through the life cycle . Toronto: Thomson Wadsworth. 
 Posted in adolescent , blood sugar , breakfast , children , fast food , snacks | 3 Comments ← Older posts 
 Search for: 
categories
 adolescent blood sugar breakfast children exercise fast food fruits grocery store junk food nutrition labelling overweight physical activity picky eaters pop snacks trans fats vegetables 
archives

 November 2010  (4) October 2010  (4) September 2010  (1) 
 
 
 
 July 2012 S M T W T F S «Nov     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
 
 
 email subscriptions: 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

 

 
 
a healthier kid, one view at a time...

 1,470 views 
 
 Health&amp;Wellness for Your Child Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Twenty Ten . Health&amp;Wellness for Your Child Theme: Twenty Ten Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“Health&amp;Wellness for Your Child” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
