<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008297" url="http://www.abovetopsecret.com/forum/thread812303/pg1" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="1" score="0.001931481664660528" bingtitle="Has Anyone Had More Than One Type of Paranormal Experience?, page 1" webtitle="Has Anyone Had More Than One Type of Paranormal Experience?, page 1">
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="121"/>
	<description>I came to this fast food restaurant and remember looking at my ... Once I placed my order I pulled up with 2 cars still ... Mandatory ‘Big Brother’ Black Boxes In All New ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME TOP TOPICS + NEW TOPICS + ABOUT + GET ATS FORUMS RECENT POSTS CREATE ATS ACCOUNT SEARCH LOG IN 
 
 Has Anyone Had More Than One Type of Paranormal Experience?, page 1 
 privacy Pages: &lt;&lt;    1      2      3      4    &gt;&gt; 
 ATS Members have flagged this thread 49 times Topic started on 22-2-2012 @ 05:44 PM by sled735 I had a ghost follow me around from age six until my late teens, channeled spirits, seen UFOs (close), had an object materialize from thin air in
front of my face, and had a monster of some kind over 8 ft. tall walk past my bathroom window during my lifetime. I am now 54 years old. Until now I
had no way of communicating with others about all these strange occurrences, but thanks to ATS, I can now ask the question, &quot;Are there others who
experience more than one type of paranormal phenomena, or am I just a paranormal magnet?&quot; 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 05:57 PM by DrHammondStoat reply to post by sled735 
 

Hello Sled735, I doubt you&apos;re the only one here on Ats. In my life I&apos;ve encountered ghostly goings on
at my first school as a child, alien abduction type memories from as long as I can remember,
poltergeist acrivity as a teen, a disembodied voice/possible guardian angel that told me not to do
something dangerous right before I did it, a misty &apos;thing&apos; hovering above me on waling from a meditation
and various Out of body experiences. Also a couple of Ufo sightings that by definition are not
necessarily &apos;paranormal&apos;.

These things have calmed down since i got to my 30s. Ats is a good place to try and
get some answers and sometimes more questions! 

(Meant to say I would love to hear about your close up UFO sightings please Sled) edit on 22-2-2012 by DrHammondStoat because: (no reason
given)
 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 06:41 PM by imalitehaus Originally posted by sled735 
I had a ghost follow me around from age six until my late teens, channeled spirits, seen UFOs (close), had an object materialize from thin air in
front of my face, and had a monster of some kind over 8 ft. tall walk past my bathroom window during my lifetime. I am now 54 years old. Until now I
had no way of communicating with others about all these strange occurrences, but thanks to ATS, I can now ask the question, &quot;Are there others who
experience more than one type of paranormal phenomena, or am I just a paranormal magnet?&quot; 

No, you aren&apos;t alone in the diversity of your paranormal experiences. I&apos;ve had the weirdest life I&apos;ve ever heard about, read about or have seen in
movies / television. Extreme &quot;high strangeness&quot;, and I don&apos;t mean the mind-altering-substance kind.

I don&apos;t want to go into it, but there&apos;s a reason my name is &quot;I&apos;m a lighthouse&quot;. Hey, we&apos;re the same age, too. 
 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 06:49 PM by odinson Hello
I am 46 and I have seen a couple of demons. One was because I was using the ouija board and pissed off satan. He was supposed to have cursed me. I am
saved now through confessing my sins to Jesus. I also seen. Phantoms during a vision that continued when I got up to use the john.
There are spirits out there that are biting at the bit and can&apos;t wait until God gives the go ahead.
Seek God before it is to late. We have days at most.
God Bless 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 06:49 PM by smyleegrl Now look, all of you.

You can&apos;t just write things like, &quot;I&apos;m a lighthouse&quot; or &quot;alien abduction&quot; and not give details!!!!! It&apos;s the worst form of teasing!!!!!
Aagggghhhhh!

So now that I&apos;ve got that off my chest.... Please go into detail and share your stories!

And congrats OP on your first post. S&amp;F;! 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 06:54 PM by ofhumandescent reply to post by sled735 
 

Yes my whole life has been one big paranormal experience.

Not going into it because I do not have a tough skin and do not feel like getting flamed, ridiculed and having people throw ignorant and cruel remarks
at me.

Keep in mind, what we consider &quot;paranormal&quot; today will be explained by quantum physics tomorrow.

There are more things in heaven and Earth, Horatio, than are dreamed of in thy philosophy. - (William Shakespeare, Hamlet) 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:01 PM by imalitehaus Originally posted by smyleegrl 
Now look, all of you.

You can&apos;t just write things like, &quot;I&apos;m a lighthouse&quot; or &quot;alien abduction&quot; and not give details!!!!! It&apos;s the worst form of teasing!!!!!
Aagggghhhhh!

So now that I&apos;ve got that off my chest.... Please go into detail and share your stories!

And congrats OP on your first post. S&amp;F;! 

I know, hon, and I&apos;m so sorry. For me, it&apos;s going to take a long time to get all the details together (it&apos;s been ongoing for 52 out of my 54
years), before I can even begin a thread about all of it. It&apos;s a whole lot to explain, all at once, or even a little at a time,
unfortunately.

I will though, as soon as I can get some &quot;me&quot; time. You guys will be the first to hear all of it, all at once.

And, to the OP. Thank you for bringing this up. I may have stayed completely quiet forever, if it weren&apos;t for your thread. 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:02 PM by wonhunlo reply to post by sled735 
 

Clairvoyance, remote influencing, telepathy (effective sender), clairaudience.

Have witnessed poltergeist activity. Attempts at remote viewing unproductive.

------------------------------------

 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:03 PM by sled735 reply to post by DrHammondStoat 
 

This is a post I entered on another thread, but I&apos;ll post it again here just for you. :-)
Back in the early 1970&apos;s I looked out the window one night and saw a huge white light in the sky, about the size of a dime if you held it up to the
sky. It was really bright. You could tell it wasn&apos;t still; it was kind of hovering. As I stood watching it trying to figure out what it was there
were 5 or 6 smaller objects that came out of the bottom of the large craft and took off into space! I just stood there with my mouth open. The large
object stayed in the same location until I finally got tired of standing there, and went back to the living room. I grew up in the country, so there
were no street lights blocking out the night sky.
I continued to see UFOs in the sky after that. They would go in crazy directions, stop, zigzag, and take off from a dead stop to being gone from view
in a split second! All these just appeared as a bright round light from a distance, but could have been a different shape up close. Some appeared to
flash different colors.
My close encounter was went I was coming home one night after working second shift. I came to this fast food restaurant and remember looking at my
watch to see if I had time to go through the drive-through before they closed. It was 10:40 p.m., and they closed at 11:00 p.m. So I pulled into the
drive-through lane with 3 cars ahead of me and another behind me. Once I placed my order I pulled up with 2 cars still ahead of me at the serving
window. Then I saw something flashing in the sky. I kept watching it, and it got closer, and closer. It was flashing orange/red and green lights. As
it approached even closer I could see it was oblong-shaped like a cigar, and flipping end over end. One end had the orange/red light glowing from it,
and the other end had the green light. This object made absolutely no noise at all! As it approached just above the tree tops across the road it
stopped flipping, and just glided through the air. It came down extremely low, just over the top of the building, and shot down a bright beam that
went right beside my car in the parking lot! I noticed no one else seemed to be looking at it so I stuck my head all the way out my window and
hollered at the car behind me, &quot;What the hell is that thing?!!&quot; I was so scared I was shaking! No one answered, and actually, everyone seemed to be
suspended in time, no one was moving at all! After the light beam passed my car it started slowly flipping again, and then took off into the sky, and
was gone in the blink of an eye!
The strange thing that confused me most about this encounter was the fact I lost 20 minutes from the time I saw the UFO until it took off again, which
only seemed like maybe 2 or 3 minutes, and the fact that no one else seemed to even notice it, like they were all statues, not moving at all! I still
haven&apos;t figured this out, but I heard of others losing time when they saw UFOs, and it turned out they were abducted! I won&apos;t go that far, but if I
was, I don&apos;t want to remember it! 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:07 PM by sled735 Originally posted by imalitehaus 
 Originally posted by smyleegrl 
Now look, all of you.

You can&apos;t just write things like, &quot;I&apos;m a lighthouse&quot; or &quot;alien abduction&quot; and not give details!!!!! It&apos;s the worst form of teasing!!!!!
Aagggghhhhh!

So now that I&apos;ve got that off my chest.... Please go into detail and share your stories!

And congrats OP on your first post. S&amp;F;! 

I know, hon, and I&apos;m so sorry. For me, it&apos;s going to take a long time to get all the details together (it&apos;s been ongoing for 52 out of my 54
years), before I can even begin a thread about all of it. It&apos;s a whole lot to explain, all at once, or even a little at a time,
unfortunately.

I will though, as soon as I can get some &quot;me&quot; time. You guys will be the first to hear all of it, all at once.

And, to the OP. Thank you for bringing this up. I may have stayed completely quiet forever, if it weren&apos;t for your thread.
 
Thank You for responding. I look forward to reading your experiences. I feel better knowing I&apos;m not alone.... or just plum crazy! LOL 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:07 PM by imalitehaus reply to post by ofhumandescent 
 

Yes, I understand completely. I don&apos;t want to be ridiculed, either and I think that&apos;s had a lot to do with my silence. I&apos;m going to see about
getting more quiet time in the future. So, who knows?

But, I do understand your reluctance to go into details. I have the same reluctance myself.

 edit on 22-2-2012 by imalitehaus because: (no reason given)
 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:09 PM by imalitehaus reply to post by sled735 
 


For sure, you&apos;re not alone and NOT crazy!

We&apos;ll all look forward to each other&apos;s experiences. 

Edit to add: Awesome event, sled!
 edit on 22-2-2012 by imalitehaus because: (no reason given)
 
 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:26 PM by sled735 Here is another one of my experiences, probably the most mind-boggling of them all...

I had a ring setting that was made from Kentucky coal that my husband gave me (ex-husband now). He said it was one of a kind. About a year after we
were divorced I lost the setting in the ring at a local club. Three months later my cousin and I went to a drive-in theater (this was in the mid
1970&apos;s). During intermission I went to the bathroom located inside the concession building . As I stood and looked up, there was something black
dangling in mid-air in front of my face. I thought at first it was a spider hanging on a web, but then it fell to the concrete floor and made a noise,
so I knew whatever it was, it was a solid object. As I knelt over getting a closer look, I realized this was the setting from my ring that I had lost
three months prior in a totally different place! It was like it just materialized in front of my eyes, stayed there until I saw it, and fell at my
feet. I picked it up and put it in my pocket. When I went back to the car my cousin asked me if I was okay because she said I was pale as a ghost. I
told her what happened, and she was speechless! When I got home I placed the setting in my ring, put the ring away in my jewelry case, and I have
never taken it out again since that day! Still don&apos;t know what to make out of this! Anyone ever experienced anything like this? 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:41 PM by smyleegrl Originally posted by imalitehaus 
 Originally posted by smyleegrl 
Now look, all of you.

You can&apos;t just write things like, &quot;I&apos;m a lighthouse&quot; or &quot;alien abduction&quot; and not give details!!!!! It&apos;s the worst form of teasing!!!!!
Aagggghhhhh!

So now that I&apos;ve got that off my chest.... Please go into detail and share your stories!

And congrats OP on your first post. S&amp;F;! 

I know, hon, and I&apos;m so sorry. For me, it&apos;s going to take a long time to get all the details together (it&apos;s been ongoing for 52 out of my 54
years), before I can even begin a thread about all of it. It&apos;s a whole lot to explain, all at once, or even a little at a time,
unfortunately.

I will though, as soon as I can get some &quot;me&quot; time. You guys will be the first to hear all of it, all at once.

And, to the OP. Thank you for bringing this up. I may have stayed completely quiet forever, if it weren&apos;t for your thread.
 

I completely understand. Yes, there are folks here who delight in ridiculing others, but please know there are folks here with an open mind. When you
feel ready, share. In the meantime I&apos;ll be watching for your thread! 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:41 PM by sled735 Here is my monster experience:

I grew up in the foothills of the Appalachian Mountains. When I was around 10 years old there was a very tall creature of some kind that walked past
our bathroom window. It had to be at least 8 or 9 feet tall to be seen in that window because it was very high off the ground. My teenage sister was
in the bathroom curling her hair when she heard something and looked over at the window just in time to see this creature walk by. It was just turning
dusk, but still light enough for her to see it. She screamed bloody murder! We all heard something hollering in the woods for months before, and after
that. The sound wasn&apos;t like the long, low howl they give on the &quot;Finding Bigfoot&quot;show, but it was a high-pitched squeal; sounded more like one of
those large flying prehistoric birds! All the &quot;old-timers&quot; that lived in the area said they had never heard anything like it! My mother wouldn&apos;t
let me go outside to play all year because everyone around was terrified of this thing!
One of our neighbors that lived about 2 miles up the road found his pig ripped open on it&apos;s belly, but the only thing taken was the liver. He said it
was a very clean cut; looked like it could have been done with a knife. He found long white hairs caught on the barbed wire fence close by. This was
back in 1967. One day the screams in the woods just stopped, and we never heard it again. I&apos;ve always wondered what that thing was! Possibly a Big
Foot? 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:49 PM by alienorgy 

 

 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:50 PM by smyleegrl Originally posted by sled735 
Here is my monster experience:

I grew up in the foothills of the Appalachian Mountains. When I was around 10 years old there was a very tall creature of some kind that walked past
our bathroom window. It had to be at least 8 or 9 feet tall to be seen in that window because it was very high off the ground. My teenage sister was
in the bathroom curling her hair when she heard something and looked over at the window just in time to see this creature walk by. It was just turning
dusk, but still light enough for her to see it. She screamed bloody murder! We all heard something hollering in the woods for months before, and after
that. The sound wasn&apos;t like the long, low howl they give on the &quot;Finding Bigfoot&quot;show, but it was a high-pitched squeal; sounded more like one of
those large flying prehistoric birds! All the &quot;old-timers&quot; that lived in the area said they had never heard anything like it! My mother wouldn&apos;t
let me go outside to play all year because everyone around was terrified of this thing!
One of our neighbors that lived about 2 miles up the road found his pig ripped open on it&apos;s belly, but the only thing taken was the liver. He said it
was a very clean cut; looked like it could have been done with a knife. He found long white hairs caught on the barbed wire fence close by. This was
back in 1967. One day the screams in the woods just stopped, and we never heard it again. I&apos;ve always wondered what that thing was! Possibly a Big
Foot? 

I remember the furor of the &quot;skunk ape&quot; in your neck of the woods a few years ago. Perhaps a similar creature?

My Dad, who is the most down-to-earth skeptic of all time, once told me he often felt &quot;watched&quot; while walking in the area. He theorized a mountain
lion but never got confirmation. Possibly the same thing? 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 07:58 PM by sled735 Here is my experience with channeling...

When I was in my early twenties I was driving down a country two-lane road when I came upon an extremely sharp curve. As I approached the curve I
heard a voice in my head saying, &quot;STOP!&quot; I was startled, and wondered where that voice came from, and if I really heard it. Again the voice said,
&quot;Pull over off the road as far as you can, and STOP!!&quot; The voice was so demanding, I obeyed. Just as I got over in the grass and sat there for a
couple of seconds wondering if I was &quot;losing it&quot;, a big dump truck came around the curve on my side of the road! If I hadn&apos;t pulled off the road I
would have been hit head-on, and probably killed! I about went into shock. I pulled back onto the road and stopped at the first available place (a
country store) to compose myself!
I have rarely, actually heard a voice in my head like I did that time since that experience, but I get extremely strong feelings (for lack of a better
way to describe it) sometimes, and I know when it&apos;s someone from the other side speaking to me, or just my own thoughts. 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 08:02 PM by Keliah Hi,
I have seen shadow people or whatever you wanna call them on several occasions. Once my son saw one as well. Here&apos;s what happened......

I was asleep and something woke me up. It felt like someone was looking at me. My son was maybe 2-3 yrs old at the time and he was at that stage
where he was too scared to sleep by himself, so he would sleep in my room on the floor. Well as I woke up, I looked towards the area where I felt
someone looking at me and I saw a blob of a shadow. My son then woke up frightened and jumped in the bed with me. This shadow seemed to float from
the side of my room towards my ceiling above us and it seemed to vanish into my wall. The entire time, my son&apos;s eyes followed the motion of this
shadow, scared and terrified out of his wits.

Not sure what it was exactly, needless to say, I didn&apos;t go back to sleep that night. edit on 22-2-2012 by Keliah because: (no reason
given)
 edit on 22-2-2012 by Keliah because: spelling errors
 
 

 reply posted on 22-2-2012 @ 08:05 PM by sled735 Originally posted by smyleegrl 
 Originally posted by sled735 
Here is my monster experience:

I grew up in the foothills of the Appalachian Mountains. When I was around 10 years old there was a very tall creature of some kind that walked past
our bathroom window. It had to be at least 8 or 9 feet tall to be seen in that window because it was very high off the ground. My teenage sister was
in the bathroom curling her hair when she heard something and looked over at the window just in time to see this creature walk by. It was just turning
dusk, but still light enough for her to see it. She screamed bloody murder! We all heard something hollering in the woods for months before, and after
that. The sound wasn&apos;t like the long, low howl they give on the &quot;Finding Bigfoot&quot;show, but it was a high-pitched squeal; sounded more like one of
those large flying prehistoric birds! All the &quot;old-timers&quot; that lived in the area said they had never heard anything like it! My mother wouldn&apos;t
let me go outside to play all year because everyone around was terrified of this thing!
One of our neighbors that lived about 2 miles up the road found his pig ripped open on it&apos;s belly, but the only thing taken was the liver. He said it
was a very clean cut; looked like it could have been done with a knife. He found long white hairs caught on the barbed wire fence close by. This was
back in 1967. One day the screams in the woods just stopped, and we never heard it again. I&apos;ve always wondered what that thing was! Possibly a Big
Foot? 

I remember the furor of the &quot;skunk ape&quot; in your neck of the woods a few years ago. Perhaps a similar creature?

My Dad, who is the most down-to-earth skeptic of all time, once told me he often felt &quot;watched&quot; while walking in the area. He theorized a mountain
lion but never got confirmation. Possibly the same thing? 

Yes, I used to feel &quot;watched&quot; when I&apos;d go for walks in those woods also. I remember once when I was around 12 years old I got the feeling sooooo
strongly I got out of there as quick as I could. Didn&apos;t run in case it was something that would have chased me, but definitely something lurking in
those woods! I really don&apos;t think a mountain lion would have reached to the top of Mom&apos;s bathroom window in that house. If it was a cat, it would
have been walking on its rear legs past the window, and still not tall enough. 
 Pages: &lt;&lt;    1      2      3      4    &gt;&gt;      ^^TOP^^ 

 
 24 hours of Paranormal Activity at my house 
   Posted 12 days ago with 44 member flags The Coming Trials: What Happens Next? 
   Posted 7 days ago with 43 member flags Scientists Prove Ancient Alien Cauldrons in Siberia are Real 
   Posted 1 days ago with 26 member flags Do the developmentally delayed become &quot;normal&quot; after death? 
   Posted 15 days ago with 14 member flags Springheel Jack is back! 
   Posted 14 days ago with 10 member flags Curious EVP at Loveland Castle 
   Posted 5 days ago with 10 member flags Are these ghosts in the cemetery 
   Posted 19 days ago with 8 member flags Results from a Ghost Hunt 
   Posted 12 days ago with 7 member flags 
 Newest topics, updated in real-time: 

 1995 UFO Sighting UK Norfolk (Help me find the video) 
   Aliens and UFOs : 3 minutes ago Aliens and the Great deception 
   Aliens and UFOs : 14 minutes ago If these actors turned one-time MMA fighters for charity 
   U.S. Sports : 17 minutes ago Biden Addresses Empty Seats at NAACP Convention? 
   2012 US Elections : 21 minutes ago Solar Flare Headed Our Way! 
   Other Current Events : 23 minutes ago Build-up to a terrorist act 2012 
   Other Current Events : 25 minutes ago Bath Salt Zombie: Guy Disfigures Victim, Bites Cops 
   Breaking Alternative News : 29 minutes ago The bible supports life on other planets. 
   Aliens and UFOs : 31 minutes ago 
 Newest topics getting flags, in real-time: 

 Look no further~ The Gentleperson&apos;s Guide To Forum Spies 
   Deconstructing Disinformation : 8 hours ago, 37 flags Warren Buffet says he can end the deficit in 5 minutes! 
   Political Issues : 7 hours ago, 28 flags I wanted to be in control of my happiness. My wish may have been granted so i will share it. 
   Philosophy and Metaphysics : 12 hours ago, 26 flags Poll: Americans Confidence In Television Media Falls To All-Time Low 
   Breaking Alternative News : 16 hours ago, 23 flags The UFO Files: aliens &apos;might come here for holidays&apos;/ Tony Blair briefed by the MOD 
   Breaking Alternative News : 13 hours ago, 21 flags Ademo Freeman Facing 21 Years For Video Taping A Cop Beating Up A Teenager 
   Breaking Alternative News : 9 hours ago, 15 flags Multiple witness UFO cases: the hoaxes? 
   Aliens and UFOs : 7 hours ago, 14 flags Have the major Gov&apos; of the world already surrendered to ET ? 
   Aliens and UFOs : 10 hours ago, 14 flags 
 Newest topics getting replies, in real-time: 

 How many Disinfomation agents are members here? 
   General Conspiracies : 17 hours ago, 117 replies Beautiful Crop Circle: Italy June 25th 2012 : Alien Made or 2 Guys With A Board 
   Aliens and UFOs : 8 hours ago, 90 replies I wanted to be in control of my happiness. My wish may have been granted so i will share it. 
   Philosophy and Metaphysics : 12 hours ago, 70 replies The UFO Files: aliens &apos;might come here for holidays&apos;/ Tony Blair briefed by the MOD 
   Breaking Alternative News : 13 hours ago, 69 replies Parts of Chicago now akin to Iraq-Afghanistan tribal/civil war 
   Social Issues and Civil Unrest : 9 hours ago, 59 replies Look no further~ The Gentleperson&apos;s Guide To Forum Spies 
   Deconstructing Disinformation : 8 hours ago, 53 replies Mitt Romney stayed at Bain 3 years longer than he stated 
   2012 US Elections : 6 hours ago, 44 replies Obama&apos;s Re-Election Campaign Selects Hemp Fabrics 
   US Political Madness : 15 hours ago, 38 replies 
 [close] The Above Top Secret Web sites are a
wholly owned social content community of
The Above Network, LLC.

 This content community relies on
user-generated content from our member contributors.
The opinions of our members are not those of site ownership
who maintains strict editorial agnosticism and simply provides
a collaborative venue for free expression.


ATS Server: www2.theabovenetwork.com 
Header data: 0.008 seconds
Page processed in: 0.172 seconds

 INFO 
 About ATS 
 Info for Journalists 
 Site Statistics 
 Advertising 
 The Above Network 
 Contact Us 
 CONTENT 
 Board Home 
 ATS News 
 Firehose 
 Recent Posts 
 Popular Forums 
 10-Day Summary 
 Email Newsletter 
 RSS Feeds 
 Twitter 
 Facebook 
 VIDEO 
 ATS News 
 Top Videos 
 Videos Home 
 Pro Videos 
 Member Videos 
 HELP 
 DMCA info 
 Join ATS 
 Recover Password 
 Terms&amp;Conditions 
 Privacy Policy 
 Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
