<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008029" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080926203754AAnQte0" time="2012-07-13-01:06" support="20" score="0.12321602321489457" bingtitle="Why is it whenever i order a milk shake at a fast food restaurant ..." webtitle="Why is it whenever i order a milk shake at a fast food restaurant the always make the milkshake first? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001376" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000884" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="106"/>
	<description>Best Answer: It&apos;s a conspiracy. They hate you. ... i work @ hardees and the reason we make our milkshakes first is becaus ethey are handscooped and they ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Cavalier KCS mom Member since: 10 March 2007 Total points: 18,744 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Why is it whenever i order a milk shake at a fast food restaurant the always make the milkshake first?
 Has anyone else ever noticed that? It sits there on the counter melting while my food is being cooked. Think about it. Don&apos;t most people generally eat their milk shake during the time they are eating their food or take it home and freeze it for later. By the time my hot food is ready it&apos;s always halfway melted. Why do all fast food restaurant do it that way? When someone orders their meal that is always the last thing to be ordered. It shouldn&apos;t be the first thing prepared. I have even tried ordering my milk shake on a separate order to avoid my milk shake from melting and still they made it first before my food was ready. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Effem T Member since: 17 May 2008 Total points: 6,627 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 It&apos;s a conspiracy. They hate you. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Hey thanks! I never drink my milkshake with my dinner. Since the day i was old enough to drink a milk shake i have always taken it home, put it in my freezer and ate it with a spoon after it had the consistency of ice cream. Yum. I know a lot of people who do that. 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Why is it whenever i… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by AB Member since: 24 March 2007 Total points: 2,286 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i work @ hardees and the reason we make our milkshakes first is becaus ethey are handscooped and they sometimes take long to make plus the hot food is suppose to be up with in 3 minutes and 30 seconds....but we usually give the customers there milkshake when it comes up so they can drink it 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by rachel7 Member since: 27 September 2008 Total points: 311 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I used to work at dq and this is how it worked there: we had a staff that worked at the front--taking orders and making all drinks, blizzards, and shakes, and we had a staff that worked the back making all the hot food. We always worked a little faster in the front than in the back, so that is why the shakes always are done first. The back takes a little longer for everything to cook. They were two seperate operations, making hot food and making drinks and such. 
Source(s):
 personal experience 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Pervis M Member since: 22 August 2008 Total points: 793 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I checked with the authorities who control the sequence of food preparation at all fast food restaurants and I was told this: Aunt Jemima wraps her hair in a red scarf. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Zwisslb Member since: 27 September 2008 Total points: 1,276 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well personally that does not bother me for the following reason: fresh milkshakes are very difficult to suck through a straw. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Lamar&apos;s Alarm Member since: 18 December 2007 Total points: 26,101 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It was the cashier that fixed or the manager I bet. They have a little more&quot;free&quot;time to fix it. It&apos;s easy to fix and readily fast.

 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Will McDonald&apos;s call me back for hire? Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Deeny! 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
