<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008691" url="http://www.veggieboards.com/newvb/archive/index.php/t-102079.html" time="2012-07-13-02:09" support="1" score="0.0013834674143048955" bingtitle="Have you ever accidentally eaten meat? [Archive] - VeggieBoards ..." webtitle="Have you ever accidentally eaten meat?">
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>... and she was very apologetic and changed my order. ... haven&apos;t bought so much as a soda at any fast food restaurant. ... table in the corner and pout while they eat their meal XD</description>
	<body>
		VeggieBoards Join VeggieBoards 
 Home Forums Reviews Articles Gallery My Profile 
 Remember Me or Connect with Facebook Advanced Search VeggieBoards  ›  Forums  ›  Support Forums  ›  Vegetarian Discussion  ›  Have you ever accidentally eaten meat? Join Now 
Be a part of the community.

It&apos;s free, join today!
 
Tags
 ( ? ) 

 
Recent Reviews
 See All the Latest Reviews 
 Tofutti Better Than Cream Cheese - Herbs&amp;Chives Reviewed by saretta It was the first time I bought the tofutti cream cheese. I like the taste and especially with herbs. it is easy to accomodate on bread or bagels, and also to eat with vegetables; However I... Full Review Tofurky Roast Beef Style Deli Slices Reviewed by saretta It was the first time I tasted a Tofurky product. I found it pretty good, not too much spicy. In a bagel with tomato and green salad it is tasty, or with a plate of vegetables. I&apos;ll try... Full Review gardein Home Style Beefless Tips Reviewed by Fozziebear We love these things. Great for making steak sandwiches. Fry em up with some onions and peppers and toss it in a bun. Sooo good. Also good for making&quot;beef&quot;stew with some carrots, potatoes,... Full Review Primal Spirit Foods Primal Strips - Hickory Smoked Reviewed by Fozziebear Absolutely LOVE the flavor. My only complaint is that opening the package and not making a mess can be tricky. Most traditional jerky is more on the dry side, like Stonewalls vegan jerky. But... Full Review gardein Seven Grain Crispy Tenders Reviewed by Fozziebear Flavor and texture is great, but the&quot;breading&quot;stuff can stick easily if you don&apos;t watch and flip them on an ongoing basis during baking. Overall, a great product. Full Review 
 New Posts   All Forums: Forum Nav: Home Subscriptions Private Messages Who&apos;s Online Forums    Forum Information       Introduce Yourself       Community Assistance       VB Star of the Week       VeggieBoards Chatroom    Support Forums       New to Vegetarianism
	</body>
</document>
