<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008089" url="http://www.becas.net.au/software.html" time="2012-07-13-01:10" support="12" score="0.017335139070268474" bingtitle="Becas POS Solution" webtitle="Becas POS Solution">
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>... an existing order, you can change the order list by add new items ... such as birthday cake needed, baby seats ... Kitchen Display System for Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		English Tiếng Việt 
   
 
 
   
 
 
 
 POS&amp;PAGING Gallery Restaurant POS Bar and Club POS Retail POS Petrol Station POS Supermarket POS POS Hardware Paging System EFTPOS R&amp;D Screenshot 
   
   
 
 BTPOS, The fast POS system for Restaurants, Cafes, Fast Food Bars, Take Away , Hotel 
 
 Becas Restaurant POS system is easy to use, fast and robust 

Becas provides complete POS solution for Restaurant/Take Away/Cafe/Bar/Club/Hotel application.
 Becas has integrated all daily tasks in one system, and many other tasks that never can be found elsewhere: Dine-in and/or Takeaway services Bar and Kitchen printers filter Secured Network with upto hundreds POS terminals and Handheld devices at one venue Multi-venues and franchise management support Pizza Style operation with multiple LCD screen Kitchen Display System Reliable Handheld ordering terminal Integrated MSR (Magnetic Stripe Card) membership reward card Customised Loyalty Program: up to ten prices level per item, Happy Hour, Membership Card discount, Gift Card, etc Restaurant Guest/Staff Paging system Fully integrated with LRS&apos;s Paging System Customised integrated with SMS service (Promotion, Remind for confirmed Booking) Wireless Table Call paging system Support Booking, Reservation and Queue Management System Remote Back Office monitor software based on Web interface Support Order online and booking online Interface to Hotel Property Management System (PMS) Can be customised to suit specific application 
BECAS POS(BTPOS) is a powerfull point of sale system designed for the hospitality such as restaurant, cafes, fast food chain, etc. 
 BTPOS is suitable for any size of business with the installation ranging from a single stand alone workstation to an fully network of many workstations, handheld orderings, printers, kitchen display systems and electronic variable message signs.
 BTPOS software can be configured to adapt to any type of table service business and quick service such as bars, RSL&apos;s clubs, hotels,
 resorts, restaurants with delivery and take away, fast food chains.

BTPOS system operating on Linux Operating System, and equipped with powerfull database server MySQL, web server based on Php and Apache. Every POS terminal can be configured to run in stand-alone or fully network mode.

Followings are just a few available features of BTPOS system:

Easy to program and modify menu

 Easy to program and modify menu Menu Item buttons could be configured as text or image, different color activated by item price Multiple menus supported; The purpose of multiple menus is to minimise the time spent for order taking in restaurants with browsing or scrolling complex menu of hundreds groups and thousand items and items modifiers On the fly touch screen keyboard provided for add in any new item or item modifier Multiple levels of menu and sub-menu item such as Soft Drink (main item), and Coke, Fanta, (Sub Item) 

Table Service Management

 

 A standard and customised table layout could be embedded into the POS stationary. A standard table layout has a table name as numbers, such as table 1, table 10. Each table could be shared between different customers. The shared table is named such as Table 1, 1A, 1B and 1C You can view, re-print a list of items ordered of an unpaid order table or extract the tax invoice of paid order table With an existing order, you can change the order list by add new items or cancel items. The printers only print the added or cancel items. It does not print the whole list. That prevent the mistakes in the kitchen. The chefs only make newly added items When a table presented with the bill, that means that table should soon become available and if you have a waiting guests, you could tell them table should be available in few minutes. That could increase your turn over per table Support Split Bill Support Takeaway and Home delievry on the same system 

Quick Service Management

 Easy to assign and call any guest pager for every take away order (pay upfront and wait for the meal, no waiter/waitress) on any POS terminals in the network 

 

 Suitable for Food Court Counter or RSL&apos;s club ranging from one POS terminal to many POS terminals Support Kitchen/Bar/Tax Invoice printers and Kitchen Display System (KDS) 

Reservation, Booking and Queue Management

For Dining In Restaurant, reservation function plays very important role to increase business turnover and keep customer come back. Becas POS system has provided a Web Host User Interface window that allows operator to view all reservations in any particular day and time, how many seats available, and in case of restaurant fully booked when estimated time for next available seats or tables. Each reservation will also have special note such as birthday cake needed, baby seats, etc. Those little things will make customer feel well looked after and ofcourse they keep coming back. A customised SMS service can be integrated for member promotion, booking confirmed and queue management.

Many busy restaurants have lost significant income of customers who dont want to wait in the long queue in front of venue for their seat. That can make traffic congestion and get customers feel inconvenient. With BTPOS queue management, customers have choice to either give out their mobile phone or receive the coaster pager, soon when a table asked for bill, the paging message will be sent to next waiting customer.

Push Button Service

Most of hotel/resort venue today have built-in restautants, bars, outdoor swimming pools. In order to keep customers high satisfactory level, Becas help you to deliver world class standard and personalised push button services that make your hotel/resort outstanding among other hotels. Becas have two different product range that applied for indoor or outdoor facilities: Restaurant Table Genie (Table Call service) or Beach Buttler (Beach resort Push Button Service)

 

 

Table Genies products applied mostly for indoor restaurant, every table is attached with 3 push buttons unit. Customer can press button such as Meal Button, Beverage Button or Bill Button. The alert message with information like which service and what table will be apear on staff pager. Staff will then response to those request. The Table Genie and Beach Butler products can work as stand alone system with no need of computer, no wiring, no software. These products are simple to use, low maintenance cost and very effective way to improve customer service and also generate more income (more service request that means more order and therefore more income).

 Staff Security (Optional) 
Becas provides three options for staff security control: On Screen Sign In and Sign Out with password protection, Magnitic swipe card with incorporated card reader and proximity swipe card with integrated proximity (no contact) card reader. Each operational functions can be locked depend on the level of signed in members. Those functions could be Open Till, Discount, Price Update, Menu Update, etc.
Powerloss Proof
Any orders that has been sent to kitchen printers, they automatically saved into the central database server on the hard disk. If you have power loss situation, don&apos;t panic, when the power resumed, every orders are still there and the POS system still stayed intact.
Comprehensive Reports
Features rich extensive reports include: sales reports such as Daily, Weekly reports and also the best and worst performane items reports
Database Server

Database played vital role in any of POS software solution. Becas has incorporated MySQL database server in any of our BTPOS terminals. MySQL database has been widely used by many big corporations in the world. MySQL is a open source software and recently been acquired by Sun Microsystems.

 The central database server could be hosted in one of the POS stationary. It allows to save cost for extra PC-based server Large database storage which can store many years of sales records Database easy to backup (Different options available: USB, remote internet backup, Becas annually paid service) 

Kitchen Display System for Fast Food Restaurant

 
Kitchen Display System (KDS) works perfectly in the quick service Take Away/Delievry restaurants such as Cafe/Bakery/Pizza venues, that means customers queued at counter to pay upfront and wait for the kitchen to prepare and serve their meals. The Quick Service restaurant is different with the Eat-In restaurant where an order is served in due course (Entree, Main Meal, Deserve), order can be changed like add new items, cancel item and customer pay their bill afterward. KDS is not prefered to use in Eat-In restaurant.

Chefs or kichen hand staffs will prepare the meal based on complete items list displayed on the KDS screens. Becas KDS system includes one or multiple screens connected in parallel and the little keypad to bump orders in and out of the screen.

Handheld Ordering (PDAPOS)

PDAPOS features include big 4 inches touch screen. PDAPOS is reliable, fast and very easy to use. Orders taken with PDAPOS at tables are sent directly to kitchen/bar printers or KDS. 
 
 The kichen printers print the food items only and the bar printers print the beverage items. A cutting edge software technology ensures the order registered by PDAPOS will be printed out at kitchen printers in the harsh environment (waves from microwave, mobile phones could interfere with BemPOS network).

PDAPOS also have a window of venue&apos;s table floorplan that marks which table paid, get billed, available or occupied. That helps waiter/waitress to lead customers to their seat easily.

Remote Management and Online Orders (Optional)
BECAS Web Host Server (BWHS) provides all venue&apos;s management task such as menu change, loyalty program and scheduling, stock control, membership managenment, featured rich reports, export reports to MS Excel, etc. Followings are key features of BWHS server:
 Franchise Business applies Becas remote services to send over any new menu, new price and check the sales record from internet to its franchisees Remote monitor: Remote monitor keep business owner inform of sales data, stock data, performance data at anywhere internet can be accesed. Remote Database Backup and Restore: If your database is important to your business, Becas provides backup and restore service in daily, monthly, quarterly, yearly, etc. We rather prevent problem to happen than sorry when lost data happen. Remote troubleshoot and new software update: Becas has applied this feature successfully for particularly customers in interstate. Most of problems, software bugs can be fixed using this feature. 
 
 
 
 © 2006-2011 BECAS Technology P/L. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
