<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008518" url="http://weblogs.sun-sentinel.com/features/food/restaurants/blog/magazines/" time="2012-07-13-01:58" support="4" score="0.013873794768692205" bingtitle="SUP: Eating around South Florida. Restaurant reviews, news ..." webtitle="SUP: Eating around South Florida. Restaurant reviews, news, specials, recipes, chef stories, and more | Sun Sentinel blogs">
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001101" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>... and did so well that this now signature item has a permanent spot on the menu board. ... While the good folks at Consumers Union aren’t recommending we eat fast food, we all ...</description>
	<body>
		Jobs Cars Autos A-Z Real estate Rentals New homes MERCHANDISE HOME DELIVERY 
   
 Home 
 OBITS WEATHER TRAFFIC LOTTERY HOROSCOPES ADVERTISE CONTACT US HOME DELIVERY Subscriber Rewards CLASSIFIED VIDEO 
 News 
 SCHOOLS WEATHER OBITS CRIME&amp;SAFETY TRAFFIC FLORIDA NATION/WORLD BLOGS NEWS TIPS Broward Palm Beach Co MIAMI-DADE 
 Broward 
 P. PINES HOLLYWOOD FT. LAUD C.SPRINGS DAVIE DEERFIELD POMPANO SUNRISE PLANTATION C. CREEK TAMARAC WESTON MIRAMAR MORE CITIES 
 Palm Beach 
 WELLINGTON BOYNTON BEACH WEST BOCA BOCA RATON DELRAY BEACH ROYAL PALM BEACH 
 Sports 
 BROWARD HIGH SCHOOL PALM HIGH SCHOOL MIAMI HEAT Miami Dolphins PANTHERS MARLINS UM UF FSU FAU OUTDOORS Recreation 
 Entertainment 
 CULTURE Events MOVIES MOVIE TIMES FOOD&amp;RESTAURANTS dining blog Go Guide MUSIC Gambling What&apos;s Hot TV LISTINGS JICHA/TV 
 Travel 
 Getaway of the Day Your vacation photos Florida beach guide Top 50 at Florida theme parks Florida cruises Travel blog 
 Lifestyle 
 FASHION YOUR HOME Food Drinks YOUR KIDS Parenting blog SHOPPING BLOG DEALS FAITH Society Pets Jewish Journal 
 Business 
 YOUR CAREER It&apos;s Your Money blog House Keys blog PERSONAL FINANCE DEALS Business News Consumer blog Real Estate CONDOS&amp;HOAS 
 Health 
 HealthKey.com Wellness Women Seniors Fitness Family 
 Opinion 
 CONTACT US Today&apos;s Buzz Cartoons BLOGS 
 Jobs Cars Autos A-Z Real estate 
 New Construction Foreclosures Apts&amp;Rentals Sell a home HomeSource Magazine Tax Credit Info Open Houses 
 Rentals New homes MERCHANDISE HOME DELIVERY 
 
 SUP 

 Eating around South Florida 


Category: Magazines (35)
 
 Southern Living calls Georgia Pig one of the best barbecue joints 

 By John Tanasychuk May 16, 2012 03:26 PM
	</body>
</document>
