<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008010" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080105144121AABzz8P" time="2012-07-13-01:05" support="1" score="0.00030212809539981503" bingtitle="Does anyone have a suggestion for a topic that i can use for a ..." webtitle="Does anyone have a suggestion for a topic that i can use for a persuasive speech? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>Why we should wear seat belts in cars Why you ... If you believe - they put a man on the moon ... The best fast food restaurant and why! Just a few...Good Luck</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Education&amp;Reference &gt; Homework Help &gt; Resolved Question 
 cutie Member since: July 19, 2006 Total points: 441 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Does anyone have a suggestion for a topic that i can use for a persuasive speech?

 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by corn4lun... Member since: June 15, 2007 Total points: 241 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Choose the topic that you&apos;re most opinionated about. Something that you feel everyone needs to do or get involved with. Your opinion makes a huge difference on how your speech will turn out. For me it would be the government, but thats a different story. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Laura Member since: April 05, 2007 Total points: 1,122 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Persuasive Speech Topics

The case for organ donation
The need for recycling
Why the death penalty should be abolished
The need for gun control
The dangers of taking illegal steroids

How to pay off your credit card

Avoiding drinking or drunk driving

Why we should abolish school uniform

Global Warming - What we can do about it

Why we should wear seat belts in cars

Why you should become a blood donor

The dangers of gambling

Gay marriage

Euthanasia

Avoiding student debt

Avoiding junk food

More topics

Animal rights
Ten things you can do for a Dollar/ Euro/ Pound
What you should wear for your next date/ job interview
I can make you thin
Pay off your student loan in three easy steps
Volunteering - What can you do about it?
Golf - the best hobby in the world or a complete waste of time?

Can drugs reverse the ageing process?
If you believe - they put a man on the moon
Princess Diana - a cover up?
Internet - the death of the newspaper?
Can we eradicate AIDS in Africa?
Is Broadband economic in rural areas?
What good is keep fit?
Sex, drugs and rock and roll - good fun or a major health hazard?
Getting to the top of the waiting list
Road congestion charging - the way of the future?
Dogs - wolves in the living room or man&apos;s best friend?
7 easy ways to simplify your life?
The five day detox
The Loch Ness monster really does exist
Creative thinking
Has the DaVinci code just been made up?
Half man - half robot. Should we be scared?
Political

Creative thinking
Vote for me
Why there should be a United States of Europe
An easy way to give up smoking
Why prostitution should be legalized
How we can get more people to vote?
Why the death penalty should be abolished in the United States
Why we should not consume genetically modified crops?
Should religious clothes be banned in schools?
The war in Iraq - was it justified?
Famous lives

The greatest American./ Briton/ French Person/ Scientist/ Discoverer/ Adventurer of all time
Scott of the Antarctic - hero or failure?
Winston Churchill - good man or a famous alcoholic? 
Source(s):
 http://www.presentationhelper.co.uk/pers… 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by ageless Member since: December 16, 2007 Total points: 1,066 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Private School (Why it&apos;s better or worse for students)
Public School (&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;)
Why our society should or should not idolize size 2 models.
Why we should stay a democratic society
The best cold cereal is______________and why!
Why schools should be year round!
Why schools should be only 6 months a year!
The best fast food restaurant and why!

Just a few...Good Luck 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Flames Girl Member since: September 30, 2007 Total points: 1,788 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Persuade everyone that Team Canada has the best hockey players in the world. We just won in the juniors so it would make it more persuasive because it would prove your point. 
Source(s):
 My head, and team canada just won sweden and got the gold medal. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by *.*.BaRb... Member since: September 21, 2007 Total points: 831 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 hey;)
i did one on animal testing for speech class..
and it was superr easy..
theres so many sites on it..
so it took like 15 minutes and i was done hahah
muahSs;) 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by yourdrea... Member since: December 29, 2007 Total points: 714 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 that the cubs are the best baseball team plagued by poor ownership 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Homework Help 

 Operations on complex numbers? When setting voter requirements today, States CAN use...? Normal distribution (statistics), can you please help? DESPERATE NEED OF HELP!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!… 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Education&amp;Reference 
 Financial Aid Higher Education (University +) Home Schooling Homework Help Other - Education Preschool Primary&amp;Secondary Education Quotations Special Education Standards&amp;Testing Studying Abroad Teaching Trivia Words&amp;Wordplay 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
