<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008117" url="http://www.theage.com.au/business/bendigo-scales-up-its-offer-20111218-1p0pp.html" time="2012-07-13-01:12" support="1" score="0.0015721929700349953" bingtitle="Bendigo scales up its offer" webtitle="Bendigo scales up its offer">
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>... France&apos;s BRED Banque Populaire retained its near 5 per ... $0 Fee Credit Card. 0% balance transfers for 6 months + $0 ... Property Price Data; Tributes &amp; Celebrations; Place an ad</description>
	<body>
		Skip to navigation Skip to content Help using this website - Accessibility statement 
Sorry but this feature is currently unavailable. Please try again later.
 
 9:12AM Friday Jul 13, 2012 617
 online now See today&apos;s paper 
 Fairfax Digital 
 The Age Real Estate Cars Jobs Dating Newsletters More 
 Essential Baby Stayz InvestSMART Trading Room Weatherzone More sites» 
 
 
 The Age 

 Business 

 News 
 Today&apos;s News&amp;Views Comment&amp;Analysis World Business Media&amp;Marketing BusinessDay Mobile Small Business 
 Markets Quotes Portfolio Money Property Focus Small Business 
 Startup Managing Franchising Trends Entrepreneur Marketing Finance Technology Resources 
 Executive Style 
 Travel Motors Culture Gadgets Luxury Management Style Fitness Wine 
 Compare&amp;Save 
 Credit Cards Debit Cards Home Loans Personal Loans Car Loans Term Deposits Bank Accounts Savings Accounts 
 Events 

 You are here: Home BusinessDay Article 
 
Search age:
 
Search in:

 Business 
 theage.com.au Web Business 
 
 
Bendigo scales up its offer
 Date December 19, 2011 
 Read later 
 
Eric Johnston
 
 Tweet Pin It Email article Print 
 
On Friday, Bendigo said it would pay $130 million for the local arm of Bank of Cyprus Group, marking the European bank&apos;s exit from Australia. Photo: James Davies 
 
BENDIGO and Adelaide Bank is this morning expected to scale up the size of its $120 million institutional placement after the offer was rushed by investors late on Friday.

The placement, which will be used to help fund the acquisition of the Bank of Cyprus&apos; Australian arm, was nearly three times oversubscribed, suggesting strong support for banking shares even in the face of a subdued credit outlook for the sector and rising concern over Europe.

On Friday, Bendigo said it would pay $130 million for the local arm of Bank of Cyprus Group, marking the European bank&apos;s exit from Australia.

While Bendigo is understood to have taken on new institutional shareholders as part of the capital raising, key Bendigo shareholder France&apos;s BRED Banque Populaire retained its near 5 per cent stake by taking up its full entitlement.
 Advertisement 
New shares were sold to institutions at $8.45 each, a discount to when they last traded at $9.

The regional bank will also push ahead with a share purchase plan for retail investors, which is expected to raise up to an additional $70 million.

Bendigo shares were placed under a trading halt on Friday and are expected to resume trade this morning.

Despite problems in its home market, Bank of Cyprus&apos; 14 branches in Victoria, New South Wales and South Australia were generating a strong performance. The Australian network had high levels of liquidity and its $1.4 billion lending book remains healthy.

Marking the first acquisition for Bendigo chief executive Mike Hirst, the deal is expected to be both earnings and return-on-equity positive as soon as the business is integrated into Bendigo&apos;s own.

Still, analysts remain lukewarm, describing the buyout as expensive and relying on deep cost savings for it to boost Bendigo&apos;s profit in the near term.
 
 Tweet Pin It Email article Print Reprints&amp;permissions 
 Advertisement 
 Executive Style 

 Travel Motors Culture Gadgets Management Style 
 
 How I learned to love the Tour de France 

Three weeks of drama, tension, glory, defeat and fatigue and that&apos;s just in late-night lounge rooms.
 
 Networking nosh: Let&apos;s (not) do lunch 

 Are the days of the &quot;long lunch&quot; dead and gone?
 
 Dressing like dad: &apos;Kidult&apos; fashion 

 Why do fathers insist on dressing like their teenage sons?
 
 Trump turns tartan: Trump&apos;s Scottish birdy 

 He struck out in the casino business, now Trump is teeing off.
 Featured advertisers 
Special offers Powered by Mozo 
 View these special offers by Mozo. Sponsored links Advertisement Advertisement 
 Business 
 
 How to calculate your tax rate 
 
 Theage.com.au Ask our small biz experts How to price website ads Online coffee success story 
 
 Motoring 
 
 New Cars for 2012 
 
 Drive.com.au Great Aussie Road Trip Sell your car easily Find us on Facebook 
 
 Real Estate 
 
 Renovating bit by bit 
 
 Domain.com.au Buy real estate Need an inspection report? Download a Domain mobile app 
 
 Holiday Rentals 
 
 Find the best deals in executive accommodation 
 
 Rent-a-home.com.au Sydney city accommodation Melbourne accommodation Short-term rentals 
 
 TheVine 
 
 &quot;Model comps gave me an eating disorder&quot; 
 
 Thevine.com.au Entertainment&amp;celebrity news Latest fashion coverage Music news and reviews 
 
Compare and Save
 
Skip to:

 Best Deals Mobile Broadband Home Loans Credit Cards Low Rate Cards Rewards Cards Savings Accts Term Deposits Loans 
 
Check out today&apos;s best deals
 
 USaver Rate Increase 
 
 NEW 5.71% bonus rate for popular USaver account 
 
 Compare rates 
 
 ANZ Online Saver 
 
 5.25% bonus rate. Until 30/11/2012 
 
 Check it out&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 UHomeLoan 
 
 Low 5.62% comparison rate + $500 EFTPOS gift card 
 
 Save now&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 Bonus Beats Headphones 
 
 On HTC One S and HTC One. RRP of $279 
 
 Free Headphones 
 
 Samsung Galaxy S3 
 
 Save 10% online, compare double data offers and more.... 
 
 Compare Online Deals 
 
Readers&apos; most viewed
 Most viewed articles on Brisbane Times 
Top 5 Business articles

 Economy sheds 27,000 jobs Markets Live: Slide fuelled by job losses House prices slide with more to come: NAB Card fraud soars as shoppers move online Nullarbor widens as WA leaves rest behind 
 Most viewed articles on WA Today 
Top 5 Business articles

 Markets Live: Slide fuelled by job losses Economy sheds 27,000 jobs House prices slide with more to come: NAB Jobs data misses the real story Myer axes jobs as retail woes grow 
 Most viewed articles on The Sydney Morning Herald 
Top 5 Business articles

 Markets Live: Slide fuelled by job losses Economy sheds 27,000 jobs House prices slide with more to come: NAB Myer axes jobs as retail woes grow Card fraud soars as shoppers move online 
 Most viewed articles on Canberra Times 
Top 5 Business articles

 Markets Live: Slide fuelled by job losses House prices slide with more to come: NAB Economy sheds 27,000 jobs Dollar demand may see currency higher: RBA Jobs data misses the real story 
 Most viewed articles on The Age 
Top 5 Business articles

 Economy sheds 27,000 jobs House prices slide with more to come: NAB Markets Live: Slide fuelled by job losses Myer axes jobs as retail woes grow Jobs data misses the real story 
 
 The Age Home Victoria National World Environment Opinion Business Technology Digital Life Entertainment Life&amp;Style Travel Cars Exec Style Sport Weather 
 
 
The Age
 Sitemap About Us Contact Us Advertise With Us AM Today Last 8 days Text Version Site Accessibility Guide 

 
Products&amp;Services
 Subscribe to the Newspaper Manage My Subscription Subscriber Benefits Good Food Guide The Age Shop Newsletters 

 
Connect
 Mobile Site The AGE for iPad Digital Edition iPhone App RSS Facebook Twitter LinkedIn 

 
Classifieds
 Place an Ad Classifieds&amp;Notices Accommodation Cars Dating Jobs Property Price Data Real Estate Trading Post Tributes&amp;Celebrations 

 
Fairfax Media
 Member Centre Conditions of Use Privacy Policy News Store Archive Photo Sales Purchase Front Pages Fairfax Syndication Fairfax Events Fairfax Careers Press Council 
 Fairfax Media 
Our Sites

 The Sydney Morning Herald The Age MyCareer Domain Drive RSVP Essential Baby InvestSMART APM Stayz Weatherzone The Vine 

Our Partners

 Business Hair Salons Computer Repairs Electricians Painters Lawyers Credit Cards Cruises Rubbish Removals Tax Refunds Weddings 
 Copyright©2012 Fairfax Media
	</body>
</document>
