<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008770" url="http://www.bizbuysell.com/franchise-for-sale/Food-and-Restaurant-Franchise" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="35" score="0.17809795462782244" bingtitle="Food And Restaurant Franchises for Sale - BizBuySell.com" webtitle="Food And Restaurant Franchises for Sale - BizBuySell.com">
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="001459" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001471" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001018" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001030" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001502" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000890" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>58 Food And Restaurant Opportunities Found. The following are the top Food And ... Get ready for fun and great made-to-order pizza when you enter the door of this ...</description>
	<body>
		Already a BizBuySell Member?

Log In to Continue
 


Invalid log in. Check your user name and password.
 Email Address (Member ID): Password: 
 Verifying... 
 
 Forgot Your Password? 

 Note : The email address you provided matches an existing account. Please log in using this email address and your original password. If you don&apos;t recall your password, click the &apos;Forgot Your Password?&apos; link.
 
 Are you new to BizBuySell? 
 
 
BizBuySell - The Internet&apos;s Largest Business for Sale&amp;Franchise for Sale Marketplace
 
 Welcome! Sign In Register For Brokers 

 My BizBuySell BrokerWorks 
 My Listings My Watch List My Saved Searches My BizAlerts My Ad Responses My Ad Inquiries My Valuation Reports My Community Questions My Community Answers My Profile 
 Sign Out For Brokers 
 
 
 
 
 Food And Restaurant Franchises 
 64 Food And Restaurant Opportunities Found. 

The following are the top Food And Restaurant Franchises for sale on BizBuySell. Buying a Buffalo&apos;s, Kona Ice or other Food And Restaurant can be a wise and fulfilling means towards business ownership. You may click to view more information on each franchise, but for complete franchise requirements, benefits and financial information use our Request List. 

 Showing 1 - 50 of 64 Franchises Found Page: 1 2 Refine Results 
Franchise Category
 All Franchises Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Child Related Cleaning And Maintenance Computer And Internet Food And Restaurant Health, Beauty, and Fitness High Capital Franchises Home Based Businesses Home Services Hot Franchises Low Cost Franchises Retail Franchises Sports And Recreation Travel And Lodging SubCategory Loading... All SubCategories Coffee Deli&amp;Sandwich Fast Casual Fast Food Ice Cream Make&amp;Take Pizza Restaurant Smoothies Wine, Drink 
State
 All States Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
Capital to Invest
 All Amounts Up to $25,000 Up to $50,000 Up to $100,000 Up to $250,000 Up to $500,000 Up to $1,000,000 Up to $5,000,000 
 Business Financing with IRA/401k-Guidant Financial 

 Use retirement funds as a loan down payment or to purchase a business or franchise. Lower debt and increase potential for success. No tax penalties. (Min $50k in IRA/401k)  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Fresh Healthy Vending $120,000 Capital Required 

 Join the &quot;Healthy Vending Revolution&quot; - Operate Your own Fresh Healthy Vending Franchise.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 FiltaFry - FiltaCool - Filta Groups Mobile $79,000 - $88,500 Capital Required 

 FiltaFry- Filta Group&apos;s Filtafry is a unique green, mobile franchise opportunity with one of the lowest SBA loan default rates in the franchising industry. See why today!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Automated Distributors $10,295 - $49,500 Capital Required 

 Automated Distributors is currently offering an opportunity for individuals looking to establish their own business for a low cost investment. Learn how our high quality machines can work...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Boozelator™ Breathalyzer Vending Business $1,995 Capital Required 

 The Boozelator™ 3001 is a much needed safety product for any alcohol-serving establishment. Awesome growth potential and LOW start-up cost!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Lemon Heaven 

 Lemon Heaven Beverages is actively seeking qualified individuals to own and operate exclusive territories around the world.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Jimmy John&apos;s Gourmet Sandwich $289,900 - $386,500 Capital Required 

 Gourmet sandwich shops franchise specializing in fresh french bread subs and 7 grain wheat bread subs.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Kona Ice $98,900 Capital Required 

 EXPLOSIVE 400% GROWTH, AMAZING MARGINS, AND UNBEATABLE SUPPORT all make KONA ICE a NO BRAINER! STILL AVAILABLE IN EVERY MAJOR MARKET!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Joey Bag a Donuts $207,000 - $587,000 Capital Required 

 Joey Bag a Donuts is your way to own one of the most competitive donut shop franchises in the business! We will provide you with an efficient system that allows you to bring the nostalgia...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Berrylicious Frozen Yogurt $250,000 Capital Required 

 Premium frozen yogurt where you can taste the difference.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Bella Pita $80,000 Capital Required 

 Fresh and Healthy Mediterranean Cuisine!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 BevIntel $29,900 - $39,900 Capital Required 

 BevIntel is the global leader in Profit Management for Bars and Restaurants. Since 1987, BevIntel Franchisees have helped restaurant and bar owners increase revenue and decrease operational...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Mama Romano&apos;s $250,000 Capital Required 

 An Italian Restaurant that Delivers Profits and Great Food!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Healthy U Snacks $20,000 Capital Required 

 Healthy U Snacks Inc. is a new concept in healthy snacks and beverages. You can own a piece of one of the largest industries in the world! Americans are finally seeing how eating better...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Boneheads Seafood $200,000 Capital Required 

 Healthy is in! Turn on your TV and odds are you will hear a story about healthy eating, more seafood, less fried food. That is what Boneheads is all about, over 90% of the menu is less than...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Cousins Subs $119,200 - $300,800 Capital Required 

 YOUR FUTURE LOOKS DELICIOUS! With the best product, the right pricing, low cost of entry and the support of a highly energized team - Cousins Subs represents a ground-floor opportunity to...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Between Rounds Bagels $25,000 - $35,000 Capital Required 

 Between Rounds Bakery Sandwich Cafe is your competitive edge in the explosive quick-serve restaurant franchise field. We stand apart from the competition when it comes to providing a...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Grow Vending $25,000 Capital Required 

 The Grow Modular Vendor System combines Healthy Balanced Vending with a patented field replaceable product cartridge loading system and the most technically advanced software on the market.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Steak &apos;n Shake $450,000 - $1,100,000 Capital Required 

 Famous For The Original Steakburger&amp;Hand-Dipped Milk Shakes!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Doc Popcorn 

 Make a Life, Not Just a Living!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Maui Wowi $42,500 - $250,000 Capital Required 

 The ultimate Hawaiian Experience!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Jerry&apos;s Subs&amp;Pizza $50,000 - $250,000 Capital Required 

 Jerry&apos;s is more than a sandwich shop. It is more than a pizza shop. It is America&apos;s two hottest franchise concepts rolled into one.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Scrambler Maries 

 Scrambler Marie&apos;s is a unique restaurant franchise that serves breakfast and lunch. By focusing on the breakfast and lunch niche, Scrambler Marie&apos;s achieves powerful market differentiation...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Juice It Up! $137,200 - $325,300 Capital Required 

 Juice It Up! specializes in blended-to-order real fruit smoothies, fresh-squeezed juices, açaí bowls and other healthy snacks and beverages served in a vibrant, energy-infused environment,...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Souper Salad $550,000 - $800,000 Capital Required 

 Souper Salad is a one-of-a-kind restaurant, a progressive yet comfortable destination for customers who want more than assembly line products and services.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 American Restaurant Services $40,000 Capital Required 

 The Leaders In Commercial Restaurant Cleaning Services Throughout the United States and Canada.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Rita&apos;s Italian Ice $198,400 - $385,400 Capital Required 

 Rita&apos;s Italian Ice is the nation&apos;s largest Italian Ice concept! We didn&apos;t achieve this success without help, and plenty of it!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Cafe2U $104,025 - $112,100 Capital Required 

 Cafe2U is the global market leader in Mobile Café Franchising, with over 180 successful franchisees.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Dickey&apos;s Barbecue Pit $50,000 Capital Required 

 Dickey&apos;s Barbecue Pit is the fastest growing barbecue chain in the country, with 40% growth and a store opening every 6 business days. Find out more about this new fast casual barbecue...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Hoodz $80,000 - $100,000 Capital Required 

 Hoodz cleans commercial kitchen exhaust systems. Here are 5 reasons Hoodz has awarded more than 100 franchises in about 1½ years: Federally Mandated Locally Enforced Service; Limited...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 ZooHoo&apos;s Eatery $69,000 - $140,000 Capital Required 

 Gourmet restaurant on wheels! Get into what Nation&apos;s Restaurant News recently called a &quot;white hot&quot; segment.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Cool Hand Luke’s Wild West Grill Southern CA $200,000 Capital Required 

 Join one of the hottest concepts currently expanding in the San Diego and Los Angeles Area.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Rapid Recovery $170,000 Capital Required 

 Large-Exclusive territories from coast-to-coast! Help the environment while making a great living - That&apos;s Rapid Recovery!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 The Garlic Knot $100,000 - $250,000 Capital Required 

 The Garlic Knot NY style Pizza and Pasta is finally offering franchising opportunities in the beautiful state of Colorado. Come and join the team that offers delicious, fresh pasta and the...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Panchero&apos;s Mexican Grill $305,175 - $629,000 Capital Required 

 With 18 years of successful operating experience and 55+ locations, Panchero&apos;s is ready to spread our fresh pressed tortillas across the country!  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Quiznos $70,000 Capital Required 

 Own a BIG brand without a big investment. For as little as $10,000* you can own your own Quiznos.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Extreme Pizza $202,000 - $406,000 Capital Required 

 Extreme Pizza offers you the opportunity to provide your community with tradtitional and gourmet style pizzas, at affordable price...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 The Knife Guys $100,000 - $120,000 Capital Required 

 Our business goal is to introduce our mobile knife service across the United States, establish territories in new markets, and create new opportunities for both our new and existing...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 All The Perks $85,000 - $250,000 Capital Required 

 Whether your goal is to open a café, a double drive-thru coffee shop or a cart or kiosk, All The Perks is committed to providing a complete business package.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Wok Box $178,700 - $425,200 Capital Required 

 There are plenty of lunch and dinner choices to make when you’re looking for Chinese food, Japanese dishes and other Asian food specialties. As a franchise operator, wouldn’t it be...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Clear Choice Franchising $70,000 Capital Required 

 Overwhelmed by all the franchise choices? Don’t despair…Our FREE service can help you find the RIGHT one! Download our “10 CRITICAL STEPS You Must Take Before Choosing a Franchise”.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Truitt Franchise Advisors $60,000 Capital Required 

 For people seeking to start a business, Truitt Franchise Advisors is the trusted resource for hundreds of successful business owners. Unlike franchise companies who only have one product...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Franchise Innovations For You $50,000 Capital Required 

 We will match you with the perfect Business to Business franchise based on your background and economic goals.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Mega Wrap $150,000 - $200,000 Capital Required 

 We cater to the &quot;New Millennium&quot; consumers&apos; desire for healthy, nutritious food fast, unlike the typical &quot;fast food&quot; that they have experienced in the past. Each and every Wraps is prepared...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Let&apos;s Make Wine $226,000 - $405,000 Capital Required 

 Let&apos;s Make Wine franchises are upscale, state-of-the-art retail stores where franchisees offer customers the opportunity to make and private label their own great-tasting wine! The fusion...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 WingStop Restaurant $181,500 - $250,000 Capital Required 

 Our unique concept and menu, combined with our experience and support will provide you with an extraordinary opportunity to become part of this business franchise system.  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 All American Ice Cream $90,050 - $224,300 Capital Required 

 As one of three unique, quick service restaurant concepts introduced by All American Specialty Restaurants Inc., our proprietary premium high butterfat ice cream and non-fat frozen yogurt...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Rotelli Pizza&amp;Pasta $300,000 Capital Required 

 Modern. Classic. Delicious. Perfect. Just a few words that have been used to describe our brand - Rotelli Pizza&amp;Pasta. And it all begins and ends here - with people. That&apos;s the difference...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Vito&amp;Nick&apos;s II Pizza $178,600 - $231,600 Capital Required 

 In 1932, Vito Barraco, my grandfather, opened his first business on the south side of Chicago located at 80th and Halsted, naming it Vito&apos;s Tavern. Working hard at a thriving business for...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Little King Deli and Subs $125,000 Capital Required 

 Little King has more than 27 years experience and now operates in several states. With a unique sandwich and deli operation, Little King has developed a complete systems approach to quality...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Johnny Brusco&apos;s Pizza $100,000 - $275,000 Capital Required 

 When you purchase a Johnny Brusco&apos;s, you can be guaranteed hands on guidance from our highly trained staff. Beginning the day you sign your contract, until the day your doors open, and well...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 All American Deli $90,050 - $224,300 Capital Required 

 As the operator of a unique, quick service restaurant concept, our stores operate with a simple premise; offer high quality food in an inviting environment at a competitive price, served by...  
 Request Information Add to Request List 
 Rollerz Fast Food $162,000 - $386,000 Capital Required 

 Designed to meet the growing demand of on-the-go consumers who care about what they eat, Rollerz is a fresh twist on fast food! The Rollerz menu offers specialty meats such as fajita...  
 Request Information Add to Request List Showing 1 - 50 of 64 Franchises Found Page: 1 2 

 Food And Restaurant:   Coffee ,   Deli&amp;Sandwich ,   Fast Casual ,   Fast Food ,   Ice Cream ,   Make&amp;Take ,   Pizza ,   Restaurant ,   Smoothies ,   Wine, Drink 
 
 Listed above are all the new Food And Restaurant opportunities currently available on BizBuySell. Did you know that one of the best ways to begin franchise ownership can be to buy an existing franchise? Existing franchises have a ready-made customer base and staff, they have established recognition and presence in the community, and they often offer additional support and training from the current owner. Many pre-existing and established Food And Restaurant Franchises that are available for sale can be found under our business for sale search section. To see those, go to buy an existing franchise and do a keyword search for &quot;franchise&quot;. 
Franchise Request List

 Max 25 Franchises 
 
Select up to 10 franchises that you want to learn more about!
 
 Your request list is currently empty. 

The Franchise Request List allows you to request information from several franchises with a click of a button!
 
 0 Selected Franchise(s)
 
 All Fields Required 
 First Name Last Name Email Phone City Zip 
Min. Liquid Capital: 
 Available Capital Less than $10,000 $20,000 $30,000 $40,000 $50,000 $60,000 $70,000 $80,000 $90,000 $100,000 $150,000 $200,000 $250,000 $300,000 $350,000 $400,000 $450,000 $500,000 $500,000+ Timeframe to Invest 1-3 months 3-6 months 6+ months Desired Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Sign me up for the BizBuySell® Franchise Newsletter Learn how to use your IRA/401K to purchase a franchise - Guidant Financial (Min. $50k needed in IRA/401K) Get More Info Submit My Request Is my information safe? Absolutely.
View our privacy policy .   
 Yes! Send me information for:



All fields are required.
 First Name Last Name Email Phone Available Capital Less than $10,000 $20,000 $30,000 $40,000 $50,000 $60,000 $70,000 $80,000 $90,000 $100,000 $150,000 $200,000 $250,000 $300,000 $350,000 $400,000 $450,000 $500,000 $500,000+ Timeframe to Invest 1-3 months 3-6 months 6+ months Desired Business Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming City Zip Code Sign me up for the BizBuySell® Franchise Newsletter 
 Send My Request Cancel Request 
 Your information is safe. View our privacy policy. 
 
Processing...
 
Your request failed.
 Try Again Cancel Request 
 
 
 
 
 advertise terms&amp;conditions privacy policy about us contact us careers site map mobile 
 
 
 
©1996 - 2012 BizBuySell.com®   |
	</body>
</document>
