<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008585" url="http://www.wlbt.com/Global/story.asp?S=13866198" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="1" score="0.0003967375475940543" bingtitle="Nurse practitioners want more power to treat patients - WLBT.com ..." webtitle="Nurse practitioners want more power to treat patients - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS">
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Jackson fast food restaurant armed robbery ... have a written agreement with a physician in order ... State Board of Medical Licensure oppose the bill.</description>
	<body>
		WLBT.com - Jackson, MSNurse practitioners want more power to treat patients
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 St. Jude Dream Home Video Landing Page Decision 2012 Jackson Gas Prices Editorials America Now Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts Contact Us 
 
 Decision 2012 Editorials MDOT Traffic Cams Wednesday&apos;s Child Look Around Mississippi Most Wanted Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Olympic Zone Sign up for Alerts 
 
 MedNOW Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 SkyCopter 3 Community Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Sign up for Alerts Contact Us Closed Captioning This TV Network 
 
 WLBT Community St. Jude Dream Home SkyCopter 3 Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Contact Us Fresh from the Flame 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Nurse practitioners want more power to treat patients
 Posted: Tuesday, January 18, 2011 10:43 PM EST Updated: Tuesday, January 18, 2011 11:44 PM EST By Roslyn Anderson - bio | email 
 
 Most Popular Stories Most Read More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 

 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:34 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:34:44 GMT A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl that he met on Facebook. More &gt;&gt; A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl whom he met on Facebook, according to police. More &gt;&gt; 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:53 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:53:55 GMT The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; 
 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 

 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 11:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 03:44:46 GMT A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. Virgie Peterson was More &gt;&gt; A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now, her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Sponsored Information More&gt;&gt; 
 
 sponsored information: 

 Personal Injury Attorney 

 Personal Injury Attorney 
 
 
Roslyn Anderson - bio | email 

JACKSON, MS (WLBT)–A medical turf war is brewing at the State Capitol.

With a shortage of physicians in the state nurse practitioners want more power, but doctors believe things could get dangerous without their oversight.

Doctors and nurse practitioners in white lab coats packed a hearing by the Public Health and Welfare Committee on House Bill 605.

It would eliminate the need for nurse practitioners to have a written agreement with a physician in order to practice within their scope.

According to the Mississippi Nurses Association there are 2,000 nurse practitioners who fill the void particularly in rural areas like Issaquena and Sharkey counties which have no physicians.

&quot;All this does is remove the signature of the one collaborating physician. They would continue to collaborate with physicians all over the state, but they wouldn&apos;t have to have the signature of one particular,&quot; said Mississippi Nursing Association Executive Director Dr. Ricki Garrett.

The Mississippi Medical Association and the State Board of Medical Licensure oppose the bill.

More than 5,000 doctors practice in the state according to medical officials.

The groups said that number will increase through the Mississippi Rural Scholarship Program.

Thirty medical students and residents have received scholarships that would require them to work in rural counties.

Physicians think the legislation would allow nurse practitioners to have independent practices.

&quot;To abandon that approach and put the nurse practitioner in the driver&apos;s seat where they have total responsibility and total control in effect practicing medicine, I think that puts us a little bit on a slippery slope,&quot; said MS State Medical Association President Dr. Tim Alford.

Lawmakers urged both sides to come up with compromises that would benefit the patients.

&quot;We can&apos;t get doctors to Tutweiler and to Tremont. They will not live there and practice. That&apos;s not where the money is quite frankly. So that&apos;s all this is about. We&apos;re gonna talk about it. I&apos;m not sure we&apos;re ready for an independent practice. I don&apos;t think so,&quot; said Public Health and Welfare Committee Chairman Rep. Steve Holland.

The committee could possibly vote on the bill Wednesday.

 Copyright 2011 WLBT. All rights reserved. 
 
 
Explore WLBT.com
 Home Local News Decision 2011 Gas Prices America Now Point of View Sound Off News Most Read Local News Skycopter 3 Most Wanted Look Around Mississippi 3 On Your Side Wednesday’s Child Taking Back our Neighborhoods Red Blue Review Medical Matters Weather Local Weather Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Interactive Radar 4-Day Pollen Forecast Sports Sports National Sports Mississippi Sports Friday Nite Lites Video Latest Videos Most Watched Video Center Contact Us Contact Us Sign Up for Email Alerts Our Team Birthday Club All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WLBT, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
