<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008354" url="http://topics.vlex.com/tags/fast-food-restaurant-2714558" time="2012-07-13-01:50" support="9" score="0.01726942914666558" bingtitle="Fast-Food-Restaurant - vLex" webtitle="Fast-Food-Restaurant - vLex">
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>Fast-Food-Restaurant. News and Business, Case Law, U.S. Code ... It was taken at the drive-through order sign at M ... to identify the man, who allegedly tricks cashiers at ...</description>
	<body>
		Fast-Food-Restaurant
 2 similar searches for Fast-Food-Restaurant 
 fast food restaurants Fast-Food-Restaurants 
 
 Receive alerts: by e-mail E-mail Your information will be added to a database with the sole purpose of serving your subscription. This database is the exclusive property of vLex Networks S.L. and will never be shared with any other company. By sending your request you accept the Data Protection Policy of vLex Networks S.L. I have read and accept the Terms of Use via RSS 
 1 headnote for Fast-Food-Restaurant 
 
 Fast food restaurants 
 
 4.551 documents for Fast-Food-Restaurant 
 
 ; Dispute Ended in Brawl at Glen Burnie Fast-Food Restaurant 

A homeless man was sentenced to four years in prison for fatally stabbing a fellow&quot;tent city&quot;resident during a fight outside a fast- food restaurant last winter.
 Roland Michael Long, 39, pleaded guilty Thursday to manslaughter in the Dec. 18 killing of 43-year-old Jimmy Liberto in the parking lot of the McDonald&apos;s in the Cromwell Station Shopping Center in Glen Burnie.

 Maryland Gazette August 01, 2011 
 
 Scenes From a Fast-Food Restaurant 

Brooklyn rap duo Das Racist really need no introduction, not because you already know everything about them, but because, at the moment, mere&apos;s only one really important thing to know They are responsible for the song Combination Pizza Hut and Taco BeH, which deftiy locates the fine Une between stupid and clever, and snorts it It consists, essentially, of two guys repeating the line Tm at the Pizza Hut/Pm at the Taco Bell/Tm at the combination Pizza Hut and Taco Bell until it passes from grating to absurd to hilarious to poignant to transcendent It is either very, very meaningful or completely meaningless. Name, ages, countries of origin, current residences, astrological signs . . . arrything else you&apos;d care to share in that vein would be lovely. Luckily,&quot;hipster&quot;begins with&quot;H,&quot;an...

 Village Voice, The October 08, 2009 
 
 Woman Dies After Crashing Into Fast-Food Restaurant 

VIRGINIA BEACH
 A woman died Monday after driving her car into a fast-food restaurant.

 The Virginian-Pilot and The Ledger-Star, Norfolk, VA April 13, 2011 
 
 Armed Man Robs Montebello Fast-Food Restaurant 

MONTEBELLO - A gunman corralled employees in an office as he robbed a fast-food restaurant Wednesday, police said.
 The crime was reported shortly before 3 a.m. at Jack-in-the-Box, 892 N. Garfield Ave., Montebello police Lt. Rich Meadows said.

 San Gabriel Valley Tribune September 22, 2011 
 
 Memories of Fast-Food Restaurant Slow to Surface 

Some Redlanders of a certain age may have recognized last week&apos;s photo, but none of them called or emailed to say so.
 The photo is from an advertisement in the 1972 Redlands High School yearbook, the Makio. It was taken at the drive-through order sign at M.J.&apos;s on Q, a fast-food mostly Mexican restaurant that was at 535 Orange St.

 Redlands Daily Facts May 05, 2011 
 
 Church Takes Ownership of Fast-Food Restaurant 

The church does vast work in the community and with those who have troubled pasts: We clothe, feed and house many that are unable to do it for themselves. We have a drug treatment program, a food program and a housing program. Mr. [Walter Brooks Sr.] has been with us every step of the way. When he came to me with his offer, I had to take him up on it,&quot;Rev. Thomas Barclay, pastor of Progressive said.&quot;I&apos;ve been in and out of prison, treatment facilities, churches and jobs. I used to live in a shelter and the church would pick us up and bring us to church every Sunday for a meal. After I saw how much they try to help exfelons integrate back into society, I knew that&apos;s what I wanted,&quot;the 51-year-old assistant manager said.&quot;It&apos;s very exciting. I have a background in cooking and complete...

 Chicago Defender August 27, 2009 
 
 Verdicts&amp;Settlements July 18, 2011: Coffee Case 

A federal jury has sided with a fast-food restaurant in a dispute over spilled hot coffee.
 Timothy Person Sr. filed a lawsuit after he was injured in 2008 at a White Castle restaurant drive-through window in St. Louis.

 Missouri Lawyers Media July 25, 2011 
 
 Fast-Food Restaurant Scammer Eludes Police 

PICO RIVERA - Police say it is unlikely that they will catch a scam artist targeting the mayor&apos;s fast-food restaurant in Pico Rivera.
 Sgt. Albert Leyva said sheriff&apos;s officials have been unable to identify the man, who allegedly tricks cashiers at drive-throughs and front counters into handing him money.

 San Gabriel Valley Tribune January 16, 2008 
 
 Positivity Helps Woman Lose 190 Pounds ; Fast Food Restaurant Worker Says Dedication to Meeting Goal Helped Develop Healthy Habits 

MILTON - Susan Cain faced numerous challenges to lose more than 190 pounds.
 Working in the fast-food industry meant she had to skip the high- calorie, readily available menu items.

 Charleston Daily Mail June 29, 2012 
 
 Robber Holds Up Redlands Fast Food Restaurant 

REDLANDS -- A man walked into a Jack in the Box drive-through window Wednesday night, said he had a gun and made off with money from a cash register.
 The man walked into the restaurant at 2062 W. Redlands Blvd. about 10 p.m., said city spokesman Carl Baker. He walked into the drive-through window area behind the counter and demanded money from the register.

 The Sun (San Bernardino, CA) June 10, 2011 
 

 

 Next Page 
 
 All Constitutions Regulations U.S. Code Case Law Legal Books and Journals Contracts News and Business 
 
 All Jurisdictions United States International Law 

 
 
ver las páginas en versión mobile | web 

ver las páginas en versión mobile | web 
 
© Copyright 2012, vLex. All Rights Reserved.

 Language 中国版 Català Deutsch English Español Euskera Français Galego Italiano Nederlands Português (Brasil) Português (Portugal) Русский 
 
 Contents in vLex United States 

 Contracts News and Business Case Law U.S. Code Legal Books and Journals Regulations Constitutions Tags Sources 
 
 Explore vLex 

 Countries in vLex Publishers in vLex Testimonials 
 
 For Professionals 

 Free trial Professional Subscription Corporate Subscriptions Librarian Center Search API 
 
 For Partners 

 For Publishers For Authors 
 
 Company 

 About us Press Room Work with us Terms of Use 
 
Other interesting searches:

 Ben Affleck | coronary circulation | Tarpon Springs Hospital Foundation Inc | Angelica Textile Services, Inc. | Residuum | Tribunaux maritimes commerciaux | Catégorie socioprofessionnelle | Puerto pesquero | informes periciales construccion | machette 
 
 Login Help 
 
 All of vLex United States ▼ 
 All of vLex United States Constitutions Regulations U.S. Code Case Law Legal Books and Journals Contracts News and Business More countries 
   Search Advanced Search New search 
 vlex /
	</body>
</document>
