<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008998" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20110605182453AAlbABN" time="2012-07-13-02:24" support="2" score="0.0019639745096661303" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - What is the number 1 fast food restaurant ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - What is the number 1 fast food restaurant chain in the world?">
			<query id="000230" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="11"/>
	<description>Food &amp; Drink; Games &amp; Recreation; Health; Home &amp; Garden; Local Businesses ... What is the number 1 fast food restaurant chain in the world? 10 months ago</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Gem Member since: July 13, 2010 Total points: 846 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What is the number 1 fast food restaurant chain in the world?

 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by ? Member since: June 06, 2011 Total points: 326 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 By sales Mcdonalds. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Money talks 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What is the number 1… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Captain ChiliDog Member since: May 08, 2007 Total points: 21,798 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Subway just recently took the number one spot, as far as number of locations. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by Lexi Leece Member since: June 04, 2011 Total points: 276 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 McDonalds 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Will McDonald&apos;s call me back for hire? Any1 who works at mcdonalds answer please? Is the taco bell cantina bowl any good? I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 Chain Many additional accessory products. All items delivered free. www.kaiserkraft.co.uk/accessories Calgary Deals 50-70% Off Daily Deals. Join Free! Restaurants , Shopping,... www.LivingSocial.com See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
