<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008646" url="http://www.jacksoncasino.com/careers/openings.aspx" time="2012-07-13-02:06" support="17" score="0.020470672582389937" bingtitle="Jackson Rancheria Casino &amp; Hotel | Openings" webtitle="Jackson Rancheria CasinoHotel | Openings">
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001074" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000634" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001076" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001042" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001075" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000648" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Ability to climb ladders in order to clean vents ... Pick up, sort or compact using the baler recyclable ... five years of relevant cooking experience in a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Casino Promotions Lodging Dining Entertainment Shopping Tribal careers Links 
 
 

 Posting Date: 6/21/2012 Position: Restaurant Supervisor (Margaret&apos;s Cafe and Bakery) Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $16.00 to $24.00 Requirements: Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 
 Directly supervises and assigns work to food service employees Customarily and regularly directs the work of 2 or more employees performing the following functions: Customarily assigns work stations Responsible for training new employees Coordinates break schedules and insures team members are in proper work stations Determines work procedures under the direction of management Works with management to ensure coverage of all work stations. Creates and updates schedules for subordinates under the supervision of management Completes paperwork as needed for food transfers, waste, attendance, medical reports, and break sheets Monitors the storage and stocking of all products necessary to the operations. Requisitions product using CBORD and assists in the monthly inventory Addresses guests concerns with food preparation, food temperature, food presentation, and/or service Demonstrates the flexibility and adaptability necessary to work in an environment that may require working in various locations and with various menus Performs a wide range of related duties as needed or requested by management Preparation of menu items as directed Portion controls Proper plate presentation Meat cutting Food storage, labeling, and rotation Cooking temperatures Must have knowledge of and follow proper food handling and health and safety regulations Banquet preparations Must be proficient in the Micros Point of Sale System Other duties may be assigned. 

 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 Any combination of education that could likely prove the required knowledge and skills required for this position; minimum two years previous restaurant or catering experience or apprenticeship. A minimum of one-year experience as a line cook, broiler, or sautécook. Must attend Business Skills and LDI Classes when schedule permits 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/21/2012 Position: Restaurant Manager (Margaret&apos;s Cafe and Bakery) Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $40,000 to $60,000 Requirements: SUMMARY  
Responsible for the operation of the designated restaurant and personnel in accordance with the Food&amp;Beverage Department policies.

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Must demonstrate the ability to direct a team of managers and supervisors within the assigned restaurant.  Guest Service, Cleaning, Stocking and Maintenance of work stations. Performs a wide range of related duties as needed or requested by Food&amp;Beverage Director. Selects, hires, trains, and oversees front-of-the-house personnel. Manages shifts, labor costs, guest services, and sanitation. Builds average sales and guest counts. Builds and maintains relationships with guests. Inventories, orders and maintains sufficient levels of small wares and equipment. Provides team members with performance feedback and recognition. Maintains consistent staffing levels and staff efficiency. Must have knowledge of front and back of the house restaurant operations; restaurant staffing; menu planning and costs analysis; and operation of proper food service, buffet and plate presentation. Performs research and analysis of sales, trends and expenses for the preparation of budgets. Assists in presenting operational improvement proposals to executive management. Knowledge and maintenance of proper food handling, storage and rotation procedures, and all related health and safety standards. Works with the Marketing Department to ensure proper advertising of menus, promotions, events and web site content. Interviews, selects, trains, and evaluates departmental supervisors and managers. Analyzes guest attendance and comment information and responds accordingly in order to maintain the standards of operation. Prepares schedules for assigned restaurant staff. Ensures necessary products and supplies are adequately stocked and properly stored. Maintain order, production and leadership in an environment with constantly changing conditions Keeps communications open with vendors to assure the maintenance of equipment and quality of product. Participates in end of the month inventory taking and record keeping. Performs the following duties. Other duties may be assigned. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

To perform this job successfully, an individual must be able to perform each essential duty satisfactorily. The requirements listed below are representative of the knowledge, skill, and/or ability required. Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with disabilities to perform the essential functions. Minimum of four years related experience and/or equivalent combination of education and experience. Serve Safe certification required.

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/21/2012 Position: Restaurant Supervisor (Margaret&apos;s Cafe and Bakery) Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $33,280 to $49.920 Requirements: Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 
 Directly supervises and assigns work to food service employees Customarily and regularly directs the work of 2 or more employees performing the following functions: Customarily assigns work stations Responsible for training new employees Coordinates break schedules and insures team members are in proper work stations Determines work procedures under the direction of management Works with management to ensure coverage of all work stations. Creates and updates schedules for subordinates under the supervision of management Completes paperwork as needed for food transfers, waste, attendance, medical reports, and break sheets Monitors the storage and stocking of all products necessary to the operations. Requisitions product using CBORD and assists in the monthly inventory Addresses guests concerns with food preparation, food temperature, food presentation, and/or service Demonstrates the flexibility and adaptability necessary to work in an environment that may require working in various locations and with various menus Performs a wide range of related duties as needed or requested by management Preparation of menu items as directed Portion controls Proper plate presentation Meat cutting Food storage, labeling, and rotation Cooking temperatures Must have knowledge of and follow proper food handling and health and safety regulations Banquet preparations Must be proficient in the Micros Point of Sale System Other duties may be assigned. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 Any combination of education that could likely prove the required knowledge and skills required for this position; minimum two years previous restaurant or catering experience or apprenticeship. A minimum of one-year experience as a line cook, broiler, or sautécook. Must attend Business Skills and LDI Classes when schedule permits 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/15/2012 Position: Rancheria Security Officer Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $12.50 to $18.75 Requirements:  
 SUMMARY  

Under general direction, perform security and crime prevention work and do related work as required. Responsible for maintaining and securing Rancheria Reservation fixed post entry gates, off site properties, and access to Reservation remote areas.

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Perform security patrols; enforce Casino / Rancheria badge procedures, protect JRCH / Rancheria property from unlawful trespassers, theft, sabotage, fire and accidents.  Provide needed assistance to customers, employees and visitors.  Enforcement of Rancheria rules and regulations by both customers and employees. Train new employees May be required to secure transportation of money between departments or outside of secured areas to Main Bank in Casino. May be required to assist in various types of money drops (from outside Casino departments, such as R.V. Park, General Store, etc.) Able to respond to emergencies, problems and disputes when needed. Required to review all company/department policies and procedures and required to know / learn standard and custom radio codes. Required to know the location of all departments and emergency exits and posts in the event of an emergency. Operate telephones. May be required to dispatch personnel when working posts. May establish and maintain record and identification systems; Generates incident and information reports. Keeps equipment in good working condition. Other duties may be assigned. 

 QUALIFICATIONS  

To perform this job successfully, an individual must be able to perform each essential duty satisfactorily. The requirements listed below are representative of the knowledge, skill, and/or ability required. Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with disabilities to perform the essential functions.

 Must successfully pass medical screening to include physical exam, audiogram, EKG and drug screen. Knowledge of: 
 The general geography and topography of Amador County and Tribal Land. First aid techniques. Simple firefighter techniques and available equipment 
 Perform a wide variety of professional security work. Perform specialized security assignments. May work a post that can permit / deny access to sensitive areas. Carefully observe incidents and situations, accurately remembering names, faces, numbers, circumstances, and places. Make independent judgments and adopt quick, effective, and responsible             courses of action during emergencies. Write clear and comprehensive reports. Meet standards of adequate physical stature, endurance and agility. Effectively represent the Rancheria Security Department in contacts with the public and other law enforcement agencies. Establish and maintain cooperative relationship with those contacted during the course of work. May be required to drive department patrol vehicles. (*requires satisfactory driving record and able to provide DMV printout to keep on file) May be required to provide radio communication support to emergency personnel. 

 EDUCATION and/or EXPERIENCE  

 A High School Diploma, GED, or six months to one year related experience and/or training; or equivalent combination of education and experience. 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/12/2012 Position: Sous Chef Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $33,280 to $49,920 Requirements: SUMMARY 
Responsible for achieving mastery of skills for all culinary stations within the assigned venue and monitoring preparation of all foods during an assigned shift, ensuring the efficiency of the line and kitchen operation on a scheduled shift.

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

1. Responsible for delegation of the kitchen line and technical food production and actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food, implementing policies and procedures and food specifications

2. Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food in kitchen preparation in accordance with established recipes.

3. Assists, in the absence of the Sous Chef, in checking for quality and consistency.

4. Inspects all refrigeration and dry storage for proper handling and rotation.

5. Ensures that stations are clean and that all food items are properly covered, labeled and stored at the end of shift.

6. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures.

7. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations.

8. Maintains professional grooming and appearance and acts as a role model according to established grooming and appearance policy.

9. Adheres to the specification and standards set forth by Executive Chef

10. Masters the EATEC ordering system

11. Supervises day to day operations of kitchens

12. Maintains and writes production, transfer reports, temperature and waste charts

13. Completes daily food ordering and inventory control processes utilizing computerized systems and Inventory Control

14. Responsible for technical food production, sauce and soup making

15. Communicate daily&quot;special&quot;menu items to all line cooks to facilitate product utilization

16. Complete all monthly inventories

17. Verbally communicates orders to fellow co workers to insure that all food is presented in a timely manner.

18. Provides feedback to Exec Chefs on quality of incoming goods

19. Reports product shortages, equipment issues and safety concerns to Exec Chefs

20. Supervises front line kitchen staff in the performance of their daily duties

21. Trains Kitchen Staff and Leads in proper procedures for use of cleaning machines, ware washers, chemicals and cleaning tools

22. Trains Kitchen Staff and Leads in the proper procedures for breakdown, cleaning and assembly of kitchen equipment.

23. Trains Kitchen Workers and Leads in proper procedures for cleaning surfaces

24. May assist with weekly schedules and assigning employees to different areas of operation as necessary

25. Regularly uses computer systems including, not limited to network-based point of sale systems, inventory control, time&amp;attendance and Microsoft Office software (email, Excel, Word, internet)

26. Participates in employee coaching and counseling sessions

27. Consistently demonstrates knowledge including roasting, sauté, broiling, deep frying, shallow frying, steaming, boiling, braising, large batch cookery, sauce production, soup production

28. Maintain positive guest relations at all times, resolving guest complaints and ensuring guest satisfaction.

29. Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braisers, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation.

30. Provide clear direction, instruction and guidance to lower-level cooks. .

31. Organize and delegate work assignments and tasks to meet deadlines.

32. Train lower-level cooks in proper equipment usage.

33. Communicate regularly with kitchen staff to ensure efficient and effective operations. .

34. Exhibit knowledge, understanding, and application of various cooking techniques.

35. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity.

36. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups.

37. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations.

38. Maintain a solid knowledge of all food products.

39. Prepare order lists for recipe preparations.

40. Perform all assigned sidework to include replenishing/restocking work station with supplies.

41. Adhere to control procedure for food costs and quality.

42. Check station before, during, and after shift for proper set-up and cleanliness.

43. Abide by all health codes and hand washing guidelines and encourage team members to do the same.

44. Assists guests with special requests.

45. Encourages mutual respect, dignity and integrity with all employees, by setting positive examples at all times.

46. Instills an atmosphere that encourages employees to share ideas, discuss concerns, and resolve conflicts.

47. Retains employees through involvement in training and development.

48. Explains why we do things, in advance of doing them.

49. Responsible for conducting all responsibilities in a professional and ethical manner

 QUALIFICATIONS  

1. A minimum of five years of relevant cooking experience in a production kitchen within a casual/fine dining environment.

2. A minimum of two years of experience in a leadership position within a kitchen work environment.

3. Vocational or culinary school graduate preferred.

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/12/2012 Position: Cashier/Host Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $8.00 to $12.00 Requirements:  
 SUMMARY 

Responsible for providing pleasant, prompt and efficient guest service and payment transactions

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Be knowledgeable of standard alcoholic and non-alcoholic drinks and wines specific to restaurant bar. . Greets guests upon arrival and provides them with a prompt and courteous escort to a dining table. Advises guests of waiting time and maintains a waiting list. Responsible for assisting and facilitating the restaurant seating and paging system Presents menus and specials to guests. Must have knowledge of the menu in its entirety and how the food is prepared in order to service guests and recommend food and beverage items to the guests Maintains seating chart with servers&apos;station assignments and ensures that guests are seated in the appropriate areas. Maintains a seating rotation to ensure the best possible guest service. Handles small to large sums of money, coupons, comps, credit cards and other forms of payment Count currency and give proper change during cash transactions. Accurately enters food and beverage orders into point of sale system. Respectfully request and receives payments from guests when required.  Adheres to established cash handling policies and procedures including the Variance policy. Knows and can communicate information about venues, menus and pricing. Ability to answer questions pertaining to the ingredients in food items being sold Responsible for learning suggestive selling techniques and using them during services.  Communicates with guest in a respectful, friendly and diplomatic fashion to answer guest inquiries and concerns. Resolves guest concerns and/or refers them to the appropriate personnel when necessary. Maintains a professional attitude and appearance at all times. Maintains the cashier and host stands by stocking supplies, cleaning menus, and cleaning as needed. Ability to recognize and stock proper items as needed. Ability to work effectively in an environment with constantly changing conditions. Must have knowledge of and follow proper food handling and health and safety regulations Answers telephones and guest questions in a professional manner. Takes and expedites food and beverage orders. Creates a fun atmosphere for casino guests and employees. Performs other tasks as assigned by management 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of six months to 3 years of consistent and relevant cash handling and customer service responsibilities in a retail, or bistro/casual/fine dining environment. Must be able to accurately handle cash, count change and process all other tender methods 

 *Graveyard shift receives $1.00/hr differential                            

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/12/2012 Position: Bus Person Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $8.00 to $12.00 Requirements:  
 SUMMARY  

Responsible for keeping all server side stations stocked and cleaned, assisting servers in providing beverage service to guests and meeting guests&apos;service needs in a prompt, friendly, and professional manner.

 

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Set up and stock designated areas with glasses, cups, napkins, silverware and condiments. Keeps all areas and or counters wiped down, clean and stocked with plates, silverware, etc. Clears all bus carts from side stations and or trash areas and replaces with clean bus carts and bus tubs. Maintains cleanliness of all side stations by ensuring the station is free of clutter and debris. Assist server in refilling drinks and bussing tables as needed. Empties garbage cans Keep ice stocked in ice bins and soda machines. Assists servers/cooks in keeping floors clean of all debris. Anticipates guests needs and responds to any questions or requests for service. Abides by all health and safety regulations. Creates a fun atmosphere for casino and restaurant guests and employees 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 Prior restaurant/bus person experience preferred. Must present a well-groomed appearance. Must be able to work in a team environment to complete tasks. 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 *Graveyard shift receives $1.00/hr differential                            

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/12/2012 Position: Restaurant Chef Shift: FT - ALL Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $40,000 to $60,000 Requirements: 
 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Responsible for delegation of the kitchen line and technical food production and actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food, implementing policies and procedures and food specifications Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food in kitchen preparation in accordance with established recipes. Ensures that stations are clean and that all food items are properly covered, labeled and stored at the end of shift. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations. Adheres to the specification and standards set forth by Executive Chef Masters the EATEC ordering system Supervises day to day operations of kitchens Maintains and writes production, transfer reports, temperature and waste charts Completes daily food ordering and inventory control processes utilizing computerized systems and Inventory Control Responsible for technical food production, sauce and soup making Communicate daily&quot;special&quot;menu items to all line cooks to facilitate product utilization Complete all monthly inventories Verbally communicates orders to fellow co workers to insure that all food is presented in a timely manner. Provides feedback to Exec Chef on quality of incoming goods Reports product shortages, equipment issues and safety concerns to Exec Chef Supervises front line kitchen staff in the performance of their daily duties Trains Kitchen Staff and Leads in proper procedures for use of cleaning machines, ware washers, chemicals and cleaning tools Trains Kitchen Workers and Leads in proper procedures for cleaning surfaces Regularly uses computer systems including, not limited to network-based point of sale systems, inventory control, time&amp;attendance and Microsoft Office software (email, Excel, Word, internet) Consistently demonstrates knowledge including roasting, sauté, broiling, deep frying, shallow frying, steaming, boiling, braising, large batch cookery, sauce production, soup production Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braises, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation. Provide clear direction, instruction and guidance to lower-level cooks. . Organize and delegate work assignments and tasks to meet deadlines. Train lower-level cooks in proper equipment usage. Communicate regularly with kitchen staff to ensure efficient and effective operations. . Exhibit knowledge, understanding, and application of various cooking techniques. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations. Maintain a solid knowledge of all food products. Prepare order lists for recipe preparations. Perform all assigned side work to include replenishing/restocking work station with supplies. Adhere to control procedure for food costs and quality. Check station before, during, and after shift for proper set-up and cleanliness. Abide by all health codes and hand washing guidelines and encourage team members to do the same. Assists guests with special requests. Encourages mutual respect, dignity and integrity with all employees, by setting positive examples at all times. Instills an atmosphere that encourages employees to share ideas, discuss concerns, and resolve conflicts. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of eight to ten years of relevant cooking experience in a production kitchen within a casual/fine dining environment. A minimum of five years of experience in a leadership position within a kitchen work environment. Vocational or culinary school graduate preferred. 

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/12/2012 Position: Food Server Shift: PT - ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $8.00 to $12.00 Requirements: Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 
 Delivers prompt efficient and courteous service of food and beverages to restaurant guests in accordance with venue standards. Performs necessary tasks to service guests. Takes and fills all food and drink orders and assists in maintaining guests dining area in a clean and neat manner. Performs tray and/or cart service. Must have knowledge of the menu in its entirety and how the food is prepared in order to service guests and recommend food and beverage items to the guests. Accurately enters food and beverage orders into point of sale system. Performs pre-busing of tables on a continual basis, keeping tables free of dirty dishes and excess clutter. Abides by all health and safety regulations. Monitors guests&apos;needs, ensuring all requests for food and service will be promptly fulfilled in accordance with policies and procedures. Completes maintenance work consisting of cleaning, stocking, and preparation of work areas. Assists other restaurant personnel with maintenance (side work, opening/closing duties) as necessary. Adheres to established cash handling policies and procedures. Creates a fun atmosphere for casino and restaurant guests and employees. Other duties may be assigned. 

 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 High school diploma or equivalent (GED) and six months to one year food service experience; or equivalent combination of education and experience. Must have knowledge of proper service etiquette. Knowledge of the menu in its entirety and how it is prepared. Must be proficient in tray service 

 *Graveyard shift receives $1.00/hr differential                            

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 6/11/2012 Position: Restaurant Manager (Buffet) Shift: ALL Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $40,000 to $60,000 Requirements: 
Now open, the all new Rancheria Buffet provides a new and exciting dining experience. Open 7 days a week, this 300 seat buffet will provide guests the opportunity to experience live action cooking stations.

The buffet will showcase six new action cooking stations, open for guests to see. A Fresh Salad Station will include numerous choices, from compound salads, to fresh fruit, and everything in between. An Asian Wok Station will feature many Asian favorites. . . and the wok&apos;s will be moving all the time.

A Live fire Charrascaria Grill, an active vertical rotisserie, will be full of roasting meats on long skewers. Guests will have the opportunity to enjoy Mexican favorites along side the Charrascaria meats in the Mexican Station.

An Italian station will feature a Brick Oven to cook pizzas, Plancha style seafood, and even pastas. An American Station will feature a carvery to showcase everything from prime rib to roasted turkeys, and traditional favorites such as fried chicken and mashed potatoes. And of course, a Dessert Station, with many opportunities for our guests to interact with their final course.

Currently we are seeking a talented Buffet Manager to manage the day to day operations of the Rancheria Buffet. Duties and responsibilities include but are not limited to:

 Must demonstrate the ability to direct a team of managers and supervisors within the assigned restaurant.  Guest Service, Cleaning, Stocking and Maintenance of work stations. Performs a wide range of related duties as needed or requested by Food&amp;Beverage Director. Selects, hires, trains, and oversees front-of-the-house personnel. Manages shifts, labor costs, guest services, and sanitation. Builds average sales and guest counts. Builds and maintains relationships with guests. Inventories, orders and maintains sufficient levels of small wares and equipment. Provides team members with performance feedback and recognition. Maintains consistent staffing levels and staff efficiency. Must have knowledge of front and back of the house restaurant operations; restaurant staffing; menu planning and costs analysis; and operation of proper food service, buffet and plate presentation. Performs research and analysis of sales, trends and expenses for the preparation of budgets. Assists in presenting operational improvement proposals to executive management.â€¢Knowledge and maintenance of proper food handling, storage and rotation procedures, and all related health and safety standards. Works with the Marketing Department to ensure proper advertising of menus, promotions, events and web site content. Interviews, selects, trains, and evaluates departmental supervisors and managers. Analyzes guest attendance and comment information and responds accordingly in order to maintain the standards of operation. Prepares schedules for assigned restaurant staff of approximately 10-70 employees. Ensures necessary products and supplies are adequately stocked and properly stored. Maintain order, production and leadership in an environment with constantly changing conditions Keeps communications open with vendors to assure the maintenance of equipment and quality of product. Participates in end of the month inventory taking and record keeping. Other duties may be assigned. 

Minimum Qualifications

 Minimum of 5 to 8 years of relevant work experience managing the day to day operations of a high volume restaurant. Management experience working in a high volume buffet preferred. 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 5/16/2012 Position: Cook/Cashier I (Pacific Grill) Shift: ALL Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $9.50 to $14.25 Requirements: 
Currently under construction and opening soon, the Pacific Grill isn&apos;t a restaurant per se - it&apos;s a destination of two restaurants. The California Grill and Asian Grill are featured within a shared 164 seat dining room at the Pacific Grill and provide the culmination of Pacific cultures in a quick pace setting.

The California Grill features include Uncle Bud&apos;s current favorites: Burgers, hand dipped Fish and Chips, and Onion Rings. However, we&apos;ve also expanded the menu to include Pizzas, Panini&apos;s, and hand dipped Corn Dogs, plus grab-n-go Salads and Indian Tacos.

The menu within Asian Grill will include Pho Noodle Bowls, char-grilled Meat&amp;Rice Bowls, and many signature wok dishes, plus whole Fish, steamed or fried, and other Asian favorites.

We&apos;re currently seeking talented Cook/Cashiers to join the Pacific Grill&apos;s staff.   

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Handles small to large sums of money, coupons, comps, credit cards and other forms of payment Count currency and give proper change during cash transactions. Respectfully request and receives payments from guests when required.  Adheres to established cash handling policies and procedures including the Variance policy. Knows and can communicate information about venues, menus and pricing. Ability to answer questions pertaining to the ingredients in food items being sold Communicates with guest in a respectiful, friendly and diplomatic skills to answer guest inquiries and concerns. Resolves guest concerns and/or refers them to the appropriate personnel when necessary. Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food. Maintains all refrigeration and dry storage areas to ensure proper handling and rotation of products. Ensures that their culinary work station is clean and that all food items are properly covered and stored at the end of shift. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups. Actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations. Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braisers, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation. Assists with guest requests when needed. Helps stock dishes when needed. Assists with storage, proper rotation and labeling of food products. Uses dry and liquid measure and scales. Stirs and strains soups and sauces. Maintains a culinary work station when required. Performs proper receiving, thawing, and storage in correct location, proportioning prep area sanitation, heating and holding, and re-thermalization (including sauces, soups, salad bar items, lunch, dinner, and produce). 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of six months to two years of relevant cooking experience in a fast food restaurant or casual/fine dining environment with cash handling and customer service responsiblities. Have the ability to stand for long periods of time Must be able to frequently lift and/or move up to 25 pounds and occasionally lift and/or move up to 50 pounds Must be able to work weekends and holidays 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 5/16/2012 Position: Cook I (Rancheria Buffet) Shift: ALL - Full Time Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $9.50 to $14.25 Requirements: 
Now open at Jackson Rancheria, the new Rancheria Buffet provides a new and exciting dining experience. Open 7 days a week, this 300 seat buffet will provide guests the opportunity to experience live action cooking stations.

The buffet will showcase six new action cooking stations, open for guests to see. A Fresh Salad Station will include numerous choices, from compound salads, to fresh fruit, and everything in between. An Asian Wok Station will feature many Asian favorites. . . and the wok&apos;s will be moving all the time.

A Live fire churrascaria Grill, an active vertical rotisserie, will be full of roasting meats on long skewers. Guests will have the opportunity to enjoy Mexican favorites along side the churrascaria meats in the Mexican Station.

An Italian station will feature a Brick Oven to cook pizzas, Plancha style seafood, and even pastas. An American Station will feature a carvery to showcase everything from prime rib to roasted turkeys, and traditional favorites such as fried chicken and mashed potatoes. And of course, a Dessert Station, with many opportunities for our guests to interact with their final course.

We&apos;re currently seeking talented Cooks to join the Rancheria Buffet&apos;s staff. Available positions include:

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food. Maintains all refrigeration and dry storage areas to ensure proper handling and rotation of products. Ensures that their culinary work station is clean and that all food items are properly covered and stored at the end of shift. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups. Actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations. Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braisers, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation. Assists with guest requests when needed. Helps stock dishes when needed. Assists with storage, proper rotation and labeling of food products. Uses dry and liquid measure and scales. Stirs and strains soups and sauces. Maintains a culinary work station when required. Performs proper receiving, thawing, and storage in correct location, proportioning prep area sanitation, heating and holding, and re-thermalization (including sauces, soups, salad bar items, lunch, dinner, and produce). 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of six months to two years of relevant cooking experience in a fast food restaurant or casual/fine dining
environment. Have the ability to stand for long periods of time Must be able to frequently lift and/or move up to 25 pounds and occasionally lift and/or move up to 50 pounds Must be able to work weekends and holidays 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 4/20/2012 Position: I.T. Manager Shift: FULL TIME Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $70,105 to $105,000 Requirements: 
 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Responsible for assuring users are provided efficient and timely service support and vendor support on a 7x24 basis Monitors problem management database and follows up with assigned personnel to ensure timely resolution of problems Provides staff support for administrative tasks and projects relative to the desktop, application, system, and network functions Maintains a central source of information enabling Service Desk team members to recover outages with minimal disruption to the business and resume expected service levels Invokes problem escalation procedures to coordinate recovery Isolates problem trends and ensures that troubleshooting efforts are completed for recurring problems until permanent solutions are found Ensures that daily, weekly, and monthly statistics, and status reports are completed and continually modified to meet the needs of the department Ensures that decisions made to improve the overall customer service level and to provide consistent technical support level within the Service Desk Contributes to departmental productivity and development objectives by participating in training programs Accurately communicates pertinent information. Assists in the development and implementation of quality improvement programs Ensures that effective Service Desk representation takes place for the coordination of work processes and projects with other departments and divisions Leads the implementation of new projects Installs new software releases, new hardware, system upgrades and evaluates and installs patches. Prepares and maintains documentation of system configurations Assists with change management, incident management, and disaster recovery planning and system testing in a controlled environment Other duties may be assigned as required 

 EDUCATION and/or EXPERIENCE 

 B.S. in Computer Science or Management Information Systems preferred 5+ years experience with Systems/Network Technologies management preferred 

Knowledge of the following required -

 Windows 200x Server SQL&amp;MS SQL 200x Database Administration Feasibility and Needs Assessment Change Management and Asset Management Data and System Security Project Development Minimum Internal Control Standards for IT 

Knowledge of the following preferred -

 Aristocrat Oasis Cisco Infrastructure MCSE MS Exchange 2010 VM Ware VSphere/View Gaming Systems 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 4/6/2012 Position: Systems Engineer II Shift: FT - Days Pay Type: Salary Pay Range: $58,000 to $87,000 Requirements: Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 
 Primary responsibility is to administer systems, resolve daily operational issues and assist with projects Configure and perform maintenance of MS Exchange 2010 Participate in Service Desk duties Participate in a team oriented environment Perform maintenance, configuration, and monitoring of SQL database systems Assists with planning, designing and reviewing systems to identify and mitigate risks Installs new software releases, new hardware, system upgrades and evaluates and installs patches Monitors and reports on system performance, stability and security Coordinates with third-party support for hardware and software services. Performs system backups and recovery Prepares and maintains documentation of system configurations Assists with change management, disaster recovery planning and system testing in a controlled environment Assists with developing and implementing system and user security requirements Other duties may be assigned 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 2-4 years of professional experience with Microsoft Windows Enterprise administration Can work independently under general supervision Analytical thinker, detail oriented and a decision maker Must have a solid working knowledge of Microsoft Windows Enterprise environment, AD, Exchange, MS SQL, IIS, DHCP, DNS Must be able to provide courteous and professional customer service to customers and fellow IT team members. 

 EDUCATION and/or EXPERIENCE 

 High school diploma or general education degree (GED) A.S. in Computer Science or equivalent experience Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE) MCSE: Security and/or MCSE: Messaging are highly desirable Comptia Server+ and Comptia Security+ certifications are highly desirable 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 3/23/2012 Position: Valet Attendant/Van Driver Shift: FT-Graveyard Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $8.00 to $12.00 Requirements: Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 
 Valet Attendants will follow all safety procedures of Jackson Rancharia Casino and Hotel and the policy and procedures of the Transportation dept. Valet Attendants must be able to perform Tagging procedures, Driving duties as well as Key Room Monitor duties. Valet Attendants must be able to operate vehicles with Manual and Automatic Transmissions. Valet Attendants must perform Guest Services as set by the standards of the Jackson Rancharia Casino and Hotel and of those of the Transportation Services dept. Valet Attendants must be able to communicate with guest and answer questions on Casino current events. Valet Attendants are required to maintain a professional appearance and present them always in the manner as described in the Employee Handbook and by the policy and procedures established by the Transportation Services dept. Valet Attendants are responsible for the safety and security of all guest vehicles&apos;while under Valet depts. control. All Valet Attendants will help and maintain cleanliness of all areas of operation. All Drivers will perform vehicle inspection prior to driving vans and insure that proper paper work is completed and filled out properly. All Drivers will report to Supervisor on duty prior to driving van at start of their shifts. All drivers will follow proper radio procedures and follow radio etiquette. Driver is responsible for daily maintenance of van and insures that the van is clean and ready for their shifts to include adding proper fluids as needed. Driver will follow all Policy and Procedures of the Casino as well as those of the Transportation Services Department at all times. Drivers are responsible for the safety of their passengers at all time and must report any and all unsafe conditions to Supervisor on duty. Driver will perform driving duties for a period of 8 hr. unless relieved by Supervisor on duty. Must be on time for start of shift and in proper uniform. Ability to drive vehicles with automatic and manual transmission. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 Drivers must have a valid CA Drivers.  Clean DMV record. The employee must occasionally lift and/or move up to 25 pounds.  

 *Graveyard shift receives $1.00/hr differential                           

  Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 3/15/2012 Position: Cook II Shift: Swing - Full Time Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $10.50 to $15.75 Requirements: 
We are currently seeking talented cooks to fill the position of Cook II at the Lone Wolf.

 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food in kitchen preparation in accordance with established recipes. Maintains all refrigeration and dry storage areas to ensure proper handling and rotation of products. Ensures that stations are clean and that all food items are properly covered, labeled and stored at the end of shift. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations. Provide clear direction, instruction and guidance to team members. Organize and delegate work assignments to lower-level cooks and tasks to meet deadlines. Train lower-level cooks in proper equipment usage. Communicate regularly with co-workers to ensure efficient and effective operations. Exhibit knowledge, understanding, and application of various cooking techniques. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups. Actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations. Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braisers, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation. Maintain a solid knowledge of all food products. Perform all assigned sidework to include replenishing/restocking work station with supplies. Check station before, during, and after shift for proper set-up and cleanliness. Assists with guest requests Perform other duties as assigned by management. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of two to five years of relevant cooking experience in a fast food restaurant or casual/fine dining environment. Have the ability to stand for long periods of time Must be able to frequently lift and/or move up to 25 pounds and occasionally lift and/or move up to 50 pounds Must be able to work weekends and holidays 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 3/15/2012 Position: Cook III Shift: Full Time - All Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $11.50 to $17.25 Requirements: We are currently seeking talented Cooks to fill the position of Cook III at the Lone Wolf Restaurant and Pacific Grill. 
 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Actively participate with staff to cook, prepare, dish-up and assemble food. Serves as expediter in absence of Restaurant Chef. Prepares, seasons, finishes, and garnishes all food in kitchen preparation in accordance with established recipes. Assists, in the absence of the Restaurant Chef, in checking for quality and consistency. Inspects all refrigeration and dry storage for proper handling and rotation. Ensures that stations are clean and that all food items are properly covered, labeled and stored at the end of shift. Follows all recipes, specs, and control procedures. Maintains a clean and sanitary area at all times in full accordance with health regulations. Maintains professional grooming and appearance and acts as a role model according to established grooming and appearance policy. Maintain positive guest relations at all times, resolving guest complaints and ensuring guest satisfaction.  Operate kitchen equipment including slicer, steamer, deep fryer, ovens, broiler, grill, mixer, kettle, flat top, slow cookers, griddles, braisers, ranges, salamanders, combination ovens, knives, and other equipment for food preparation. Provide clear direction, instruction and guidance to lower-level cooks. . Organize and delegate work assignments and tasks to meet deadlines. Train lower-level cooks in proper equipment usage. Communicate regularly with kitchen staff to ensure efficient and effective operations. . Exhibit knowledge, understanding, and application of various cooking techniques. Ability to work with small, delicate, and sensitive equipment (knives) requiring fine finger dexterity. Exhibit preparation and knowledge of base sauces, stocks, and soups. Demonstrate ability to work in different food outlet locations. Maintain a solid knowledge of all food products. Prepare order lists for recipe preparations. Perform all assigned sidework to include replenishing/restocking work station with supplies. Adhere to control procedure for food costs and quality. Check station before, during, and after shift for proper set-up and cleanliness. Abide by all health codes and hand washing guidelines and encourage team members to do the same. Assists guests with special requests. Encourages mutual respect, dignity and integrity with all employees, by setting positive examples at all times. Instills an atmosphere that encourages employees to share ideas, discuss concerns, and resolve conflicts. Retains employees through involvement in training and development. Responsible for conducting all responsibilities in a professional and ethical manner

 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 A minimum of five years of relevant cooking experience in a fast food restaurant or casual/fine dining environment. A minimum of two years of experience in a leadership position within a kitchen work environment. Vocational or culinary school graduate preferred Have the ability to stand for long periods of time Must be able to frequently lift and/or move up to 25 pounds and occasionally lift and/or move up to 50 pounds Must be able to work weekends and holidays 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 Posting Date: 3/15/2012 Position: Dishwashers Shift: Swing - Full Time Pay Type: Hourly Pay Range: $9.00 to $13.50 Requirements: Responsible for all functions necessary to provide assistant and maintenance in the kitchen and restaurant.
 Job Duties Include but are Not Limited To: 

 Must demonstrate the flexibility and adaptability necessary to work in a gaming environment. Must perform a wide range of related duties as needed or requested by the supervisor. Responsible for the washing of soiled dishes, silverware, glasses, pots and pans. Maintain supplies to the dining area such as silverware, glassware and dishes. Assist in all phases of service in the kitchen as directed. Knowledge of proper operation and cleaning procedures of all kitchen equipment utensils. Must be quick, accurate and able to follow instructions. Must maintain a professional attitude and appearance at all times. Must be able to effectively communicate with guests and co-workers. 

 Minimum Qualifications: 

 Prior restaurant/bus person experience preferred. Must present a well-groomed appearance. Must be able to work in a team environment to complete tasks 

 This is not a smoke free workplace.  Although we employ state-of-the-art air filtration systems, cigarette smoke is in the work environment

 Click here to submit your resume 
 
 
 Openings Application Benefits 
 
 Copyright©2011 Jackson Rancheria. All Rights Reserved. Home Privacy Policy General Information Responsible Gaming Contact 
 12222 New York Ranch Road  Jackson California 95642  (800) 822-WINN
	</body>
</document>
