<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008406" url="http://www.flyertalk.com/forum/s-p-m/1017094-fast-food-restaurant-loyalty-programs.html" time="2012-07-13-01:53" support="11" score="0.020239784165742784" bingtitle="Fast Food restaurant loyalty programs - FlyerTalk Forums" webtitle="Fast Food restaurant loyalty programs - FlyerTalk Forums">
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Burger King has had a survey on the back of its receipts for several years. Make any purchase, call the toll-free number on the receipt, answer the questions, and ...</description>
	<body>
		Flyertalk 
 Home Blog Forums 
 Forum Home Register Miles&amp;Points Travel&amp;Dining Community OMNI Destinations Search Wireless Access New User Guide Guidelines 
 Members 
 Register My Flyer Talk Private Messages Subscribed Threads TalkMail Newsletter Member Do&apos;s&amp;Events City Connect Events FlightConnect Town Hall FlyerTalk Premium Flyer Talk Cares 
 Extras 
 FlyerTalk Awards Blogs@FlyerTalk Book Club Credit Card Reviews FlyerTalk Merchandise Live Chat Photo Gallery WebFlyer 
 Help 
 About FlyerTalk Advertise on FlyerTalk Airport Code Lookup Contact Us FAQ Guidelines&amp;Rules Glossary Legal Notices Lost Password Privacy Policy Support Forums 
 
 Forums: 
 Miles&amp;Points Travel&amp;Dining Community OMNI Destinations 
 my flyertalk 
 
   
 
 
 

 
   FlyerTalk Forums &gt; Miles&amp;Points &gt; S.P.A.M. Fast Food restaurant loyalty programs 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Use your Facebook account to securely log into this site! Click the logo to log in! Connect with Facebook 
 
 Register FAQ Calendars Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Advanced Search - Google Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 Search 
   
 Web flyertalk.com 
 
 
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 

   Thread Tools Search this Thread 
 
 Nov 15, 09, 7:14 am  # 1 mschroed  
 Join Date: Apr 2002 Location: Washington, DC Posts: 46 Fast Food restaurant loyalty programs 
 
Apologies if this belongs in another thread, but is there a relatively comprehensive listing of fast food restaurant frequent eating programs? Subway, etc.?

Thanks   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 8:06 am  # 2 bitburgr  
 Join Date: Nov 2005 Programs: Marriott Plat, EZ Pass, Back of the Plane Platinum Posts: 3,687 I posted a similar question in Dining Buzz about a month ago ( Dining Rewards?) and got no responses. I hope this gets some traction.   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 9:24 am  # 3 Jeeves  
 Join Date: Jan 2002 Location: Seattle, WA Programs: AS MVPG, Hyatt Diamond, Hilton Gold Posts: 3,061 Subway did away with the Club Card earlier this year. They said it was replaced by the $5.00 foot long value meal selections.

I&apos;m unaware of any fast food loyalty programs. Most chains have you provide them with your e-mail and they will then send you coupons and promotions.   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 4:27 pm  # 4 mschroed  
 Join Date: Apr 2002 Location: Washington, DC Posts: 46 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Jeeves Subway did away with the Club Card earlier this year. They said it was replaced by the $5.00 foot long value meal selections.

I&apos;m unaware of any fast food loyalty programs. Most chains have you provide them with your e-mail and they will then send you coupons and promotions. 
 Ok, thanks for that. I didn&apos;t know about Subway doing away with their program. That settles it, I might just start tracking what I can find.   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 4:33 pm  # 5 SkiAdcock TalkBoard Vice President, FlyerTalk Evangelist  
 Join Date: Aug 2002 Programs: UAPremierGold/1.75MM, Marriott LifetimePlatinum Posts: 30,751 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Jeeves 
I&apos;m unaware of any fast food loyalty programs. Most chains have you provide them with your e-mail and they will then send you coupons and promotions. 
 What he said. I&apos;m on the list of a few.

Cheers. __________________
Sharon   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 5:05 pm  # 6 CMK10 FlyerTalk Evangelist  
 Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Durham, NC (RDU/GSO) Programs: AA Platinum, DL Silver (FO), UA Premier Gold, BW Platinum, HH Silver, PC Gold Posts: 10,247 If you are near a Paradise Bakery they have one. It&apos;s called the Taste of Paradise card and every time you buy ten sandwiches/salads you get the next one (along with a soda or coffee) free. They&apos;re in ten states.

 http://www.paradisebakery.com/ __________________
Proudly celebrating one decade as a member of Flyertalk all month!   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 5:57 pm  # 7 gleff FlyerTalk Evangelist  
 Join Date: Apr 2001 Location: DCA Programs: AMC MovieWatcher, Giant BonusCard, Petco PALS Card, Silver Diner Blue Plate Club Posts: 22,216 What I&apos;m more interested in is elite levels of loyalty programs. Not a fast food chain, but Mortons has one, and CO Presidential Plus Mastercard holders are comped in.

I wonder what elite status would look like at Quiznos? __________________
 View from the Wing blog : everything you need to know about earning/redeeming miles&amp;getting the most bang for your travel $$   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 10:41 pm  # 8 RobertTheTraveler  
 Join Date: Aug 2001 Location: Hinterlands, CA Posts: 277 BK Free Whopper or Free Original Chicken Sandwich Burger King has had a survey on the back of its receipts for several years. Make any purchase, call the toll-free number on the receipt, answer the questions, and receive a code.

The code entitles you to either a free whopper or a free original chicken sandwich when you purchase ANY SIZE fries and ANY SIZE beverage, including the $1 Value Menu.

The survey indicates one redemption per month.

I am CA-based, but have seen the offer printed on receipts in the midwest and FL.

Not exactly a&quot;frequent dining&quot;deal, however, depending on your own personal ethics, and the number of BK outlets in your area, you could dine daily for $2+tax.   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 10:47 pm  # 9 RobertTheTraveler  
 Join Date: Aug 2001 Location: Hinterlands, CA Posts: 277 Wendys Survey = Free Single I do not believe this offer is nationwide, but the receipts given throughout Southern CA have surveys printed on the back. You can either call a toll-free number or use www.talktowendys.com to submit the survey and receive a code valid for a free Single Burger. This is not the 99-cent Jr Burger, but rather the standard regular, one-patty burger.

There is no additional purchase requirement.

You can only complete one survey per month and software prevents calls from the same telephone number or repeat e-mail addresses until after 30-days.   
 
 Nov 15, 09, 11:48 pm  # 10 Fly2LAX  
 Join Date: Sep 2006 Location: Worldwide - Cruising altitude Programs: LH Senator, Delta PM, AA Platinum, UA Dirt Grey, British Midland, Hyatt Diamond Posts: 387 Just what people need... a way to encourage them eating more unhealthy and fattening food ! __________________
 Life is like a Mileage Run !   
 
 Nov 16, 09, 10:34 am  # 11 767-322ETOPS  
 Join Date: Jun 2001 Location: Madison NJ Programs: AAPLT, Marriott Silver, HHGLD Posts: 3,130 Cosi Card - combo stored value and reward card. 10:1 purchase to freebie ratio.   
 
 Nov 16, 09, 10:57 am  # 12 bitburgr  
 Join Date: Nov 2005 Programs: Marriott Plat, EZ Pass, Back of the Plane Platinum Posts: 3,687 There&apos;s the Qdoba Rewards Card program.   
 
 Nov 16, 09, 2:17 pm  # 13 PG FlyerTalk Evangelist  
 Join Date: Nov 1999 Location: IAD Programs: AA Lifetime Platinum Posts: 22,285 Some Grocery Stores (Giant, Safeway) will give you a free sub after you purchase a certain number of subs.

Some stores will have cards which will you get stamped/puched each time you eat and you get a free meal or discount after all boxes have been stamped. I know in my area some Subways that will give you a free 6 inch sub when you redeem - you have to purchase a drink to get the sub though.

Manchu Wok near my work has a card which gets you the 12th meal free. Last edited by PG; Nov 20, 09 at 8:46 pm ..   
 
 Nov 16, 09, 9:45 pm  # 14 Nexus  
 Join Date: Aug 2006 Posts: 20 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by mschroed Apologies if this belongs in another thread, but is there a relatively comprehensive listing of fast food restaurant frequent eating programs? Subway, etc.?

Thanks 
 I have no idea about a list but I know about a related program. Is called The biggest loser and it airs on NBC on Tuesdays.

On the subject now : I know about a loyalty program on Penn station sandwiches but I don&apos;t know if they still have it. 8 sandwiches brought you a free one.   
 
 Nov 17, 09, 5:16 am  # 15 sobore  
 Join Date: Mar 2005 Location: ORD MDW Programs: AA, UA, DL , PC Gold, SPG Gold, Avis PC - 2009 FT Fantasy Football Champion Posts: 6,063 I just want a bigger booth with more legroom at Subway, how do I get upgraded! __________________
Bring back Ted airlines, I miss the moaning and complaining.   
 
     
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 


 Bookmarks 
 Facebook Twitter Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page Suggest Thread for TalkMail 
 
 Search this Thread 
 Advanced Search 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are Off Pingbacks are On Refbacks are Off 
 
 Forum Jump 
 MyFlyerTalk Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Miles Points   MilesBuzz!   Hotel Deals   Mileage Run Deals     Mileage Run Discussion   S.P.A.M.   Airline Programs     Aegean Airlines Miles&amp;Bonus     airberlin topbonus     Air Canada Aeroplan     Air New Zealand Air Points     AirTran Airways A+ Rewards     Alaska Airlines Mileage Plan     Alitalia MilleMiglia     All Nippon Airways Mileage Club     American AAdvantage     Asiana Club     bmi diamond club     British Airways Executive Club     Cathay Pacific Asia Miles     Delta SkyMiles       Delta SkyMiles (Pre-WorldPerks Merger)       Northwest WorldPerks (Discontinued Program)     EL AL Matmid     Emirates Skywards     Etihad Airways Etihad Guest     Finnair Plus     Flying Blue (Air France, KLM, and Other Partners)       Air France Frequence Plus       KLM Flying Dutchman     Frontier Airlines EarlyReturns     Hawaii-based Airlines     Iberia Airlines Iberia Plus     India-based Airlines     JAL Mileage Bank     JetBlue TrueBlue     Korean Air Skypass     LAN LANPASS     Miles&amp;More (Lufthansa, Austrian, Swiss, and other partners)       Swiss International Airlines     Qantas Frequent Flyer     Qatar Airways Privilege Club     Russia/CIS-based Airlines     SAS EuroBonus     Singapore Airlines KrisFlyer     Southwest Rapid Rewards     Thai Airways Royal Orchid Plus     Turkish Airlines Miles&amp;Smiles     United MileagePlus (Consolidated)       Continental OnePass (Pre-Merger)       United Mileage Plus (Pre-Merger)     US Airways Dividend Miles       2011 Grand Slam Promotion     Virgin America Elevate     Virgin Atlantic Flying Club     Virgin Australia Velocity     WestJet Rewards     Other Asian, Australian and South Pacific Frequent Flyer Programs     Other European Frequent Flyer Programs     Other Middle East and Africa Frequent Flyer Programs     Other North&amp;South America Frequent Flyer Programs   Global Airline Alliances     oneworld     SkyTeam     Star Alliance   Hotel Programs     Best Western Rewards     Choice Privileges     Club Carlson     Fairmont President&apos;s Club     Hilton HHonors     Hyatt Gold Passport     InterContinental Hotels: Priority Club&amp;Inter-Continental Ambassador       InterContinental Hotels Group Stay Forum     Le Club Accorhotels (was Accor A-Club)     Marriott Rewards     Starwood Preferred Guest     Wyndham Rewards     Other Hotel Programs   Credit Card Programs/Partners     Credit Card Programs     American Express Membership Rewards     Diners Club Club Rewards   Car Rental Programs/Partners     Avis     Budget     Dollar     Hertz     National     Sixt     Thrifty     Other Car Rental Programs/Partners (ie. Alamo, Enterprise)   Other Loyalty Programs/Partners     Amtrak Guest Rewards     iDine/Rewards Network     Gaming Loyalty Programs Travel&amp;Dining   TravelBuzz!   DiningBuzz!   Travel Technology   Travel Photography   Travel Products   Travel Tools   Travel News   Free Travel Contests and Sweepstakes   Travel Safety/Security     Practical Travel Safety Issues     Checkpoints and Borders Policy Debate   Online Travel Booking and Bidding Agencies   Luxury Hotels   Cruises   Budget Travel   Special Interest Travel     Disability Travel     GLBT Travelers     Group and Event Travel Planning     Religious Travelers     Travel Health and Fitness     Travel with Children     Travel with Pets     Women Travelers Destinations   Africa     Africa   Americas     Canada     Caribbean     Central America     Cuba     Mexico     South America       Argentina       Brazil       Peru   America - USA     New England     Mid-Atlantic       New York City       Washington D.C. (including Baltimore)     South     Florida       Orlando     Midwest       Chicago     Texas     West       Las Vegas     California       Los Angeles       San Francisco     Hawaii     Alaska   Antarctica     Antarctica   Asia     Asia     China     Hong Kong and Macau     India     Japan     Singapore     Thailand   Europe including Turkey     Europe     European Rail Travel     France     Germany     Italy     Nordic Countries     Russia     U.K. and Ireland   Middle East including Egypt     Middle East   Oceania (Australia, New Zealand&amp;the South Pacific)     Oceania (Australia, New Zealand&amp;the South Pacific) Community   CommunityBuzz!   Flyertalk Cares!   FlyerTalk Live! (chat)   Itineraries   Trip Reports   Blog@FlyerTalk   TalkBoard Topics     Town Hall - Official TalkBoard Voting Decisions Support&amp;Services   Technical Issues   Suggestions   New Features 
 

 
 
 All times are GMT -6. The time now is 5:53 pm . 
 
 Contact Us - FlyerTalk - Archive - Top 

 
 
 Privacy Policy Glossary Airport Code Lookup The Gate FrugalTravelGuy FrequentFlier 
 This site is owned, operated, and maintained by Flyertalk.com. Copyright©2012 Flyertalk.com. All rights reserved.
Designated trademarks are the property of their respective owners. 
 SEO by vBSEO 3.6.0©2011, Crawlability, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
