<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008281" url="http://www.thefreelibrary.com/Looking+Through+Potato+Glass%2c+Darkly%3a+Will+quality+Problems+Eat+Up...-a060020484" time="2012-07-13-01:46" support="2" score="0.0010632247643348313" bingtitle="Looking Through Potato Glass, Darkly: Will quality Problems Eat Up ..." webtitle="Looking Through Potato Glass, Darkly: Will quality Problems Eat Up Supply? - Free Online Library">
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>Free Online Library: Looking Through Potato Glass ... See also: Fast-food restaurant, Casual dining, List of reference ... Meanwhile the work of packing potato products goes on ...</description>
	<body>
		Printer Friendly 
19,791,913 articles and books Periodicals Literature Keyword Title Author Topic 
 Member login User name    Password     Remember me 
 Join us   Forgot password? 
 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Agricultural industry &gt;  Quick Frozen Foods International &gt;  January 1, 2000 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Business &gt;  Quick Frozen Foods International &gt;  January 1, 2000 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Food and beverage industries &gt;  Quick Frozen Foods International &gt;  January 1, 2000 The Free Library &gt;  Date &gt;  2000 &gt;  January &gt;  1 &gt;  Quick Frozen Foods International 
 
Looking Through Potato Glass, Darkly: Will quality Problems Eat Up Supply?

No shortage of potatoes harvested in 1999 as yields from increased
acreage were abundant. However, quality problems cropping up for
processors makes the job of turning out `perfect&apos; french fries French fry 
 n. 
A thin strip of potato fried in deep fat. Often used in the plural.  ever
challenging.

One thing is sure about the potato processing industry, Mother
Nature is the boss. Come what may, she always has a way of having the
final say. Just when European french European French may refer to:
 Belgian French Swiss French French of France
 See also 
 European English
  fry packers were counting on a
&quot;normal year&quot; and hoping to make up for volumes lost last year
due to regional shortages and resistance to high prices, it appeared
that a &quot;revised speech&quot; on the state of the industry might
have to be delivered.

At first it seemed that the 1999 autumn harvest -- notwithstanding
the dry and hot months of August and September -- was coming in nicely
throughout the growing regions A growing region is an area suited by climate and soil conditions to the cultivation of a certain type of crop. Most crops are cultivated not in one place only, but in several distinct regions in diverse parts of the world.  of the Benelux and northern France.
Unlike the previous year, crops were abundant in Holland, though short tuber tuber,  enlarged tip of a rhizome (underground stem) that stores food. Although much modified in structure, the tuber contains all the usual stem parts—bark, wood, pith, nodes, and internodes.  length was less than ideal for cutting long french fries. All
looked well in Belgium&apos;s fertile Flanders fields For the article about the war poem, see In Flanders Fields 

 Flanders Fields is the generic name of the World War I battlefields in the medieval County of Flanders. , which were
generally spared from the hard rains and early frost that wreaked havoc
in the Netherlands during late &apos;98.

Looks can be deceiving, however, as the beauty of potatoes is only
skin-deep. Processors frying up test batches of frozen flies during
December were shocked to find the tell-tale sign of glassiness glass·y  
 adj. glass·i·er , glass·i·est 
 1. Characteristic of or resembling glass.

 2. Lifeless; expressionless: &quot;the face changing to a demon&apos;s face with a fixed glassy grin&quot;    (generally associated with second growth tubers following drought)
evident in black spots and dark blotches. The superficial blemishes,
apparent in perhaps two or three chips per half-kilo, is not something
that quality-minded A-grade buyers for fast food restaurant chains The following is a list of restaurant chains .

See also: Fast-food restaurant, Casual dining, List of reference tables. International 


 Bennigan&apos;s Burger King Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs Domino&apos;s Pizza Hard Rock Cafe 
  and
supermarket multiples want their customers to see.

The problem for processors is that the starch starch,  white, odorless, tasteless, carbohydrate powder. It plays a vital role in the biochemistry of both plants and animals and has important commercial uses.  concentration of
&quot;top glass&quot; which causes the dark spots is invisible until
after frying. If the ratio of glass to dry matter (or solid) content is
high, affected spuds will float to the top of saltwater baths and be
diverted from further processing. Such was the case during the 1994-95
season, the last time that glassiness seriously reduced yields and
hampered efficiency. This reliable method of flushing out undesirable
raw materials is not feasible, unfortunately, when a relatively small
percentage of the tuber is affected.

&quot;It could be that the apparent surplus of supply on the market
today will quickly melt away if huge amounts of potatoes are
rejected,&quot; Geert Demeester of Clarebout Potatoes warned Quick
Frozen Foods International magazine on December 2. &quot;Frankly, I am
surprised that there has not been speculation on the potato futures
market futures market,  a commodity exchange where contracts for the future delivery of grain, livestock, and precious metals are bought and sold. Speculation in futures serves to protect both the developers and the users of the commodities from unfavorable and unpredictable  yet.&quot;

An unscientific unscientific  Unproven, see there  survey suggested that the &quot;top glass&quot;
condition was affecting late-harvest spuds in a wide geographical region
spanning from the west of Amsterdam southward south·ward  
 adv. &amp;adj. 
Toward, to, or in the south.

 n. 
A southward direction, point, or region.

 
 south  to France. &quot;We have
greatly curtailed buying potatoes in this area,&quot; said Nieuwkerke,
Belgium-based Demeester (Fax: 32-57-44-6906). &quot;Extra efforts are
being made to procure only raw material from unaffected fields and place
it in coldstores as insurance for the future.&quot;

With half a year to go before the next potato crop is harvested,
processors will carefully scrutinize scru·ti·nize  
 tr.v. scru·ti·nized , scru·ti·niz·ing , scru·ti·niz·es 
To examine or observe with great care; inspect critically.

 
 scru  deliveries made from farmers&apos;
stocks in late January and February. That&apos;s because it typically
takes eight to 10 weeks for a stored potato to show its true face in
terms of quality. Five years ago, unprocessed potato piles collapsed
under the weight of glassy tubers.

&quot;There is no obvious solution to this complicated
problem,&quot; shrugged Demeester. &quot;Customers certainly don&apos;t
understand its complexity. Some think incorrectly that it&apos;s just an
excuse to raise prices.&quot;

Meanwhile the work of packing potato products goes on at the
private label specialist&apos;s plant, which boasts annual capacity of
125,000 tons. &quot;We must concentrate on processing and be happy with
the result,&quot; said Demeester. &quot;If the yield is 90% instead of
100%, so be it.&quot;

Clarebout aims to continue prospecting further afield for business
opportunities -- especially in Latin America Latin America,  the Spanish-speaking, Portuguese-speaking, and French-speaking countries (except Canada) of North America, South America, Central America, and the West Indies.  and Asia. &quot;The market
in Europe is tough -- it&apos;s all about undercutting your competition
on price. While we compete in the EU, I like to explore new
territory,&quot; said the sales and marketing director.

View from Vriezo&apos;s Bridge

Sies de Vries de Vries.  For some persons thus named use Vries.   , commercial director of Vriezo BV, confirmed the
existence of top glass in potatoes harvested from the north of Holland.
&quot;We can handle it,&quot; he was quick to add, &quot;though it will
take greater production efforts to meet our customers&apos;
specifications.&quot;

The Oosterbierum-based potato businessman (Fax: 31-518-48-11-58)
believes that the problem was more acute in the southern Netherlands The historical terms Spanish Netherlands and Austrian Netherlands  both redirect to here. 

The Southern Netherlands (Dutch: Zuidelijke Nederlanden, Spanish: Países Bajos del Sur, French: Pays-Bas du sud , as
well as in the south of Belgium and north of France. &quot;Despite this,
the futures market remains calm,&quot; he said on Dec. 7. &quot;Maybe in
January prices will edge up. Who knows what will happen if the
glassiness problem persists?&quot;

Clearly, the Vriezo commercial director is hoping for price
stability. &quot;It&apos;s no secret that Dutch suppliers lost market
share in Middle East and South America South America,  fourth largest continent (1991 est. pop. 299,150,000), c.6,880,000 sq mi (17,819,000 sq km), the southern of the two continents of the Western Hemisphere.  due to high prices,&quot; he
said. &quot;Brazil was an especially difficult place in which to do
business last year. There the national currency fell, the dollar rose,
and so did the price of french fries.&quot;

While there is little Vriezo can do about the cost of raw
materials, over the years it has gone the extra mile to assure that its
factory remains on the cutting edge of high efficiency. Price
competition is fierce, which is why every effort is made to maximize
product yield to the fullest extent possible. &quot;We strive to be a
low-cost producer operating from a high-tech factory,&quot; said de
Vries.

The company&apos;s french fry and flake lines produce approximately
100,000 tons of finished product a year by operating three shifts per
day, seven days a week, 50 weeks per year. During a one-week shutdown
between Christmas and the New Year a new Tegra optical sorting machine
was installed by Key/Superior.

&quot;The Tegra will enable us to eliminate black and blue spots
identified on free-falling fries as they move down the conveyor
line,&quot; said the commercial director. &quot;Next we will modernize
our weighing system in the packaging department. Constantly upgrading is
the way to remain viable.&quot;

Looking ahead, the Vriezo executive expects to see increased
business in both private label and Copacking spheres this year.
&quot;Consumption of frozen potato products is growing internationally,
along with competition,&quot; he said. &quot;Our main market will
continue to be United Kingdom, followed by Spain, Italy, France, Germany
and Scandinavia.&quot;

Lamb-Weston/Meijer

With the numerous global supply lines and resources available to
Lamb-Weston/Meijer as a unit of ConAgra, Inc., it takes pride in doing
whatever is necessary to fulfill customer contracts regardless of
adverse conditions. In 1998, when the autumn potato crop failure struck
Holland, a large fleet of trucks were mobilized to roll south into the
Belgian countryside and bring back 50,000 tons of spuds in one month to
keep Lamb-Weston&apos;s high-capacity Kruinigen plant humming. Five
years earlier, the last time that second growth glassy tubers were a
problem, it imported finished product from sister operations in the USA
to assure an uninterrupted supply of top quality french fries to fast
food operators in Europe.

Last year, when two severe earthquakes devastated dev·as·tate  
 tr.v. dev·as·tat·ed , dev·as·tat·ing , dev·as·tates 
 1. To lay waste; destroy.

 2. To overwhelm; confound; stun: was devastated by the rude remark.  Turkey, the Dutch
factory geared up to ship finished goods to customers there.
Fortunately, assistance was not required as the company&apos;s Turkish
plant in Bolu escaped serious damage from the deadly natural disaster
which left thousands of survivors homeless.

Joop van Gurp, director of sales and marketing, was taking
everything in stride Adv. 1. in stride - without losing equilibrium; &quot;she took all his criticism in stride&quot;
in good spirits  when QFFI QFFI Quick Frozen Foods International  visited the company&apos;s Europe
headquarters in December. &quot;The harvest in Holland was normal,
though there are quality problems which must be dealt with,&quot; he
commented. &quot;The potatoes are more round than oval, and there are
fewer than we would like measuring above 50 millimeters in length.&quot;

Having said that, Joop expressed confidence that all was under
control. &quot;One of our big advantages is that we have contracts with
good farmers,&quot; he said. &quot;Most of what we buy is contracted,
which gives us control over raw materials right from the beginning. We
don&apos;t speculate -- that&apos;s our Golden Rule.&quot;

Kees van Loo The French Van Loo family (of Flemish origin) included a number of notable painters:
 Jean-Baptiste van Loo (1684–1745). Charles-André van Loo (1705–1765), brother of Jean-Baptiste. Louis-Michel van Loo (1707–1771), son of Jean-Baptiste.
  of the marketing department reported that a lot of
positive feedback was received from customers in response to the
introduction of six new products at the Anuga fair last autumn. Among
the American Specialities unveiled in Cologne were Hash Browns hash browns 
 pl.n. 
Chopped cooked potatoes, fried until brown. Also called hash brown potatoes . , Seasoned Crispy crisp·y  
 adj. crisp·i·er , crisp·i·est 
 1. Firm but easily broken or crumbled; crisp.

 2. Having small curls, waves, or ripples.  Cubes and Potato Stix.

&quot;We continue to work closely in product development with our
Lamb-Weston counterparts in the USA,&quot; said Van Loo. &quot;If there
is a big enough market in Europe for certain American-style
specialities, we will produce them here.&quot;

Growth is very much in the picture for Lamb-Weston/Meijer, which
currently has production capacity for more than 250,000 tons of finished
product per annum Per annum

Yearly. . Plans call for further increasing capacity this
summer.

Lutosa Invests Big Time

&quot;There are plenty of potatoes available at low prices at the
moment. As for glassiness, we think the worst is over and that
better-quality potatoes will come forward once prices move up in January
or February when those holding will start to sell.&quot;

So assessed Kurt de Lange of Van den Broeke-Lutosa (Fax:
32-69-66-11-70). &quot;There is less pressure on the buying side,
that&apos;s for sure,&quot; he added. &quot;We can reject truckloads
that are not up to standard.&quot;

On the job as commercial director for the family-owned company for
two years now, de Lange has taken on additional responsibilities to
boot. &quot;Logistics and sales are my current priorities,&quot; he told
QFFI. That no doubt has to do with the fact that the Belgian company,
which operates two plants in Flanders, has boosted output of finished
potato products by 30,000 tons to 200,000 per annum.

A visitor to the company&apos;s flagship factory will find a
sprawling and towering monument to high-technology potato processing and
warehousing efficiency. Indeed, owners Guy and Luc Van den Broeke have
invested approximately 1 billion Belgian francs Noun 1. Belgian franc - formerly the basic unit of money in Belgium
franc - the basic monetary unit in many countries; equal to 100 centimes

centime - a fractional monetary unit of several countries: France and Algeria and Belgium and Burkina Faso and  into a modernization
project which is grand in scale.

&quot; Reinvestment Reinvestment

Using dividends, interest and capital gains earned in an investment or mutual fund to purchase additional shares or units, rather than receiving the distributions in cash.

1. In terms of stocks, it is the reinvestment of dividends to purchase additional shares.  of profits to assure this company&apos;s
competitiveness in the new millennium is what this is all about,&quot;
said de Lange. &quot;The brothers are obviously intent in seeing that
Lutosa will remain a legitimate force in the marketplace.&quot;

The future is now in Leuze-en-Hainaut. There a white-walled,
34-meter-high fully-automated cold-store rises from it solid foundation
to embrace the blue sky above. It took the connection of two 17-meter
industrial panels (supplied by Isocab NV) to measure up to the design,
which incorporates an overhead tunnel linking the refrigerated re·frig·er·ate  
 tr.v. re·frig·er·at·ed , re·frig·er·at·ing , re·frig·er·ates 
 1. To cool or chill (a substance).

 2. To preserve (food) by chilling.  warehouse
to the factory. The use of fork-lift trucks fork-lift truck 
 Noun 

a vehicle with two moveable arms at the front that can be raised and lowered for transporting and unloading goods

 fork-lift truck   n → máquina elevadora    has been greatly reduced,
since conveyor belts conveyor belt 

One of various devices that provide mechanized movement of material, as in a factory. Conveyor belts are used in industrial applications and also on large farms, in warehousing and freight-handling, and in movement of raw materials.  move the spuds every inch of the way -- starting
from the first steps of incoming raw tubers to their incarnation as
bagged and boxed finished french fries, rosti with vegetables or pommes noisettes Noisettes (occasionally written as NOISEttes ) are an indie rock band from London comprising singer and bassist Shingai Shoniwa, guitarist Dan Smith, and drummer Jamie Morrison. .

&quot;We now have enough storage capacity to last six weeks,
compared to four weeks before,&quot; advised De Lange. &quot;From the
end of January all logistics will be handled from here, as we will no
longer have much need for the services of public cold stores.&quot;

The commercial director was pleased to report that Lutosa achieved
volume growth of 12% in 1999. &quot;It could have been greater, but we
closed down for several weeks in May and June to concentrate on
construction,&quot; he stated. &quot;Of course, that&apos;s just before
the first harvest -- a period when good potatoes for processing are
extremely short.&quot;

While Belgium and France are the company&apos;s primary markets, De
Lange noted that sales in Germany were up 250% in 1999. &quot;The payoff
came after only two years of real dedication to that market,&quot; he
said. &quot;Everything sold, though I realize that it had something to
do with the fact that others were short of product to sell.&quot;

As for sales beyond Europe, the commercial director expressed a debonair deb·o·nair  also deb·o·naire 
 adj. 
 1. Suave; urbane.

 2. Affable; genial.

 3. Carefree and gay; jaunty.  attitude: &quot;Sure it&apos;s nice to export some volume
overseas, though we can sell close to everything that&apos;s produced
right here in the EU. Nonetheless that didn&apos;t stop us today from
making a shipment to Latin America, where we supply the Carrefour
supermarket chain. There are also orders from the Middle East,
Yugoslavia and Russia which must be filled.&quot;

On the packaging front, De Lange said that a redesigned look will
be unveiled in the French market this January, as well as a Gratin gra·tin  
 n. 
A top crust consisting of browned crumbs and butter, often with grated cheese.

 
[French, from obsolete grater , to scratch, scrape , from Old French; see grate 1 .]   Dauphinois Dauphinois is a dialect of the Franco-Provençal language, which is spoken in Isère departement, roughly formerly Bas-Dauphiné. This is in France. The South of the Dauphiné is within the area of the Occitan language. See also 

 Languages of France
  featuring the recipe of a highly-regarded chef. Admittedly,
the commercial director has run a little behind schedule in launching
the vigorous campaign to enhance brand image that had been enunciated
when QFFI visited his office a year ago. But then the man has been
extremely busy tending to, shall we say, more concrete matters.

The trade can definitely look for Lutosa to put forth a fresh new
look and polish up polish up 
 Verb 

 1 . to make smooth and shiny by polishing

 2 . to improve (a skill or ability) by working at it: I&apos;m going to evening classes to polish up my German 

 Verb 1.  its image in Y2K See Y2K problem and Y2K compliant. 
 Y2K - Year 2000 , assured De Lange. As approximately
60% of the company&apos;s sales are in branded products, the change
should be easy to spot in both retail and foodservice channels.

Global Strategy for Farm Frites

As the third largest frozen potato products producer in Europe,
Farm Frites BV is intent on broadening its horizons even farther and
looming larger as a global player. As such, it has entered into a
strategic alliance with the J.R. Simplot Co., which ranks as the
world&apos;s No. 3 supplier of french fries (See sidebar on this page.).

&quot;The marriage of European and American expertise is going
quite well,&quot; observed Albert van der Vlies, director of marketing
and sales. &quot;Simplot has a lot of knowledge about processing, and we
know our way around the fragmented European market. It&apos;s a
win-win-win situation for Farm Frites, Simplot and our customers.&quot;

As for the &quot;top glass&quot; potato problem reported in the
Benelux, Van der Vlies responded in general terms: &quot;Potato sourcing
is the issue, which means you have to spread the risk. Fifty percent of
the European french fry market is supplied by the Dutch. But there is a
limit to how much can be harvested in any given location, so additional
growing areas have to be utilized. That is why we have invested in
France and other countries.&quot;

This is not to say that investment at the company&apos;s flagship
Oudenhoorn factory is not ongoing. Plans call for the upgrading of
technology and installation of new equipment as well as further
enhancing the on-site water treatment plant in 2000. Over the past five
years Farm Frites has invested more than 100 million euros in making
improvements system-wide. In-house development of a new coating
technology for fries, enhancing computer capabilities, and building a
self-contained electricity generation station are three examples of
where the money is going.

Kruin van Toledo, marketing manager, was pleased to report that
sales were brisk during the fourth quarter of 1999. &quot;A lot of
people stocked up in advance of the holidays, perhaps with the Y2K bug Y2K bug 
 or Year 2000 bug or millennium bug 

Potential problem in computers and computer networks at the beginning of the year 2000. Until the 1990s, most computer programs used only the last two digits to designate the year, the first two digits being  hype in mind,&quot; he said. &quot;No matter what the reason, increased
orders are fine with us. Just imagine if everybody takes delivery of an
additional week&apos;s worth of inventory. That would add up to about
50,000 more tons of potato products sold in Europe!&quot;

While Van Toledo did not reveal sales figures sales figures   npl → cifras fpl de ventas   , he smiled and
commented: &quot;Let&apos;s just say that from the time harvesting of
the potato crop began in August until now (Nov. 30), we have been
producing at full speed to fill orders.&quot;

What a difference a year makes! Around that time in 1998 the
problem was finding enough raw material to process. &quot;In bad times
you get to know who your real friends are,&quot; remarked Albert van der
Vlies.

Looking at Farm Frites&apos; track record over almost three
decades, the company generally doubles sales every five years. It
projects that by 2001 annual turnover will surpass 200 million euros.

Now listing more than fifty different potato products, Farm
Frites&apos; offerings run the gamut from standard french fries and
rosties to croquettes and potato rings. Recently, coated french fries
were added to the catalog. Customers can expect more introductions
coming in the near term.

Eurofreez Expands

Investment at the Eurofreez NV potato and specialities plant in
Proven, Belgium (Fax: 32-57-30-13-08), has been ongoing for the past
several years. Recently a high-capacity blanching For the term used in coinage, see Blanching (coinage). Blanching is a cooking term that describes a process of food preparation wherein the food substance, usually a vegetable or fruit, is plunged into boiling water, removed after a brief, timed interval  system was installed
by Kiremko. Soon a revamped potato grading station will be come on line.
Furthermore, a new coldstore is expected to be operational by late
January, providing 3,000 more pallet positions for a total of 7,000.

Eurofreez has four lines capable of annually producing up to 50,000
tons of french fries, other potato-based items, cheese croquettes and
additional specialities.

After nine years at the helm, Alan Palmer has retired as managing
director of the company. Taking over the position is Dirk de Pandelaere,
who had been serving as adjunct director. Palmer intends to make himself
available as a consultant after taking a well earned respite that will
no doubt include ample time for recreational golf.

Meanwhile, Palmer&apos;s successor is looking forward to growth of
about 15% in the year 2000. Reviewing last year&apos;s results, he
commented: &quot;We are pleased to say that all contracts were honored.
Exports beyond Europe suffered during the first half of 1999, but now
they are coming back due to the strong dollar.&quot;

On the new product front, De Pandelaere reported that two items
unveiled at the Anuga fair in Cologne last autumn were favorably
received by the trade. Eurofreez&apos;s innovative Porn&apos; Moscouvite
contains mashed potatoes n. pl. 1. Potatoes which have been boiled and mashed to a pulpy consistency, usu. with sparing addition of milk, salt, butter, or other flavoring. It is a popular accompaniment to a meat course [U.S., 1900&apos;s], providing bulk and calories to a meal. , chives chives

allium schoenoprasm .  and Danish caviar caviar  or caviare   (kăv`ēär) , the roe (eggs) of various species of sturgeon prepared as a piquant table delicacy.  (lumpfish) in
partially-peeled potato shell. The second offering, Potato Croque, is a
cheese fondue product that features a slice of ham enrobed in cheese and
breaded potato slices.

Shipments of both items in 2.5 kilo Thousand (10 to the 3rd power). Abbreviated &quot;K.&quot; For technical specifications, it refers to the precise value 1,024 since computer specifications are based on binary numbers. For example, 64K means 65,536 bytes when referring to memory or storage (64x1024), but a 64K salary means $64,000.  foodservice packs will commence
during the first quarter of 2000. Retail packaging will also be
available.

&quot;Belgium, France and the UK are our main markets,&quot; said
De Pandelaere. &quot;However, we think that the Pom&apos; Moscouvite
will appeal to a broader base of buyers in much of Europe.&quot;

Fri-d&apos;Or Spices Up its Offerings

Danisco Food BT logged &quot;a successful year in 1999, with
increased volumes and new introductions such as Fri-d&apos;Or Coated
Spicy Wedges,&quot; reported Carlos Matthijs.

The Bergen op Zoom Bergen op Zoom   (bĕr`gənôp zōm`) , town (1994 pop. 47,483), North Brabant prov., SW Netherlands, on the Zoom River near its confluence with the Eastern Scheldt. , Holland-based marketing manager said that new
clients nave nave   (nāv) , in general, all that part of a church that extends from the atrium to the altar and is intended exclusively for the laity. In a strictly architectural sense, however, the term indicates only the central aisle, excluding side aisles.  shown confidence in the Fri-d&apos;Or line, adding:
&quot;Consequently sales were slightly above last year&apos;s (1998)
level. With new contracts recently gained, sales will increase
further.&quot;

Matthijs conceded that high sugar content glassiness in tubers
harvested last autumn has been problematic for processors. However, he
emphasized that end-users supplied by Danisco Foods have no need for
concern: &quot;By implementing above-normal quality control standards
for incoming potatoes, we are in full control of the situation. As such,
we can supply our customers with the same high quality french fries that
their specifications call for.&quot;

Mydibel Chips In

&quot;It&apos;s true that there are quality problems with top glass
in the West Flanders West Flanders,  Du. West-Vlaanderen, Fr. Flandre Occidentale, province (1991 pop. 1,106,829), W Belgium, bordering on the North Sea in the west, on the Netherlands in the northeast, and on France in the south.  potato crop,&quot; Carlo Mylle of Mouscron-based
Mydibel s.a. (info@mydibel.be) told QFFI. &quot;But the situation is
manageable because supply is plentiful. Fortunately farmers put 10-15%
more land into production last year.&quot;

In business since 1988, Mydibel prides itself on being the only
family-run company in Europe offering a full line of processed potato
products. In addition to making frozen and chilled french fries,
puree-based items, flakes and specialities, it also produces crisps
(which are known as chips in the USA).

&quot;We saw a hole in the market and began supplying private label
crisps to Benelux customers last year,&quot; said Mylle, who runs the
factory. Brother Bruno is in charge of procuring raw material (primarily
Bintje tubers) from farmers, while their father Roger Mylle heads up
general management. He is assisted by Johann Allaert, who takes care of
sales. The plant contains two chip lines which are capable of turning
out 16 tons of finished product per hour under normal conditions This article is about the philosophical argument; for normal conditions in the sense of standards see the corresponding articles, e.g. Standard conditions for temperature and pressure. . An
additional eight tons per hour can be managed, if required. More than
50,000 tons were packed in 1999, of which 90% was shipped to 28
countries beyond Belgium.

&quot;We are very export-minded,&quot; said Mylle. &quot;Working in
cooperation with frozen vegetable supplier Dicogel in nearby Staden, our
products are distributed throughout Europe, Central and South America.
We are now looking to extend our reach to the Far East and other distant
markets.&quot;

While frozen potato products account for approximately 80% of
Mydibel&apos;s sales, strong growth is seen on the chilled side. Both
frozen and chilled lines are available in standard 1 kilo, 2.5kg and 5kg
bags.

Benelux Green Vegelable Scene

The big news from Westrozebeke, Belgium-headquartered Pinguin NV
(Fax: 32-51-77-83-82) last year was an initial public offering of 30% of
its shares on the stock exchange in June, which raised BFR ( B ig F ast R outer) A routing switch (or switch router). See layer 3 switch.  630 million
(approximately US $16 million). Seventy percent of the company remains
in the hands of family members, with second generation representative
Herwig Dejonghe still firmly at the wheel as general manager.

&quot;We are the first vegetable company to go public, which
certainly came as a surprise to our competitors,&quot; said Dejonghe.
&quot;These days a great deal of capital is needed to assure continued
growth in our rapidly evolving markets, and we surely intend to keep on
expanding.&quot;

He knows about the expense of modernizing all too well, having
invested 350 million francs (US $9 million) in totally revamping
Pinguin&apos;s Langemark factory and building a brand new coldstore. The
facility accounts for approximately 30% of the company&apos;s 115,000
tons of annual production. IQF IQF Individually Quick Frozen (food processing) 
IQF International Quilt Festival
IQF Intrinsic Quality Factor (EIA-440/A) 
IQF Interactive Query Facility
IQF Integra Query File  vegetables in sauce and other value-added
items are produced there.

This year a new tunnel freezer will be installed at the larger
Westrozebeke plant. Two old processing lines will be replaced with a
single line capable of running 20 tons per hour. &quot;This will assure
that we have state-of-the-art capability for the next five years,&quot;
said Dejonghe.

The managing director sees his company evolving from a European
company to a truly global operation with an emphasis on what he calls
&quot;value-added, ready-to-eat components and vegetable meal
solutions.&quot; As such, Pinguin&apos;s sales and marketing staff has
been almost quadrupled from four to 15 persons. Indeed, an office has
been set up in Beijing under the direction of Zhao Zhenshou (Fax:
86-10-646-867-40) to pursue opportunities in the PRC.

&quot;We are not only sourcing from China, we are selling there
too,&quot; said Dejonghe. &quot;The first container, containing mainly
frozen peas, has already been shipped.&quot;

As for the current supply situation in Europe, the Pinguin
executive said that it was stable as 1999 saw normal harvest levels
devoid of real disasters. He elaborated:

* The pea pea,  hardy, annual, climbing leguminous plant ( Pisum sativum ) of the family Leguminosae (pulse family), grown for food by humans at least since the early Bronze Age; no longer known in the wild form.  crop was fair. Since carryover from the year before was
low, just enough stock entered to stream to take care of needs.

* The cauliflower cauliflower   (kô`lĭflou&apos;ər, käl`ĭ–) , variety of cabbage, with an edible head of condensed flowers and flower stems. Broccoli is the horticultural variety ( botrytis ); both were cultivated in Roman times.  harvest was good, though not great.

* Beans, while problematic in August, ended the season in fine
form.

* Sprouts sprout  
 v. sprout·ed , sprout·ing , sprouts 

 v. intr. 
 1. To begin to grow; give off shoots or buds.

 2. To emerge and develop rapidly.

 v. tr. , for which there was no carryover, seemed to be abundant
at first. But in the end the harvest was average.

&quot;Except for baby carrots In North America the term baby carrot is commonly applied to either miniature carrots harvested before their roots develop or adult carrots chopped into smaller pieces. Taking fully grown carrots and chopping them into smaller pieces was the idea of California farmer Mike Yurosek. , there are no major vegetable
shortages,&quot; said Dejonghe. &quot;Still, the pressure on prices was
a bit stronger in 1999. I don&apos;t understand why some processors saw
fit to begin cutting prices already in October at the Anuga.&quot;

Ardovries: No. 1 in Vegetables

Roger Maes, sales manager sales manager   n → gerente m/f de ventas 

 sales manager   n → directeur commercial 

 sales manager  sale n →  of Ardovries NV in nearby Ardooie,
Belgium, pretty much agreed with the supply assessment made by his
colleague at Pinguin. &quot;There are no quality problems to speak of,
and availability is generally good though there is no excess of
spinach,&quot; he commented. &quot;As for baby carrots, demand is very
high and yields are not as expected both quantity- and
quality-wise.&quot;

Suggesting that shortages of baby carrots were real, as evidenced
by firm prices, the sales manager was confident that all contracts would
be honored by Ardovries. &quot;We might have an advantage because we run
a dedicated carrot line, continuously guaranteeing us substantial
overall volumes. Exports are going worldwide.&quot;

Elsewhere outside of Europe, business in Latin America is
developing nicely for the company. It is now engaged commercially with a
South American producer of frozen vegetables Frozen vegatables (also freeze-dried vegetables ) are commercially packaged vegetables that are sold in the frozen section of the store, usually packaged in either rectangular boxes or plastic bags. . Furthermore, business is
starting to bounce back in Brazil following the downturn of imports last
year caused by a meltdown meltdown 

Occurrence in which a huge amount of thermal energy and radiation is released as a result of an uncontrolled chain reaction in a nuclear power reactor. The chain reaction that occurs in the reactor&apos;s core must be carefully regulated by control rods, which absorb  of the nation&apos;s currency.

The sales manager sees an overall trend toward greater use of
vegetable blends, coated products, stir-fry items and other value-added
products in developed markets. Demand for organic offerings continues to
grow, though perhaps at a lower pace than some had hoped.

For some time now Ardovries has offered a Bio range of beans in
450g retail packs, as well as soup vegetables, leaf spinach and garden
peas in 600g packs. The company&apos;s Okkohof line of organically grown
vegetables, which is geared to large catering kitchen operations,
features beans, cauliflower, celery celery,  biennial plant ( Apium graveolens ) of the family Umbelliferae (parsley family), of wide distribution in the wild state throughout the north temperate Old World and much cultivated also in America. , peas, spinach and carrots.

&quot;Retail sales are fairly predictable, as a certain percentage
of the population is prepared to pay more for organics for health
reasons. And certainly the presence of upscale private label organic
products is expanding,&quot; said Maes. &quot;The sales effort is a
little more challenging on the catering side, where menu planners with
fixed budgets tend to hesitate when it comes to paying premium
prices.&quot;

Meanwhile Ardovries -- which with 240,000 tons of frozen vegetables
production and sales of US $240 million in 1999, is ranked No. 1 in
Europe -- will spend a good deal of money to upgrade plant and equipment
in Y2K -- same as in 1999. This year&apos;s investments will, in part,
go to increasing capacity of certain products, improving quality
control, and boosting cold storage capacity in the UK (see story on page
68) and Belgium.

On the new product front, buyers can expect to see a number of
innovations unveiled toward the latter part of the year. Along the way,
don&apos;t be surprised if the long-standing red and yellow ARDO brand
logo gets spruced up. &quot;We plan to phase in a new look in the near
future,&quot; said Maes.

Oerlemans Gears Up Bio Unique

The big news coming from Venlo-Holland-headquartered Oerlemans
Foods BV is the introduction of a completely renovated assortment of Bio
Unique products for 2000. The &quot;fresh frozen,&quot; organically
grown range includes such offerings as green beans green beans 
 Noun, pl 

long narrow green beans that are cooked and eaten as a vegetable , red cabbage,
cauliflower, sliced and diced carrots, corn and oven-ready french fries
in 450g and 600g retail packs which have been redesigned to sport the
new Oerlemans logo.

&quot;Our goal is to make Oerlemans a leading A brand in
Holland&apos;s expanding retail organic vegetable segment. By March we
should have 50% distribution of our line in supermarkets,&quot; said
Maurice Koolen, marketing manager. &quot;By September we aim to enhance
the line further by launching value-added organic vegetables.&quot;

Looking at the overall vegetable and fruit supply situation [which
is reported in greater detail on page 71], Huub Munten reported that the
harvests of most crops came in as expected. &quot;However, there is not
much overstock o·ver·stock  
 tr.v. o·ver·stocked , o·ver·stock·ing , o·ver·stocks 
To stock more of (something) than necessary or desirable.

 n. 
An excessive supply.

 Verb 1.  either,&quot; added the sales director for industrial
accounts.

In the past year it has not so much been growing conditions as
selling conditions that have negatively affected the market. &quot;We
can&apos;t complain about volume sales, which are good,&quot; said
Munten. &quot;The problem is that pressure on prices hasn&apos;t let up.
This is largely because certain competitors have increased capacity and
are disrupting the market. Add to that greater concentration on the
retail buying side and the result is not difficult to figure.&quot;

Nonetheless, the Oerlemans sales director perseveres. &quot;We are
a strong and reliable supplier of nutritious and healthy products -- but
not at any price,&quot; he continued. &quot;For the last five years
Dutch farmers who produce vegetables for industrial processing have made
little or no profit. This can&apos;t go on much longer.&quot;

Koolen said that Oerlemans is looking to broaden its customer base
for blended products. &quot;We want to go global by providing recipes
with local appeal,&quot; he said. &quot;Already we have more than 150
mixes and assortments on offer. More will come in the future, made
especially to appeal to specific regional tastes.&quot;

McCain to Close Old Factory; Buys Pizza Company

While steadily expanding plant capacity in other locations, McCain
Foods has decided to discontinue production at its aging factory in
Waspik, Holland. The facility, which suffered damage from a fire last
January, produces relatively low output of about 10,000 tons of finished
potato products per annum -- mostly speciality items such as Dollar
Chips.

It will close on May 1. Approximately 20 employees are expected to
be shifted to McCain&apos;s other plants in Holland.

Management cited high costs of modernizing the factory as its
primary reason for ceasing production. After all numbers were crunched,
the grand total came in about 50% greater than had been anticipated. Add
to that an extra 11 million guilders needed for environmental and fire
safeguards, and the result would be a plant operating at a 15% premium
over other McCain factories in the Netherlands.

The company&apos;s strategy to put more emphasis on expanding
business in southern

Europe also figured into the decision. Director Hans Sterkenburg told
Agrarisch Dagblad (a Dutch agriculture newspaper) that construction of a
new factory in that region will begin within the next year.

Meanwhile, on the other side of the Atlantic, McCain Foods
announced the acquisition of Aloro Foods Inc. of Ontario. The Canadian
manufacturer of frozen pizza products has annual sales approaching $10
million. CEO (1) ( C hief E xecutive O fficer) The highest individual in command of an organization. Typically the president of the company, the CEO reports to the Chairman of the Board.  Arnold Park said that the plant in Mississauga, which
employs 80, will continue to operate on a business-as-usual basis.

RELATED ARTICLE: Royal Ahold a·hold  
 n. 
Hold; grip: &quot;I knew I could make it all right if I got . . . back to the hotel and got ahold of that bottle of brandy&quot;   Jimmy Breslin.    of Netherlands Buys into Swedish
Retailer

Royal Ahold, the international food retailing conglomerate, has
acquired a 50% interest in the ICA Ica   (ē`kä) , city (1993 pop. 108,724), capital of Ica dept., SW Peru, on the Pan-American Highway. It is a commercial center for the cotton, wool, and wine produced in the region. There are several summer resorts nearby.  Group, the largest food retailer in
Scandinavia.

Ahold paid 1.8 billion euros ($1.83 billion) for the Swedish chain,
which has 3,100 stores in a variety of formats and grossed 6.7 billion
enros last year. ICA has 35% of the market in Sweden and 27.7% in
Norway.

The acquisition boosted Ahold&apos;s European sales to 19 billion
euros, and gives the Dutch mega-retailer a chance to expand further into
the Baltic states Baltic states,  the countries of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, bordering on the eastern coast of the Baltic Sea. Formed in 1918, they remained independent republics until their involuntary incorporation in 1940 into the USSR. They regained their independence in Sept. , where ICA has opened stores since the collapse of the
Soviet Union. Ahold also owns several chains in the United States United States,  officially United States of America, republic (2005 est. pop. 295,734,000), 3,539,227 sq mi (9,166,598 sq km), North America. The United States is the world&apos;s third largest country in population and the fourth largest country in area.  and
the Pacific Rim Pacific Rim,  term used to describe the nations bordering the Pacific Ocean and the island countries situated in it. In the post–World War II era, the Pacific Rim has become an increasingly important and interconnected economic region. .

RELATED ARTICLE: Strategic Global Potato Alliance Formed By
USA&apos;s Simplot and Dutch Farm Frites

A Global Potato Alliance to share vital information has been formed
by two of the world&apos;s largest potato processors -- J. R. Simplot John Richard &quot;Jack&quot; Simplot (born January 4 1909) is the founder of the J. R. Simplot Company, an agricultural supplier specializing in potato products. In 2007 he was estimated to be the 214th richest person in America, with $3.6 billion.  Company, based in Boise, Idaho “Boise”redirects here. For other uses, see Boise (disambiguation).

 Boise is the capital and most populous city of the U.S. state of Idaho. It is the county seat of Ada County and the principal city of the Boise metropolitan area. , USA, and Farm Frites, headquartered in
Oudenhoorn, the Netherlands.

The coalition is aimed at enabling both companies to defend and
improve their positions in existing markets through comprehensive
technology exchanges and further penetrate emerging markets through
formal joint operations A general term to describe military actions conducted by joint forces or by Service forces in relationships (e.g., support, coordinating authority) which, of themselves, do not create joint forces. .

The alliance partners will share information involving raw produce
supply, operations and processing efficiencies, product development,
environmental protection and other areas of importance. The two firms,
which will continue to be independent organizations, operate 18 potato
processing plants on five continents.

&quot;There is no geographical overlap of operations or markets
between the two companies,&quot; said Simplot Food Group President Jim
Munyon. &quot;When you combine our capabilities, we cover virtually the
entire world.&quot; The alliance partners reportedly account for nearly
one-fourth of the world&apos;s potato processing production capacity.

&quot;We are very pleased to be allied with Simplot,&quot; said
Gerrit de Bruijne, Farm Frites president. &quot;Clients today
increasingly want to do business with global suppliers, which is exactly
what we are.&quot;

Simplot&apos;s businesses are concentrated in North America North America,  third largest continent (1990 est. pop. 365,000,000), c.9,400,000 sq mi (24,346,000 sq km), the northern of the two continents of the Western Hemisphere. , but
the firm also has substantial food processing Food processing is the set of methods and techniques used to transform raw ingredients into food for consumption by humans or animals. The food processing industry utilises these processes.  operations in Australia
and smaller facilities in China and Indonesia. Similarly, Farm Frites
has branched out from its primary business base in Europe with
production facilities in Egypt and Argentina.

&quot;This alliance will provide customers all assured supply on a
global scale and the opportunity for account management through a single
contact,&quot; said Pieter de Bruijne, Farm Frites managing director.
&quot;We will be able to leverage our combined global capabilities to
deliver local solutions.&quot;

Each company will benefit from the complimentary strengths of the
other to create enhanced value for customers, according to according to 
 prep. 
 1. As stated or indicated by; on the authority of: according to historians. 

 2. In keeping with: according to instructions. 

 3.  Munyon.
&quot;We are merging the best of American and European potato
expertise,&quot; he said.

Simplot is a diversified agribusiness agribusiness 

Agriculture operated by business; specifically, that part of a modern national economy devoted to the production, processing, and distribution of food and fibre products and byproducts.  finn with substantial
holdings in food processing, fertilizer manufacturing, cattle feeding Different cattle feeding production systems have separate advantages and disadvantages. All cows have a diet that is composed of at least some forage (grass, legumes, or silage). In fact most beef cattle are raised on pasture until they reach a year of age. ,
and other agriculture-related businesses. Its food business covers
frozen potatoes, vegetables, guacamole, meats, bakery, fish and sauces.

The company turns out more than two billion pounds of french flies
and other frozen potato products a year, and employs more than 12,000
people in the USA, Canada, Mexico, Australia and the Pacific Rim. Annual
sales approach $3 billion.

Farm Frites is Europe&apos;s third-largest manufacturer and
marketer of frozen and chilled potato products. The company has about
1,600 employees and annually produces almost one billion pounds of
finished potato products worldwide.

&quot;Foodservice and retail buyers on the Continent today are
demanding Euro-sourcing. As nine of the world&apos;s Top 10 retail
chains are currently European, we have no doubt that global-sourcing
requirements will soon loom larger,&quot; said Albert van der Vlies,
Farm Frites director of marketing and sales. &quot;So the fit with
Simplot is ideal -- both in terms of one company complimenting the other
and in similar corporate culture.&quot;

Simplot and Farm Frites have remarkably comparable histories, with
founders J. R. Simplot and Gerrit de Bruijne striking out on their own
at an early age and building a large, privately held company privately held company 

A firm whose shares are held within a relatively small circle of owners and are not traded publicly.  from
scratch.

RELATED ARTICLE: Nestle Makes It Official, Unloads Findus As Part
of European QFF Restructuring

Nestle SA, world&apos;s largest food company, clinched a deal in
October sell part of its European frozen food business and nearly all of
its Findus brand to a U.S.-Swedish investment group.

Analysts said the sale to EQT EQT Environmental Qualification Test
EQT Engine Qualification Test
EQT Engineering Qualification Testing
EQT Equatorial Crossing Time
EQT Emotional Quotient Theory
EQT Engineer Qualification Tables  Scandinavia BV brought Nestle less
than the businesses&apos; annual turnover of 900 million Swiss francs Noun 1. Swiss franc - the basic unit of money in Switzerland
franc - the basic monetary unit in many countries; equal to 100 centimes

centime - a fractional monetary unit of several countries: France and Algeria and Belgium and Burkina Faso and Burundi and  ($884 million) -- evidence that Nestle was eager to get out of
low-margin business, even if it included a well-known brand like Findus.

Peter Brabeck, Nestle chief executive, who launched his career by
driving a Findus truck, had earlier announced that the company
didn&apos;t have any sentimental attachment to the Findus brand, which
is largely identified with commodity vegetable, fruit and seafood
products,

&quot;The transaction shows that Nestle no longer has any sacred
cows sacred cow 
 n. 
One that is immune from criticism, often unreasonably so: &quot;The need for widespread secrecy has become a sacred cow&quot;   Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists. ,&quot; observed Chris Burger, a Bank Sarasin analyst. &quot;The
company&apos;s strategy will be to divest To deprive or take away. 

 Divest is usually used in reference to the relinquishment of authority, power, property, or title. If, for example, an individual is disinherited, he or she is divested of the right to inherit money.  businesses with low added
value Added value in financial analysis of shares is to be distinguished from value added. Used as a measure of shareholder value, calculated using the formula:

 Added Value = Sales - Purchases - Labour Costs - Capital Costs  and low margins and invest in those with high added value and high
margins.&quot;

The deal includes all of Nestle&apos;s frozen food activities in
Britain and Scandinavia as well as parts of the business -- mainly
vegetables and fish -- in five European countries, Nestle said. Some 14
factories in seven countries would change hands and about 3,500
employees would get a new employer. It gave no financial terms.

The Findus brand will become the property of EQT Scandinavia
worldwide, except for Switzerland and Italy. The deal is subject to
regulatory approval. The sale was part of Nestle&apos;s restructuring of
its European frozen food business to focus on the prepared dishes, snack
and pizza markets.

Sarasin&apos;s Burger estimated that the sale price was less than
the business turnover of 900 million Swiss francs. He left his earnings
estimates and &quot;market performer&quot; rating for Nestle stock
unchanged.

Bank Julius Baer analyst James Amoroso Am`o`ro´so 

 n. 1. A lover; a man enamored.
 adv. 1. (Mus.) In a soft, tender, amatory style.  said the deal would be
neutral for earnings overall because the reduction of net debt would
offset the loss of earnings before interest and tax of 50 million francs
or more. He added that it was surprising that Nestle was disposing of
the Findus brand in France, where it had a strong market position.

RELATED ARTICLE: McCain Building New Plants From Argentina to
France

McCain Argentina S.A. will double the size of its potato processing
plant at Balcarce. McCain France, meanwhile, will expand a plant at
Matougues. The projects will cost $68.4 million and $75 million,
respectively.

Construction began last month on the Argentine project, which
involves a second french fry line with a capacity of 15 tons an hour,
bringing total capacity to 27 tons an hour. Work was about to get under
way at press time on the French plant, capacity of which will increase
from 15 to 25 tons an hour.

The French plant is scheduled to start production before the close
of the year 2000. It will be sourcing potatoes from 4,500 hectares in
the Champagne--Ardennes region and in Aisne department. The expanded
Argentine plant will include an ultramodern 2,800-square meter potato
receiving and grading facility and additional office space as well as
production.

Based in Florenceville, New Brunswick The village of Florenceville is located on the banks of the St. John River, in Carleton County in the Canadian province of New Brunswick.

Florenceville was originally known as Buttermilk Creek. , Canada, the McCain Group
registered $5.6 billion in sales for the year ended June 30, 1999, a
9.5% increase over fiscal 1998. European and South American sales had a
lot to do with the gain, according to Harrison McCain Harrison McCain , CC, ONB, (November 3, 1927–March 18, 2004) was a Canadian businessman, co-founder of McCain Foods Limited.

Born in Florenceville, New Brunswick, he was the co-founder, along with his brothers Andrew, Robert and Wallace, of McCain Foods. , chairman of the
company. Worldwide, McCain has the capacity to produce a million tons of
fries every hour.

RELATED ARTICLE: Shearway Plans New Office, Coldstore at 10-Acre
Site

Ardovries Shearway Ltd., Headcorn, Kent, UK, plans to build a new
head office and coldstore at a recently-acquired 10-acre site between
Ashford and Maidstone. Production will remain at Headcorn.

The refrigerated warehouse will have a capacity of 10,000 pallets.
Together with the new headquarters building, it will cost 6 [pounds
sterling] million. Shearway, a subsidiary of the Belgian Ardovries NV,
is the second largest frozen fruit and vegetable specialist in the UK.
It already had a 4,000-pallet cold store at Headcorn.

&quot;Sales have almost doubled over the last five years, and the
new coldstore will alleviate a long-standing and intensifying storage
problem for the company,&quot; said Tony Goodson, managing director.
&quot;We will also be providing a modern and more spacious work
environment for our staff for the new millennium.&quot;

RELATED ARTICLE: Fruit, Vegetable Supplies OK; Poor Crops, Dollar
Daze Hit Some

Well, at least there aren&apos;t any glassy peas or carrots to
worry about in Europe. But there are shortages in onions and carrots and
potential shortages in other items. In a couple of cases, asparagus asparagus,  perennial garden vegetable ( Asparagus officinalis ) of the family Liliaceae (lily family), native to the E Mediterranean area and now naturalized over much of the world.  and broccoli broccoli   (brŏk`əlē)  [Ital.,=sprouts], variety of cabbage grown for the edible immature flower panicles. It is the same variety ( Brassica oleracea botrytis ) as the cauliflower and is similarly cultivated. , a strong dollar is running up prices.

That was the word in late December from Oerlemans Foods. Based in
the Netherlands (Fax: 31-77-3821-448), Oerlemans has has its fingers on
the pulse of the frozen vegetable and fruit markets. Most of the recent
news has been good.

For the first time, the Oerlemans bulletin -- issued by managing
director Jan Hulsen -- also reported separately on organic vegetables, a
segment in which it is establishing a presence with the Bio Unique
brand. Here too, recent news is generally good.

Organic carrot harvest began just in time to fill the pipeline for
diced carrots, but volume and quality both seem adequate. No problems
were reported for corn or sliced carrots, while the autumn harvest for
organic cauliflower appeared normal.

As for traditional vegetables, first the mixed or not-so-good news:

* Asparagus. Harvest was normal in both quantity and quality, but
prices are increasing because of the stronger dollar.

* Brocolli. As before, broccoli from South America continues to be
expensive on account of the high dollar rate. Europe is thus relying on
Spain as an alternative supplier.

* Onions. As previously reported, the 1999 crop was 30% short due
to a severe drought last summer in Poland. Fresh onion prices are
rising, and the market is becoming so turbulent that it is impossible to
predict what prices will be like by March.

* Brussels sprouts Brussels sprouts,  variety ( gemmifera ) of cabbage producing small edible heads (sprouts) along the stem. It is cultivated like cabbage and was first developed in Belgium and France in the 18th cent. . Harvesting had just begun at press time, but
yields were forecast to be good. Just in time, too; the stocks were
virtually exhausted. Prices have now stabilized, and supplies should be
sufficient -- provided good weather holds up.

* Peppers. Prices have been fairly stable in both Spain and Turkey,
and the market is quiet. But prices are beginning to inch up, because
Turkish production was far less than in previous years.

* Carrots. With stocks of baby carrots virtually gone, and the
autumn crop coming in at only 80%, demand is expected to increase, but
still short of demand. Sliced carrot prices are stable, despite
substantial demand, thanks to a good crop. Diced and strip items are no
longer scarce, thanks to a winter carrot harvest that made up for last
year&apos;s short supply -- this despite a smaller crop in Poland.

* Spinach. The autumn crop came in, and was reasonably good. Stocks
are sufficient.

* Cauliflower. The autumn harvest was short and hectic, thanks to
good weather. Stocks are adequate.

* Peas. Despite good crops, there isn&apos;t any downward pressure
on prices, thanks to increased demand from outside Western Europe Western Europe 

The countries of western Europe, especially those that are allied with the United States and Canada in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (established 1949 and usually known as NATO). .

* Whole and cut green beans. The autumn crop was good, and stocks
will easily last until the next harvest.

* Corn. The crop was normal, but prices are under pressure.

* Cabbage products. Harvests were good for kale kale,   borecole   (bôr`kōl) , and collards,  common names for nonheading, hardy types of cabbage (var. , red cabbage and savoy cabbage Noun 1. savoy cabbage - cabbage plant with a compact head of crinkled leaves
Brassica oleracea capitata, head cabbage, head cabbage plant - any of various cultivated cabbage plants having a short thick stalk and large compact head of edible usually green leaves , and stocks are sufficient.

* Celery. Following 1998&apos;s poor crop, the 1999 harvest
appeared to be sufficient at press time, and no further problems are
anticipated before the 2000 crop comes in.

In fruits, there was bad news in some items.

* Raspberries. A poor crop in Serbia brought a substantial price
increase, and forced importers to turn to Chile -- where a rising dollar
combined with the European situation is making for further substantial
price increases.

* Blueberries. THe cupboard was bare when harvests came in from
Poland, Russia and Scandinavia -- only those crops were 10-20% short,
due to a late frost in May followed by a dry summer. Prices are rising
fast, and even imports from Canada and the USA won&apos;t change that.

* Black currants. Prices have been so low in past years that
farmers gave up planting them. Now production is falling short of
demand, and prices are rising.

* Strawberries. Shhhh! The market is quiet after a reasonably good
harvest. In fact, prices are expected to slip below last year&apos;s
levels.

* Sour cherries. The harvest was good and the market is quiet, but
with some downward pressure on prices.

* Blackberries, apples, red, currants, plums. Stable prices.

Checking Out Equipment Suppliers in Benelux

Quick Frozen Foods International arrived at the Bakel,
Holland-headquarters of Convenience Food Systems ( CFS CFS 
 abbr. 
chronic fatigue syndrome

 CFS, 
 n.pr See syndrome, chronic fatigue.
 CFS  Chronic fatigue syndrome, see there ) just in time for
lunch. This was hardly coincidental co·in·ci·den·tal  
 adj. 
 1. Occurring as or resulting from coincidence.

 2. Happening or existing at the same time.

 
 co·in , as the editors were quite aware
that the company&apos;s dining room serves up products formulated in the
on-site technology center. On any given day the appetizing menu may
feature anything from grilled chicken fillets or Cordon bleu cor·don bleu  
 n. pl. cor·dons bleus 
A person highly distinguished in a field, especially a master chef.

 
[French : cordon , ribbon + bleu , blue . , to shrimp tempura Tempura - Language based on temporal logic. &quot;Executing Temporal Logic Programs&quot;, B. Moszkowski, Camb U Press 1986. , fish kebabs, homestyle schnitzel schnit·zel  
 n. 
A thin cutlet of veal, usually seasoned, that is dipped in batter and fried.

 
[German, from Middle High German snitzel , diminutive of sniz , slice , from snitzen , potato croquettes, breaded
mushrooms or cauliflower.

John-Ole Hansen joined us for the mid-day meal. As the president
and chief executive officer of perhaps the world&apos;s largest provider
of turnkey food processing systems, QFFI was keen to hear his take on
the state of the global marketplace. A year-in-review synopsis follows:

By and large, 1999 results were positive -- especially in the area
of supplying solutions to manufacturers of home meal replacement ( HMR HMR Hazardous Materials Regulations
HMR Human Resources
HMR Home Meal Replacement
HMR Hamrun (postal locality, Malta) 
HMR Hôpital Maisonneuve-Rosemont (Montréal, Canada)   )
dishes and components. Business picked up nicely in the second half of
the year, following a slow start attributed largely to economic
slowdowns in Russia, China and Latin America.

The ruble meltdown and hard currency controls implemented in Russia
resulted in an almost overnight disappearance in demand for imports of
processed foods, recalled Hansen. Elsewhere, activity stalled in China,
where Western-style supermarkets struggled for profitability and the
once rapid-expansion of fast food restaurants slowed down appreciably.

On the other hand, &quot;business in the North American North American

named after North America.
 
 North American blastomycosis 
see North American blastomycosis.

 North American cattle tick 
see boophilus annulatus .  market was
good throughout the year,&quot; reported Hansen. He added that continued
growth in the HMR and chilled food Chilled foods are prepared foods stored at refrigeration temperatures (at or below 8°C). They have been available in the United Kingdom and many other industrialised countries since the 1960s.  segment translated to a steady stream
of orders.

In a way, CFS (Fax: 31-492-343-969) is to food processors what HMRs
are to consumers: a convenient and complete solution to their needs. The
company supplies everything from single-unit continuous fryers and
freezers to compact thermoformer packaging lines and complete production
lines. (See story about integrated installation for Eyckeler&amp;Malt
on this page.). Its highly-regard brand names range from Kramer + Grebe grebe   (grēb) , common name for swimming birds found on or near quiet waters in most parts of the world. Grebes resemble the loon and the duck; they have short wings, vestigial tails, and long, individually webbed toes on feet that are set far back  and Koppens to Tiromat, TiroPak and Aquarius.

CFS systems are found in plants manufacturing value-added meat,
poultry, vegetable, cheese, fish and seafood products. Machinery
components run the gamut from grinders, mixers, batchers and cutters to
equipment for forming and portioning, pre-dusting, battering, breading,
frying, grilling, cooling and freezing.

On the packaging end, CFS supplies high-performance thermoformers,
tray sealers, vertical form, fill and seal machines, and flow wrappers In data mining and treatment learning, wrappers were used by Ron Kohavi and George John. Their idea was to wrap their treatments learners in a preprocessor that would search to make subsets from the current set of attributes. .
To complete the system, packaging material solutions are offered to
producers of frozen, non-frozen, MAP- and vacuum-packed products.

An opportunity to &quot;test before you invest&quot; is something
that Convenience Food Systems makes available at its technology centers
in the Netherlands, Germany and the USA. There clients are able to make
trial runs of recipe and packaging concepts, and in so doing determine
which equipment and packaging concept best suit their needs.

In recent years CFS has intensified efforts to enhance processing,
efficiency and safety features. &quot;We have become a software company
in the process, as a big part of our R&amp;D goes into software
solutions,&quot; said Hansen. &quot;The emphasis is not only on
providing productivity, but in building systems which incorporate total
traceability in terms of when, where and under what conditions a product
is produced.

Looking ahead, the president predicted that food safety issues will
continue to stimulate investment in risk-free processing systems.
&quot;In the near future food will be produced with the same critical
attention to detail as are pharmaceuticals,&quot; he commented.
&quot;Consumers want 100% safety, and we certainly intend to do our part
to make it so.&quot;

Big Order for Bosch

A tour of the Robert Bosch Robert Bosch (September 23, 1861 - March 12, 1942) was a German industrialist, founder of Robert Bosch GmbH. Biography 
Bosch was born in Albeck, a village to the northeast of Ulm in southern Germany. He was the eleventh of twelve children.  Verpakkingsmachines BV factory in Weert,
Holland, on Dec. 9 found technicians hard at work completing a major
order for a North American client. They were in the final stages of a
year-long job which called for the manufacture and installation of 56
vertical bag form, fill and seal machines at plants in the United
States.

&quot;It&apos;s been a busy time for us,&quot; said Bert Jan
Hardenbol, marketing manager (Fax: 31-495-574094), as he showed QFFI
editors around the shop floor. &quot;The SVB ( S witched V ideo B roadcast) See switched video.  3601 R model machines will
run 5-lb (2.26kg) heat-sealed laminated bags at a rate of 40 per minute
-- which is fast for such a big stand-up stand·up  or stand-up 
 adj. 
 1. Standing erect; upright: a standup collar. 

 2. Taken, done, or used while standing: a standup supper; a standup bar. , recloseable pack. It features
stabilized corner sealing as well as TransZip, which makes for easy
opening and reclosing.&quot;

A forming collar inside the stainless steel stainless steel:  see steel. stainless steel 

Any of a family of alloy steels usually containing 10–30% chromium. The presence of chromium, together with low carbon content, gives remarkable resistance to corrosion and heat.  machine shapes the
infeed packaging material. A simplified corner forming process requires
no adjustments. All the machines bought by the customer, a major
manufacturer of frozen food products, are equipped with the ability to
apply Trans-Zip reclosure strips on the the web material (laminates or
PE) directly in front of the forming set. All are computer controlled
and touch screen operated.

Bosch makes another machine specifically designed for continuously
applying the zipper zipper 

Device for binding the edges of an opening, as on a garment or a bag. A zipper consists of two strips of material with metal or plastic teeth along the edges, and a sliding piece that interlocks the teeth when moved in one direction and separates them again when moved  material at rates of up to 80 units per minute.
It&apos;s the SKV SKV Sport Und Kulturverein (St. Oswald) 
SKV Socket Version 3600L Trans-Zip model, which has made believers of a
number of frozen vegetable and potato producers on the Continent.

Zipper bags provide a convenience that is gaining popularity in
northern Europe. It enables consumers to remove only as much product as
is needed, with the assurance that what&apos;s left in the freezer will
remain well protected.

As a unit of diversified, Stuttgart, Germany-headquartered Robert
Bosch GmbH Robert Bosch GmbH [1] is a German corporation which was started in 1886 by Robert Bosch in Stuttgart, Germany. [2] 

Bosch businesses include:
 automotive parts and systems supplier; [2] 
  -- which had turnover of DM 55 billion (over US $30 billion)
last year -- the Dutch operation is exclusively engaged in engineering
and building vertical form, fill and seal packaging equipment. Designs
specified in Holland are also assembled at other Bosch factories in the
USA, Brazil, Japan and India.

In recent years the packaging division has taken steps to better globalize glob·al·ize  
 tr.v. glob·al·ized , glob·al·iz·ing , glob·al·iz·es 
To make global or worldwide in scope or application.

 
 glob  its R&amp;D, sales and marketing efforts. Personnel from
abroad are brought to the Weert facility for training, just as Dutch and
European staffers are sent overseas to participate in team-building
workshops. In addition to the bonding advantages reaped from this kind
of cross-cultural interaction, practical payoffs are also anticipated.
Indeed, Bosch engineers have taken to the drawing board to create a
simpler, lower-cost packaging machine model that may appeal to small-
and mid-size companies. The SVE SVE

special visceral efferent. 2510 model, now available in stainless
steel, is especially suited for the vegetable and seafood sectors.

Good Futura for BMV BMV Bolsa Mexicana de Valores
BMV Bureau of Motor Vehicles
BMV Bundesministerium für Verkehr (German: Federal Ministry of Transport) 
BMV Below Market Value
BMV Brome Mosaic Virus
BMV Bedside Medication Verification  

One year after implementation of a management restructuring at
Barco Machine Vision (BMV), Marc van Gerven was pleased to report that
all is going according to plan. &quot;We have met our sales projections
for 1999,&quot; the marketing manager told QFFI on Nov. 30.

While Van Gerven remains based in Eindhoven, Holland (e-mail:
pulsarr@barco.com) at the Barco Pulsarr industrial research center,
administration functions have been consolidated at the Barco Elbicon
office in Aarschot, Belgium (e-mail: elbicon@barco.com).

Overseas, the West Sacramento, Calif., USA office is headed up by
Rex Hawley, sales director (e-mail: machine.vision.na@barco.com).

BMV, a business unit of the diversified Barco Group, generated
turnover of 26.2 million euros in 1998. The company manufactures and
markets a number of sorting and inspection systems to the food
processing industry. In the frozen sector, it is especially active in
the vegetable, potato and seafood areas. On the dry side, its forte is
nuts and raisins as well as non-food applications.

With the recent unveiling of the Elbiscan Futura x-ray system, the
company is now poised to further penetrate the meat, poultry and ready
meal segments. Combining x-ray technology with advanced image processing image processing 

Set of computational techniques for analyzing, enhancing, compressing, and reconstructing images. Its main components are importing, in which an image is captured through scanning or digital photography; analysis and manipulation of the image, accomplished  and recognition software, the optical sorting equipment is able to
detect small foreign objects and high-density contaminants such as
glass, metal, stone and bone. Undesirable material is automatically
rejected from the production line.

Here&apos;s how the Futura works: Food product is conveyed between
an x-ray source and a receiver. X-rays pass through or are partially
absorbed by the products or contaminants. The varying intensities of
x-rays received by the detector is then combined into a viewable image The actual diagonal image on a monitor screen. For a long time, CRT measurements have been overstated; for example, a 17&quot; CRT is generally between 15&quot; and 15.8&quot; diagonal. On the other hand, flat panel monitors on laptops, and later on desktops, have always provided accurate measurements, ,
which is instantly analyzed by computer. If anything is out of the
ordinary, a signal is sent to remove the deficiency.

&quot;Since introduction at the Interpack, we have already sold a
lot of them, and the future for more Futura sales looks bright,&quot;
said Van Gerven. &quot;Our x-ray department, which really works as a
company within a company, focuses 100% on continually making
improvements in the technology.&quot;

Meanwhile, Barco has great expectations for its new RX-F1020 Dual
Sorter, which pairs CCD cameras See digital camera.  and lasers on one platform. Thus far,
many units have been sold in Europe and in the USA. Cameras are able to
recognize color and shapes, while lasers distinguish texture differences
in all kinds of products. As such, a production line with this kind of
setup will be highly efficient at identifying and sorting out stones,
bones, wood, plastic, metal, golf balls and foliage as well as discoloration dis·col·or·a·tion  
 n. 
 1. 
 a. The act of discoloring.

 b. The condition of being discolored.

 2. A discolored spot, smudge, or area; a stain.

 Noun 1.  such as dark and/or green spots in potatoes or carrots.

Scan data is sent to a computer which directs jets of air to blow
defective product away from the mainstream. It all takes place so
quickly and accurately that good product is rarely disturbed by the
process. The bottom line for frozen food processors is a much improved
yield of high-quality output.

Barco Machine Vision will be exhibiting at a number of important
international food fairs this year, including the Boston Seafood Show,
Snaxpo in Philadelphia, Anuga Foodtec in Cologne, IPA IPA - International Phonetic Alphabet  in Paris, and IEFP IEFP Instituto De Emprego E Formação Profissional (Portugal) 
IEFP International Exposition for Food Processors  in Chicago.

At the Anuga Foodtec, BMV will introduce the next generation
Pulsarr camera sorter -- the MIRA Mira   (mī`rə) , [Lat.,=marvelous], variable star in the constellation Cetus; Bayer designation Omicron Ceti; 1992 position R.A. 2 h 19.0 m , Dec.−3°05&apos;. . Able to scan product from all sides,
the state-of-the-art system features full color and shape recognition
modules, can accommodate skin-on sorting, UV and Ir techniques. It is
designed for subsequent laser add-ons.

New Vision in Air at Kiremko

When QFFI visited the Montfoort, Holland headquarters of Kiremko
Food Processing Equipment (Fax: 31-348-471307) on Dec. 3, the company
had just concluded a week-long open house during which time 62 customers
and potential clients came by to see the recently unveiled Visionair
optical sorting system in action. &quot;It&apos;s been an extremely busy
five-day period,&quot; said Peter Brouwer, managing director.

As a well established specialist supplier of machinery for the
potato and vegetable processing industries, Kiremko is especially known
for a range of machines required to produce french fries, crisps and
byproducts. Its expertise has long run the gamut from transporting and
washing of tubers, to destoning, peeling, cutting, sorting, drying,
frying, coating, cooling, freezing, weighing and packaging.

In the past Kiremko has had to rely on other companies when it came
to installing optical sorting systems. No more. &quot;We see great
potential in being able to offering a complete package,&quot; said Arjan
Brouwer, sales engineer.

The Visionair is equipped with black and white and color cameras
which can be placed in practically any position to scan products moving
on conveyor belts or in free fall, during which time every surface of
the raw material is scanned. Computer software programs are designed for
instant analysis of four sorting thresholds as well as standard shape
recognition and visualization. Other options include infrared,
ultraviolet and laser detection.

Kiremko has collaborated with Best NV of Belgium to offer the laser
scanning option. A laser box allows the Visionair to not only
&quot;see&quot; undesirable elements and color defects in products such
as potatoes and carrots, but even to spot defects that are of the same
natural color as the product itself

A further option with the camera/laser sorter is to mount the
camera behind the freezer in a french fry factory to make one last pass
over the finished product before packaging.

Meanwhile, both Brouwers expressed satisfaction with results
realized in 1999. &quot;Investment in Europe remains steady. In the
United States we are successfully cooperating with Idaho Steel, which
knows that market well. Steam peelers are selling well, as are hot air
ovens for skin-on potato products,&quot; said the managing director.

In developing markets, Kiremko continues to seek and find new
opportunities. &quot;We installed a processing line in Iran last year,
as well as a flake line in China,&quot; noted the sales manager.
&quot;Recently an order came in from India. In time that market will no
doubt grow, as I understand it is now open to imported seed
potatoes.&quot;

 GMF GMF Graphical Modeling Framework
GMF German Marshall Fund
GMF Groupes de Médecine de Famille (French; Quebec, Canada) 
GMF Genetically Modified Food
GMF Gulf of Mexico Foundation  Gouda Peels On

Business levels for GMF Gouda were reported to have been good in
1999. &quot;We did especially well in the potato sector, which
represents about 75% of our turnover,&quot; said Paul van der Schoot.

The Waddinxveen, Holland-based company (Fax: 31-182-619217)
specializes in making potato skin removal equipment and related systems.
Its high-volume Sepa-Stator steam peeler is promoted as being second to
none in reducing peel loss and maximizing product yield. The
&quot;ultra-blast steam exhaust system Noun 1. exhaust system - system consisting of the parts of an engine through which burned gases or steam are discharged
exhaust

automobile engine - the engine that propels an automobile &quot; efficiently removes all condensate condensate,  matter in the form of a gas of atoms, molecules, or elementary particles that have been so chilled that their motion is virtually halted and as a consequence they lose their separate identities and merge into a single entity.  during exposure, thereby eliminating the cooling effect of
the relatively cold condensate touching the spuds.

GMF Gouda also markets a conveyorized Brush-&apos;n-Belt dry peel
remover, which takes away 95% of the peel without the use of water. This
substantially reduces steam exposure time later in the process, as
tubers are made ready for further processing into french fries or other
items.

Potato flake dryers figure prominently in the company&apos;s
product line. As the world&apos;s largest manufacturer of same, it
produces units with capacity up to 500-600kg per hour.

GMF Gouda recently installed a Sepa-Stator/Brush-&apos;n-Belt
combination and flake dryer at the new Aviko factory in Bavaria. They
were among many that have gone to Holland&apos;s leading potato
processing company over the last three decades.

The marketing manager said that GMF Gouda has grown with the potato
processing industries by supplying reliable machines that &quot;prove to
be the best in saving money for customers.&quot;

Success in the potato field has been transferable to the vegetable
patch, where approximately 10% of the company&apos;s revenues are
earned. &quot;Nearly every frozen vegetable processor in Belgium is a
customer of ours,&quot; said Van der Schoot.&quot;

 FAM FAM  5-FU, adriamycin/doxorubicin, mitomycin C Oncology A chemotherapeutic regimen used with varying degrees of failure for advanced gastric CA. See Stomach cancer.  on Cutting Edge

When in March of 1997 the personnel of FAM NV (Fax: 32-2-457-0496)
moved into larger quarters in Kontich, Belgium, there was plenty of room
to spare in which the food reduction equipment specialist could later
expand. &quot;Since then we have grown quite dramatically. Now we are
running out of space,&quot; said Guy Baeten.

The sales manager cited &quot;big investments in the potato
business&quot; as the reason that its high-capacity french fry cutters
are selling well. &quot;Producers are boosting output in both Europe and
North America,&quot; he said, &quot;whether it&apos;s through upgrading
existing lines or by building entirely new factories.&quot;

FAM supplied six heavy duty french fry cutters, for example, to the
new Aviko plant in Germany. Equipped with slicing, circular and crosscut
knives, the FAM ILC-3D models are each capable of hourly cutting 600kg
of 1mm slice-thickness product.

When it comes to french fries, crinkle crin·kle  
 v. crin·kled , crin·kling , crin·kles 

 v. intr. 
 1. To form wrinkles or ripples.

 2. To make a soft crackling sound; rustle.

 v. tr. 
To cause to crinkle.  cuts ranging in size from
6mm to 20mm can be produced at a rate of up to 5,000kg per hour.

In addition to potato products, the equipment may be used to slice
and dice Refers to rearranging data so that it can be viewed from different perspectives. The term is typically used with OLAP databases that present information to the user in the form of multidimensional cubes similar to a 3D spreadsheet. See OLAP.  cabbage for cole slaw slaw  
 n. Chiefly Southern U.S. 
Coleslaw.

 Noun 1. slaw - basically shredded cabbage
coleslaw

salad - food mixtures either arranged on a plate or tossed and served with a moist dressing; usually consisting of , as well as root celery, carrots, eggplant eggplant,  name for Solanum melongena, a large-leaved woody perennial shrub (often grown as an annual herb) of the family Solanaceae (nightshade family), and also cultivated for its ovoid fruit. , peppers, melon melon,  fruit of Cucumis melo, a plant of the family Curcurbitaceae (gourd family) native to Asia and now cultivated extensively in warm regions. There are many varieties, differing in taste, color, and skin texture—e.g. , onions, apples, pears and cucumbers.

Baeten reported that growth in both the frozen and the fresh
vegetable business has spurred sales among FAM&apos;s extended line of centrifugal centrifugal  /cen·trif·u·gal/ ( sen-trif´ah-gal ) efferent (1). 
 cen·trif·u·gal 
 adj. 
 1. Moving or directed away from a center or axis.

 2.  and transverse To cross from side to side.  slicers, leaf dicers and bean cutters.
&quot;There are 13 or 14 vegetable companies in Belgium alone that are
investing in methods to improve their cut quality and reduce raw
material losses,&quot; he said.

While the Benelux in particular and Europe in general are
FAM&apos;s main areas of activity, it is engaged in export markets
farther afield. The USA and Canada are high on the list for further
penetration. Elsewhere, an agent has been appointed in Japan to
represent the company&apos;s entire line -- including meat and poultry
dicers, strip-cutters and slicers.

Good Vibrations from CPS (1) ( C haracters P er S econd) The measurement of the speed of a serial printer or the speed of a data transfer between hardware devices or over a communications channel. CPS is equivalent to bytes per second.  

Designing and building dual case packing systems for the horizontal
and vertical positioning of bags into boxes is what Case Packing Systems
(CPS) is all about. It has installed more than 170 case packer packer  /pack·er/ ( pak´er ) an instrument for introducing a dressing into a cavity or a wound. 
 pack·er 
 n. 
 1. An instrument for tamponing.

 2. See plugger.  lines
around the world.

Some of the biggest names in the food processing industry are
clients of CPS (Fax: 31-495-563486), with frozen product manufacturers
accounting for more than 70% of last year&apos;s 8.2 million euros in
turnover. &quot;In Belgium [which is just one kilometer from the CPS
headquarters in Stamproy, Holland], our equipment has an 80% share of
the market,&quot; said Peter Aquarius, managing director. &quot;Two
high-speed lines were recently installed at the new Lutosa french fry
plant in Leuze-en-Hainaut. They can easily move 12 to 14 tons of 2.5
kilo boxes per hour.&quot;

Active as CPS since 1988, the family-owned company first
manufactured vertical form, fill and seal machinery for 21 years before
selling off the bag making rights to PMB PMB Private Message Board
PMB Print Measurement Bureau
PMB Performance Measurement Baseline
PMB Private Mail Box (non-USPS) 
PMB Plant and Microbial Biology
PMB Private Mailbox
PMB Physics in Medicine and Biology  Group/NL 12 years ago.
Today&apos;s operation, which employs 45 persons at a 2,000 square meter Noun 1. square meter - a centare is 1/100th of an are
centare, square metre

area unit, square measure - a system of units used to measure areas  assembly plant, is exclusively dedicated to industrial PC-driven ( IPC (1) ( I nter P rocess C ommunication) The exchange of data between one program and another either within the same computer or over a network. It implies a protocol that guarantees a response to a request. )
end-of-line packaging systems.

With trained engineers representing almost 20% of its work force,
CPS is able to design software specifically tailored to the needs of
each user. &quot;Our technology works on the Internet, just like normal
computers. There is not even a need for paper manuals anymore,&quot;
said Aquarius.

Jan W. Egging, area manager, explained that the system operates on
the principle of belt-conveying and vibrating vibrating, 
 v using quivering hand motions made across the client&apos;s body for therapeutic purposes.  packaged products to their
destination: the case packer. A computer-controlled bag compressing
mechanism compacts pillow bags for problem-free containerization con·tain·er·ize  
 v. tr. con·tain·er·ized , con·tain·er·iz·ing , con·tain·er·iz·es 
 1. To package (cargo) in large standardized containers for efficient shipping and handling.

 2. .

Cartons are presented by the carton erector erector  /erec·tor/ ( e-rek´ter ) [L.] a structure that erects, as a muscle which raises or holds up a part. 
 e·rec·tor 
 n. 
A muscle that makes a body part erect. Also called arrector . , bottom-taped and
supplied to the case packer unit via case infeed belts. Next the cases
are transferred to a case check weighing station equipped with a reject
system. From there a short transfer belt brings the checked cases into
the vibrating/tape closing machine where the top flaps are sealed. Ink
jet See inkjet printer.  coding or labeling follows before the completely finished cases are
transferred for palletization pal·let·ize  
 tr.v. pal·let·ized , pal·let·izing , pal·let·izes 
To store or move (freight, for example) by means of pallets.

 
 pal .

For Eyckeler&amp;Malt&apos;s New Minced Meat Minced meat may refer to:
 Ground meat - meat that has been minced or ground
 Minced meat may be confused with:
 Mincemeat - a conglomeration of bits of meat, dried fruit and spices, commonly does not contain any meat
  Line There Was Just
One Source for Equipment

More than 360 tons of fresh and frozen meat a day are shipped out
from the Eyckeler&amp;Malt AG plant near Dusseldorf, Germany. Now, the
firm wants to increase its output of value-added product with
high-quality minced meats.

To set up the new production line, from mincer and portioner to
packaging machine and materials, the company turned to Convenience Food
Systems (CFS), Bakel, the Netherlands, which offered one-stop shopping
and other advantages.

Eyckeler&amp;Malt processes more than 20,000 beef quarters, 4,500
hogs and 500 calves per week for distribution throughout Germany and the
rest of Europe. For its new further processing line, it wanted to ensure
top quality by using the most modern and efficient technology available.
And it wanted all new equipment and packaging materials delivered by one
partner.

All this led to CFS as sole supplier of the Eyckeler&amp;Malt&apos;s line for mincing, portioning, prepackaging and freezing. The
new line comprises a Kramer + Grebe mincer with loader A program routine that copies a program into memory for execution.  and twin Mixer Grinder Grinder

A slang term for a person who works in the investment industry and makes small amounts of money at a time on small investments, over and over again.

Notes:  200/1500 with [CO.sub.2] cooling, Koppens MultiFormer 400 and
Tiromat Powerpak PP-420 thermoformer featuring TiroPak&apos;s unique
TiroFreeze packaging solutions.

Throughput of the new line should soon reach 30-40 tons a day,
according to Eyckeler&amp;Malt manager Frank Wolf Frank Rudolph Wolf , born January 30 1939, American politician, has been a Republican member of the United States House of Representatives since 1981. He represents Northern Virginia&apos;s 10th congressional district. He is the most senior of Virginia&apos;s eleven Congressmen. . Primary output so
far consists of single-serve 400 and 500-gram frozen portions. Wolf
stressed that among the reasons for giving CFS the order were the
opportunity for product testing before making a final decision, and the
offer of training operating staff at CFS&apos;s technology center in
Bakel.

Another reason for choosing CFS, he said, was the level of quality
control possible. The frozen mince portions are aimed at premium-price
segments which mean that quality, color and fat content have to be
exactly the way the customer wants it. Packaging materials are also very
important, added Wolf. &quot;Eyckeler&amp;Malt customers not only want
the products shown off in the best way possible, but demand materials
that guarantee absolute safety while at the same time meeting
ever-increasing environmental demands with minimum impact on natural
resources and maximum recycling potential.&quot; COPYRIGHT 2000 E.W. Williams Publications, Inc.
No portion of this article can be reproduced without the express written permission from the copyright holder. Copyright 2000 Gale, Cengage Learning. All rights reserved. 
 Reader Opinion
 Title:
 
Comment:
 

 
   
 
 Article Details Printer friendly Cite/link Email Feedback Comment: Looking Through Potato Glass, Darkly: Will quality Problems Eat Up Supply? Author: SAULNIER, JOHN M. Publication: Quick Frozen Foods International Geographic Code: 1USA Date: Jan 1, 2000 Words: 10239 Previous Article: ICE CREAM SCOOPS. Next Article: Frozen Tonnage Hits 625,000 in Italy As Market Value Surpasses $2 Billion. Topics: Frozen foods industry Management 
 Frozen potato products Vegetable industry Management 
 




 Related Articles Competition intensifies in potato field as overcapacity puts pressure on profits. In the eye of the European potato storm imports stretching dwindling supplies. Economic slowdown may cool Europe, but heat is on in Benelux QFF sector. It&apos;s a great time now for &apos;potato eaters,&apos; and a great time for potato suppliers too! Millennium Factory in Bavaria Triples Capacity to Meet Demand. Full Service is Key to Success In Highly Fragmented Market. Innovative Product Assortment Wins Customer Loyalty for Aviko. Potato Raw Material Prices Stable; Pressure on Producers. NORTHERN EUROPE: Deep Potato Roots Stretch Far. Frozen potato producers plow ahead in tough, price-driven environment: in strategy to widen thin margins, manufacturers look to further cultivate... 
 
 
 Publications by Name Publications by Date Authors Literature A-D E-O P-T U-Z before 1995 1995-1999 
 2000-2004 2005-2009 2010- A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 

 Terms of use |
Copyright©2012 Farlex, Inc. | Feedback | For webmasters | Submit articles
	</body>
</document>
