<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008695" url="http://www.ehsrestaurantmanagementjobs.com/counter_offer_resignation_letters/beware_counter_offers.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:09" support="3" score="0.0067051142394313045" bingtitle="EHS Hospitality Group | Recruiting, Career Management &amp; Counseling" webtitle="EHS Hospitality Group | Recruiting, Career ManagementCounselingEHS Hospitality Group, Restaurant Manager Jobs, Restaurant Bar
Manager Jobs, Hotel Restaurant Jobs, Restaurant Service Manager Jobs,
Restaurant Kitchen manager Jobs, Restaurant Sous Chef Jobs, Restaurant 
Chef
Jobs, Restaurant Executive Chef Jobs, Restaurant General Manager Jobs,
Restaurant Assistant Manager Jobs, Restaurant Catering Manager Jobs,
Restaurant Manager Jobs, Fast Food Restaurant Jobs">
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Restaurant Opportunities; Hotel / Resort; EHS Partnerships ... We didn’t count on those people long ... band-aid treatment, nothing will change ...</description>
	<body>
		EHS Hospitality Group

 
 
   
NAVIGATION TOOLS

 HOME | CANDIDATES | CLIENTS | RESTAURANT OPPORTUNITIES 
 
EHS HOSPITALITY GROUP
 
 About Us Contact Us 

EHS SERVICES
 
 Client Services Career Management Opportunities Hotel / Resort EHS Partnerships 

EHS RESOURCES
 
 Testimonials Who We Represent - Web Links 

EHS LIBRARY
 
 Interview Resume Tips Interview Documents Counter Offers Career Tips 

 

 
 
 

 

 
 
 Back to Counter Offer Resignation 
Letters main page 



BEWARE OF COUNTEROFFERS

 

You’ve been offered a position with growth potential and a 
 moderate increase in compensation. You’ve analyzed and agonized 
 over the decision to leave a good (or bad) job for what could be a 
 better one, and have accepted (or decided to accept) the offer. However, 
 upon resigning, your current boss asks you to stay. This appeal is 
 known as a counter offer or buyback.

 

In recent years, counteroffers have practically become the norm. 
 But while counteroffers can be tempting, take care not to fall into 
 the trap or be blindsided to your own detriment. Career changes are 
 tough enough as it is, and anxieties about leaving a comfortable job, 
 friends and location and having to reprove yourself again in an unknown 
 opportunity can cloud the best of logic. But just because the new 
 position is a little scary doesn’t mean it’s not a positive 
 move.


Since counteroffers can create confusion and buyer’s remorse, 
 you should understand what’s being cast upon you. Counteroffers 
 are typically made in conjunction with some form of flattery.


 For example: 


•You’re too valuable, and we need you.
•You can’t desert the team/your friends and leave them 
 hanging.
•We were just about to give you a promotion/raise, and it was 
 confidential until now.
•We were just about to give you a promotion/raise, and it was 
 confidential until now.
•What did they offer, why are you leaving, and what do you 
 need to stay•
•Why would you want to work for that company•
•The President/CEO wants to meet with you before you make your 
 final decision.


 Counters usually take the form of: 


•more money
•a promotion/more responsibility
•a modified reporting structure
•promises or future considerations,
•disparaging remarks about the new company or job, and/or
•guilt trips

 

Of course, since we all prefer to think we’re MVPs, its natural 
 to want to believe these manipulative appeals, but beware! Accepting 
 a counter offer often is the wrong choice to make.


 Think about it: 

If you were worth“X”yesterday, why are they suddenly 
 willing to pay you“X + Y”today, when you weren’t 
 expecting a raise for some time.

 

Also consider how you’ve felt when someone resigned from your 
 staff. The reality is that employers don’t like to be“fired”. 
 Your boss is likely concerned that he’ll look bad, and that 
 his career may suffer.

 

Bosses are judged by their ability to retain staff. When a contributor 
 quits, morale suffers. Further, your leaving might jeopardize an important 
 project, increase staffers’workload or even foul up a vacation 
 schedule. It’s never a good time for someone to quit, and it 
 may prove time-consuming and costly to replace you, especially considering 
 recruitment and relocation expenses. It’s much cheaper to keep 
 you, even at a slightly higher salary. And it would be better to fire 
 you later, on the company’s time frame.

 

“We’ve made counteroffers on occasion, if a good person 
 approaches the issue professionally,”says a former senior partner 
 of a Big Six accounting and consulting firm.“But usually it 
 was a stop gag measure because we couldn’t afford a defection 
 at that point in time. We didn’t count on those people long 
 term, and usually they’d burn bridges two or three levels up, 
 if not with their immediate manager. It definitely put them in a career 
 holding pattern.”

 

The senior partner cites a long conference he once attended with 
 his boss and two subordinate managers, in which they approved a counteroffer 
 and raise to an employee two levels down.“Immediately after 
 that meeting, my boss called me and said,“We can’t afford 
 to lose him now, but our No.1 priority is to find a replacement, ASAP!”he says.“And we placed him within a few months.”

 

Another senior executive from a major Dallas based band says,“If 
 it’s a real‘hitter,’I’ll try to get him 
 to stay. But to be honest, any additional compensation is‘stealing’from his future earnings, and I’ll always question his convictions, 
 knowing he can be bought. Further, I’ll wonder if I can really 
 count on him [which equates to limited future opportunities]. In other 
 words, the damage is done.”

 

While your employer may truly consider you an asset and genuinely 
 care about you personally, you can be sure that your interests are 
 secondary to your boss’s career and your company’s profit 
 or survival.

 

Thus, flattering offers and comments are attempts to manipulate you 
 to act in your employer’s best interests - which aren’t 
 necessarily your own. In other words, they’re not about you.

 

Accepting a counter offer can have numerous negative consequences. 
 Consider:


•Where did the additional money or responsibility you’d 
 get come from? Was it your next raise or promotion - just given early? 
 Will you be limited in the future? Will you have to threaten to quit 
 to get your next raise? Might a (cheaper) replacement be sought out?


•You’ve demonstrated your unhappiness (or lack of blind 
 loyalty), and will be perceived as having committed blackmail to gain 
 a raise. You won’t ever be considered a team player again. Many 
 employers will hold a grudge at the next review period, and you may 
 be placed at the top of the next reduction-in-force“hit list.”As one executive who requested anonymity says,“Like an adulterous 
 affair that’s been discovered, the broken trust is never fully 
 recovered.”

 

•Apart from the short-term, band-aid treatment, nothing will 
 change within the company. After the dust settles from this upheaval, 
 you’ll be in the same old rut. A rule of thumb among recruiters 
 is that more than 80% of those accepting counteroffers leave, or are 
 terminated within six to 12 months anyway. Half of those who do succumb 
 reinitiate their job searches within 90 days, recruiters say.

 

“They butter you up, give you more money, but nothing really 
 changes. In fact, they can get worse.”says once insurance executive 
 in Utah who accepted a counteroffer.“My immediate boss was 
 really agitated, since his boss interceded. At raise time, he told 
 me that nothing had been budgeted (since I’d already gotten 
 a raise), and that if I wanted, I could negotiate with the president 
 as before.”This executive, by the way, left the company within 
 months.

 

To be sure, recruiters have a vested interest in candidates not accepting 
 counteroffers, since they can’t complete their search assignments 
 without willing candidates.


•Attempted buybacks can demonstrate disrespect for your well-thought-out 
 decision and commitment to the new company. Should your current employer 
 decide to eliminate your position or pass you over for promotion, 
 successfully countering their decision is unlikely. Besides you’ve 
 analyzed, accepted and committed to the new company, which as surely 
 made plans and accommodations around you and is counting on you.

 

Finally, when making your decision, look at your current job and 
 new position as if you were unemployed. Which opportunity holds the 
 most real potential? Probably the new one, or you wouldn’t have 
 accepted it in the first place.

 
 

 
 Copyright©2008 - , EHS Hospitality Group.   Home | Contact | Privacy Policy 
Website design: Abacus Web Services
	</body>
</document>
