<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008567" url="http://galena.org/place_to_dine/pageSubPlace/7" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="2" score="0.0015882830720278889" bingtitle="Galena/Jo Daviess County - Galena Fast Food, Pizza, Ice Cream ..." webtitle="Galena/Jo Daviess County - Galena Fast Food, Pizza, Ice Cream Shops, Drive Thru and Dining">
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>... check out its fast food selection, pizzerias, ice ... finest in fresh frozen custard to cooked-to-order ... This Galena fast food restaurant is conveniently located off of US ...</description>
	<body>
		877-Go Galena   
 Where To Stay 
 Hotels&amp;Resorts Bed&amp;Breakfasts Motels Vacation Rental Homes 
 What To Do Where To Dine Travel Professionals Weddings 
 
Upcoming Events

 Galena Festival of the Performing Arts 
 Jul 14, 2012 Elizabeth Community Fair 
 Jul 19-22, 2012 
 
 Search Calendar of Events 
 July 2012 August 2012 September 2012 October 2012 November 2012 December 2012 January 2013 February 2013 March 2013 April 2013 May 2013 June 2013 July 2013 August 2013 September 2013 October 2013 November 2013 December 2013 January 2014 February 2014 March 2014 April 2014 May 2014 June 2014 
 Home Where to Dine Fast Food/Pizza 
 
 Fast Food/Pizza     

 Leave plenty of time for local attractions with a stop for a quick burger, sandwich, soup and salad. Or stay and relax a while with a tempting homemade pizza. 


 
 Culver&apos;s Frozen Custard   815-777-9401
11371 Oldenburg Ln., Galena, IL 61036

Culver&apos;s brings the often forgotten hometown values of quality and customer service to neighborhoods throughout the country! More... 

 
 Happy Joe&apos;s Pizza&amp;Ice Cream Parlor   815-777-1830
9919 US Hwy 20 West, Galena, IL 61036

Pizza, pasta, sandwiches, and more. Lots of family fun, including redemption game room. Lunch smorgasbord&amp;Sunday brunch. Smoke-free restaurant. More... 

 
 J.M.&apos;s Tap   815-747-7730
7625 N. Menominee Rd., East Dubuque, IL 61025

Country tavern restaurant. Family owned and operated for more than 60 years, specializing in homemade pizza and a friendly atmosphere. More... 

 
 L.A. Drive In   815-947-2312
216 E. North Ave. (US Hwy 20 East), Stockton, IL 61085

Offering a large menu of fast food items, countless ice cream choices. Something for everyone, just how you like it. More... 

 
 McDonald&apos;s Restaurant   815-777-2600
US Hwy 20&amp;Irvine St., Galena, IL 61036

Great parking; large seating area with patio seating; large bathrooms; bus driver eats free with 20 people. Free Wi-Fi available. More... 

 
 Subway   815-947-9100
207 E. North Ave. (US Hwy 20), Stockton, IL 61085

Fresh subs and salads made to order. Party subs, platters and cookie platters available. Clean, friendly environment. More... 

 
 Subway   815-777-4322
11358 Industrial Park Dr., Galena, IL 61036

Fresh subs and salads made to order. Party subs, platters and cookie platters available. Clean, friendly environment. More... 

 
 
 About CVB Maps Trip Planning Tools News/Media FAQ 
 Links To Us Contact Us Business Login Submit an Event Staff Mission&amp;Purpose Wedding Maps Test Landing page Travel Resources2 Travel Resources Galena Lead Rush Half Marathon Visit Galena Now Blog Image Library Media Center ©Galena/Jo Daviess County Convention&amp;Visitors Bureau
101 Bouthillier Street,
Galena, IL 61036,
877-Go Galena (464-2536) site search 
If you’re in to grab a quick bite to eat or a slice of pizza, then the fast food and pizza places in Galena is what you need. Whether you are in the mood for a sandwich, ice cream, a juicy burger or a specialty pizza visit Jo Daviess County and explore the finest fast food and pizza places.



Stop in for some fun, friendly service at Culver’s Frozen Custard in Galena. This Galena ice cream and fast food stop offers everything from the finest in fresh frozen custard to cooked-to-order burgers, fries, salads, smoothies and kids meals. This fast food in Galena is the perfect place to stop for fresh and fast food in Jo Daviess County. Culver’s Frozen Custard in Galena is open year round, and serves lunch and dinner.



If you are looking for a fun atmosphere pizza and ice cream parlor in Galena , Happy Joe’s Pizza&amp;Ice Cream is the stop for you. This pizzeria in Galena offers everything from pizza, pastas, sandwiches, salads and of course ice cream! Bring the whole family and enjoy the game room and some fun at this Galena pizzeria ! Happy Joe’s is open all year and serves breakfast, lunch and dinner.



When it comes to old-fashioned homemade pizza J.M.’s Tap has the best in Jo Daviess County. This country tavern restaurant in East Dubuque provides the best pizza and a fun, friendly atmosphere. This pizzeria in East Dubuque has been family owned and operated for more than 60 years. This pizza place in Jo Daviess County has the finest in homemade pizza! Stop in for dinner at this East Dubuque restaurant and check out the best pizza in the area!



Experience an old-fashioned drive-in with the L.A. Drive In . This fast food drive-in located in Stockton offers everything from burgers to ice cream. When it comes to a family night out in Jo Daviess County the L.A. Drive In has something from everyone. This drive-in restaurant near Galena is open all year and serves breakfast, lunch and dinner. Swing by and enjoy and old-fashioned treat in Jo Daviess County.



 Fast food in Galena would not be complete without the infamous McDonald’s restaurant . McDonald’s Restaurant in Galena provides great parking, large amounts of seating including patio seating, large bathrooms and free wireless internet is available. If you are a bus driver in Galena stop by McDonald’s with 20 people and eat free! This Galena fast food restaurant is conveniently located off of US HWY 20.



Stop in for fresh subs and salads at one of the two great Subway locations in Jo Daviess County. You can stop by Subway in Galena or in Stockton during your stay. This Galena fast food restaurant offers party subs, platters and cookies! Subway now serves breakfast, lunch and dinner!



When it comes to fast food in Galena , this small town has something for everyone. Give yourself more time to explore the great attractions in Jo Daviess County with a quick stop at one of the fast food restaurants in Galena .
	</body>
</document>
