<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008324" url="http://bottomline.msnbc.msn.com/_news/2012/03/26/10831705-fast-food-chains-with-the-unhealthiest-customers" time="2012-07-13-01:48" support="5" score="0.004011905305731321" bingtitle="Bottom Line - Fast-food chains with the unhealthiest customers" webtitle="Fast-food chains with the unhealthiest customers - Bottom Line">
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000871" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>Granted, it is too easy to just stop by a fast food restaurant ... What&apos;s interesting to me about this junk science ... Forget parent error: Car designs make seats ...</description>
	<body>
		MSN Hotmail More 
 Autos My MSN Video Careers&amp;Jobs Personals Weather Delish Quotes White Pages Games Real Estate Wonderwall Horoscopes Shopping Yellow Pages Local Edition Traffic Feedback Maps&amp;Directions Travel Full MSN Index 
 Bing 
 
 msnbc.com sites&amp;shows: TODAY Rock Center Nightly News Meet the Press Dateline Morning Joe Hardball Ed Maddow Last Word msnbc tv 
 
 Home US World Politics Business Sports Entertainment Health Tech&amp;science Travel Local Weather 
 
 Recommended: Senator questions results of Toyota safety probe Recommended: Audi&apos;s race to dominate luxury market hits speed bump Recommended: Yoga teacher fired for defying Facebook cellphone policy Recommended: The best cities for Millennials 
 
Breaking news and analysis of the economy, markets, autos, real estate and consumer issues. Check us out on Facebook, follow us on Twitter. Get quote 
 ↓About this blog ↓Archives 
 E-mail updates Follow on Twitter Subscribe to RSS 
 
 204 comments Print 26 Mar 2012 7:41am, EDT 
Fast-food chains with the unhealthiest customers
 
Seth Perlman / AP
 
At McDonald&apos;s, 24 percent of its frequent customers report being either unhappy or very unhappy with their health.
 By Charles B. Stockdale, 24/7 Wall St. 
While most Americans are happy with their family, friends and home life, more than one in five Americans are unhappy with their health.

According to a new survey conducted by consumer-focused information site BIGinsight, those who frequent certain fast-food restaurants are even less happy with their health than the average American. 24/7 Wall St. examined the results of the survey to identify the fast-food chains with the most-unhealthy customers.

 24/7 Wall St.: Fast-food chains with the most unhealthy customers 

Customers of four of the eight largest fast-food restaurants report a higher rate of being either totally unhappy or somewhat unhappy with their health than the general population. Not surprisingly, the fast-food diners who are most unhappy with their health also report other relatively unhealthy habits. Customers of three of the four restaurants also report among the lowest rates of exercising regularly among all major fast-food chains. McDonald’s, whose customers are the most unhappy with their health, has the lowest rate of customers who exercise regularly.

The four restaurants with the most-unhealthy customers also have the lowest rates of customers who watch their caloric intake. Three have among the lowest rates of customers watching their fat intakes. This behavior does not mix well with a diet that includes a number of fast-food meals.

However, not all fast-food restaurants have unhealthy customers. Chains where customers exhibit healthier behaviors, such as Arby’s, Chick-fil-A and Subway, have customers with above-average levels of happiness with their health. As Consumer Insights Director Pamela Goodfellow told 24/7 Wall St.,“The difference between these consumer groups lies in what they do beyond the drive-thru: exercising, counting their calories, focusing on fat intake and watching their health in general.”

These are the fast-food chains with the most unhealthy customers.

 1. McDonald’s 

 Unhappy/totally unhappy customers: 24% Exercise regularly: 34.8% Watching calorie intake: 34.1% Watching fat intake: 33.2% Watching carbohydrate intake: 21.7% 

Except for Chick-fil-A, none of the fast-food restaurants skew so heavily female, with women representing 56 percent of the company’s regular customers. An alarming 24 percent of the chain’s frequent customers report being either unhappy or very unhappy with their health. Almost 30 percent of the restaurant’s regular customers report avoiding all the healthy habits measured by BIGinsight: watching calories, fat, salt or carbohydrate intake, or exercising regularly. This compares to 20 percent nationwide who report avoiding these healthy habits. McDonald’s has attempted to improve its image in recent years. It has begun automatically including apple slices and reducing the size of the fries in every happy meal.

 2. Taco Bell 

 Unhappy/totally unhappy customers: 22.7% Exercise regularly: 40.3% Watching calorie intake: 33.9% Watching fat intake: 31.0% Watching carbohydrate intake: 19.0% 

Taco Bell’s customers have the lowest rank in a number of health-related metrics measured by BIGinsight. Less than 31 percent of the customers report that they watch their fat intake, and only 19 percent watch their carbohydrate intake. The restaurant is second-worst when it comes to customers watching their calorie intake, as well as their salt/sodium intake. There are ways to eat healthily at Taco Bell. By ordering items“Fresco Style,”the sauce and cheese are exchanged for a“fiesta salsa.”Many items frequently considered healthy, such as salads, are among the restaurant’s highest-calorie items.

 24/7 Wall St.: America’s most corrupt states 

 3. Wendy’s 

 Unhappy/totally unhappy customers: 22.1% Exercise regularly: 40.2% Watching calorie intake: 37.2% Watching fat intake: 38.1% Watching carbohydrate intake: 25.4% 

According to the report, 22.1 percent of Wendy’s regular customers are either unhappy or very unhappy with their health. About 40 percent exercise regularly. The average household income of a frequent Wendy’s customer is $60,468, the second-highest of the eight major fast-food chains, behind only Chick-fil-A. Just 22.6 percent of the restaurant’s frequent customers are single adults, second-lowest behind Arby’s in this category. Wendy’s offers healthy choices, including apple slices and salads. Even the salads, however, can be unhealthy, with high sodium and saturated fat.

 4. Burger King 

 Unhappy/totally unhappy customers: 21.5% Exercise regularly: 36.0% Watching calorie intake: 26.6% Watching fat intake: 32.4% Watching carbohydrate intake: 19.7% 

The demographics of the diners who frequent Burger King are unique in two major ways. A majority of restaurant’s customers—58.6 percent—are men, the highest of all fast food chains. Also, the restaurant is frequented by customers with the lowest average annual household income among fast-food chains, at $52,958. Burger King’s customers watch their caloric intake the least among major fast-food chains, at just 26.6 percent. Only 32.4 percent of the restaurant’s customers watch their fat intake, the second lowest percentage. The company has made efforts to provide healthier menu items over the past year, as an attempt to expand its customer base. It continues to offer fattening classics, however, such as the 1,140-calorie Triple Whopper.
 Explore related topics: health , featured , fast-food 
older
 26 Mar 2012 7:30am, EDT 
Younger veterans want to work, but face roadblocks
 
newer
 26 Mar 2012 7:49am, EDT 
Stocks set to rise ahead of housing report
 
Discuss this post
 Jump to discussion page: 1 2 3 4 Mymomdidnotraiseafool 
Gee, we&apos;re shocked! Shocked! Imagine that! Fat people with poor eating habits are sometimes not happy about their health. Who&apos;d a thunk?
 
 47 votes 
 #1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:00 AM EDT JohnSixty 
Amazing! Unhappy fat people at McDonalds?
 
 18 votes 
 #1.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:13 AM EDT stull 
Unhappy, then quit eating at fast food restaurants. Spend the money on healthy food and prepare it yourself. Quit being so LAZY!
 
 23 votes 
 #1.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:21 AM EDT willowbrook 
I guess MSNBC is running out of things to talk about........
 
 26 votes 
 #1.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:32 AM EDT I-belive 
Fast Food should come with a Warning Label just like Cigarettes. Eating this my cause Obesity, Diabetes etc.
 
 11 votes 
 #1.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:54 AM EDT Wet Willy 
Amazing. Here we have fat lazy people blaming the fast food restaurants for their unhappiness with themselves when the true culprit is that person looking back at them from a mirror. It&apos;s always someone else&apos;s fault, eh?
 
 20 votes 
 #1.5 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:13 AM EDT Phil-673730 
Couple of points

1) It was obviously McD would &quot;win&quot; this, because they have the most stores

2) Most fast food places reside at either interstate junction or the poorer areas of towns

3) Why? because when your poor it is cheaper to eat there than buy ingredients and cook, assuming you have not had your power cut off (&amp;using charcoal in an apartment is somewhat risky)

4) Instead of castigating these people, why not help to set up low cost food bank, or get a farmers (type) markets in these areas of supermarket deserts?
 
 21 votes 
 #1.6 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:22 AM EDT Byron Raum 
So are they unhappy because they have poorer health, or are they unhappy because they are being continually told by the media that they should be unhappy with their health?
 
 14 votes 
 #1.7 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:28 AM EDT pandas are awesome 
i&apos;m actually surprised that taco bell is not #1 in unhappy customers... when i order a taco, i want a whole taco, not 1/8 of one for the price of 2.
 
 2 votes 
 #1.8 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:31 AM EDT tontosh-2444879 
What is sad is the fact that lot of these people take pills for high cholesterol, high blood sugar level, and high blood pressure and yet they still eat this cr.p. We need to educate these people. 5% of the people cause 50% of our health care cost around the nation, I just wonder what these 5% are eating everyday.
 
 7 votes 
 #1.9 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:42 AM EDT Derek-381097 
This is like a list of things we already know.
 
 2 votes 
 #1.10 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:42 AM EDT schoolyard 
Every &quot;meal&quot; (and I use that term loosely) that McDonalds sells should come with the phone number to a good Cardiologist!
 
 5 votes 
 #1.11 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:09 AM EDT JCB-1236504 
Phil67, your quote &quot;4) Instead of castigating these people, why not help to set up low cost food bank, or get a farmers (type) markets in these areas of supermarket deserts?&quot;

 How about this Phil, how about these fat do nothings take care of themselves like responsible adults? Are they to lazy to do the right thing on their own? Probably. But there is nothing surprising when it comes to the stupidity or the laziness of the American people, it&apos;s just who we are, and we are getting fatter year after year after year. That is a fact. Never underestimate the laziness of the American people. We have shows that are about fat people losing weight, we have another &quot;hit&quot; TV show about an obese couple &quot;Mike and Molly&quot;, makes fat people feel it&apos;s OK to be an obese person, well it&apos;s not. The new American lie, it&apos;s OK to be who you are. No it&apos;s not when your decisions cost me money, and fat people cost this country billions upon billions every year, more and more each year, and that is also a fact. 
 
 10 votes 
 #1.12 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:20 AM EDT Baddog40 
I don&apos;t know why everyone blames only the fast food places, most food in the grocery stores these days are so loaded with either pesticides, preservatives, hormones, antibiotics, etc. its almost impossible to seriously eat healthy. Its no wonder 1 out of 3 kids born today will develop diabetes and 1 out of 2 of us will develop cancer. Make us sick with the food and get rich treating the sickness, thats the American way.
 
 14 votes 
 #1.13 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:26 AM EDT floyd-335513 
have no fear, If Obama get re-elected Michelle will destroy all the fast food restaurants then tell us what we can and cannot eat. They will have refrigerator checks and you had better not have any fattening food or you will get 30 lashes. Have you read the book 1984?
 
 3 votes 
 #1.14 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:46 AM EDT D Buck-2239568 
This story rates right up their with the Fat guy that sued the fast food chain because he was to fat to get into their booths and was angry because he had to order out. he never stoped eating their food.
 
 2 votes 
 #1.15 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:06 PM EDT old deputy 
I&apos;ll bet alot of these folks gained weight after their local governments forced them to give up smoking( sarcasm). Why, if they could just curb their need for oral fixation by puffing a cigarette, think of how much healthier they would be. The fast food joints would fold-up for lack of revenue.
 
 1 vote 
 #1.16 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:26 PM EDT Rod_Father 
McDonald&apos;s ground beef washed with chlorine. How does that not need a warning label?
 
 6 votes 
 #1.17 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:42 PM EDT beanathome 
JCB-1236504--thanks for your concern.

This was an incredibly badly reported study. It says, on the one hand, that &quot;more than&quot; one in five people is unhappy (with their health and overall). That would be 20% plus a bit. Then they say that people at fast-food restaurants are even more unhappy with their health. Here are the results:

McDonald&apos;s: 24%
Taco Bell: 22.7%
Wendy&apos;s: 22.1%
Burgar King: 21.5%

Wow--perhaps up to four percent more people who eat at McDonald&apos;s are unhappy (with their health and perhaps more). Now, let&apos;s think--who eats at McDonald&apos;s who would not be able to eat someplace that is &quot;healthier.&quot; You think, perhaps, it is working class people? So, what we have found is that the working class people are less happy (with their health and apparently overall) by about four more percent? Wow--we are so surprised.

This study does not show that people who are unconcerned with their fat and calorie intake are less likely to be happy (about their health and otherwise)--it shows that working class people are less likely to be happy. Gosh--you think maybe the fact that the rich are getting richer, that food prices are going through the roof, that one of the few places you can get a meal for a dollar or so per person is McDonald&apos;s (not really a place to be thrilled about being) and the fact that many working class people cannot afford health care (much less all the pills people think they are taking) has to do with it?

There are steroids in inexpensive milk and meat. There is BPA in virtually all inexpensive packaged foods. There is corn syrup in virtually all inexpensive foods. Inexpensive foods will put fat on people. Individuals who work two and three part-time jobs because wealthy people do not establish businesses that employ people full time any more because it means that they can have a revolving staff, fire anyone who doesn&apos;t toady up quickly enough, and not be dependent on any group of people so that they cannot unionize and demand a living wage . . . well, guy, they don&apos;t really have the leisure time to &quot;exercise&quot; or the money to be able to be concerned with calories (fat, by the way, is not a factor--plenty of studies have already confirmed that calories are calories and fat is not relevant).

You&apos;ve got to love Americans--if they don&apos;t have a group of people that they can openly discriminate against, call names, consider less than human, and blame for their own situation . . . well, by golly, they just aren&apos;t happy. The current concern with &quot;obesity&quot; is little more than a code for &quot;people of color&quot; and &quot;poor whites.&quot;

Back when it was wealthy people who were &quot;obese&quot; (go back and look at pictures of the &quot;robber barons&quot;--they weren&apos;t exactly fit), nobody had a problem with obesity even though it caused health problems (like gout--the &quot;rich man&apos;s disease&quot;). Now that it is poor people who are obese because the food that is available has changed, obesity is this symbol of poor morality. Charming.

 
 10 votes 
 #1.18 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 1:01 PM EDT JCB-1236504 
Beanathome, so it&apos;s rich peoples fault that Americans are fat and lazy? Well gez, that&apos;s news to me. your quote &quot;There is corn syrup in virtually all inexpensive foods.&quot; That is an outright lie. You can buy &quot;juice&quot; that is 100% juice for the same money as a &quot;juice drink&quot;. Banana&apos;s are dirt cheap, and a great food source, and to think that &quot;poor&quot; people have to eat at McDonald&apos;s just gives them an excuse to be lazy and fat. They offer a boatload of better food choices, but fat people like Big Mac&apos;s, a large fry and a coke. Take a tuna fish sandwich to work instead. Order grilled instead of fried, and french fries are not an unalienable right. You sound like a &quot;hater&quot; of those who succeeded. Excuses are the last vestige of a person who is to lazy to be in control of their own results in life. &quot;choice&apos;s not chance makes you who you are&quot;
 
 4 votes 
 #1.19 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 2:09 PM EDT Another 1 
Eating alone could be a contributing cause of unhappiness. Sharing a meal with family/friends/co-workers, etc. can make a meal more pleasurable.
 
 2 votes 
 #1.20 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 4:11 PM EDT Auto 101 
You people should watch &quot;fat head&quot;.
 

 #1.21 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:50 PM EDT Phil-673730 
 JCB-1236504 : No it&apos;s not when your decisions cost me money, and fat people cost this country billions upon billions every year. 
 
Just like runners, cyclists, climbers, weight lifters, cost everyone money as they mess up their joints, break bones, tear muscles blow their hearts up (happened to a very fit 20 year old I knew once) . etc. and run to the ER.

JCB, life in general kills us all one way or another, under our system of medicine we all pay for each others bad choices 
 
 
 4 votes 
 #1.22 - Tue Mar 27, 2012 9:24 AM EDT timberwolfgirl2 
PHIL

I inconcur with your post suggesting healthy people (at least doing healthy stuff) are raising the cost of health insurnace. Come on. Most americans and kids are seriously obese. Most are spoiled, vapid and lazy. They rather eat fast food because they lost the wisdom of &quot;waiting&quot; and rather run home to watch their Reality TV garbage.

Fast Food and Reality TV are the two that are killing Americans soul..
 
 1 vote 
 #1.23 - Wed Mar 28, 2012 12:03 AM EDT Sirlafalot 
I&apos;m unhappy with my thyroid gland. Too much food passes by this gland; causing me to gain weight.
 
 9 votes 
 #2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:12 AM EDT Ruken 
So eat less and/or exercise more.
 
 4 votes 
 #2.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:16 AM EDT Sirlafalot 
But won&apos;t I still be hungry?
 
 2 votes 
 #2.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:06 AM EDT Phil-673730 
But won&apos;t I still be hungry?
 
Yep; the more you exercise the hungrier you&apos;ll get.

 
 2 votes 
 #2.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:25 AM EDT Derek-381097 
Does your &apos;thyroid gland&apos; have twin yellow arches on it? :D
 
 9 votes 
 #2.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:44 AM EDT SYNO 
I thought fat people were supposed to be jolly.
 
 6 votes 
 #3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:13 AM EDT Chris-629698 
&quot;Ho ho ho! I loooove my diabetes and atherosclerosis. Come, kids, sit on my lap and let me tell you the charming story of heart disease and joint degradation! Hoo hoo hooo.... Solo! Hay lapa no ya, Solo!&quot;
 
 3 votes 
 #3.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:18 AM EDT Sirlafalot 
It&apos;s easy to be jolly when you have a bag of fries from McD&apos;s and a side of gravy from KFC to dip them in.
 
 7 votes 
 #3.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:10 AM EDT Derek-381097 
Yes, every day I go to work, I see all the jolly people in cars driving next to me!
 
 2 votes 
 #3.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:45 AM EDT Sirlafalot 
That&apos;s not a leather bound steering wheel wrap; it&apos;s a layer of dried gravy!
 
 4 votes 
 #3.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:06 AM EDT Derek-381097 
LOL. That&apos;s got to be really hard to deal with in the summer.
 
 1 vote 
 #3.5 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:20 AM EDT ChrisWanker 
I still prefer Burger King overall. Tastes much, MUCH better than McD.
 
 6 votes 
 #4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:16 AM EDT dimisur 
and Burger King tastes like dog food so what does that make McDonalds?
 

 #4.1 - Wed Mar 28, 2012 9:51 PM EDT wichasha 
Fast food, for the most part, is eaten by people who don&apos;t have enough motivation to prepare a decent meal. Why would they have the motivation to exercise? To me it is a foregone conclusion that they would be among the least healthy, regardless of which restaurant.
 
 15 votes 
 #5 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:20 AM EDT Chris-629698 
I agree. Fast food should be a last resort during a busy schedule when no other options are available. There should never be an instance when a person says, &quot;Hey kids, feel like McDonalds for dinner tonight?&quot; when healthier options are available at home.
 
 8 votes 
 #5.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:24 AM EDT wichasha 
Chris

That&apos;s for sure. If people wont make a decent meal in their own interest, they should at least do it in the interest of their children.
 
 6 votes 
 #5.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:33 AM EDT The Lunatic 
Everyone should watch the cult flick &quot;Muffin Man&quot; ( www.MuffinManTheMovie.com ) - no one will want to eat fast food again!
 
 3 votes 
 #6 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:22 AM EDT ThePolitician 
Something tells me that people will still eat fast food, no matter what you have to offer that&apos;s so disgusting. If you&apos;re too lazy to do it yourself, you&apos;re gonna eat fast food. Period.
 

 #6.1 - Tue Mar 27, 2012 1:52 AM EDT Auto 101 
How about watch Fat head.
 

 #6.2 - Tue Mar 27, 2012 4:09 AM EDT Tidybowl1 
Another reason to love Chick-fil-A!
 
 6 votes 
 #7 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:25 AM EDT stc1993 
That&apos;s my favorite too. Can&apos;t beat Chick-Fil-A The service or the food.
 
 1 vote 
 #7.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:22 AM EDT Pam Montgomery 
Agreed, Lunatic....That&apos;s a really good one. &quot;Fast Food Nation&quot; is the one that did it for me. Made me go vegan for almost 3 years, and has kept me out of FF restaurants ever since.
 
 2 votes 
 #7.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:48 AM EDT Linda from CT 
Not that I&apos;m advocating fast food, but...

If &quot;more than one in five Americans are unhappy with their health,&quot; doesn&apos;t that mean that&gt;20% of people who eat ANYWHERE are unhappy/totally unhappy?

Am I missing something?
 
 6 votes 
 #8 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:25 AM EDT rkaralius 
Yes, you&apos;re missing the way that percentage breaks out. If 20% of the country&apos;s population make over $65,000/year, does that mean every state/county/town has 20% of its population making over $65,000/year? No. Some states/counties/towns average a lot more, some a lot less.
 

 #8.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:11 AM EDT kirstyloo2 
rkaralius - You need to work on your agruement bit before you make that comment. Household incomes vary significantly so that the average is pulled up by a few high earning individuals. This study involved a yes/no format. This means there isn&apos;t likely to have much of a difference due to a few people because there isn&apos;t a spectum. That is why 24% (McD) isn&apos;t that far off the national average. It might have nice if they had delivered the data as relative risk. This would have normalized it; however, it wouldn&apos;t be all that exciting to state that McD had a RR of 1.2.

Depending on the size of the study, these numbers/differences might not even be statistically significant.
 

 #8.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:43 PM EDT Kiki123 
Some people find it cheaper to eat at fast food, why make fun of overweight people, some try hard to lose weight, I hate fast food of any kind, groceries are expensive if you want to eat healthy, fruits, vegetables.

Be kind please.
 
 10 votes 
 #9 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:26 AM EDT Kevin In NY 
Everybody breakout the sympathy card for Kiki... Kiki123, that&apos;s a load of crap. Example: You eat at a fast food joint for 3 meals a day, averaging $7.00 per meal X 7 days is $147 a week. For $147 - I can eat healthy fruits and Veggies and chicken and fish and eggs and whole grain bread for 2-3 weeks.

Obesity-related illness results in hundreds of thousands of preventable deaths each year in the United States and Billions of dollars in health care costs.

Which costs more... buying food at the store and preparing at home... or the rest of us paying for your fast food related medical bills for 30-50 years.
 
 10 votes 
 #9.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:01 AM EDT JJGarner 
Food stamps will buy healthy food, IF a person so chooses. Most of the gimme mo&apos; free stuff welfare moochers load up on pop and chips and then head of to the local fast food drive through and order their super-sized fat burger meals.

No ones fault but their own!
 
 9 votes 
 #9.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:10 AM EDT Ruken 
I heard going outside for a walk is cheap.

 
 12 votes 
 #9.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:21 AM EDT eph521 
Kevin, Kiki asked for kindness. Surely you can make your point and be kind at the same time. You get a big F for your response. Go ahead, now attack me.
 
 9 votes 
 #9.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:37 AM EDT MM-584706 
 Kiki123 ....yes, be kind, but.........................fast food is actually much more expensive than real food. There is no savings to be found at the Golden Arches. Don&apos;t hide behind the expense factor, it does not hold water.
 
 4 votes 
 #9.5 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:47 AM EDT Howie Phelterbush 
its not cheaper to eat fast food infact its very expensive. Last night I grilled 5 lbs of chicken breasts for $11. I ate some with some thai style sweet chili sauce and had some canned low sodium green beans with Italian dressing. What I cooked up last night will last me 3-4 meals total. i spent about $12 total. Last time at subway I spent $9 and change for 1 meal. You can cook healthy balanced meals for $2-4 each easily.
 
 1 vote 
 #9.6 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:54 AM EDT PH-3046605 
Kiki, everyone should be kind but it&apos;s really hard to feel bad for people who eat this junk every day and then complain that they are unhealthy and fat. As Kevin put it, fast food really is not nearly as inexpensive as people claim it is. Eating healthier than fast food does not have to mean buying all sorts of expensive organic fruits and vegetables. It can be as simple as making an omelet for dinner and microwaving some frozen broccoli. This is way less expensive than McDonald&apos;s over time.
 
 2 votes 
 #9.7 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:11 AM EDT skunky-shoes 
Poor people don&apos;t spend $7 for a fast food meal. DOLLAR menu...
 
 2 votes 
 #9.8 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 2:10 PM EDT OccupyWI 
I often find it cheaper to run to Wendys or Little Caesers for a meal than to make my own. Marie Calendars steamers cost over $3.50 and throw in a yogurt cup and some milk and you&apos;re already at about 4.25 for the meal, then add a granola bar and some celery.. 4.75 for that meal or so. A hot and ready lasts me two meals, which comes to $5.28/2 meals. Lunches at Wendy&apos;s run me $3.13. Two monterey chicken sandwiches and a small frosty. I&apos;m a 24y/o male that is 6&apos; and 140lbs. not overweight at all. (Btw, the last time I made a home-made meal, it came to about $30 for four servings. (30/4=$7.5 per serving!)

While many overweight people lack the support system to eat healthy or exercise, many are unable to exercise due to medical reasons like bad joints and pain caused by their weight.Diet modification and slowly increasing physical activity is the only way they&apos;ll have a chance, short of lap-bands.
 
 1 vote 
 #9.9 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 2:26 PM EDT justhefax-2437807 
Occupy,

just wait &apos;till you get older ;-). (kiddin&apos;)

I have seen many of obese people eat, they don&apos;t eat just one meal. You ever seen them shop for groceries in the supermarkt? They eat MORE than an average person. They eat double and tripple stackers, have everything supersized. One of their meals would last me a week.
 

 #9.10 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 3:55 PM EDT Hankster-2496399 
Sort of like cigarette smoking...people don&apos;t stop just because they are warned. If your body craves it, you like it. Part of this has to be social upbringing...ever see grocery carts piled full of junk food and soda pop and the size of the families buying it? You are often what you live and grow up into. Good education has a lot to do with it, but parents ultimately lead and set the example. Granted, it is too easy to just stop by a fast food restaurant as it is a quick way to fill the need with less time to fix meals at home. As our younger generation steps away from physical activity and more into social networking, texting, video gaming, they are mostly seditary couch potatos. Don&apos;t have the answer but wish there was a way to motivate.
 
 5 votes 
 #10 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:41 AM EDT bob1/28 
Hankster

You are on to something there !!!!

The cycle must be broken before we all become super sized. Lack of exercise and a proper diet with portion control is the key. Problem is most large people refuse to believe they suffer from over active fork. Most large people don&apos;t see or understand what they are doing to them selves physically . The first things to wear out are the knees, hips and feet. When they hurt you don&apos;t go any where or do anything. Lack of activity leads to greater weight gain and so it goes.
 
 5 votes 
 #10.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:06 AM EDT Roscoe2u 
I say that it&apos;s not so much about where we eat, it&apos;s more about how much we eat. Anything in moderation but the portion sizes I see people chowing down on is astounding..................
 
 6 votes 
 #11 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:41 AM EDT PH-3046605 
True, but eating processed foods that are high in sodium every day, even in small portions, will induce cravings for more and cause bloating and sluggishness. Fast food should be a treat - maybe once a month, but no more.

I haven&apos;t eaten fast food in 10 years and I don&apos;t miss it. Took some time to stop craving it though!
 
 2 votes 
 #11.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:14 AM EDT Daisy70 
I can&apos;t believe I agree with something you said Roscoe. But... I AGREE!!!! I was a dancer, broke both ankles falling in a pothole (yes, graceful, I know), gained almost 80 lbs just laying around and eating like a pig (fast food was involved... a lot). Lost 100 lbs by cutting my portions drastically. I still eat whatever I want, just a lot less of it. I&apos;m eating JimmyJohn&apos;s right now. But I&apos;m eating half the sandwich and saving the other half for dinner. And after it bugging the living daylights out of me for about a week, my stomach SHRUNK (no lapband needed) and now I am hardly ever hungry.
 
 1 vote 
 #11.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:30 PM EDT Roscoe2u 
See Daisy, I knew you&apos;d come around to my way of thinking. It was only a matter of time...........LOL
 

 #11.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 1:18 PM EDT Mrs Wilberforce 
How did I know -- before even reading this article -- that McDonald&apos;s would be at the top of the list?????
 
 3 votes 
 #12 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:43 AM EDT Raymond-1126037 Comment collapsed by the community 
 Mrs Wilberforce , How did you know ? Because you always eat there. Go use those coupons.
 

 #12.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:57 AM EDT rkaralius 
Raymond, don&apos;t be obnoxious. I knew McD&apos;s would be at the top of the list too, and I eat there maybe 3 times a year.
 
 9 votes 
 #12.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:07 AM EDT eph521 
Thanks Raymond. It&apos;s always so refreshing to see someone like you automatically judge another person based on ZERO facts.
 
 9 votes 
 #12.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:39 AM EDT Ron-2224851 
Why is it the commercials of fast food places show you a nice burger covering the entire bun then when you get one its hiding under the pickle. For the most part I quit eating fast food in my 20&apos;s after I got married. Wifes a good cook and mainly eat home cooked meals. Last time I ordered from mcdonalds was a few months ago, 2 chicken sandwiches an ice cream and a drink. 13 dollars, not exactly a cheap meal.
 
 1 vote 
 #13 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:44 AM EDT maddog-752810 
Wouldn&apos;t it be smarter to pull into the grocery store parking lot go in and get the fixings for a decent meal instead of going the easy route and stopping at a burger joint? And at a much better price. It takes no longer to slap together a decent sandwich than it does to stand in line waiting for a greasy meal and eat it at a table that hasn&apos;t been cleaned in hours.
 
 5 votes 
 #14 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 8:45 AM EDT Troy-2251798 
You have to be brain dead to not see this connection. So, for all you FAT, SELF-INDULGENT PIGS out there, get a fricken clue already. There are faster ways to kill yourself if you&apos;re that bent on it.
 
 5 votes 
 #15 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:03 AM EDT Ruken 
2/3 of the USA is overweight, and 1/3 of the USA is obese.

Tons of those &quot;fat self-indulgent pigs&quot; out there.
 
 1 vote 
 #15.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:20 AM EDT skunky-shoes 
People who have numbers after their tag are being watched by the Internet police...Kicked off too many boards for your rants there Troy? If caloric intake is not your problem, what exactly is?
 

 #15.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 2:14 PM EDT Cynic-537088 
Worthless. Where&apos;s the age/marital status demographic correlation? Taco Bell targets teenagers; McDonalds targets children. Different health levels, different styles of usage.
 
 2 votes 
 #16 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:04 AM EDT JJGarner 
Most of he people who regularly patronize places like McDonalds are also the same people you see waddling around the local WalMart store, or riding the motorized scooters up and down the aisles as they slurp down their 64 ounce sugar laden sodas. Then they complain that they just can&apos;t seem to lose the weight, because of a &quot;glandular&quot; problem of course.

99% of obese people are that way because of their own choice, and no I do not feel sorry for them.
 
 5 votes 
 #17 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:06 AM EDT Rob in Warwick NY 
a very unfair comment.
 
 5 votes 
 #17.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:15 AM EDT Ruken 
A factual comment actually. Americans these days have the victim mentality, whenever something goes wrong it&apos;s never their fault.

When I worked at Target in HS there were several instances of fatties actually breaking those scooters because they were too heavy. They didn&apos;t hesitate to leave their 48oz sodas on the shelves for me to pick up however.
 
 4 votes 
 #17.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:19 AM EDT Rob in Warwick NY 
Ruken.....you do know the difference between &quot;factual&quot; and &quot;anecdotal&quot;, right?? lol
 
 5 votes 
 #17.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:21 AM EDT Panhead-3909678 
Come on JJ, 64 ouncers where you been they went out when the 128s hit the market. A 128 in one hand and an insulin rig in the other. Ah the world we live in!
 
 1 vote 
 #17.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:19 AM EDT PH-3046605 
Rob, it could be said in a nice way, but the reality is that thyroid problems are not nearly as prevalent as overweight people claim it is. Americans need to take personal responsibility for their health.

Overweight people who have tried everything to be healthy, including exercise and a proper, small portion, fast-food free diet may indeed have a problem, but that is rare. In understand it&apos;s hard to break habits and that obesity is a self-perpetuating cycle, but the majority simply do not want to put in the time, effort and sacrifice it takes to lose weight.
 
 1 vote 
 #17.5 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 11:18 AM EDT Rob in Warwick NY 
I mean, this goes without saying.....someone who is conscience of their weight and what they eat, is NOT going to be a regular customer of McDonalds, BK, Wendy&apos;s etc.

Those that do not care or don&apos;t have the education about living healthy will be their regualr customers.

they really spent money on this??
 
 1 vote 
 #18 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:14 AM EDT Emanuelle 
Yup. They spent money on this. Apparently it takes a scientific study with awesome parameters like asking someone an objective question, to conclude that fast food is bad for you and regular patrons of those places aren&apos;t healthy or happy.

I&apos;m going to conduct a study about sleep. The more sleep I get the happier I am--who wants to fund it?
 
 2 votes 
 #18.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:23 AM EDT Rob in Warwick NY 
LOL.....dude, i&apos;m pretty sure they&apos;ve done that sleep study to death already.


funny.
 
 2 votes 
 #18.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:31 AM EDT Tim P-2903950 
Lets see, I&apos;ll have a quarter pouder with cheese, lg fry, and oh wait I&apos;ll take an extra cheeseburger, and a lg diet coke with no ice.....to go
 
 2 votes 
 #19 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:21 AM EDT Ruken 
lg diet coke
 
Well that more than makes up for it. Clearly.
 
 1 vote 
 #19.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:28 AM EDT WilliamOfRites 
McDonald’s, whose customers are the most unhappy with their health, has the lowest rate of customers who exercise regularly.
 
What a surprise.
 
 2 votes 
 #20 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:33 AM EDT Big John-5071382 
What a useless study. So because some people may not count carbs, fat, or calories makes them unhealthy. Garbage science at its finest.
 
 2 votes 
 #21 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:35 AM EDT FeO2 Dreams 
What&apos;s interesting to me about this junk science survey is who isn&apos;t on the list. KFC, Jack-in-the-Box, Long John Silvers, Popeye&apos;s, and a few others are easily as bad as McDonalds.

There are work-arounds if you do get stuck eating fast food. In a lot of burger joints, you can get a salad with chicken breast and a vinaigrette dressing- or at least a side-salad and a naked burger.

Skip the fries, though- those might as well be rat poison.

Fries are a salted, fat coated, carb-loaded invitation to an early death by diabetes or heart failure.

Also: NO SODA. Diet too- anything which tastes really sweet causes the release insulin and leads to diabetes- and fructose, as in &quot;high fructose corn syrup- goes straight to fat and also makes it far harder to take that fat off later.

I eat lunch at Carl&apos;s Junior on a fairly regular basis while working- because they offer a lettuce wrapped turkey burger.

I skip the mayo and catsup, which are basically whipped fat and sweetened tomato sauce.

I get an iced tea (no sugar) and fried zucchini- because the breading peels very readily, so I end up with something pretty close to a steamed vegetable.

This nets me a very low-carb, fairly low-fat lunch at a reasonable price.
 
 1 vote 
 #21.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:02 AM EDT elithian-1701225 
Sheesh, why not just buy nutriloaf. The prisoners say it taste terrible but it has all the right stuff and easy to prepare; just unwrap it.
 

 #21.2 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:41 PM EDT Daisy70 
Fe02 - Only because there are so very few of those particular restaurants around. I just moved from DC to IN. No Popeyes here. Jack-in-the-Box is mainly West Cost. None in the Mid West. And what&apos;s left of LJS is sporadic at best. KFC isn&apos;t as omnipresent as the others either. I&apos;m just guessing that&apos;s why these didn&apos;t top the list. Sounds like the statisticians didn&apos;t really do a very good job of... statistizing!
 

 #21.3 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 12:52 PM EDT Panic Moon 
Um....am I missing something here? If 24% are unhappy/totally unhappy about their health, would that mean that 76% are ok with it? If you eat a balanced diet and practice &quot;everything in moderation&quot; the occasional fast food meal isn&apos;t going to hurt you, especially when you opt for a more appropriate sized serving like the Happy Meal.

Just for kicks, last year I did a nutritional comparison of the McRib to a few supposedly &quot;healthy&quot; items at restuarants that advertise as being a fresh and/or healthy aternative, and the &quot;healthy&quot; items had more calories and saturated fat, and just as many chemicals I couldn&apos;t pronounce. Do your own homework people - don&apos;t just repost from something you saw in an ad or some meme on Facebook.
 
 1 vote 
 #21.4 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 1:10 PM EDT Steven100 
 So then what the Frick are these people doing in MCD instead of going to the super market and getting and making something besides lousy hamburgers and fries? 

 When you take a survey and admit that you are &quot;unhappy&quot;, (what ever that means) then it&apos;s LONG PAST time to take a good look at your lifestyle and stop bitching about where you eat, when you should be bitching about WHAT you eat. 

 MCD has salads, and other choices. I don&apos;t eat at MCD because I don&apos;t like the food, but if I have to go with a someone who wants to eat there, a salad is always available. 
 
 1 vote 
 #22 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:37 AM EDT skunky-shoes 
You can do more damage at the grocery store with all the cookies, mac&amp;cheeses, hamburger helpers, pot pies, and frozen pizzas, not to mention cases of beer. Obesity is not that much related to choice of place to eat as it is what and how much you put into the mouth.
 

 #22.1 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 2:21 PM EDT Bobbymc 
What a crock! A poll in 2009 showed that over 60% of Americans were obese. How does that relate? I means that with fast food patrons only 1/3 of the obese are unhappy. I guess the other 2/3 don&apos;t eat fast foods or don&apos;t give a damn.
 
 1 vote 
 #23 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:41 AM EDT James Only 
Most of their flavors are lab created. Look it up.
 

 #24 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 9:51 AM EDT brian-1903576 
Why didn&apos;t the author of this article include the data for the general population as a control group comparison? It&apos;d be nice to compare these figures to the general population. What if the general population is 24% unhappy with their health? How else do we put the 24% for McDonald&apos;s into context?

 
 4 votes 
 #25 - Mon Mar 26, 2012 10:01 AM EDT janellect 
But then the article wouldn&apos;t be as interesting.
 

 #25.1 - Wed Mar 28, 2012 12:28 PM EDT Jump to discussion page: 1 2 3 4 Leave a Comment: 
 
 Name: Email Address (will be verified, but never shown) : 
 You&apos;re in Easy Mode. If you prefer, you can use XHTML Mode instead . You&apos;re in XHTML Mode. If you prefer, you can use Easy Mode instead . (XHTML tags allowed - a,b,blockquote,br,code,dd,dl,dt,del,em,h2,h3,h4,i,ins,li,ol,p,pre,q,strong,ul) Post to my Facebook Wall Newsvine Privacy Statement 
 As a new user, you may notice a few temporary content restrictions. Click here for more info . 
Most popular posts
 
older
 26 Mar 2012 7:30am, EDT 
Younger veterans want to work, but face roadblocks
 
newer
 26 Mar 2012 7:49am, EDT 
Stocks set to rise ahead of housing report
 
Most popular posts
 714 Bailed-out AIG wants $30.2 million in tax interest 6 days ago 3202 Scranton, Pa., slashes workers&apos; pay to minimum wage 2 days ago 615 A scandal over rate-fixing is about to hit the US 1 day ago 502 Wells Fargo pays $175M to settle race discrimination probe 8 hours ago 646 Falling prices point to further global slowdown 3 days ago 
Browse
 
 featured , economy , stocks , markets , europe , autos , real-estate , employment , retail , consumer-news , facebook , fed , apple , jobs , banks , wall-street , housing , zillow , greece , ford , cnbc , consumerman , china , video , gm , chrysler , gas-prices , careers , food-inc , ipo , taxes , food , inflation , advertising , bernanke 
 Also 
Top msnbc.com headlines
 3147,10 
Archives
 
 2012 
 July (78) June (220) May (227) April (213) March (324) February (331) January (304) 
 2011 
 December (257) November (267) October (263) September (189) 
 
 
Most Commented

 Scranton, Pa., slashes workers&apos; pay to minimum wage (3202) Bailed-out AIG wants $30.2 million in tax interest (714) US economy still struggling to create jobs (1682) A scandal over rate-fixing is about to hit the US (615) Wells Fargo pays $175M to settle race discrimination probe (502) Falling prices point to further global slowdown (646) High rents, tight credit put many at the mercy of the market (527) IRS gearing up for new responsibilities in health care (326) 
 
Other blogs

 Economy Watch Red Tape Chronicles Technolog PhotoBlog Gadgetbox Open Channel InGame Life Inc. Animal Tracks 
 
 top stories
 3147,10 ©2012 msnbc.com 
 Business on msnbc.com About us Contact Help Site map Careers Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 MSN Privacy Legal Advertise 
 Advertise | AdChoices
	</body>
</document>
