<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008907" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/employee-gift-ideas-under-5-1219.html" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="5" score="0.005246263781378118" bingtitle="Employee Gift Ideas Under $5 | Small Business - Chron.com" webtitle="Employee Gift Ideas Under $5 | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="109"/>
	<description>Jams, preserves, salsas or other specialty condiments ... A gift card to a nearby fast food restaurant may be appreciated ... Her work has appeared online at Bill Savings ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Business Technology&amp;Customer Support | Business Communications&amp;Etiquette | Human Resources | Managing Employees | Setting Up a New Business | Advertising&amp;Marketing | Business&amp;Workplace Regulations | Types of Businesses to Start | More» 
 
 » Business Models&amp;Organizational Structure » Accounting&amp;Bookkeeping » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Finances&amp;Taxes » Running a Business » Money&amp;Debt 
 
 Small Business » Human Resources » Employee Gifts » Employee Gift Ideas Under $5 
 
Employee Gift Ideas Under $5
 by Kristie Lorette, Demand Media 

 
Discover inexpensive gifts for employees.

gift boxes.christmas gifts. image by L. Shat from Fotolia.com
 
 Related Articles 

 Gift Etiquette Between a Boss&amp;an Employee Ideas for Engraving Messages for an Employee Anniversary Implementing Employee Ideas Can an Employer Make His Own Determination as to the Eligibility of an Employee Under the FMLA? Protocol for Dealing With an Employee Who Is Under the Influence in the Workplace Employee Rights Under Subrogation 
 
Businesses often desire to give their employees a little something to say â??thanks.â? Unfortunately, when you are dealing with many employees and a tight budget, you might worry about finding the right thing inexpensively. Online companies usually offer discounts with high quantities of the same item, and you might earn free shipping with a large purchase. Many items can be purchased or made for less than $5 each.
 
Food Items

Something everyone can use and appreciate is food. Jar mixes make functional, attractive gifts that you create in your own kitchen. Dry ingredients for cookies, soups or brownies layered in a jar with instructions attached for adding specific liquids or perishable ingredients to complete the recipe are a nice touch. Jams, preserves, salsas or other specialty condiments can be store-bought or homemade for a simple gift. Put together a pasta dinner in a basket with pasta, a jar of sauce and a can of vegetables. A plate of homemade or store-bought cookies should score points with employees. Stay away from highly allergenic foods like nuts and anything perishable.
 
Home Items

You can purchase jar candles inexpensively, especially in bulk. Potholders and homemade cookbooks are handy and can be thematic by holiday or season. A unique new kitchen gadget is a fun conversation starter that people may rush home to try. Small plants make nice gifts, and may cost under $5 if presented in an inexpensive pot. Tote bags are useful these days, as people are making the effort to consume less plastic from the grocery store. Some websites personalize the bags with your company name or the employeesâ?? monograms.
 
Office Items

Some businesses opt to give employees gifts for use in the office. Believe it or not, you can find pen and pencil sets, journals and pocket calendars online for $5 or less. Calculators always come in handy. Business card holders imprinted with your company name or logo and presented to your employees are useful gifts. Small picture frames or albums are also cost-effective choices. Magnetic sculpture paperweights and pen holders serve a purpose and look nice on desks, and a coffee mug with an instant coffee or hot chocolate packet inside is good for the caffeine lovers.
 
Money

If you prefer not to hand out cash for a small gift, give an equivalent, like a sought-after gift card. A $5 gift card to a coffee shop provides a few coffees or a latte with a pastry. A gift card to a nearby fast food restaurant may be appreciated by employees who enjoy running out for lunch. Gift cards to movie rental stores can make most employees happy. Lottery tickets are also a fun alternative to giving cash.
 
References

 Frugal Families: Great Gifts for Under $5 Office Arrow: Chic on the Cheap: 24 Employee Gift Ideas for Under $20 
 
Resources

 Garret Specialities: Gifts Below $5 
 
About the Author

Kristie Lorette started writing professionally in 1996. She earned her Bachelor of Science degree in marketing and multinational business from Florida State University and a Master of Business Administration from Nova Southeastern University. Her work has appeared online at Bill Savings, Money Smart Life and Mortgage Loan.
 
Photo Credits

 gift boxes.christmas gifts. image by L. Shat from Fotolia.com 
 
More Articles

 
Ideas for Business Gifts
 
Employee Birthday Ideas
 
Themes for Employee Innovation Programs
 
Does Workplace Compliance Fall Under Employee Relations?
 
 
People Also Viewed

 Creative Poster Ideas for Making Business Posters to Show How an Employee Is Recognized or Praised Employee Fundraising Ideas Ideas for Employee Morale Employee Team Building Ideas Ideas for Low Cost Employee Incentives Employee Gifts for Holidays 
 
Related Topics

 Objectives in Human Resources Training on How to Run a Human Resources Department Qualifications for a Human Resources Assistant About Training in Human Resources Advantages&amp;Disadvantages of Not Having Human Resources 
 
 
The Web&apos;s 6 Most Influential Tech Bloggers
 
America&apos;s 9 Most Tech-Friendly Cities
 
Phone Pas: 9 Places You Should Pocket Your Cell Phone
 
10 Highest Valued Tech Companies
 
9 Gadgets You Can&apos;t Live Without
 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
