<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008706" url="http://www.amazon.com/The-McDonaldization-Society-George-Ritzer/dp/1412980127" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="19" score="0.03330714504927599" bingtitle="Amazon.com: The McDonaldization of Society 6 (9781412980128 ..." webtitle="Amazon.com: The McDonaldization of Society 6 (9781412980128): George Ritzer: Books">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000276" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000581" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>... expressing America: A Critique of the Global Credit Card ... Please select the problem below and submit. ... Yoyo.com A Happy Place To Shop For Toys: Zappos Shoes &amp; ...</description>
	<body>
		amazon.com 
 Hello. Sign in to get personalized recommendations. New customer? Start here .   
 FREE Two-Day Shipping: See details 
 
 
 Your Amazon.com  |       Today&apos;s Deals  |  Gifts&amp;Wish Lists  |  Gift Cards   Your Digital Items  |  Your Account  |  Help 
 Shop All Departments 
 
 Search 
 All Departments Amazon Instant Video Appliances Apps for Android Arts, Crafts&amp;Sewing Automotive Baby Beauty Books Cell Phones&amp;Accessories Clothing&amp;Accessories Computers Electronics Gift Cards Grocery&amp;Gourmet Food Health&amp;Personal Care Home&amp;Kitchen Industrial&amp;Scientific Jewelry Kindle Store Magazine Subscriptions Movies&amp;TV MP3 Downloads Music Musical Instruments Office Products Patio, Lawn&amp;Garden Pet Supplies Shoes Software Sports&amp;Outdoors Tools&amp;Home Improvement Toys&amp;Games Video Games Watches   
   
 Cart Cart Wish List 
 
 Books Advanced Search Browse Subjects New Releases Best Sellers The New York Times Best Sellers Children&apos;s Books Textbooks Sell Your Books 
 
 
 
 Quantity: 1 2 3 4 
 or Sign in to turn on 1-Click ordering. or 
 Amazon Prime Free Trial required. Sign up when you check out. Learn More 
 Amazon Prime Free Trial Free Two-Day Shipping is available to Amazon Prime members. To join, click &quot;Add to Cart with FREE Two-Day Shipping&quot; and confirm your Amazon Prime Free Trial sign-up during checkout.

 Amazon Prime members enjoy: 

 Unlimited Free Two-Day Shipping No Minimum Purchase for free or discounted shipping Unlimited instant streaming of thousands of movies and TV shows with Prime instant videos A Kindle book to borrow for free each month from the Kindle Owners&apos; Lending Library 

 Important: Your card will NOT be charged when you start your Free Trial or if you cancel during the trial period. If you&apos;re happy with Amazon Prime, do nothing. At the end of the Free Trial, your membership will automatically upgrade to a full year for $79. 
 Kindle Edition $30.97 (You can always move it to a different device later with Whispersync) Also 
on Kindle , iPhone , iPad , Android , BlackBerry , PC and Mac .     
 More Buying Choices 150 used &amp; new  from  $2.96 Have one to sell? Sell yours here Share 

 
   
   
 Share your own customer images Search inside this book 
 
 The McDonaldization of Society 6 [Paperback] 
 George Ritzer George Ritzer (Author) › Visit Amazon&apos;s George Ritzer Page Find all the books, read about the author, and more. See search results for this author Are you an author? Learn about Author Central (Author) 3.5 out of 5 stars     See all reviews   ( 4 customer reviews ) | 
 
 List Price: $52.00 Price: $33.60 &amp;this item ships for FREE with Super Saver Shipping . Details Deal Price: You Save: $18.40
 (35%) o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o 
 In Stock. 
Ships from and sold by Amazon.com . Gift-wrap available. Want it delivered Monday, July 16? Order it in the next , and choose One-Day Shipping at checkout. Details 
 34 new  from  $9.77 116 used  from  $2.96 
 
 FREE Two-Day Shipping for students on millions of items. Learn more 

 
 

 
 
Formats
 Amazon Price New from Used from Kindle Edition $30.97   -- -- Paperback $33.60   $9.77 $2.96 
 
 
Frequently Bought Together
 
 + + 
 Price For All Three:  $112.22 
 
 Show availability and shipping details 
 Buy the selected items together 
 This item: The McDonaldization of Society 6 by George Ritzer Paperback $33.60 

 Ten Questions: A Sociological Perspective by Joel M. Charon Paperback $68.42 

 Nickel and Dimed: On (Not) Getting By in America by Barbara Ehrenreich Paperback $10.20 

 
 
Customers Who Bought This Item Also Bought
   Page of ( Start over ) Back 
 Social Change by Jay Weinstein $49.95 Ten Questions: A Sociological Perspective by Joel M. Charon $68.42 Our Social World: Introduction to Sociology by Jeanne H. Ballantine 3.7 out of 5 stars   ( 3 ) Random Violence: How We Talk about New Crimes and Ne... by Joel Best $24.95 Cultures and Societies in a Changing World (Soc... by Wendy Griswold 4.0 out of 5 stars   ( 1 ) $34.57 Music and Social Movements: Mobilizing Traditions... by Ron Eyerman $35.57 
 Next 
Editorial Reviews
 
Product Description
 As one of the most eye-opening and popular sociology books of all time, The McDonaldization of Society 6 demonstrates the power of the sociological imagination to today’s readers in a way that few other books have, linking theory to contemporary pop-culture examples that resonate with 21st-century students. This Sixth Edition includes a new concluding Chapter 10“The DeMcDonaldization Society?”that examines recent phenomena like Web 2.0 and its relationship to the McDonaldization thesis. 
About the Author
 
 George Ritzer is Distinguished University Professor at the University of Maryland, where he has also been a Distinguished Scholar-Teacher and won a Teaching Excellence Award. He was awarded the 2000 distinguished Contributions to Teaching Award by the American Sociological Association and an honorary doctorate from LaTrobe University in australia. He is best-known for The McDonaldization of Society (translated into over a dozen languages) and McDonaldization: The Reader 3 as well as several related books, including expressing America: A Critique of the Global Credit Card Society, Enchanting a Disenchanted World 3, The Globalization of Nothing 2 , Globalization: A Basic Text , and The Outsourcing of Everything (forthcoming, with Craig Lair). He is the Editor of the Encyclopedia of Social Theory (2 vols.), the Encyclopedia of Sociology (11 vols.), is currently editing the Encyclopedia of Globalization (5 vols.) , and is Founding Editor of the Journal of Consumer Culture .
 
 
Product Details
 
 Paperback: 328 pages Publisher: Sage Publications, Inc; Sixth Edition edition (June 2, 2010) Language: English ISBN-10: 1412980127 ISBN-13: 978-1412980128 Product Dimensions: 6 x 0.6 x 9 inches Shipping Weight: 1 pounds ( View shipping rates and policies ) Average Customer Review: 3.5 out of 5 stars     See all reviews   ( 4 customer reviews ) Amazon Best Sellers Rank: #55,888 in Books ( See Top 100 in Books ) 
 
  Would you like to update product info , give feedback on images , or tell us about a lower price ? 
 

 

 
   
Customer Reviews
 
 
 4 Reviews 
 5 star :  (1) 4 star :  (1) 3 star :  (1) 2 star :  (1) 1 star :    (0)       
     Average Customer Review 3.5 out of 5 stars ( 4 customer reviews )   
      Share your thoughts with other customers: Create your own review Most Helpful Customer Reviews 
 
 1 of 1 people found the following review helpful 4.0 out of 5 stars book full of facts , December 27, 2011 By  moni - See all my reviews This review is from: The McDonaldization of Society 6 (Paperback) Great book, lot of interesting facts, easy to read, well arranged, good for using in some research papers or essays. Help other customers find the most helpful reviews   Was this review helpful to you?  Yes No Report abuse | Permalink Comment   Comment 
 
 2 of 3 people found the following review helpful 3.0 out of 5 stars Interesting concept conveyed in a disappointingly average text , October 26, 2011 By  Jonathan (Philadelphia, PA USA) - See all my reviews 
 (VINE VOICE)    Amazon Verified Purchase ( What&apos;s this? ) This review is from: The McDonaldization of Society 6 (Paperback) I took an Introduction to Sociology course that used both this and Jon Witt&apos;s The Big Picture: A Sociology Primer . While I found Witt&apos;s book to be engaging and informative to someone new to the field, I did not enoy Ritzer&apos;s book very much. Not to say he doesn&apos;t have good ideas, but I found the writing bland and, at times, overly technical.

Ritzer argues that the fast-food priciples epitomized by McDonald&apos;s - efficiency, calculability, predictability and control - are permeating society as a whole. He takes examples from the mundane (food shopping) to the extravagent (climbing Mount Everest) to the horrifyingly extreme (the Holocaust) to illustrate his point. He also devotes time to detailing how one can &quot;deMcDonaldize&quot; society. He also has extensive endnotes for further reading.

However, this book contains some very serious flaws. It is very obvious that Ritzer views this McDonaldization as a completely negative entity, glossing over the fact that, in non-extreme doses, some of those four priciples can be good things. His bias is so evident he goes as far to quote Weber and say that McDonaldization is leading us into a &quot;polar night of icy darkness.&quot; I find it a little hard to take his text seriously when he uses such metaphors.

He also devotes a chapter to &quot;Globalization and McDonaldization,&quot; which starts out well enough but ends up being little more than a plug for another of Ritzer&apos;s books that made my head hurt with its liberal use of jargon and confusing syntax (&quot;Although the grobalization of nothing is at odds with the glocalization of something,... the grobalization of nothing is also at odds with the grobalization of something... there is no conflict between the grobalization and the glocalization of nothing.&quot; - The whole chapter reads like that).

And one more thing that bothered me - a pet peeve, I know, but still - was that the kerning (text spacing, or the space between the letters) is sometimes noticably different from page to page. As someone who has a passing knowledge of basic layout, this irked me.

This text conveys some very interesting concepts, but it is executed in a less-than-stellar manner. I&apos;d take this book a chapter at a time to minimize frustration. Help other customers find the most helpful reviews   Was this review helpful to you?  Yes No Report abuse | Permalink Comment   Comment (1) 
 
 4 of 14 people found the following review helpful 2.0 out of 5 stars McDonalds is like the Holocaust? , February 27, 2011 By  Just Me (here and there across the USA) - See all my reviews This review is from: The McDonaldization of Society 6 (Paperback) Argument is taken too far when he compares McDonalds to the Holocaust. Interesting topic, but the argument is stretched too thin on qustionable statements and extreme views. Help other customers find the most helpful reviews   Was this review helpful to you?  Yes No Report abuse | Permalink Comment   Comments (2) 
 Share your thoughts with other customers:  Create your own review ›   See all 4 customer reviews...       Most Recent Customer Reviews 
 
 5.0 out of 5 stars not a scratch!!1 
I bought this book immediately following finals, getting an AMAZING deal on this BRAND NEW book!!! It doesn&apos;t have a scratch, mark, or any highlighting in it!! Read more Published 18 months ago by Bryce M. Mitchell 
 
 Search Customer Reviews Only search this product&apos;s reviews 
 
 ›   See all 4 customer reviews... 
 
 
 All Lists&amp;Registries › Wish List › Gift Organizer › Wedding Registry › Baby Registry › Amazon Remembers 
 
 Unlimited Instant Videos 
 Prime Instant Videos Unlimited streaming of thousands of
movies and TV shows with Amazon Prime Learn More About Amazon Prime Amazon Instant Video Store Rent or buy hit movies and TV shows
to stream or download Your Video Library Your movies and TV shows
stored in the cloud Watch Anywhere Watch instantly on your Kindle Fire,
TV, Blu-ray player, or set-top box 
 MP3s&amp;Cloud Player 20 million songs, play anywhere 
 MP3 Music Store Shop 20 million songs Cloud Player for Web Play from any browser Cloud Player for Android For Kindle Fire, Android phones, and tablets Amazon MP3 for Mobile For BlackBerry and Palm 
 Amazon Cloud Drive 5 GB of free storage 
 Your Cloud Drive 5 GB of free storage Get the Desktop App For Windows and Mac Learn More About Cloud Drive 
 Kindle 
 Kindle $79 Lighter, smaller, faster Kindle Touch $99 Simple-to-use touchscreen Kindle Touch 3G $149 The top-of-the-line e-reader Kindle Fire $199 Vibrant color, movies, apps, and more Kindle DX $379 Large 9.7&quot; E Ink Display Accessories Kindle Owners&apos; Lending Library With Prime, Kindle owners read for free Kindle Cloud Reader Read your Kindle books in a browser Free Kindle Reading Apps For PC, iPad, iPhone, Android, and more Kindle Books Newsstand Kindle Store Manage Your Kindle 
 Appstore for Android Get a premium app for free today 
 Apps Games Amazon Apps Kindle, mobile shopping, MP3, and more Your Apps and Devices View your apps and manage your devices 
 Digital Games&amp;Software 
 Game Downloads For PC and Mac Software Downloads For PC and Mac Your Games&amp;Software Library 
 Audible Audiobooks 
 Audible Membership Get to know Audible Audible Audiobooks&amp;More Bestsellers New&amp;Notable Listener Favorites 
 Books 
 Books Kindle Books Children&apos;s Books Textbooks Audiobooks Magazines 
 Movies, Music&amp;Games 
 Movies&amp;TV Blu-ray Amazon Instant Video Music MP3 Downloads Musical Instruments Video Games Game Downloads 
 Electronics&amp;Computers 
 TV&amp;Video Home Audio&amp;Theater Camera, Photo&amp;Video Cell Phones&amp;Accessories Video Games MP3 Players&amp;Accessories Car Electronics&amp;GPS Appliances Musical Instruments Laptops, Tablets&amp;Netbooks Desktops&amp;Servers Computer Accessories&amp;Peripherals External drives, mice, networking&amp;more Computer Parts&amp;Components Software PC Games Printers&amp;Ink Office&amp;School Supplies 
 Home, Garden&amp;Tools 
 Kitchen&amp;Dining Furniture&amp;Dcor Bedding&amp;Bath Appliances Patio, Lawn&amp;Garden Home Improvement Power&amp;Hand Tools Lamps&amp;Light Fixtures Kitchen&amp;Bath Fixtures Hardware Building Supplies Arts, Crafts&amp;Sewing Pet Supplies 
 Grocery, Health&amp;Beauty 
 Grocery&amp;Gourmet Food Natural&amp;Organic Health&amp;Personal Care Beauty 
 Toys, Kids&amp;Baby 
 Toys&amp;Games Baby Clothing (Kids&amp;Baby) Video Games for Kids 
 Clothing, Shoes&amp;Jewelry 
 Clothing Shoes Handbags Accessories Luggage Jewelry Watches 
 Sports&amp;Outdoors 
 Exercise&amp;Fitness Outdoor Recreation Athletic&amp;Outdoor Clothing Team Sports Bikes&amp;Scooters Golf Boating&amp;Water Sports Fan Shop All Sports&amp;Outdoors 
 Automotive&amp;Industrial 
 Automotive Parts&amp;Accessories Automotive Tools&amp;Equipment Car Electronics&amp;GPS Tires&amp;Wheels Motorcycle&amp;ATV Industrial&amp;Scientific 
 
 
Customers Also Bought Items By
 Front Cover  | Table of Contents  | First Pages  | Index  | Surprise Me! 
 Search Inside This Book: 
 Inside This Book ( learn more ) Browse Sample Pages: 
 Front Cover  | Table of Contents  | First Pages  | Index  | Surprise Me! 
 Search Inside This Book: 
 
 
What Other Items Do Customers Buy After Viewing This Item?

 The McDonaldization of Society   by George F. Ritzer  Paperback 
 4.0 out of 5 stars   ( 24 ) 
 The McDonaldization of Society: An Investigation Into the Changing Character of Contemporary Social Life   by George Ritzer  Paperback 
 4.3 out of 5 stars   ( 7 ) 
 The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life   by Erving Goffman  Paperback 
 4.3 out of 5 stars   ( 21 ) 
 $10.85 McDonaldization: The Reader   by George F. Ritzer  Paperback 
 4.7 out of 5 stars   ( 3 ) 
 $47.23 
 › Explore similar items 
 
Tag this product
   ( What&apos;s this? ) Think of a tag as a keyword or label you consider is strongly related to this product.
Tags will help all customers organize and find favorite items. ›   Explore product tags Search Products Tagged with   See most popular tags 
 Like 1342138221 false -1 10 10 9 ( 10 ) 
 
 
Customer Discussions
 
Listmania!
 
So You&apos;d Like to...
 
 
Look for Similar Items by Category
 
 Books &gt; Education&amp;Reference Books &gt; New&amp;Used Textbooks &gt; Social Sciences &gt; Sociology Books &gt; Politics&amp;Social Sciences &gt; Social Sciences 
 
Look for Similar Items by Subject
 Search Books by subject: 
 Sociology 
 Fast food restaurants 
 Management 
 Social aspects 
 Social structure 
 United States 
 Supplementals&amp;Ancillaries 
 Social Science 
 Social Science / Sociology / General 
 Sociology - General 
 Cultural studies 
 Social theory 
 USA 
 Social Sciences: Textbooks&amp;Study Guides 

 
i.e., each book must be in subject 1 AND subject 2 AND ...
  
 
 
Feedback
 
 If you need help or have a question for Customer Service, contact us . 
  Would you like to update product info , give feedback on images , or tell us about a lower price ? 
 Is there any other feedback you would like to provide? Click here 
 
 Your comments can help make our site better for everyone. Please note that we are unable to respond directly to all feedback submitted via this form, but we&apos;ll ask you to sign in so we can contact you if needed. Feedback is limited to 1000 characters. 

 
 
 
Feedback
 Thanks for your feedback. 
We appreciate your effort to make our site better. Please note that we are unable to respond directly to all submissions made via this form.


 
 
 Your Recent History   ( What&apos;s this? ) 
 
 
 
After viewing product detail pages or search results, look here to find an easy way to navigate back to pages you are interested in.
 › View and edit your browsing history 
 
 
After viewing product detail pages or search results, look here to find an easy way to navigate back to pages you are interested in.
 › View and edit your browsing history 
 
 
 
 Get to Know Us 
 Careers Investor Relations Press Releases Amazon and Our Planet Amazon in the Community 
 Make Money with Us 
 Sell on Amazon Become an Affiliate Advertise Your Products Independently Publish with Us › See all 
 Let Us Help You 
 Shipping Rates&amp;Policies Amazon Prime Returns Are Easy Manage Your Kindle Help 
 
 Canada China France Germany Italy Japan Spain United Kingdom 
 AbeBooks
 Rare Books
&amp;Textbooks AmazonLocal
 Great Local Deals
in Your City AmazonSupply
 Business, Industrial
&amp;Scientific Supplies AmazonWebServices
 Scalable
Cloud Services AmazonWireless
 Cellphones&amp;
Wireless Plans Askville
 Community
Answers Audible
 Download
Audio Books BeautyBar.com
 Prestige Beauty
Delivered   Book Depository
 Books With Free
Delivery Worldwide CreateSpace
 Indie Publishing
Made Easy Diapers.com
 Everything
But The Baby DPReview
 Digital
Photography Fabric
 Sewing, Quilting
&amp;Knitting IMDb
 Movies, TV
&amp;Celebrities Junglee.com
 Shop Online
in India MYHABIT
 Private Fashion
Designer Sales   Shopbop
 Designer
Fashion Brands Soap.com
 Health, Beauty&amp;
Home Essentials Wag.com
 Everything
For Your Pet Warehouse Deals
 Open-Box
Discounts Woot
 Never Gonna
Give You Up Yoyo.com
 A Happy Place
To Shop For Toys Zappos
 Shoes&amp;
Clothing   
 Conditions of Use Privacy Notice Interest-Based Ads 1996-2012, Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates
	</body>
</document>
