<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008905" url="http://feefighters.com/blog/credit-card-processing-for-fast-foodsmall-restaurants/" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="2" score="0.0031937921872486003" bingtitle="Credit Card Processing for Fast Food/Small Restaurants" webtitle="Credit Card Processing for Fast Food/Small Restaurants">
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Have you ever wondered how much a fast food shop pays in credit card processing fees? I have, since transaction size tends to be small (one component in the ...</description>
	<body>
		FeeFighters Business Chops 
 
 Twitter Facebook RSS 
 Save 40% on Your Credit Card Processing 
in 3 Minutes. 
 Home / Business / News / Payments / Quick Hits / Samurai / RSS 
 Permalink to this post Uncategorized 
Credit Card Processing for Fast Food/Small Restaurants
 
By Stella 
 
 

Have you ever wondered how much a fast food shop pays in credit card processing fees?  I have, since transaction size tends to be small (one component in the calculation of fees is transaction size). Since healthy sandwich shops seem to be the craze, let’s examine a sandwich shop. 

So for an example, let’s look at Jimmy John’s, which has about $850,000 in revenue per store. About a quarter of that is collected in credit card and debit card sales according to the 2008 Hitachi Consulting Study of Consumer Payment Preferences (for fast food restaurants).

The average interchange rate that FeeFighters expects such a restaurant to have is in the neighborhood of $0.1255 + 1.56% for transactions greater than $15 and about $0.04 + 1.60% on transactions less than $15.

If we assume that 50%  transactions are&lt;$15 that the average size for such a small transaction is $7.50 while the average size of a transaction&gt;$15 is $20 (which means that this restaurants overall ticket size is about $14) then the average interchange rate for this restaurant is about 2.16%.

FeeFighters’proprietary software has read thousands of customer bills, only to find that the average restaurant pays around 0.75%+$.20 markup above interchange, meaning this is about 2.2% for a sale of $14.

If we apply the overall rate of 4.36% (2.16% + 2.2%) to the 27% of this restaurant’s $850,000 in sales we can calculate that this restaurant will pay $10,006 per year in credit card processing fees.

Yikes!

Restaurant owners can get the best deal on credit card processing by comparison shopping for a processor using FeeFighters. Start an auction now to keep more of your hard earned money!

Image thanks to http://www.flickr.com/photos/28233229@N00/1407449118/
 
 We&apos;re a comparison shopping website for credit card processing. Our unique auction process leads to an average savings of 40%. Check us out and tell your friends about us for a $25 gift card!

p.s. We also have a simple and cheap an all-in-one solution for your online payments ... Check it out!
 
 Twitter Updates 

 FeeFighters (@feefighters) is hiring a Ops / sysadmin http://t.co/qHmeaTrO 06:43:16 AM June 06, 2012 FeeFighters (@feefighters) is hiring a Rails Generalist Ninja http://t.co/7szvxS5Z 06:41:47 AM June 06, 2012 What will the JOBS law actually accomplish? A quick description for startups. | Entrepreneurs Unpluggd http://t.co/EE8luEH3 01:45:18 PM April 05, 2012 @groupon Wassup bro? Go GroupFeeFightersOn! 05:20:02 AM March 24, 2012 in reply to Groupon Good news! FeeFighters is now a part of @groupon Now we&apos;re fighting fees with the combined power of GroupFeeFighterson! http://t.co/05sQMUnb 07:15:05 PM March 23, 2012 
 
Most Popular

 1 How Can A Free Conference Call Be Free? 2 The 10 Worst Businesses To Start 3 FeeFighters Loses BBB Accreditation Over Investigative Blog Post 4 Meet Samurai: The Most Powerful Way to Accept Payments Online 5 Largest Merchant Acquirers 6 The BBB is a F*&lt;!
	</body>
</document>
