<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008219" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/333/1480655/restaurant/Kabob-House-Yakima" time="2012-07-13-01:42" support="3" score="0.000988167864011499" bingtitle="Kabob House - Yakima | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Kabob House - Yakima | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>... eye contact with one young male there took a seat . ... find myself being forced to go to Yakima to pick up ... The service can be slow (compared to a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Yakima » Yakima » Kabob House 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Calgary Los Angeles New York Portland Sacramento Seattle Vancouver More... 
 
Kabob House
 
(509) 469-0504
 Yakima 3609 W Nob Hill Blvd 
 Yakima , WA 98902 
 mykabobhouse.com 

Added by FatMom 
 See all 61 reviews Cuisine Mediterranean , Middle Eastern , Greek Features Delivery , Kid Friendly , Outdoor Dining Menu $ Under $10 per entree Mast-o-museer, Mast-o-khiyar, Torshi, Hummus, Dolmas, Panner- Sabzi... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   389 people have voted 89 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 23, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Hussy ( 1 review ) I&apos;ve been once ,I had a spicy hummus with pitta and gyro sandwich.. It was awesome,, they have new staff to like lamb and beef chengeh and chkn showarm they look good l,, Ill try them next time cuz friend of mind hadthe chengeh he went crazy he says it was soo tender and soft;,) 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 22, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Bethanie L. ( 2 reviews ) Be aware: when I first started coming here, the falafel tasted homemade. The second time I had them, they were huge and dry. I told the waitress they weren&apos;t very good and she said they vary by who makes them and it comes from a box mix! Seriously?! Their Dolma are likely from a can. They sell both in their store. I also know their baklava is from a frozen package as I saw one of the waitresses puting more out. That being said the highlights of the place is their hummus, gyros, kabobs and moussaka. What I don&apos;t care for is their inconsistency in the dishes they carry daily, their very spotty and sometimes unknowledgeable staff and their not so clean bathroom (once it was down right disgusting!). I know this sounds like a bad review but the dishes above keep us coming back for more. It looks as though they&apos;ll have some competition in the near future with a restaurant called ”Mediterranean Kabob House” opening up just a few blocks away. Kabob House better think about stepping up their game! May 24, 2012 Likes it Delicious by Tom ( 1 review ) The Lamb kabob was tender and grilled perfectly. Also had a Gyro dinner, which was also delicious. Super polite and friendly staff. The kitchen staff all wore gloves while preparing the food. We even had a sample of the Baklava which was wonderful. The prices were exceptional for the quality and amount of food given. Definitely a thumbs up. Would love to have the Kabob House in Wenatchee! March 8, 2012 Really likes it revisited march 5th bad night by darren98909 ( 29 reviews ) The day after the unexpected experience I received. I called the manager explained what happened. Believe it or not he heard about the incident before I called. To refresh your memory or just reading this for the first time. I went there and sat there at a table for over 10 min without any one approaching us. We ended up leaving. Now getting back to the review. The manager took care of the matter and was resolved to all parties involved. I was happy with the outcome. I will be back there again real soon. If you have a problem with the food or service at any establishment. I encourage you to say something it is the only way they can improve or know what is either happening or not happening. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful +1 more review from darren98909 March 5, 2012 Must have been a bad night I have gone to the Kabob House many times. I drive all the way over from Terrace Hights. I was looking forward to another excellent dinner. However that never happened. We made it there safely got there before closing it was around 6:30pm. There three staff on hand that I saw and including us there were two tables of two and one large table of about 8 guys right when you walk in. Anyway, as we entered and a few other times made eye contact with one young male there took a seat . We sat there... more» I have gone to the Kabob House many times. I drive all the way over from Terrace Hights. I was looking forward to another excellent dinner. However that never happened. We made it there safely got there before closing it was around 6:30pm. There three staff on hand that I saw and including us there were two tables of two and one large table of about 8 guys right when you walk in. Anyway, as we entered and a few other times made eye contact with one young male there took a seat . We sat there for over 10 minutes not one person approached us. decided to get up and leave. the staff looked at us as we were leaving. i thanked them for the lack of service. Not one of them said a word just let us go. My advise to you is you can not let that happen again. due to you will be getting some competition down the road. If you can not get to me right away at least say something so I know you know i exist. I will be calling the manager or owner tomorrow to share my experience. April 6, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Well... ? by colesmeister ( 11 reviews ) First let me say to take what I say with a grain of salt because the only way to truly tell if a restaurant is good is to go there yourself. Having said that, I will say that I won&apos;t be back to the Kabob House. The meat was tough. No getting around that. The Greek salad was boring in my mind. And it may be that I just don&apos;t like this type of cooking, the seasoning and all. (I thought the beef had a mean salty streak to it.) But try it. A lot of people like Kabob House. I&apos;m just not one of them. February 12, 2012 Likes it SO GOOD! by Matt Johnson ( 3 reviews ) I live in Ellensburg, but often find myself being forced to go to Yakima to pick up things not available in the Burg. Kabob House makes this trip 100x more bearable. Their food is FANTASTIC for a wonderful price. We showed up hungry, ate our souls out, and brought home 2 doggie bags. Most dinners come with a delicious Greek Salad, but I highly recommend getting the veggie tray to start off with (Ask for a side of their awesome hummus to go with it). Their pitas are always warm and delicious. Their staff is very enjoyable and friendly and Kabob House has an adorable atmosphere. I&apos;ve heard rumors that they may be coming to Ellensburg, and my only complaint about the restaurant is that they aren&apos;t over here now! GO THERE NOW! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful March 16, 2011 Likes it Fresh, healthy Mediterranean Food at a fair price! by Tim D. ( 19 reviews ) I&apos;ve eaten at Kabob House several times and find it a great little restaurant. The food is prepared before you by expert cooks and the variety and taste is amazing. I particularly like the lamb kabobs. The atmosphere of the place is also very well-done and the staff is friendly. The Kabob House also features a nice little&quot;Mediterranean deli&quot;in the same building, so you can pick up hard-to-find items like tahini, Persian tea, and fava beans and make some of these dishes at home. I often make my own hummus at home using Kabob House deli ingredients. The service can be slow (compared to a fast food restaurant), but that is because quality food is not fast food. The main dishes there are prepared fresh per order. You will be glad you waited and you are in for a wonderful surprise. By the way, Mediterranean food is not only very tasty, but very healthy food. It&apos;s also a nice change from the&quot;same old-same old foods&quot;we find at other restaurants. Enjoy! :-) 2 out of 2 found this review helpful July 18, 2010 Likes it Good fresh food by Kate ( 28 reviews ) The best thing about Kabob House is definitely the freshness and flavor of the food. It&apos;s a great Mediterranean restaurant that also has a little store to sell some of their ingredients that may be difficult to track down elsewhere. The Gyros lunch was fantastic, and the lamb kabob was delicious. Some of the staff is a little off-ish, but friendly for the most part. They do take out and dine in. If you like Mediterranean food, you&apos;ll be happy with the freshness and the price. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful October 28, 2010 Likes it LOVE it! by Karrilee ( 13 reviews ) Someone told me about the Kabob House awhile ago... they knew I loved Mediterranean food! I have gone several times - for lunch and for dinner and the food is ALWAYS incredible! We love the lamb gyros... the Greek salad ...thehummus plate... the tea... the saffron rice... I could go on and on! The staff is helpful and quick - while not super friendly. I need to go back now that they have expanded. My only complaints were how crowded it was at lunch when trying to meet with friends... and sometimes the video/music that they had playing on the tv was a little less than family friendly for young kids (in my opinion). But honestly - if that is a concern - do not let it stop you! Place an order to go - the prices are great and the food is amazing! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful March 19, 2011 Likes it Good, but slow by Biting Bacon ( 48 reviews ) The food is good and satisfying. I feel that it is a good deal for the price. However, as delish as the food is, the service is a bit slow. If that can be remedied, this would be one of my absolute fav&apos;s. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful +1 more review from Biting Bacon December 19, 2010 Mobile review The food was authentic and delicious. The service was personable but a bit slow. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful January 12, 2012 Loved It by Paul ( 9 reviews ) We stopped at this place and fell in love with it and have been back several times. Great food everytime we have visited! I love the rice and Greek Salad that comes with your meal. We have this on our list of places that we will go back to... and in Yakima that is a very short list! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful July 15, 2010 Likes it Very different for Yakima by Cranky Diner ( 51 reviews ) After one visit to the Kabob House I was hooked. The location is a little unlikely for a restaurant; a small strip mall in the middle of what is mostly a residential neighborhood. It is easy to miss it while going down Nob Hill, but once you have been there, you will want to come back. I had the chicken kabob during my most recent visit. The chicken was juicy and flavorful. Served along side a green salad or Greek salad along with saffron rice. My wife had a gyro, filled to the brim with good stuff. We also had the hummus plate. Hummus isn&apos;t all that uncommon anymore, but between the hummus plate and our entrées, we left full and happy. The owners also have a Mediterranean/middle eastern grocery store, selling various ingredients of such origin. The wait staff was pretty enthusiastic about some of the cookies and other packaged goods. I&apos;ll definitely be back. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 8, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it pay attention! by Bill ( 4 reviews ) They have an absolute best deal in town going here. ...but they have gotten so complacent it is amazing! I called in an order to go and I finally gave up after 45 minutes of being ignored. The lady that runs this better treat it and its customers like the goose that lays the golden eggs. They have great food and value! ...if they dont get too complacent 3 out of 4 found this review helpful March 24, 2011 Really likes it Mobile review by Horatio ( 33 reviews ) Hey bacon, food gotta cook. Don&apos;t come out of a can. This place serves yummy food. Period. January 13, 2011 Likes it Mmmm by travelchick ( 6 reviews ) Unique favors! I have gone back time and time again. I stick to my usual, but the taste never gets old. Consistant and great service. A fantastic traditional family run restaurant! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful October 30, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Shawn ( 8 reviews ) Great food, but horrible service and rude staff. Think I may be done +1 more review from Shawn October 2, 2011 Mobile review Time to hire some new servers that don&apos;t stand around and drink their water while we wait 20 minutes to order... November 12, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Starla ( 3 reviews ) The food is awesome. It&apos;s satisfying but healthy, and it never leaves you feeling gross afterwards. However, I feel the other reviewers&apos; complaints about the service. It was great when they first opened, and it was just the owners (who are lovely people) running the place. But things have really fallen off lately. Seriously, fire your lazy, hipster,&quot;I&apos;m-too-good-for-this-job&quot;staff, and hire some new servers. January 11, 2011 Likes it Mr. Eat Out A Lot by Wes ( 10 reviews ) Great menu, excellent food,&amp;outstanding service! 1 out of 2 found this review helpful September 13, 2010 Likes it Pita and Hummus!!! by GetInMyBelly ( 11 reviews ) The hummus was so delicious! My boyfriend and I both had the gyro, let me just say I have never had meat that delicious. We&apos;re hooked! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful November 28, 2010 Likes it Pretty, pretty, pretty good. by Melea ( 7 reviews ) Despite the tasteless whole wheat pita bread, the gyros are delicious and satisfying. The Greek salads are fresh and crunchy. But the hummus ... oh, the hummus steals the show. It&apos;s creamy and has a rich flavor that I crave. I do not recommend the baklava. I thought it tasted like it came out of a box. Overall, Kabob House is pretty darn good. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful 
 Show 38 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by sam outside by ERIC Kabob House 
 All 7 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Sack Yakima Baskin-Robbins $ Yakima - Desserts/Ice Cream Last Frontier Restaurant Yakima - American Sloppy Slaw 69% $$ Yakima - American, Barbecue, Burgers Arctic Circle $ Yakima - Burgers 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 kabob house yakima kabob house yakima menu kabob house greek food yakima wa greek kabob yakima 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
