<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008488" url="http://gflunches.blogspot.com/2012/03/eat-out-chick-fil.html" time="2012-07-13-01:57" support="6" score="0.017058733721542114" bingtitle="Living Life! Gluten-Free: Eat Out! - Chick-fil-a" webtitle="Living Life! Gluten-Free: Eat Out! - Chick-fil-a">
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... quality of my food and actually enjoy my meal ... Is it wrong to love a fast-food restaurant? Because I am head ... gluten-free offerings, including sauces, condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Friday, March 23, 2012 
 
Eat Out! - Chick-fil-a
 Hands down one of the most difficult parts of dealing with living gluten-free is eating out. In your own kitchen you can control the ingredients, quality, and watch for cross contamination. When you eat out you&apos;re at the mercy of the chef and waiters at what ever restaurant you&apos;ve chosen, and unfortunately sometimes they don&apos;t take food allergies as seriously as they should.   
 
 But...I have good news! 
 
 
 There are several restaurants I&apos;ve found where I can eat and feel completely at ease about the quality of my food and actually enjoy my meal without worrying about whether or not I&apos;ll be sick. In these posts I&apos;ll highlight the restaurants I enjoy eating at now that I&apos;m gluten-free, but remember everybody&apos;s different and everyone will react differently to food so don&apos;t take my analysis as the infallible word. :) 
 
 
 
 Today&apos;s restaurant is... Chick-fil-a ! 
 Is it wrong to love a fast-food restaurant? Because I am head over heels for Chick-fil-a and I can&apos;t see that changing anytime soon.&lt;---I sound like a teenager in their first relationship...pathetic :/ 
 Truett Cathy first graced the South with his culinary genius in 1946 when he opened The Dwarf Grill in Atlanta, Georgia. Eighteen years later in 1964, Cathy invented his now infamous original chicken sandwich. This (delicious) culinary invention laid the foundation for the future success of Chick-fil-a restaurants as a whole.  
 Because their menu (mainly) consists of breaded chicken, I was so sad when I went gluten-free because I thought that meant I couldn&apos;t eat there anymore. Much to my delight, I soon found out that wasn&apos;t the case. They may market their breaded chicken heavily through advertisements displaying their chicken sandwich, chicken nuggets or even their chicken minis at breakfast time, but there are so many options available for anyone gluten-free! I&apos;ll list (and link) the options below in my highlights. 
 Chick-fil-a, how much do I love thee? Let me count the ways... 
 1. The workers are fantastic! Every employee I&apos;ve met has been incredibly helpful, understanding and seems genuinely happy even though they&apos;re at work (which, as anyone knows, is a feat!) They keep the restaurants clean, do their jobs efficiently and prepare your food in a timely manner, what more could you ask for?    To exemplify their employees helpfulness, I have a story. My first trip to Chick-fil-a after going gluten-free was a tentative one. I walked in thinking the only thing I could have was a grilled chicken salad and a glass of ice water. I walked up to the counter while quietly said goodbye my Combo #1s of yesteryear and ordered. I think I asked the cashier about every aspect of that salad I could think of; preparation, ingredients, packaging, etc. After multiple times of reminding her not to add croutons to my salad she looked up and asked if I had a gluten allergy. Let me stop here and say that I was absolutely astounded that she even knew gluten-allergies existed; sometimes I feel like people think others are making it up. Anyway back to the story, I said that I was gluten-free and she went above and beyond her duties and had a salad and piece of chicken freshly prepared for me. She also told me that beginning in January of 2012 Chick-fil-a was going to start marketing a healthier option for their kid&apos;s menu which included grilled chicken nuggets as the meat option. Grilled. Chicken. Nuggets. Yum! She went on to say that I could go ahead and ask for grilled chicken nuggets at anytime for the remainder of 2011 (this was in November) and they would prepare them for me! THAT, is quality service. She didn&apos;t have to prepare my meal completely fresh and she certainly didn&apos;t have to explain Chick-fil-a&apos;s new menu addition for 2012 while stating that I could ask for and receive it right then. That story has solidified Chick-fil-a in the #1 spot of my favorite restaurants. While I&apos;m sure that means nothing to them, it means so much to me to know that their service and quality means that I can have a meal without worry. 
 2. They have SO many options. Unlike many fast food restaurants I have multiple meal options when I go to Chick-fil-a! They even have a page on their website devoted to Gluten Information, click here to go.   Entree     Chargrilled Chicken Filet (no bun)      Chargrilled Chicken Garden Salad     Chargrilled Chicken and Fruit Salad     Grilled Chicken Nuggets     Sides      Fruit Cup      Side Salad     Cole Slaw     Carrot and Raisin Salad     Waffle Fries     Yogurt Parfait     Buddy Fruits Fruit To Go Applesauce    Breakfast     Bacon       Egg     Sausage Patty     American Cheese     Hash Browns         Click the link above to see a complete list of their gluten-free offerings, including sauces, condiments, and salad dressings. 
 3. As I&apos;ve stated in my other restaurant reviews, cleanliness is extremely important to me and Chick-fil-a always scores a perfect ten in this department. 
 4. Simply put, their food is fantastically delicious! 
 Kudos to Truett Cathy for the food and the dream and a big thank you to Chick-fil-a restaurants as a whole who have kept Cathy&apos;s dedication to wonderful food and service alive and thriving. You appeal to the mass market while taking into consideration the smaller, diverse market of allergen sufferers. Thank you for not forgetting us! For more information, visit the  Chick-fil-a Allergen Information page on their website. Posted by Rachel at 12:09 PM Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Restaurant , Review 
No comments:
 
 
Post a Comment


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Followers
 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (8) 
 ►  May (1) 
 What a Deal! - Rudi&apos;s Bakery 
 

 ►  April (1) 
 Eat It! - Candy 
 

 ▼  March (6) 
 Make it! - Homemade Potato Chips Eat Out! - Chick-fil-a Eat Out! - The Big 3 - McDonalds Eat It! - Cereal Eat Out! - Chipotle Happy St. Patrick&apos;s Day! 
 
 
 
About Me
 Rachel A blog about the adventures of learning to live gluten-free after 20 years without dietary restrictions. A highlight of restaurants, food and recipes tailored to young adults with minimal time and no money to spare. View my complete profile 
 
 Simple template. Template images by andynwt . Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
