<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008544" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/45031111/Fast-Food-Restaurant-Business-Plan" time="2012-07-13-02:00" support="70" score="0.1815678013533585" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan - Scribd" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan">
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000203" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001514" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000326" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan Fresin Fries ... Point of Purchase We will use &quot;tray toppers&quot; to ... further, we will add new categories to our menu ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan Fresin Fries Executive Summary Fresin Fries is a locally owned fast food outlet that will be positioned as an international franchise through our creative approach to the company&apos;s image and detail presentation. Fresin Fries will provide a combination of excellent food at value pricing, with fun packaging and atmosphere. Fresin Fries is the answer to an increasing demand for snack-type fast food, to be consumed while window shopping and walking around inside a shopping mall. In today&apos;s highly competitive environment, it is becoming increasingly difficult to differentiate one fast food outlet from another. Singapore, a city state, is now becoming the model metropolis for Asia&apos;s new economic boom. With more than 11 million visitors yearly, mainly from neighboring countries (Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand and the Philippines), Singapore&apos;s retail sector is the strongest in the region. Our main priority is to establish one outlet in a crowded mall, preferably in one of prominent shopping malls in Singapore. Later, our effort will be a further development of more retail outlets in the surrounding area. This plan is prepared to obtain a location for the initial launch of this concept. Additional financing will need to be secured for the two subsequent outlets, anticipated in month 13 and early in year three. The financing, in addition to the capital contributions from shareholders, will allow Fresin Fries to successfully open and expand through year two. The initial capital investment will allow Fresin Fries to provide its customers with a value-driven, entertaining experience through the creativity of its founders. Fresin Fries will entice youngsters to bring their friends and family with our innovative environment, fresh-cut Belgian fries, and selection of unique signature dipping sauces. Please note that all tables are in Singaporean Dollars (1 USD= S$1.60) 1.1 Objectives y To establish a presence as a successful local fast food outlets and gain a market share in Singapore&apos;s fast food industry. y To make Fresin Fries a destination spot for mall-goers.   y To expand into a number of outlets by year three, and sell the franchise to neighboring metropolitan cities, such as Jakarta, Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok and Manila. 1.2 Mission Our main goal is to be one of the most successful fast food outlets in Singapore, starting with one retail outlet located inside a major shopping mall as a &quot;market tester.&quot; Fresin Fries will strive to be a premier local fast food brand in the local marketplace. We want our customers to have the total experience when visiting our outlet(s) and website as they will learn about this fascinating new &quot;pop culture.&quot; We will sell merchandise from pre-packaged sauces and t-shirts, to potato cutters, all with our official brand attached to them. Our main focus will be serving high-quality food at a great value. 1.3 Keys to Success To succeed in this business we must: y Create a unique, innovative, entertaining menu that will differentiate us from the rest of the competition. y Control costs at all times, in all areas and implement a conservative approach to growth policy. Although, we provide more than enough fund to open more than one outlet, we want to be on the safe side of the business. y Sell the products that are of the highest quality, as well as keeping the customers happy with all of our product categories from food to store merchandising. y Provide 100% satisfaction to our customers and maintaining the level of excellent services among other competitors. y Encourage the two most important values in fast food business: brand and image, as these two ingredients are a couple of main drivers in marketing communications. y Get access to high-traffic shopping malls near the target market. y Promote good values of company culture and business philosophy. C ompany Summary What is Fresin Fries? Fresin Fries sells gourm et fries in a c one with a choice of sauce. We use the concept o f Belgian Fries, where the fries are all made from fresh potatoes and fried twice. Our outlet also provides excellent and friendly customer service to support the ambience of fun, energetic and youthful lifestyle. Y outhful and fresh surroundings We will imitate successful establishments, such as Jamba Juice and Starbucks, which represent the majority of our core target market, between 18 to 35 years of age. Our store will feature display cooking of our featured Belgian Fries from cutting to frying. Our customers will also be able to read our in-house brochures in regards to all knowledge about Belgian Fries and our featured sauces. Our store will be decorated with fast food setting, such as a bright counter and display menu on the wall. Quality food Each store will offer nothing but freshly fried Belgian fries, sandwiches and variety of unique blend sauces, all served with old-fashioned home-style care. Open everyday Our store is open everyday from 10 am to 9 pm. Variety, variety, variety A different selection of sauces will be featured every three months and we will also change our Italian soda flavors to accompany our fries. 2.1 C ompany Ownership Fresin Fries is a privately held company. It will be registered as a Limited company, with ownership 25% - Guy Fry, 25% - Sam Sauce, 25% - Carl Cone, 25% - Harry Hip.   Guy Fry and Sam Sauce have more than 10 years of experience in the food industry. Both are currently employed as Corporate Staff of Company A. Sam Sauce holds an MBA degree from University V. A true entrepreneur by heart, his latest entrepreneurial project is a diamond store in the heart of Singapore. Guy Fry holds a BA degree in Graphic Design from the Academy of Arts. His projects are widely varied from product design to brand development of several reputable companies. Harry Hip holds a MS degree from Institute Y. He completed several projects and served as project manager for multi-national companies in Singapore. Carl Cone holds a BS degree from University Z, majoring in Management and Information Technology. Prior to his return to Singapore, he has held several management positions in a U.S.-based IT company. 2.2 Start-up Summary The retail outlet will be rented at one of the target location shopping malls. Our preference is Space A, for the main reason of reaching larger traffic. Startup requirements will be financed through owner investments. Start-up Requirements Start-up Expenses Kitchen and Fixtures $21,600 Furniture and Interior $16,500 Legal $3,000 of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan
 Download or Print 676 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 12/10/2010 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
