<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008312" url="http://www.sheknows.com/holidays-and-seasons/articles/811468/kids-birthday-party-budgets" time="2012-07-13-01:48" support="4" score="0.005118631014511086" bingtitle="Kids&apos; birthday party budgets - Entertainment | Recipes | Love ..." webtitle="Kids&apos; birthday party budgets">
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>... and you have the budget, hosting the party offsite -- such as at a fast-food restaurant ... If you don&apos;t have the funds for the themed plates, napkins, cups, goody bags ...</description>
	<body>
		Revolving
 
 Baby Names Sweepstakes and contests Fruit tacos allParenting How to sun dye fabric 
 
 Login Sign up 
 Search 
 SheKnows Homepage Entertainment Beauty Love Parenting Pets Home Living Food Health How-To Shopping Contests More SheKnows TV 
 

 &lt; &gt; 
 Holidays&amp;Seasons Christmas Father&apos;s Day New Year&apos;s Mother&apos;s Day Valentine&apos;s Day Thanksgiving Halloween Easter Birthdays&amp;Celebrations St. Patrick&apos;s Day 
 
 
 
 Kids&apos; birthday party budgets 
 Oct 10, 2009 12:00 PM by Celeste Gish Posted in Holidays&amp;Seasons / Birthdays&amp;Celebrations Rate this Article: Max 5 stars 5 My Rating Tweet Pin It 0 
 
 The Perfect Party For Your Budget
 With careful preparation and a dash of creativity, you can throw a party the kids will love, and they won&apos;t even notice you did it on the cheap. 
First, establish a head count (because many of your expenses will be priced per child), then establish a budget and stick to it.

 

Here are a few ideas to fit your budget.

Budget: The sky&apos;s the limit

Just won the lottery? Think along the lines of a small wedding in terms of decorations, favors, food and expenses. For a base cost of only $30,000 or so -- plus food, goody bags and limo service --
 your little darling can have her own sleepover at the flagship FAO Schwartz in New York. If you still have money to burn, you can hire professional Broadway performers to dance on the piano
 featured in the movie Big and play Happy Birthday . Engraved invitations from Tiffany, of course.

Budget: $200 to 500

If you&apos;re planning on a large group and you have the budget, hosting the party offsite -- such as at a fast-food restaurant or toy store -- is a convenient option. Fast-food restaurants provide
 space and a meal at a per-head cost, while you provide the cake, ice cream, favors and decorations. Big plus: They do the clean-up. Franchises such as Build-A-Bear also offer varying birthday
 packages without snacks or cake. Check the Internet for details on pricing.

Budget: $75 to 200

Host an at-home theme party for a few friends or the whole neighborhood. Obviously, the low end of the budget means fewer guests. If you don&apos;t have the funds for the themed plates, napkins, cups,
 goody bags, decorations etc., purchase a few themed items and a few in a complementary color. For example, if you are having a Dora the Explorer party. Choose a stand-out color from the
 themed plates you&apos;ve chosen and buy plain cake plates of that color. By asking around, you may find a stay-at-home mom who moonlights as a clown, magician or puppeteer. Many of these part-timers
 are very affordable and provide a lot of smiles per dollar. Goody bags can include moderately priced items like a shovel and pail set filled with Play-doh, bubbles, crayons, a coloring book and
 some candy for a cost of $10 to $15 per child. Serve take-out pizza, cake and ice cream.

Budget: less than $75

Yes, it can be done! And the kids will probably enjoy it just as much as a full-blown extravaganza. Pick an inexpensive or free location such as a park, playground or the backyard. Limit guests to
 close friends and family, and plan a late-afternoon event so you can save by serving cake and snacks instead of a meal. Make the cake yourself, and let your child get excited about the party by
 helping you decorate it. Serve juice, punch or soda from large bottles instead of individual containers. Have the kids paint &quot;pet rocks&quot; as both an activity and an inexpensive but special party
 favor.
 
 Tags: birthday parties kids&apos; parties party ideas 
 0 
 Comments 
 
Comments on &quot;Kids&apos;birthday party budgets&quot;
 
+ Add Comment
 Name 
 E-mail (required - not published)
 Comment Submit Comment 
Trending Stories
 
 Halloween Crafts&amp;Activities 0 Halloween Votives craft Father&apos;s Day 3 iDad Father&apos;s Day card Thanksgiving Crafts&amp;Fun 1 Family Tree Shirt Holidays&amp;Seasons 0 4th of July decorations for a patriotic party 
 
Follow SheKnows 

 +1 SheKnows on Google Follow @SheKnows Follow us on Pinterest RSS     NEWSLETTERS 
 
Popular Today
 
 How to sun dye fabric 
 
 Twilight crew bids goodbye... The Dark Knight Rises ...
	</body>
</document>
