<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008576" url="http://www.bigpictureconsulting.com/Global%20Inc/pgs/repcorp/mcd/mcds.html" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="1" score="0.0008180431829914558" bingtitle="McDonalds - BigPictureConsulting—Welcome" webtitle="McDonalds">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>McDonald’s has become not only the largest fast food restaurant organization, but has ... Each day, about eight percent of the U.S. population will eat a meal at McDonald ...</description>
	<body>
		McDonald&apos;s 
 

 
McDonalds has become not only the largest fast food restaurant organization, but has come to symbolize globalization itself as it has literally changed eating habits around the world. It commands the leading share (42%) of the U.S. fast food market and runs more than 28,000 restaurants in 120 countries. Each day, about eight percent of the U.S. population will eat a meal at McDonalds, and each year, ninety six percent of the U.S. population will eat at a McDonalds. By 1988 McDonalds had opened 10,000 restaurants in just 33 years. It was then able to reach the 20,000 mark in another 8 years. By 1997 McDonalds was opening 2,000 restaurants per yearan average of one every five hours. McDonalds serves less than one percent of the global market per day and sees the opportunity to continue growth into the next century.

Richard and Maurice McDonald originally founded McDonalds in the 1930s, but its success is due to the efforts of Ray Kroc, who put the hamburger on the assembly line. Each workers steps were calculated in order to ensure maximum efficiency. The result was a decrease in preparation time and an increase in volume, allowing for cheap prices and fast service.

The restaurant chain grew slowly at first. Kroc decided to build all of the restaurants and then franchise them out in order to have uniformity. He later founded the Hamburger University in 1961 in order to train franchisees and corporate decision-makers. Hamburger Universities were later founded in Tokyo, Munich, and London. He built primarily in the suburbs as suburban America was just developing in the 1950s after WWII. The popularization of the automobile also increased McDonalds popularity and throughout the 1960s and 70s the chain grew incredibly quickly.

In 1973 McDonalds first opened for breakfast with the creation of the Egg McMuffin. By 1987 one fourth of breakfasts eaten outside the home in the United States came from McDonalds. In 1975 McDonalds pioneered its first drive-thru window; drive-thru sales eventually accounted for more than half of McDonalds system wide sales.

In the 1970s competition with other fast food chains intensified, culminating in the&quot;Burger Wars&quot;of the early 1980s. In order to cater to changing consumer preferences, McDonalds introduced Chicken McNuggets in 1983 and by the end of the year, McDonalds was the second largest retailer of chicken in the world. However, due to a series of difficulties including failed marketing strategies and new sandwiches that flopped, growth in the U.S. slowed during the 1990s.

Overseas, the 1990s saw an increase in international units from 3,600 in 1991 to more than 11,000 by 1998, largely in Japan, Canada, Germany, Great Britain, Australia, and France. The number of overall countries with McDonalds nearly doubled from 59 in 1991 to 114 in 1998. In 1993 McDonalds first expanded in to the Middle East and opened in Tel Aviv, Israel. As the company entered new markets, it showed flexibility with respect to the local preferences: in Germany, McDonalds serves beer with meals; in Israel, the first kosher McDonalds opened in Jerusalem in 1995; in Arab countries, the restaurant chain used Halal menus; in 1996 McDonalds entered India where they offered the Maharaja Mac, made with lamb rather than beef; in Sweden, the first McSki-thru opened in Lindvallen, Sweden.

McDonalds ubiquity has made it a lightning rod for criticism from numerous fronts. Vegetarian groups, farmers, university students, labor groups, and groups from practically every foreign country have attacked McDonalds for damaging peoples health with bad food, using produce from huge factory farms, invading college student centers, using toys made in sweatshops, being the front-man for economic globalization, and every kind of global cultural hegemony.
 International Expansion 
 McDonald&apos;s in the World Today
	</body>
</document>
