<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008315" url="http://www.franchiseinfomall.com/Alphabetical_Franchise_Company_Search_2.asp" time="2012-07-13-01:48" support="6" score="0.007876281595461837" bingtitle="franchise opportunities and franchise directory of best franchises ..." webtitle="franchise opportunities and franchise directory of best franchises and top franchise businesses.">
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>In their 15 years of doing business, Charley&apos;s fast food restaurant ... Round Table Pizza Round Table Pizza is the fifth ... success, opportunity and fun on the same tray ...</description>
	<body>
		The Big
  Picture Click HERE for
The Best Business
Categories to Start
Your Dream Franchise Read About Top Franchises Franchises: Top 100 Franchises: Top 500 Franchises: International Top 200 Food Franchises Franchises - Best Suited for Women Home Based Franchises Fastest Growing Franchises Expert Advice Prime Links - Up&amp;Coming Franchises Alphabetical Franchise Companies Hot Franchises Franchise Company Press Releases Franchises For Sale 

 Best of
the Best Franchises #1 Internet Franchise WSI 1-800 Water Damage 1-800-DryClean 32 A Yogurt Bar 360Clean - Janitorial Service 7-11 Convenience Store 7-Eleven AAMCO Transmissions Aero-Colours AIM Mail Centers All Tune&amp;Lube All Tune Transmission Aloette Cosmetics Alphagraphics - Printing&amp;Copying Alta Mere - Toys For Your Car American Business Registries Amerispec Home Inspection Service At Work Medical Services At Work Personnel Services ATL Motor Mate Billboard Connection - Outdoor Advertising BizCard Xpress Blimpie Subs&amp;Salads Build Your Own American Dream Home BuildingStars Inc. - Commercial Cleaning Solutions Burger King Corporation Business Alliance, Inc. - Brokers Business Alliance, Inc. - Consultants Cafe2U California Closet Company Carpet Network - Mobile Floorcovering Franchise Cash Plus CertaPro Painters Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs Churchs Chicken City Publications - Advertising Cleaning Authority - Maid Service Closet Factory, The - Custom Closets Color Your Carpet Computer Troubleshooters Coverall Cleaning Concepts Cruiseone, Inc. Denny&apos;s Inc. DIGIKIDS - Child ID Program Discovery Point Franchising Dollar Discount Stores Dollar Store Services Dr. G&apos;s Weight Loss&amp;Wellness Duraclean International, Inc. DVDNow Kiosks, Inc. EmbroidMe Fabulous Floors Fantastic Sams FastFrame Fastrackids International Fastsigns, Inc. First Choice Business Brokers Franchise Alliance Inc. FranchiseMart - Business Consulting Get Found In Town GNC-General Nutrition Centers Guard-A-Kid - Child ID Program Handyman Connection Home Helpers Hometown Threads - Custom Embroidery Franchise HomeWatch CareGivers - Senior Care Honest-1 Auto Care House of Bread Huntington Learning Centers, Inc. Instant Tax Service INTERIORS By Decorating Den Jackson Hewitt Tax Service Jiffy Lube International Jimmy John&apos;s Gourmet Sandwich Shops Junk King - Junk Removal Service Liberty Tax Service Link Staffing Services Liquid Capital of America Corporation Little Gym , The MAACO Auto Painting&amp;Bodyworks Maid Brigade Maid To Sparkle Mara&apos;s Cafe&amp;Bakery Martinizing Dry Cleaning Massage Heights - Health and Fitness Franchise McDonald&apos;s Corporation Meineke Car Care Centers Menchie&apos;s Frozen Yogurt Merle Norman Cosmetics Studios Mint Condition - Commercial Cleaning Minuteman Press International Molly Maid New Horizons Computer Learning Centers New York Butcher Shoppe, The Nurse Next Door OneClick Cleaners Packaging And Shipping Specialists - P.A.S.S Padgett Business Services USA, Inc. Patrice and Associates - Hospitality Recruiting Plan Ahead Events - Special Events Planners Planet Beach Contempo Spa Precision Tune Auto Care Quizno&apos;s Classic Subs Rubbish Works Service Team of Professionals SIGN World Sign-A-Rama Signs By Tomorrow Sonic Drive-In Restaurants Specialty Stores&amp;Restaurants Speedee Oil Change&amp;Tune-Up Speedy Transmission Centers Starkey International Startup HomeCare Steak-Out Franchising Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads SuperCoups - Direct Mail Advertising The Cravery - Gourmet Pot Pies The Maids Home Services The Marketing Department The Queen&apos;s Residence Bed and Breakfast Inns The Sadkhin Complex - Fast&amp;Effective Weight Loss Top Dollar 4 Gold Tropical Smoothie Cafe Trova Home Care - Senior Care Franchise Tuffy Auto Service Centers U.S. Lawns, Inc. UBuildIt United Country Real Estate U-Turn Vending-Vending Machine Sales Waiting Game Publications Wienerschnitzel - Fast-Food Franchise WSI Internet - USA WSI Internet-Canada Yogli Mogli Frozen Yogurt 


 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
 
 
 

 
 Welcome to the Alphabetical Listings of Franchise Opportunities on Franchise Info Mall . Here you will find franchise opportunities in every possible franchise business category from Internet franchises to C osmetics franchises to S kin Care franchises .  Most of the franchise opportunities under  Alphabetical Listings  are among the Top 500 Franchises and Top 100 Franchises. All  franchise opportunities and Business opportunities posted under Alphabetical Listings provide detailed franchise information on more than 1000 franchise and business opportunity companies . 
 The purpose of Franchise Info Mall is to provide a franchise opportunities web site where you can find everything you could ever need in the way of franchise information to make your franchise opportunity venture the best it can possibly be for you, and without ever having to leave the web site! 

 
 Check Out These Really Cool Franchises 
 Carpet Network - Mobile Floorcovering Franchise  
 
 
 
 What could be better than shopping in your own home for the very products that will be used there?  Carpet Network&apos;s  customers view thousands of carpet, floor and window selections from the comfort of their own homes.  By bringing the floor and window store to consumershomes,  Carpet Network  offers their customers the ultimate in convenience while allowing you to maintain a low overhead business without a storefront.   Carpet Network is in a league of its own. In a world of imitations, our franchise opportunity stands apart.  The &quot;Traveling Floor and Window Store concept is coupled with a state-of-the-art mobile vanmade bigger and better to accommodate a full spectrum of merchandise for our home-based clients. To find out more information about this amazing, one-of-a-kind franchise business, complete and submit a request more information form now! 
 
 
 
 

 
 Click green button below to receive info 
 
 
 DIGIKIDS - Child ID Program  
 If you are looking for an exceptionally rewarding, flexible and affordable business that will make a positive difference in your community, DIGIKIDS might be the ideal franchise opportunity for you. DIGIKIDS is a full time, home-based business with very low overhead.

 With more than 2,000 children reported lost, missing or separated from their parents every day in the United States, authorities everywhere ask that parents carry child identification designed to help police find missing children. These experts agree that quick access to high-quality digital photos and accurate descriptions are key to a safe and speedy recovery. 
 

 
 Click green button below to receive info 
 
 SIGN World  
 SIGN World is a national organization with more than 250 independently owned sign companies, which provide commercial custom signage and graphics. It&apos;s personable, creative, rewarding and ideal for people-oriented individuals who have the desire to learn how to manage a sales and production business. SIGN World affiliates are a cut above traditional sign companies. With over 20 years in the business, SIGN World has established itself as the leader in the no-royalty sign business concept. This helps you surpass all of the normal rules and reporting requirements that come with a franchise, allowing you to do more things your way, while still reaping the benefits of support from the corporate staff and the owners as well. 
 Click green button below to receive info #1 Internet Franchise WSI   
 WSI Internet franchise has established itself as the worlds leading Internet Services Franchise whose systems are used by over 2000 franchisees worldwide, successfully servicing tens of thousands of business customers globally. Currently rated the #1 Fastest Growing Business Services Internet Franchise and the 4th Fastest Growing Global Internet Franchise . WSI Internet franchise has established one of the most prosperous, proven Franchise Opportunities in the world today. Your task as a WSI Internet franchise entrepreneur is simple. Using WSI Internet franchise proven and patent pending Business Systems, your job is to help small and medium sized companies within your community profit from WSI Internet franchise system. For businesses, having a website is simply not enough. Businesses must have the knowledge of how they can profit from this new technology. It&apos;s comforting for businesses to know that they have a partner who is looking out for their ongoing interests throughout the Internet&apos;s evolution. As new Internet technologies emerge and will continue to emerge, as a trained and certified WSI Franchise Internet Consultant , you are positioned to assist businesses in capitalizing on these new possibilities. 
 Click green button below to receive info Unclick the boxes 
 
 above for those companies you do not wish to receive information 
 
 
 

 Alphabetical Listing: 

 
 
 Select By Company Name: 

 Contains or Starts With 
 Example: PEPSI contains letters EPS and starts with PEP
( this will help narrow the search) or Click Search 
 to View All. 
 
 
 Or By Company Name Starting with: 

 # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 
 Go back to Franchise Companies page 
 

 
 
 Check from 1 to 10 companies and press the&quot;Request More Information&quot;
button 
 to receive additional information.
 
 
     
 
 #1 Internet Franchise WSI    WSI supports you with proprietary Internet server systems, advanced Internet development services, Internet marketing materials and training updates. With WSI INTERNET&apos;s award winning technology to back you up, you can build your business with all the freedom and flexibility you&apos;ve dreamed.   More... 
 
 1-800 Water Damage    Franchisees and their technicians will provide Emergency Water Damage Restoration services along with disaster clean up, sewage clean-ups, structural drying and odor control to home and business owners in their protected territories.   More... 
 
 1-800-DryClean    More Americans used to take the &quot;do-it-yourself&quot; approach, but the growing trend is to hire it done. Convenience is king. There are more two-income households, more super-busy families, more hard working, career-minded people who need the services others provide just to make life manageable. How many of these busy people would say &quot;yes&quot; if asked, &quot;Would you like us to pick up and deliver your dry cleaning and we won&apos;t charge you for the service?&quot; All those &quot;yes&quot; people are your potential customers ...repeat, year-round customers.   More... 
 
 32 A Yogurt Bar    At 32 A Yogurt Bar, they pride themselves on providing an environment and experience like no other! When you walk into a 32 A Yogurt Bar store, you will immediately feel energized. The bright, fun atmosphere is just the beginning of the 32 experience. There are a lot of yogurt concepts, but 32 A Yogurt Bar stands out from the rest.   More... 
 
 360Clean - Janitorial Service    360clean, Commercial Janitorial Service, provides an exceptional business opportunity, allowing you to become your own boss in a growing industry through the guidance and support of an established franchise organization. Additionally, it&apos;s a business that can fit your individual situation. You can start on a part-time or full-time basis and build the business to achieve your goals.   More... 
 
 7-11 Convenience Store    7-Eleven offers an extended hour, retail convenience store, providing groceries, take out foods and beverages, dairy products, non-food merchandise, specialty items and selected services which emphasize convenience to the customer.   More... 
 
 7-Eleven    7-Eleven offers an extended hour, retail convenience store, providing groceries, take out foods and beverages, dairy products, non-food merchandise, specialty items and selected services which emphasize convenience to the customer. 7-Eleven franchise stores or 7-11 convenience stores have been around for more than 75 years and have become synonymous with ready-to-go, quick-service convenience operations.   More... 
 
 AAMCO Transmissions    Over 720 locations in the U.S., Canada, and Puerto Rico make AAMCO the clear choice in a market full of opportunity. For years, you&apos;ve put in your forty or more hours, week after week. Now you&apos;re ready to take the next step on your road to financial independence. As so many before you, you can live your dreams with AAMCO.   More... 
 
 Adventures In Advertising    Business-to-business sales opportunity in the promotional products industry. This franchise opportunity is specifically designed for salespeople, marketing and business professionals. If you enjoy working with mid-size and large corporate accounts and have experience in business-to-business sales, fill out the form today.   More... 
 
 Aero-Colours    AERO COLOURS, Inc. has been delivering high-quality mobile auto touch-up and paint repair service since 1985. Our expertise and value sets our service apart from our competitors. If you are looking for a fast, quality repair, at a cost-effective price, AERO COLOURS has the know-how to do it right.   More... 
 
 AIM Mail Centers    AIM Mail Centers are complete postal and business service centers, providing up to 30 different products and services, including shipping, packaging, faxing, notary, mail box rental, photocopy, business cards, office supplies and much, much more.   More... 
 
 All Tune&amp;Lube    All Tune and Lubes Total Car Care Centers provide today&apos;s motorists with high quality maintenance and repair services. We are very excited about our Multi-Branded Franchise Concept, which provides the franchise owner with Three Times the Potential under one Roof. This innovative concept allows the franchisee the opportunity to purchase one or a combination of the following franchises.   More... 
 
 All Tune Transmission    Our multi-branded Franchise Centers Offer Total Car Care to the motoring public. This innovative concept provides the franchise owner with Three Times the Potential Under One Roof. Our support includes extensive training at headquarters and continuing education programs for owner and staff, along with operations staff visits in the individual center locations.   More... 
 
 Aloette Cosmetics    Aloette is the only cosmetics company with &quot;No inventory investment.&quot; We stock, pack and deliver the products right to your customers. Just think, you&apos;ll never tie up your money in inventory. You set up your schedule. Hostess gifts are provided by the Company -- at no expense to you.   More... 
 
 Alphagraphics - Printing&amp;Copying    The Alphagraphics Network of more than 340 centers is the leading provider of print-related and digital publishing services for businesses worldwide. All Alphagraphics digital centers, in more than 20 countries, offer design, copying, offset, digital printing services and web site design including secure, online ordering web site for customers.   More... 
 
 Alta Mere - Toys For Your Car    Alta Mere offers a complete auto aftermarket line of accessories including auto security, video, GPS and paint protection. In addition, we offer residential and automotive window tinting.   More... 
 
 American Business Registries    The American Business Registries (ABR) is a comprehensive on-line business resource directory, specializing in local established professional services. Imagine you, the owner of a marketing vehicle so powerful and effective, that local professionals may actually fear being left out of your service! This is the reality happening right now with the American Business RegistriesAnd you can be a part of it in your area.   More... 
 
 Amerispec Home Inspection Service    Since its inception, AmeriSpec has conducted in excess of 1.5 million inspections. Today, over 350 independently owned and operated businesses conductin excess of 150,000 AmeriSpec inspections annually in the U.S. and Canada.   More... 
 
 Arthur Treacher&apos;s Fish&amp;Chips    English style fish and chips. The product can be found in free standing units, mall locations, or co-branded with Pudgie&apos;s Famous Chicken, Nathan&apos;s Famous, Miami Subs and Kenny Roger&apos;s Chicken.   More... 
 
 At Work Medical Services    Know the freedom of owning your own business with the backing of a national franchise system. @WORK Medical Services offers the best low investment personnel franchise in the industry while allowing you to set prices and control service programs without barriers from the franchisor. The @WORK Medical Services franchise has been designed to hold costs down for the franchise office and assist in marketing to the end client.   More... 
 
 At Work Personnel Services    For over a decade, AT WORK Personnel Services has built upon its core foundation of meeting and exceeding the needs and expectations of people seeking employment opportunities as well as clients seeking a full service partner to assist with their company&apos;s staffing needs. By providing temporary, temp-to-hire, pay rolling and full time placement services, AT WORK Personnel Services is committed to offering flexible employment solutions and the highest level of service available today.   More... 
 
 ATL Motor Mate    Our support includes extensive training at headquarters and continuing education programs for owner and staff, along with operations staff visits in the individual center locations. In addition we offer dynamic advertising and marketing programs, toll-free telephone assistance, newsletters, national buying power, and more.   More... 
 
 Billboard Connection - Outdoor Advertising    There are countless forms of advertising, but there is only one you cannot turn off, throw away or fast forward through: outdoor advertising. That is why billboards and other outdoor advertising continue to be so popular. Heres your chance to get on the inside track of an outstanding opportunity as a Billboard Connection franchisee.   More... 
 
 BizCard Xpress    BizCard Xpress has a proven business method that is not only time tested, but recession tested, offering their customers everything in the sign and printing industry at a low, reasonable price, with fast, accurate development.   More... 
 
 Blimpie Subs&amp;Salads    There are many opportunities available to franchisees when you join the Blimpie franchise team. Blimpie franchise has opportunities available to you if you are interested in owning a single fast food Blimpie franchise or you can be the owner of a multiple-unit of Blimpie franchise systems.   More... 
 
 Budget Blinds    Entrepreneur Magazine has ranked Budget Blinds as the #1 window covering franchise in America every year since 1996. What do we have that other window covering companies dont? Everything!   More... 
 
 Build Your Own American Dream Home    Build Your Own American Dream Home (BYOADH) is more than a consulting service for building homes. We provide an alternative to a high cost building experience. We impact every aspect of the building process, meeting high standards for quality and livability with our simple support system. Whether a client is looking for a new home, considering a major renovation or contemplating an addition to an existing home, BYOADH will provide the confidence needed and to help turn their dreams into reality.   More... 
 
 BuildingStars Inc. - Commercial Cleaning Solutions    BuildingStars delivers high quality facility services to customers in a variety of markets including office, medical, financial and educational institutions. Their service is complete, consistent, courteous and now environmentally-friendly through their Green Star program.   More... 
 
 Burger King Corporation    Burger King is one of the most well-known fast food restaurants in the world, known for great food, a good dining environment, and fast service where you can have it your way.   More... 
 
 Business Alliance, Inc. - Brokers    Plan Ahead Events is a home-based, full-service event management company serving clients worldwide. We offer creative solutions for meetings, conventions, trade shows, special events, and incentive travel, and will handle all the details for planning your event, from concept to completion. Plan Ahead Events is your single source for excellence on all occasions. We offer unparalleled service with one-stop shopping convenience, providing you with the services you require to ensure continuity and quality.   More... 
 
 Business Alliance, Inc. - Consultants    Become a Business Alliance Franchise Consultant and enjoy the personal satisfaction and financial rewards that come from helping others achieve their goals. Many of their Franchise Consultants do not have prior experience in franchising. It is not required, because their comprehensive training and support program will provide you with the knowledge and the tools that will enable you to come up to speed quickly and to be very successful.   More... 
 
 California Closet Company    World&apos;s largest franchisor of installed closet storage systems. Over 156 domestic and international locations. A division of The Franchise Company.   More... 
 
 Carpet Network - Mobile Floorcovering Franchise    Satisfy the needs of todays busy consumers, while you enjoy the freedom and flexibility of owning your own home-based, affordable business! As a franchisee of the best Traveling Floor and Window Store in North America, you can own a low overhead business that gives you the opportunity to enjoy a flexible, home-based business while offering busy consumers the convenience of selecting the finest floor and window coverings right in the convenience of their own homes.   More... 
 
 Cash Plus    Cash Plus stores are computerized businesses that provide much needed financial services to a significant and growing customer universe. Our current core service mix includes check cashing, payday advance loans, money orders, wire transfers and more.   More... 
 
 CertaPro Painters    CertaPro Painters gives you the opportunity to run your own Multi-Million Dollar Company, generate tremendous income and build asset value. CertaPro is a full service painting company servicing both residential and commercial customers with superior interior, exterior and specialty painting services.   More... 
 
 Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs    Charley&apos;s popular menu features freshly grilled Steak and Chicken Subs, fresh-cut fries and old-fashioned fresh squeezed lemonade. All orders are made-to-order fresh, right in front of each guest. In their 15 years of doing business, Charley&apos;s fast food restaurant franchises have been recognized at the &quot;top&quot; of more than 10 national lists for successful franchising, entrepreneurship and management.   More... 
 
 Chem-Dry    Chem-Dry carpet&amp;upholstery cleaning franchise has become the largest, most successful, upholstery and carpet cleaning company in the world, with nearly 3,800 franchises in all 50 states and in more than 50 countries.   More... 
 
 Churchs Chicken    Its your time to grow and Churchs Chicken has the brand strength, innovative spirit and long-standing experience to position you for business growth and success. If you are seriously interested in exploring the possibility of becoming a member of the Churchs Chicken franchise system and feel your qualifications meet our standards it&apos;s YOUR time to grow!   More... 
 
 City Publications - Advertising    City Publications is one of the fastest growing franchises throughout the US and Canada. Their franchisees service local businesses who market their products and services to the active affluent consumers in their local marketplaces. If you are searching to own a rare business-to-business opportunity and be your OWN boss, this could be a perfect Fit! The opportunity City Publications offers is unlike most others because they know exactly how to create interest for our affluent homeowner direct mail piece and e-mail marketing campaigns. We build product awareness and demand for their program in each city through their successfully proven sales and innovative marketing programs!   More... 
 
 Cleaning Authority - Maid Service    Residential house cleaning has become one of the fastest growing industries in the U.S. The success of our franchisees stems from a unique business model not found anywhere else. We provide you with systems and tools so that you are in control of your success.   More... 
 
 Closet Factory, The - Custom Closets    Closet Factory was established in 1983. We do more than custom closets. We have been providing our customers with truly custom storage solutions for different areas of the home, including the home office, garage, entertainment centers, kids&apos; rooms, pantries and more. Rather than offering our clients pre-sized or semi-custom products, we create individualized custom solutions from scratch.   More... 
 
 Cold Stone Creamery    If the ice cream weren&apos;t enough to convince you, Cold Stones franchise opportunities are about as solid as they come. And no wonder, when you consider Cold Stone Creamery stands alone as the fastest-growing super-premium ice cream concept in the country. As if selling ice cream werent good enough, Cold Stone owners are backed by a business structure and track record of stability and growth.   More... 
 
 Color Your Carpet    Our only business is dyeing! The only on-site, full time, 100% carpet dyeing&amp;color restoration service in the world. High demand for unique commercial&amp;residential property service.   More... 
 
 Computer Troubleshooters    Since launching in 1999, Computer Troubleshooters has skyrocketed to more than 475 franchises worldwide in more than 28 countries, making them the largest international network of franchise owners providing onsite computer services to small business.   More... 
 
 Coverall Cleaning Concepts    Success in any venture requires knowledge of the most cutting-edge techniques and programs being developed today. Coverall Cleaning Concepts offers you the opportunity to achieve entrepreneurial success by taking control of your professional future and financial independence. We will provide you with the skills you need to help you become successful now and the flexibility to help you grow in the future.   More... 
 
 Cruise Holidays    Cruise Holidays produces the marketing tools that franchisees are able to implement locally. And cooperative advertising funds, provided by cruise line partners, can be used to maximize your marketing budget and exposure.   More... 
 
 Cruiseone, Inc.    CruiseOne, with over 400 locations coast to coast, prides itself on providing attention to detail and expert advice to every customer. Each independently owned and operated business combines the latest technology with old-fashioned customer service. Our computerized best fare search program enables cruise specialists to identify excellent values on all major cruise lines.   More... 
 
 Denny&apos;s Inc.    With nearly 1,600 locations, you can enjoy Denny&apos;s restaurants nationwide within the United States, Canada, Costa Rica, Guam, Mexico, New Zealand and Puerto Rico. We are committed to becoming the best family restaurant system in the world. Denny&apos;s care in recruiting, training and developing franchisees is a key factor in the growth of our franchise system.   More... 
 
 DIGIKIDS - Child ID Program    As a DIGIKIDS franchise owner, you will offer the most advanced and effective child ID available anywhere. You will launch your new business with established marketing systems, proprietary patent-pending software, an accepted trademark, national purchasing power, and thorough training and support.   More... 
 
 Discovery Point Franchising    
 
 Dollar Discount Stores    As a Dollar Discount Store owner, you will receive a step by step program for opening and operating your own Dollar Store. Franchisees receive: In-depth training at the company&apos;s home office, the company&apos;s comprehensive operations manual, regular on-site visits and telephone support from the home office managers, access to a toll free 800 help line, full opening support and assistance with buying and opening inventory.   More... 
 
 Dollar Store Developers    
 
 Dollar Store Services    What&apos;s the hottest concept in retailing right now? Our Dollar Store, where everything sells for only one dollar! More than any time during the past 20 years, consumers want the most for their money. They are fed up with paying high prices for fancy names. Instead, they want the most for the least. Dollar Stores take that philosophy to the extreme! Introduced in 1992, our dollar store concept markets toys, paper goods, snacks, novelties, school supplies and just about anything you can imagine--all for one dollar. It&apos;s an irresistible blend of merchandise that prompts customers to stock up on things that they need the most.   More... 
 
 Dr. G&apos;s Weight Loss&amp;Wellness    
 
 Dreammaker Bath&amp;Kitchen By Worldwide    DreamMaker Bath&amp;Kitchen by Worldwide is an exclusive bath and kitchen remodeling franchise organization. We have franchisees in over 190 locations around the world and over 30 years experience in taking businesses to the next level of success. DreamMaker Bath&amp;Kitchen is the premier kitchen and bath remodeling business, offering exciting opportunities in the residential and commercial markets.   More... 
 
 Dryclean - U.S.A.    Dryclean USA is one of the largest most respected recognizable names in the industry with over 400 stores in the Western Hemisphere. Single stores and Master development programs available. We have been ranked as an industry leader by Entrepreneur Magazine&apos;s Top 500 Franchises Issue for eight consecutive years (2001 to 2007). Drycleaning franchise offering exclusive development territories in USA and worldwide.   More... 
 
 Duraclean International, Inc.    With specialized equipment and education, you can tap into the huge commercial carpet cleaning market in a meaningful manner. You can establish contracts resulting in ongoing monthly income from commercial accounts by offering continuous and comprehensive carpet care utilizing special equipment and unique customer benefits.   More... 
 
 El Pollo Loco    The secret to El Pollo Loco&apos;s success is our great tasting food. Our menu has a broad and deep consumer acceptance across a wide span of demographic and socioeconomic sectors and is a healthy alternative to traditional fast food. From the day you begin working with us, through your development, grand opening and ongoing operations we&apos;ll be here to support your needs and growth.   More... 
 
 EmbroidMe    EmbroidMe is a full service embroidery, screen-printing, and promotional products franchise. EmbroidMe currently has about 220 stores nationwide as well as in Australia&amp;Canada. After years of testing the concept in high-traffic shopping malls, EmbroidMe has proven results and are willing to pass this on to you, as the proud owner of a EmbroidMe franchise business.   More... 
 
 Fabulous Floors    Fabulous Floors franchisees help homeowners enjoy the beauty of their hardware floors using our proprietary dustless and odorless refinishing system! The remarkable Fabulous Floors system brings back the beauty and character of hardwood floors by gently buffing minor nicks and scratches in the floor&apos;s finish, without sanding away precious wood. Fabulous Floors customers include homeowners, businesses, and remodeling contractors.   More... 
 
 Fantastic Sams    Fantastic Sams is a full-service salon providing family hair care services to business franchise owners with the tools and experience to meet the need for: color, straightening, cutting, perms, texturizing waves, and waxing.   More... 
 
 FastFrame    Custom picture framing and art retail. At FastFrame, we offer quality picture framing craftsmanship to consumers, art collectors, interior designers and commercial clients. We carry a wide selection of custom framing materials and moldings. We also carry an assortment of prints and fine art in easy to view catalogs.   More... 
 
 Fastrackids International    Are you interested in owning your own business and making a substantial contribution to your community? Providing early childhood education enrichment is a positive business environment that is also profitable. With our strong franchise support and outstanding training programs, you are in business for yourself, not by yourself.   More... 
 
 Fastsigns, Inc.    At FASTSIGNS, we understand that your success is our success. Our primary goal is to help our franchisees build successful stores that achieve and maintain high sales volumes and maximum profits, year after year. As a FASTSIGNS franchisee, you&apos;ll have the benefit of one of the most respected names in the sign business - and in franchising as a whole.   More... 
 
 First Choice Business Brokers    Become Part of the Elite in Your CommunityBeing a First Choice Business Broker will have you working with the elite level of business owners in your area. This is an executive franchise system that will allow you be a part of an elite group in your community. When you invest in a First Choice franchise, you get the ability to build a Firm... By hiring associates you can build a team and go far beyond a one-person business if you choose to. Each associate/agent brings in an additional revenue stream, with minimal overhead. Thus with the investment in just one franchise you can build an entire firm.   More... 
 
 Flamers Charbroiled Hamburgers&amp;Chicken    Flamers&apos; recipe for its tremendous success has been combining great food with an easy to use system and high-traffic customer locations. The final ingredient for continued success is YOU!   More... 
 
 Four Seasons Sunrooms    As a Four Seasons Sunrooms franchise, you gain access to this information and can capitalize on the unique marketing benefits we offer your business. We are the company that sets the standard other companies attempt to follow. The proven track record of our over 300 successful franchises and dealers validates our effectiveness of leading the market around the world.   More... 
 
 Fox&apos;s Pizza Den    We can assist our franchisees with site selection, business plans, bank referrals, instructions for bookkeeping and inventory control, layout, purchasing and installation of equipment, and in-house advertising. Our long-range goals for Fox&apos;s Pizza Den franchises are health, wealth and happiness, because our success hinges on your success.   More... 
 
 Franchise Alliance Inc.    Become a Franchise Consultant and enjoy the personal satisfaction and financial rewards that come from helping others achieve their goals.   More... 
 
 FranchiseMart - Business Consulting    FRANCHISEMART is the first business of its kind to match people looking for franchise opportunities with franchise companies through a convenient retail location. FRANCHISEMART works with every customer to match them to the opportunities that correspond with their personal goals, interests, background and financial qualifications. 

FRANCHISEMART provides a variety of income streams for its franchisees to earn money, including: passing leads to franchisors, franchisor referral fees when franchises are sold, commissions from United Franchise Group (UFG) business services, seminar fees, renting in-store poster space, on-site videos, web banner ad space, and more.   More... 
 
 Franklin&apos;s Printing    Franklin&apos;s Printing offers convenient, one-stop shopping for all of your business and marketing materials.   More... 
 
 Fuddruckers, Inc.    With more than 200 restaurants from Miami, Florida to Great Falls, Montana, Fuddruckers has made a lot of progress in making the United States a great burger place. Fuddruckers is in the business of serving the worlds greatest hamburgers and other exceptional foods.   More... 
 
 Get Found In Town    Get Found In Town (GFIT) is an internet advertising service that specializes in Internet Marketing for small to medium size businesses. GFIT helps businesses get recognized through dynamic Search Engine Marketing (SEM) Google Places Optimization (GPO) as well as Yahoo Local and Bing Local. In addition, GFIT provides Social Media Marketing (SMM) services which include strategically placing your product, service or brand in front of millions of web users that religiously participate in social networking.   More... 
 
 GNC-General Nutrition Centers    General Nutrition Centers, Inc., a wholly-owned subsidiary of GNC Corporation, is the largest global specialty retailer of nutritional supplements, which includes vitamin, mineral and herbal supplements, sports nutrition products, diet and energy products and specialty supplements.   More... 
 
 Grease Monkey International    Grease Monkey International, Inc. is one of the largest vehicle preventive maintenance franchisors not owned by a major oil company. The Grease Monkey organization has approximately 240 vehicle preventive maintenance service providers across the United States and in Mexico, and the market potential for Grease Monkey centers continues to increase.   More... 
 
 Guard-A-Kid - Child ID Program    Guard-A-Kid, is the country&apos;s leading child ID and family safety program. With more than 100 franchises sold in less than 3 years, Guard-A-Kid is one of the fastest growing franchise systems in the industry. With franchises in England, Scotland, Guam, Ireland, Canada and throughout the United States, Guard-A-Kid is a recognized name globally. Guard-A-Kid has been ranked in the top 500 franchises for two years in a row and has also been ranked in the top 50 new franchises by the Entrepreneur magazine.   More... 
 
 Handle With Care Packaging Store    Handle With Care Packaging Store is the dominant franchise brand in the niche it created more than 20 years ago. We would be happy to tell you more. New and existing Packaging Store franchises are available in many U.S. markets.   More... 
 
 Handyman Connection    As chairman of his condominium&apos;s maintenance committee, Arthur Neuman discovered that residents often had trouble finding repairmen. When Marvin Belkin discovered there was room in the marketplace for a small repair business, he and Neuman founded Handyman Connection in 1990. The company began franchising in 1993, with the first franchise in Dayton, Ohio, and now has locations throughout the United States and Canada.   More... 
 
 Home Helpers    Helping aging seniors safely manage and enjoy an active lifestyle while maintaining their independence. Home Helpers&apos; personal care services are tailored to meet the needs of each and every individually unique client.   More... 
 
 Hometown Threads - Custom Embroidery Franchise    Hometown Threads is a retail embroidery and personalization store that comes with everything you need to open your doors for business. It also has the ultimate location-Wal-Mart, which ensures a high degree of visibility, exposure and consumer traffic.   More... 
 
 HomeWatch CareGivers - Senior Care    Homewatch CareGivers is the largest and most experienced full-service home care franchise that enables our franchisees to capture the largest market share possible. Our 30 years of medical and non-medical experience translates to success. Today, we are the premier provider of senior care franchises and in-home care services for people of ALL ages.   More... 
 
 Honest-1 Auto Care    Partner with Americas most trusted family of automotive maintenance and repair centers and enjoy the most powerful automotive franchise experience in the industry.   More... 
 
 Hooters Of America, Inc.    Casual full service restaurants serving chicken wings, seafood, hamburgers, beer&amp;wine.   More... 
 
 Hot Stuff Pizza    Hot Stuff Foods offers fast food franchise opportunities for quick service restaurants (QSR) in convenience stores, shopping mall food courts, colleges and universities, hospitals and military bases.   More... 
 
 House Doctors Handyman Service    The time is right because the market is growing at an incredible rate. Each year, almost every homeowner has some repair work done. Last year, that represented over $42 billion in minor home repairs. The majority of these repairs are ones that people don&apos;t have the time or skill to do themselves. As a result, handymen are becoming very popular, but in most cases, a good one is hard to find. That&apos;s why they call the House Doctors.   More... 
 
 House of Bread    At House of Bread, we take our time to produce some of the best tasting goods, using natures ingredients, just like Grandma. Here are reasons why our products are better tasting, and better for you, than mass-produced bread purchased from the grocery store: We use fresh, natural stone-milled wheat flour for all of our products. Fresh flour is more nutritious for you and makes tastier bread. High-fiber whole grains. Our breads are ideal for individuals who want to eat the good carbohydrates for optimum health and weight control. Pure honey as a sweetener. Honey is a natural preservative, a natural antioxidant, and is digested easily.   More... 
 
 Housemaster    We are certain you will be impressed with the level of support and systems in place to help you start and grow your franchise. The reason most qualified prospects choose our system is our people - from the talented staff at HouseMaster&apos;s corporate office to our respected franchisees and their staffs.   More... 
 
 Huddle House Restaurant    The Huddle House Franchise and Development team is ready to assist you in becoming a member of our family. The Franchise and Development playbook is full of strategies and proven procedures to make the most of your business venture. Our company continues to grow at a phenomenal rate due to the high level of excellence expected and delivered by our franchisees.   More... 
 
 Huntington Learning Centers, Inc.    With a Huntington Learning Center Franchise, we help you achieve your business dreams by helping children reach their full potential in school. For this reason and many more, a Huntington Learning Center franchise is an ideal means by which you can participate in the exploding supplemental education market.   More... 
 
 Instant Tax Service    Instant Tax Service is the expert in quick, accurate tax return preparation, electronic filing, refund options and financial services, including a customer satisfaction guarantee.   More... 
 
 INTERIORS By Decorating Den    INTERIORS by Decorating Den, in business since 1969, is the worlds largest independently owned franchisor of interior decorating businesses. INTERIORS by Decorating Den has been featured in major news publications, extolled on national television, heard on radio and reviewed in literally thousands of local newspapers.   More... 
 
 Jackson Hewitt Tax Service    Full service income tax preparation company specializing in computerized tax preparation, electronic filing and refund anticipation loans. Jackson Hewitt offers a 5-day training session covering operations, marketing and systems training on our state-of-the-art proprietary tax software program. Ongoing management training is also provided throughout the year.   More... 
 
 Jamba Juice    Premium quality blended-to-order fruit smoothies, squeezed-to-order juices, blended beverages.   More... 
 
 Jenny Craig Weight Loss Centres    For over 20 years, Jenny Craig has been helping people live healthier, happier lives through weight management. As one of the leading weight- management service companies in the world, Jenny Craig not only offers franchisees strong financial potential, but also provides you with an opportunity to make a significant positive impact on the lives of your clients and the health of our nation.   More... 
 
 Jersey Mike&apos;s Subs&amp;Salads    Its been almost 50 years since the first sub was made with quality and care at the original Jersey Mikes. Over the years, Jersey Mikes has fueled its growth and success by continuing its tradition of quality and commitment to making the best sub sandwich in the industry. With a Jersey Mikes franchise, you can own a business that capitalizes on this solid tradition and excellent reputation for giving customers what they want great food that is fresh, fast and affordable.   More... 
 
 Jiffy Lube International    Jiffy Lube offers support, service, guidance and leadership to help its franchisees succeed. You can look to Jiffy Lube for assistance in acquiring a location, training you and your management personnel, and setting up an efficient operation. We can even assist qualified franchisees in financing.   More... 
 
 Jimmy John&apos;s Gourmet Sandwich Shops    Jimmy John&apos;s World&apos;s Greatest Sandwiches are made from the highest quality meats, cheeses and toppings available. Each sandwich is made one at a time, fast and flawless. Jimmy John&apos;s success is built upon an unyielding commitment to quality coupled with an unbeatable, repeatable process.   More... 
 
 Junk King - Junk Removal Service    Junk King removes non-hazardous junk from homes and commercial locations. All you have to do is call us. Just show us what you want to get rid of and we&apos;ll do all the work. We&apos;ll collect your junk from anywhere on your premises, clean up the area, and then dispose or recycle your junk. Junk King provides the fastest, easiest and most affordable way to get rid of anything you no longer need. Junk King will haul away &quot;Anything and Everything&quot; except hazardous waste.   More... 
 
 Just-A-Buck    Just-A-Buck offers franchisees a proven successful method of operations. We take care of many of the details so you can concentrate on running your store and building your business. Our franchise package is like a road map. It shows you the steps that can start you on the road to success right away.   More... 
 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC)    KFC Corporation, based in Louisville, Kentucky, is the world&apos;s most popular chicken restaurant chain, specializing in Original Recipe, Extra Crispy, Twister and Colonel&apos;s Crispy Strips chicken with home style sides.   More... 
 
 Kiddie Academy Child Care Learning Centers    We operate and franchise education-based child care learning academies throughout the United States. For over 20 years we have developed extensive operating systems and methodologies which enable all Kiddie Academy locations to maintain a uniform, high-quality standard across the Kiddie Academy System   More... 
 
 Kinderdance International, Inc.    Kinderdance is the original nationwide dance, motor development, gymnastics, and fitness program that combines academic readiness skills which are specifically designed for children ages 2 to 8. Take control of your life and make a positive difference in the lives of young children in your area by becoming a Kinderdance franchisee.   More... 
 
 Kitchen Solvers    You will utilize innovative sales strategies, targeted marketing programs and state-of-the-art technology to showcase a superior product line. Kitchen Solvers prides itself on providing franchise owners critical support in all areas of operation, as well as a choice of franchise plans, tailored to your unique skills and objectives.   More... 
 
 Kitchen Tune-Up    We are one of the nation&apos;s leading remodeling service companies. We breathe new life into wood in homes, businesses and other spaces. Kitchen Tune-Up is the only company that provides In-Tune Customer Service. It&apos;s customer service that&apos;s in tune with you. It&apos;s the fresh new look you want without the hassles you may have experienced in the past.   More... 
 
 Kwik Kopy Printing    Kwik Kopy Business Solutions and Kwik Kopy Printing is a convenient, one-stop shop for your company&apos;s business and marketing needs. We will carefully conceptualize and produce each project to ensure the right piece, the right way and at the right price...   More... 
 
 Lawn Doctor    The nation&apos;s leading lawn care, tree and shrub care, and pest control specialist.   More... 
 
 Liberty Tax Service    If youre going to look into buying a franchise, why not join a powerhouse?Liberty Tax Service is committed to creating a business system and environment that will be held up as the paragon for all other retail tax services to emulate. The good news is you do not need experience in the tax business to be a successful Liberty Tax Service franchisee.   More... 
 
 Link Staffing Services    We&apos;ve been a respected name in industrial staffing for over 25 years. Our services allow companies to focus on building their core businesses while we provide the staff they need to get the job done.   More... 
 
 Liquid Capital of America Corporation    The goal of Liquid Capital is to build an international network of franchises focused on the core business of Factoring small and medium-sized business clients in a professional and personalized manner. They support their Franchise Principals with the training, resources and systems they need to professionally service their customers.   More... 
 
 Little Gym , The    The Little Gym has set the standard not only as the best motor skill development program for children in the world, but also for providing the best customer service and support to our owners. Best of all, our owners would tell you that you can own a successful business while having fun everyday!   More... 
 
 Little Scientists    Little Scientists is a &quot;hands-on&quot; approach to teaching science to young children. The goal of Little Scientists is to excite all children about the world of science, using innovative educational techniques. Coupling interactive projects, entertaining demonstrations and simple experiments with children&apos;s natural curiosity, Little Scientists introduces children to the thrill of scientific discovery   More... 
 
 Long John Silver&apos;s    Long John Silver&apos;s is the world&apos;s most popular quick-service seafood chain with more than 1,200 restaurants worldwide and more than 200 additional points of distribution in Yum! Brands, Inc. multibrand restaurants.   More... 
 
 Lubepro&apos;s International, Inc.    At LubePro&apos;s, our technicians are experienced professionals, so not only do they recognize what needs to be done, but it takes them less time to get it done. From our 10-minute oil change and included 21-point inspection, to cleaning your windows and vacuuming your interior, LubePro&apos;s means great vehicle maintenance inside and out.   More... 
 
 Maggie Moo&apos;s Ice Cream    Our Franchisees enjoy a close working relationship with our experienced sales team. We provide valuable information and coaching at Moo University and you will have at your disposal a wealth of knowledge and expertise that help to ensure your success as a MaggieMoo&apos;s Franchisee.   More... 
 
 Maid Brigade    Maid Brigade is the only Green Clean Certified cleaning company in the industry, using cleaning supplies that are better for your health, better for their maids, and better for the environment; all while cleaning your home the way you want it to be cleaned: consistently, reliably, and affordably.   More... 
 
 Maid To Sparkle    
 
 Mail Boxes Etc. USA    By understanding our customers&apos; needs and challenges, we help you to do more while saving time and money. The UPS Store and Mail Boxes Etc. locations offer businesses and consumers a wide range of products and services available in one convenient location.   More... 
 
 Mara&apos;s Cafe&amp;Bakery    Mara&apos;s Caf&amp;Bakery is a winning concept, combining all the key elements of a caf, including a relaxing atmosphere and fresh brewed coffee, along with the fresh baked goods of a fine bakery. Mara&apos;s also has a full menu that features everything from sandwiches, quiches, soups and salads to pizzas, sliders and even a kids&apos; menu full of delicious dishes. Whether their customers want breakfast, lunch, dinner or dessert, they offer something for everyone, and every time of day.   More... 
 
 Martinizing Dry Cleaning    Martinizing is the largest dry cleaning franchise in the U. S. and ranked #1 by Entrepreneur Magazine. It is the most recognized brand name in dry cleaning. Join the upscale industry leader who pioneered on-premise express service and who continues to inovate with environmentally friendly solvents like GreenEarth Cleaning process and offering an array of sales-building options such as satellite stores, route service, commercial accounts, and more.   More... 
 
 Massage Heights - Health and Fitness Franchise    Massage Heights offers a distinguished Membership program that allows our Members to take advantage of the many benefits of rejuvenating massage more frequently. Our mission is to help all types of people incorporate convenient, high-quality, rejuvenating massage into their healthy lifestyles. Our business is built on a membership model that helps make massages more affordable, while still providing the level of service youd expect at a five-star resort.   More... 
 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporation    Quick service fast food restaurant.   More... 
 
 Meineke Car Care Centers    Make an investment in your future with a Meineke franchise. A name that&apos;s recognized by over 85% of all vehicle owners. Meineke has been a stable presence in the market for 30 years and a proven business system for nearly 900 franchisees.   More... 
 
 Merle Norman Cosmetics Studios    Founded in 1931, Merle Norman Cosmetics is an innovative company. We manufacture state-of-the-art, scientifically developed cosmetic products distributed exclusively through approximately 2,000 independently owned Studios, in the US and Canada.   More... 
 
 Midas Inc.    Midas is a leader in more than automotive products and services. Building consumer trust is at the heart of our brand. Midas and our franchisees work every day to earn that trust by providing expertise, responsiveness and value to every customer, every time.   More... 
 
 Mint Condition - Commercial Cleaning    Mint Condition offers you clearly superior commercial cleaning and janitorial services for your business. Our cleaning systems, our standard practices, and our owner-operator franchise program are all designed to provide highly reliable cleaning services and more, just the way you want them.   More... 
 
 Minuteman Press International    All businesses, large or small, from high tech to your neighborhood shops, all use printed matter in the daily operation of their business. We are sure that you can see the magnitude of the industry, and the wide market base we serve. As a Minuteman Press owner, you will have a unique place in the printing industry, having the capability to serve virtually all the printing needs a business may be faced with.   More... 
 
 Molly Maid    Residential house cleaning and maid service market is $12 billion and growing! Molly Maid offers 25 years of franchising expertise in this industry. Molly Maid founded in 1979, is the world&apos;s largest house cleaning franchise. Entrepreneur Magazine ranked Molly Maid #1 in the industry for 5 consecutive years.   More... 
 
 Music Go Round    The music equipment retail business has never been this exciting. Today&apos;s value-conscious consumers are choosing our music equipment retail stores, which buy, sell, trade and consign used and new music instruments and equipment.   More... 
 
 National Property Inspections, Inc.    Founded in Omaha, Nebraska in 1987, NPI is proud to be among the oldest and most widely respected names in the residential and commercial property inspection business, with experience and knowledge in home, building, and commercial property inspections.   More... 
 
 New Horizons Computer Learning Centers    At the heart of the New Horizons franchise is the world&apos;s most successful business model for IT training. Our sales system is unsurpassed in the industry, successfully tapping the revenue potential of all types of clients, from individuals to corporations.   More... 
 
 New York Butcher Shoppe, The    Our line of hand cut steaks using Premium Angus Beef, prepared entres, side dishes, salads and dips are always fresh and provide a unique shopping niche for our customers. We also offer fresh sausages, frozen pastas, vegetables, hard to find grocery items, and a top selection of fine wines and cheeses.   More... 
 
 New York NY Fresh Deli    New York Burrito Gourmet Wraps is quickly becoming famous for the generous portions and appetizing flavors our mouth-watering Mexican Specialties and Gourmet Wraps offer the casual gourmet aficionado.   More... 
 
 Novus Franchising, Inc.    NOVUS franchisees enjoy the benefits of the interdependent relationship that exists within our franchise system. We are proud to be able to offer a wonderful variety of products and services to a NOVUS customer such as, Auto Glass Repair&amp;Replacement, Spray on Bedliners, SRP Paint Restoration and SRP Glass Scratch Removal. Our complete support services and network of programs offer credibility and confidence, as they were built on a sound foundation of experience.   More... 
 
 Nu-Look 1Hr Cleaners    Nu-Look 1 Hr Cleaners can make that dream a reality without all the hassles of starting a business from scratch. Join a team of franchisees/licensees that have learned and continue to grow with Nu-Look. You will be provided with the ways of doing business that have been proven successful. We know what will work to bring the customers in, and what will keep them coming back to your store.   More... 
 
 Oil Butler International    Oil Butler is a mobile oil change and windshield repair franchise company servicing cars from individuals while at work and small to large fleets of vehicles of any business.   More... 
 
 Once Upon A Child    A retail children&apos;s store that buys and sells new and gently used children&apos;s products including toys, furniture, equipment, appareland accessories.   More... 
 
 OneClick Cleaners    Whether you have dreamed of the independence and success of owning your own profitable business or looking for a high yield investment, then OneClick Cleaners is for you! Gone are the days of traditional long retail hours, 7 days a week, paying rent and high expenses while waiting for customers. OneClick Cleaners software and technology works all day, every day helping you grow and expand with little or no overhead.   More... 
 
 Orange Julius Of America    Customers have enjoyed Orange Julius products for over 80 years. The independent franchise operators of Orange Julius restaurants and their employees, together with Orange Julius of America (OJA), strive to provide customers with the best products and service possible.   More... 
 
 Orion Food Systems    Orion Food Systems is the convenience store industrys leading U.S. franchisor of multi-branded quick-service concepts. Its various menus and proprietary concepts are found in over 1,500 locations. We are actively updating this site, so please be sure to check back often!   More... 
 
 Packaging And Shipping Specialists - P.A.S.S    P.A.S.S. provides total support in store operation, pricing, marketing, and advertising, as well as comprehensive ongoing assistance. Each store may choose their own name as they are owned and freely operated by enterprising people from all walks of life.   More... 
 
 Padgett Business Services USA, Inc.    Padgett Business Services is a professional network of locally owned and operated offices across North America. We are a financial reporting company specializing in the unique needs of owner-operated businesses. And, we provide personal, accurate, confidential and guaranteed on time service.   More... 
 
 Pak Mail Centers Of America    As the world&apos;s premier business solutions center, Pak Mail offers custom packaging and shipping solutions as well as an array of value-added servicesin one convenient location.   More... 
 
 Patrice and Associates - Hospitality Recruiting    Patrice&amp;Associates is one of the largest recruiting firms in the U.S., specializing in the hospitality industry. We&apos;ve earned a reputation for delivering the highest quality management candidates, using the kind of personal touch that&apos;s usually found in smaller recruiting firms. This business is designed to be a turnkey operation. We&apos;ve developed a large network of contacts in businesses across the U.S., and we&apos;ll share our leads with you! Our proprietary Applicant Tracking System gives you access to a database filled with job opportunities and management candidates. What&apos;s more, our extensive Internet presence generates new leads daily.   More... 
 
 Pip Printing    PIP offers a complete suite of Document Services to meet your specific needs. From complete project consultation to graphic design, online ordering, printing, and scanning&amp;archiving, PIP offers a document solution for your business.   More... 
 
 Plan Ahead Events - Special Events Planners    Plan Ahead Events is a home-based, full-service event management company serving clients worldwide. We offer creative solutions for meetings, conventions, trade shows, special events, and incentive travel, and will handle all the details for planning your event, from concept to completion. Plan Ahead Events is your single source for excellence on all occasions. We offer unparalleled service with one-stop shopping convenience, providing you with the services you require to ensure continuity and quality.   More... 
 
 Planet Beach Contempo Spa    Planet Beach Contempo Spas provide the ultimate skincare solution for customers in a non-invasive boutique environment. Our contempo spa services are exclusively available at Planet Beach locations and cannot be found anywhere else!   More... 
 
 Plato&apos;s Closet    Plato&apos;s Closet is all about being fashion savvy and shopping smart. We&apos;re a nationwide unique recycling retail store specializing in clothes for teens and twenty somethings we buy and sell the latest looks in gently used clothing and accessories from the hottest brand name designers for girls and guys.   More... 
 
 Play It Again Sports    For over 20 years, Play It Again Sports has been the preferred store of value-conscious consumers because we buy, sell and trade used and new sports equipment and gear. Because our customers can sell or trade in their quality used sports gear for cash or store credit, they are able to get deeper discounts and better prices on really great used and new equipment.   More... 
 
 Popeyes Chicken And Biscuits    Thirty-three years ago in New Orleans, Louisiana, a taste sensation was born. What began with one small restaurant and one big idea turned into a craze that swept the nation-- and the world.   More... 
 
 Postalannex +    Today&apos;s busy lifestyles demand our services of shipping and packaging, copying and printing, plus postal services. We save consumers time and money and, as we all know, that&apos;s what keeps them coming back.   More... 
 
 Postnet International Franchise Corporation    With the combined experience of over twenty years in the franchised postal and business services industry, PostNet&apos;s founders Steven Greenbaum and Brian Spindel launched the PostNet franchise program in July of 1993 and never looked back. In just twelve short years, PostNet International Franchise Corporation has become the fastest growing, largest privately-held company in both the postal and business services, and copy and print shop industries.   More... 
 
 Precision Tune Auto Care    Its all about Customer Loyalty. While no one can be all things to all people, Precision Tune Auto Care can proudly say that we have been providing a total car care approach for years ahead of our competition. We understand that consumers are looking for their mechanic and we offer consumers convenience by being in their neighborhoods and delivering a good value from owners who actually know their customers names. This, we believe, is the right mix to succeed in the automotive aftermarket. Afterall, were not just servicing cars, were serving people.   More... 
 
 Quizno&apos;s Classic Subs    Quiznos delivers uncompromising quality for today&apos;s busy consumers who are looking for a tasty, fresher alternative to traditional fast food restaurants. Using premium quality ingredients, Quiznos offers better-tasting food through creative, chef-inspired recipes to give you an experience thats truly a cut above all the others.   More... 
 
 Rainbow Intl. Carpet Care&amp;Restoration    Rainbow International is a worldwide restoration and cleaning company offering total restoration solutions for home and business, as well as cleaning services. Established in 1981, Rainbow International Restoration and Cleaning has over 300 service locations around the world offering solutions for water damage, smoke damage, fire restoration, odor removal, expert carpet cleaning, carpet repair, spot and stain removal and much more.   More... 
 
 Rally&apos;s Hamburgers, Inc.    Rallys is the nations largest chain of double drive-thru restaurants. With a left side and right side drive-thru lane and a walk-up window at each of our more than 800 locations, the brand is ideally positioned for todays on-the-go guest. Our mission is to serve top-quality meals at a great value with Guest-Obsessed hospitality, speed and accuracy at our double drive-thru lanes, and to foster a culture where employees are well-trained and well rewarded and franchisees are supported in their endeavors to better the brand.   More... 
 
 Re-Bath Corporation    Owning a Re-Bath Franchise will provide you with a proven business opportunity.
Over 84 million homes in the United States are over 15 years old, and each of these homes has at least one bathroom. That is a huge number of bathtubs, showers and walls in the residential market alone. Our comprehensive approach, excellent products, years of experience, sound management and positive reputation all combine to give you a unique opportunity in the booming remodeling industry.   More... 
 
 Remedy Staffing Services    As a Remedy franchisee, you&apos;ll be contributing to the economic health of your community. You&apos;ll be an important part of your community&apos;s fabric - the one people come to when they need a job for themselves, their kids, relatives or friends. In today&apos;s fast-changing business world, human resource management requirements change daily. And as a Remedy franchisee, you&apos;ll be there with solutions. Which is why Remedy offices are among the most profitable of today&apos;s franchise opportunities - outperforming many fast food and automotive services.   More... 
 
 Rita&apos;s Italian Ice    As a Rita&apos;s Franchisee, all of the staff at Rita&apos;s Water Ice Franchise Company, LLC is a part of your life for the entire term of your franchise agreement. You receive the benefit of the personal attention of a professional management team with years of retail, operations, franchising and business experience. Together, we form a substantial team that is always working together to help grow your business.   More... 
 
 Rocky Mountain Chocolate Factory    We are known for our entertaining fudge-making demonstrations, old-fashion caramel apples, and larger-than-life hand made chocolates. And with over two decades&apos; experience in chocolate candy making, operations and marketing, we offer the training and support that only a franchise company can provide. Plus, it&apos;s the perfect family business with market opportunities for single and multi-unit expansion.   More... 
 
 Roto-Rooter Corporation    In business since 1935, Roto-Rooter provides plumbing repair and sewer-drain cleaning services to homeowners, businesses, towns and cities. As a prospective franchisee, you will be associated with the recognized leader in the industry in fact, the creator of the industry. Roto-Rooter currently has a network of more than 600 franchisees and affiliates, both in the United States and throughout the world - a network of dedicated business people with whom you would be associated.   More... 
 
 Round Table Pizza    Round Table Pizza is the fifth largest pizza chain in the U.S. with over 500 restaurants in nine western states and five foreign countries. Headquartered in Concord, California, in the San Francisco Bay Area, Round Table has built a reputation as the pizza brand of choice and market share leader in the most competitive and discriminating restaurant markets in the country. We are recognized throughout the West for gourmet taste, quality and menu innovation.   More... 
 
 Rubbish Works    The Rubbish Works franchise opportunity offers a wide range of services from On-Demand Labor, Hauling, Waste Disposal, Junk Removal, Rubbish Pickup and Recycling Solutions for both residential and commercial customers. Rubbish Works can assist you with the removal of single items to multiple truckloads, helping you remove everything from old furniture and appliances, to garage items and renovation debris.   More... 
 
 Service Team of Professionals    Service Team of Professionals is a property restoration franchise that can be called on for prompt, professional and ethical service for any and all property damage needs, including water damage, smoke and fire damage, mold/mildew remediation, etc. No job is too big or too small.   More... 
 
 Servicemaster    Established in 1952, ServiceMaster Clean is one of North America&apos;s leading cleaning and restoration companies. A worldwide network of over 4,500 franchises provides an unparalleled reputation for service, quality, professionalism, and customer satisfaction. The company now operates in more than 12 countries and serves over 1 million customers through its broad network of quality services.   More... 
 
 SIGN World    
 
 Signal Graphics Printing    Signal Graphics stores are full service centers that offer a wide array of printing, copying and graphic design. From simple black and white to full color projects, our professional staff is waiting to assist you. Signal Graphics centers are part of a dynamic and growing industry that falls under the category of Digital Printing. What makes this industry so excitingand so enticingis that almost all businesses require the services offered by digital printershigh-speed digital copying (in both color and black and white), commercial printing, binding and design services.   More... 
 
 Sign-A-Rama    As a franchisee, you&apos;ll be able to offer a full range of the sign-making services that businesses need with a brand name they&apos;ve come to trust and respect. Just as significant, you&apos;ll get the benefit of time-tested business concepts that have worked for hundreds of other stores throughout the world. Best of all, you&apos;ll get the full support of the SIGN-A-RAMA team - a group that is committed to providing you with the training, consulting, equipment and resources you need to make your SIGN-A-RAMA store the sign of a successful business.   More... 
 
 Signs By Tomorrow    The Signs By Tomorrow family will enable you to learn from experienced custom sign business owners who were once in your position, and by doing so, you will gain the knowledge to make better decisions and enjoy greater success!   More... 
 
 Signs Now Corporation    Here at Signs Now, we help you &quot;Stand out in a crowded world&quot; with our world-class signage solutions. We take a consultative approach to developing the right solution for you. We listen to you and develop solutions that meet your requirements for image, communication, and durability.   More... 
 
 Smoothie King    A Smoothie King franchise offers two concepts in one. First, our smoothies please customers with delicious blends of real fruits, pure juices, and nutritional supplements available in over 50 flavors, 40 of which contain less than 1g of fat. Second, our stores feature a wide selection of branded nutritional products such as vitamins, minerals, low-fat snacks, sports nutrition supplements and much, much more.   More... 
 
 Snelling Personnel Services    What is already one of the fastest growing industries in the country, the staffing business provides tremendous opportunity for those who wish to take advantage of an expanding market amplified by increased job growth and a shrinking workforce. These changing dynamics in the economy provide an amazing opportunity for a Snelling Franchisee. Theres no better way to achieve the great American dream than by helping others achieve theirs.   More... 
 
 Sonic Drive-In Restaurants    It&apos;s hard to find a franchise concept that serves success, opportunity and fun on the same tray. SONIC has been doing just that since 1953. Along the way, we&apos;ve managed to become the largest chain of drive-in restaurants in the nation. Much of this success is due to our early beginnings and continued belief in the franchise system. It also reflects a strong relationship between our company and our customers, franchisees, employees and the communities where SONIC is located.   More... 
 
 Specialty Stores&amp;Restaurants    A specialty store or restaurant is a store, usually retail, that offers specific and specialized types of items or foods. These stores focus on selling a particular brand, or a particular type of item or food. For example, a store that exclusively sells cell phones or video games, or a restaurant that uses all organic foods, would be considered specialized.   More... 
 
 Speedee Oil Change&amp;Tune-Up    SpeeDee Oil Change and Tune-Up centers provide a full range of preventive and corrective maintenance services which includes oil and fluid change services, tune-up and complete brake service.   More... 
 
 Speedy Transmission Centers    Transmission service, repair, and rebuilding.   More... 
 
 Spring-Green Lawn Care Corp.    Professional lawn and tree care service.   More... 
 
 Stained Glass Overlay, Inc.    Patented decorative glass.   More... 
 
 Stanley Steemer International, Inc.    Carpet and furniture cleaning. Add-on licenses available for air duct cleaning ans carpet sales.   More... 
 
 Starkey International    
 
 Startup HomeCare    Startup HomeCare (SHC) provides quality, non-medical home care companionship, meal preparation, medication reminders, light housework, incidental transportation, errand management, personal care, grooming, shopping, and much, much more.   More... 
 
 Steak Escape, The    The original pioneer of the Philly Cheesesteak segment features the genuine Philly Cheesesteak, Fresh-cut French Fries and fresh squeezed lemonade with a variety of other grilled sandwiches, grilled salads and our very own &apos;Smashed Potato&apos;.   More... 
 
 Steak-Out Franchising    Delivery, carry-out and catering of charbroiled steak, burgers, chicken, salads and desserts to homes and offices.   More... 
 
 Steamatic, Incorporated    Residential and commercial carpet, furniture and drapery cleaning. Insurance restoration. Air duct and coil cleaning.   More... 
 
 Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads    Quick serve restaurant concept featuring submarine sandwiches&amp;assortment of fresh made salads. International chain of restaurants, serving fresh sliced, high quality meats and cheeses on fresh baked bread.   More... 
 
 SuperCoups - Direct Mail Advertising    Since 1982, SuperCoups&apos; direct marketing solutions have delivered local coupons with super savings to consumers, helping America&apos;s small businesses grow while maximizing returns on their advertising investment. SuperCoups&apos; exclusive coupn distribution model provides franchisees with a cost-effective way to creat high-impact returns for their customers.   More... 
 
 The Cravery - Gourmet Pot Pies    The company pioneers an innovative concept, offering, high quality, nutritious, handheld Gourmet pot pies a tastee entre wrapped in a golden crust which can be eaten without a fork. The Cravery pies are 100% handmade from scratch with all natural ingredients. The light flakey signature crust contains no Transfats.   More... 
 
 The Maids Home Services    The Maids is a professional residential cleaning service you can trust, not only for housekeeping and home cleaning services, but also for carpet cleaning and window cleaning. When you are looking for professional maid services to fulfill your house cleaning needs, don&apos;t call just anybody, call the best residential cleaning service: The Maids Home Services.   More... 
 
 The Marketing Department    The Marketing Department Worldwide is introducing a revolutionary new way for small business America to purchase affordable marketing and advertising solutions. This new experience is the nation&apos;s first marketing agency located in a high-profile, high traffic retail environment.   More... 
 
 The Queen&apos;s Residence Bed and Breakfast Inns    The Queen&apos;s Residence Bed and Breakfast Inns is a full service luxury bed and breakfast franchise offering guests an unrivaled lodging experience. The Queen&apos;s Residence Bed and Breakfast Inns is a new brand recognized for its high quality, exceptional service, tasteful and comfortable guest rooms, fine dining, and spotless cleanliness.   More... 
 
 TOGO&apos;s Eatery    A Togo&apos;s Eatery restaurant is a distinctive food service concept based upon a specific and distinctive family of specialty sandwiches and related food items.   More... 
 
 Top Dollar 4 Gold    Today, you don&apos;t have the local pawnshop as an only choice if you decide to sell your jewelry. You now have several options to get more benefits. Business is always about competition. Our greatest battle lies in providing the most accurate charge of your items and a service you can always count on.   More... 
 
 Tropical Smoothie Cafe    Tropical Smoothie Cafe is more than just great smoothies. Our gourmet wraps, specialty sandwiches and salads are made with only the highest quality Boar&apos;s Head brand meats and cheeses. Like our famous smoothies, every ingredient we use in our food is of the highest quality. Tropical Smoothie Cafe is quickly becoming one of the fastest growing franchises in the quick casual restaurant segment.   More... 
 
 Trova Home Care - Senior Care Franchise    Our Companion Care services are non-medical and were created to help encourage&amp;maintain the independent lifestyle. If you need assistance for yourself, or for a loved one, help is available a few hours a day up to full time live in care. Conversation, game playing and a walk around the neighborhood are just a few of the options we provide to promote mental and physical stimulation. Whether you live in the same house, around the corner, or miles away, caring for a loved one can be very stressful.   More... 
 
 Tuffy Auto Service Centers    General automotive service franchise. Tuffy Auto Service Centers deliver the quality and service people are looking for at a price they can afford. Our corporate buying power allows us to offer quality parts produced by nationally known manufacturers at prices most of our competitors can&apos;t match. And all Tuffy parts meet original equipment specifications. And when it comes to service.   More... 
 
 U.S. Lawns, Inc.    U.S. Lawns provides professional landscape management services to the commercial market. This includes annual contract to supply maintenance and related services to customers located within a protected territory. Home-based business.   More... 
 
 UBuildIt    UBuildIt offers a thorough and comprehensive system to aid an owner-builder in completing their self-managed construction projects. There is a growing do-it-yourself trend and mentality in this country, with more and more people expressing a desire to have control and involvement in their building project, while saving money in the process. UBuildIt provides a service that satisfies that need. Our motto says it all - Expert Help/Owner Control.   More... 
 
 United Country Real Estate    United Country Real Estate franchise system specializes in properties in America&apos;s small cities, towns and recreational areas. With over 700 offices nationwide, franchisees benefit from United Country&apos;s national advertising and an average of over 75 corporate-generated, no-fee buyer leads per week.   More... 
 
 United Coupon Corporation    Franchisees sell direct mail advertising products and services to businesses and other commercial entities.   More... 
 
 U-Save Auto Rental Of America, Inc.    New and used auto rental outlets. The initial investment varies according to whether it&apos;s an ad-on business or stand-alone franchise, and according to the size of the fleet with which you open.   More... 
 
 U-Turn Vending-Vending Machine Sales    
 
 ValPak Direct Marketing Systems    Valpak is the #1 brand by far with over 70,000 advertisers distributing over 20 billion inserts to targeted consumers in 44 million homes monthly. Consumers have grown to depend on Valpak products to deliver great savings and business owners continually enjoy the measured results and ongoing success of cooperative direct mail and web based advertising with Valpak, among the Top 100 Franchises.   More... 
 
 Vanguard Cleaning Systems, Inc.    Commercial cleaning and maintenance franchise. We provide accounts. training, equipment, billing and collection support, and customer service control.   More... 
 
 Waiting Game Publications    The WAITING GAME is a free, full-color, interactive, incentive-based monthly publication distributed anywhere consumers experience wait times (eg doctors&apos;/dentists&apos; offices, car washes/dealerships, karate/dance studios, beauty salons and anywhere people wait for services).   More... 
 
 Wienerschnitzel - Fast-Food Franchise    Wienerschnitzel was started with the opening of a single hot dog stand in 1961. Today, Wienerschnitzel is the World&apos;s Largest Hot Dog Chain with over 340 restaurants in ten states and Guam. Besides their signature chili dog, they are also loved for their delicious corn dogs, chili cheese fries and chili cheeseburgers. Wienerschnitzel is a hot dog heaven.   More... 
 
 Wingstop Restaurants Inc.    Through the development of our proprietary sauces and seasonings, we offer the consumer a unique variety of flavor selections while focusing on a single entree - buffalo style chicken wings. From a unique product mix to an aviation themed interior decor, Wingstop has positioned itself as the market leader. Fresh made-to-order buffalo style wings.   More... 
 
 WSI Internet - USA    WSI has developed one of the most profitable and established franchise opportunities in the world today, placing them at the #1 Internet Franchise and #1 Overall Technology Franchise spots in Entrepreneur Magazine. WSI Internet, with their outstanding track record, is now in its 11th year of business, with over 1500 franchises in more than 87 countries, making them the worlds leading Internet Services Franchise   More... 
 
 Yogli Mogli Frozen Yogurt    Yogli Mogli is a premium frozen yogurt store that offers a variety of nutritional yogurt flavors in a self serve environment. You also have the choice to top off your yogurt with a wide variety of options from fruits to nuts to gummy worms. The options here at Yogli Mogli are endless. With 16 flavors and over 40 different toppings to choose from, each delicious yogurt creation is unique. Everything is self-serve, and is priced by the weight, so you get exactly how much of a treat you want at the price that you want   More... 
 
 
             


 #1 WSI Internet 


 
 Site Map 
 Franchise Companies 
 Franchises: Top 500 
 Franchises: Top 100 
 Franchise Consultants 
 Franchise Attorneys 
 Fanchise Industry Categories 
 Our Mission Statement 
 Upcoming Franchise Expos 
 Fanchises For Sale 
 
 Preferred Franchises 
 Franchises:International Top 200 
 Business Categories of the Future 
 National Franchise Associations 
 General Information on Franchising 
 Are you cut out to be a franchisee? 
 Home-Based Franchises 
 Low Investment Franchises 
 Advertisers Index 
 
 Hot Franchises 
 FTC&apos;s Offices and It&apos;s Function 
 Expert Advice 
 Read About Top Franchises 
 Advertise on FIM 
 Fastest Growing Franchises 
 Food Franchises 
 Dream Franchises 
 Minority Franchise Opportunities 
 


 Suggestions&amp;Comments   - Links    - FIM&apos;s Newsletters   - Contact FIM   - Sitemap   - Feedback 
 Demographics   - Franchise Your Business   - Advertisers&apos; Index   - Advertise on FIM
	</body>
</document>
