<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008099" url="http://www.ocala.com/article/20100806/articles/8061000" time="2012-07-13-01:11" support="1" score="0.001665532318556988" bingtitle="Police and community briefs from Ocala and the Mario County region ..." webtitle="Police and community briefs from Ocala and the Mario County region for Aug. 6 | Ocala.com">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>... housed in the medical area of the Marion County Jail. ... A man who allegedly tried to rob a fast-food restaurant Wednesday ... Arby&apos;s manager said Jones came behind the counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Ocala.com Ocala Mom Bargain Shouter Veterans Health Pets Mugshots 
 Register | Log in   
 News Web Search by YAHOO! 
 Web Search
by YAHOO! | Home Delivery | eBANNER | Print Ads | Mobile | Place Ad 
 Home News 
 Local State Nation World Business Crime Elections Data Center Photo Galleries Video Weather Mugshots In Education Archive 
 
 Special Section Columnists Storm Guide Data Center Mobile SMS Mobile Alerts Mobile Real Estate Ocala.com Mobile Subscriptions Daily Headlines Breaking News Alerts Star Banner Print Edition 
 Sports 
 Prep Sports Gatorsports.com Colleges NFL MLB NBA NHL Golf Horse Racing Auto Racing 
 
 Scores Football Scoreboard Mobile Stats Blogs Bowling Blog User Photos Opix 
 Entertainment 
 TV Listings Movies Photo Galleries Video Games Events Tickets 
 
 Special Section Johnny on the Spot Multimedia Opix Community Events Calendar Featured Events Deal of the Week 
 Living 
 Health Crossword Sudoku Coupons 
 
 Home Decor In Education TV Listings Multimedia Photo Galleries Video Opix Data Center Restaurant Inspections Mobile Mobile Real Estate 
 Opinion 
 Send us a Letter Editorial Cartoons Blogs 
 
 Blogs The Legal Dish What is That? Snapshots from the Past 
 Blogs Obituaries Classifieds 
 Merchandise Boats Motorcycles Yard Sales Roommates Pets Services Announcements Personals Print Ads Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad Legal 
 

 Real Estate Jobs Cars 
 Home Article Repository 
 Comments Share 
 Digg Reddit LinkedIn Mixx Technorati Myspace 

 FARK FURL 
 Email Print 
 WITH PHOTO NO PHOTO 
 Reprints Enlarge Text 
 Tweet 
 Police and community briefs for Aug. 6, 2010 
 Staff and wire reports.
 
Published: Friday, August 6, 2010 at 6:30 a.m.

Last Modified: Friday, August 6, 2010 at 12:14 a.m.
 
POLICE BEAT

 Bank robbery suspect hospitalized Wednesday 
 
Wayne Leonard Hurst, who surrendered to authorities Wednesday in connection with a bank robbery, was hospitalized Wednesday night.

Jail officials, who could not discuss his medical problem, said he was transported to Munroe Regional Medical Center at 10:30 p.m.

Officials said there was no suicide attempt and that Hurst had been housed in the medical area of the Marion County Jail.

A neighbor at the RV park where Hurst lived with a female roommate told the Star-Banner that Hurst has epilepsy. He said Hurst did odd jobs around the RV park and was a hard worker.

Hurst remained in the hospital late Thursday.

 Man accused of trying to rob Arby&apos;s on SR 40 

A man who allegedly tried to rob a fast-food restaurant Wednesday was arrested by police and charged with attempted strong arm robbery, according to officials.

Cpl. Christopher Scaglione was dispatched to Arby&apos;s at 2130 E. Silver Springs Blvd. about a criminal mischief. On scene, the officer noticed a man, later identified as Robert Craig Jones, behind the counter. When asked to come from behind the counter, Jones fled and the officer called for assistance.

The Arby&apos;s manager said Jones came behind the counter, grabbed his hand and pushed him up against the cash register and said, &quot;Just do it!&quot;

When he asked, &quot;Do what?&quot;, the manager said Jones pointed at the cash register.

That&apos;s when the officer arrived and Jones ran away.

The manager at a nearby Taco Bell told officials Jones came to the restaurant and she told him to leave as he was shirtless. He refused to leave and began acting suspiciously and walked toward an employee entrance door. He was prevented from entering, and employees called police.

Cpl. Richard Knobloch saw Jones running outside Taco Bell and pulled into the parking lot to cut him off. When Jones saw the officer, he stopped running.

 Woman, 23, charged with hit and run, DUI 

Police arrested a 23-year-old Ocala woman Wednesday night after she admitted leaving the scene of an accident that injured a man.

Officer Ira Stokes went to Village West Apartments at 3016 S.W. 20th St. and met a woman who said her brother Jose Ayala, 25, had been struck by a vehicle and was taken to West Marion Hospital with head and leg injuries.

The officer went to the hospital and spoke with Ayala, who said he left his apartment around 8:30 p.m. to go to the Kangaroo gas station on Southwest 20th Street to return videos. He said he didn&apos;t remember the crash, only that he woke up in the grass and was unable to move his legs because they were numb.

Ayala said he laid there until he could move his legs, then walked home.

His sister went to the scene and found her brother&apos;s eyeglasses and what appeared to be a broken headlight.

While investigating, the officer received a call from a sheriff&apos;s deputy telling him he stopped a silver 2001 Ford Explorer driven by Kayla Ann Nunn near the 6200 block of Southwest 80th Avenue. The deputy noted the windshield on the right passenger side was damaged, the passenger side mirror was hanging down and the right headlight was broken.

Passenger Erica Orme told the deputy that Nunn hit a man wearing a light colored tank top near the Kangaroo.

The officer contacted Orme and was told a similar story. Orme told the officer she begged Nunn to stop, but she continued to drive until stopped by the deputy.

Officials went to the crash scene and found a piece of a side mirror, an antenna and tire tracks.

Nunn told the officer she was driving and had struck a man. She claimed Ayala was in the middle of the road.

Police say that was impossible based on evidence at the location.

Nunn was arrested and charged with leaving the scene of a crash with injuries. She was also charged with DUI.

 Police investigating shooting at Ocala home 

Police need assistance finding the person or persons who fired multiple shots at a pickup parked in front of an Ocala home.

Shortly before 5 a.m. Thursday, officers received a report about shots fired in the 1600 block of Northwest 17th Place. There, officers were told by a neighbor that she was inside her home when she heard several gunshots. She said she waited a few minutes before going outside.

A silver Ford F-150 truck parked nearby had six bullet holes in it, from the front left bumper to the rear passenger door.

At the time of the shooting, sleeping inside the home at which the truck was parked was one of two men reportedly seen earlier in the week with Kenterrell Wright, 20, who was arrested by Detective Matt Bos and charged with shooting Monday into a vehicle that contained a woman and her 5-year-old son.

Wright was in the Marion County Jail at the time shots were fired at the pickup.

Detectives do not know if the incidents are related, and said the investigation is ongoing.

Anyone with information can call Bos at 369-7000.

Two men arrested in separate sex cases

Two men were arrested Wednesday by sheriff&apos;s detectives in separate sex cases.

A 14-year-old girl told Detective Mark Peavy that Joseph Nieves De Leon, 21, gave her a tattoo and she performed a sex act on him.

De Leon at first denied such activity but, later on, a crying De Leon admitted to the accusations.

De Leon, who was arrested in June for manufacturing marijuana, was taken to the Marion County Jail and charged with lewd and lascivious battery, lewd and lascivious molestation and tattooing a minor.

While that case was unfolding, Detective Miriam Diaz was assisting in a domestic dispute case when deputies were told a girl might be a victim of sexual abuse.

The 17-year-old girl told Diaz that when she was 7, their family moved from New Jersey to Marion County, where she was molested by Eric Lamont Tardy, now 43.

The teenager said the abuse occurred more than a 100 times when she was in middle school.

She also said Tardy was a deacon at House of Prayer and he took her there and exposed himself.

The church no longer exists.

The incidents were reportedly known by the teen&apos;s mother, who told officials she confronted Tardy, but he denied them.

Tardy told Diaz he may have molested the girl once, mistaking her for his wife. He said it was during a time when he was abusing drugs.

He was arrested and charged with capital sexual battery, lewd and lascivious battery and lewd and lascivious exhibition.

 Deputies investigating theft of 100 chickens 

DUNNELLON - Deputies want to know who stole a number of young chickens as well as feed and wire cages from a home nearly a week ago.

Officials say on Sunday, they received a call from a woman saying 100 chickens, which were 1- to 3-month-old Rhode Island Reds, Buff Orpingtons and White Rocks; 20 50-pound sacks of feed; and eight wire cages were missing from her barn.

The items were valued at $1,100.

Anyone with information can call the Sheriff&apos;s Office at 732-9111 or Crime Stoppers at 368-STOP, or visit www.ocalacrimestoppers.com.

COMMUNITY

 Second case of EEE identified in horse 

A horse in the Micanopy area has tested positive for Eastern Equine Encephalitis, according to the Marion County Health Department. It was the second case of EEE this year, and both were in horses.

EEE is transmitted to animals and humans through bites of infected mosquitoes. Symptoms can begin four to 10 days after a bite and can include sudden headache, high fever, chills and vomiting. The disease can progress into disorientation, seizures and coma.

An infant in Tampa and a Hillsborough County woman died of the disease in mid-July.

To avoid mosquito bites, the health department recommends the &quot;5 Ds&quot; approach:

Dusk and Dawn: Avoid being outdoors when mosquitoes are most active.

Dress: Wear clothing that covers most of the skin.

DEET: Use repellents containing DEET (N,N-diethyl-meta-toluamide or N,N-diethyl-3-methylbenzamide). Picaridin and oil of lemon eucalyptus are options.

Drainage: Rid areas of standing water where mosquitoes can lay eggs.

For more information, call the Health Department at 629-0137.

 Businesses can apply for faade grants 

Businesses in the city of Ocala&apos;s Community Redevelopment Area - both the North Magnolia and downtown sections - are eligible for matching faade grants to revitalize the area.

The city has $50,000 available for those in the CRA, which is bounded by Northwest 20th Street on the north, Southeast 10th Street (&quot;S&quot; Curve) on the south, Southeast Watula Avenue/Northeast Eighth Avenue on the east and Pine Avenue/Highway 441 to the west.

The grants are available on a 50-50 matching basis, with a maximum of $10,000 per property.

The city will accept applications through March 1, 2011.

For an application package or program guidelines, call Endira Sharma at 629-8313. Applications may be downloaded from www.ocalafl.org.

Since 2009, the city has awarded faade grants totaling $106,822 to 16 projects.

 Sign language course begins Aug. 24 

Citrus Hearing Impaired Program Services will offer a six-week class for American Sign Language from 5:30 to 7 p.m. beginning Tuesday, Aug. 24, at 8960 S.W. Highway 200, Suite 2.

Cost is $40. Registration required. For more information, call 368-4070.

 Student leadership program set for CF 

LECANTO - The College of Central Florida Citrus Campus is accepting enrollment for its fourth year of Leadership, Ethics&amp;Public Service (LEAPS). The program is free and open to all CF and high school students from Citrus, Levy and Marion counties.

Workshops will be held 6 to 8:30 p.m. Thursdays, Sept. 23 through Nov. 4, at 3800 S. Lecanto Highway. Sessions will cover: Appreciating Cultural Diversity, Solving the Personality Puzzle, Team Building, Improving Communication Skills, Youth Activism and Grassroots Advocacy, Exploring Leadership Styles and Exploring Volunteer Opportunities.

Registration required. For more information, call 249-1207.

 MCFR not involved in phone solicitation 

Marion County Fire Rescue has received calls from citizens expressing concerns about a phone solicitation requesting funds to support local firefighters.

MCFR is not associated with any organization collecting money for firefighters and has not received any funds from any agency.

Before giving donations to any entity, citizens should investigate the legitimacy of the solicitor and find out how the agency plans to allocate donations. If citizens suspect the donation request is a scam, they should contact the Marion County Sheriff&apos;s Office non-emergency line at 732-9111.
 Police and community briefs for Aug. 6, 2010 Staff and wire reports. Ocala.com August 6, 2010 12:14 AM &lt;p class=&quot;bold allcaps&quot;&gt;POLICE BEAT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bank robbery suspect hospitalized Wednesday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wayne Leonard Hurst, who surrendered to authorities Wednesday in connection with a bank robbery, was hospitalized Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jail officials, who could not discuss his medical problem, said he was transported to Munroe Regional Medical Center at 10:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials said there was no suicide attempt and that Hurst had been housed in the medical area of the Marion County Jail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A neighbor at the RV park where Hurst lived with a female roommate told the Star-Banner that Hurst has epilepsy. He said Hurst did odd jobs around the RV park and was a hard worker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hurst remained in the hospital late Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Man accused of trying to rob Arby&apos;s on SR 40&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A man who allegedly tried to rob a fast-food restaurant Wednesday was arrested by police and charged with attempted strong arm robbery, according to officials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cpl. Christopher Scaglione was dispatched to Arby&apos;s at 2130 E. Silver Springs Blvd. about a criminal mischief. On scene, the officer noticed a man, later identified as Robert Craig Jones, behind the counter. When asked to come from behind the counter, Jones fled and the officer called for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Arby&apos;s manager said Jones came behind the counter, grabbed his hand and pushed him up against the cash register and said,&quot;Just do it!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he asked,&quot;Do what?&quot;, the manager said Jones pointed at the cash register.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s when the officer arrived and Jones ran away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The manager at a nearby Taco Bell told officials Jones came to the restaurant and she told him to leave as he was shirtless. He refused to leave and began acting suspiciously and walked toward an employee entrance door. He was prevented from entering, and employees called police.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cpl. Richard Knobloch saw Jones running outside Taco Bell and pulled into the parking lot to cut him off. When Jones saw the officer, he stopped running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Woman, 23, charged with hit and run, DUI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police arrested a 23-year-old Ocala woman Wednesday night after she admitted leaving the scene of an accident that injured a man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officer Ira Stokes went to Village West Apartments at 3016 S.W. 20th St. and met a woman who said her brother Jose Ayala, 25, had been struck by a vehicle and was taken to West Marion Hospital with head and leg injuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The officer went to the hospital and spoke with Ayala, who said he left his apartment around 8:30 p.m. to go to the Kangaroo gas station on Southwest 20th Street to return videos. He said he didn&apos;t remember the crash, only that he woke up in the grass and was unable to move his legs because they were numb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ayala said he laid there until he could move his legs, then walked home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His sister went to the scene and found her brother&apos;s eyeglasses and what appeared to be a broken headlight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While investigating, the officer received a call from a sheriff&apos;s deputy telling him he stopped a silver 2001 Ford Explorer driven by Kayla Ann Nunn near the 6200 block of Southwest 80th Avenue. The deputy noted the windshield on the right passenger side was damaged, the passenger side mirror was hanging down and the right headlight was broken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passenger Erica Orme told the deputy that Nunn hit a man wearing a light colored tank top near the Kangaroo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The officer contacted Orme and was told a similar story. Orme told the officer she begged Nunn to stop, but she continued to drive until stopped by the deputy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials went to the crash scene and found a piece of a side mirror, an antenna and tire tracks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nunn told the officer she was driving and had struck a man. She claimed Ayala was in the middle of the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police say that was impossible based on evidence at the location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nunn was arrested and charged with leaving the scene of a crash with injuries. She was also charged with DUI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Police investigating shooting at Ocala home&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police need assistance finding the person or persons who fired multiple shots at a pickup parked in front of an Ocala home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shortly before 5 a.m. Thursday, officers received a report about shots fired in the 1600 block of Northwest 17th Place. There, officers were told by a neighbor that she was inside her home when she heard several gunshots. She said she waited a few minutes before going outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A silver Ford F-150 truck parked nearby had six bullet holes in it, from the front left bumper to the rear passenger door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time of the shooting, sleeping inside the home at which the truck was parked was one of two men reportedly seen earlier in the week with Kenterrell Wright, 20, who was arrested by Detective Matt Bos and charged with shooting Monday into a vehicle that contained a woman and her 5-year-old son.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wright was in the Marion County Jail at the time shots were fired at the pickup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detectives do not know if the incidents are related, and said the investigation is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone with information can call Bos at 369-7000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two men arrested in separate sex cases&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two men were arrested Wednesday by sheriff&apos;s detectives in separate sex cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 14-year-old girl told Detective Mark Peavy that Joseph Nieves De Leon, 21, gave her a tattoo and she performed a sex act on him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;De Leon at first denied such activity but, later on, a crying De Leon admitted to the accusations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;De Leon, who was arrested in June for manufacturing marijuana, was taken to the Marion County Jail and charged with lewd and lascivious battery, lewd and lascivious molestation and tattooing a minor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While that case was unfolding, Detective Miriam Diaz was assisting in a domestic dispute case when deputies were told a girl might be a victim of sexual abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 17-year-old girl told Diaz that when she was 7, their family moved from New Jersey to Marion County, where she was molested by Eric Lamont Tardy, now 43.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teenager said the abuse occurred more than a 100 times when she was in middle school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She also said Tardy was a deacon at House of Prayer and he took her there and exposed himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The church no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incidents were reportedly known by the teen&apos;s mother, who told officials she confronted Tardy, but he denied them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tardy told Diaz he may have molested the girl once, mistaking her for his wife. He said it was during a time when he was abusing drugs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was arrested and charged with capital sexual battery, lewd and lascivious battery and lewd and lascivious exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deputies investigating theft of 100 chickens&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DUNNELLON - Deputies want to know who stole a number of young chickens as well as feed and wire cages from a home nearly a week ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials say on Sunday, they received a call from a woman saying 100 chickens, which were 1- to 3-month-old Rhode Island Reds, Buff Orpingtons and White Rocks; 20 50-pound sacks of feed; and eight wire cages were missing from her barn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The items were valued at $1,100.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone with information can call the Sheriff&apos;s Office at 732-9111 or Crime Stoppers at 368-STOP, or visit www.ocalacrimestoppers.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;COMMUNITY&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Second case of EEE identified in horse&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A horse in the Micanopy area has tested positive for Eastern Equine Encephalitis, according to the Marion County Health Department. It was the second case of EEE this year, and both were in horses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EEE is transmitted to animals and humans through bites of infected mosquitoes. Symptoms can begin four to 10 days after a bite and can include sudden headache, high fever, chills and vomiting. The disease can progress into disorientation, seizures and coma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An infant in Tampa and a Hillsborough County woman died of the disease in mid-July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To avoid mosquito bites, the health department recommends the&quot;5 Ds&quot;approach:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dusk and Dawn: Avoid being outdoors when mosquitoes are most active.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dress: Wear clothing that covers most of the skin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DEET: Use repellents containing DEET (N,N-diethyl-meta-toluamide or N,N-diethyl-3-methylbenzamide). Picaridin and oil of lemon eucalyptus are options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drainage: Rid areas of standing water where mosquitoes can lay eggs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information, call the Health Department at 629-0137.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Businesses can apply for faade grants&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Businesses in the city of Ocala&apos;s Community Redevelopment Area - both the North Magnolia and downtown sections - are eligible for matching faade grants to revitalize the area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city has $50,000 available for those in the CRA, which is bounded by Northwest 20th Street on the north, Southeast 10th Street (&quot;S&quot;Curve) on the south, Southeast Watula Avenue/Northeast Eighth Avenue on the east and Pine Avenue/Highway 441 to the west.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The grants are available on a 50-50 matching basis, with a maximum of $10,000 per property.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city will accept applications through March 1, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an application package or program guidelines, call Endira Sharma at 629-8313. Applications may be downloaded from www.ocalafl.org.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2009, the city has awarded faade grants totaling $106,822 to 16 projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sign language course begins Aug. 24&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Citrus Hearing Impaired Program Services will offer a six-week class for American Sign Language from 5:30 to 7 p.m. beginning Tuesday, Aug. 24, at 8960 S.W. Highway 200, Suite 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cost is $40. Registration required. For more information, call 368-4070.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student leadership program set for CF&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LECANTO - The College of Central Florida Citrus Campus is accepting enrollment for its fourth year of Leadership, Ethics&amp;amp; Public Service (LEAPS). The program is free and open to all CF and high school students from Citrus, Levy and Marion counties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Workshops will be held 6 to 8:30 p.m. Thursdays, Sept. 23 through Nov. 4, at 3800 S. Lecanto Highway. Sessions will cover: Appreciating Cultural Diversity, Solving the Personality Puzzle, Team Building, Improving Communication Skills, Youth Activism and Grassroots Advocacy, Exploring Leadership Styles and Exploring Volunteer Opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Registration required. For more information, call 249-1207.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MCFR not involved in phone solicitation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marion County Fire Rescue has received calls from citizens expressing concerns about a phone solicitation requesting funds to support local firefighters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MCFR is not associated with any organization collecting money for firefighters and has not received any funds from any agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before giving donations to any entity, citizens should investigate the legitimacy of the solicitor and find out how the agency plans to allocate donations. If citizens suspect the donation request is a scam, they should contact the Marion County Sheriff&apos;s Office non-emergency line at 732-9111.&lt;/p&gt; Copyright 2012 Ocala.com - All rights reserved. Restricted use only. 
All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published 
 without permission. Links are encouraged.
 ▲Return to Top 
 Most Read Most Emailed Most Recent 
 
 Local favorite Tommy&apos;s Bar-B-Que closes doors Former Gator coach Zook enjoying life on Lake Weir Doctor: Fla. teen in beating case deeply troubled Ocala city manager proposes cutting $700K from OPD Police, community and calendar briefs for July 12, 2012 
 
 Local favorite Tommy&apos;s Bar-B-Que closes doors Former Gator coach Zook enjoying life on Lake Weir Last drugs standing: Key Alzheimer results coming Call center may bring 300 jobs to downtown Ocala Foley gets funny 
 
 Lane closures, roadblocks planned for I-75 Several factors cited in death of lineman, report says Part of Franck&apos;s network sold Steven Tyler exiting as &apos;American Idol&apos; judge Progress’ex-CEO to testify 
 
 Photos 

 
 Pictures of the day 
 
 Jr. Team Tennis Camp 
 
 Foals at Ocala Stud 
 
 Ron Zook at Brantley Quarterback Camp 
 
 Pictures of the day 07.11.12 
 
 Ballerinas downtown 
 
 
Events Calendar More Events Submit Event 

 12 Thu 13 Fri 14 Sat 15 Sun 16 Mon 
 
 Find Local Businesses 
 
 Keyword(s): Location: Popular Searches Apartments in Ocala 
 Attorneys in Ocala 
 Auto Dealers in Ocala 
 Auto Parts in Ocala 
 Auto Repair in Ocala 
 Beauty Salons in Ocala 
 Car Rental in Ocala 
 Dentists in Ocala 
 Doctors in Ocala 
 Flowers in Ocala 
 Hotels in Ocala 
 Insurance in Ocala 
 Loans in Ocala 
 Mortgages in Ocala 
 Movers in Ocala 
 Pizza in Ocala 
 Realtors in Ocala 
 Restaurants in Ocala 
 Storage in Ocala 
 Tax Preparation in Ocala 
 Travel in Ocala 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com 
 
 News 

 Local Politics State Nation/World Weather News Archive 
 
 Multimedia 

 Photos Video Blogs Forums 
 
 Sports 

 Local Colleges Professional Youth Horse Racing Golf Tickets 
 
 Entertainment 

 Movies TV Listings Promotions Tickets 
 
 Living 

 In Education Coupons 
 
 Real Estate 

 For sale Rentals Find an Agent 
 
 Classifieds 

 For Sale/Wanted Special Sections Services Legal Rentals Autos Print Ads Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad Local Businesses 
 
 Contact Us About Us Advertising Subscribe Work for Us Help Privacy Policy About Our Ads Corrections RSS Terms of Service Photo Reprints Site Map 
 Copyright©2012 Ocala.com—All rights reserved. Restricted use only.
	</body>
</document>
