<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008036" url="http://legalnews.findlaw.com/article/0eLO9Sf3Foe1i?q=%28%28nba+OR+nfl+OR+nhl+OR+mlb+OR+mls+OR+nascar+OR+ncaa+OR+football+OR+baseball+OR+hockey+OR+soccer+OR+basketball+OR+golf+OR+tennis+OR+cycling+OR+sports+OR+boxing+OR+%22swim+meet%22+OR+%22track+meet%22+OR+olympics+OR+coach+OR+%22extreme+sports%22+OR+skiing+OR+snowboarding+OR+sprinter+OR+marathon+OR+triathlon%29+AND+%28arrested+OR+union+OR+charged+OR+accused+OR+fired+OR+hired+OR+regulation+OR+law+OR+doping+OR+rigging+OR+rigged+OR+%22drug+abuse%22+OR+legislation%29%29+OR+%22eligibility+violation%22+OR+%22sports+law%22" time="2012-07-13-01:06" support="1" score="0.0012081877011106367" bingtitle="Hurricanes beat Canadiens 2-1 in shootout" webtitle="Hurricanes beat Canadiens 2-1 in shootout">
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>... Florida and across the nation have racked up credit card ... Fast food restaurant sued by former employee 9 hours ago ... year and a team that can vie for the Stanley Cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you a legal professional? 
 Visit Our Professional Site Law firm marketing Search 
 Learn About the Law Find a Lawyer FindLaw Answers Legal Forms News Blogs 
 
 FindLaw Legal Pulse Story 
 Idaho Statesman 3 months ago 
Hurricanes beat Canadiens 2-1 in shootout
 
 Eric Staal scored in the shootout to lead the Carolina Hurricanes past the Montreal Canadiens , 2-1 on Thursday night. Chad LaRose scored a power-play goal, and Cam Ward made 30 saves before stopping the Canadiens cold in the tiebreaker to give the Hurric Full Article at Idaho Statesman 
 
 Related Articles from FindLaw 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Related Articles from Attorneys 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Related Articles from the web 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Share this page 
 
 Share 
 Delicious Myspace Yahoo! Buzz StumbleUpon Mixx Reddit Digg Newsvine 
 Share on Facebook Email Your Name* Your Email* Recipient&apos;s Email* (separated by commas) Message I want to share&quot;Hurricanes beat Canadiens 2-1 in shootout&quot;via FindLaw Legal Pulse with you. Send Done Share on Twitter 
 
 Search FindLaw News 
 
 All Content Articles Quotes Photos Topics 
 
 Related Photos 
 

 
 Cast of Characters 
 
There are no results for this module. You may be filtering results with a topic filter, or else there are no results. Edit the module to change the filter options or the search term used to query related topics.
 
 Related Quotes 
 
 The way he played the second half (of the season), it was great to see him be the final shooter and score the final goal – Kirk Muller SOURCE: Boston Herald 3 months ago It wasn’t the prettiest looking goal ... I’m just glad it went in for Cam because I thought he played a real solid game. – Eric Staal SOURCE: Boston Herald 3 months ago I definitely didn’t want it to end with Erik Cole scoring on me in a shootout ... The thing about the shootout is, you have to be able to be relaxed. I felt like I was more patient than previous shootouts, and it paid off. It’s almost like the less you try, the better you get. – Cam Ward SOURCE: Boston Herald 3 months ago We&apos;re pleased in the fact that nobody quit and it was great effort on many guys&apos; part SOURCE: The Sports Network 3 months ago 
 View all Related Quotes » 

Learn More About
 Legal Topics / State Laws / Bookshelf / Blogs / FindLaw RSS Feeds / Sitemap /
 Geography Sitemap / FindLaw En Español / LawBrain / FindLaw UK / FindLaw Mobile 


Find a Lawyer
 Browse by Location / Browse by Legal Issue / Search by Name 


Find Answers
 FindLaw Answers / Community Guidelines 


Get Legal Forms
 Visit our Legal Forms site 


For Lawyers
 Visit our professional site / Edit your legal profile / Website development / Advertise on our site 


About Us
 Company History / Media / Contact Us / Privacy / Terms / Disclaimer / Advertising / Jobs 


Local Lawyers
 Atlanta Lawyers / Boston Lawyers / Chicago Lawyers / Dallas Lawyers / Houston Lawyers /
 Los Angeles Lawyers / Miami Lawyers / New York City Lawyers / Phoenix Lawyers /
 San Diego Lawyers / UK-based Lawyers / More... 


Find Us On
           
 Copyright©2012 FindLaw, a Thomson Reuters business. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
