<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008295" url="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20100136168" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="2" score="0.0008192988679952288" bingtitle="SUPPLEMENTED FRUIT OR VEGETABLE PRODUCT - Patent application" webtitle="SUPPLEMENTED FRUIT OR VEGETABLE PRODUCT - Patent application">
			<query id="001137" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>... are sealed in cans, jars or plastic cups. In ... chain, a theme park, a restaurant, a fast food restaurant, a ... on the tree, branch, or other growing receptacle where ...</description>
	<body>
		Inventors list 
 
 Assignees list 
 
 Classification tree browser 
 
 Top 100 Inventors 
 
 Top 100 Assignees 
 

Patent application title: SUPPLEMENTED FRUIT OR VEGETABLE PRODUCT 

Inventors:  Blair C. Mchaney (Wenatchee, WA, US)   Kevin P. Johnson (East Wenatchee, WA, US) 
IPC8 Class: AA23L1212FI 
USPC Class: 426 52 
Class name: Fermentation processes of plant or plant derived material with added enzyme material or microorganism 
Publication date: 2010-06-03 
Patent application number: 20100136168 
 
 
 
 
 Sign up to receive free email alerts when patent applications with chosen keywords are published SIGN UP 
 
Abstract:

Compositions of supplemented fruit and/or vegetable products as well as
 methods for making the same are provided. Certain embodiments include
 supplements of macronutrients and/or micronutrients. Also provided are
 processes of manufacture and business methods relating to the
 compositions disclosed.
Claims:

 1. A composition comprising a pureed fruit or vegetable product and an
 additive selected from the group consisting of flavoring, sweetener,
 color, vitamins, minerals and a macronutrient.

 2. The composition of claim 1 wherein said vitamin is selected from the
 group consisting of vitamin C, folic acid, vitamin D, and vitamin E.

 3. The composition of claim 1 wherein said mineral is selected from the
 group consisting of iron, calcium and magnesium.

 4. The composition of claim 1 wherein said macronutrient is selected from
 the group consisting of fatty acids, oil, protein, and amino acids.

 5. The composition of claim 4 wherein said macronutrient is from the
 source of flaxseed oil.

 6. The composition of claim 1 wherein said flavor is selected from the
 group consisting of apple, chocolate, rum, triple sec, peppermint,
 ginger, orange, lemon, lime, blueberry, blackberry, strawberry,
 margarita, pina colada, daiquiri, cherry, root beer, butterscotch, peanut
 butter, vodka, gin, whiskey, brandy, cheese, wine flavors (such as
 merlot, cabernet, chardonnay, etc.), smoked, barbeque, chipotle, ranch,
 curry, vanilla, mint, cinnamon, apple pie, raspberry, maple, grape, cola,
 caramel, mango, kiwi, English Toffee, cocoa, tropical flavors, bubble
 gum, peach, coconut, bergamot, cinnamon bark, ginger ale, grapefruit,
 lemon-lime, mandarin, sweet orange, triple sec, almond butter, butter
 pecan, coffee, cream, honey, peanut, guava, amaretto, Asian Blender,
 Creme de Menthe, Kalamansi, Sloe berry, Chai Tea, Tequila, white
 strawberry, white cranberry, ginger, white grape, guarana, jasmine,
 malted milk, mint, orange juice, orange sherbet, Oriental Herbal, punch,
 sugar, tropical fruit, Chichamorada, Cherimoya, Ginseng mint, melon,
 papaya, Ming Tea, Sweet Musk melon, pandan, tamarind, tangerine,
 strawberry kiwi, guanabana, peach apricot, Apple strudel, chocolate
 cherry, chocolate mint, French vanilla, licorice, minty melon, Amaretto,
 chocolate fudge, green bell pepper, Muscat, baby powder, Boston Creme,
 cantaloupe, cheesecake, chocolate hazelnut, cologne, hazelnut, pine oil,
 pizza, sesame oil, pumpkin spice, rose, brown sugar, sweet roll, tropical
 punch, vanilla cream, Bleu Cheese, melted butter, sweet butter, roasted
 chicken, milk chocolate, toasted coconut, ginger snap, graham cracker,
 mushroom, pecan, pistachio, red raspberry, blue raspberry, strudel,
 wafer, walnut, Royal cream, sour cream, dry apricot, caramel corn, cotton
 candy, cranapple, Temple orange, fresh pineapple, black raspberry, fresh
 strawberry, passion fruit, wildberry, orange cream, sweet cherry, banana,
 mango, wild raspberry, wild blueberry, wild blackberry, root beer cream,
 cola cream, carrot, carrot cake, pumpkin, &quot;buttery&quot; versions of any
 flavors described herein, any flavors described herein with cinnamon or
 extra cinnamon or other spice, or any combination thereof.

 7. The composition of claim 1 wherein said sweetener is selected from the
 group consisting of: white cane sugar or syrup, brown sugar or syrup,
 dextrose, glucose, lactose, whey, ribose, xylose, xylitol, rhamnose, date
 sugar, white or brown rice syrup, malt, molasses or molasses powder,
 honey, dehydrated honey, corn syrup or corn syrup solids, maple syrup,
 high fructose corn syrup, fructose, saccharin, Splenda® (sucralose),
 NutraSweet® (aspartame), acesulfame-K, stevia, Shugr® (a mixture of
 erythritol, maltodextrin and sucralose), any modification of these
 sweeteners, any combination thereof, and the like.

 8. The composition of claim 1 wherein said fruit or vegetable is selected
 from the group consisting of apples, pears, Asian pears, cherries,
 strawberries, plums, peaches, nectarines, grapes, melons guava, dates,
 figs, apricots, kiwi, lemons, limes, grapefruit, oranges, tangelos,
 kumquats, ugli fruit, mandarin oranges, Satsuma oranges, mango, bananas,
 passion fruit, pineapple, cranberries, blueberries, blackberries, papaya,
 coconut, jackfruit, tomatoes, lettuce, spinach, Swiss chard, potatoes,
 carrots, beans, and corn.

 9. The composition of claim 1 wherein said fruit or vegetable comprises
 apples.

 10. The composition of claim 1 wherein said fruit or vegetable product
 comprises applesauce.

 11. The composition of claim 10 wherein said fruit or vegetable product
 comprises applesauce, and said additive comprises at least flaxseed oil
 and protein.

 12. A method of making a processed fruit or vegetable product comprising
 comminuting a fruit or vegetable into particulate matter, contacting said
 fruit or vegetable matter with at least one additive selected from the
 group consisting of flavoring agent, coloring agent, preservative,
 vitamins, minerals, and macronutrients.

 13. The method of claim 12 wherein said fruit or vegetable is selected
 from the group consisting of apples, pears, Asian pears, cherries,
 strawberries, plums, peaches, nectarines, grapes, melons guava, dates,
 figs, apricots, kiwi, lemons, limes, grapefruit, oranges, tangelos,
 kumquats, ugli fruit, mandarin oranges, Satsuma oranges, mango, bananas,
 passion fruit, pineapple, cranberries, blueberries, blackberries, papaya,
 coconut, jackfruit, tomatoes, lettuce, spinach, Swiss chard, potatoes,
 carrots, beans, and corn.

 14. The method of claim 12 wherein said flavoring agent is selected from
 the group consisting of apple, chocolate, rum, triple sec, peppermint,
 ginger, orange, lemon, lime, blueberry, blackberry, strawberry,
 margarita, pina colada, daiquiri, cherry, root beer, butterscotch, peanut
 butter, vodka, gin, whiskey, brandy, cheese, wine flavors (such as
 merlot, cabernet, chardonnay, etc.), smoked, barbeque, chipotle, ranch,
 curry, vanilla, mint, cinnamon, apple pie, raspberry, maple, grape, cola,
 caramel, mango, kiwi, English Toffee, cocoa, tropical flavors, bubble
 gum, peach, coconut, bergamot, cinnamon bark, ginger ale, grapefruit,
 lemon-lime, mandarin, sweet orange, triple sec, almond butter, butter
 pecan, coffee, cream, honey, peanut, guava, amaretto, Asian Blender,
 Creme de Menthe, Kalamansi, Sloe berry, Chai Tea, Tequila, white
 strawberry, white cranberry, ginger, white grape, guarana, jasmine,
 malted milk, mint, orange juice, orange sherbet, Oriental Herbal, punch,
 sugar, tropical fruit, Chichamorada, Cherimoya, Ginseng mint, melon,
 papaya, Ming Tea, Sweet Musk melon, pandan, tamarind, tangerine,
 strawberry kiwi, guanabana, peach apricot, Apple strudel, chocolate
 cherry, chocolate mint, French vanilla, licorice, minty melon, Amaretto,
 chocolate fudge, green bell pepper, Muscat, baby powder, Boston Creme,
 cantaloupe, cheesecake, chocolate hazelnut, cologne, hazelnut, pine oil,
 pizza, sesame oil, pumpkin spice, rose, brown sugar, sweet roll, tropical
 punch, vanilla cream, Bleu Cheese, melted butter, sweet butter, roasted
 chicken, milk chocolate, toasted coconut, ginger snap, graham cracker,
 mushroom, pecan, pistachio, red raspberry, blue raspberry, strudel,
 wafer, walnut, Royal cream, sour cream, dry apricot, caramel corn, cotton
 candy, cranapple, Temple orange, fresh pineapple, black raspberry, fresh
 strawberry, passion fruit, wildberry, orange cream, sweet cherry, banana,
 mango, wild raspberry, wild blueberry, wild blackberry, root beer cream,
 cola cream, carrot, carrot cake, pumpkin, &quot;buttery&quot; versions of any
 flavors described herein, any flavors described herein with cinnamon or
 extra cinnamon or other spice, or any combination thereof.

 15. The method of claim 12 wherein said preservative is selected from the
 group consisting of citric acid; NatureSeal®; vitamin(s); mineral(s);
 ascorbic acid; potassium sorbate; enzymes; acids; bases; erythorbic acid;
 calcium; sulfur dioxide; sulfites; benzoic acid; Freshxtend®, a blend
 of vitamins and minerals, other antioxidants such as butylated
 hydroxyanisole (BHA), butylated hydroxytoluene (BHT),
 tert-butylhydroquinone (TBHQ), propyl gallate, ascorbyl palmitate; or any
 combination thereof.

 16. The method of claim 12 wherein said vitamin is selected from the group
 consisting of vitamin A, vitamin B1, vitamin B2, vitamin B3, vitamin B5,
 vitamin B6, vitamin B7, vitamin B8, vitamin H, vitamin B9, vitamin B10,
 vitamin B12, vitamin B13, vitamin B15, vitamin B17, vitamin C, vitamin P,
 vitamin D, vitamin E, and vitamin K.

 17. The method of claim 12 wherein said mineral is selected from the group
 consisting of: chromium, copper, fluorine, manganese, lycopene, lutein,
 selenium, zinc, inositol, calcium, chlorine, magnesium, phosphorus,
 potassium, sodium, sulfur, cobalt, iodine, iron, molybdenum, bismuth,
 boron, nickel, rubidium, silicon, strontium, tellurium, titanium, tin,
 tungsten, and vanadium.

 18. The method of claim 12 further comprising packaging said fruit or
 vegetable product.
Description:

 BACKGROUND 

 [0001] 1. Technical Field

 [0002] The present invention relates generally to processed fruit and/or
 vegetable products, including purees, pulps, sauces, spreads, pastes, pie
 fillings, or other products, and methods of making the same. Particular
 embodiments of the present invention are described herein.

 [0003] 2. Description of the Related Art

 [0004] Fruit and vegetable products are generally recognized as a
 nutritional food for a meal or snack. In particular, fruit or vegetable
 purees, sauces, pulps, pastes, spreads, pie fillings or other products
 are useful as food for humans and animals, especially the young and old.
 Fruit and vegetable products are typically high in vitamins and may be
 low in calories. In addition, processed fruit and vegetable products
 typically have a long shelf-life and due to the pasteurization and/or
 canning. These canned or preserved products provide quick and easy access
 by consumers, as well as provide a staple food source in emergency
 situations.

 [0005] Some methods of cooking or canning fruit or vegetable products
 diminish the fruit&apos;s nutritional value or taste. The present invention
 fills this void and provides other related advantages.

 DETAILED DESCRIPTION 

 Definitions 

 [0006] For the purposes of the present invention, the terms and phrases
 used herein, shall have their plain and ordinary meaning as appreciated
 by one of skill in the art. In particular instances, we set forth the
 following terms to be defined as set forth herein.

 [0007] &quot;Preservative,&quot; and any and all derivations, refers to an agent that
 preserves, protects, retains, or promotes the flavor, color, texture,
 cell wall structure, appearance, moisture, &quot;mouth feel,&quot; or other
 desirable characteristic of processed fruit or vegetable products.

 [0008] Processed fruit or vegetable products, as well as any and all
 derivations, refers to any variety of fruit or vegetables as well as any
 combination of fruits or vegetables which may be any of whole or cut,
 pitted, cored, dehydrated, frozen, stoned and/or peeled, with inedible
 parts removed (seeds, pits, stones, etc.) and which have undergone
 cooking, pressure cooking, or general heating above about 90-120°
 F. The term &quot;processed&quot; may also include fruit or vegetable products that
 have been coated, filled, contacted with at least one additive, including
 a flavoring agent, a sweetening agent, a preservative; and/or canned or
 packaged.

 [0009] &quot;Organic,&quot; and any and all derivations, refers to products whose
 source has been certified organic by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
 (See the U.S. Department of Agriculture&apos;s website at: usda.gov).

 [0010] Additives

 [0011] Certain embodiments may comprise additives, such as sweeteners or
 sweetening agents, flavoring agents, coloring agents, macro-nutrients
 (protein, carbohydrate and fat levels), micro-nutrients (vitamins,
 minerals, etc.), thickening agents, stabilizers, and flavor enhancers.
 Additives may take any physical or chemical form, including but not
 limited to a solid, liquid, gas, gel, paste, syrup, and the like or any
 combination thereof that directly or indirectly contacts the fruit or
 vegetable and may penetrate throughout the fruit or vegetable (or be
 absorbed by the same).

 [0012] Any of the additives disclosed herein may be diluted or directly
 applied to the processed fruit/vegetable product. The additive may be
 natural, artificial or organic. In one particular embodiment, the
 additive takes the form of a liquid. Such liquid form may be water-based,
 alcohol-based, glycerol-based, glycol-based, or fat or oil-based. In one
 particular embodiment, the liquid additive is heated to produce an
 additive vapor to which the whole fruit or vegetable and/or the processed
 fruit/vegetable product may be contacted.

 [0013] In another particular embodiment the one or more additives are in
 the form of a solid. In one further embodiment, the additive is a powder,
 flake, ribbon, film, fiber, string, capsule, bead, microbead, tablet,
 pellet or shavings. In one embodiment, the additive is a tablet that may
 be soaked in a liquid. In another embodiment, the additive is dusted on
 the fruit or vegetable whole or processed product(s).

 [0014] In another particular embodiment, the one or more additives are in
 the form of a gas, such as an atomized gas. In a further embodiment, the
 gas vapor is pumped onto or around the uncut fruit/vegetables or
 processed fruit/vegetable products.

 [0015] In another embodiment, the porous or nonporous pad or surface
 further comprises an adhesive. In another particular embodiment, the one
 or more additive resides inside a crushable ampule that may or may not be
 edible. In another particular embodiment, the one or more additives are
 in the form of a gel. Such gel may include gelatin-based or polymerized
 glycol-based. In another particular embodiment, the additive takes the
 form of a paste. In another particular embodiment, the additive takes the
 form of an edible matrix or adhesive. One example of such edible adhesive
 is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,827,553, which is hereby incorporated by
 reference in its entirety. In a further embodiment, the additive is in
 the form of a xanthan gum or carrageen base.

 [0016] Other additives may include liquid media, for example fruit or
 vegetable juices, syrups (for example, heavy syrup or light syrup),
 stocks or concentrates. The liquid media may be useful in packing, and
 may contain additives itself (such as preservatives, flavoring agents
 such as spices, sweeteners, etc.).

 [0017] Sweetening Agents

 [0018] In certain embodiments, an additive may comprise one or more
 natural, artificial or organic sweeteners or sweetening agents. Such
 natural, artificial or organic sweeteners or sweetening agents are well
 known to one of skill in the art and include, but are not limited to,
 white cane sugar or syrup, brown sugar or syrup, dextrose, glucose,
 lactose, whey, ribose, xylose, xylitol, rhamnose, date sugar, white or
 brown rice syrup, malt, molasses or molasses powder, honey, dehydrated
 honey, corn syrup or corn syrup solids, maple syrup, high fructose corn
 syrup, fructose, saccharin, Splenda® (sucralose), NutraSweet®
 (aspartame), acesulfame-K, stevia, Shugr® (a mixture of erythritol,
 maltodextrin and sucralose), any modification of these sweeteners, any
 combination thereof, and the like.

 [0019] Flavoring Agents

 [0020] In at least one embodiment, the present invention also relates to
 methods of flavoring a fruit or vegetable product and compositions of the
 same, wherein the flavoring agent(s) include, but are not limited to,
 apple, chocolate, rum, triple sec, peppermint, ginger, orange, lemon,
 lime, blueberry, blackberry, strawberry, margarita, pina colada,
 daiquiri, cherry, root beer, butterscotch, peanut butter, vodka, gin,
 whiskey, brandy, cheese, wine flavors (such as merlot, cabernet,
 chardonnay, etc.), smoked, barbeque, chipotle, ranch, curry, vanilla,
 mint, cinnamon, apple pie, raspberry, maple, grape, cola, caramel, mango,
 kiwi, English Toffee, cocoa, tropical flavors, bubble gum, peach,
 coconut, bergamot, cinnamon bark, ginger ale, grapefruit, lemon-lime,
 mandarin, sweet orange, triple sec, almond butter, butter pecan, coffee,
 cream, honey, peanut, guava, amaretto, Asian Blender, Creme de Menthe,
 Kalamansi, Sloe berry, Chai Tea, Tequila, white strawberry, white
 cranberry, ginger, white grape, guarana, jasmine, malted milk, mint,
 orange juice, orange sherbet, Oriental Herbal, punch, sugar, tropical
 fruit, Chichamorada, Cherimoya, Ginseng mint, melon, papaya, Ming Tea,
 Sweet Musk melon, pandan, tamarind, tangerine, strawberry kiwi,
 guanabana, peach apricot, Apple strudel, chocolate cherry, chocolate
 mint, French vanilla, licorice, minty melon, Amaretto, chocolate fudge,
 green bell pepper, Muscat, baby powder, Boston Creme, cantaloupe,
 cheesecake, chocolate hazelnut, cologne, hazelnut, pine oil, pizza,
 sesame oil, pumpkin spice, rose, brown sugar, sweet roll, tropical punch,
 vanilla cream, Bleu Cheese, melted butter, sweet butter, roasted chicken,
 milk chocolate, toasted coconut, ginger snap, graham cracker, mushroom,
 pecan, pistachio, red raspberry, blue raspberry, strudel, wafer, walnut,
 Royal cream, sour cream, dry apricot, caramel corn, cotton candy,
 cranapple, Temple orange, fresh pineapple, black raspberry, fresh
 strawberry, passion fruit, wildberry, orange cream, sweet cherry, banana,
 mango, wild raspberry, wild blueberry, wild blackberry, root beer cream,
 cola cream, carrot, carrot cake, pumpkin, &quot;buttery&quot; versions of any
 flavors described herein, any flavors described herein with cinnamon or
 extra cinnamon or other spice, or any combination thereof.

 [0021] As one of skill in the art would recognize, flavoring agents may be
 obtained from any number of producers or manufacturers. In some
 circumstances, the exact chemical formulation for the flavoring agent may
 be proprietary. In other circumstances, the exact chemical formulation
 may be known or obtainable. Some examples of flavorings for which the
 chemical formula is known include benzaldehyde (C 6 H 5 CHO) and
 benzyl chloride (C 7 H 7 Cl).

 [0022] In at least one embodiment, the flavoring agent and/or preservative
 is not methyl anthranilate (also referred to as methyl-o-aminobenzoate,
 neroli oil, or 2-Aminobensoic acid methyl ester).

 [0023] Coloring Agents

 [0024] The colors or coloring agents used herein for the fruit or vegetable
 products include natural or artificial colors. In one embodiment, the
 coloring agents are of edible food grade dye. In another particular
 embodiment, the coloring agents are not edible and are used as fruit or
 vegetable product decorations. Some coloring agents which may be used
 with the present invention include Red, Pink, Gray, Orange, Yellow,
 Green, Blue, White, Indigo, Violet (Purple), Black, fluorescent or neon
 versions of any color, shades, tones or tints of any color, and any
 combinations of colors.

 [0025] As one of skill in the art will recognize, the colorant may take any
 particular form, including solid, liquid, gas, gel, paste, or any other
 form disclosed herein. In addition, one of skill in the art would
 recognize that colorants may be water-soluble dyes or pigments; an
 aluminum lake pigment that may be dispersed in oils, fats, or other
 carriers such as propylene glycol, glycerin or a sucrose suspension;
 oil-soluble dyes or pigments, as well as others, or any combination
 thereof. The colorants of the present invention may be natural,
 artificial, organic, inorganic, or any combination thereof.

 [0026] Some examples of &quot;natural&quot; colorants that may or may not be edible
 include beet, paprika, annatto, tumeric, cabbage, caramel, and others.
 Some examples of pigments that are not edible include azo dyes,
 phthalocyanine, quinacridone, molybdate orange, chromium yellow,
 chromocyanine green, mica, iron oxide, titanium dioxide, and others.

 [0027] More specifically, some edible colorants include, but are not
 limited to, Food, Drug&amp;Cosmetic (FD&amp;C;) Blue 1, FD&amp;C;Green 3, FD&amp;C;Yellow 3, FD&amp;C;Yellow 4, FD&amp;C;Yellow 5, FD&amp;C Yellow 1, FD&amp;C;Yellow 10,
 FD&amp;C;Yellow 6, FD&amp;C;Red 7, FD&amp;C;Blue 2, FD&amp;C;Red 3, FD&amp;C;Red 2, FD&amp;C;Red
 14, FD&amp;C Red 40, FD&amp;C;Red 4, FD&amp;C;Red 9, FD&amp;C;Red 22, FD&amp;C;Red 28, FD&amp;C;Yellow 13, FD&amp;C;Blue 1, FD&amp;C;Brown 2, FD&amp;C;Blue 5, FD&amp;C;Brown 3, FD&amp;C;Green 5, FD&amp;C;Green 6, FD&amp;C;Red 17, FD&amp;C;Blue 15, FD&amp;C;Green 4, FD&amp;C;Black 1, and any combination thereof.

 [0028] Some colorants that may be used with the present invention but are
 inedible include, but are not limited to, Drug and Cosmetic (D&amp;C;) Green
 5, D&amp;C;Green 6, D&amp;C;Green 8, D&amp;C;Red 28, D&amp;C;Red 30, D&amp;C;Red 33, D&amp;C;Yellow 10, and any combination thereof.

 [0029] Preservatives

 [0030] As disclosed herein for other additives, the preservatives may take
 any form of solid, liquid, gas, or any combination or mixture thereof. If
 the preservative is in the form of a liquid, such liquid may be
 water-based, alcohol based, glycerol based, glycol-based, or fat or
 oil-based. If the preservative is in the form of a solid, it may be a
 powder, flake, ribbon, film, fiber, string, capsule, bead, microbead,
 tablet, pellet or shavings, for example.

 [0031] Some preservatives that may be used with certain embodiments
 include, but are not limited to, citric acid; NatureSeal® (for
 example, as described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,925,395, which is hereby
 incorporated by reference); vitamin(s); mineral(s); ascorbic acid;
 potassium sorbate; enzymes; acids; bases; erythorbic acid; calcium;
 sulfur dioxide; sulfites; benzoic acid; Freshxtend® (a proprietary
 blend of vitamins and minerals, including vitamin C and calcium chloride
 that is available from Fortitech, Inc.) other antioxidants such as
 butylated hydroxyanisole (BHA), butylated hydroxytoluene (BHT),
 tert-butylhydroquinone (TBHQ), propyl gallate, ascorbyl palmitate; or any
 combination thereof. Further examples of preservatives that may be used
 with the present invention include those described in U.S. Pat. No.
 5,939,117, which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety.

 [0032] In addition to any preservative qualities achieved by adding
 vitamins and/or minerals, at least one vitamin and/or mineral may be
 added to the fruit or vegetable products for additional nutritional
 value. Any added vitamin(s) and/or mineral(s) may take any form herein
 described (e.g. solid, liquid, gas, gel, etc.), and may be applied by any
 mode described herein for the same (spraying, immersing, etc.).

 [0033] Micronutrients and Macronutrients

 [0034] Some examples of vitamins and/or minerals (also referred to as
 &quot;micronutrients&quot;) that may be added to the fruit or vegetable products
 for additional nutritional value (as well as for any flavoring,
 anti-browning or other beneficial characteristics) include the following,
 which may be known in the art by several different names: vitamin A
 (carotene, retinol, beta-carotene), vitamin B1 (thiamine), vitamin B2
 (riboflavin), vitamin B3 (nicotinic acid, niacin, vitamin PP), vitamin B5
 (calcium pantothenate, pantothenic acid), vitamin B6 (pyridoxine,
 pyridoxamine), vitamin B7 (choline), inositol, vitamin B8 (coenzyme R),
 vitamin H (biotin), vitamin B9 (vitamin M, folic acid, folacin), vitamin
 B10 (para-aminobenzoic acid or PABA), vitamin B12 (cobalamin,
 cyanocobalamin), vitamin B13 (orotic acid), vitamin B15 (pangamic acid),
 vitamin B17 (laetrile), vitamin C (ascorbic acid), vitamin P (C-complex,
 citrus bioflavonoid, rutin, hesperidin), vitamin D (calciforol), vitamin
 E (tocopherol), vitamin K (menadione), chromium, copper, fluorine,
 manganese, lycopene, lutein, selenium, zinc, calcium, chlorine,
 magnesium, phosphorus, potassium, sodium, sulfur, cobalt, iodine, iron,
 molybdenum, bismuth, boron, nickel, rubidium, silicon, strontium,
 tellurium, titanium, tin, tungsten, vanadium, and others.

 [0035] Macronutrients (nutrients of which the body requires relatively
 large amounts) may be added to the fruit segments as well. Exemplary
 macronutrients include but are not limited to: carbohydrates, fiber, fat,
 fatty acids, cholesterol, protein, amino acids, and water. If
 macronutrients (especially protein and/or fat) are added to the fruit
 segments, they may be derived from plant matter (such as soy, seaweed or
 nuts), from animal matter (such as meat, dairy or egg products), or from
 another source (plankton, fungus, cyanobacteria, other microorganisms,
 etc.). Some examples of fatty acids that may be introduced to or
 incorporated in the fruit segments include saturated fatty acids, which
 do not contain any double bonds or other functional groups along the
 chain (such as butyric, caproic, caprylic, capric, lauric, myristic,
 palmitic, steric, arachidic, behenic, and others), unsaturated fatty
 acids, which contain one or more alkenyl functional group along the chain
 and be monounsaturated or polyunsaturated, cis or trans. Some examples of
 unsaturated fatty acids include omega 9 fatty acids (such as oleic acid,
 and erucic acid), omega 6 fatty acids (such as linoleic acid, and
 arachidonic acid), and omega 3 fatty acids (such as alpha-linelenic,
 eicosapentaenoic acid, docosahexaenoic acid) and others. Various types of
 fatty acids may come from any number of sources, including plant or
 animal products such as corn, soy, flax, rice, barley, fish, seaweed,
 wheat, oat, or other oil sources.

 [0036] Some examples of carbohydrates include monosaccharides, such as
 glucose, galactose and fructose, and polysaccharides, such as starch,
 glycogen, or cellulose. In addition, carbohydrates may contain one or
 more modified monosaccharide units that have one or more groups replaced
 or removed. For example, deoxyribose is a modified version of ribose.

 [0037] Flavor Enhancers

 [0038] In one particular embodiment, the additive further comprises at
 least one flavor enhancer. Flavor enhancers are well known to one of
 skill in the art and include, but are not limited to, natural or
 artificial sweeteners, monosodium glutamate (MSG), disodium glutamate
 (DSG), inosine 5&apos;monophosphate (IMP), guanosine 5&apos;monophosphate (GMP),
 D-tagatose, any combination thereof, or the like. Flavor enhancers may
 also function as preservatives, in some embodiments.

 [0039] Types of Fruits or Vegetables

 [0040] In particular embodiments of the present invention, the processed
 product may relate to any fruit or vegetable capable of being processed
 and may include or exclude any specific fruit or vegetable listed herein:
 apples, pears, Asian pears, cherries, strawberries, plums, peaches,
 nectarines, grapes, melons (including watermelon, cantaloupe, honey dew
 melon, muskmelon, etc.), guava, dates, figs, apricots, kiwi, citrus fruit
 (including lemons, limes, grapefruit, oranges, tangelos, kumquats, ugli
 fruit, mandarin oranges, Satsuma oranges, etc.), mango, bananas, passion
 fruit, pineapple, cranberries, blueberries, blackberries, papaya,
 coconut, jackfruit, tomatoes, leafy vegetables (also called potherbs,
 greens, or leafy greens and include lettuce, spinach, Swiss chard,
 clover, grasses such as wheat, barley and alfalfa), stem vegetables
 (including asparagus), root vegetables (including tuberous roots,
 taproots, tubers, rhizomes, corms, and bulbs); some examples of true root
 vegetables include celeriac, burdock or gobo, arracacha, beet and
 mangelwurzel, rutabaga, turnip, black cumin, carrot, maca, jicama and
 ahipa, parsnip, parsley root, daikon and radish, black salsify, skirret,
 salsify, earthnut, sweet potato, cassava, mauka or chago, breadroot,
 tipsin, or prairie turnip, yacon, konjac, taro, Chinese water chestnut,
 enset, katakuri, arrowhead or wapatoo, malanga, cocoyam, tannia,
 rengarenga, vanilla lily, canna, ti, arrowroot, lotus root, cattail or
 bulrush, hog potato or groundnut, tigernut or chufa, yams, ube, daylily,
 artichoke, artichoke hearts, Jerusalem artichoke or sunchoke, earthnut
 pea, oca or New Zealand yam, potato, kembili, dazo, Chinese artichoke or
 crosne, mashua or anu, ulluco, bulibs (garlic, onion, shallot),
 mushrooms, quamash, seeds (peas, beans), flowers (broccoli), botanical
 fruits (cucumbers, squash, pumpkins, capsicums), culinary fruits (nuts,
 grains, herbs), Brussels sprouts, pumpkins, squash, cabbage, cauliflower,
 kale, rapini, kai-lan, bok choy, komatsuna, mizuna greens, oriental
 mustard, amaranth, arugula, bitterleaf, catsear, celtuce, Ceylon spinach,
 chicory, Chinese mallow, chrysanthemum, corn salad, cress, dandelion,
 endive, epazote, fat hen, fiddlehead, fluted pumpkin, golden samphire,
 Good King Henry, Iceplant, Kuka, lagos bologi, land cress, Lizard&apos;s tail,
 Melokhia, mustard, New Zealand spinach, orache, radicchio, samphire, sea
 beet, seakale, Sierra Leone bologi, soko, sorrel, summer purslane,
 watercress, water spinach, winter purslane, Armenian cucumber, eggplant,
 avocado, caigua, cayenne pepper, chayote, chile pepper, courgette, globe
 artichoke, luffa, Malabar gourd, marrow, parwal, snake gourd, sweetcorn,
 tinda, West Indian gherkin, zucchini, black-eyed pea, chickpea, dolichos
 bean, fava bean, guar, horsegram, lentil, lima bean, moth bean, mung
 bean, okra, peanut, pigeon pea, rice bean, soybean, cardoon, celery,
 Florence fennel, kohlrabi, leek, Prussian asparagus, Welsh onion, wild
 leek, bamboo shoot, ginger, rutabaga, chokeberry, hawthorn, serviceberry,
 loquat, medlar, quince, rowan, rose-hip, shipova, apricot, cherry, plum,
 peach, nectarine, blackberry, boysenberry, loganberry, cloudberry,
 wineberry, salmonberry, thimbleberry, bearberry, bilberry, crowberry,
 huckleberry, lingonberry, barberry, currant, elderberry, gooseberry,
 hackberry, mayapple, Oregon grape, wolfberry, mulberry, arhat, che,
 k-pong, persimmon, sageretia, cocoplum, pawpaw, Saw Palmetto, Toyon,
 dragonfruit, prickly pear, Saguaro, date, fig, olive, pomelo, citron,
 lemon, limes, avocado, tamarillo, banana, bael, babco, akee, guarana, or
 others. One of skill in the art would recognize that any variety or
 hybrid of fruit or vegetable, including any variety of apples, pears,
 Asian pears, cherries, or any other fruit could be used to practice the
 presently claimed invention.

 [0041] In particular, varieties of apples that may be used for certain
 embodiments include, but are not limited to: Red Delicious, Golden
 Delicious, Gala, Fuji, Rome, Ginger Gold, Granny Smith, Braeburn, Cameo,
 Pink Lady, Jonagold, Rome Beauty, Wealthy, Stayman, Jonathan, McIntosh,
 Cortland, Akane, Jonamac, Nittany, Vista Bella, Elstar, Royal Gala,
 Winter Banana, or any combination of these or any other varieties.
 Particular varieties of pears that may be used in certain embodiments
 include, but are not limited to: European or Asian pears, Bartlett, Red
 Bartlett, Taylor&apos;s Gold®, Concorde®, Seckel, Red Anjou, Green
 Anjou, Bosc, Comice, Forelle, D&apos;Anjou, Clairgeau, Easter Beurre, Flemish
 Beauty, Kieffer, Pound, Sheldon, Winter Nelis, P. Barry, or any
 combination of these or any other varieties. Particular varieties of
 cherries that may be used in certain embodiments include, but are not
 limited to: Bing, Black Tartarian, Brook, Tulare, Garnet, Chelan, Lapin,
 Sonata, Hill Bing, Hill Lambert, Hill Lapin, Sweetheart, Skeena,
 Staccato, Schmidt, Chapman, Republican, Lambert, Ranier, Regina, Sandra
 Rose, Van, Sonata, Black Gold, Early Robin, Attika, and any combination
 thereof.

 [0042] One of skill in the art would recognize that the present invention
 may be practiced with fruit or vegetables that are cultivated, organic,
 genetically modified, hybrid cross, or wild cultivars.

 [0043] Fruit and Vegetable Grades

 [0044] Certain embodiments relate to methods for assessing fruit or
 vegetable quality based on one or more fruit or vegetable grade
 assessments selected from the group consisting of measuring sugar content
 or testing soluble solids; measuring whole fruit or vegetable size;
 measuring starch content; measuring firmness or pressure; testing
 acidity; assessing color; assessing seed color; assessing taste or
 general &quot;mouth feel&quot;; assessing texture and assessing aroma.

 [0045] One particular exemplary embodiment disclosed herein includes that
 the fruit or vegetable comprises an apple. In one exemplary embodiment
 wherein the fruit comprises an apple, the fruit may have a United States
 Department of Agriculture federal grade selected from the group
 consisting of: U.S. No. 1, U.S. Fancy, U.S. Extra Fancy and any
 combination thereof. In certain embodiments wherein the fruit comprises
 an apple, the fruit product comprises applesauce. In certain embodiments
 wherein the fruit product comprises applesauce, the applesauce may be of
 any United States Department of Agriculture federal grade, including U.S.
 Grade A or U.S. Grade B.

 [0046] Alternatively, the fruit or vegetables used for certain embodiments
 herein may have any federal grade available, including any grade level
 utilized internationally.

 [0047] Accordingly, this disclosure includes the U.S. Standards for Grades
 of Apples, §§51.300-51.321 of the Agricultural Marketing Act,
 as amended (7 U.S.C. 1624), are hereby incorporated by reference in its
 entirety. Several specific standards for apple grades are disclosed
 herein, as well as in Tables 1 and 2.

 [0048] As used herein, the federal food grade of fruit refers to the
 criteria established by the U.S. Department of Agriculture. In
 particular, &quot;U.S. Extra Fancy&quot; includes apples of one variety (except
 where more than one variety is printed on the container) which are mature
 but not overripe, clean, fairly well formed and relatively free from
 decay, internal browning, internal breakdown, soft scald, scab, freezing
 injury, visible water core, and broken skins. &quot;U.S. Extra Fancy&quot; apples
 are also relatively free from injury caused by bruises, brown surface
 discoloration, smooth net-like russeting, sunburn or sprayburn, limb
 rubs, hail, drought spots, scars, disease, insects, or other means. &quot;U.S.
 Extra Fancy&quot; apples are relatively free from damage caused by bitter pit
 or Jonathan spot and by smooth solid, slightly rough or rough russeting,
 or stem or calyx cracks, as well as damage by invisible water core after
 January 31 st of the year following the year of production except for
 Fuji variety of apples.

 [0049] As used herein, &quot;U.S. Fancy&quot; apples include apples of one variety
 (except when more than one variety is printed on the container) which are
 relatively mature but not overripe, clean, fairly well formed, and
 relatively free from decay, internal browning, internal breakdown, soft
 scald, freezing injury, visible water core, and broken skins. &quot;U.S.
 Fancy&quot; apples are also relatively free from damage caused by bruises,
 brown surface discoloration, russeting, sunburn or sprayburn, limb rubs,
 hail, drought spots, scars, stem or calyx cracks, disease, insects,
 bitter pit, Jonathan spot, or damage by other means, or invisible water
 core after January 31 st of the year following the year of
 production, except for Fuji variety of apples.

 [0050] As used herein, &quot;U.S. No. 1&quot; includes apples which meet the
 requirements of &quot;U.S. Fancy&quot; grade except for certain characteristics,
 such as color, russeting, and invisible water core. &quot;U.S. No. 1&quot; apples
 are relatively free from excessive damage caused by russeting. That is,
 the apples meet the russeting requirements for &quot;U.S. Fancy,&quot; except the
 aggregate area of an apple which may be covered by smooth net-like
 russeting usually does not exceed 25%; and the aggregate area of an apple
 which may be covered by smooth solid russeting usually does not exceed
 10%, except that in the case of the Yellow Newtown or similar varieties,
 the aggregate area of an apple which may be covered with smooth solid
 russeting usually does not exceed 20%. Invisible water core is generally
 not scored in this grade.

 [0051] As used herein, &quot;U.S. No. 1 Hail&quot; includes apples that meet the
 requirements of U.S. No. 1 grade except that hail marks where the skin
 has not been broken and well-healed hail marks where the skin has been
 broken, are permitted, provided the apples are fairly well formed.

 [0052] As used herein, &quot;U.S. Utility&quot; includes apples of one variety
 (except when more than one variety is printed on the container) that are
 relatively mature but not overripe, not seriously deformed and relatively
 free from decay, internal browning, internal breakdown, soft scald, and
 freezing injury. &quot;U.S. Utility&quot; apples are also relatively free from
 serious damage caused by dirt or other foreign matter, broken skins,
 bruises, brown surface discoloration, russeting, sunburn or sprayburn,
 limb rubs, hail, drought spots, scars, stem or calyx cracks, visible
 water core, bitter pit or Jonathan spot, disease, insects or other means.

 [0053] In addition to these typical characteristics, apple varieties of the
 grades disclosed herein also typically have the color specified in Table
 1. Apple varieties other than those listed in Table I have no color
 requirements pertaining to these grades.

 TABLE -US-00001
 TABLE 1
 The apple
 varieties listed
 below have color
 requirements U.S. Extra Fancy U.S. Fancy U.S. No. 1
 VARIETY PERCENT PERCENT PERCENT
 Red Delicious 66 40 25
 Red Rome 66 40 25
 Empire 66 40 25
 Idared 66 40 25
 Winesap 66 40 25
 Jonathan 66 40 25
 Stayman 50 33 25
 McIntosh 50 33 25
 Cortland 50 33 25
 Rome Beauty 50 33 25
 Delicious 50 33 25
 York 50 33 25

 [0054] As used in Table 1, the color requirements for the solid red
 varieties indicate the percentage of the area of the surface, which
 should be covered with a good shade of solid red characteristic of the
 variety. However, an apple having color of a lighter shade of solid red
 or striped red than that considered as a good shade of red characteristic
 of the variety may be admitted to a grade, if it has sufficient
 additional area covered so that the apple has as good an appearance as
 one with the minimum percentage of good red characteristic of the variety
 required for the grade. For the striped red varieties, the percentage
 stated refers to the area of the surface in which the stripes of a good
 shade of red characteristic of the variety typically predominates over
 stripes of lighter red, green or yellow. However, an apple having color
 of a lighter shade than that considered as a good shade of red
 characteristic of the variety may be admitted to a grade, provided it has
 sufficient additional area covered so that the apple has as good
 appearance as one with the minimum percentage of stripes of a good red
 characteristic of the variety required for the grade.

 [0055] Color standards U.S. Dept. of Agriculture Visual Aid APL-CC-1
 (Plates a-e), hereby incorporated by reference in their entireties,
 illustrate minimum good shade of solid red or striped red color, minimum
 compensating color and shade not considered color, for the following
 varieties: Red Delicious, Red Rome, Empire, Idared, Winesap, Jonathan,
 Stayman, McIntosh, Cortland, Rome Beauty, Delicious and York.

 [0056] When size is designated by the numerical count for a container,
 typically not more than 10% of packages in the lot may fail to be fairly
 uniform. As used herein, &quot;fairly uniform&quot; may indicate that the size of
 the fruit within the container does not vary more than 1/2 inch diameter
 from the smallest to largest fruit, and that any particular apple may be
 slightly abnormal in shape but not to an extent which detracts materially
 from its appearance.

 [0057] When size is designated by minimum or maximum diameter, generally
 not more than a5% of the apples in any lot may be smaller than the
 designated minimum, and generally not more than 10% may be larger than
 the designated maximum. For Red Delicious or Golden Delicious varieties,
 a combination of minimum diameter and/or weight may be used.

 [0058] Any decay, scald, or other deterioration which may have developed on
 apples after they have been in storage or transit is generally considered
 as affecting the condition of the apples, and not the grade.

 [0059] Generally, as used in the U.S.D.A. guidelines and herein, &quot;mature,&quot;
 refers to apples that have reached the stage of development which will
 insure the proper completion of the ripening process. Before a mature
 apple becomes overripe, it will show varying degrees of firmness,
 depending on the stage of the ripening process.

 [0060] In addition to the term, &quot;mature,&quot; apples may be referred to by the
 following U.S.D.A. descriptions: &quot;hard,&quot; generally refers to apples with
 a tenacious flesh and starchy flavor; &quot;firm,&quot; generally refers to apples
 with a tenacious flesh but which are becoming crisp with a slightly
 starchy flavor, except the Delicious variety; &quot;firm ripe,&quot; generally
 refers to apples with crisp flesh except that the flesh of the Gano, Bed
 Davis, and Rome Beauty varieties may be slightly mealy; &quot;ripe,&quot; generally
 refers to apples with mealy flesh and soon to become soft for the
 variety; and &quot;overripe,&quot; generally refers to apples which have progressed
 beyond the stage of ripe, with flesh very mealy or soft, and past
 commercial utility.

 [0061] In addition to these U.S.D.A. standard grades for fresh apples, the
 present disclosure also includes the U.S.D.A. standards for grades of
 frozen apples (§§52.361-52.371 of the Agricultural Marketing
 Act, as amended), dried apples (§§52.2481-52.2490 of the
 Agricultural Marketing Act, as amended), dehydrated (low moisture) apples
 (§§52.2341-52.2352 of the Agricultural Marketing Act, as
 amended) and canned apples (§§52.2161-52.2173 of the
 Agricultural Marketing Act, as amended), all of which are hereby
 incorporated by reference in their entireties.

 [0062] In any of the particular embodiments set forth herein, the fruit
 used to practice the presently claimed invention has a Washington state
 grade selected from the group consisting of: Washington Extra Fancy,
 Washington Fancy, Washington C grade and any combination thereof.
 Alternatively, the fruit used to practice the presently claimed invention
 has any state grade available. As used herein, the Washington state apple
 grades specified refer to the standard grades set forth by the Washington
 State Department of Agriculture, Chapter 16-403 WAC, which is hereby
 incorporated by reference in its entirety. Except where noted, the
 Washington State apple term definitions parallel the U.S.D.A.
 definitions, and such definitions may be used interchangeably herein.

 [0063] As used herein, &quot;Washington Extra Fancy&quot; apples include apples of
 one variety which are relatively mature but not overripe, carefully hand
 picked, clean, fairly well formed, relatively free from decay, internal
 browning, internal breakdown, scald, scab, bitter pit, Jonathan spot,
 freezing injury, visible watercore, and broken skins and bruises except
 those which are slight and incident to proper handling and packing.
 &quot;Washington Extra Fancy&quot; apples are also relatively free from injury
 caused by smooth net-like russeting, sunburn or spray-burn, limb rubs,
 hail, drought spots, scars, disease, insects or other means; and
 relatively free from damage by smooth solid, slightly rough or rough
 russeting, or stem or calyx cracks and free from damage by invisible
 watercore after January 31 st of the year following the year of
 production, provided that the invisible watercore is not be a quality
 factor of Fuji variety at any time.

 [0064] As used herein, &quot;Washington Fancy&quot; apples refer to apples of one
 variety which are mature but not overripe, carefully hand-picked, clean,
 fairly well-formed; relatively free from decay, internal browning,
 internal breakdown, bitter pit, Jonathan spot, scald, freezing injury,
 visible watercore, and broken skins and bruises, except those which are
 incident to proper handling and packing. &quot;Washington Fancy&quot; apples are
 also relatively free from damage caused by russeting, sunburn or
 sprayburn, limb rubs, hail, drought spots, scars, stem or calyx cracks,
 disease, insects, invisible watercore after January 31 st of the year
 following the year of production, or damage by other means, provided that
 invisible watercore is not a quality factor of Fuji variety at any time.

 [0065] As used herein, &quot;Washington C grade&quot; includes the same requirements
 for &quot;Washington Fancy&quot; except for color, russeting and invisible
 watercore. &quot;Washington C grade&quot; apples are relatively free from excessive
 damage caused by russeting with the aggregate area of an apple covered by
 smooth net-like russeting typically will not exceed 25%, except that with
 the Yellow Newtown, Granny Smith or similar varieties, the aggregate area
 of an apple which may be covered with smooth solid russeting typically
 will not exceed 20%; and the aggregate area of an apple which may be
 covered with excessively rough or barklike russeting or limb rubs will
 generally not exceed the area of a circle three-fourths of an inch in
 diameter.

 [0066] Color requirements for all Washington State grades listed are
 described in Tables 2 and 3. For the solid red varieties listed in Table
 2, the percentage stated refers to the area of the surface which must be
 covered with a good shade of solid red characteristic of the variety.
 However, an apple having color of a lighter shade of solid red or striped
 red than that considered as a good shade of red characteristic of the
 variety may be admitted to a grade provided it has sufficient additional
 area covered so that the apple has as good an appearance as one with the
 minimum percentage of good red characteristic of the variety required for
 the grade.

 TABLE -US-00002
 TABLE 2
 EXTRA FANCY FANCY
 SOLID RED VARIETY PERCENT PERCENT
 Black Ben 50-66 33-40
 Gano 50-66 33-40
 Winesap 50-66 33-40
 Other similar varieties 50-66 33-40
 Red sport varieties 66 33-40

 [0067] For the striped or partial red varieties listed in Table 3, the
 percentage stated refers to the area of the surface in which the stripes
 of a good shade of red characteristic of the variety typically
 predominates over stripes of lighter red, green or yellow. However, an
 apple having a color of a lighter shade than that considered as a good
 shade of red characteristic of the variety may be admitted to a grade,
 provided it has sufficient additional area covered so that the apple has
 as good an appearance as one with the minimum percentage of stripes of a
 good red characteristic of the variety required for the grade. Faded
 brown stripes are generally not considered as color.

 TABLE -US-00003
 TABLE 3
 EXTRA FANCY FANCY
 VARIETY PERCENT PERCENT
 Delicious 50 25
 Rome Beauty 35-50 15-33
 Wealthy 50 25
 Stayman 50 33
 Other similar varieties 50 25
 Jonathan 35-66 15-33
 McIntosh 35-50 15-33
 Cortland 50 33
 Akane 331/3 15
 Jonamac 50 33
 Nittany 25 10
 Vista Bella 25 10
 Other similar varieties 50 33
 Red sport varieties 66 33-40

 [0068] For the red cheeked or blushed varieties, such as Braeburn, Elstar,
 Fuji, Gala and Royal Gala, Jonagold, Winter Banana and other similar
 varieties, &quot;Washington Extra Fancy&quot; apples require a blush cheek, while
 &quot;Washington Fancy&quot; apples require a tinge of color. For the green or
 yellow varieties, such as Golden Delicious, for &quot;Washington Extra Fancy&quot;
 or &quot;Washington Fancy,&quot; grades, 75% or more of the surface of the apple
 typically will show white or light green predominating over the green
 color. In &quot;Washington C grade,&quot; 331/3% or more of the surface of the
 apple will typically show white or light green predominating over the
 green color.

 [0069] In addition to these state guidelines, WAC Chapter 16 includes the
 state guideline standards for other various fruits that are included in
 the present disclosure, and is hereby incorporated by reference in its
 entirety.

 [0070] In addition to the U.S. federal and Washington state guidelines, the
 present disclosure also includes international guidelines for fruit
 standard grades. For example, The European Community Marketing Standards
 for Fresh Fruits and Vegetables, European Council Regulation No.
 2200/1996, Council Regulation No. 444/2004, Amending Regulation
 No.1535/2003 laying down detailed rules for applying Council Regulation
 No. 2201/96 as regards the aid scheme for products processed from fruits
 and vegetables, and Council Regulation No.1010/2001, all of which are
 hereby incorporated by reference in their entireties, as set forth
 regulations and marketing standards for fresh fruits and vegetables.

 [0071] Briefly, the EC marketing standards state fresh fruit must be sound,
 clean and of marketable quality, and that each container or display of
 produce must be clearly marked with the correct information regarding
 quality class, origin and--in some cases--variety. For example, apples,
 apricots, avocados, cherries, citrus fruit, kiwifruit, melons,
 nectarines, peaches, plums, strawberries, table grapes and watermelons
 may be classified as part of three main quality classes: Extra Class,
 Class I and Class II. As used herein, &quot;Extra Class&quot; includes produce of
 excellent quality and specially selected produce; &quot;Class I&quot; may refer to
 good quality produce, well-shaped and colored and generally free of
 blemishes and marks, while &quot;Class II&quot; produce refers to produce of sound
 marketable quality with certain allowances in relation to shape, coloring
 and slight minor defects such as blemishes, healed cracks or marks.

 [0072] In addition other international standards or grades may be used,
 including the Canadian Agricultural Products Act Fresh Fruit and
 Vegetable Regulations, (C-0.4/C.R.C.-c.285, Schedule I, §§1-56,
 as amended Aug. 31, 2004),as well as the Canadian Processed Products
 Regulations and Maple Products Regulations (C.R.C., c. 291), which are
 hereby incorporated by reference in their entireties.

 [0073] For example, fresh apples graded in Canada include &quot;Canada Extra
 Fancy,&quot; &quot;Canada Fancy,&quot; &quot;Canada Commercial,&quot; &quot;Canada Hailed,&quot; &quot;Canada
 Commercial Cookers,&quot; &quot;Canada No. 1 Peelers&quot; and &quot;Canada No. 2 Peelers.&quot;

 [0074] As used herein, &quot;Canada Extra Fancy&quot; apples may include apples that
 are smooth and well formed, are relatively free form bruises; be
 relatively free from hail damage that has broken the skin or has caused
 discoloration, be relatively free from limb rub that is depressed, be
 relatively free from russeting, be relatively free from scab, including
 pinpoint scab, be relatively free from insect damage, be relatively free
 from insects and disease, be relatively free from Jonathan spot, drought
 spot or marks resembling drought spot, be relatively free from sprayburn
 or sunscald and be relatively free from skin breaks at the stem.

 [0075] As used herein, &quot;Canada Fancy,&quot; apple grade refers to apples that
 are relatively smooth and fairly well-formed, relatively free from
 bruises, relatively free from hail damage, relatively free from limb rub,
 relatively free from russeting, relative free from pinpoint scab,
 relatively free from storage scald, relatively free from sprayburn and
 sunscald, relatively free from insect damage, relatively free from
 insects, relatively free from Johathan spot, drought spot or marks
 resembling drought spot and be relatively free from skin breaks at the
 stem.

 [0076] As used herein, &quot;Canada Commercial&quot; apple grade refers to apples
 that are relatively free from bruises, relatively free from hail damage,
 relatively free from limb rub, relatively free from russeting, relatively
 free from scab, relatively free from storage scald, relatively free from
 sprayburn and sunscald, relatively free from drought spot or marks
 resembling drought spot and relatively free from insect damage.

 [0077] As used herein, &quot;Canada Hailed&quot; apple grade includes apples that are
 relatively free from hail damage, and have not less than the amount of
 color required for &quot;Canada Fancy.&quot;

 [0078] As used herein, &quot;Canada Commercial Cookers&quot; include apples that meet
 the standards of the Canada Commercial grade, with the exceptions of
 russeting and scab, be mature except for Northern Spy varieties, and have
 a minimum diameter of 63 mm (21/2 inches) except for Northern Spy
 varieties.

 [0079] As used herein, &quot;Canada No. 1 Peelers&quot; grade refers to apples that
 are one variety and fairly well formed, are fairly clean, mature and
 sound; have a minimum diameter of 57 mm (21/4 inches), be relatively free
 from insect larvae, and be free from any damage or defect.

 [0080] As used herein, &quot;Canada No. 2 Peelers&quot; include apples that are
 generally of one variety, are reasonably clean, mature and sound, have a
 minimum diameter of 57 mm (21/4 inches); be relatively free from insect
 larvae and be relatively free from any damage or defect.

 [0081] The color requirement for the Canadian apple standards are set forth
 in Table 4. In the case of solid red or fully striped varieties, or
 partially red or partially striped varieties, the apple must be of a red
 or red striped color on a proportion of their surface area that is at
 least equal to the percentage set out in Table 4. In the case of red
 cheeked, blush, green, yellow or russet varieties, the apple must have
 the minimum shade of color described Table 4.

 TABLE -US-00004
 TABLE 4
 CANADA
 COLOR EXTRA CANADA CANADA
 CATEGORY FANCY FANCY COMMERCIAL
 Solid red or fully 65% 40% 15%
 striped varieties
 Partially red or 55% 30% 15%
 partially striped
 varieties
 Red cheeked or Perceptibly blush- Tinge of color --
 blush varieties cheeked
 Green, yellow or Color Color --
 russet varieties characteristic of characteristic
 variety when of variety when
 mature mature

 [0082] For processed fruits and vegetables, the Canadian grades include,
 &quot;Canada Fancy,&quot; or &quot;Canada A;&quot; &quot;Canada Choice,&quot; or &quot;Canada B;&quot; and
 &quot;Canada Standard,&quot; or &quot;Canada C.&quot; These grades apply to imported as well
 as domestic produce.

 [0083] In addition to the guidelines set forth herein, the present
 disclosure further relates to other various fruit, the standards for
 which are included in the U.S. Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (as
 amended), which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety, and
 WAC Chapter 16 of the Washington state guidelines, which is also hereby
 incorporated by reference in its entirety.

 [0084] In certain embodiments of the invention, the fruit suitable for
 flavoring includes cherries. The present disclosure includes the U.S.D.A.
 guidelines for cherries, such as §§51.4340-51.4348 (for red
 sour cherries) and §§51.2646-51.2660 (for sweet cherries) of
 the Agricultural Marketing Act, as amended, which are hereby incorporated
 by reference in their entireties. The present disclosure further includes
 the Washington State Department of Agriculture standards for cherries, as
 wet forth in WAC Chapter 16, which is hereby incorporated by reference in
 its entirety. The present disclosure further includes the European and
 Canadian standards for cherries, described in the documents cited herein
 which were previously incorporated by reference.

 [0085] For example, cherries used in any embodiments of the present
 disclosure may include the grade of &quot;U.S. No. 1,&quot; or &quot;U.S. Commercial&quot;
 grade according to the U.S.D.A. federal regulations, &quot;Washington No. 1&quot;
 or &quot;Northwest No. 1,&quot; according to the Washington state guidelines, or
 another grade.

 [0086] In another example, peaches used in any embodiments of the present
 disclosure may include the grade of &quot;U.S. Grade A&quot; or &quot;U.S. Fancy;&quot; &quot;U.S.
 Grade B&quot; or &quot;U.S. Choice;&quot; &quot;U.S. Grade C&quot; or &quot;U.S. Standard;&quot; &quot;U.S. Grade
 D&quot; or &quot;U.S. Substandard;&quot; &quot;U.S. No. 1;&quot; &quot;U.S. No. 2;&quot; &quot;Washington Extra
 Fancy,&quot; &quot;Washington Fancy,&quot; or another grade.

 [0087] As recognized under the U.S. Standards for Grades of Canned
 Applesauce (47 FR 5877) and its amendments, color, flavor, types of pack,
 styles and all other terms and definitions (for example from
 §52.331-§52.345) are hereby incorporated by reference and used
 similarly herein unless otherwise noted. For example, certain embodiments
 disclosed herein may include regular or comminuted applesauce has been
 reduced to granular particles, or chunky applesauce that has been chopped
 into small pieces. In this regard, applesauce that is &quot;U.S. Grade A&quot;
 meets the quality requirements of Table 5 or Table 6 and scores not less
 than 90 points. By contrast, applesauce that is graded &quot;U.S. Grade B&quot;
 meets the quality requirements of Table 5 or Table 6 and scores not less
 than 80 points. Substandard quality fails to meet the requirements of
 U.S. Grade B.

 TABLE -US-00005
 TABLE 5
 Regular or Comminuted
 Factors Grade A Grade B
 Color:
 Natural: Bright, practically uniform, Dull, reasonably uniform,
 typical of variety or typical of variety or
 varieties used, no varieties used. Slightly
 discoloration due to brown, slightly pink, or
 oxidation or scorching. slightly grey.
 Spice flavored: Characteristic of the color The color imparted by
 imparted by added spice, added spice may be
 free from discoloration slightly affected by pink or
 due to oxidation or grey color, but is not off
 scorching. color.
 Artificially colored Bright and distinct. Reasonably bright and
 distinct.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Consistency:
 Product Flow: Not more than 6.5 cm (2.5 in) Not more than 8.5 cm (3.3 in)
 Free liquid: Not more than 0.7 cm (0.3 in) Not more than 1 cm (0.4 in)
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Absence of Defects:
 Dark stamens: Not more than 3 Not more than 5
 Seed particles, discolored Not more than 0.5 cm 2 Not more than 1.0
 cm 2 apple particles, carpel (0.08 in 2 ) Total but, (0.16 in 2 ) Total
 but
 tissue: Not more than 0.25 cm 2 Not more than 0.5 cm 2 Medium and dark colored (0.04 in 2 ) (0.08 in 2 )
 particles
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Finish
 Evenly divided, not lumpy, Evenly divided, slightly
 pasty or salvy. slavy or pasty.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Flavor:
 Good natural sugar-acid Reasonably good natural
 balance. sugar-acid balance.
 Unsweetened: Slightly tart or slightly Moderately tart, may be
 bland. Free from bland, slightly astringent
 astringent flavor. flavor.
 Sweetened: Slightly tart to sweet. May be tart, not
 Free from astringent excessively sweet, slightly
 flavor. astringent.
 Spice flavored: Flavor is distinct and Flavor derived from
 characteristic of the added flavoring(s) or
 added spice(s) or spice(s) may be slightly
 flavoring(s) but not strong. weak or strong but not
 objectionable.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Total Score: 90-100 80-89
 Analytical:
 Brix-unsweetened Not less than 9.0 degrees Not less than 9.0 degrees
 Brix-sweetened Not less than 15.5 Not less than 14.5
 degrees degrees

 TABLE -US-00006
 TABLE 6
 Chunk or Chunky
 Factors Grade A Grade B
 Color:
 Natural: Bright, practically uniform, Dull, reasonably uniform,
 typical of variety or typical of variety or
 varieties used, no varieties used. Slightly
 discoloration due to brown, slightly pink, or
 oxidation or scorching. slightly grey.
 Spice flavored: Characteristic of the color The color imparted by
 imparted by added spice, added spice may be
 free from discoloration slightly affected by pink or
 due to oxidation or grey color, but is not off
 scorching. color.
 Artificially colored Bright and distinct. Reasonably bright and
 distinct.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Consistency:
 Product Flow: Not more than 7.5 cm Not more than 9.5 cm
 (2.95 in) (3.75 in)
 Free liquid: Slight amount. Moderate amount.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Absence of Defects:
 Dark stamens: Not more than 3 Not more than 5
 Seed particles, discolored Not more than 0.5 cm 2 Not more than 1.0
 cm 2 apple particles, carpel (0.08 in 2 ) Total but, (0.16 in 2 ) Total
 but
 tissue: Not more than 0.25 cm 2 Not more than 0.5 cm 2 Medium and dark colored (0.04 in 2 ) (0.08 in 2 )
 particles
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Finish
 High proportion of apple Fairly high proportion of
 chunks. Any fine apple apple chunks. Any fine
 particles present, do no apple particles present,
 more than moderately do not seriously affect eh
 affect the appearance of appearance or eating
 eating quality of the quality of the product.
 product.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Flavor:
 Good natural sugar-acid Reasonably good natural
 balance. sugar-acid balance.
 Unsweetened: Slightly tart or slightly Moderately tart, may be
 bland. Free from bland, slightly astringent
 astringent flavor. flavor.
 Sweetened: Slightly tart to sweet. May be tart, not
 Free from astringent excessively sweet, slightly
 flavor. astringent.
 Spice flavored: Flavor is distinct and Flavor derived from
 characteristic of the added flavoring(s) or
 added spice(s) or spice(s) may be slightly
 flavoring(s) but not strong. weak or strong but not
 objectionable.
 SCORE POINTS 18-20 16-17
 Total Score: 90-100 80-89
 Analytical:
 Brix-unsweetened Not less than 9.0 degrees Not less than 9.0 degrees
 Brix-sweetened Not less than 15.5 Not less than 14.5
 degrees degrees

 [0088] In certain embodiments, the applesauce soluble solids may fall
 within the range of 18.0° to 24.0° brix, or greater or less
 than. In certain embodiments, the pH of the applesauce may fall within
 the range of 3.0-4.2 or greater or less than. In certain embodiments, the
 acidity of the applesauce may fall within 0.25-0.50 grams/100 grams or
 greater or less than.

 [0089] The fruit or vegetable produce guidelines disclosed herein further
 encompass the produce sheets of Choice Plus, Publication No. FCS-297, a
 joint publication of the U.S.D.A. and the National Food Service
 Management Institute at the University of Mississippi. (See the website
 at pma.com). In addition to these guidelines, the present invention may
 include fruits and vegetables that fall under any number of other
 federal, state or local guidelines. Such guidelines may include those
 established under NAFTA, the United Nations, other treaties or other
 laws.

 [0090] Fruit Characteristics

 [0091] One of skill in the art would realize that the fruit(s) and/or
 vegetable(s) suitable for disclosed embodiments may be assessed in a
 variety of ways. In particular, tests of soluble solids, acidity, size or
 weight, starch content, firmness, or other factors may determine the
 suitability of the produce.

 Apples 

 [0092] In one embodiment, apples suitable for processing will have soluble
 solids measurement of fruit sugar content of 9 brix or higher. In one
 particular embodiment, the test of soluble solids measurement of fruit
 sugar content is 12 brix or higher. In another particular embodiment, the
 test of soluble solids measurement of fruit sugar content is 13 brix or
 higher. In yet another embodiment, the test of soluble solids measurement
 of fruit sugar content is 14 brix or higher.

 [0093] In one embodiment, apples suitable for processing may be assessed by
 size or weight. One of skill in the art will recognize that whole fruit
 or vegetable size may be measured in a number of ways. In particular, the
 diameter of whole fruit or vegetable size may be measured, carton &quot;count&quot;
 may be measured, or its packaged weight may be measured. An exemplary
 embodiment of the present invention includes apples that measure from 2
 to 4 inches in diameter. If the whole fruit size is measured as a &quot;count&quot;
 of fruit per standard 40 or 48 lb. Carton, or its metric equivalent,
 fruit size for one example embodiment of the invention is from 72 count
 to 163 count. In another particular embodiment, the measurement of whole
 fruit size is 100 count or less. In another particular embodiment, the
 measurement of whole fruit size is 150-48 lb, or its metric equivalent.

 [0094] One of skill in the art will also recognize that measuring fruit
 acidity may, alone or in combination with other factors, indicate the
 quality of the fruit suitable for processing. In an exemplary embodiment
 of the present invention, wherein the fruit is an apple, the fruit
 acidity is in the range of pH 1.5-6.0. In another particular embodiment,
 the fruit acidity is in the range of pH 4.0-7.0.

 [0095] One of skill in the art will further recognize measuring starch
 content may, alone or in combination with other factors, indicate the
 quality of the fruit suitable for processing. In an example embodiment,
 wherein the fruit is an apple, the fruit starch content is in the range
 of 1.0-6.0. In another embodiment, the fruit starch content is in the
 range of 2.5-3.0.

 [0096] As one of skill in the art would recognize, measuring fruit
 firmness, alone or in combination with other factors, may indicate
 quality of the fruit suitable for processing. In an exemplary embodiment,
 wherein the fruit is an apple, the fruit firmness is in the range of 10
 force pounds (lbf) or higher. In another embodiment, the fruit firmness
 is in the range of 11 force pounds (lbf) or higher. In another
 embodiment, the fruit firmness is in the range of 10-17 force pounds
 (lbf).

 [0097] Pears

 [0098] In another particular embodiment, pears may be used. The present
 disclosure includes standards for grades of pears as described by the
 U.S. Department of Agriculture (§§51. 1345-51.1359 of the
 Agricultural Marketing Act as amended, and §§51.1300-51.1323 of
 the Agricultural Marketing Act, as amended), which are hereby
 incorporated by reference in their entireties.

 [0099] In general, and as used herein, &quot;U.S. Extra No. 1&quot; pears include
 fruit of one variety which are mature, but not overripe, carefully
 hand-picked, clean, well formed, relatively free from decay, internal
 breakdown, scald, freezing injury, worm holes, black end, hard end,
 drought spot, and relatively free from injury caused by russeting, limb
 rubs, hail, scars, cork spot, sunburn, sprayburn, stings or other insect
 injury, or mechanical or other means, except that they shall be
 relatively free from damage caused by bruises, broken skins, or disease.

 [0100] In general, and as used herein, &quot;U.S. No. 1&quot; for fresh pears
 includes pears of one variety which are relatively mature, but not
 overripe, carefully hand-picked, clean, fairly well formed, relatively
 free from decay, internal breakdown, scald, freezing injury, worm holes,
 black end, and from damage caused by hard end or broken skins. The &quot;U.S.
 No. 1&quot; fresh pears are also generally free from serious damage caused by
 bruises, russeting, limb rubs, hail, scars, cork spot, drought spot,
 sunburn, sprayburn, stings or other insect injury, disease, or mechanical
 or other means.

 [0101] In general, and as used herein, &quot;U.S. No. 1&quot; for processing pears
 includes pears of one variety which are relatively mature, handpicked,
 firm, well formed, free from scald, hard end, black end, internal
 breakdown, decay, worms and worm holes, and from damage caused by broken
 skins, limb rubs, sprayburn, sunburn, scab, russeting, bruises, hail,
 frost, drought spot, disease, insects, mechanical or other means. Unless
 otherwise specified, the &quot;U.S. No. 1&quot; pears for processing are generally
 not further advanced than yellowish green. In general, tree-ripened pears
 and pears grown from late blooms are not considered as meeting the
 requirements of this grade.

 [0102] In general, and as used herein, &quot;U.S. No. 2&quot; for processing pears
 includes pears of one variety which are relatively mature, hand-picked,
 firm, not seriously deformed, free from scald, hard end, black end,
 internal breakdown, decay, worms and worm holes, and free from serious
 damage by any other cause. Unless otherwise specified, the pears in this
 grade are not further advanced than yellowish green. In general,
 tree-ripened pears and pears grown from late blooms shall not be
 considered as meeting the requirements of this grade.

 [0103] In general, and as used herein, &quot;Unclassified&quot; includes pears which
 have not been classified in accordance with any of the foregoing grades.
 As such, &quot;Unclassified&quot; is not a grade within the meaning of the U.S.D.A.
 standards, but is provided to designate that no grade has been applied to
 the lot. In addition, &quot;culls&quot; are pears which do not meet the
 requirements of any of the foregoing grades for fresh or processing
 pears.

 [0104] As used herein, &quot;serious damage&quot; may refer to any injury or defect
 which seriously affects the appearance, or the edible or shipping
 quality. In addition, for processing pears, &quot;serious damage&quot; cannot be
 removed during the usual commercial preparation for use without a loss of
 over 20%, by weight, of the pear in excess of that which would occur if
 the pear were not defective.

 [0105] As with any fruit, decay, scald or other deterioration which may
 have developed on pears after they have been in storage or transit are
 generally considered as affecting fruit condition and not the grade
 thereof.

 [0106] As used herein to describe pears, &quot;mature&quot; generally refers to pears
 that have reached the stage of maturity which will insure the proper
 completion of the ripening process, and before the fruit has become
 overripe it will show varying degrees of firmness depending on the stage
 of the ripening process. Thus, a description of firmness may also be
 given in order to indicate the stage of the ripening process.

 [0107] In referring to the firmness of pears, &quot;hard&quot; means the flesh of the
 pear is solid and does not yield appreciably even to considerable
 pressure; &quot;firm&quot; means that the flesh of the pear is fairly solid but
 yields somewhat to moderate pressure but is not wilted, shriveled,
 rubbery or flabby; &quot;firm ripe&quot; means that the flesh of the pear yields
 readily to moderate pressure; &quot;ripe&quot; means that the pear is at the stage
 where it is in its most desirable condition for eating; &quot;overripe&quot; means
 dead ripe, very mealy or soft, past commercial utility. Generally, a
 description of the ground color may also be given, according to &quot;green,&quot;
 &quot;light green,&quot; &quot;yellowish green,&quot; and &quot;yellow.&quot;

 [0108] As used herein, &quot;hand-picked&quot; may refer to fruit that does not show
 evidence of having been on the ground, and &quot;carefully hand-picked&quot; may
 refer to fruit that shows no evidence of rough handling or of having been
 on the ground. As used herein, &quot;black end&quot; is indicated by an abnormally
 deep green color around the calyx, or black spots usually occurring on
 the one-third of the surface nearest to the calyx, or by an abnormally
 shallow calyx cavity.

 [0109] One of skill in the art would recognize that the test of soluble
 solids measurement of fruit sugar content in raw pears may be
 immeasurably low due to incomplete ripening. By contrast, the test of
 soluble solids measurement may be greater or less than 5 Brix, 7 Brix, 9
 Brix, 11 Brix, 12 Brix, 13 Brix, or any value therebetween.

 [0110] Pear size may be measured as individual fruit size or whole packaged
 size or weight. In particular, the measurement of individual fruit size
 may be from 2 to 4 inches in diameter. Alternatively, the whole fruit
 size as measured by a &quot;count&quot; of fruit per standard 40 or 48 lb. carton,
 or its metric equivalent, may be from 72 count to 163 count. In one
 particular embodiment, the measurement of whole fruit size is 100 count
 or less. In another particular embodiment, the measurement of whole fruit
 size is 150-48 lb, or its metric equivalent.

 [0111] One of skill in the art would recognize that fruit acidity, alone or
 in combination with other factors, may indicate fruit quality in fruit
 suitable for processing. In a particular embodiment, the fruit acidity of
 the pear used is in the range of pH 1.5-6.0. In another particular
 embodiment, the fruit acidity of the pear is in the range of pH 4.0-7.0.

 [0112] One of skill in the art would recognize other factors in determining
 fruit quality are fruit starch and/or fruit firmness in fruit suitable
 for processing. In particular, the fruit starch content of a pear used in
 the present invention is in the range of 1.0-6.0. In any particular
 embodiment, the firmness of the pear is in the range of 8 force pounds
 (lbf) or higher.

 [0113] In the particular embodiment wherein the fruit is a pear, the fruit
 has a United States Department of Agriculture federal grade selected from
 the group consisting of: U.S. Extra No. 1, U.S. No. 1, and any
 combination thereof. Alternatively, the fruit or vegetables used in any
 particular embodiment may have any state or federal grade available.

 [0114] In another particular embodiment, the present invention relates to
 Asian pears. One of skill in the art would recognize that Asian pears
 include &quot;Tsu Li,&quot; &quot;Ya Li,&quot; Kikusui,&quot; &quot;Nijisseiki,&quot; &quot;20 th Century,&quot;
 &quot;Seigyoku,&quot; &quot;Shinseiki,&quot; &quot;Chojuro,&quot; &quot;Doitsu,&quot; &quot;Imamura Aki,&quot; &quot;Hosui,&quot;
 &quot;Kosui,&quot; Niitaka,&quot; &quot;Shinko,&quot; &quot;Ishiiwase,&quot; and other Chinese or Japanese
 varieties or cultivars. Other common names for Asian pears include
 Oriental pears, Chinese pears, Japanese pears, nashi, sand apples, salad
 pears, &quot;apple pears,&quot; and others.

 [0115] In certain aspects, Asian pears that are suitable for processing
 have a firmness of approximately 7-25 lbs. In certain aspects, the Asian
 pears have a firmness of approximately 7 lbs, 8 lbs, 9 lbs, 10 lbs, 11
 lbs, 12 lbs, 13 lbs, 14 lbs, 15 lbs, 16 lbs, 17 lbs, 18 lbs, 19 lbs, 20
 lbs, 21 lbs, 22 lbs, 23 lbs, 24 lbs, 25 lbs, or any value therebetween.

 [0116] In certain aspects, the Asian pears that are suitable for processing
 may have approximately 11-14% soluble solids. In certain aspects, the
 Asian pears that are suitable for processing may have approximately
 11.0%, 11.5%, 12.0%, 12.5%, 13.0%, 13.5%,14.0%, 14.5% soluble solids or
 any value therebetween or greater.

 [0117] One of skill in the art would recognize a variety of other factors
 may be considered in determining the quality control of Asian pears
 suitable for processing.

 Cherries 

 [0118] Another particular embodiment relates to cherries. In certain
 aspects of this embodiment, the fruit sugar content of cherries suitable
 for processing is approximately 10-27%. In certain aspects of this
 embodiment, the fruit sugar content of cherries suitable for processing
 is approximately 10%, 11%, 12%, 13%, 14%,15%,16%,17%,18%,19%, 20% 21%,
 22%, 23%, 24%, 25%, 26%, 27%, or any value therebetween. As one of skill
 in the art would understand, total soluble solids content may also be
 measured in ° Brix, rather than percentage, and thus the present
 disclosure includes the total soluble solids content for cherries
 suitable for processing as approximately 10.5 to 16° Brix. In
 certain aspects of the invention, the total soluble solids content may be
 approximately 10.5°, 11.0°, 12.0°, 13.0°,
 14.0°, 15.0°, 16.0° Brix, or any value therebetween
 or greater.

 [0119] In certain aspects of the invention, the fruit firmness for cherries
 suitable for processing is approximately 4.0 N to 7.5 N. In certain
 aspects of this embodiment, the fruit firmness for cherries suitable for
 processing is approximately 4.0 N, 4.5 N, 5.0 N, 5.5 N, 6.0 N, 6.5 N, 7.0
 N, 7.5 N or any value therebetween. In certain aspects of the invention,
 the pH of cherries suitable for processing may be approximately 3.0 to
 5.0. In certain aspects of the invention, the pH of cherries suitable for
 processing may be approximately 3.0, 3.5, 4.0, 4.5, 5.0, or any value
 therebetween.

 [0120] One of skill in the art would recognize that other factors may also
 be considered when determining the quality control of cherries or other
 fruit or vegetable that is suitable for processing.

 [0121] The processed fruit or vegetable products disclosed herein may be
 used for direct human or animal consumption, or may be processed for
 cakes, cookies, breads, crackers, cereals, other baked goods, cake mixes,
 jams, jellies, yogurt mixes, doughnuts, pie fillings, or other food
 add-ins or other processed food(s).

 [0122] In at least one embodiment, the fruit is not a pome fruit. In at
 least one embodiment, the fruit is not an apple. In at least one
 embodiment, the fruit is not a pear. In at least one embodiment, the
 fruit or vegetable is not a tomato.

 Packaging and Storing 

 [0123] At least one embodiment of the present invention also relates to a
 method for packaging and/or storing the processed fruit and/or vegetable
 products. In one embodiment, the processed fruit or vegetable products
 are vacuum packed in a container. In the same or a different embodiment,
 the processed fruit or vegetable products are sealed in cans, jars or
 plastic cups. In the same or a different embodiment, the processed fruit
 or vegetable products are packaged in a modified or controlled atmosphere
 container. Such modified or controlled atmosphere may comprise elevated
 carbon dioxide levels, elevated nitrogen levels, reduced oxygen levels,
 reduced ethylene levels, or any combination thereof.

 [0124] The present invention also relates to storing the processed fruit or
 vegetables prior to or subsequent to packaging. In one particular
 embodiment, the processed fruit or vegetables are stored prior to
 packaging. In another particular embodiment, the processed fruit or
 vegetables are stored subsequent to packaging. In one embodiment, the
 fruit or vegetables are stored and/or packaged prior to processing.

 [0125] In one embodiment, the uncut fruit or vegetables are stored in an
 environment with a temperature range of 30-80° F. prior to cutting
 or comminuting. In another particular embodiment, the uncut fruit or
 vegetables are stored in an environment with a temperature range of
 30-53° F. In another embodiment, the uncut fruit or vegetables are
 stored in an environment with a relative humidity range of 85-95%.

 [0126] At least one embodiment includes compositions comprising processed
 fruit and/or vegetable products that have a shelf-life of up to 14 days,
 21 days, 30 days, 40 days, 60 days, 75 days, 90 days, 100 days, 110 days,
 120 days, 150 days, 180 days, 200 days, 225 days, or any number
 therebetween or greater. One embodiment of the presently claimed
 invention includes harvesting, processing and packaging the fruit and/or
 vegetables all within 1 to 7 days. One embodiment of the presently
 claimed invention includes harvesting, possibly processing, and packaging
 the fruit and/or vegetables all within one month to one year.

 System 

 [0127] At least one embodiment disclosed herein relates to an automated
 system for processing fruits and/or vegetables into products and
 optionally packaging said products and further optionally transporting
 the products from the place of processing to a place of packaging (if
 product is packaged) and further optionally to a place of sale to the
 consumer. In at least one embodiment, the fruit(s) or vegetable(s) are
 first transported from a truck, dock, or other carrier to the place of
 processing. In another embodiment, the system further comprises
 transporting the fruit from an orchard, greenhouse or other growing
 facility to the place of processing. The place of processing includes the
 place of cutting, mashing, splitting, pulverizing or comminuting the
 fruit(s) or vegetable(s) such that they are reduced to particulate matter
 or product. Subsequently, the particulate matter or product may be
 contacted with one or more additives, including a flavoring agent, a
 coloring agent, a sweetener or sweetening agent, a preservative or
 anti-browning agent, a micronutrient or a macronutrient.

 [0128] In one particular embodiment, the system further comprises packaging
 the processed fruit or vegetable products. In another particular
 embodiment, the system further comprises unloading the fruits or
 vegetables from a truck, dock or other carrier. Thus, the system may be
 located at a main processing facility that is capable of handling
 multiple fruits and/or vegetables and/or various fruits and/or
 vegetables.

 [0129] In another particular embodiment, the system further comprises
 transporting the fruits or vegetables from an orchard, field, greenhouse
 or other growing facility to the processing facility. Thus, the system
 may be located in the orchard, field, greenhouse or other growing
 facility or the system may be located away from the growing facility.

 [0130] In one particular embodiment, the system is regulated, operated or
 controlled by a computer system. In one particular embodiment, at least
 part of the computer system is remote from the rest of the automated
 fruit and vegetable processing system. In another particular embodiment,
 information contained on or in the fruit or vegetable may be entered into
 the computer and used for tracking the fruit or vegetable through the
 processing and/or packaging steps.

 Business Methods 

 [0131] At least one embodiment of the present invention further relates to
 a business method comprising processing the fruits or vegetables into
 products, supplementing the fruit or vegetable products with one or more
 additives, packaging said fruit or vegetable products, and selling said
 supplemented fruit or vegetable products. In a further embodiment, the
 business method comprises the step of storing said fruits or vegetables
 after harvest and prior to processing into products.

 [0132] In another particular embodiment, the invention comprises the step
 of a company licensing rights from another organization to market or sell
 the processed fruit or vegetable products. In another particular
 embodiment, the step of marketing or selling the fruit or vegetable
 products comprises an organization collecting royalties from a company
 that sells the fruit or vegetable products. The invention further
 comprises the step of storing and/or tracking fruit or vegetables after
 harvest and prior to processing. In another particular embodiment, the
 invention further comprises the step of collecting fees from a company
 that sells the fruit or vegetable products. In one particular embodiment,
 the fees comprise at least one of license fees or milestone fees.

 [0133] In another particular embodiment, a company licenses or acquires the
 rights to market or sell the processed fruit or vegetable products and
 the company identifies another product formulation. In one particular
 embodiment, the product formulation is a marketed flavoring. In another
 particular embodiment, the product formulation is off patent.

 [0134] The present invention further comprises the step of patenting the
 newly-identified product formulation or method of using the product
 formulation for the processed fruit or vegetable products.

 [0135] In any of the aforementioned business methods, the company may be a
 wholesale or retail grocery, a franchise chain, a theme park, a
 restaurant, a fast food restaurant, a food processing or manufacturing
 plant, or any combination thereof. In any of the aforementioned business
 methods, the organization may be a packer owned orchard, a privately held
 orchard, a grower-owned field or garden plot, a corporate or agribusiness
 field, a fruit or vegetable cooperative, or any combination thereof. In
 any one of the aforementioned business methods, the fruits or vegetables
 may be derived from one single grower, or the fruits and vegetables may
 be derived from multiple growers. In any one of the aforementioned
 business methods, the processed fruit or vegetable products may be
 exported from the United States.

 [0136] Certain embodiments further relate to business methods comprising
 the step of storing the processed fruit or vegetable products subsequent
 to canning or packaging. Other embodiments further relate to business
 methods comprising storing the uncut fruit or vegetables prior to
 processing.

 [0137] The present invention also relates to a business method comprising
 tracking the fruit or vegetables through the processing and/or packaging
 steps. In another embodiment, the business method further comprises
 tracking the fruit or vegetables from an orchard, greenhouse or other
 growing facility, through the processing and/or packaging steps. In
 another embodiment, the business method comprises tracking the fruit or
 vegetables through transporting and up to and including delivery to the
 wholesale or retail seller. In another particular embodiment, the
 invention comprises tracking the fruit or vegetables up to and including
 consumer purchase. Such method may include the use of a computer to
 enter, store, access and retrieve information regarding the status of the
 fruit or vegetables or status of the processing, packaging, and/or
 transporting steps. A computer used for tracking fruit or vegetables
 (including the origin of the fruit or vegetables), may be operated by a
 remote user, such as a human being, another computer or robot.

 [0138] One of skill in the art would recognize that a variety of types of
 tracking devices might be employed with embodiments disclosed herein. In
 particular, radio frequency tags, bar codes or other identifying marks or
 information may be used to track fruit or vegetables from the orchard,
 field, greenhouse or other growing facility all the way up to and
 including the consumer purchase. Such identifying marks or information
 may be physically contained on the fruit or vegetable itself, contained
 on the tree, branch, or other growing receptacle where the fruit
 originated, and may be transferred to a packaging label or entered into a
 computer tracking system. Identifying marks may include a chemical or
 color tattoo, a laser etching, a burn mark or brand, or other color mark,
 a sticker or label, or other informational tag.

 Process for Manufacture 

 [0139] At least one embodiment disclosed herein relates to a process for
 manufacturing processed fruit or vegetable products, supplementing the
 products with at least one additive, and packaging said products, thereby
 manufacturing said processed fruit or vegetable products. For purposes of
 practicing this particular aspect of the presently claimed invention, the
 fruit or vegetable is selected from the group consisting of apples,
 pears, Asian pears, cherries, corn (including cream style corn), beans,
 carrots, peas, pumpkin, any other fruit or vegetable disclosed herein and
 any combination thereof (including fruit cocktail). The particular
 aspects described herein for all other embodiments may likewise be
 applied to this particular aspect of the invention.

 [0140] Known methods of processing fruits and/or vegetables for pureed
 products may be utilized with specific embodiments disclosed herein. The
 fruit and/or vegetable products may be processed in accordance with good
 manufacturing process, as set forth in 21 CFR Part 110 of the USDA
 guidelines, and may be commercially ready to use. Such products may meet
 the requirements for Grade A, Grade B, or other grades according to the
 USDA guidelines. In certain embodiments, the fruit or vegetable products
 may not be more than 90 days old prior to delivery to the place of sale
 or to the consumer.

 [0141] Typically, fruit and vegetables suitable for processing are canned
 or frozen (or dried or dehydrated) quickly in order to preserve their
 nutritive quality. Most of the processing is usually done by automated
 equipment, which provides high-speed processing and sanitary, wholesome
 products preserved with good flavor and quality.

 [0142] In one exemplary embodiment, preparing fresh fruits or vegetables
 for processing may include sorting into sizes by hand or machine, washing
 the produce by continuously circulating water, sprays of water or diluted
 bleach or other cleaners, and possibly peeling the produce. In some
 embodiments, the produce may be peeled and/or cut prior to further
 processing (for sliced, diced, quartered, julienne, or other cut
 products).

 [0143] Once the fruits and/or vegetables are peeled and/or cut, they may be
 heated and/or mixed with additives disclosed herein. The mixture of fruit
 and/or vegetable product(s) may then be transferred to containers, such
 as cans or jars. In some embodiments, the containers may be filled by
 automatic or semi-automatic means, including conveyor belts. Once the
 containers are filled, they may be heat-sealed, regular packed, solid
 packed, vacuum packed, or otherwise sealed or packed.

 [0144] By contrast, in certain embodiments the containers may be filled
 first with the peeled and/or cut produce, sealed and then heated under
 controlled conditions of time and temperature.

 [0145] The containers may be cooled deliberately by cold gas or liquid
 cooling, or they may be air-cooled. Once the containers are cooled, they
 are stored in a cool, dry, well-ventilated warehouse until shipment to
 market.

 [0146] Still in other embodiments, the fruits and/or vegetables may be
 blanched and then frozen. Blanching involves a heat treatment of
 foodstuffs for a sufficient time and at a sufficient temperature to
 partially or completely inactivate the naturally occurring enzymes and to
 effect other physical or biochemical changes in the food. Blanching
 ensures that the product will retain much of its natural appearance,
 flavor, and nutrition. After freezing, the products may be packaged in
 containers (bags, or the like).

 [0147] Thus, the additives disclosed herein may be contacted with the fruit
 and/or vegetable puree or pulp at numerous times during production.
 Depending on the particular embodiment, all of the additives of a
 particular product may be introduced at a single time during production,
 or at multiple times during production. Further, the same or different
 additives may be introduced at the same or different time points during
 production. Of course, one of skill in the art would understand that,
 depending on the additive, there may be preferable time points for
 introduction for one or more additive (depending on temperature
 sensitivity of the additive, for example). For example, if a particular
 additive (such as a vitamin) is heat-sensitive, the vitamin may be added
 once the product is cooled, or may be added in such a way that the
 integrity of the vitamin (or other additive) is maintained.

 [0148] As another example, one or more additives may be placed in contact
 with the processed fruit and/or vegetables at the same time or subsequent
 to cleaning the fruits or vegetables. In another exemplary embodiment,
 one or more additives may be placed in contact with the processed fruit
 and/or vegetables at the same time or subsequent to comminuting the fruit
 and/or vegetables. In still another exemplary embodiment, one or more
 additives may be placed in contact with the processed fruit and/or
 vegetables at the same time or subsequent to heating, freezing, drying,
 dehydrating, mixing, or otherwise altering the fruits and/or vegetables
 in size, shape or form. In still other embodiments, the fruit and/or
 vegetable product may be contacted with one or more additive upon
 canning, freezing, or otherwise packaging.

 [0149] The following examples are offered by way of illustration and not by
 way of limitation of the invention. It is understood that the examples
 and embodiments described herein are for illustrative purposes only and
 that various modifications or changes in light thereof will be suggested
 to persons skilled in the art and to be included within the scope and
 spirit of the invention.

 [0150] All of the U.S. patents, U.S. patent application publications, U.S.
 patent applications, foreign patents, foreign patent applications and
 non-patent publications referred to in this specification and/or listed
 in the Application Data Sheet are incorporated herein by reference, in
 their entirety.

 [0151] From the foregoing it will be appreciated that, although specific
 embodiments of the invention have been described herein for purposes of
 illustration, various modifications may be made without deviating from
 the spirit and scope of the invention. Accordingly, the invention is not
 limited except as by the appended claims.


 
Patent applications by Blair C. Mchaney, Wenatchee, WA US
 
Patent applications in class With added enzyme material or microorganism
 
Patent applications in all subclasses With added enzyme material or microorganism
 
 
User Contributions:
 
Comment about this patent or add new information about this topic:
 Public Comment:   (50-4000 characters) Name: E-mail: Display my email: Security Code: 
 New patent applications in this class: Date Title 2012-05-31 Composition for low-salt food or beverage 2012-05-17 Method for production of tea extract 2012-04-26 Production of natural truffle flavours from truffle mycelium 2012-04-26 Reduction of acrylamide formation 2012-02-23 Novel asparaginases and uses thereof 

 Top Inventors for class &quot;Food or edible material: processes, compositions, and products&quot; Rank Inventor&apos;s name 1 William H. Eby 2 Kevin I. Segall 3 Martin Schweizer 4 Thomas Lee 5 Yoshihiro Nakao
	</body>
</document>
