<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008892" url="http://forums.corral.net/forums/5-0-5-8-engine-tech/11492-hawks-racing-crankshafts-anyone-bueller.html" time="2012-07-13-02:19" support="5" score="0.004588820657209043" bingtitle="Hawks Racing Crankshafts? Anyone...Bueller??? - Ford Mustang ..." webtitle="Hawks Racing Crankshafts? Anyone...Bueller??? - Ford Mustang Forums : Corral.net Mustang Forum">
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001211" bing-rank="103"/>
	<description>Hmmm...take it how you will here fellas! This was ... doing good and in the 2nd different block for near 5 ... They were able to reference my receipt number. I sent the crank ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News 
 Corral News Mustang and Ford News 
 Multimedia 
 Videos Photos 
 Forums 
 Forums Blog 
 Tech 
 Articles Audio Drivetrain Electronics Engine Exterior Interior Maintenance Poweradders Suspension&amp;Brakes Resources Calculators Product Reviews Wiki 
 Classifieds 
 Corral Mustang Classifieds Corral Parts Classifieds Classifieds Feedback Area Corral Photo Classifieds Corral Advertisers&apos; Showcase Used Cars New Parts 
 Outside the Fence Advertise Links Contact 
 
 Corral 
 
Popular

 Latest Corral and Mustang news Corral Technical Articles and Product Reviews Classifieds Register an account 
 
Support the Corral! Click Here:
 
 Blogs Recent Entries Best Entries Best Blogs Blog List 
 
 
 
 
   Ford Mustang Forums : Corral.net Mustang Forum &gt; Windsor Tech Forums &gt; 5.0/5.8 Engine Tech Hawks Racing Crankshafts? Anyone...Bueller??? 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register Garage 
 Garage Garages Browse by Username Browse Recently Added Browse Recently Modified Browse Most Popular Advanced Search Help 
 Blogs FAQ Calendar 
 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 Corral.net is the premier Ford Mustang forum on the internet. Registered Users do not see the above ads.Please Register - It&apos;s Free! 
 

   LinkBack Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
 11-27-2001, 09:52 AM  # 1 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Hawks Racing Crankshafts? Anyone...Bueller??? Has anyone heard ANYTHING good or bad about them. Anyone out there using one? Thanks in advance!

Todd   
 
 Remove Advertisements Sponsored Links Corral.net Advertisement  
 
 
 11-27-2001, 07:45 PM  # 2 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Hawk or Hawks Racing? Anyone even heard of them.   
 
 11-27-2001, 09:19 PM  # 3 fast4d Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 0 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2000 Location: camarillo, CA Posts: 232 
 Are they in so cal?

I believe it&apos;s the same outfit that sells on ebay under THE MUSTANG DEPOT.

probably parts from CAT. __________________
Alan
&apos;89 GT (331, Canfields, FAST EFI, T-70, Griggs GR-40) 550rwhp/640rwtq @ 15psi 91 octane
&apos;98 M3 /4   
 
 11-28-2001, 08:41 AM  # 4 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 CAT PRODUCT??? Quote: 
 Originally posted by fast4d 
 Are they in so cal?

I believe it&apos;s the same outfit that sells on ebay under THE MUSTANG DEPOT.

probably parts from CAT. 
 Somebody PLEASE tell me this isn&apos;t a CAT product! I&apos;ve heard horror stories about the balancing and eventual destruction of engines because of these CHEAPER cranks. ANYONE ELSE???   
 
 11-28-2001, 08:51 AM  # 5 Lee8995 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 16 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Odessa ,Tx Posts: 5,011 
 Garage 
 Lee8995&apos;s Garage  Mine  Mine too 
 Yeah Hawks and TMD are one in the same. If you enter eithers website it goes to the same place. I dont know who makes their parts but they will conveniently leave the brand name out when they are auctioning off their products. I say buyer beware if they wont furnish you honest info regarding their product line. You get what you pay for, A 120 dollar stroker crank is just what you get for 120 bux in my opinion. Have you ever heard the expression of saving too much money?


Lee   
 
 11-28-2001, 10:35 AM  # 6 fast4d Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 0 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2000 Location: camarillo, CA Posts: 232 
 the price should be a warning to you. The cheapest crankshaft out there I would consider is the cast steel scat units. It&apos;s probably casted in china but scat does the machine work here.

TMD is making a killing off ebay newbies who practically pay retail prices and their outrageous S/H fees. __________________
Alan
&apos;89 GT (331, Canfields, FAST EFI, T-70, Griggs GR-40) 550rwhp/640rwtq @ 15psi 91 octane
&apos;98 M3 /4   
 
 11-28-2001, 11:30 AM  # 7 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Quote: 
 Originally posted by Lee8995 
 Yeah Hawks and TMD are one in the same. If you enter eithers website it goes to the same place.


Lee 
 Who is TMD? I haven&apos;t been able to find any information or web site on either Hawks or TMD. What I&apos;m getting at here is that I found a pretty good deal on a stroker kit and recognise all parts except the crank. Any information is appreciated...   
 
 11-28-2001, 11:51 AM  # 8 Lee8995 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 16 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Odessa ,Tx Posts: 5,011 
 Garage 
 Lee8995&apos;s Garage  Mine  Mine too 
 Hawks Racing and The Mustang Depot, Thats who they are. The last time I looked they had alot of stuff on ebay that was being sold with minimal info especialy the manufacturer.   
 
 11-28-2001, 11:55 AM  # 9 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 The Mustang Depot I tried to look for the crankshafts or engine kits on The Mustang Depot web site and they don&apos;t list any cranks or engine kits there. Hmmm...this is a tuff one. I don&apos;t want to buy crap! Thanks for the input guys. Keep it coming if anybody else knows anything about these cranks.   
 
 11-28-2001, 12:26 PM  # 10 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Mustang Depots Reply to my question! Hmmm...take it how you will here fellas! This was the administrators reply at Mustang Depot...


Me:

Do you guys carry Hawks Racing crankshafts? If so, can you give me the specs of them or ANY information on them? Are they from CAT, SCAT or EAGLE etc...etc...Also, how would I contact Hawks Racing?

Thanks for your help,


Their reply:

We do not carry crankshafts at this time!

Thanks again

Taylor
Admin Dept
 www.MustangDepot.com   
 
 11-28-2001, 02:24 PM  # 11 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Forget about these cranks!!! Well guys, if these cranks are any good, you won&apos;t hear it from Mustang Depot. I emailed them twice after I received the email that they no longer sell cranks and I got&quot;ZERO&quot;replys!

This was both of my emails...

(1) I have a crank that was purchased off of eBay from you guys. Can you give me the info on it? It is a 331 Stroker S/B Ford unit.

NO REPLY!!!!

(2) Please go here to view the cranks y&apos;all no longer carry.

 http://cgi.ebay.com/ebaymotors/aw-cg...item=598284281 

AGAIN, NO REPLY!!! What kind of customer service do you call this????? They have answered any other question about purchasing one of their cranks, you know, the ones they no longer carry!!!

Thanks for all the replys!!!   
 
 11-28-2001, 03:44 PM  # 12 HAWK327 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 1 )  
 Join Date: Mar 2001 Location: Port Saint Lucie, Florida Posts: 1,167 
 put a&quot;the&quot;in front of mustang depot and try that, they are 2 different companies. TMD lists their cranks as hawks racing on ebay. __________________
90&apos;lx hatch, 2950# w/me, Girdled/studded 347,Scat 9000 crank,4340 scat I beams,SRP pistons, SFI 28 oz dampner,11.1cr, Vic jr heads, probe shaft rockers,BIG custom solid Roller,Comp hi-tec roller lifters,Vic jr intake,830cfm holley HP carb, edelbrock gear drive, 1 3/4-1 7/8 kooks LT&apos;s w 3&quot;X pipe, CSI electric WP, Pro shifted G-force 5 speed,auburn pro w/31 spline mosers,4.30 gears..and so on.   
 
 11-28-2001, 04:00 PM  # 13 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 The Mustang Depot/ Mustang Depot You are correct but The Mustang Depot has no web address. I was trying to email Mustang Depot and thay may not sell cranks. (silly me) MY BAD!!! None the less, I&apos;m still skeptical...   
 
 11-29-2001, 01:26 AM  # 14 Eagle Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 22 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2000 Location: Seattle, WA Posts: 3,020 
 Out of curiosity what&apos;s the price on the kit?

I think that you&apos;ll be surprised on the pricing Scat can offer on a cast kit that you can actually run with confidence.

Brian __________________
 www.ADperformance.com   
 
 11-29-2001, 05:29 AM  # 15 BlownSkillet Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Concord, Ga. (ATL) Posts: 724 
 Scat pricing. Hey Eagle, shoot me some information or a web site where i can check the kits and prices out. Do they offer a low comp. kit?   
 
 11-29-2001, 11:10 AM  # 16 Eagle Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 22 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2000 Location: Seattle, WA Posts: 3,020 
 Scat&apos;s webight is [/url]

Unfortunately my websight is still in the works so for now you need to email me if you want quotes, I can&apos;t quote prices on the Corral.

As for low compression yes, we do have a dish piston as an option.

Brian __________________
 www.ADperformance.com   
 
 10-13-2010, 06:30 PM  # 17 all junk Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 0 )  
 Join Date: Aug 2010 Location: waynesboro,va. Posts: 6 
 bbf hawks racing i purchased a 523 bbf stroker kit from the mustang depot off ebay put the motor together and installed an f-1r procharger producing 14 lbs. of boost and had no troubles at all car on dyno put down 877 hp 800 tq to the wheels everyting is holding up fine so far have 75 passes on car now   
 
 10-13-2010, 06:33 PM  # 18 Mark O&apos;Neal Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Torrance, CA Posts: 932 
 Same cranks everyone sells.   
 
 10-13-2010, 06:34 PM  # 19 Mark O&apos;Neal Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Torrance, CA Posts: 932 
 Please allow me to add......


A Chinese crank is a Chinese crank is a Chinese crank........   
 
 10-13-2010, 06:54 PM  # 20 csgoody Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 3 )  
 Join Date: Jul 2007 Location: witch city ,mass Posts: 2,476 
 9 year old thread...   
 
 10-13-2010, 06:57 PM  # 21 MurPHy4570 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 3 )  
 Join Date: Jul 2006 Location: West Deptford, NJ Posts: 6,587 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by csgoody 9 year old thread... 
 Holy #### that has got to be a necro-rezzing record. __________________
&quot;Our Country! In her intercourse with foreign nations, may she always be in the right, but our country right or wrong.&quot;

- Commodore Stephen Decatur, Norfolk, Virginia, April 4, 1816   
 
 10-13-2010, 07:01 PM  # 22 csgoody Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 3 )  
 Join Date: Jul 2007 Location: witch city ,mass Posts: 2,476 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by MurPHy4570 Holy #### that has got to be a necro-rezzing record. 
 Could be,Any corral historians?   
 
 10-13-2010, 07:50 PM  # 23 Lee8995 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 16 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Odessa ,Tx Posts: 5,011 
 Garage 
 Lee8995&apos;s Garage  Mine  Mine too 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by csgoody Could be,Any corral historians? 
 This is the oldest one I have seen pop up, The only other thread that I know of anywhere close is the one where someone in Waco bought a set of bare ProComp heads when they first came out and walked everyone through his assembly of the heads. __________________
The real reason that we can&apos;t have the Ten Commandments posted in a courthouse is this:
You cannot post &apos;Thou Shalt Not Steal,&apos; &apos;Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery,&apos; and &apos;Thou Shall Not Lie&apos; in a building full of lawyers, judges and politicians...It creates a hostile work environment.   
 
 10-13-2010, 07:59 PM  # 24 white-stang Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 0 )  
 Join Date: Aug 2001 Location: Wash. st. Posts: 565 
 My hawks crank and rods are still doing good and in the 2nd different block for near 5 years, wish I could say the same for my made by ford p o s 5.0 block.
Is it from china, yep it is, same place my made for ford motorsports valve covers were made. China has me covered from top to bottom. __________________
80 mustang, 331, ported E7`s, 780 vac sec, rpm airgap, mac 1 5/8 lt`s, C4 w/3200 stall, 255x60x15 MT dr`s, 3.73`s
1.63 60&apos; 114.78 mph ET 11.76
3020 lbs with driver.   
 
 10-13-2010, 09:17 PM  # 25 85gt66 Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 18 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2008 Location: BOONDOCKS Posts: 812 
 I have a 11 to 1 306 with kb domes and hawks racing rods that have run fine, had to take a good bit off in various spots to balance them properly, not the best casting quality IMO   
 
 10-15-2010, 12:49 PM  # 26 Mark O&apos;Neal Registered User 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jun 2003 Location: Torrance, CA Posts: 932 
 Most forgings have poor casting quality.   
 
 10-15-2010, 12:51 PM  # 27 Lee8995 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 16 )  
 Join Date: May 2000 Location: Odessa ,Tx Posts: 5,011 
 Garage 
 Lee8995&apos;s Garage  Mine  Mine too 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Mark O&apos;Neal Most forgings have poor casting quality. 
 Would that be before or after you hammer the #### out of it?
ROFLMAO __________________
The real reason that we can&apos;t have the Ten Commandments posted in a courthouse is this:
You cannot post &apos;Thou Shalt Not Steal,&apos; &apos;Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery,&apos; and &apos;Thou Shall Not Lie&apos; in a building full of lawyers, judges and politicians...It creates a hostile work environment.   
 
 01-18-2011, 07:05 PM  # 28 saleen9973 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: Mar 2001 Location: middletown,ny,usa Posts: 837 
 I want in on this 9 yr old post!! How did the Hawks kit balance out? Did it need a ton of heavy metal?   
 
 01-18-2011, 08:48 PM  # 29 white-stang Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 0 )  
 Join Date: Aug 2001 Location: Wash. st. Posts: 565 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by saleen9973 I want in on this 9 yr old post!! How did the Hawks kit balance out? Did it need a ton of heavy metal? 
 Mine didnt __________________
80 mustang, 331, ported E7`s, 780 vac sec, rpm airgap, mac 1 5/8 lt`s, C4 w/3200 stall, 255x60x15 MT dr`s, 3.73`s
1.63 60&apos; 114.78 mph ET 11.76
3020 lbs with driver.   
 
 01-18-2011, 10:05 PM  # 30 saleen9973 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 5 )  
 Join Date: Mar 2001 Location: middletown,ny,usa Posts: 837 
 white-stang is the 331 in your sig the hawks kit?   
 
 01-18-2011, 10:14 PM  # 31 strokeme Authorized corral.net Advertiser 
 Trader Feedback: ( 13 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2006 Location: Chicago IL Posts: 6,714 
 you need to be much more specific other than did it need mallory, what crank, what balance and so forth __________________
Yes I am&quot;Woody&quot;, Yes I am the Owner. 110% QUALITY Driven!
630-462-3978 Shop Direct
877-723-5487 Shop Toll-Free

TONS of Build Photos Ck at Facebook 
 
Make sure to sign up for SBFBuilding.com The single most exciting thing to happen to the small block ford community in a LONG TIME. 
 

   
 
 01-18-2011, 11:00 PM  # 32 Sprayaway Fox Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jul 2008 Location: Plymouth Posts: 536 
 I did a Hawk rotating assembly (had KB forged pistons in the kit) 347 Had a X cam and AFR 165 heads. It balanced pretty darn good actually not alot of heavy metal needed. I had it balanced just like a 89 GT would be. (Its been a while and cant remember offhand).. I got the kit on a trade. Built the engine and sent it on its way.

I sold it to a bud that put it in one of his customers car (70 mustang I beleive?) at the body shop he works at. Its been about 2 years and havent heard anything bad about it from him or the owner I never met. He came up to me at the bar and said the owner was pleased how the car turned out this last fall. Id be worried about the block splitting before anything else. IMO Last edited by Sprayaway Fox; 01-18-2011 at 11:03 PM .   
 
 01-21-2011, 05:23 PM  # 33 juice_man_86 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jun 2006 Location: Uniontown, PA Posts: 133 
 I just sent my&quot;Hawks&quot;racing crank to the machine shop yesterday. We&apos;ll see how it turns out. part number dg3-302a. Turns out it&apos;s an RPM crank. They just put there sticker right over RPM&apos;s, lol. It&apos;s for a 331, hopefully internally balnced. Supposed to be...   
 
 01-21-2011, 09:47 PM  # 34 strokeme Authorized corral.net Advertiser 
 Trader Feedback: ( 13 )  
 Join Date: Nov 2006 Location: Chicago IL Posts: 6,714 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by juice_man_86 I just sent my&quot;Hawks&quot;racing crank to the machine shop yesterday. We&apos;ll see how it turns out. part number dg3-302a. Turns out it&apos;s an RPM crank. They just put there sticker right over RPM&apos;s, lol. It&apos;s for a 331, hopefully internally balnced. Supposed to be... 
 Thats not an internal crank, its a 28oz crank and will cost a small fortune to go internal __________________
Yes I am&quot;Woody&quot;, Yes I am the Owner. 110% QUALITY Driven!
630-462-3978 Shop Direct
877-723-5487 Shop Toll-Free

TONS of Build Photos Ck at Facebook 
 
Make sure to sign up for SBFBuilding.com The single most exciting thing to happen to the small block ford community in a LONG TIME. 
 

   
 
 02-25-2011, 06:22 PM  # 35 juice_man_86 Registered User  
 
 Trader Feedback: ( 2 )  
 Join Date: Jun 2006 Location: Uniontown, PA Posts: 133 
 You were correct on both. I called The Mustang Depot...it&apos;s been 2 years since my purchase. They were able to reference my receipt number. I sent the crank back to them, and they are sending me DG-302AI. No questions asked...no restocking fee...no shipping charges. They said it was their mistake, so they would take care of it.   
 
 Remove Advertisements Sponsored Links Corral.net Advertisement  
 
 
 


 Bookmarks 
 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are On Pingbacks are On Refbacks are On Forum Rules 
 
 
 

 
 
Support the Corral! Click Here:
 All times are GMT -4. The time now is 08:19 PM . 
 

 
 
 
 Contact Us Ford Mustang Forums : Corral.net Mustang Forum Archive Privacy Statement Top 
 

 Powered by vBulletin®Copyright©2000 - 2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
Search Engine Friendly URLs by vBSEO 3.5.2 ©2010-2011 Corral.net 
 Terms of Use 
 
 LinkBack LinkBack URL About LinkBacks Bookmark&amp;Share Digg this Thread! Add Thread to del.icio.us Bookmark in Technorati Tweet this Thread! 
 
 Garage Plus vBulletin Plugins by Drive Thru Online, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
