<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008625" url="http://www.agrsveml.com/category/xsjado/" time="2012-07-13-02:04" support="3" score="0.002349837001019456" bingtitle="Xsjado - Aggressive Skates, Aggressive skate news, aggressive ..." webtitle="Xsjado">
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>... side of a Burger King receipt. Which, by the way was just recently voted the worst fast food restaurant on the MF’n planet. Don’t take my ... served with the P.Diddy cups ...</description>
	<body>
		AG + RS + VE + ML 
 
Archive for the‘Xsjado’Category
 «Previous Entries 
 Xsjado Jeff Stockwell 4 edit: With Kyle Notle 
 Friday, December 9th, 2011 
 

Speaking of running around with a Glidecam…

You like the Xsjado Jeff Stockwell skates? Kyle Nolte likes Xsjado Jeff Stockwell skates too! Klye Jr. was out the game for a couple months, mostly due to him relinquishing‘the family pants’.  He was subsequently locked down by his‘woman’and was fibbing injuries so he didn’t have to skate with us. TISK-TISK. He even went as far to faking a doctors note that was obviously scribbled on the back side of a Burger King receipt. Which, by the way was just recently voted the worst fast food restaurant on the MF’n planet. Don’t take my word for it ask anyone,“Hey, what do you think is the worst fast food restaurant?”It’s like one of those crazy mind melting math games that always ends up kicking you in the ass with the same number - Without fail everyone ALWAYS says Burger King - OH and lol, Paco Ass Dre swore over his terrible onion bomb habit that it was a UK based food chain (dude eats onions like their freaking apples). HAHA! The King? You fool! I know Burger president or Burger democracy would have been a little more obvious, but dude - DO THEY EVEN EAT BURGERS IN THE UK!?!? Do they get served with the P.Diddy cups? Someone please tell me. Anyways, Paco - What made you think the UK? Why not Tonga? Or Monaco? Let me guess,  the Lion King also from the UK? NO. HE WAS NOT. How about Hershey Sundae pies tho? I dunno, but those are still okay in my book.

 

WHAT YOU GOT ON MY PIE, HOMIE?

But I must digress…This post was about Nolte and his new skates. We had a lot of fun making this edit, and Nolte is skating Xsjado’s now for those of you who cannot accept him on another set of blades, I’ve got just the tickey for yall.

 

YEP.
 
Posted in edits , Xsjado , youtube , A BANANA , 2011 | 3 Comments» 
 
 Xsjado JC Rowe Pro Boot 
 Wednesday, November 16th, 2011 
The new Xsjado JC Rowe pro boot is an incredible looking boot with an urban feel to it with its color scheme of various shades of gray, off white and red. The Rowe’s feature the Xsjado double style upper velcro strap and his new Xsjado mid top footwrap/sneaker.

It is available stock as a boot only for $234.00.

 Click here for our full description and large detailed pics. 

Side View
 

Close Up
 

The new JC Rowe mid top footwrap
 

 Click here for our entire selection of Xsjado skates. 
 
Posted in New Products , Xsjado , 2011 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Xsjado Jeff Stockwell 4 Pro Skate 
 Tuesday, November 1st, 2011 
The new Xsjado Jeff Stockwell 4 boot is here with its western styling including stamped leather used for the upper straps. The Stockwell 4 is definitely a good looking Xsjado and should be a favorite among those of you rolling on Xsjados and is nice boot for those of you looking to try Xsjados for the first time.

Make sure to check out Jeff battle Chris Haffey in the newest B.L.A.D.E. edit on Chris’s website www.chris-haffey.com. 

 Click here for more detailed pics and description. $234 Boot Only.

 

Stamped leather straps
 

Back of cuff stamped in gold brand
 

Stockwell 4 footwrap
 

Random crappy bonus photo
 
 Settings: Unknown so get your own settings. 

 Click here to check out our entire selection of Xsjado skates. 
 
Posted in New Products , Xsjado , 2011 | 3 Comments» 
 
 Xsjado Avant 2011 Skate 
 Thursday, April 14th, 2011 
For 2011, Xsjado drops their new Avant Xsjado team skate to get you excited to go out and film with an awesome looking pair of skates. The Avant truly stands out with it’s black upper that runs straight into a blast of all white souls plates and Mook frames.

Click the pics for detailed descriptions and more detailed pics.
 
Xsjado Avant 2011 Complete Skate
 
 
Xsjado Avant 2011 Boot Only
 
 
Xsjado Avant Custom Skates
 

 Click here to check out our entire selection of Xsjado skates. 
 
Posted in Inventory , New Products , Xsjado , 2011 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Xsjado Skeleton 
 Monday, September 27th, 2010 
Xsjado offers their new Skeleton for those of you who prefer to use your own shoes or footwraps and only need a new Xsjado shell.

 Xsjado Skeleton Boot Only ($164.95)
 

 Click here to check out our entire selection of Xsjado Skates. 
 
Posted in New Products , Xsjado , 2010 | No Comments» 
 
 Get Your Xsjado Farmer 4 Skates! 
 Friday, September 24th, 2010 
We just received our shipment of Xsjado Chris Farmer 4 skates in today and Xsjado once again shows that they are committed to making sure all of the details of their skates not only function great but look incredible too.

The Xsjado Farmer 4 pro complete skate features his pro Create Originals frame, his 4×4 pro 57mm 90a wheels and Undercover Royal ABEC 7 bearings.

 Xsjado Chris Farmer 4 Pro Skate
 

 Xsjado Farmer 4 Boot Only
 

 Click here to check out our entire selection of Xsjado skates. 
 
Posted in New Products , Xsjado , 2010 | No Comments» 
 
 New Conference Skate Releases 
 Tuesday, August 24th, 2010 
The Conference is rolling strong with 2 new skate releases for the end of summer, AKA back to school! Make the yearbook by skating your school’s infamous drop rail in one of these new skates.

The Nick Lomax Classic Throne skate has a bunch of art displayed in the mix of colors and USD finally released a skate that comes with Anti-Rockers to begin with, so you can just throw these on out of the box and go roll!
 
USD Nick Lomax Skates
 
 
USD Nick Lomax Boot
 

Xsjado is back with another team skate, this time aptly named the Pioneer for those of you leaping over boundaries in the aggressive skate world.
 
Xsjado Pioneer Complete Skate
 

 Xsjado Pioneer Boot
 
 
Posted in New Products , usd skates , Xsjado , 2010 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Xsjado Damien Wilson II Skates 
 Tuesday, August 17th, 2010 
Xsjado quietly released the Damien Wilson II skates and a lot of skaters are still not aware that these sick new Wilson boots are available now!

It is obvious that Xsjado spent a lot of time in designing the look of the Wilson II’s because these skates look darn good. They even gave the footwraps clear soles to match the clear smoke cuffs.

Bolt on your favorite frames, wheels and bearings and get rolling on some Xsjado’s asap.

 Xsjado Damien Wilson II Boots
 
Wilson II Front
 
Wilson II Footwraps
 

 Click here to view our entire selection of Xsjado aggressive skates. 
 
Posted in New Products , Xsjado , 2010 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Holiday Xsjado time! 
 Wednesday, December 2nd, 2009 
Where do I start? Right here with the Schwabs (only because they came in first).

Once Mindgame phenom Ben Schwab has always had skills. Originally from Ohio (our favorite prank callers home state) and now residing in SOCAL and skating with ?????? I don’t know. Ben’s kind of a mystery dude. Just comes out on tour, makes video sections and kills it. Well Xsjado kind of fits him then. Hides in his Xsjado’s in the shadows. Cool. Well for his pro skate he went with Xsjado’s original theme with it’s earthy undertones and gratuitous use of canvas. Anyways for the first time they come with another brand of freestlye frame. (crazy right?) Plus I didn’t even know Ben Schwab was sponsored by Kizer. Well, they match perfectly and look great (if you like Xsjado).

 

 

Available with Chimera wheels and ABEC 5 bearings for $289.00 HERE NOW !

Last but not least, for super shreder Jeff Stockwell, Xsjado decided to release not one, but two color ways. Primarily sold as boot only but we have a KILLER pro complete with matching GC Featherlite frames for only $299 Right here . If you are a fan of colors or Jeff, you have to pick a pair up. I Demand it!

 

CHECK OUT MORE STOCKWELLS!

 (more…) 
 
Posted in 2007 , Xsjado | No Comments» 
 
 The Mooks be calling me! 
 Friday, August 7th, 2009 
The new Xsjado mooks have arrived just in time to be perfectly matched up with the latest batch of Xsjado Farmer boots and Xsjado Wilson boots . The phone lines are already busy with Mook Mayhem.
 
 

 
BLACK/White Mooks
 

 WHITE/Black Mooks
	</body>
</document>
