<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008143" url="http://www.pirwahostelscusco.com/backpackersperu.html" time="2012-07-13-01:14" support="6" score="0.016850020518884692" bingtitle="Pirwa Backpackers hostel Cusco Colonial::Youth hostels Cusco Peru" webtitle="Pirwa Backpackers hostel Cusco Colonial::Youth hostels Cusco Peru">
			<query id="001240" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>with credit card BOOK NOW by email Free charge BOOK NOW ... FREE Luggage Storage/li&gt; FREE Movie &amp; Game Nights ... In-house Fast Food Restaurant; TV Lounge with Pool Table</description>
	<body>
		Pirwa Hostels Peru:
 Youth Hostels in Peru enjoy cheap budget accommodation, atmosphere and entertainment in the same spot. Idiomas 
 
 Hostels 
Lima 
 
 Hostels 
Arequipa 
 
 Hostels 
Cusco 
 
 Hostels 
Nazca 
 
 Hostels 
Puno 
 
 Hostels 
Machu Picchu 
 
 Hostels 
La Paz 
 
 | Home | | About Us | | Our Hostels | | Recomendations | | Contact Us | | Book now | | Blog | | Events | 
 
BOOK HERE
 City Cusco Machu Picchu Puno Arequipa Nazca Lima La Paz Hostel Date Check-in 
 Nights 1 night 2 nights 3 nights 4 nights 5 nights 6 nights 7 nights 
 
Pirwa Backpackers Hostel Cusco
 
 The Hostel The Rooms Entertainment Live Concerts Our Bar Volunteers The Main Square The History 
 Plaza San francisco #360
Two Block Of The Main Square
+5184244315
info@pirwahostelsperu.com 
 Pirwa Backpackers Hostel Cusco Colonial is centrally located at Plaza San Francisco #360 just
a couple blocks from the Plaza de Armas, Cusco&apos;s city center. The home itself has a fascinating
history dating back to the colonial era: This 16th monument was once the home of Francisco
Pizarro&apos;s niece, the mestizo daughter of his brother and one of the women of Huayna Capac,
who offered her in exchange for not sacking the city. Now it&apos;s a welcoming community for
travelers; here you&apos;ll be within walking distance to all the major attractions, markets, cafes,
restaurants, bars and clubs!

Our Cusco youth hostel has a variety of lounging areas to facilitate socializing and relaxation.
These include two open-air courtyards with ample seating, hammocks, and a barbecue grill that
you&apos;re welcome to use on those sunny Cusco afternoons. In the TV lounge you&apos;ll be able to
challenge your new friends to a pool, ping-pong, or dart match- maybe you can even convince
the winner to spring for drinks at the in-house bar. Those of you who want to experiment with
local cuisine will appreciate the 24hr self-catering kitchen, while on lazy days you can order
pizzas, burgers, or sandwiches from the restaurant. Pirwa Colonial has events throughout the
week- our competitions, parties, and barbecues will ensure that there&apos;s always some fun to be
had!

Start your day with a satisfying breakfast in the balcony overlooking the Plaza and the tower
San Francisco Church next door. You&apos;ll find many sites of interest just a stone&apos;s throw from the
hostel, but if you&apos;d like a little guidance, you can stop by the travel desk and let our staff answer
any of your questions or design tour packages for you.

 Pirwa Colonial provides cheap budget accommodation for guests in dorms designed for 4-12
people or private rooms with double beds and shared or private bathrooms. Regardless of your
room preference, all guests enjoy access to comfortable beds and hot water 24hrs a day. Those
wanting to share their adventures with friends and family back home can use our computer
lab free, or access the internet connection if you&apos;ve brought your own device. There&apos;s no
need to worry about security, as all guests receive keys to special safety lockers for valuables
and documents. If you&apos;re looking for a cheap hostel in Cusco , Peru where you won&apos;t have to
sacrifice comfort for budget prices- you&apos;ve found it!

 Pirwa Backpacker Hostel Colonial Cusco Rooms Room&apos;s Types Rates Private Double Ensuite 
One bed for two people with a private bathroom Rates X Room S./ 90.00 - (Aprox. $ 33.50) Private Double 
One bed for two people Rates X Room S./ 75.00 - (Aprox. $ 28.00) Dorm x 4 Beds 
A room for 4 people with shared bathroom Rates X Person S./ 30.00 - (Aprox. $ 11.00) Dorm x 6 Beds 
A room for 6 people with shared bathroom Rates X Person S./ 30.00 - (Aprox. $ 11.00) Dorm x 8 Beds 
A room for 8 people with shared bathroom Rates X Person S./ 27.00 - (Aprox. $ 10.00) Dorm x 10 Beds 
A room for 10 people with shared bathroom Rates X Person S./ 25.00 - (Aprox. $ 9.50) Dorm x 13 Beds 
A room for 13 people with shared bathroom Rates X Person S./ 22.50 - (Aprox. $ 8.50) BOOK NOW 
with credit card BOOK NOW 
by email
 Free charge BOOK NOW 
by Facebook
 10% discount 
 These rates are per day, in Peruvian Nuevos Soles (S/.) 
 

Pirwa Backpcakers Colonial Events
 
 Our Bar BBQ Movie Pocker Pool and Dart Kitchen 
 
Enjoy cheap budget accommodation , atmosphere and entertainment in the same spot. Pirwa Hostel Backpackers Colonial is your destination! 

Pirwa Hostels Facilities:
 
 Pick-up Service (additional cost) FREE Continental Breakfast FREE Mate de Coca FREE Bed Linens and Towels FREE internet access + FREE Security Lockers FREE Luggage Storage/li&gt; FREE Movie&amp;Game Nights 
 
 24hr Reception 24hr Self-Catering Kitchen Private Bathrooms Available 24hr Hot Water In-house Bar In-house Fast Food Restaurant TV Lounge with Pool Table Medical Service 
 
 Salsa Classes Same-Day Laundry Service Barbecue Area In-house Travel Service Travel informstion comfortable beds Credit Cards Accepted* Colonial House 
 * Visa will be an additional charge of 6% and MasterCard will be an additional charge of 8%

 Pirwa offers other accommodations in Cusco 
 
 Pre-Columbian Art Museum 
 

One of Cusco&apos;s best museums, the MAP occupies a site first used as an Incan
ceremonial court and then as a colonial mansion. Its 450 masterpieces span
from 1250BC-1532AD and were selected from 45,000 objects based on
their level of artistry and the insight they provide into the artistic values and
evolution of ancient Peruvian civilizations like the Inca, Mochica, Nazca, and
Chimu. The collection is organized according to materials, with a gold room,
silver room, seashell room, stone room, etc.
 
 Barrio de San Blas 
 

The narrow and twisting cobblestone streets of San Blas are a bit steep,
but you&apos;ll be rewarded with views of one of Cusco&apos;s most picturesque
neighborhoods and the many art studios, galleries, stores and (on Saturdays)
art fairs that give this part of town its unique personality. Known as the Artists&apos;s
District, San Blas also has several choice restaurants. Here you&apos;ll find Cusco&apos;s
oldest church, built on an Incan Sanctuary consecrated to the Illapa cult(god of lightning).
 
 Remains of Hatunrumiyoc 
 

The Incan wall on the narrow cobblestone street of Hatunrumiyoc formed part
of the palace of Inca Roca. Today, combined with colonial
structures, it forms the Archbishop&apos;s Palace/Art Museum. The stones were
shaped and then fitted together without mortar. Look for the famous
12-angled stone, famous for the perfect union of its sides and corners with the
surrounding stones. This stonework was favored for the residences of the elite
for its strength and aesthetic appeal.
 
 Chinchero 
 

Chinchero Village is worth a visit to witness how it preserves its pre-Columbian
traditions through the centuries. This legendary birthplace of the rainbow (the
Incan deity k&apos;uychi) was once the royal country estate of Túpac Inca Yupanqui.
It&apos;s known for its bright Sunday market where one can find traditional woven
textiles being sold in front of the colonial church, built atop the palace ruins
and decorated with murals inside and out, and a sturdy Inca wall with 12 large
trapezoidal niches.
 

 
 
 HOSTELS IN LIMA: Pirwa Bed&amp;Breakfast Inclan | Pirwa Backpackers Prada HOSTELS IN AREQUIPA: Pirwa Hostel Arequipa HOSTEL IN NAZCA: Pirwa Hostel Nazca HOSTEL IN PUNO: Pirwa Hostel Puno HOSTELS IN CUSCO: Pirwa Backpackers Colonial | Pirwa Posada Del Corregidor | Pirwa Bed&amp;Breakfast Suecia | Pirwa Backpackers San Blas HOSTEL IN MACHU PICCHU: Pirwa Hostel Machu Picchu | Pirwa Bed&amp;Breakfast Machu Picchu HOSTEL IN BOLIVIA: Pirwa Hostel La Paz §Copyright©2007§- Pirwa Hostels Peru - @email
	</body>
</document>
