<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008952" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/06/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349.html" time="2012-07-13-02:22" support="2" score="0.0011403857627357386" bingtitle="Santa Finds Kids Giving Shorter Lists With Recovery Weak" webtitle="Santa Finds Kids Giving Shorter Lists With Recovery Weak">
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>Money for the heating bill. Food or a place to live ... to buy toilet paper because his mother was taking napkins and paper towels from a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 Financial Crisis Warren Buffett Paul Krugman AP 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k Romney -- George, Not Mitt -- Got Standing Ovation At NAACP 1k WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 43k When Did Romney Leave Bain? 18k Romney Campaign Releases New Ad Accusing Obama Of Spreading Lies 11k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Entertainment 
 Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 6k Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 49 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 19 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 World 
 1,000-Year-Old Coins Unearthed At Crusader Battleground 318 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 962 French President Ridiculed For This Photo 217 And The World&apos;s Largest Heroin Consumer Is... 180 French Alps Avalanche Sweeps Climbers To Their Deaths 46 
 Like 55k   Go to World More in World 
 Foreign Affairs World Elections Arab Uprising Afghanistan War Syria Crisis 
 You might also like 
 Travel Politics Business Tech Religion 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 918 Facebook Fires Yoga Teacher For Banning Smartphones In Class 781 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 539 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 213 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 438 Katie Couric&apos;s Photo Shows Up In Unexpected Place 38 WATCH: Greg Gutfeld Freaks Out 2k Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 286 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Green 
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother 366 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 271 A &apos;Snow Monster&apos; In Mount Rainier Creek 552 Young Man Mysteriously Found Dead Inside Tiger Den 84 Waldo Canyon Fire Fully Contained 102 
 Like 104k   Go to Green More in Green 
 Energy Climate Change Animals Green Tech Green Holiday 
 You might also like 
 Politics Food World Science Healthy Living 
 Sports 
 LOOK: Athlete Fashion On ESPY Red Carpet 29 Woman Catches Shark! 394 LOOK: Paulina Gretzky Is At It Again 116 Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Penn State Administration, Joe Paterno Covered Up Jerry Sandusky&apos;s Child Abuse (UPDATED) 5k 
 Like 22k   Go to Sports More in Sports 
 Wimbledon London 2012 Baseball Sports Crime The Schultz Report 
 You might also like 
 TV Food Entertainment Comedy Detroit 
 Science 
 WATCH: Snake Venom Does Terrifying Thing To Human Blood 285 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 271 Was Famous Physicist Snubbed Over Higgs Find? 707 WATCH: Virgin Galactic Makes Huge Announcement 112 Strange Sounds Of Auroras Explained In New Study 80 
 Like 17k   Go to Science More in Science 
 Space Brain Earth Talk Nerdy To Me Weird Science 
 You might also like 
 Tech Green Arts Religion Weird News 
 Culture 
 There Is Something Wrong With This Rock 214 50 YEARS 102 Bollywood Action Hero Dies At 84 34 10 Movies To Watch At Comic-Con 2012 28 Guess Who&apos;s Playing Janis Joplin? 660 
 Like 14k   Go to Culture More in Culture 
 Arts Books TV 
 You might also like 
 Black Voices Latino Voices Gay Voices Comedy Impact Education Religion 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 
 TechCrunch Autoblog 
 Business 
 Small Business Money The Watchdog Occupy Wall Street 
 
 
Santa Finds Kids Giving Shorter Lists With Recovery Weak
 
 MARTHA WAGGONER   12/ 6/11 04:43 PM ET   Associated Press 
 React Inspiring
 Greedy
 Typical
 Scary
 Outrageous
 Amazing
 Innovative
 Infuriating
 Read more Christmas Economy , Santa Economy , Santa Recession , Children Economy Santa , Children Santa , Christmas Recession , Santa 2011 , Santa Unemployment , Business News 
share this story
 Get Business Alerts Sign Up Submit this story digg reddit stumble 
RALEIGH, N.C.—A job for their mom or dad. Money for the heating bill. Food or a place to live. Maybe gloves or boots.

More and more, Santas say the children on their laps are asking for less for themselves–and Santa is promising less as well.

With unemployment stubbornly high, more homes in foreclosure and the economic outlook dim, many children who visit Santa are all too aware of the struggle to make ends meet.

&quot;These children understand the conditions around the home when they ask for stuff,&quot; said Richard Holden, a 69-year-old Santa from Gastonia, N.C. &quot;They understand when there are other children in the family, they need to be cautious or thoughtful of them as well and not ask for 10 to 12 items.&quot;

Cliff Snider, who&apos;s been playing Santa since he was a teenager, agrees.

&quot;I think the parents are saying, `It&apos;s an economic thing. Just list two to three things you really want to have,&apos;&quot; he said. &quot;Parents are trying to encourage the children to be thrifty.&quot;

And the 64-year-old Snider does his best to help out. When he gets a big-ticket request, he typically responds: &quot;There&apos;s an awful lot of children asking for that this year. What else do you want?&quot;

At the Charles W. Howard Santa Claus School, Santas learn lines like, &quot;Wow, that&apos;s a big gift. Is there anything else you might like?&quot;

These days, though, Santas are having to use it less and less.
 
&quot;I think it&apos;s becoming more popular not to have that long list,&quot; said Tom Valent, dean of the Howard Santa school in Midland, Mich., which gets more than 3,000 letters to Santa a year and just graduated its 75th class. &quot;Families are teaching their children to be as much of a giver as a receiver.&quot;

Starlight Fonseca has been teaching her five children, ages 5 to 14, &quot;that we&apos;re not the only ones who have to cut things back. We&apos;re not the only ones struggling.&quot;

The 31-year-old mother and her husband Jose had been relying on a stipend from the University of Texas law school that Fonseca lost when an illness made it impossible for her to keep her grades up. She&apos;d hoped to graduate in May but was unable to attend school this semester and can&apos;t get student loans due to poor credit.

Fonseca tells her kids that &quot;to make it fair for everyone, Santa has to cut back for everyone. ... We paint it in a way that Santa is doing the best he can to make everybody happy at Christmas.&quot;

It&apos;s especially hard for the oldest children.

&quot;They were two little kids who used to be excited about Christmas, and now they know every gift under the tree should have gone to the utility company,&quot; she said. &quot;It shouldn&apos;t be that way, but that&apos;s where we are now.&quot;

Of course, Santas still see some kids like the 9-year-old who pulled out a BlackBerry and showed Snider photos of all the things he wanted. &quot;It cracked me up,&quot; he said.

Holden&apos;s response to a long list is to say something like, &quot;Why don&apos;t you narrow this down just a little bit and choose two or three items you would really like?&quot; Sometimes he&apos;ll even mention prices, and say, &quot;With things like they are, Santa Claus will do what he can to help you get what you like. But we can&apos;t make you any promises.&quot;

Tim Connaghan, who runs the International University for Santa Claus in Riverside, Calif., conducts an annual survey among the 500 Santas he employs. The economy has become such a big issue that Connaghan asked them for advice on how to handle some of the questions kids were asking about unemployed parents or having to move.

&quot;Let&apos;s all hope your dad will find a new job, or you will get into a new home,&quot; is one recommended response.

&quot;Acknowledge the problem, give them a positive response and say, `Santa loves you, too. Maybe I could get something special for you,&apos;&quot; said Connaghan. &quot;It&apos;s that quick, usually. But the hope is that when the child leaves, he feels a little better.&quot;

Connaghan recalled the night he and other Santas took some needy children shopping. One boy wanted to buy toilet paper because his mother was taking napkins and paper towels from a fast food restaurant for toilet paper.

&quot;He wanted to buy her real toilet paper–a common, everyday item that we all take for granted,&quot; Connaghan said. &quot;And this child is thinking this is a Christmas gift.&quot;

Holden has had children ask for things like heat at home. He&apos;ll tell the child Santa will do what he can, then try to let the parents know about agencies that might help.

One child returned a year later and &quot;said she wanted to thank Santa for getting her some help when they didn&apos;t have food or a place to stay.&quot; Someone had overheard the conversation with Santa and helped the family.

&quot;There&apos;s more to being a Santa Claus than you think there is,&quot; Holden said. &quot;You don&apos;t just go `ho, ho, ho,&apos; pat them on the back of the head and send them on their way. You get involved with them. ... You just make sure they feel loved and they feel special when they leave your lap.&quot;

___

Online:

 http://www.santaclausschool.com/ 

 http://realsantas.com/iusc.htm 

 http://www.lawmommyandthecrazybunch.com 

___

Martha Waggoner can be reached at http://twitter.com/mjwaggonernc 
 FOLLOW 
 HUFFPOST BUSINESS ON Facebook: Like 34k Twitter:   Get Alerts CONTRIBUTE TO THIS STORY 
 Send Corrections Send us a Link Contact us 

 Send a Tip Send Photos/Videos Comment 
 Subscribe to the HuffPost Money newsletter ! 
 Copyright 2012 The Local Paper. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Related News On Huffington Post:   
 Lincoln Chafee, Rhode Island Governor, Stirs Controversy By Erecting &apos;Holiday&apos; Tree In Statehouse California, Nevada Team Up To Prosecute Mortgage Fraud Lucky Supermarket Identity Theft Ring Leads Company To Urge Customers To Close Accounts Americans On Track To Spend Most On Christmas Trees Since Before Recession 
 Lincoln Chafee, Rhode Island Governor, Stirs Controversy By Erecting &apos;Holiday&apos; Tree In Statehouse 

 PROVIDENCE, R.I. -- Rhode Island Gov. Lincoln Chafee unwrapped a Christmas conundrum when he erected a &quot;holiday&quot; tree in the Statehouse, incensing the Roman Catholic... 
 California, Nevada Team Up To Prosecute Mortgage Fraud 

 California and Nevada&apos;s attorneys general are expected to announce Tuesday that they are teaming up to prosecute mortgage fraud in their respective states, according to... 
 Lucky Supermarket Identity Theft Ring Leads Company To Urge Customers To Close Accounts 

 If you&apos;ve shopped at a Bay Area Lucky supermarket in the past few months, you might want to strongly consider closing your bank account--or, at... 
 Americans On Track To Spend Most On Christmas Trees Since Before Recession 

 The sagging economy may have Americans worried, but many aren&apos;t letting that stop them from getting a Christmas tree any longer. Analysts say that Christmas-tree...   Loading... TOP LINKS ON THIS TOPIC 1 of 5 
 Santa Claus Is Coming to Facebook to Infect Your Computer With Koobface [ALERT] 
 
 Twitter Secret Santa | Sign Up! 
 
 Santa Monica Nativity Scenes Replaced by Atheists - NYTimes.com 
 
 Twitter Users That Bring Christmas Cheer | Bit Rebels 
 
 What Is Santa&apos;s Carbon Footprint? [Infographic] : TreeHugger 
 
 Hippo Madness | TELUS 
 
 http://espn.go.com/nfl/story/_/id/7310317/san-francisco-49ers-santa-clara-secure-funding-stadium 
 
 What is Santa&apos;s carbon footprint? [infographic] - Holy Kaw! 
 
 Santa FAILS (VIDEO) 
 
 Sarah Khan: Santa Claus Is Coming to Town... NOT 
 
 G1 - Golfinho albino é encontrado pela primeira vez em Santa Catarina - notícias em Brasil 
 
 Santa Clara County supervisors to consider $1.35 million in vouchers to house 100 chronically homeless - San Jose Mercury News 
 
 A year without a Santa Claus | USPS carrier not allowed to deliver while wearing Santa suit - Bellevue Reporter 
 
 Santa Claus Killer Was Estranged Husband and Father - ABC News 
 
 Santa gets cutting edge with Siri [video] - Holy Kaw! 
 Around the Web: 

 Santa finds kids giving shorter lists in recession 

 Don&apos;t You Dare Tell Me Santa Claus Doesn&apos;t Exist -- &apos;Tis the Season to Believe! 

 Santa comes to Hampshire 

 Macy&apos;s Santa tour delivers toys to patients at DMC Children&apos;s Hospital of Michigan 

 Crucified skeleton Santa sparks controversy in Loudoun 

 Stolen Santa Returned With Money Back 

 Santa Visits North Texas at Mrs Baird&apos;s Fort Worth Bakery 

 Filed by Maxwell Strachan  |  
 More in Business... 

 New Evidence Michael Marin, Ex-Wall Street Trader... Paul Krugman Slams New York Times Colleague,... Aubrey Lee Price, Missing Georgia Bank Director,... Libor Scandal Could Turn &apos;Ugly&apos; As U.S....     
 Comments 34 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 Comments are closed for this entry Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   Next ›   Last »  (2 total) Crystal8080 0 Fans 07:58 PM on 12/07/2011 Why should kids have to get a job? Why should we blame children for a white lie that parents have been telling their children for ages - that there is this magical being who will slide down the chimney on Christmas morning and leave them presents that they have been asked to write down on a wish list weeks and months before? This seems a little unfair to me. Children are hardly to blame for the economy, rather they are the helpless victims. Parents can still keep the magic of Christmas and Santa alive. It&apos;s just a matter of getting creative and possibly instilling new values into the whole tradition of holiday giving. It might also mean being blatantly honest with kids - breaking the news that there is no Santa. My youngest figured out several years ago that Santa is really Mom. Now he insists on calling me Santa! He loves it! There are so many other ways to celebrate the holidays and get kids involved (and smiling). But again, it will require effort and creativity. And if you just cannot let go of the magic of Santa, I just discovered you can visit his social media profile online here http://bizabacus.com/santa. Crystal8080: Why should kids have to get a job? Why should http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Crystal8080/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122265875.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 troyscreename90 0 Fans 02:49 PM on 12/07/2011 even the kids knowits hard times
vizunmark.deco-shirs.com troyscreename90: even the kids knowits hard times vizunmark.deco-shirs.com http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/troyscreename90/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122204202.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 fortressfountain 510 Fans 10:56 AM on 12/07/2011 &quot;You cannot always get what you want.&quot; Unless you are the banks and corporations. fortressfountain:&quot;You cannot always get what you want.&quot;Unless you are http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/fortressfountain/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122151297.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program AZreb equal-opportunity Independent heathen 1277 Fans 10:49 AM on 12/07/2011 These children are learning a hard lesson that hopefully will stay with them as they become adults. You can&apos;t always get what you want - situations occur that make life difficult. Oldsters like me learned that during the Depression and it stuck with most of us. The recurring saying then was &quot;Make do or do without&quot; and that is happening in many families today. AZreb: These children are learning a hard lesson that hopefully will http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/AZreb/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122150023.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER trekie70 Lifelong bibliophile and political junkie 191 Fans 08:32 PM on 12/06/2011 &quot;In economic news, North Pole Inc. is reporting a larger than expected drop in demand this year, warning if it continues, layoffs may be necessary. A representative for Elf Union Local #1 stated that the union is committed to fighting any demand for layoffs.&quot; trekie70:&quot;In economic news, North Pole Inc. is reporting a larger http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/trekie70/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122051790.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 mutopis 224 Fans 08:25 PM on 12/06/2011 Meanwhile Wall Street&apos;s demand lists get bigger. No really, consumer luxury is at all time high... mutopis: Meanwhile Wall Street&apos;s demand lists get bigger. No really, consumer http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/mutopis/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122050280.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 JohnMavis41 63 Fans 08:06 PM on 12/06/2011 This is so sad.
One kid had only one item on the list &quot;World Peace&quot; --- JohnMavis41: This is so sad. One kid had only one item http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/JohnMavis41/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122046701.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER Aaron Peeples What I say won&apos;t change the world 395 Fans   07:35 PM on 12/06/2011 Some of us older kids aren&apos;t even bothering with a list. This year, a good-sized dinner will be enough of a gift. Aaron_Peeples: Some of us older kids aren&apos;t even bothering with a http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Aaron_Peeples/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122040454.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 MRb1000 210 Fans 07:26 PM on 12/06/2011 They understand if you are not rich you cannot get what you want! Kids are on the internet just like their parents. They are more intone than we were growing up! MRb1000: They understand if you are not rich you cannot get http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/MRb1000/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122038552.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER nikolasoddfellow Well la de freakin da !!! 159 Fans   07:22 PM on 12/06/2011 Christmas is not a huge &quot;gimmie gimmie&quot; holiday for my son. He gets a few gifts but I never go overboard. I want him to grow up remembering Christmas as our holiday and not a products or corporations holiday. He is 12 now and he looks forward more to our traditions of being with family and friends more than the gifts. He is not a spoiled little brat like some of the ones that I see here and there not asking for but demanding something. nikolasoddfellow: Christmas is not a huge&quot;gimmie gimmie&quot;holiday for my http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/nikolasoddfellow/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122037762.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER jimstaro 1260 Fans   06:37 PM on 12/06/2011 For you adults? that think kids don&apos;t get it, by the way they&apos;re learning by everything around them even that fox blasting on your tv, many are much more aware then many adults, just look around!! jimstaro: For you adults? that think kids don&apos;t get it, by http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/jimstaro/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122027975.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been removed. History  | Permalink  | Show replies(1) HUFFPOST SUPER USER jimstaro 1260 Fans   06:38 PM on 12/06/2011 You&apos;re one that refused to grow up from infancy!!! jimstaro: You&apos;re one that refused to grow up from infancy!!! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/jimstaro/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122028223.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program Pagoas Imagine no religion... it&apos;s easy if you try. 274 Fans 05:52 PM on 12/06/2011 sorry kiddies, santa claus, like an honest republican, is just make-believe that grown-ups try to make you believe in when you&apos;re young and gullible to get your hopes up and make you behave. Pagoas: sorry kiddies, santa claus, like an honest republican, is just http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Pagoas/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122017673.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 webwzrd Reality is liberal indoctrina­tion. 1789 Fans 05:36 PM on 12/06/2011 The first generation of Americans who can expect to do worse than their parents. Thanks again, Republicans. You are killing Christmas. WWJD? webwzrd: The first generation of Americans who can expect to do http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/webwzrd/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122013748.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 ciskokid 283 Fans 05:12 PM on 12/06/2011 Writing is kinda strange for kids these days. ciskokid: Writing is kinda strange for kids these days. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/ciskokid/santa-finds-kids-giving-s_n_1132349_122007840.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Page:  1   2   Next ›   Last »  (2 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost AjyQ%2F%2BQ7dbO8TqWbrG8N9umpY2bkGd%2BAkVt%2FcONaMmCuFEMJ4aU5GioLBae9WKriZ00nV3bSoYfycPzBAHC15KmaaTdvQ5ik wTnsJaY2LMrstGQtAXaU88huBEWUuXZ775BI17t2y%2Bl5vYbbTOyc0jCdaB3OukQSahxdgotOnJCGsI9SkmoR8LW8fD%2Bb05de 1 of 2 World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 
 Like 10k WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 
 Like 7k &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 
 Like 5k Photos Of Kardashian Baby Are A Hard Sell 
 Like 98 Penn State Administration, Joe Paterno Covered Up Jerry Sandusky&apos;s Child Abuse (UPDATED) 
 Recommend 2k Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 
 Like 948 Kim Kardashian Tweets Yet Another Bikini Pic 
 Like 50 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 
 Like 1k Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 
 Like 1k Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of AOL Money&amp;Finance 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
