<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008244" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/the-cheesecake-factory-cleveland-363075" time="2012-07-13-01:44" support="1" score="0.0005013750358648413" bingtitle="The Cheesecake Factory - Reviews &amp; Menu - Cleveland 44124" webtitle="The Cheesecake Factory - Reviews&amp;Menu - Cleveland 44124">
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="110"/>
	<description>... is a American (New), Traditional, and Fast Food restaurant where ... Large and varied menu selection. entree seemed like an ... The bill was $44.07 and I left an $8 dollar tip.</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 The Cheesecake Factory Menu 

 The Cheesecake Factory Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Cleveland Restaurants » American (New) » The Cheesecake Factory Share | 
The Cheesecake Factory
 
 3.25 star rating           
  3.2 rating over 4 reviews 
 (216) 691-3387 

 24265 Cedar Rd ( ) 

 Cleveland , OH 44124-3700 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (4) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  The Cheesecake Factory is a American (New) , Grill , and Pub Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a family meal , paid between $25 and $50 , and tipped more than 18% . Tags: American (New), Grill, Pub Food, Salads, Sandwiches, Good For Kids, Takeout, Good for groups, Burgers, and Pizza Stats: 
 957 dishes entered by diners at The Cheesecake Factory 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own The Cheesecake Factory? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for The Cheesecake Factory
 Write a review 
 4 reviews First reviewed by justmyopinion 
 
&quot;Hot Cars and Great Food.&quot;

 0 helpful votes over 8 reviews 
 justmyopinion 
 8 Restaurant Reviews 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 The Cheesecake Factory justmyopinion 
 January 15, 2012 
 2.0 
 2.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Seared (AHI style) Tuna Salad Entree... disappointed
 
Large and varied menu selection.

entree seemed like an appetizer portion at best.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Seared Tuna Tataki Salad
 
 2.0 star rating           
 
Slight fishy odor.

2-3 ounces of seared tuna! five small slices?
(2 ounces is probably overgenerous estimation of the portion size)

1 and a half to two ounces of mixed greens (seriously?) yes seriously. it was not even a handfull!

3 (three) slices of tomatoe!

a quarter (1/4) of an avacado (that someone has no clue on how to prep for presentation).

for $16.50…I’ve had appetizers at (that australian bar b) steakhouse of seared Ahi Tuna for around $10.00 that was more filling than this entree.

I mentioned this to the server, after the dinner that the size of the salad was shockingly small, but also told her not to worry about it at this point. It was not the servers fault and I did ask her to tell her management later that I was surprised at the size of the entree.

The wifes chopped salad was huge. I felt taken advantage of.

I tried to eat somewhat healthy and left starved.

The bill was $44.07 and I left an $8 dollar tip.

The value proposition just didn’t seem fair to me, even the day after.

We arrived at 5:30 on a saturday, early enough to avoid the evening crowd, it should have been so much more than it was.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply cassaendra 
 from Citysearch 
 
March 21, 2006
 
 5 star rating           
 
More than just cheesecake
 
Depending on where you sit, the atmosphere can be fairly private to noisy. The hues and fixtures create a lush feel, almost to the point of decadence. 

We&apos;ve eaten here at least 10 times, with only one negative incident. Having waited ~40…

 read full review» 
 powder_angel 
 from Citysearch 
 
November 4, 2005
 
 5 star rating           
 
Gorgeous!
 
This was my first experience at The Cheesecake Factory after hearing lots about it, not sure what to expect. HUGE menu, excellent food, a little pricey but something for everyone. We were seated immediately. Portion sizes were adequate.…

 read full review» 
 diva216 
 from Citysearch 
 
October 17, 2004
 
 3 star rating           
 
All Hype, Very Expensive
 
The restaurant policy is no reservations. We waited over TWO HOURS to be seated. There was no where to sit while waiting. Most of us stood the entire time. Simply ridiculous.

We finally got to our table, and the waitress was wonderful.…

 read full review» 
 Read 3 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at The Cheesecake Factory

These dishes from the The Cheesecake Factory menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Stuffed Chicken Tortillas
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Fresh Banana Cream Cheesecake ( $6.50 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Pasta Da Vinci
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Jazzercise Brecksville Community Center Pearle Vision AT&amp;T;Mobility Larry I Madorsky&amp;Assoc Co LensCrafters Cedar Green Wine&amp;Cheese Nicholas Jewelers Inc 
 1 review 1.0 star Michael&apos;s Beauty Salon Pollack Studio Agin Earl R&amp;Associates, Inc. 
 The Cheesecake Factory is located near the cities of Tremont, Newburgh Heights, Brooklyn Centre, Brooklyn Heights, and Bratenahl. People found this by searching for: Chessecake Factory Phone Number On Cedar Road, Cheesecake Factory Seared Tuna Salad, Cheesecake Factory Cedar Road, Cheesecake Factory Cedar Rd, Cedar Road Cheesecake, Cleveland Cheesecake Factory Menu, and Italian Cheesecake Cleveland. 
Featured in Cleveland
 
 3.85714 star rating           
 Dina&apos;s Pizza&amp;Pub 
 4.66667 star rating           
 China Jade Restaurant 
 4.83333 star rating           
 Master Pizza 
 5.0 star rating           
 Lydia&apos;s Hungarian Strudel Shop 
 5.0 star rating           
 Pizzazz Pizza 
 5.0 star rating           
 Pizzazz Pizza&amp;Dining Room 
 5.0 star rating           
 Athens Pizzeria 
 5.0 star rating           
 Sirius Pizza 
 5.0 star rating           
 Don Ramon 
 5.0 star rating           
 Marsella&apos;s Pizza 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 31 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Chipotle Mexican Grill Brio Tuscan Grille Tropical Smoothie Cafe Atria&apos;s Bar Louie 
Link to The Cheesecake Factory
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Reviews on TripAdvisor 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
