<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008912" url="http://www.journalstandard.com/news/x313654506/A-new-place-to-eat-in-town-SONIC-plans-a-fast-food-restaurant-at-Freeport-location" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="15" score="0.05443568440089343" bingtitle="A new place to eat in town: SONIC plans a fast-food restaurant at ..." webtitle="A new place to eat in town: SONIC plans a fast-food restaurant at Freeport location - Freeport, IL - The Journal-Standard">
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>... plans to construct a new fast-food restaurant in ... A new place to eat in town: SONIC plans a fast-food restaurant at Freeport location ... chain specializes in made-to-order ...</description>
	<body>
		Search our print archives» 
 Jobs 
 Classifieds 
 Cars 
 E-Edition 
 Local Ads 
 Homes 
 Homepage News Lifestyle Health Business Sports Opinions Blogs Obituaries Photos Video Local Loop 
 
 Facebook Twitter Online Forms Coupons Text Alerts Mobile 

 Business Education Police and Fire State News 

 Celebrations Lifestyle Columns Community Entertainment Faith Food Home&amp;Garden Heroes Branded Content 

 Health Columns Health Events&amp;Services 

 Prep&amp;Local College National Sports Columns Pretzels NUIC Sports Blog Cubs White Sox Bears NFL Blackhawks 

 Editorials Letters to the Editor Guest Columns Blogs Columnists 

 Memorials 

 Purchase Photos 
 Hot Links: Election 2012 
A new place to eat in town: SONIC plans a fast-food restaurant at Freeport location
 Zoom 
Photos
 
SONIC&apos;s logo.
   
Yellow Pages
 Find whatever you&apos;re looking for
with Totally Local Yellow Pages Search provided by local.com Featured Business» 
 Freeport Apartments Freeport Attorneys Freeport Auto Dealers Freeport Auto Parts Freeport Auto Repair Freeport Beauty Salons Freeport Car Rental Freeport Dentists Freeport Doctors Freeport Flowers Freeport Hotels Freeport Insurance Freeport Loans Freeport Mortgages Freeport Movers Freeport Pizza Freeport Realtors Freeport Restaurants Freeport Storage Freeport Tax Preparation Freeport Travel 
 By Eric Petermann The Journal-Standard Posted May 22, 2009 @ 08:45 PM Last update May 23, 2009 @ 03:15 PM 
 
 
Business News
 
 The Digital Skeptic: Are Bieber&apos;s Bagels Next? Nielson Takes Consumer Break From TV Programming 10 London Summer Olympics Brands You Can&apos;t Escape 
 Freeport, Ill.— 
A national economy that has effectively stopped real estate development will not deter plans to construct a new fast-food restaurant in Freeport.


SONIC, America’s Drive-In, will locate on South West Avenue, on an outlot at the Southgate Market, directly west of China Buffet restaurant at 1797 S. West Avenue.


The development is being planned by Mason, Harrison, Ratliff, LLC, a franchise-holding company based in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. With ownership in 272 locations and annual revenues of $354 million, Mason, Harrison, Ratliff is the country’s sixth largest restaurant franchisee. In the past four years it has added 28 units and $81 million in revenue. It recently worked out a deal to open Sonic stores in Indiana, Illinois, and Wisconsin.


SONIC started as a hamburger and root beer stand in 1953 in Shawnee, Okla., and was called Top Hat Drive-In, It changed its name to SONIC in 1959. The first drive-in to adopt the SONIC name is still serving customers in Stillwater, Okla. As the nation’s largest chain of drive-in restaurants, SONIC has 3,500 drive-ins coast to coast. More than a million customers eat at SONIC every day; and with more drink combinations than any other quick-service restaurant—more than 168,000—SONIC sells itself as the“Ultimate Drink Stop.”


The restaurant chain specializes in made-to-order fast food, and is known for its specialty menu items and personal carhop service. SONIC restaurants offer a full menu all day, giving guests the option of eating breakfast for dinner. Favorites include TOASTER®Sandwiches (sandwiches served on thick Texas Toast), Extra-Long Cheese Coneys (hot dogs with chili and cheese), fresh-made onion rings, Tater Tots and a variety of frozen treats.


Reeder Ratliff, a spokesman for Mason, Harrison and Ratliff, said construction of the restaurant is being scheduled and once ground is broken, SONIC will open for business before Labor Day. Currently the company is constructing a new SONIC in Belvidere.

 

Also online: SONIC&apos;S web site 
 
A national economy that has effectively stopped real estate development will not deter plans to construct a new fast-food restaurant in Freeport.


SONIC, America’s Drive-In, will locate on South West Avenue, on an outlot at the Southgate Market, directly west of China Buffet restaurant at 1797 S. West Avenue.


The development is being planned by Mason, Harrison, Ratliff, LLC, a franchise-holding company based in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. With ownership in 272 locations and annual revenues of $354 million, Mason, Harrison, Ratliff is the country’s sixth largest restaurant franchisee. In the past four years it has added 28 units and $81 million in revenue. It recently worked out a deal to open Sonic stores in Indiana, Illinois, and Wisconsin.


SONIC started as a hamburger and root beer stand in 1953 in Shawnee, Okla., and was called Top Hat Drive-In, It changed its name to SONIC in 1959. The first drive-in to adopt the SONIC name is still serving customers in Stillwater, Okla. As the nation’s largest chain of drive-in restaurants, SONIC has 3,500 drive-ins coast to coast. More than a million customers eat at SONIC every day; and with more drink combinations than any other quick-service restaurant—more than 168,000—SONIC sells itself as the“Ultimate Drink Stop.”


The restaurant chain specializes in made-to-order fast food, and is known for its specialty menu items and personal carhop service. SONIC restaurants offer a full menu all day, giving guests the option of eating breakfast for dinner. Favorites include TOASTER®Sandwiches (sandwiches served on thick Texas Toast), Extra-Long Cheese Coneys (hot dogs with chili and cheese), fresh-made onion rings, Tater Tots and a variety of frozen treats.


Reeder Ratliff, a spokesman for Mason, Harrison and Ratliff, said construction of the restaurant is being scheduled and once ground is broken, SONIC will open for business before Labor Day. Currently the company is constructing a new SONIC in Belvidere.

 

Also online: SONIC&apos;S web site 
 Copyright 2009 The Journal-Standard. Some rights reserved 
Popular Videos
 Mich. Woman: I Lived With Corpse, Watched NASCAR SUV Winds Up on Boat Obama reflects on his biggest mistake as president Inquiry: Penn St. Officials Concealed Sex Abuse Kim K. Shares Racy, Unretouched Pic Shark Steals Woman&apos;s Catch Loading commenting interface... Comments Thank you for the abuse report. We will review the report and take appropriate action. Loading comments... Site Services • Purchase Photos • Subscribe • E-Edition • Contact Us • Gas Prices • Submit News Market Place • Classifieds • Find Freeport jobs • Autos • Rentals • Coupons Community Info • City of Freeport • Stephenson County • Carroll County • Ogle County • Jo Daviess County Sports • iHigh • IHSA • HighSchoolSports.net Lifestyle • Health • Home&amp;Garden • Food • Faith Sister Publication • Rockford Register Star 
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | About our Ads 

The Journal-Standard |
 27 S. State Ave. Freeport, IL 61032

Copyright©2006-2012 GateHouse Media, Inc. Some Rights Reserved.

Original content available for non-commercial use under a Creative Commons license, except where noted.
 RadarFrog Merchant Directory | Internet Marketing by Propel Marketing | RadarFrog
	</body>
</document>
