<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008043" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?McDonalds-Nutrition:-New-Menu-Offers-Healthy-Lifestyle-Choices&amp;id=5846008" time="2012-07-13-01:06" support="1" score="0.0026771032656742982" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices" webtitle="McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices">
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>... have to feel bad about venturing into a fast food restaurant ... McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: See the Change in Their Menu, It Is for ... 02, 2011. Viewed 172 times. Word count: 434.</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Food and Drink » Restaurant Reviews Reggie Lee 
 Platinum Author |   15 Articles 
 Joined: May 28, 2008 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices

 By Reggie Lee 
 
With more and more people living a healthier lifestyle the McDonald&apos;s nutrition menu now offers healthier choices for you to pick from. Some of the major changes they have made over the past couple years is adding a variety of garden salads, yogurts with granola in fresh fruits. They have also gone on to change the type of oils they use in the deep fryers and change their grade of beef to that which has a lower fat content.

All of this is to attract the new healthier lifestyle consumer who possibly is never even eaten at a McDonald&apos;s restaurant before. You no longer have to feel bad about venturing into a fast food restaurant because with a healthier food choices you can leave feeling good about yourself for eating one of the healthy salads.

On the side of the wall usually adjacent to the cash registers you will see a nutrition placard which lists all of the nutritional values of every item on the menu. You be able to see the total calories and grams of fat, carbohydrates and fat in each of the food choices. This is a good tool to use to assist you in picking the proper menu item for your dietary needs.

All of their French fries, onion rings and apple pies I now deep-fried in oil which has a dramatically reduced trans fat content. This translates in a healthier you by eating this as the oil actually promotes healthy organs inside of you.

All of these changes allow you to teach your children great lessons in eating because you can let them know that they can now eat at their favorite fast food restaurants but still enjoy a healthy menu. Again, no longer do you have to be worried about eating at a fast food burger joint in getting a bad name for yourself as a parent who feed their child fat laden food. Now you can feed your children salads and yogurt and still allow them to play around on the fantastic inside playground that they&apos;ll enjoy.

Think about the great family times you can have with your spouse and children while eating a healthy meal and watching your children swimming around in the colorful plastic balls, swinging on the place that and sliding down the swooping sliding board. These are great times that your children will remember for their whole life not to mention the great nutritional advice you past the long which will not only let them know what is the best thing to eat but also prolong their life by living a healthier lifestyle.
 
For more information, go to McDonald&apos;s nutrition [http://www.mcdonaldscoupons.biz/]
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Reggie_Lee 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Food and Drink: Restaurant-Reviews 
 Reggie Lee 
 Email Address: Subscribe Restaurant Reviews Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 McDonalds Nutrition Best Choice Awards McDonalds Nutrition Facts For Health What a McDonalds Nutrition Guide Does Not Say What Products Are the Healthiest at McDonalds? McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: Healthier Food Choices for A Healthier You McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: Healthier Cheeseburgers for A Healthier You The McDonalds Campaign for &quot;Good Nutrition&quot; - Hit or Miss? McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: See the Change in Their Menu, It Is for Real! McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: Try Our Great Salads, Yogurt and More Information On The Nutritional Items A McDonald&apos;s Menu Offers 
 
Recent Articles

 Riddle and Finns: Definitely the Best Seafood Restaurant in Town Red Restaurant - Huntington, NY How Brooklyn Chef Brings Raw Foods to Life Chance - One Of The Hottest Restaurants In Brooklyn Offers Flavor Visiting a Korean Restaurant and Other Attractions Hagemeister Park Restaurant Review in Green Bay, WI St. Brendan&apos;s Restaurant Review in Green Bay, WI Ogan Restaurant Review in Green Bay, WI When It&apos;s Time To Have Some Fun In London, Book Bars In Clapham And Covent Garden Opening a Fine Dining Restaurant 
 
Submitted On February 02, 2011. Viewed 178 times. Word count: 434.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Lee, Reggie &quot;McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices.&quot; McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices .
 2 Feb. 2011 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?McDonalds-­Nutrition:-­New-­Menu-­Offers-­Healthy-­Lifestyle-­Choices&amp;id=5846008 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Lee, R. (2011, February 2). McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?McDonalds-­Nutrition:-­New-­Menu-­Offers-­Healthy-­Lifestyle-­Choices&amp;id=5846008 Chicago Style Citation: 
Lee, Reggie &quot;McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices.&quot; McDonald&apos;s Nutrition: New Menu Offers Healthy Lifestyle Choices EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?McDonalds-­Nutrition:-­New-­Menu-­Offers-­Healthy-­Lifestyle-­Choices&amp;id=5846008 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
