<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008083" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g293748-d1208396-r50104938-Marrybrown-Dar_es_Salaam.html" time="2012-07-13-01:09" support="10" score="0.020534930959867612" bingtitle="OK fast food - Review of Marrybrown, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania ..." webtitle="OK fast food - Review of Marrybrown, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... the right change and when I asked for a receipt ... Found this nice &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant in Dar-es-Salaam called ... most comprehensive source for airline seats ...</description>
	<body>
		Marrybrown reviews
 
 Home Dar es Salaam 
 Dar es Salaam Tourism Dar es Salaam Hotels Dar es Salaam Vacation Rentals Flights to Dar es Salaam Dar es Salaam Restaurants Things to Do in Dar es Salaam Dar es Salaam Travel Forum Dar es Salaam Photos Dar es Salaam Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Africa &gt; Tanzania &gt; Dar es Salaam &gt; Dar es Salaam Restaurants &gt; Marrybrown 
 
 Back to Marrybrown 
Marrybrown: Restaurant Reviews
 Haile Selasie Road , Dar es Salaam , Tanzania 0776075277 Ranked #50 of 87 restaurants in Dar es Salaam 21 Reviews 3 visitor photos Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
21 reviews from our community
 23% Recommend 
 Excellent 3 Very good 2 Average 8 Poor 7 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 21 reviews sorted by Date Rating nightgardener Banbury, UK Contributor 16 reviews Reviews in 12 cities 7 helpful votes “OK fast food” Reviewed November 26, 2009 
I went to the Marrybrown&apos;s in Mlimani City. It&apos;s a Malaysian chain, but looks exactly like any other fast food chain inside. I can only assume it&apos;s popular here because it&apos;s halal. It was very difficult ordering in English, despite there being huge menus to point to and my order being very simple (e.g.&quot;Menu 2 with Diet Coke, please&quot;). The cashier struggled with giving the right change and when I asked for a receipt she seemed confused. My chicken burger was awful - random bits of disgusting chicken in breadcrumbs. Not quite what I expected! The burgers arrived first and the chips a lot later. My friend ordered a particular type of sauce and got another one. The chips were nice, though. I absolutely don&apos;t have high expectations of fast food chains, but this was just not very good!
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by nightgardener for Dar es Salaam Ask nightgardener about Marrybrown This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. maximus2390 Malaysia Senior Reviewer 10 reviews Reviews in 7 cities 8 helpful votes “Fast Food at Dar-es-Salaam” Reviewed November 13, 2008 1 person found this review helpful 
Found this nice&quot;fast food&quot;restaurant in Dar-es-Salaam called Marrybrown. The place used to be a club house and renovated to be the biggest fast food joint with plenty of parking space.

It has a huge outdoor playground for children. Lots of families with children came to enjoy the facilities especially in the weekends.

The main menu is 2 types of fried chicken. An assortment of sandwiches and side orders. Interestingly it also serves various rice dishes appealing to the Asian market.

Attached to the restaurant is a bakery called &apos;The Loaf&apos;. All breads used at the restaurant is baked fresh daily. Most people come for quick breakfast or to grab fresh bread in the evening time.
 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask maximus2390 about Marrybrown This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. ples72 Dar es Salaam, Tanzania Senior Contributor 21 reviews Reviews in 13 cities 9 helpful votes “Une bonne boulangerie&quot;industrielle&quot;avec un fast food moyen” Reviewed May 21, 2012 

 Visited May 2012 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 4 more reviews by ples72 for Dar es Salaam Ask ples72 about Marrybrown This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 19-21 of 21 reviews « 1 ... 4 5 » 
Travelers who viewed Marrybrown also viewed
 Mamboz Restaurant 36 Reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania Addis in Dar 82 Reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania   Zuane 54 Reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania Nawabi Khana 39 Reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania   All restaurants in Dar es Salaam (87) 
Been to Marrybrown? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?
 
If you own or manage Marrybrown, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.

 Manage your listing 
 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 BEST WESTERN Coral Beach Hotel 73 Reviews Read reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania Dar es Salaam Serena Hotel 113 Reviews Read reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania Southern Sun Dar es Salaam 133 Reviews Read reviews Dar es Salaam, Tanzania 
 All hotels in Dar es Salaam (61) 
Free Dar es Salaam Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Dar es Salaam restaurants

 Addis in Dar Zuane Mamboz Restaurant Osaka Sushi&amp;Teppanyaki restaurant Kilimanjaro Kempinski Oriental Restaurant Alcove Restaurant George&amp;Dragon Karembezi Sea Cliff Village Fish Monger Nawabi Khana Khana Khazana Epi d&apos;or Cafe Chef&apos;s Pride Dulce Cafe Baraza Subway at Shoppers Plaza Masaki The Alcove Alexander&apos;s Restaurant 
 
Hotels around Dar es Salaam

 Doubletree by Hilton Dar es Salaam-Oysterbay 3.5 out of 5, 61 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Transit Motel Airport 3.0 out of 5, 43 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Friendly Gecko 4.5 out of 5, 11 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Tanzanite Executive Suites 4.5 out of 5, 94 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Jangwani Seabreeze Resort 3.5 out of 5, 15 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Hyatt Regency Dar es Salaam, The Kilimanjaro 4.0 out of 5, 137 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 BEST WESTERN Coral Beach Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 73 reviews Last reviewed Jul 6, 2012 Q-Bar&amp;Guest House 3.5 out of 5, 25 reviews Last reviewed Jun 29, 2012 Heritage Motel 3.5 out of 5, 23 reviews Last reviewed Jun 27, 2012 Kipepeo Beach Camp 4.0 out of 5, 4 reviews Last reviewed Jun 19, 2012 White Sands Hotel And Resort 2.5 out of 5, 64 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Mwanzo Park Lodges 4.0 out of 5, 1 review Last reviewed Jun 9, 2012 Atlantis Hotel 4.5 out of 5, 14 reviews Last reviewed Jun 7, 2012 Sleep Inn Hotel 3.0 out of 5, 26 reviews Last reviewed Jun 1, 2012 Hotel Nikko Tower 4.0 out of 5, 4 reviews Last reviewed May 17, 2012 
 Explore the world Hotels 
 The Buttes, A Marriott Resort in Tempe 4.5 out of 5, 436 reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 Hotel Fleur de Lys 4.0 out of 5, 7 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Kapari Natural Resort in Imerovigli 5.0 out of 5, 85 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 
 Travel Destinations 
 Charlestown hotels 6 hotels, 25 Reviews Winona hotels 16 hotels, 305 Reviews El Berron 2 hotels, 4 Reviews Abu Dhabi 107 hotels, 7,288 Reviews Ocean City deals 582 hotels, 12,238 Reviews Asheville deals 242 hotels, 18,218 Reviews 
 Sightseeing 
 Dongquan Onsen of Taishun 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor™ provides traveler reviews of Marrybrown . Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
