<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008228" url="http://sternowski.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-13-01:43" support="1" score="0.0017605284430775624" bingtitle="American Torontoid" webtitle="American Torontoid">
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>... that marvels at the number of times I go to a fast food restaurant. ... so I don’t get the same reading content on my food ... How to Jump Safely from a Moving Train” and exit ...</description>
	<body>
		American Torontoid 
 
 Fat Americans, Canadian Cause and Effect 
 August 2, 2011
 Leave a Comment 
I have a co-worker in Canada that marvels at the number of times I go to a fast food restaurant. Who can blame me? There is a delicious Wendy’s across the street from my office. I don’t go there that often by American standards–maybe once a week or once every two weeks. I still catch a lot of flak for it.

There are a lot of differences between American and Canadian Wendy’s. Yes, there is still a Baconator on the menu. However, there isn’t a delicious Dollar Menu. In the US, I was able to enjoy a Junior Bacon Cheeseburger for $1. Here, there is no such thing as a Junior Bacon Cheeseburger, just a Bacon Cheeseburger, which is twice as big and unhealthy as the sandwich I enjoyed in Atlanta, Georgia. That got me thinking that maybe Canadians have a misperception about American fast food because the Canadian experience has subtle differences. Within a week of this hypothesis, I walked into a McDonald’s and was struck dumbfounded. DUMBFOUNDED, I TELL YOU!

McDonald’s is widely regarded as the quintessential American restaurant. You hear about how McDonald’s preaches consistency worldwide in their restaurants. They buy entire crops of potatoes and entire flocks of cows and entire schools of whatever is used for McRib Sandwiches. This would lead the average Canadian to believe that going into a Canadian McDonald’s is the same as going into an American McDonald’s. It is not. Here is the difference and why Canadians think Americans are fat and lazy due to the amount of fast food they eat.

American menu item:

 

Canadian menu item:

 

I know these pictures aren’t huge, but take a close look. The American sandwich is called a“Big Mac”the Canadian sandwich is called the“DOUBLE BIG MAC’. Yes, that means Canadians can buy two Big Mac’s in one–sort of. Double the meat, cheese, lettuce with the same three pieces of bun and probably extra thousand island dressing. When I first saw the Double Big Mac in Toronto, I immediately called friends and relatives in the US. I asked them to go to McDonald’s as soon as possible to let me know if the Double Big Mac was on the menu. IT IS NOT. (At least not in Iowa, Georgia, Colorado, or Washington.) All these Canadians I work with think that I am scarfing down Double Big Macs two at a time at least three times a week! It suddenly explains a lot.

What is even more strange is the lack of athletics here versus the US. I can’t figure out how Canadian school kids get any exercise. It is a blessing and a curse for Canadians, I suppose. In the US, my high school had a football stadium that held a few thousand people. We also had a track, baseball, and soccer stadium. We had a basketball court with bleachers. We also offered volleyball and some other lame sports. All of this was funded by the wonderful American tax payers. In Canada, the tax money is used to educate students rather than put them in physical competition with one another. Maybe that is why Americans are perceived as dumb but strong. In Canada, there aren’t a bunch of stadiums at every school. In fact, i can’t remember seeing bleachers at ANY school. If there isn’t a school athletic program, how do kids get exercise and stay in shape? One guess is that kids stay in shape by running away from wolves in the snowy month of January. Another guess is that the socialized health system in Canada either pays for free liposuction OR doesn’t waste money on saving obese people’s health resulting in a survival-of-the-fittest situation. Another guess is that the moose in Canada feed on fat, lazy Canadians and leave the healthy ones to perpetuate the species–we all have natural predators.

To support this claim, I have joined a soccer team and a softball team in Canada. Most Canadians I have played with like to call it“baseball”instead of“softball”. How did I get on one of the teams? A friend said they knew me and that I wanted to play.“Is he any good?”“Well, he’s American.”Done deal, I was on the team. I’m sure if it were hockey or competitive ice fishing, I would not have made the team. But since it was a real sport, everyone knew that Americans were not quite as fat and lazy as the stereotype. Is that a contradiction? Anyway, I’m doing my best to dispell the myth of fast food and lazy Americans.

Vigilance.
 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Hot in the City 
 June 3, 2011
 Leave a Comment 
Did you know there are beaches in Florida? For those of you reading that are Canadian or from other non-US locations or from the less educated parts of Arkansas, Florida is in the southeastern US and is a raft trip away from Havana. The coast of Florida is covered with a sand-like substance that goes right into the water, which is pretty salty. What is the source of the salt? We may never know, but I suspect it has something to do with the lack of indoor plumbing available to fish and whales of the entire course of history. (*THAT* is why I don’t like swimming in natural bodies of water.) The beaches in Florida are very nice. People wear skimpy bathing suits, it is hot and you can get a great tan, and there are lots of bars and restaurants lining the beaches. My favorite beach is St. Pete Beach in the Tampa Bay area and I enjoyed going to the Undertow, next to the Don Cesar Hotel. If you are ever in the area, I suggest checking it out.

My co-workers in the Washington DC area frequently talked about vacationing at the“beach”. However, they were not going to Florida.“Were they going all the way to California?”you are likely asking yourself. No, not California.“Were they going to Cancun, Mexico?”Excellent follow-up question, but also incorrect.“Were they going to Australia?”Now you are just being ridiculous–the plane ticket and the inconvenience of international travel make going to the beach in Australia highly impractical–plus they are in the Southern Hemisphere, so beach time in the US is wintertime in Australia. (That reminds me, does anyone else find it odd that the Summer Olympics in Sydney were actually played during the Australian winter? The Olympics are Northern Hemisphere biased.) People from Washington DC go to beaches in DELAWARE. I thought this was a joke. First, I didn’t know there were beaches in Delaware. Second, I didn’t think anyone actually went to Delaware intentionally. I doubt most people even know the capital of Delaware is Wilmington. HA! Trick–the capital is Dover. I am not making that up. There is really a city in this universe that is called Dover outside of the UK and it is the capital of Delaware. Third, I didn’t know that if there really were beaches in Delaware that they would be the sort of thing people would want to visit. It is far colder in Delaware than Florida. It is much more difficult to get a tan there. Evidence: Spring Breakers don’t pack up and head to Delaware in droves–they even prefer the Redneck Riviera (Panama City/Destin, Florida) to Delaware. When your beach is not as good as someplace called“Redneck Riviera”, you know it isn’t any good.

Remarkably, Toronto claims to have“beaches”, no matter hap ridiculous it makes Torontoids sound. There is a large body of mostly saltless water here (Lake Ontario). It is freezing and can get partially covered with icebergs in the winter. Also, winter lasts from October until April (give or take a week). This year it snowed twice in April. There is sand next to the lake, but since there aren’t any waves like in the ocean and not a large tidal effect, nor are there significant currents running through the lake, I don’t know where the sand came from. I have two theories: when the asteroid crashed into the Earth and made a big, lifeless void in North America that we now know as Boston, all the dust from the blast fell on Toronto. Over the years, Torontoids used their curling skills to sweep away all of the sand. They swept it towards Lake Ontario, and the sand just piled up there. Now they have beaches. Second theory: somebody bought sand and put it by the lake so they could claim to have a beach. Maybe there is a third possibility, but I have already rejected all other potential explanations.

Anyway, when I found out that Toronto had beaches, I laughed and laughed. I suggested that people here were using the Canadian definition of the word“beach”because I could not see a sane individual saying,“Hey, let’s go to the beach in Canada.”It makes no sense. I checked around and asked people if it ever gets hot in Toronto. The unanimous answer was that it DOES get hot in Toronto. But only for a limited amount of time. Limited? Try July and part of August. Also, I think they were using the Canadian definition of“hot”. In Toronto, they use the Celsius thermometer. 0 is freezing and 100 is boiling. In the US, Farenheit measurements are used. 32 degrees is freezing and something like 212 degrees is boiling. From now on, I think I am going to stick to the Kelvin scale. Freezing in Kelvin is 273.15 and boiling is 373.15. By using Kelvin, I can make sure I offend and confuse Americans and Canadians equally and stop playing favorites. I am used to going to the beach when it is AT LEAST 305 degrees Kelvin (32 C, 90 F). Unfortunately, it NEVER gets that hot here.

Example: yesterday it had to be about 297 degrees Kelvin (24 C, 75 F). I was outside with some co-workers and they were standing in the shade. I was actually cold because there was a breeze. I asked why they were in the shade and they said because it is so hot and they didn’t want to get sunburned. On that day, if I had a magnifying glass, I don’t think the sun would have been strong enough to burn an ant on the sidewalk. It was warm enough to make me feel like I should celebrate the temperature by wearing a short sleeve shirt, but not warm enough that I wished I was wearing shorts or a kilt.

Lesson: Hot is a VERY relative term. Torontoids go to the salt-free beaches in weather that I consider pleasant rather than hot. I will have to bring a jacket to the beach here and I can throw away the SPF 75 that I used in Florida. It is kind of worrying me about what they consider COLD here.

Writing this blog just made me think of another observation that I didn’t quite recognize. My thermostat in my home is in FARENHEIT not CELSIUS or KELVIN! How did this happen? Maybe I have a blackmarket American thermostat. Canadians must have a real problem with heating and air conditioning if they have to convert everything in their heads when they set the temperature of their homes. I am going to have to look into this and find out if other people in Canada have been subverted to American thermostat technology. If America can start a beachhead with thermostats, it won’t be long before the entire metric system and culture of Canada is infiltrated and defeated and all of Canada becomes North North Dakota.

Vigilance.
 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Important Follow-Up to Prior Posts 
 April 17, 2011
 1 Comment 
I took a few pictures to support my prior posts. I took a couple of pictures of Canadian goose protection in action and I also took a photo at the grocery store that exemplifies the consiracy to keep Canadians from buying milk in cartons. I’m not saying that there is anything wrong about what they put on their cartons of milk, but it is clearly ambiguous. I’ve never even heard of anyone using an abbreviated form of the word they are employing on the milk carton. I looked around, and I could not find this same stuff on bags of milk. That, my friends, is why it’s called a conspiracy. Lastly, to show the obsession Canadians have for milk pitchers, I have a photo that shows milk CARTONS but they still have special pitchers they use to hold milk cartons. I think this is a sign of successful brainwashing.
	</body>
</document>
