<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008716" url="http://fastfood.einnews.com/state/ohio" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="1" score="0.000569940133670563" bingtitle="Ohio Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today" webtitle="Ohio Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today">
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Ohio bill seeks to regulate sweepstakes devices at ... in 1954, BURGER KING ® is the second largest fast food… ... You will be able to choose which days you want to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Friday Jul 13, 2012 Fast Food News Today A service for Global Professionals 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 News by Topic News by Country 
 Tools 
 Publications Submit News Members About Contact 
 
Ohio Fast Food News

Latest Ohio News
 from
 Fast Food News Today.
 United States &gt;Ohio
 | Ohio
 Topics 
 Get by: Email or RSS 
 
 
 Sip costs star $1.5M 
 12 Jul 20:36 GMT 
 …)facial hair  (1)fail  (1) fast food (1)FBI  (1)FDA  (1…)Florida  (4) Food (50) Food Integrity Campaign  (1) Food Network  (1) Food Safety News…Stewart  (2)JPL  (1)junk food (1)jury duty  (1)kabbfox29…Wall Street  (2)Odd  (68) Ohio (1)Okla.  (1)Oklahoma  (1… 
 
 Day One: What could go wrong, goes wrong! 
 11 Jul 20:19 GMT 
 …true that most Americans eat fast food and pizza and hotdogs. That…high-resolution flat screens. Artem (an Ohio State graduate, by the way…straight hours, not eaten solid food in the last 10, and…area.”  Dinner consisted of good food (Artem said the 9 inch… 
 
 Burger King burns in Tipp City 
 10 Jul 11:35 GMT 
 TIPP CITY, Ohio (WDTN) - A Tipp City…10 p.m. at the Burger King restaurant located on West Main…not immediately clear when the fast food chain may reopen. 
 
 Honeysuckle on Ohio’s hit list 
 1 Jul 10:05 GMT 
 …, forestry program director with the Ohio State University Extension. “ Honeysuckle has…. It is the equivalent of fast food for birds and threatens the…plants that provide a better food source. The plant is vigorous… 
 
 What is working at McDonald&apos;s like? An employee dishes on Reddit 
 29 Jun 17:45 GMT 
 …a golden arches in Columbus, Ohio – one of the top 500…ever, ever mess with the food that is going to a…, pay, and job atmosphere.” PHOTOS: Fast food gets outrageous As for potential… 
 
 Four McDonald&apos;s Secrets You Never Knew You Needed 
 27 Jun 15:47 GMT 
 Thanks to a Reddit&quot;Ask Me Anything&quot;with a McDonald&apos;s employee, we now know how to get our Big Macs cheaper, which McDonald&apos;s to go to if we were to get inebriated and wanted to evade the law, and all about the secret hierarchy of the… 
 
 Iowa company supplies the pork for Burger King sandwich 
 26 Jun 22:53 GMT 
 …is partnering with a national fast food chain to create a new…a store test somewhere in Ohio ,” Diez says. “Evidently, that went…have a long-term partnership with Burger King . The Memphis Bar-B-Q Pulled Pork… 
 
 Woman Banned From McDonald&apos;s For Throwing Sandwich 
 26 Jun 17:10 GMT 
 CHILLICOTHE, Ohio (WBNS-TV) - A woman was banned from a McDonald&apos;s restaurant after she threw food through a window. Amy Corey said that she became angry when her fiancée&apos;s sandwich was made incorrectly on June 21 at the restaurant.&quot;I wasn… 
 
 McDonald&apos;s USA Names Two Young Chefs To Help In New Happy Meal Creation And Testing 
 26 Jun 14:56 GMT 
 Published: June 26, 2012 OAK BROOK, lll., June 26, 2012 /PRNewswire/ -- Sarah Ralston, 11, of New Albany, Ohio, and Elayna Saley, 8, of Salt Lake City, Utah, recently whipped up winning stories of nutritious family mealtime fun to become McDonald&apos;s… 
 
 Miss Ohio winner is ... Mansfield 
 24 Jun 11:45 GMT 
 …of spending throughout north central Ohio , said Lee Tasseff, president of…past. We love the Greek food , we go to Athens Greek…businesses donate to Miss Ohio .&quot;All the food is donated to…&apos;s, Applebee&apos;s, Taco Bell . We went to the Richland… 
 
 Protesters want Kroger to sign fair food agreement 
 22 Jun 17:09 GMT 
 …a fair food agreement. The Coalition of Immokalee Workers, Ohio Fair Food , and…sign a fair food agreement, known as the ‘Fair Food Program…farmers. Protesters say other fast food and food service corporations are currently working… 
 
 Kettering&apos;s McDonald&apos;s reopens 
 22 Jun 11:33 GMT 
 KETTERING, Ohio (WDTN) - The Kettering McDonald…dollar re-building campaign for the fast food chain&apos;s Miami Valley… 
 
 Soda Ban Should Be Start Of More Limits On Unhealthy Food, Diabetes Doctors Say 
 21 Jun 15:03 GMT 
 …lead to further restrictions on food portions, from oversized hamburgers to…Weiland, a nurse practitioner from Ohio State University Medical Center in…Ice Age, is succumbing to fast food , said Dr. Gary Kilov, a… 
 
 Dozens line up for free McDonald&apos;s food 
 18 Jun 10:42 GMT 
 TROY, Ohio (WDTN) - One hundred people…41 off Interstate 75. The fast food chain closed down earlier this…got word of the free food deal, and camped out overnight… 
 
 Will Philadelphia’s experiment in eradicating ‘food deserts’ work? 
 8 Jun 19:14 GMT 
 …States shows much the same. Ohio State University’s Janne Boone-Heineman…of healthy food options (grocery stores) and unhealthy venues ( fast food restaurants). Her…between proximity to grocery stores, fast food and obesity. RAND Institute’s… 
 
 Travis Wilbur, Corrections Officer, Trafficked Drugs In Taco Bell Wrappers, Cops Say 
 7 Jun 21:01 GMT 
 Houaka Yang Houaka Yang, 20, of Wisconsin, accidentally videotaped his confession and identified himself on tape with a camcorder he stole. Once the video camera was recovered, the victim uploaded&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=… 
 
 Police find Ohio crash suspect at McDonald&apos;s 
 5 Jun 10:50 GMT 
 Police find Ohio crash suspect at McDonald&apos;…found by police at a fast food restaurant. A police spokesman tells… 
 
 Dude Rams Into Taco Bell Over Missing Taco 
 31 May 20:24 GMT 
 …Paul Reyes&quot;Police in Ohio said a man (Michael Smith…crashed his truck into a Taco Bell because his order was missing…through the drive-through at the fast food restaurant on Chambersburg Road in…99- cent taco. If a Taco Bell employee had dropped his Chalupa… 
 
 Police: Man rams into Taco Bell over slighted taco 
 30 May 15:29 GMT 
 Authorities in Huber Heights, Ohio , arrested a man who they…his truck into an area Taco Bell restaurant after drive-through employees apparently…came through and got his food . We forgot a taco. We… 
 
 Disturbance at fast food hotspot 
 25 May 00:20 GMT 
 MORAINE, Ohio (WDTN) - Walking into a McDonalds restaurant got a little dicey Thursday afternoon in Moraine. Police were called to the restaurant at 2757 West Alex  Bell Road around 4:15 p.m. A witness says a line of people were walking into the store… 
 
 Fast Food’s Slow Exit From Hospitals 
 12 Apr 16:06 GMT 
 …other hospitals interested in replacing fast food with more healthful options may…easy as it seems. In Ohio , the Cleveland Clinic tried in…Cosgove, proposed removing all fast food vendors. The Pizza Hut did close. But McDonald… 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 Next Follow @EIN_News NEW French Alps Avalanche Kills 9---Latest News Updates from EIN News Press Releases 
 Latest See All Submit a Release 

Reach our readers and post your press release.

 Country Style Cooking Restaurant Chain to Hold 2012 Annual General ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Pretzelmaker® Kicks Off Summer With the Exclusive Pretzel Dog and ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Dunkin&apos; Brands Group, Inc. to Announce Second Quarter Fiscal Year 2012 ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Domino&apos;s Pizza® Brings Mobile Ordering App to Amazon&apos;s Kindle Fire [11 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Don&apos;t Call Him Junior: Son of Baconator Joins Wendy&apos;s Hamburger Lineup [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Pizza and Garlic Bread Together At Last: Pizza Hut Introduces Garlic ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Lombardi Family Concepts Chooses GiftCardLab.com To Provide Company-... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire The Dunkin&apos; Donuts&amp;Baskin-Robbins Community Foundation Awards $127,... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Caribou Coffee Names Leigh Anne Snider Senior Vice President of Retail ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Central Coast McDonald&apos;s® Will Send One Lucky Customer to See Local ... [09 Jul 2012] PR Newswire 
 Learn more about advertising opportunities Today&apos;s Photos 
 huffingtonpost.com
 Farm Bill Lasting Five Years Approved By House Committee motherjones.com
 5 Surprising Ingredients Allowed in Organic Food 
 OP/ED 
 Latest See All Submit 

 The Great LIBOR Robbery And The Corruption of Major Markets Sorkin&apos;s Fictional&quot;Newsroom&quot;Gets It Right, As CNN, Fox And Others Get It Wrong Romney&apos;s 1 Per Cent Class Parties in Utah; What will The Uninvited Do? 
 Conferences 
 Latest See All Submit 
 GCSE-Food&amp;Health Protection Conference - Toronto Canada 
 Featuring:
 - Consumer Protection - Championing Effective Solutions
 - ... 
 3rd Juice, Nectar&amp;Soft Drinks Summit 2012 
 Magenta Global in cooperation with the Turkish Fruit Juice Industry Association (MEYED) is ... 
 
 International Conference on QA , QC&amp;Validation 
 OMICS Group cordially invites all the participants across the globe to attend the ... 
 Marketplace 
 Latest See All Post a Listing 

 Press Release Distribution 
Get your press release seen by business and industry professionals and at all corners of the web for $79 or less
 Global Technology Forum 
Business strategies for the digital age. Free website from the Economist Intelligence Unit.
 Accounting Services 
Accounting, Tax&amp;Payroll Services. Enjoy your business, leave the paperwork to us. We are certified accountants.
 
 
 FAST FOOD NEWS TODAY BACK TO TOP 

 Account Info: 
 My Account Subscriber Billing Info Member Center 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 Create an Account: 
 Sign up for a Free Trial Register for an Account 
 Help&amp;Information Center: 
 Help Contact Us 
 Submit 
 Submit Press Releases Submit Marketplace Listing Submit a Conference Reserve Ad Space 
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Members List User Agreement Privacy Policy Copyright Policy 
 Navigate: 
 Site Map Home Fast Food News by Topic Fast Food News by Country Fast Food News by US State Fast Food Press Releases Fast Food Press Releases by 24-7 
 Tools and Formats: 
 Email Alerts RSS Feeds 
 
 EIN News Home About EIN News 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 EIN Presswire EIN Marketplace EIN Events and Conferences Newsfeed Maker Inbox Robot IPD Group EIN Twitter EIN Facebook 
 
 ©1995-2012 IPD Group, Inc. All Right Reserved. +
 Fast Food News Today
 = Unlimited access to real-time news Create your EIN News account now. EDITOR&apos;S PICKS 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 

Main office: 1025 Connecticut Ave. NW, Suite 1000, Washington, DC 20036
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Aimed at business leaders and global professionals worldwide, Fast Food News Today is a media monitoring service provided by EIN News.

 About EIN News Established in 1995, EIN News began by supplying business professionals and individuals with relevant and interesting news products. It has grown to become the largest digital news provider in Europe.

 Member List See the partial member list and join a community of professionals from private industry, institutions, and governments that rely on EIN as a critical source for research, breaking news and media services.
 
 EIN Presswire A platform to publish your press or news releases online and be read by thousands of decision-makers, leading journalists and industry professionals who rely on EIN News as an indispensable source of breaking news. Your release will also immediately appear in the Google database and stream out to our content partners, Facebook and Twitter.
 
ALL NEWS PUBLICATIONS

 EIN News provides breaking news coverage on the following topics:
	</body>
</document>
