<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008899" url="http://mytabletennis.net/forum/forum_posts.asp?TID=339&amp;PN=1" time="2012-07-13-02:19" support="2" score="0.012271615135007059" bingtitle="Which Paddle is Right For me? - Alex Table Tennis - MyTableTennis ..." webtitle="Which Paddle is Right For me? - Alex Table Tennis - MyTableTennis.NET ForumTable Tennis Forum - Table Tennis Videos, Table Tennis Equipments, Table Tennis Training, Table Tennis Tournaments">
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001027" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Table Tennis Videos, Table Tennis Equipments, Table ... could go for a higher speed paddle if it offers near 5.5 ... JavaScript must be enabled on your web browser in order ...</description>
	<body>
		New Posts    FAQ    Search    Calendar    Register    Login 
 
 
 
 Home Shop General Equipment For sale Coaching Pictures Videos Events 
 
   Forum Home &gt; Equipment &gt; Equipment 
 
 
Which Paddle is Right For me?
 

  Post Reply 

 Author Message / View First Unread Post    Share Topic Printable Version Delicious Digg Facebook Furl Google MySpace Newsvine reddit StumbleUpon Translate Twitter Windows Live Yahoo Bookmarks    Topic Options Post Reply Create New Topic killerbobbarker Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Beginner
 
 

Joined: 12/24/2003
Location: United States
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 1 Post Options Post Reply Quote killerbobbarker Report Post    Quote    Reply Topic: Which Paddle is Right For me? 
    Posted: 12/26/2003 at 12:24am Hi,

I have been playing table tennis my whole life (I am 17 now), and am ready to take the big step of investing $100 into a paddle rather using the cheap ones (under $15). My playing style is very offensive, my forehand loop is exceptionally good. I am interested in the Yasaka Synergy with Mark V rubbers. I do not have a USATT ranking, and I have never played in any official tournaments. But, like I said, I have been playing my whole life (mostly against my family... we have a tournament every Thanksgiving, we are big into table tennis). I also try to practice every day, and probably practice 20 hours a week. I plan to join the table tennis team/club at the university I attend next year...

Some people say that the aforementioned paddle is ridiculously fast for me to use. Some people say it would be okay, as long as I know what I am doing.


I would be willing to switch to a Yasaka Offensive or some other paddle (and rubber) if you recommend me to do so...



ps What thickness sponge do you suggest? wooo Sponsored Links 
 

 sunny Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Silver Member
 
 

Joined: 05/09/2003
Location: Canada
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 692 Post Options Post Reply Quote sunny Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 12/26/2003 at 6:04pm 
You should get a good paddle. Cost plus features are the deciding factor. You have to decide on the blade and the rubber. You might want to search vendors (like Yasaka, Stiga, ping-pong.com, etc) web site to check out the features of blade. For blade you have to choose between Speed, Control and weight. You don&apos;t want to take a blade 90 gms and above if your wrist is not very strong, it will tire you out in long rallies. As for speed and control, you could go for a higher speed paddle if it offers near 5.5 and above control.

Then what type of grip you want for the blade needs to be decided, if you hold your racket loose and do a lot of side angle spins like flicks or during the return of a service then Anatomic or straight grip would be fine. If you want to maintain attacking style like topspin from forehand and backhand being your primary strokes then flared handle would be good.

You might want to search for Table Tennis Forums on the internet, at times I find peer reviews commenting on the rubber or blade. It helps understanding what problems or benefits others are getting.

Now for the rubber, Yasaka Mark V are good rubbers, take 2.0 mm anything higher is tough to control and anything lower may not give enough power and spin especiall with the 40 mm balls we have now.

I look at the speed, spin and control to decide the rubbers I want. I also look at any new technology such as Stiga&apos;s ACS, which makes rubber lighter but still gives good speed, spin and control. I have used Mark V in the past and use Stiga Magna 2.0 rubbers now.

Regarding the racket being too fast for you, yes it will be in the beginning, you have to get used to them and practice more to gain control, but to go to next level you have to have a good racket with good speed and spin so don&apos;t worry you will get over the hump.

Sanjeev Chopra
 stews Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Beginner
 


Joined: 12/07/2003
Location: United States
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 19 Post Options Post Reply Quote stews Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 12/27/2003 at 2:36pm 
i really like my btw primo powerfeeling as a beginner blade. its not too fast, gives good control and works well with rubbers such as sriver 2.1 (which i use right now).

in general, get either mark v or sriver. they&apos;re solid for almost any game, and last a long time
 ghspingclub Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Beginner
 
 

Joined: 12/26/2003
Location: United States
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 8 Post Options Post Reply Quote ghspingclub Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 12/29/2003 at 4:04pm 
And remember, it&apos;s always better to get a blade that is too slow for you than a blade that is too fast for you. I learned the hard way, and bought the fastest blade/setup I found. Now I&apos;m saving for an ALL+ blade. In the long run, the slower blade will allow you to learn better forms easier. As time past by, and you get better, bump up the speed one notch at a time.

I also agree with Stews that Mark V and Sriver are one of the best rubbers which offer solid control and speed.

-Matthew

-Matthew
 trying to sell, only couple of weeks used: Mark V (black, 2.0mm) for $10, Stiga Clipper Wood WRB (flared) for $30, or both for $35. Shipping included. PayPal preferred. Email pongs101@aol.com nosti49 Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Visit Members Homepage Add to Buddy List 
Beginner
 
 

Joined: 01/19/2004
Location: Germany
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 22 Post Options Post Reply Quote nosti49 Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 01/19/2004 at 5:39am 
Hi killerbobbarker,

playing very offensive I think it is a must that you minimum have an OFF- like the Primorac OFF- (I do not know, if it&apos;s available in Canada, can only speak for Europe). An ALL+ would be the ALSOLUTE MINIMUM. Please bear in mind that a lot of woods have a range of about +/- one or two ranges, i.e. one ALL+ might be in your subject feeling acting like an ALL- and the other like an OFF wood.

Therefore it is essential that you TEST it first and that means you should join a TT-club and ask the players there, if you could try their rackets for one or two matches.

Minimum here in Germany that is the usual way to safe money and get experience.

Only then I would finally decide what to buy. (Mark V I personally find too fast and use Sriver 2,5 mm with fresh glue on the forehand instead, as I also want to have a little more spin instead of only shot ability, but this depends on you own preferences)

Better try first before spending too much money for nothing I think....

Ciao

Norbert
 Speedplay Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Platinum Member
 
 

Joined: 07/11/2006
Location: Sweden
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 2496 Post Options Post Reply Quote Speedplay Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/13/2006 at 5:55am Dont know what paddle you have used before, that makes it hard to tell if your own combo is over the hill.

Yasaka synergy sound like a good option, havent played it myself though. But its a fast blade and doesnt weight a lot.

As for the fh-rubber I would go for Mark V M2 as its a little bit speedier and gives a little more spinn than the regular mark V. 2.0 or max depending on how fast you want it. Perhaps even the Stiga Almana could be something for you? Its a great rubber but it tends to be a shortlived one, but hey, its just money 

Most people wants to play ther backhand a little slower, so you could either use the same rubber with a thiner sponge or you could go for Globe 999 (Exellent controll, good speed and spin) or try out DHS G666 a rubber that I found works great for my bh. Its a little faster than the globe.

Good luck, and remember that new equipment, no matter what you choose, will take time to control. Wavestone hollow handle FH: Red Diamond BH Best Anti
 Dawei Radio A5 runners aeoliah Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Platinum Member
 


Joined: 11/18/2005
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 2834 Post Options Post Reply Quote aeoliah Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/13/2006 at 9:01am Don&apos;t rush to buy, take your time, listen around, and try to get every opportunity to try blades from your friends. In this way you will get a suitable blade for you. Member of the Single Ply Hinoki Club
Hy Blade Speed 90
Red Coppa JO Silver























 Sabito Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Gold Member
 


Joined: 05/23/2005
Location: Canada
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 1281 Post Options Post Reply Quote Sabito Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/13/2006 at 10:23am 

 Originally posted by killerbobbarker 

Hi,

I have been playing table tennis my whole life (I am 17 now), and am ready to take the big step of investing $100 into a paddle rather using the cheap ones (under $15). My playing style is very offensive, my forehand loop is exceptionally good. I am interested in the Yasaka Synergy with Mark V rubbers. I do not have a USATT ranking, and I have never played in any official tournaments. But, like I said, I have been playing my whole life (mostly against my family... we have a tournament every Thanksgiving, we are big into table tennis). I also try to practice every day, and probably practice 20 hours a week. I plan to join the table tennis team/club at the university I attend next year...

Some people say that the aforementioned paddle is ridiculously fast for me to use. Some people say it would be okay, as long as I know what I am doing.


I would be willing to switch to a Yasaka Offensive or some other paddle (and rubber) if you recommend me to do so...



ps What thickness sponge do you suggest? 


I can recommend you the synergy with stiga magna rubbers, some stiga sponsored player in my club uses it (even though its a yasaka blade) and I like a lot the combo, its very very nice, get max rubbers and enjoy!
 TT_Freak Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Platinum Member
 
 

Joined: 11/21/2004
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 2679 Post Options Post Reply Quote TT_Freak Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/13/2006 at 12:36pm You don&apos;t want to spend too much until you get a good idea of what you like. Something cheap and effective is a good bet. One of the resident dealers here is Cole_Ely, has a lot of Chinese products and includes a lot of services for no extra charge. TTman is another that has a few rarer finds. Zeropong is a good site; along with speedpong, eacheng and fashionpingpong (has very rare finds, expensive though). Violin
F1
Actor

10g at 3 and 9
10g at 12
20g at the end of handle stefanusj Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Super Member
 


Joined: 06/18/2006
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 106 Post Options Post Reply Quote stefanusj Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/13/2006 at 8:25pm You better save more money for the blade.buy the best blade available (depend on your styles. Maybe borko, nittaku acoustic, kokutaku or darker speed or tanpan series) because its durable and good investment. I prefer buy one of the best (costly) blade than a few mediocre blades (only causing regrets in the end)

Rubbers is different story, it only lasts 3 month. Sriver, mark v is good. Better search for tensioned rubbers, because the feel is superb. BigJ99678 Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Super Member
 


Joined: 02/11/2006
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 133 Post Options Post Reply Quote BigJ99678 Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/15/2006 at 5:19am i use the same EXACT setup as stews, great combination for learning and the future. Sadly they stopped making the primopowerfeeling blade so good luck with that. You&apos;re lucky I suck yogi_bear Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Assistant Moderator
 
 

Joined: 11/25/2004
Location: Philippines
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 3411 Post Options Post Reply Quote yogi_bear Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/16/2006 at 6:08am try cole ely and buy some cheap chinese rubbers Independent online TT Product reviewer of ADIDAS, STIGA, TIBHAR, YASAKA&amp;JOOLA

Im not the man, I&apos;m the bear!!
 SDRamones Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Gold Member
 
 

Joined: 11/12/2005
Location: United States
Online Status: Offline
Posts: 1466 Post Options Post Reply Quote SDRamones Report Post    Quote    Reply Posted: 07/16/2006 at 9:48am Try coles or Zeropong website for some ideas. Or you can try the some Dawei blades, they are pretty inexpensive as well. [IMG]http://i28.photobucket.com/albums/c228/SDRamones/Table%20Tennis/Blade_fan-1.jpg&quot;&gt;

 My EBAY Feedback 
 
  Post Reply 


 Forum Jump -- Select Forum --  General  ITTF President answers you  Table Tennis Quiz  Suggestions to MyTableTennis.NET  MYTT Donation  Off Topic  Equipment  Coaching&amp;Tips  Video of me playing  Pictures  Videos  For sale  Feedbacks  Events  Toronto Table Tennis Clubs  Other Table Tennis Clubs  Toronto Table Tennis Super League  Dev Testing Forum Permissions You cannot post new topics in this forum
You cannot reply to topics in this forum
You cannot delete your posts in this forum
You cannot edit your posts in this forum
You cannot create polls in this forum
You cannot vote in polls in this forum
 

 

This page was generated in 0.141 seconds. 
 Mark all posts as read :: Delete cookies set by this forum 

Cookies and JavaScript must be enabled on your web browser in order to use this forum 
 Copyright©2003-2010 MyTableTennis.NET - All Rights Reserved. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
