<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008776" url="http://www.activediner.com/fast-food/restaurant/waco/tx/us/region-115" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="11" score="0.04618368893501202" bingtitle="fast food Restaurants in waco, tx" webtitle="fast food Restaurants in waco, tx">
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>1 - 10 of 57 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt; ... They have items other than simply burgers, such as ... and I waited 2 minutes for someone to take my order ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Mexican 
 Chicken 
 Chinese 
 Burger 
 Italian 
 Comfort Food/Home Cooking 
 Japanese 
 Tex-Mex 
 
 more... 
 African American Asian Bagel Shop Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Breakfast Buffet Burger Business Lunch Cafeteria Casual/Family Catering Catfish Chicken Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Coffee Shop Comfort Food/Home Cooking Contemporary Country Deli/Sandwich/Subs Dinner Dockside/Pier Fast Food Fine Dining French Health Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Italian Japanese Karaoke Kids Friendly Late Night Dining Live Entertainment Lunch Mexican Outdoor Seating Pizzeria Romantic Scenic View Seafood Smoking/Non Smoking Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Take Out/Carry Out Tavern Tex-Mex Thai Truck Stop TV/Satellite Vietnamese Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access 
 
 





 
 
 
   
 
 



 
   United States  &gt;  Texas  &gt;  waco 
fast food Restaurants in waco, tx
 1 - 10 of 57 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt;   
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Burger Barn 
Burger, Fast Food
1700 Colcord Ave, Waco
(254) 235-9003   LATEST REVIEW   
A very unique and character-filled burger joint! The staff (Brit and Liz: owners) are just fantastic, and the food is superb. They have items other than simply burgers, such as salads (which are wonderful), hot dogs, ribs, and even frog legs! The ...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Church&apos;s Fried Chicken 
American, Chicken, Fast Food
1515 South Valley Mills Drive, Waco
(254) 753-5481   LATEST REVIEW   
I eat at theis place at lease twice a week and I love the service and the prices are within my budget. Expecailly when you have to feed a large family.
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 5.0 
 Kitok Restaurant 
Fast Food
1815 N 18th St, Waco
(254) 754-1801   LATEST REVIEW   
Great burgers and everything on the menue is unique. I eat there every week and love the Lip lockers and Oriental Fries. They are the best!
Kyung, the waitress is the BEST!
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   advertisements 
 
 
 
 RATING 4.0 
 Bluebonnet Cafe 
Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food
1506 New Dallas Highway, Waco
(254) 799-8580   LATEST REVIEW   
The Texas Bluebonnet Diner it is now undr new owners, has better quality food than ever before! Best burger in town!!!!! They also have chicken fried steaks,cat fish on friday nights,the occasional B-B-Q ( BEST I EVER ATE!!!)along with fresh baked pi...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 2.0 
 Burger King 
Burger, Fast Food
103 East Loop 340, Waco
(254) 799-4600   LATEST REVIEW   
I went to the loop 340 store on 4-8-08 @ 7:40 a.m. and ordered a double S.E.C. crisanwitch with a small Coke. I was told to pull to the second window. I did and was told that my order was $3.86
I paid and was given my food and proceeded to go to wor...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 1.0 
 Taco Bell 
Mexican, Fast Food
1725 N Valley Mills Dr, Waco
(254) 772-5629   LATEST REVIEW   
I visited this store 8/5/09. There were only 3 cars in the lot and 6 people in the store and no one waiting to order. There was no one attending the register and I waited 2 minutes for someone to take my order or acknowledge I was even there. There w...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef 
Fast Food
701 South University Parks Drive, Waco
(254) 753-3005   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef 
Fast Food
723 North Valley Mills Drive, Waco
(254) 776-0262   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Burger King 
American, Burger, Fast Food
1210 North Valley Mills Drive, Waco
(254) 776-1116   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Burger King 
American, Burger, Fast Food
1500 Interstate 35 South, Waco
(254) 753-5101   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   


 
 Next &gt;&gt; 



 Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for? Try searching here...
 
      Know of a restaurant we don&apos;t have?   Click here to add it. 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
