<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008774" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Sonic-Drive-In2.html" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="4" score="0.010126994581661332" bingtitle="SONIC DRIVE IN, 355 North Franklin Street, Christiansburg, VA ..." webtitle="SONIC DRIVE IN, 355 North Franklin Street, Christiansburg, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>... in such a way that they could contaminate single service items on the front counter. ... changing tasks and wash hands when changing from raw food to ready-to-eat (RTE) food ...</description>
	<body>
		SONIC DRIVE IN, 355 North Franklin Street, Christiansburg, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: SONIC DRIVE IN 
Address: 355 North Franklin Street, Christiansburg, Virginia 
Total inspections: 8 
Last inspection: Apr 20, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 0570 - Corrected During Inspection Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Wiping cloths being stored on counter tops between use. 0580 - Single-use gloves while worn during multi-tasked food preparation. Employee seen handling raw, frozen hamburger patties with gloves then making a sandwich (RTE) withou washing hands and changing gloves 0820 A 2 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Tomatoes cold holding at improper temperatures. 0830 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The ready-to-eat (RTE) commercially processed hot dogs in the refrigeration unit was not properly dated for disposition after opening. 1530 - Corrected During Inspection There is no properly working test kit readily available in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 1770 B - Observed accumulations of food debris on the following food contact surfaces: vegetable slicers 1890 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized: food thermometer used to take food temps 3330 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Working container of blue dish soap was not properly labeled. 
 April 20, 2009 Routine 4 4 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. April 24, 2008 Routine 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0470 - Critical Repeat Unwrapped or uncovered food in the walk-in cooler and in the standup Delfield freezer. 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor in both the walk-in cooler and the walk-in freezer. 0830 - Critical Repeat The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) salad in the refrigeration unit is not properly dated for disposition. 1450 - The Delfield two door reach in cooler at the prep line was having trouble maintaining 41 degrees or below. The unit has an adjustable thermostat. 3340 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Containers of cleaning supplies are not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food (soda and slush mix), equipment, utensils, linens or single service items. 
 April 05, 2007 Routine 3 2 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Critical The employee is smoking in areas where they may contaminate food, clean equipment, utensils or other items needing protection. 0220 - Critical In use open drinking containers stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. 0470 - Critical Repeat Unwrapped or uncovered food in the front freezer. 0610 - Corrected During Inspection Food stored on the floor in walk-in freezer or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Eggs and sausage for burritos (63F) cold holding at improper temperatures. 0830 - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) cheese, foods in the refrigeration unit and walk-in cooler are not properly dated for disposition. 1960 - Pans were found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 2310 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed employees using the automated handwashing station in a manner that was not approved by the manufacturer. Employee dumping cigarette in handwashing sink. 2720 - Dumpster or outside refuse container was open or uncovered. 3260 - Employees are not using the dressing rooms or lockers provided. Observed employee&apos;s coat stored in dry storage area. 3340 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Containers of chemicals are not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food, equipment, utensils, linens or single service items. 
 February 03, 2006 Routine 6 4 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 04, 2006 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0450 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employees observed handling ready-to-eat (RTE) food with their bare hands. 0470 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Unwrapped or uncovered food in the freezer and the cooler. 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: Cutting boards 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following utensils were observed soiled to sight and touch: Knife for cutting cooked chicken stored between dirty equipment. 2010 - Corrected During Inspection Clean equipment/utensils were found stored under the leaking condensate line in the walk-in freezer. 
 April 07, 2005 Routine 3 1 Details / Comments 
 0550 - Dispensing utensils improperly stored between. 1580 - The cutting board(s) at the Ice cream station are heavily scratched and scored. The food contact surface is no longer easily cleaned and sanitized due to condition. 2890 - Light bulb in Walk-in not shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistent and not working. 
 March 23, 2004 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 0820 - Critical Cheese on prep unit cold holding at improper temperatures (51 degrees). 2000 - Clean single service containers were observed stored with the food-contact surface facing upward. 3490 - Personal hand lotion stored in such a way that they could contaminate single service items on the front counter. 3080 - Less than 10 foot candles of light was noted in the walk-in cooler. 0610 - Food stored on the floor. Or Food stored less than 6&quot;&quot; above the floor. 
 January 14, 2003 Routine 1 4 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
