<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008900" url="http://www.cannonfuse.com/projects/2.asp" time="2012-07-13-02:19" support="2" score="0.0008813219013690614" bingtitle="The Ultimate Source For Fuse - CannonFuse.com" webtitle="The Ultimate Source For Fuse - CannonFuse.com">
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... or similar device the end is ... are the &quot;free&quot; ones you&apos;ll find at your favorite fast food restaurant. ... Form it into a little cup with the ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Items(s) $0.00

 Checkout 
 

   
 

   

 
 
~ Pyrotechnic Information ~
 



 Projects: 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | 6 | 7 | 8 | 9 | 10 | 11 | 12 | 13 | 14 | 15 | 16 | 17 | 18 

 Large Shell Assembly 
  
 The following is the procedure that has been used 
 to assemble Aerial Shells for many years. Aerial Shells 
 are launched from a Mortar (a specialized cardboard 
 or HDPE plastic pipe) sending the shell high into the 
 air with its time delay fuse lit. When the shell reaches 
 its maximum altitude, it explodes, igniting the colored 
 stars inside and throwing them a great distance. Like all fireworks, these are by no means safe to manufacture 
 and doing so is illegal in the United States unless 
 you are licensed by the BATF. An assembled Aerial Shell&quot;going off&quot;on the ground in front of you 
 (instead of hundreds of feet in the air) will most likely 
 kill you or leave you disfigured for life. These directions 
 will work for 4&quot;through 8&quot;shells, the sizes 
 most commonly used by shell makers. We show the assembly 
 of a 6&quot;shell because it&apos;s a little easier to work 
 with and photograph. Shells smaller than 4&quot;generally 
 can be assembled in a simpler fashion and shells larger 
 then 8&quot;get a lot more complicated which we&apos;re 
 not going to cover at all.

To save time&amp;trouble, most people 
 pretty much stick with using plastic shell casings (as 
 opposed to paper). Although these directions will apply 
 to any size, the most common are 4&quot;,6&quot;and 
 8&quot;. One thing to do before assembling a plastic 
 shell is to make sure the 2 halves fit together without 
 effort. This may sound strange, but we&apos;ve run into several 
 bad casings that just don&apos;t fit together (and it can 
 be quite aggravating to find this out after you&apos;ve spent 
 time loading your shell).

 Part One, Fusing  

The time-delay fuse used in aerial shell 
 is known as 1/4&quot;Time Fuse or Oriental Time Fuse. 
 It is available in coils of different lengths and has 
 a nominal outer diameter of 1/4&quot;(although occasionally 
 you will see other diameters for sale, stick with the 
 1/4&quot;) . All 4&quot;, 6&quot;&amp;8&quot;shells 
 use the same length of fuse, 1.25&quot;(1-1/4&quot;).

 

It is important that time fuse is cut 
 with a blade and not a scissor-type device. The powder 
 core is somewhat fragile and if cut with a scissors 
 or similar device the end is crushed (to varying degrees) 
 and the powder loosened from its packed state, increasing 
 its burn rate.

 

Insert a 1.25&quot;long fuse into the 
 bottom half of the shell, leaving about half the length 
 sticking out the bottom of the shell.

 

Using a Hot Melt Glue Gun, lay an even 
 bead of glue around the base of the fuse sealing it 
 to the casing. When cool, do the same on the inside 
 of the shell. It is important that there be no gaps 
 in the glue which could allow fire to enter the shell 
 during launch.

 

 

Slip a Plastic Drinking Straw over the 
 fuse end on the inside of the shell and glue into place. 
 There are some straws that are just either too small 
 or too large to fit over time fuse. Unfortunately, these 
 are the&quot;free&quot;ones you&apos;ll find at your favorite 
 fast food restaurant. What will fit are the&quot;Flexi-Straws&quot;found in just about every supermarket. They come in 
 boxes of 100 and are very inexpensive.

 

Cut the straw off so it&apos;s just under the 
 rim of the shell.

 

Fill the straw to within 1/4&quot;of 
 the top with granulated Black Powder. We use granulated 
 Homemade Black Powder. Its manufacture is described 
 in the Black 
 Powder&amp;Rice Hulls section. Commercial 3FG 
 or similar may also be used.

 

 Roll up a small ball of Tissue 
 and push it into the end of the straw with a nail or 
 pencil. It shouldn&apos;t be too tight, just tight enough 
 to hold the powder in and not fall out when the shell 
 is turned over. 

The completed, fused shell. Lay a ruler 
 across the rim to make sure that the fuse tube does 
 not protrude over the edge. If it does, just clip it 
 short.

 

 Part Two, Loading 

Now that your shell is properly fused, 
 it is ready to load with stars and a break charge.

For ease of assembly (and to protect the 
 fuse protruding from bottom half), sit the two hemispheres 
 on cardboard tubes or cups.

 

Starting with the top half (the one without 
 the fuse), begin loading stars into the shell. Spread 
 them one layer deep all around the inside of the hemisphere.

 

Continue loading until both halves of 
 the shell have a layer of stars along the inside. Do 
 not load the stars all the way up to the rim. There 
 is a small lip on shell halves that must fit together, 
 so leave a space of about 1/4&quot;from the rim on 
 both halves.

 

Next, you will need some tissue paper, 
 the kind that you wrap fragile items in or pack you 
 Christmas presents with. You can certainly use other 
 types of thin paper, even a 1 ply paper towel, but tissue 
 paper is both thin and strong and easily obtainable.

 

The next thing you&apos;ll need are some Meal 
 Coated Rice Hulls, info on making them can be found 
 in our  BP Coated Corn Cob&amp;Rice Hulls section.

 

 

Cut a piece of tissue paper about 12&quot;square, form it into a little cup and dump a heaping 
 handful of Coated Rice Hulls into it.

 

Hold the package of Hulls by the top and 
 drop it into the shell, quickly spreading the Hulls 
 up against the wall of stars. The Rice Hulls pressing 
 on the stars will prevent them from falling in. The 
 tissue paper merely prevents the stars from migrating 
 into the center of the shell during transport or launch.

 

 

Trim the tissue paper so that it&apos;s under 
 the lip of the shell casing. Add or remove some Rice 
 Hulls until the shell is full to about 1/8&quot;from 
 the top. Check with a straight edge and be careful not 
 to overfill, it would make it difficult to assemble 
 the shell. Set this half of the shell aside when complete.

 

Loading the fused side of the shell with 
 Hulls is a tad more difficult...

 

Cut another 12&quot;square of tissue 
 paper and tear a small 1/2&quot;diameter hole in the 
 center. Form it into a little cup with the hole at the 
 bottom.

 

Now gently, slide the paper cup over the 
 straw and let it rest in the shell. If you bump the 
 shell, your stars will go tumbling to the bottom, so 
 be careful.

 

Get a cupful of Coated Rice Hulls and 
 all at once, dump the entire cupful into the shell. 
 Do not do this slowly, the stars will fall in. If you 
 just dump it in all at once, the Hulls will hold the 
 stars in place before they&apos;ve got a chance to fall. 
 Spread the hulls around evenly.

 

Trim the tissue paper all around the shell 
 and make sure that it doesn&apos;t extend above the rim.

 

Do the same as you did on the other shell 
 half, adding or removing Hulls until the shell is full 
 to just about an 1/8&quot;under the rim.

 

 Part Three, Finishing&amp;Closing 

Dump half a tablespoon of Whistle Mix in each shell hemisphere. The Formula for Whistle Mix 
 and can be found in the Making Fireworks&amp;Chemical Experiments section. Some pros like 
 to use Flash Powder (as shown in the images), but stick 
 with Whistle Mix.
Flash Powder frequently breaks the shell too hard smashing 
 the stars into dust, or shoots them out so fast that 
 they blow out. You&apos;ll find that Whistle Mix works perfectly 
 almost all the time.

 

Spread the Whistle Mix around a bit and 
 work it down into the Rice Hulls. This will help the 
 shell break more evenly.

 

 

The shell is now ready to be closed. There 
 are two ways to do this. You can simply snap the two 
 halves together (as we do) or you can hold a piece of 
 thin cardboard over one half. We&apos;ll show you both ways:

  

The quick way is to line up the two 
 shell halves. One has a lip that fits inside the other. 
 Rest the opposing shell on the lip and tilt them a little 
 toward each other.

With one fast move, snap the shell together. 
 I know, it looks like everything will go flying, but 
 every person who we&apos;ve taught to do it, does it with 
 ease. If you feel you lack the coordination to accomplish 
 this daring maneuver, try the alternate method...

    

Place a thin piece of cardboard (like 
 the kind you find on the back of note pads) on one half 
 of the shell. Holding it in place, flip the shell over 
 and lay it on the bottom half. Align the two halves, 
 and slowly pull out the cardboard, snapping the two 
 hemispheres together.

 

 

  

The shell is now ready to be sealed (you&apos;ll 
 need a glass or metal container to catch the excess 
 solvent that will drip off). Pull the shell just a hair 
 apart (not too much, just a hair) and using either Xylol 
 or Methylene Chloride in an eye dropper (squirt bottle, 
 or similar), run the solvent around the seam of the 
 shell. Rotate the shell so there are no dry gaps. Capillary 
 attraction will draw the solvent into the seam and melt 
 the plastic shell lips together.Before the solvent dries, 
 push the shell halves firmly together making sure that 
 the shell is perfectly sealed.

 
 

 Support the shell and orient it 
 so the time fuse is pointing up. The next steps will 
 be the final fusing of the shell and attachment of the 
 lift charge.

 

 Part 4, Final Fusing&amp;Lift Charge 

Using a razor blade, slice the Time Fuse 
 in half to a depth of about 1/4&quot;

 

You&apos;ll need some Black Match, also known 
 as&quot;Crossmatch&quot;(Black Powder coated cotton 
 string) for the next step. You can see how that is made 
 in our Blackmatch and Quickmatch section.

Rock the blade back&amp;forth to open 
 up the time fuse and insert a 3&quot;long piece of 
 Crossmatch. Push the Crossmatch in so it&apos;s level with 
 the top of the Time Fuse.

 

Using some good quality thread (or better 
 yet, dental floss), wrap a few turns around the Time 
 Fuse&amp;Crossmatch securing them together. Tape the 
 loose ends of the thread to the shell casing.

 

Flip the shell over, dip the fuse ring 
 (that came with your shell casing) in some solvent and 
 insert it in the top hole. The fuse ring will support 
 the shell as it is loaded into the Mortar.

 

Lay the shell on its side and run a 4 
 foot length (approximately) of  Quickmatch through the Fuse Ring, around the shell ending at the 
 Time Fuse. The Quickmatch doesn&apos;t have to actually touch 
 the Crossmatched Time Fuse. They will both be inside 
 a pouch of Lift Powder (granulated Black Powder) and 
 will ignite simultaneously. Tape the Quickmatch to the 
 shell casing every few inches so it is secure. The Quickmatch 
 needs to be about 18&quot;longer than the Mortar you 
 will be using to fire your shells out of.

 

The final step is to add a pouch filled 
 with Lift Powder (coarse granulated Black Powder). We 
 use homemade Lift Powder although commercial FFG or 
 FFFG Black Powder can be used. If commercial Black Powder 
 is used, the amount of lift charge is cut just about 
 in half due to its faster burning speed. Directions 
 for making Lift Powder can be found here . 
 Lift charges are as follows:

 
Lift Charges
( in grams )
 4&quot;Shell 6&quot;shell 8&quot;shell Homemade Lift Powder  60 100 200 Commercial Black Powder 35 60 100 

These lift charge amounts should only be taken as a&quot;ballpark&quot;figure. There are many factors 
 which come into play in determining the amount of lift 
 charge to use; relative&quot;strength&quot;of the 
 Black Powder, particle size, etc. One additional parameter 
 is the length of the Mortars. Just as a point of reference, 
 our 4&quot;Mortars are 24&quot;long and our 6&quot;Mortars are 36&quot;long.

A small pouch must be attached to the 
 bottom of the shell to hold the lift charge. For the 
 smaller 4&quot;shells&quot;Solo&quot;cone shaped 
 paper cups can be used. They&apos;re cheap and easily obtainable. 
 Regular paper cups cannot be used because they&apos;re coated 
 with wax making it difficult to attach them to the shell.

 

Larger shells require that you fashion a pouch out 
 of paper. A single sheet triangular folded with the 
 ends trimmed and taped makes an excellent pouch. Of 
 course any design can be used just as long as it can 
 be attached to the shell and it doesn&apos;t leak out the 
 Lift Powder inside. The pouch is filled with the 
 appropriate amount of Lift Powder and then securely 
 taped to the bottom of the shell.

 
  

 Completed Aerial Shells showing 
 a size comparison between a 6&quot;shell, 4&quot;shell 
 and 36D breasts.

 

Always remember to tear off 12 to 18 inches 
 of paper off the end of the Quickmatch fuse for delay 
 before launching. As stated before, Aerial Shells are 
 complex and dangerous fireworks. Although this description 
 of the assembly procedure is complete, many of the potential 
 problems and warnings have not been addressed. Never 
 attempt the construction of these devices unless you 
 are licensed and have been properly trained to do so.
 

 Projects: 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | 6 | 7 | 8 | 9 | 10 | 11 | 12 | 13 | 14 | 15 | 16 | 17 | 18 

 
 
 
  
   

 
 Home | Policies | My Account | Pyro 
 Info | Links | Contact 
 Us | Site Map 

 
 Site 
 Design: AudioIntegrity.com 

 ©2005-2008 CannonFuse.com, All Rights Reserved. 
 
Secure Payment Gateway
	</body>
</document>
