<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008485" url="http://www.dipity.com/timetube/YouTube_Earthquake_In_China/#!" time="2012-07-13-01:57" support="1" score="0.0018135936107078851" bingtitle="YouTube: Earthquake In China Timeline" webtitle="YouTube: Earthquake In China Timeline">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>Israel has yet to confirm the report ... stores shelves were almost empty and the fast food restaurant ... Send a check/money order/Cashier&apos;s check to Chinese ...</description>
	<body>
		dipity 

 Sign In | Join Dipity 
 
 Home Create a Timeline Hot Topics Dipity Premium 
 
YouTube: Earthquake In China 714 Views Share: 
 Follow stumbleupon myspace digg facebook twitter Embed Search Timeline Flipbook List Map 
 In: From: Until: Search for: 1 Year Current Date Loading... Show/Hide Sources - Update Sources Edit Source List Edit | Delete Video | Picture 
 Description Map Comments 
 

   
 Link: 
 Added by: 
 Share: 
 link twitter facebook digg myspace stumbleupon 
 
 Edit | Delete Video | Picture 
 Description Map Comments 
 

   
 Link: 
 Added by: 
 Share: 
 link twitter facebook digg myspace stumbleupon 
 
 &lt; &gt; Loading... Remove this Ad 
 
Description
 
YouTube Videos matching query: Earthquake In China

 Created by timetube on Jun 23, 2008 

Last updated: 03/11/10 at 02:15 AM
 
Followers
 
YouTube: Earthquake In China has no followers yet. Be the first one to follow .
 
Comments
 Please Join or Log In to comment. 
 
Recent Events on YouTube: Earthquake In China
 
 Plasma Waffe - China Earthquake caused by HAARP weapon 
 Jun 1, 2008 4:50 AM 
Kopie von
fdsaxxxx
http://de.youtube.com/watch?v=ecLwVgvvTvU

Prove of HAARP was used to cause the big earthquake in China.
World War III is coming... borealis
A comment from a Japanese, named fonett:
&quot;why sichuan? cause theres china&apos;s largest natural gas field, SARS was a biological weapon by these same people.
why they do it? start ww3 essence is to kill off most of the human race, manage less people in the new world order plan. it&apos;s all starting right now with basic food shortages, spreading disease, and war. to present day there are still groups of white men believe racial superiority, they are the true criminals, they are crazy; believe it&apos;s destiny and god&apos;s will to do this.
olympics must be hold, wish china have successful olympics. i am japanese, sincerely support... go china!&quot; 
and i have to add sichuan is china&apos;s most populous province, and where china&apos;s nuclear research center and site are.
Prove of HAARP was used to cause the big earthquake in China.

HAARP info: http://www.conspiracyarchive.com/NWO/...
http://www.mediarare.com/haarp.html
 FULFORD VS. HAARP hi-rez 
 May 29, 2008 1:08 AM 
Benjamin Fulford investigates a mysterious plasma weapon seen prior to the Niigata earthquake in July 2007 and Red, White&amp;Blue HAARP lights near the epicenter prior to the recent quake in China. Taiwan satellites measured a 50% drop in ionospheric energy above the Sichuan epicenter on the day before the quake. Both earthquakes targeted nuclear military facilities... coincidence or war crime?
 Haarp-10 mins before the 2008 Sichuan earthquake in China 
 May 23, 2008 4:15 PM 
10 mins before the 2008 Sichuan earthquake in China
 Rebuild Our Home -The Best Song for 5.12 Earthquake in China 
 May 23, 2008 8:07 AM 
Rebuild Our Home - 重建家园
BeiJing Golden Century International Record Company and all Singers from this Record Company Including( Mencius Yan-焱 , YaFeng , HuangYong , ZhangYu , A Liao and more...) Spent two days made this song and Edit this music video for 5.12 Earthquake in WenChuan China. 
And we hope this song can bring energy to everyone for rebuild our home.
 Earthquake in China, 《爱的奉献》央视赈灾晚会,part 3 
 May 21, 2008 11:16 PM 
《爱的奉献》央视赈灾晚会,part 3. 为死者默哀、为生者祈福 , 中国,加油,CCTV, China, Chinese, Memory, earthquake, Sichuan
 A Tribute to the Victims of Earthquake in China &apos;08.05.12 
 May 21, 2008 9:13 AM 
All my feelings is here in the music ... Sad, Sorrow, Pain and Anxious ... RIP to those who lost their lives ... !!! 

A Tribute to The Victims of The Earthquake in DUJIANGYAN, Sichuan, China ...
2008.05.12 14:28 ... 

When the earthquack occured, more than 7,000 of school buildings were collapsed, lot of students of primary school were found under the tumble down buildings at 2:02. 

A dancing teacher in blue checker shirt having her body to protect students, both were buried in the collapsed school building at 2:14. 

Many students with her/his writing pens in their hands were found in the collapsed school buildings at 2:38&amp;3:02. 

All roads were blocked or cracked after the earthquake, due to the bad weather, the rescue teams were hardly go to the affected area. Also, two pandas were missing in Wolong Conservation and Research Centre ...

A 9-year-old female panda &apos;Mao Mao&apos; confirmed dead in Sichuan quake ...

******************************************************************

Child Victims Remembered On Special Day

Perhaps never before has International Children&apos;s Day been so significant in China.

After the earthquake that devastated the country on May 12, the lost children were commemorated on Sunday - their own holiday - while millions of others seemed to have grown up overnight.

Standing on a pile of rubble that was the Xinjian Primary School, Yi Jianguo held a photo of his daughter.
&quot;She always longed to celebrate Children&apos;s Day,&quot; he said, tears welling his eyes.
&quot;Although she is gone, I remember her words and must make up for her.&quot;
There were 60 students in his daughter&apos;s Just five survived the quake.
Yi was among the 500 parents who planned to celebrate Children&apos;s Day for their lost kids.
They pooled their money to buy each child a large photo frame so as to have them &quot;witness how their parents celebrate with them.&quot;
In the resettlement zone in the town of Leigu, Beichuan, four children played basketball with a ball they found in the debris.
&quot;When can we return to school?&quot; Chen Hao of the Leigu Primary School, asked.
&quot;In the past we longed for a day off for Children&apos;s Day. But this time, we just wish our could start as normal on June 1.&quot;

For 13-year-old Wang Zhen from the Mianzhu Middle School, his holiday wish was to see his mom again.
The boy has become introverted since losing his mother in the earthquake.
&quot;She was always nagging and sometimes beat me. But I know she did it because she loved me.&quot;
When Zhou Lin, his psychologist, told him &quot;you can pretend I&apos;m your mom and give me a hug,&quot; Wang threw himself into her arms and cried.

(Xinhua News Agency June 4, 2008)

As of 2008-06-21 / 06-20
Death: 69,181 / 69,180
Lost: 17,397 / 17,398 
Injured: 374,010 / 374,008 
In Hospital: NUD / 13,851

As of 2008-06-20 / 06-19
Death: No Change / 69,180
Lost: 17,398 / 17,406 
Injured: NUD / 374,008 
In Hospital: NUD / 13,851

As of 2008-06-18 / 06-17
Death: 69,176 / 69,172
Lost: 17,415 / 17,420 
Injured: 374,008 / 374,159 
In Hospital: NUD / 13,851 

As of 2008-06-14
Death: 69,170
Lost: 17,428
Injured: 374,159
In Hospital: 14,617

As of 2008-06-13 / 06-12
Death: 69,163 / 69,146
Lost: 17,445 / 17,516
Injured: 374,142 / 374,131
In Hospital: 15,007 / 15,802

As of 2008-06-11 / 06-10
Death: 69,146 / 69,146
Lost: 17,516 / 17,516
Injured: 374,131 / 374,072
In Hospital: NUD / 15,802

As of 2008-06-09 / 06-08
Death: 69,142 / 69,136
Lost: ? / 17,686
Injured: 374,065 / 374,061
In Hospital: 16,019 / 16,049

As of 2008-06-07 / 06-06
Death: 69,134 / 69,130
Lost: 17,681 / 17,824
Injured: 374,061 / 374,031
In Hospital: 16,302 / 16,463

As of 2008-06-05 / 06-04
Death: 69,127 / 69,122
Lost: 17,918 / 17,991 
Injured: 373,612 / 373,606
In Hospital: 20,878 / 21,097

As of 2008-06-03 / 06-02
Death: 69,107 / 69,019
Lost: 18,230 / 18,627
Injured: 373,577 / 373,573
In Hospital: 11,342 / 11,832

As of 2008-06-01 / 05-31
Death: 69,016 / 68,977
Lost: 18,830 / 17,974
Injured: 368,545 / 367,854
In Hospital: 12,243 / 12,797

As of 2008-05-30 / 05-29
Death: 68,858 / 68,516
Lost: 18,618 / 19,350
Injured: 366,586 / 365,399
In Hospital: 13,828 / 15,388

As of 2008-05-28 / 05-27
Death: 68,109 / 67,183
Lost: 19,851 / 20,790
Injured: 364,552 / 361,822
In Hospital: 15,394 / 22,651

As of 2008-05-26 / 06-25
Death: 65,080 / 62,664
Lost: 23,150 / 23,775
Injured: 360,058 / 358,816
In Hospital: No Update / 31,081

As of 2008-05-24 / 05-23
Death: 60,560 / 55,740
Lost: 26,221 / 24,960
Injured: 352,290 / 292,481
In Hospital: 23,864 / 28,377

As of 2008-05-22 / 05-21
Death: 51,151 / 41,353
Lost: 29,328 / 71,000
Injured: 288,431 / 27,000
In Hospital: 33,665 / 52,934

Background Music
Artist: Ondekoza 鬼太鼓座 
Album: Legend 傳說 1994
Song: Odaiko ... Part 1

*
 The most affecting story in the earthquake in China 
 May 19, 2008 11:32 AM 
Most affecting story in the earthquake in China. I wish all of them go well as soon as possible.
Story: It&apos;s told us about a mother who protected her baby from break down. She wrote a message to her baby:&quot;If you can escape, please remember mother loved you. I am lucky to be your mother in this life. &quot;

The words below are the of the video
==============================
Baby, if you are alive,
Mother would smile in heaven,
Is your fragile body as warn as mother&apos;s bosom?
Are your beautiful eyes also as pure as you came to the world? (Born)
Baby, I saw your face when you are sleeping today,
Quietly lying in the embrace of the People&apos;s Liberation Army uncle,
Mom really feels comforted and pleased,
The moment when the earthquake occurred, all the world are shaking,
Mom took you in my embrace ，running out as soon as possible.
However the floor breaks down, beam collapsed,
The big stone hit on mother&apos;s leg,
I can only take you in my embrace to kneel,
Baby, I am so worried:
Were you awaked by the voice?
Were you squeezed by the big stone?
Baby, it&apos;s darker and darker, and mother&apos;s body become colder and colder,
I don&apos;t know how long can I hold out,
I don&apos;t know if we can sustain until the rescuer come to save us?
I want...; I want to kiss your face,
I want to listen to your silvery laughter,
I want to accompany you when you grow up day after day.
When hearing you call &quot;Mum&quot; the first time, with your cute voice,
I feel proud.
Baby, if you are alive.
Please remember &quot;I love you.&quot;
May be...,
There is no chance to tell you personally,
I am so... so... love you,
I can only write it down in my mobile phone by my injured hand.
Please remember &quot;I love you, my honey baby.&quot;
I brought you to the world.
I am your mother, forever.
 四川地震 earthquake in China 终极版 
 May 19, 2008 6:31 AM 
Donate your love~!
 For Sichuan Earthquake victims: China Go! 中国万岁！ 
 May 18, 2008 11:59 PM 
After 3-minute mourning silence, in Beijing Tian&apos;an men Square, thousands of Chinese people shouting out: China Go! Sichuan Go! Wenchuan Go! Long Live China!
 Earthquake In China 
 May 18, 2008 2:30 PM 
Northernguychina&apos;s slideshow of the earthquake in China, set to &quot;Grace Of God&quot;, by Clay Aiken. Relief donations can be made to: www.unicef .org/china&amp;www.redcross .org
 Villages abandoned after earthquake hit - 17 May 2008 
 May 17, 2008 5:55 AM 
Al Jazeera&apos;s Melissa Chan reports on a devastated town on Qingcheng Mountain, that has been nearly abandoned following the earthquake.
Five days have passed since the 7.9 magnitude earthquake rocked western China, and the scale of the disaster is still unfolding.
 Be with you forever生死不离-成龙Jackie Chan(earthquake hit china) 
 May 17, 2008 4:40 AM 
maybe i shouldnot upload this vedio because some people in the pictures have already gone...praying for you.. Love and hope can make miracle to save your life，Your shouting and crying make my heart broken.( this vedio is from sohu.com&quot;
 Earthquake in China. School collapse. The Aftershocks 
 May 17, 2008 1:56 AM 
The Sichuan disaster may have wider political implications.

May 21, 2008 · China has vowed to deal severely with anyone found responsible for shoddy state building work. The vow came after nearly 7,000 collapsed in the earthquake last week, killing thousands of students.

Now some parents are trying to pressure the local government into conducting investigations into their allegations of local corruption, greed and mismanagement.

A catastrophic chain of events led to the collapse of one school in the town of Wufu.

At the Fuxing primary school Wednesday, funeral music played as parents lined the driveway. Each wore a black armband and carried the photo of a lost child. Their faces were drawn with sleeplessness and grief.

At least 127 students died when the three-story school collapsed. The buildings around the school are largely undamaged — leaving parents angry.

&quot;We parents don&apos;t believe our children died in a natural disaster,&quot; said Chen Hupei, his eyes red. &quot;It was man-made.&quot;

Chen Hupei&apos;s 10-year-old son, Chen Xin, who loved roller skating and basketball, died in a ground-floor because he couldn&apos;t escape in time.

Another parent tapped the steel rebar in the concrete pillars. The parents believe there was too little steel in the building&apos;s structure, that its foundations weren&apos;t sunk deep enough and that there were no emergency exits.

&quot;I believe the government meant well when it built this school,&quot; Chen said. &quot;But some corrupt officials were saving money to pocket themselves. This school was built in 1989 when the safety guidelines weren&apos;t so strict. But it should have been subject to safety checks twice a year, under a law passed two years ago.&quot;

Zhu Qi, the deputy director of Mianzhu education bureau, came to the school to meet the parents, but he denied responsibility.

&quot;Building safety is a matter for the construction bureau,&quot; he said, standing shoulder to shoulder with the school&apos;s headmaster. &quot;I&apos;m not passing the buck. We&apos;ll take responsibility for whatever is ours to deal with.&quot;

One angry parent shouted that none of the buildings fell down as he gestured at surrounding blocks, while following the official around.

Many noticed the town&apos;s government buildings were largely undamaged. It is a pattern that has been repeated elsewhere.

That is because China is building its schools on the cheap. Regulations allow a budget of $350 per square meter to build government offices in towns. That compares with the cost of $64 per square meter for schools in one nearby county. Money is at the heart of what went wrong here.

Another parent accused the school authorities of renting out the newer one-story to a business to make money — moving the children into the older building. The newer were unscathed. She says that the authorities condemned the children to death.

&quot;I&apos;ve never signed any rental contract,&quot; headmaster Wang Weiguo said, denying the allegations. &quot;And the relevant authorities never told me the school building was unsafe.&quot;

The parents were also angry with the school&apos;s teachers, all of whom escaped the building and fled the scene.

&quot;Look at my hands,&quot; one parent says. &quot;I dug through the rubble to look for my children. Then look at the teachers&apos; hands.&quot;

Some like Chen Hupei believe the law --- and the central government --- are on their side.

&quot;The government will help us get justice,&quot; Chen says. &quot;The government is good; it&apos;s just certain officials who aren&apos;t.&quot;

Yang Rong clutched her daughter&apos;s dictionary of proverbs to her chest. She found it in a pile of schoolbags lying in the debris. She opened the front page and found the word mama written inside the front cover.

The parents built their own shrine. They gathered desks from the and placed pictures of some of the children who died on them. Incense burned in front of the desks. And a sign ran across the top of the shrine that says: &quot;Let us remember with pain our children who died in vain.&quot;

The cameras clicked as one young woman broke down, stroking the photo of her bright-eyed son as if it might bring him back.

The parents want journalists — and the outside world — to bear witness to their suffering. Only then can they bring about change.
 China Earthquake caused by HAARP weapon 引发地震的证据 
 May 16, 2008 3:38 AM 
Prove of HAARP was used to cause the big earthquake in China.
World War III is coming... borealis

HAARP武器引发四川大地震，有证据。
中国四川汶川 大地震

刚看到一个日本人fonett写的：
&quot;为何是四川省?
宣汉普光煤气、在中国国内过去最大规模的超大型煤气田。西藏民族多。
为何，是这个时期？
西藏问题。把中国政府做为替罪羊。
胡锦涛主席、对日本的春暖的旅行。
「中国、俄罗斯、伊朗、日本」使之损坏4个国家的关系。
SARS只感染亚洲人种。禽流感也是病毒兵器。
为何，做那样的事？
Illuminati想开展世界大战。本意为了是减少人工，管理少的人类。
是世界支配的长期性的计划。
全世界的实现基础设施和饥饿，播撒病毒，世界战争,全部同时实行着。别打搅中国的发展。为了这个不可丢失人命。不是自然灾害。是恶魔的攻击。
至今还相信优生学的一部分的白人是真正犯人。
他们是发疯。预言的实行。这个相信是神的意思。

中国请绝对召开奥林匹克运动会。 beijing olympics
祈祷北京奥林匹克运动会的成功。
我是日本人。衷心支援!　中国加油!&quot;
我fdsaxxx要加四川是人口最密集的和中国的核武器研究中心在那。

A comment from a Japanese, named fonett:
&quot;why sichuan? cause theres china&apos;s largest natural gas field, SARS was a biological weapon by these same people.
why they do it? start ww3 essence is to kill off most of the human race, manage less people in the new world order plan. it&apos;s all starting right now with basic food shortages, spreading disease, and war. to present day there are still groups of white men believe racial superiority, they are the true criminals, they are crazy; believe it&apos;s destiny and god&apos;s will to do this.
 olympics must be hold, wish china have successful olympics. i am japanese, sincerely support... go china!&quot; 
 and i have to add sichuan is china&apos;s most populous province, and where china&apos;s nuclear research center and site are.
Prove of HAARP was used to cause the big earthquake in China.

HAARP info: http://www.conspiracyarchive.com/NWO/HAARP.htm
http://www.mediarare.com/haarp.html
 china earthquake 
 May 16, 2008 1:38 AM 
china earthquake, sichuan china, wenxian, 中国地震, 四川地震, 汶县, 北川
 UpDate, Earthquake in China 50,000 fear dead 7.8 Richter Sca 
 May 15, 2008 8:35 PM 
www.dateordis.com www.dateordis.com www.dateordis.com www.dateordis.com
May 15th 2008 Latest video from the Earthquake in Sichuan CHINA
Thanks to Anderson Cooper and his 360 dispatch crew for providing this video earthquake in china. The death toll is pushing 50,000. More than 4,000,000 homes and properties have been destroyed. 20,000 people are homeless; Dub the worst natural disaster in 30 years dead bodies crash in the concrete. This image is disturbing.
.dateordis.com www.dateordis.com
 Terremoto en China. Earthquake in China 
 May 15, 2008 3:09 PM 
http://geologia-hoy.blogspot.com

Earthquake in China, and its aftermath. Story and clip from Che Jia Va taken from the CNN website. Hell on Earth.

Destructivo terremoto en China. Vídeo tomado de la web de la CNN, desde Che Jia Va. Miles de muertos, pocos recursos. El infierno en la Tierra.
 Ch 9 Australia Reports on Sichuan Earthquake in China 
 May 15, 2008 2:45 PM 
Ch 9 Australia Reports on Sichuan Earthquake in China. 
The earthquake broke out at 2:28pm, May 12th local time, measuring 7.8 Richter Scale, killed 10s of 1000s. 
The video was recorded at around 7am May 16th.
 earthquake at china (7.9 magnitude) 
 May 14, 2008 5:02 PM 
some pictures form disaster area. about 18000 people dead, and 28000 lossing.
 the earthquake in china-a video by qinwei owner 
 May 14, 2008 4:55 PM 
5.12 quake in sichuan province in china.come together china.photos from xinhuanet
 Major earthquakes in China over past 5 years 
 May 14, 2008 2:40 PM 
05-13-2008 18:59

China is located in one of the most active seismic regions of the world and has suffered numerous destructive earthquakes. We now take a look at a chronology of some of the biggest over the past 5 years.

In February 2003, an earthquake measuring 6.8 magnitude hit the sparsely populated Jiashi county in Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region in northwest of the country. 94 people died and more than 200 were injured.

In November 2005, an earthquake measuring 5.7 magnitude jolted Jiangxi province in east China, leaving more than two hundred and fifty thousand people homeless.

In 2006, An earthquake measuring 5.1 on the Richter scale struck Wenan county in north China&apos;s Hebei province on July 4th. No immediate casualties were reported.

And just 3 weeks later, another 5.1 earthquake hit southwestern Yunnan Province. This time at least 22 people were killed and more than 100 injured.

In December 2006, a series of tremors off the southern coast of Taiwan Island killed two people and injured 42. The quake measured 7.2 on the Richter Scale, and was followed by over a hundred aftershocks.

In June 2007, Yunnan was hit again, by a 6.4 magnitude earthquake. Three people died and more than five hundred were injured.

In March 2008, an earthquake measuring 7.2 rocked the remote northwestern region of Xinjiang. The damage was limited.

Original video:
http://www.cctv.com/video/worldwidewatch/2008/05/worldwidewatch_300_20080513_17.shtml
 30 mins before the 2008 Sichuan earthquake in China 
 May 14, 2008 2:25 PM 
Bizarre colorful (luminous/glowing) cloud phenomenon in the sky was observed about 30 mins before the May 12, 2008 Sichuan earthquake took place. This was recorded in Tianshui, Gansu province ~450km northeast of epicenter, by someone using a cell phone.
source: http://news.qq.com/a/20080513/004283.htm

See similar cloud formation captured 20 minutes later in a different city, ~200km east of this location: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hzVamNQzfYA

A map of the locations with sightings of very similar phenomenon.
http://img223.imageshack.us/img223/2453/ecjm1.jpg

More photos taken, reported 1 hr before the quake.:
http://shenyun.epochtimes.com/b5/8/5/14/n2116538.htm

These clouds seemed to be glowing or somewhat luminous and seemed to resemble some characteristics of the Auroras. I am not sure exactly what they were or whether they indeed had anything to do with the quake. I am no expert anyways. See if any scientists are willing to give a full explanation.

If such phenomenon can be proved for its connection with earthquake occurrences, maybe they could be used as warning signs and would be life saving. If not, just learn these clouds as yet another rare atmospheric phenomenon and no need to panic when seeing them.

After all, this might well be just a rare atmospheric phenomenon occurred by coincidence. Though, just wondering if there&apos;s any possibility the formation of such rare clouds be catalyzed by any event??

I guess some of you might find the following articles interesting.
http://www.spectrum.ieee.org/print/2367
http://online.wsj.com/article/SB121124372394605609.html
http://environment.newscientist.com/article/mg19826514.600-curious-clou
For Chinese readers: (about the poem that predicting the quake)
四川強震／李白「壓箱詩」預言？　純屬網路謠言！
http://www.nownews.com/2008/05/21/162-2278152.htm
 中国四川大地震 ：让我们祈祷 (Sichuan China Earthquake ：Let&apos;s Pray) 
 May 14, 2008 9:54 AM 
轻轻在捧着你的脸，为你把眼泪擦干，这颗心永远属于你，告诉我不再孤单。深深地凝望你的眼，不需要更多的语言，紧紧地握住你的手，这温暖依旧未改变。我们同欢乐，我们同忍受，我们怀着同样的期待，我们同风雨，我们共追求，我们珍存同一样的爱。无论你我可曾相识，无论在眼前在天边，衷心地为你祝愿，祝愿你幸福平安。
 Earthquake in China. Just hold on. 
 May 14, 2008 12:41 AM 
Earthquake in China cause great damage and casualties.Please hold on.
 Earthquake in China, Please Help China 
 May 13, 2008 10:47 PM 
At least three Israelis who were in China during Monday&apos;s massive earthquake have yet to make contact with their families or the Foreign Ministry.

Two students from Jerusalem, Ma&apos;ayan Segev and Anat Bilu, were listed as missing as well, but on Wednesday morning Chinese authorities reportedly said the two were accounted for.

Israel has yet to confirm the report.
 Advertisement
China&apos;s official Xinhua News Agency on Tuesday said the death toll in the 7.9-magnitude quake exceeded 12,000. Tens of thousands were still buried in debris near the epicenter of the earthquake.

It was unclear where the other three Israelis were when the earthquake struck. The Foreign Ministry said on Tuesday that Segev and Bilu, who were part of a group of students of Chinese medicine from the Reidman College of Complementary Medicine, were thought to be alive.

Other members of the student group began searching for Segev and Bilu on Tuesday, and Chinese authorities told the Israeli Embassy they would also join in the search.The Israeli consul in Beijing is having difficulty getting to the region because the airport there and many roads are closed.

Israel offered Tuesday to send Israeli rescue teams to China, but China said it does not require assistance at this point.
 China Sichuan Earthquake * 因为爱 
 May 13, 2008 7:27 PM 
We need your help!
My best friend is still missing! 
-----------------------------------
updates:

Thanks everyone! we found my best friend and all my family members. I really feel the power of prayer. Let&apos;s keep praying for all of other families there who still can not find their families and relatives or who have relatives died, they still need our helps. 
I deeply understand that we are the only few families who were so lucky to have such a good ending. 
Thank you for all of my families here again for your prayers. Without your support, we probably will not be so lucky.

Right now, many families lost their relatives and a lot of people still missing. survivers need medical care, food and water badly. please make donations to help them.

------------------------------------------

Mercy Corp online donation.
http://www.mercycorps.org/countries/china/2155
Canada Red Cross Online Donation.
http://www.paypaq.com/redcross/new/index.php
China Red Cross Online Donation.
http://www.redcross.org.cn/

If you reside in the US,especially if you are in greater Los Angeles area, you can call 1-626-974-0153 to get details on how you can help. Monetary and Material donations are both urgently in need.
Asian American associates on that phone line will help you complete and allocate your donations in the most efficient way.

UK:
http://www.redcross.org.uk/donatesection.asp?id=77029&amp;campaigntab;=single
USA
http://www.redcross.org/news/in/profiles/Intl_profile_ChinaEarthquake.asp?s_src=HomeLatestNews#HelpNow
Canadian Redcross:
http://www.redcross.ca/article.asp?id=27348&amp;tid;=001
Australian
http://www.redcross.org.au/ourservices_aroundtheworld_emergencyrelief_Chinaearthquake.htm
 10 mins before the 2008 Sichuan earthquake in China 
 May 13, 2008 6:44 PM 
Bizarre glowing cloud phenomenon in the sky was observed about 10 mins before the May 12, 2008 Sichuan earthquake took place. This was recorded in Meixian, Shaanxi province ~550km northeast of epicenter. The phenomenon was said to last for about 1 min.
source: http://v.youku.com/v_show/id_cb00XMjczNTczNDA=.html

A map showing two locations where such clouds were sighted relative to Sichuan earthquake epicenters: http://img223.imageshack.us/img223/2453/ecjm1.jpg

See similar clouds appeared ~200km west of this location:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KKMTSDzU1Z4

More photos (reported taken 1 hr before the quake):
http://shenyun.epochtimes.com/b5/8/5/14/n2116538.htm

These clouds seemed to be glowing or somewhat luminous and seemed to resemble some characteristics of the Auroras. I am not sure exactly what they were or whether they indeed had anything to do with the quake. I am no expert anyways. See if any scientists are willing to give a full explanation.

If such phenomenon can be proved for its connection with earthquake occurrences, maybe they could be used as warning signs and would be life saving. If not, just learn these clouds as yet another rare atmospheric phenomenon and no need to panic when seeing them.

After all, this might well be just a rare atmospheric phenomenon occurred by coincidence. Though, just wondering if there&apos;s any possibility the formation of such rare clouds be catalyzed by any event??

I guess some of you might find the following articles interesting.
http://www.spectrum.ieee.org/print/2367
http://online.wsj.com/article/SB121124372394605609.html
http://environment.newscientist.com/article/mg19826514.600-curious-clou

For Chinese readers: (about the poem that predicting the quake)
四川強震／李白「壓箱詩」預言？　純屬網路謠言！
http://www.nownews.com/2008/05/21/162-2278152.htm
 Massive 7.8 Earthquake Hits China! May &apos;08 地震 
 May 13, 2008 5:37 PM 
The most powerful earthquake in 30 years devastated the southwest of the country. 
Rescue teams are digging through rubble, trying to reach survivors of a powerful earthquake in China. Bodies covered with sheets lined streets yesterday as rescue workers dug through schools and homes turned into rubble. The total number of casualties remains unknown as heavy storms prevented relief workers from reaching victims at the epicenter of the powerful quake. The official death toll rose to more than 12,000 in Sichuan Province alone, with thousands remained buried or missing.

There was concern today for a group of 15 British tourists missing in the Chinese earthquake. The quake was centered just north of the Sichuan provincial capital, Chengdu, tearing into urban areas and mountain villages. In Mianyang City alone near the epicenter, 3,629 people were dead and 18,645 were still buried in debris, Xinhua reported. 

At least 4,800 people also remained buried in Mianzhu, 100km from the epicenter, Xinhua said, citing local authorities. in Gansu Province, a 40-car freight train derailed in the quake that included 13 gasoline tankers was still burning yesterday, Xinhua said.
In Chengdu, gasoline lines grew and people huddled by TVs in shops and hotels watching the news. Grocery stores shelves were almost empty and the fast food restaurant KFC had run out of food.
In Turkey&apos;s devastating 1999 earthquake, building codes were excellent, but &quot;fly by night builders&quot; had erected buildings using &quot;extremely poor&quot; materials. 
This seems to be the case in China as many schools collapsed. I guess you can buy the building inspector, but you can&apos;t buy off the earthquake.
One of the last survivors of the quake, a woman who survived on rainwater was freed after being trapped in rubble for 195 hours. Chinese government officials raised the death toll to 60,560 with another 26,221 people missing and 353,290 injured.

Nearly every building in Yingxiu was destroyed and no residents remain there. Calls for aid help were have been sent to the international community.
Latest: Two more aftershocks struck quake-ravaged China this week, injuring at least 63 people and causing the collapse of more than 420,000 homes, according to the state-run news agency Xinhua.
 After the Earthquake in China, Please Help Them 
 May 13, 2008 1:54 PM 
Pictures after the earthquake disater.
Please help the survivals.
 Disaster bought fear, Love brings hope May13th 
 May 13, 2008 9:36 AM 
This video is only few hours after the disaster. there is other rescues, news already done that.Those men are from locals,
supplies and equipment could not be provided due to heavy rain and major routes are being block by falling rocks.


Earthquake in Sichuan China lil girl saved

Thousands of Chinese are buried alive in China due to a 7.8 magnitude earthquake.
Major roads are being block by falling rocks and heavy rains are causing more difficulties.
China is sending paratroopers but landing at such hazard area great risks are involved.
Prime Minister Weng a 66 years old man demand to be at the scene to instruct the rescue and bring hope to the people.


Up to May13th 7am the government has sent one hundred and thirty thousands soldiers and rescued around one thousand eight hundreds people. 

At a primary school, students and teachers still trapped. 
Reporter: Anyone down there. 
Police: yes, and they are calling for help. Around 7 of them.
P: Lil girl, do not talk, save your self, I will get you out.
Girl: I m scared the building will fall.
P Trust me, I will not let the building fall, I will make sure it doesn&apos;t. Did you hear me? Be good.
:
As heavy lifting machine can&apos;t be used, it could cause the remains to collapse and hurt the children, local police is digging concrete structure with bare hands to retrieve the buried survivors.

salute to those soldiers.


longbao aka firdonyt
刚看完卫星传输的救灾现场画面，一群解放军战士在抢救被掩埋的学校学生情景，因为担心大型机械可能会对被掩埋人员造成伤害，战士们就用手一点一点的挖土。
　　在听到下面有孩子的声音时，他们就呼唤孩子要保存体力，孩子在下面还乖乖的说&quot;怕上面东西掉下来&quot;，战士就说&quot;放心，叔叔不会让东西掉下去的！&quot;看的我那个心堵的疼啊，眼泪如雨！！！加油战士！加油孩子！！加油！！！！！！！！！俺说不下去了！！！！！
　　
　　刚看完卫星传输的救灾现场画面，一群解放军战士在抢救被掩埋的学校学生情景，因为担心大型机械可能会对被掩埋人员造成伤害，战士们就用手一点一点的挖土。
　　在听到下面有孩子的声音时，他们就呼唤孩子要保存体力，孩子在下面还乖乖的说&quot;怕上面东西掉下来&quot;，战士就说&quot;放心，叔叔不会让东西掉下去的！&quot;

Disaster bought fear, Love brings hope.
 Best Wishes to People Suffering 7.8-mag Earthquake in China 
 May 13, 2008 9:17 AM 
Life is given to us,
we earn it by giving it. 

Let the dead have the immortality of peace,
but the living the immortality of love.
============
Donation to China Red Cross:
http://202.108.59.10/english/donate.htm
 
1. Mail payment remittance
To:the Red Cross Society of China
Address: No.53 ganmianhutong
Dongcheng district
Beijing,100010

2. Bank post remittance (Someone got difficulty with this method)
Bank name: Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Dong Si Nan Branch, Beijing
Account number: 02000010090144132—52
Account Name: the Red Cross Society of China

3. Wire Transfer (verified to be working!)
NAME： CHINESE RED CROSS
BANK NAME： CHINA CITIC BANK
SWIFT NUMBER：CIBKCNBJ
ACCT#：7112111482600000209

4. Send a check/money order/Cashier&apos;s check to Chinese Consulate General in New York.
Title: &quot;Chinese Consulate General in New York&quot;
Add a note (For): &quot;Earthquake Relief Donation&quot;
Mailing address:
Consulate General of People&apos;s Republic of China in New York
520 12th Avenue, New York, NY 10036-1003
Tel: 212.244.9392
 EARTHQUAKE IN CHINA Sichuan - LIVE RECORDING 
 May 13, 2008 9:08 AM 
http://www.buyawebsitetraffic.com
Sichuan, China big earthquake caused thousands of people die.
 7.9 Earthquake Hits China Chengdu, 12 May 2008. 
 May 13, 2008 6:40 AM 
12 May 2008.
7.9 Earthquake Hits China Chengdu.
 Earthquake LIVE China Chengdu Wenchuan May 12, 08 
 May 13, 2008 4:00 AM 
Live Video... A 7.9 magnitude Earthquake hit western China,Chengdu Wenchuan and state media says more than 80,000 people have been killed, while some 47000 are trapped in a collapsed schools. (May 12, 2008) 

national mourning for the dead that now stands officially at 80,500.

The fresh tremor, which measured 5.7 in magnitude, brought down a large number of houses, damaged 377 km of roads and six bridges, rescue authorities said late on Sunday.

In the provincial capital, Chengdu, some 200 km south of the epicentre, thousands fled swaying buildings, Xinhua said.

More than six days after the main quake of 7.9 magnitude rattled Sichuan province, authorities are worried by the aftershocks and the build up of water in blocked rivers and have tried to stop people from entering the affected area.

China says it expects the final death toll to exceed 50,000. About 4.8 million people have lost their homes.

Three days of national mourning were declared from Monday, with flags flying at half mast, public entertainment suspended and a three-minute silence observed to mark exactly one week since the quake, the government website www.gov.cn said

State television said the Olympic torch relay through China would also be suspended for three days.
Everyone loves to vacation! Ask yourself, &quot;if you had all the time and money in the world, what would you do&quot;? That&apos;s right -- TRAVEL! And we don&apos;t have to create or change anyone&apos;s buying habits. People you know are already traveling... someone is getting paid for booking it... Why not you? NO FEE to Be A Sales Rep
Website: http://www.FUNTRAVELCO.com

#69 - Most Viewed (Today)
#20 - Most Viewed (Today) - Directors
#85 - Most Viewed (This Week) - Directors
 中国四川5.12大地震,China 7.8 magnitude earthquake 
 May 13, 2008 3:10 AM 
中国四川在5月12日发生了7.8级的大地震,上万人死亡,数万人无家可归,请全世界的华人,全世界的朋友,尽上您的一份力量,谢谢!
An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.8 struck China&apos;s Sichuan province 12,may.
please give a donate
 Earthquake in China cause 900 children buried in school 2008 
 May 12, 2008 5:17 PM 
Aftershocks in China bring fears of even greater damage and more casualties. CNN&apos;s Jaime FlorCruz reports
 Massive Earthquake hits China 
 May 12, 2008 5:03 PM 
This is a major earthquake event very large scale. Watch the weather change! The Pole-Shift has begun. Update: 05/26/08- over 420,000 more homes fall down after more aftershocks (quakes). Update: 6.8 earthquake off the coast of Taiwan, the epicenter was 29 miles (46 kilometers) below the ocean surface. 05/31/08
 earthquake in China - sichuan province 5/12/2008 Part 3 
 May 12, 2008 4:34 PM 
Bless all the quake affected people.
 earthquake in China -sichuan province 5/12/2008 Part 1 
 May 12, 2008 4:18 PM 
Bless all the quake affected people.
 7.9 Earthquake Hits China 
 May 12, 2008 2:42 PM 
May 12, 2008 CHENGDU, China -- A strong earthquake hits China and killed nearly 19,000 people in Sichuan provinces on Monday. About 900 students were trapped under the rubble of their school and caused a toxic chemical leak, state media reported. The quake hit about 60 miles northwest of Chengdu, a city of about 3.75 million in the middle of the afternoon when and office towers were full. When it hit shortly before 2:30 p.m., the quake rumbled for nearly three minutes driving people into the streets in panic. The 7.9-magnitude earthquake devastated a hilly region of small cities and towns in central China. 200 others were killed in three other provinces and the mega-city of Chongqing. 

News report that 80 percent of the buildings had collapsed in Sichuan province&apos;s Beichuan county after the quake, raising fears that the overall death toll could increase sharply. State media said a chemical plant in Shifang city had cratered, burying hundreds of people and spilling more than 80 tons of toxic liquid ammonia from the site. The earthquake sent thousands of people rushing out of buildings and into the streets hundreds of miles away in Beijing and Shanghai. The temblor was felt as far away as Vietnam and Thailand. It posed a challenge to a government already grappling with discontent over high inflation and a widespread uprising among Tibetans in western China while trying to prepare for the Beijing Olympics this August. US President George W. Bush on Monday offered his condolences to China over a devastating earthquake that killed thousands of people and said the United States &quot;stands ready to help.

My thoughts and prayers to all of the injured, fatalities and their families.
 Strong Earthquake Hits China - OperationBlessing 
 May 12, 2008 12:12 PM 
Thanks to operationblessing for upload this video to YouTube.
http://www.youtube.com/user/operationblessing

&quot;China moves quickly in quake zone&quot;
http://www.csmonitor.com/2008/0513/p01s04-woap.html
Beijing - As the death toll from Monday&apos;s earthquake mounted, China threw its Army into rescue operations -- reflecting the priority that Beijing has increasingly put on efficient disaster relief. 
The country appears to be well prepared for such an operation, says Roger Musson, a seismologist at the British Geological Survey in Edinburgh. &quot;They are very good at putting together a disaster relief plan rather quickly.&quot; 

More than 6,000 soldiers and militarized police were dispatched to the disaster area, carrying out standing orders in the event of an earthquake, a military spokesman said. 
Prime Minister Wen Jiabao, who flew to Chengdu, the provincial capital of Sichuan, less than two hours after the quake hit, told reporters en route that government leaders have &quot;asked officials at all levels to be at the front line of the fighting the earthquake and lead the people in their rescue work.&quot; 

Vast improvements in disaster relief 

China&apos;s annual buffeting from typhoons has led the authorities to build an efficient disaster relief structure, according to Xue Lan, professor of public administration at Beijing&apos;s Tsinghua University. 

&quot;One dramatic improvement is in life-saving&quot; says Professor Xue. &quot;Death tolls have been falling in recent years even though typhoons have been getting fiercer. China is doing much better than it used to, and than other developing countries [are].&quot; 

As well as passing a special law on emergency management last year, setting out the government&apos;s responsibilities, China has built a regional network of emergency management offices, reporting to the State Council, which acts as the government&apos;s cabinet. 

In a Category 1 disaster, as Monday&apos;s quake was declared, local officials are authorized to ignore normal chains of command and report directly to the top levels of government, according to Mao Shoulong, professor of public policy at Renmin University in Beijing. 

In addition to the thousands of soldiers and police dispatched to the epicenter in Wenchuan county, emergency medical teams were sent from major cities on the east coast to the quake zone. 

Their departure displayed a speed of official response that critics said had been lacking during China&apos;s last natural disaster, blizzards that gripped the south of the country last January.
 China Earthquake 7.8 [2008/05/12] 
 May 12, 2008 8:10 AM 
[2008/05/12] - Magnitude 7.8 in China, taken back by a security camera...

--------------------------------
SCTV 4 News (in Sichuan): http://wwitv.com/a1/b3686.asx

(Update) Floods force 70,000 from China quake zone 

SANSHUI, China (Reuters) - China has evacuated more than 70,000 people near the epicentre of last month&apos;s devastating earthquake to avoid further casualties from landslides and other disasters during the country&apos;s deadly annual flood season...

Leggi:
http://today.reuters.co.uk/news/articlenews.aspx?type=worldNews&amp;storyid;=2008-06-19T074044Z_01_PEK18118_RTRUKOC_0_UK-CHINA-FLOODS.xml

--------------------------------

Blog News&amp;Earthquakes Live: http://giorgius.ilcannocchiale.it/

--------------------------------
 Earthquake in China Sichuan Province May 12 
 May 12, 2008 7:23 AM 
video from mobile cam in Chendu, the capital of Sichuan Province
 Deadly Earthquake Rattles China 
 May 12, 2008 5:49 AM 
A 7.8 magnitude earthquake hit western China, and state media says more than 100 people have been killed, while some 900 are trapped in a collapsed school. (May 12)
 earthquake in China 
 May 12, 2008 5:38 AM 
some college boy taped by his cellphone.
He said:&quot;Don&apos;t get out from that desk!&quot;
&quot;Oh,damm, I just want 2 say: I luv U!dude&quot;
..................&quot;This is May 12th,2008.We are in xx college,Chengdu,Sichuan Province,China. There was just an earthquke.A lot of people went 2 the ground.The build is still shaking.It&apos;s real,I&apos;m not faking U! &quot;
 5.12.08 7.8M Earthquake in Sichuan China 
 May 12, 2008 3:22 AM 
Sichuan University student takes video at 2:29pm in dorm.

The 2008 Sichuan earthquake shook Wenchuan County, Sichuan province of the People&apos;s Republic of China at 14:28:04 local time (06:28:04 GMT). It had a magnitude of 7.8 Mw according to the State Seismological Bureau of China and United States Geological Survey. The earthquake was felt as far away as Beijing and Shanghai, where office buildings swayed with the impact and Vietnam capital Hanoi.The closest major city from the earthquake&apos;s epicenter is Chengdu.

The epicenter was at 31.084°N, 103.267°E, in Wenchuan County, Ngawa Prefecture, 90 km northwest of Chengdu, Sichuan, China, with its main tremor so far occurring at 14:28:04 local time (06:28:04 am GMT) on Monday 12 May 2008. Early reports of the earthquake&apos;s Richter scale magnitude ranged from 7.6 to 8.0. Five major aftershocks ranging in magnitude from 4.0 to 6.0 were recorded within two hours of the main tremor.

Office workers in Chengdu reported a &quot;continuous shaking for about two or three minutes&quot;, with many people rushing outside.
 the earthquake hit china (hot news !!) 
 May 12, 2008 3:17 AM 
the earthquake hit china
 Powerful Earthquake Shakes China 
 May 12, 2008 2:07 AM 
The U.S. Geological Survey says a major earthquake with a preliminary magnitude of 7.5 has struck western China. (May 12)
 God pls help them!!!! Sichuan earthquake! China 四川地震 
 Apr 13, 2008 7:26 AM 
God pls help them!!!!Victim Sichuan earthquake in China 四川地震
救命病棟24時の主題歌ですが? いい!!!
This is not the end... it is the beginning...{Ú i vethed nâ i onnad.}The strength, the weapon{i tuo i macil}

GOD n angel will fall into earth n help those ppl in suffering!!!!!

let us pray for those who really needed help!!!!God pls help them!!!! ppl in Sichuan earthquake! in China 四川地震
 dbickfordtRUTHTV NWONEWS! 7.2 EARTHQUAKE IN CHINA 20 MARCH 8 
 Mar 24, 2008 2:54 PM 
The Military&apos;s Pandora&apos;s Box

by Dr. Nick Begich and Jeane Manning

This article was prepared to provide a summary of the contents of a book written in 1995 which describes an entirely new of weapons. The weapons and their effects are described in the following pages. The United States Navy and Air Force have joined with the University of Alaska, Fairbanks, to build a prototype for a ground based &quot;Star Wars&quot; weapon system located in the remote bush country of Alaska.

The individuals who are demanding answers about HAARP are scattered around the planet. As well as bush dwellers in Alaska, they include: a physician in Finland; a scientist in Holland; an anti-nuclear protester in Australia; independent physicists in the United States; a grandmother in Canada, and countless others.

Unlike the protests of the 1960s the objections to HAARP have been registered using the tools of the 1990s. From the Internet, fax machines, syndicated talk radio and a number of alternative print mediums the word is getting out and people are waking up to this new intrusion by an over zealous United States government.

The research team put together to gather the materials which eventually found their way into the book never held a formal meeting, never formed a formal organization. Each person acted like a node on a planetary info-spirit-net with one goal held by all -- to keep this controversial new science in the public eye. The result of the team&apos;s effort was a book which describes the science and the political ramifications of this technology.

That book, Angels Don&apos;t Play this HAARP: Advances in Tesla Technology, has 230 pages. This article will only give the highlights. Despite the amount of research (350 footnoted sources), at its heart it is a story about ordinary people who took on an extraordinary challenge in bringing their research forward.


HAARP Boils the Upper Atmosphere

HAARP will zap the upper atmosphere with a focused and steerable electromagnetic beam. It is an advanced model of an &quot;ionospheric heater.&quot; (The ionosphere is the electrically-charged sphere surrounding Earth&apos;s upper atmosphere. It ranges between 40 to 60 miles above the surface of the Earth.)

Put simply, the apparatus for HAARP is a reversal of a radio telescope; antenna send out signals instead of receiving. HAARP is the test run for a super-powerful radiowave-beaming technology that lifts areas of the ionosphere by focusing a beam and heating those areas. Electromagnetic waves then bounce back onto earth and penetrate everything -- living and dead.

HAARP publicity gives the impression that the High-frequency Active Auroral Research Program is mainly an academic project with the goal of changing the ionosphere to improve communications for our own good. However, other U.S. military documents put it more clearly -- HAARP aims to learn how to &quot;exploit the ionosphere for Department of Defense purposes.&quot; Communicating with submarines is only one of those purposes.
 
 
Related Topics
 YouTube: China Earthquake 
 0 followers, 13901 views, 409 events YouTube: 2008 China Earthquake 
 0 followers, 954 views, 50 events YouTube: China Earthquake 2008 
 0 followers, 954 views, 53 events YouTube: Earthquake China 
 0 followers, 2158 views, 50 events China Earthquake 
 0 followers, 1747 views, 0 events LA Earthquake 
 0 followers, 1859 views, 1 event YouTube: Earthquake 
 0 followers, 11824 views, 228 events Flickr search for: china earthquake 
 0 followers, 3217 views, 0 events Flickr: earthquake in china 
 0 followers, 554 views, 0 events Flickr: china earthquake 
 0 followers, 1092 views, 0 events 
 
 
 A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 
 Copyright©2011 Underlying, Inc.
 Blog | Help | About | Developers | Contact | Directory | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
