<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008026" url="http://www.romanceforeveryone.com/romantic-ideas/a-cheap-date-idea.html" time="2012-07-13-01:05" support="33" score="0.09019997340546985" bingtitle="A Cheap Date Idea - Romance For Everyone - Romantic Love Letters ..." webtitle="A Cheap Date Idea">
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001026" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>When your friend seats you and your date at the ... you probably should avoid going to a fast food restaurant. You can pull off a similar cheap date ordering pizza ...</description>
	<body>
		Romance For Everyone &gt; Romantic Ideas &gt;A Cheap Date Idea 
A Cheap Date Idea

A Fancy Cheap Date
 
Not everyone has an unlimited bankroll to fund a romantic date . If you are young, you may have more energy and enthusiasm than money. Just because 
 you are short of cash does not mean you cant have a nice date with your sweetheart. Here is a cheap 
 date idea that you can set up with a couple of friends that will be fun for everyone.

The first thing you will need to do is find two good friends that are willing to help you plan and 
 execute your cheap date. They should be friends that you can count on since the success or failure 
 of the date will depend on their participation and enthusiasm.

The basic theme of this cheap date is receiving high class service even though you have a limited 
 budget. On your cheap date you are going to take your sweetheart to a nice, fancy fast food restaurant. 
 Your local fast food restaurant may not be nice or fancy, so that is where you friends come in. Basically, 
 your friends are going to set up one of the tables as if it were in a fancy restaurant.



Planning Your Cheap Date

1. Select the nicest fast food restaurant that your budget will allow. Visit the restaurant and 
 ask to talk to the manager. Share your cheap date idea with him or her and ask if that would be okay. 
 The last thing you want to do is get kicked out the restaurant in the middle of your cheap date.

2. After you have the okay from the manager, select a table for your date. A booth would work well, 
 but you might also consider a table off to the side of the restaurant.

3. Dont try to bring outside food into the restaurant. That is a big no-no. Everything you eat and 
 drink will have to be from the fast food restaurants menu.

4. Consider creating your own menu from the options available at the restaurant.



Planning The Table Setting For Your Cheap Date

1. Nicer restaurants generally have a white table cloth. If you dont have one, see if you can 
 find on old bed sheet that you can double over or cut to size.

2. A vase with a rose would be a nice touch. If you cant swing that try for other cut flowers.

3. Cloth napkins would be nice, but decent sized napkins from home or the restaurant would be okay 
 too.

4. Replace the plastic knives and forks with silverware (flatware).

5. Have glasses on the table if the restaurant will allow it, otherwise try for clear hard plastic 
 cups.



Your Fancy Cheap Date

1. On the day of your date, have you friends dress up in their fanciest clothes. They are going 
 to be your waiters.

2. Your friends can setup the table while you pickup your date.

3. As you enter the restaurant with your date, one of your friends will meet you at the door. When 
 you see him or her, ask for a nice table for two. When your friend seats you and your date at the 
 table, he or she says,&quot;Your waiter will be with you shortly&quot;.

4. Once you are seated, your other friend comes to the table. Have your friend introduce themself 
 as your waiter for the evening. Your friend can present the menus or you might just ask them to tell 
 you about the specials of the day.

5. When you and you date have decided what you would like to eat, you waiter takes down your order. 
 Her or she then goes to the fast food counter to place the order and get your drinks.

6. When your order is ready your waiter will place the food on plates and serve the food.

7. Make sure your friend comes by occasionally to check if you need anything.

8. When you are finished with your date, be sure to thank you friends for their great service.

9. After you leave, your friends clean-up. They should also try to thank the manager for allowing 
 you to use their restaurant for your special date.

That is the basic outlines of a nice cheap date. If your sweetheart is easily embarrassed, you probably 
 should avoid going to a fast food restaurant. You can pull off a similar cheap date ordering pizza 
 in a dorm room, Chinese takeout at home or a barbecue in a backyard. You can also do this with a picnic 
 at a beach or a park. Fancy cheap dates can be a lot of fun and the only limits are your imagination.

If you are looking for a fun 
 date idea in the great outdoors, a whitewater rafting trip will provide the fun and excitement 
 that you are looking for.
 
 Romantic Ideas 

 Love Letters 

 Relationship Tips 

 Relationship Advice 

 eHarmony Dating Advice For Women 

 eHarmony Dating Advice For Men 

 Add To Favorites 

Romantic Ideas

 Write An I Love 
 You Letter 

 Write A Romantic 
 Note 

 When Your Sweetheart Is 
 In A Bad Mood 

 Write A Love 
 Letter 

 I Love - A Romantic 
 Game 

 A Cheap Date Idea 

 Read A Love 
 Poem To Your Wife 

 Romantic Rose Petals 

 The Art of Saying 
 You&apos;re Sorry 

 Romantic Candles 

 Read A Love Letter To Your Sweetheart 

 Ask 
 Your Wife Out On A Romantic Date 

 Feed Each Other Grapes 

 Hold Hands In A Restaurant 

 Share A Romantic Dessert 

 Fun Date 
 Idea - Whitewater Rafting 


 Love Letters 

 Love 
 Notes 

 I Miss You 

 I Love You Letter 

 Romantic Notes 

 A Love Note 

 Goodbye Letter 


 Thrifty Living 

 Cheap Cell 
 Phone Service 

 High Interest Saving Accounts 
 
 Romance For Everyone Home 

Copyright 2006 - 2012 RomanceForEveryone.com. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
