<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008578" url="http://www.buysellcommunity.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="1" score="0.0015170966992068204" bingtitle="BuySellCommunity Classifieds - Buy &amp; Sell Locally : Free Online ..." webtitle="BuySellCommunity Classifieds - Buy&amp;Sell Locally : Free Online Classifieds">
			<query id="001059" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>French Bulldog puppies for sale in New York, NJ, LI..5 Boroughs: Make Offer ... The First Years - &quot;Carry-Me-Near&quot; - 5-In-1 Bassinet (Beaver Bank, NS): For Sale $ 85.00</description>
	<body>
		Buy&amp;Sell Locally. FREE Online Classifieds&amp;Store Fronts. Sign Up Now! 
 
 
 
 Find items nearest to your Local Area . register      sign in      about us      refer a friend      site map 
 
 
 
 
   home   
 
   browse   
 
   search   
 
   stores   
 
   sell   
 
   profile   
 
   help   
 
   
   Become A Member      Sign In      Sell Your Stuff      
   Welcome to BuySellCommunity&apos;s Classifieds. Sellers: Post free classified ads and start selling . Buyers: Browse classifieds and start shopping . 
 
 
 
Search Classifieds
 
 
 
 Enter Keywords      Advanced Search 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
Browse Classifieds
 
 
 
 Shop Categories Art&amp;Antiques Automobiles&amp;Other Vehicles Books&amp;Magazines Business / Commercial Clothing&amp;Accessories Collectibles Computers Electronics Entertainment Health&amp;Beauty Hobbies&amp;Crafts Home&amp;Garden Jewelry&amp;Accessories Pets&amp;Animals Real Estate Sports Toys&amp;Games Travel&amp;Events Video Games Everything Else Wanted Items&amp;Services Garage / Moving Sales      View all categories 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Featured Classifieds
 
 
 
 
 Microsoft Office 2010 Professional Plus-Download 1-5 users For Sale $ 85.00 
 
 Adobe Acrobat X Professional (MAC) Download+CD (1-5 user) $85.00 For Sale $ 85.00 
 
 Chihuahua Puppies! Adorable Baby Toys and Teacups For Sale $ 250.00 
 
 Free Junk Car Removal From Annapolis to Glen Burnie Maryland 410 Wanted 
 
 SolidWorks 2010 Premium Download (32/64 Bit)-SC-$135.00 For Sale $ 135.00 
 
 Adobe Photoshop Lightroom 4 new! Download (MAC) For Sale $ 119.00 
 

 
 Up to 50 in Free Bids to GiveAway (Beaumont, QC) : Free Offer queen size and full size bed NEW NEVER USED (Flushing, NY) : For Sale $ 350.00 Mega Savings? you gotta check this out!! (San Diego, CA) : Make Offer Win $500 worth of cash for as littel as $52!!!!! (Somerset, NJ) : Free Offer We pay CASH for your unused Diabetic test strips! (Charlotte, NC) : Wanted I will give you 25 or more free bids try zeekler penny auction (Sandy, UT) : Free Offer win electronics, iPads, jewelry, and much more at up to 95% off (San Gabriel, CA) : Free Offer 
     View more featured classifieds 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
Recently Added Classifieds
 
 
 
 
 &quot;DMQ&quot;LADIES GLD MESH BRACELET WATCH-BEAUTIFUL! (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 35.00 Used Profile Tires (Maricopa, AZ) : For Sale $ 200.00 Ford Ranger for Sale (Lake Worth, FL) : For Sale $ 900.00 BRAND NEW STERLING SILVER STUD EARRINGS W/LT PURPLE STONES (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 14.00 BEAUTIFUL AMETHYST MARQUISE CUT PENDANT-GORGEOUS (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 25.00 SARAH COVENTRY SILVER PUFFED HEART PENDANT W/18&quot;CHAIN (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 30.00 AKC/OFA Chocolate Labrador Retriever Puppies (Victor, MT) : For Sale $ 900.00 PERU 14K YELLOW GOLD LADIES FANCY BRACELET-GORGEOUS (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 150.00 Little Girls Antique&quot;Tilmore&quot;Windup Watch-Works Fine (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 50.00 Male and Female Black Long Haired Chihuahua Puppies (Buda, TX) : For Sale $ 350.00 &quot;CRATE&quot;120 Watt Combo AMP (Penndel, PA) : For Sale $ 100.00 Citation Classic 2001 5th wheeler/Roulotte Citation Classique 20 (Toronto, ON) : For Sale $ 10,200.00 Missoni for Target Blue Maxi Sleeveless Dress - Size S Small (Parma, OH) : For Sale $ 79.99 Canon Imageprograf W8400 (San Diego, CA) : For Sale $ 1,000.00 Missoni for Target Blue Maxi Sleeveless Dress - Size X- Small (Parma, OH) : For Sale $ 79.99 Earn 10% ROI Annually As A Strictly Passive Investment (Glendora, CA) : Free Offer Table - Bar Style&amp;Chairs (Kingsport, TN) : For Sale $ 1,300.00 REO Vendors Needed in Casper and Surrounding Areas (Clearfield, UT) : Wanted LDR Ranch and Petsitting Services (Pilot Hill, CA) : For Sale $ 100.00 pest control/ants,spiders,japanese beatles (Aurora, IL) : For Sale $ 60.00 Free Diagnostic with Approved Repairs (Charlotte, NC) : Free Offer Sharp Home Sound System (Nanaimo, BC) : For Sale $ 40.00 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Announcements 
 
 
 Verified Members FREE Store Fronts Buy&amp;Sell Locally. FREE Online Classifieds. FREE Member Sign Up 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
Local Classifieds
 
 
 
 United States Atlanta, GA Austin, TX Boston, MA Buffalo, NY Chicago, IL Columbus, OH Dallas, TX Denver, CO Detroit, MI Houston, TX Los Angeles, CA Miami, FL Minneapolis, MN Orlando, FL New York, NY Philadelphia, PA Phoenix, AZ San Francisco, CA San Jose, CA Seattle, WA St. Louis, MO Washington, DC   Canada Calgary, AB Edmonton, AB Montreal, QC Ottawa, ON Quebec City, QC Toronto, ON Vancouver, BC Winnipeg, MB Regina, SK      View all cities 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 About Us      Refer A Friend      Link To Us      Site Map      Newest Classifieds      RSS Classifieds   Copyright©2003-2012 by BuySellCommunity.com. All rights reserved. Use of this Web site constitutes acceptance of the User Agreement and Privacy Policy .
Free Classifieds: Regina, SK    Toronto, ON    Anchorage, AK    Washington, DC    New Haven, CT    Halifax, NS    Detroit, MI    Jackson, MS
	</body>
</document>
