<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008236" url="http://www.foodinmouth.com/food-porn/2010/03/filet-o-fish.html" time="2012-07-13-01:44" support="1" score="0.0016456405394647156" bingtitle="Filet o Fish - Food in Mouth - On Restaurants, Dining, Streetfood ..." webtitle="Filet o Fish - Food in Mouth">
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>I walked up to the counter ready to place my order. ... I was super ready for this, and a meal for $3.25? ... and even though it&apos;s not my favorite food, I&apos;d eat it.</description>
	<body>
		Food in Mouth 
 
 Home About Restaurant Guide Archives Mobile Pictures 
 
Filet o Fish
 
I walked up to the counter ready to place my order. This was right after seeing the two for three dollar poster on the window. I was super ready for this, and a meal for $3.25? Who wouldn&apos;t be ready? Apparently not I. Right after placing the order, it sounded wrong as it came out of my mouth.&quot;I&apos;d like to have that McFish deal you got on the window out there.&quot;Wait. McFish? No...&quot;The Filet o Fish deal? Sure.&quot;Ah yes, filet o fish. It&apos;s been so long that I don&apos;t even know the name or how to order it. Chalk it up to stupidity. After paying, I went off to enjoy the wonderful meal of fast food fish.
 
I had the proper expectations for this because Blondie and Brownie talked about all the fast food fried fish options out there. But what really got my attention about this filet o fish sale was Pat telling me that this deal would be the death of him. It&apos;s simply too cheap and good enough that it&apos;s addictive.

The filet o fish has a few things going for it. It&apos;s cheap. It has a squishy bun. The fish actually looks fried. There&apos;s tarter sauce and cheese. On the other hand, it&apos;s made by McDonald&apos;s, it has a slightly fishy after-taste, and two of these packs more than 700 calories. It&apos;s probably really good bang for your buck if we&apos;re just talking about calories per dollar here. The thing is that these suckers aren&apos;t full of carbs so they don&apos;t exactly leave you full. They kind of leave you feeling slightly disgusting and somewhat guilty that you just consumed 700 calories in 90 seconds.
 
The truth is that sometimes I just can&apos;t resist. Some people are degenerate gamblers. I&apos;m a degenerate fast food eater. Yea it&apos;s bad for me, but it hurts so good. Some folks have an unreal expectation of McDonald&apos;s. Some folks genuinely love it. Some folks utterly loathe the existence of these things. I know what to expect, and even though it&apos;s not my favorite food, I&apos;d eat it. Now if they ever have those chicken nugget sales again... it is on!

Posted by Danny on March 9, 2010 at 11:35 am 

(I invite you to follow me on Twitter so you can get more of my non-sense in another medium.)

 Share this: Twitter Facebook StumbleUpon 
 
Comments
 Type&quot; dumplings &quot;(minus quotes) in the next box, this is required 
 


 
naw son, you gotta get the BK Big Fish, it&apos;s a far better sandwich and when they have their King Deals, on one of those days you can get 2 for $4. Filet-o-fish is weak.
 
 bigjeff 
 March 15, 2010 8:09 pm 
 
In the Harlem 125th location of McDonald&apos;s, there is a manager&apos;s special... 2 filet&apos;o&apos;fish sandwiches, medium fries, and a medium drink for $5. That kicks the pants off the small fries/small drink you&apos;d get off the dollar menu. Just an FYI.
 
 Nicholas 
 March 17, 2010 9:27 pm 
 
They also have a special double fish fillet sandwich once in a while, but&apos;s only for pro&apos;s!

Also overall, the size of Mickey D&apos;s fish fillet has shrunk a bit over the past few years and they now only use a half slice of cheese.

These things are awful but I love them...Help!
 
 CheebaHawk 
 March 15, 2010 11:56 am 
 
@NYC,

actually I think not all McDonald&apos;s are doing this, especially in NYC. And those in Manhattan that participate, the price is probably slightly higher.

@CheebaHawk,

WHAT?! DOUBLES?!
 
 Danny 
 March 15, 2010 2:37 pm 
 
I find the filet o fish now has a bitter after taste. I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s the fish or the tarter sauce. I&apos;m leaning towards the tarter sauce...
 
 wonders 
 March 11, 2010 4:27 pm 
 
I got this &quot;deal&quot; when it first came out and shared it with the hubs. It was meh. Did yours only have a half a piece of cheese on it???
 
 Erica C 
 March 12, 2010 3:34 pm 
 
@James,

Jack in the Box makes tacos?! we need one of those here. My friends always say they would make a killing here. And yes my brother, lots of pride indeed.

@wonders,

mmmm... bitter aftertaste... I know what you&apos;re talking about. It&apos;s ok though, the shit ain&apos;t gonna kill ya for another fifty years or so.

@Eric,

haha, yes it had a full piece of cheese on it. It just wasn&apos;t so visible :P
 
 Danny 
 March 12, 2010 3:55 pm 
 
Is this going on at all McDonald&apos;s locations? I friggin love these things! I can just imagine how much weight I&apos;m going to put on because of this deal...
 
 NYC 
 March 14, 2010 4:40 am 
 
Throw in 4 chicken nuggets and you&apos;ve just described my dinner 3 out of the last 7 days.

I&apos;m surprised you made no mention of the annoying theme song that accompanies the filet o fish.
 
 Patrick 
 March 9, 2010 9:51 pm 
 
FILET-O-FISH IS DA BEST!!! I love that squishy bun. Never eaten two in one meal though. I mean, not yet.
 
 Robyn 
 March 9, 2010 10:01 pm 
 
@Patrick,

You&apos;re my hero. And that theme song is awesome, I love it. Most people have heard of it already though. They need a new one...

@Robyn,

Yes, yes... not yet is the right response. Do it Robyn!
 
 Danny 
 March 10, 2010 10:14 am 
 
I once walked into McDonald&apos;s and placed an order for 100 chicken nuggets. It was one of the greatest moments of my life.

Since then, though, I&apos;ve been less and less able to eat McDonald&apos;s food without feeling physically ill... especially their breakfast options. Fortunately, my body still seems to retain its addiction to Jack in the Box tacos and White Castle sliders, so I&apos;m shooting two for three in the fast food pantheon.

Junk with pride! However twisted that may be.
 
 James Boo 
 March 11, 2010 11:53 am 
 
I&apos;m a degenerate fast food eater too. I know it&apos;s unhealthy and all, but it just tastes so good. What&apos;s the point of eating without enjoying anyway, right?
 
 FlavorBoulevard 
 March 9, 2010 12:02 pm 
 
@Su-Lin,

Yes they are addictive aren&apos;t they? Fried fish sandwiches in general seem hard to find... there are lots of fried catfish sandwiches here in the states though. They usually go by the name of po&apos;boys...

@FlavorBoulevard,

You got me! The whole point seems to be enjoyment. I mean, it makes sense to prolong life and have as much enjoyment as possible too...
 
 Danny 
 March 9, 2010 12:10 pm 
 
I&apos;m a total sucker for these sandwiches. But then again, there are no other fried fish sandwiches near me... ;)
 
 Su-Lin 
 March 9, 2010 11:57 am 
 
 
 Follow Read Look 
 
Recent Posts
 
 Three tacos from Ponche in Midtown 
 
On the way to a roof top bar a few weeks ago, Steph and I walked by a Mexican restaurant that had an A grade in the window. It reminded me of getting... [more] 
 0 comments 
 July 12, 2012 at 3:42 pm 
 Identifying myself at Jade Asian 
 
The thing about eating in Flushing is that sometimes you can get things that are less likely to be found in Manhattan. Taiwanese restaurants is one... [more] 
 2 comments 
 July 10, 2012 at 2:17 pm 
 Affordable combo at Steak n Shake 
 
Summer is too damn hot. I never get tired of complaining about this, but it&apos;s true. It&apos;s been over 90 degrees for so many days in a row that I just... [more] 
 2 comments 
 July 5, 2012 at 11:50 am 
 Fried tiny buns at Johns Shanghai 
 
On Saturday, Steph and I were in suburbia land, and I tried to explain to her why menu&apos;s at chain restaurants are crazy. We walked by a casual dining... [more] 
 0 comments 
 June 26, 2012 at 11:21 am 
 Meatballs at the Meatball Shop 
 
I&apos;m caught up in NBA Finals fever as of late and what interests me are affordable and unfussy food. It&apos;s crazy that it&apos;s taken me this long to try the... [more] 
 0 comments 
 June 21, 2012 at 9:54 am 

 Copyright 2012©to foodinmouth.com. All rights reserved. If you wanna help a brother out, use my Amazon affiliate link.
	</body>
</document>
