<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008680" url="http://happyeaters.net/forums/?page=post&amp;id=58D015B4-B17D-49AE-BF38-F6F4638A9D31&amp;fid=8006C5D7-F9E2-4FA9-A434-D96CDA9E1910" time="2012-07-13-02:08" support="3" score="0.009824380027813039" bingtitle="The Anything Goes Diet" webtitle="The Anything Goes Diet">
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>Eating in at a fast food restaurant? Toss part of the fries in the trash on your way to ... Once I paid attention to my food and eating, it was easy to not unconsciously ...</description>
	<body>
		Happy Eaters food fun fitness 
 
 Member Login | Register 
 
 
 
 Navigation 
 Home Forums Blog Members Photos 
 
 
 
 
 Go Home : All Forums : Happy Eater Forums : Food Recent Posts My Posts My Subscriptions 
The Anything Goes Diet
 Subscribe New Topic Reply 
 
 Next 1 2 3 Quote Rate My Posts Admin
Posts: 3218 skwigg - Posted Jan 18th 2011 
 How do I lose weight while eating intuitively? What if I intuitively like to eat out, go to parties, eat donuts, or participate in family pizza night? Is it hopeless? 

 I get a lot of e-mails that are some variation of the above. People desperately want to relax the rules but how do you do that and lose weight? Or stay lean? Well, John Barban has written a whole program on that very subject, The Anything Goes Diet .  

 

 Plenty of us, myself included, don’t need programs anymore. We’ve got it! If you’ve got it, excellent. But if you need more guidance on how to back away from diet rules while still making a deficit happen, or how to handle social situations, or how to change your thinking, or some input on calories if you feel completely lost while winging it, this may be just what you’re looking for. 

 

There are no off-limits foods, no meal timing rules, no special ratios, no absurd protein requirements, just a deficit, a consistent, no-hassle, eating what you like, deficit. John Barban and intermittent fasting guy, Brad Pilon, are pals and have very similar philosophies on eating what you love and having a life. You shouldn’t have to become a clock-watching obsessive compulsive eater to be lean. Your“diet”should fit your life, not the other way around. John’s approach is all about including socializing, fast food and favorite treats. I picked up a few great tips I’d never even thought of, Bethennyesque tips. Eating in at a fast food restaurant? Toss part of the fries in the trash on your way to sit down. WHAT?! I will totally use that because you can’t order“small”anything anymore. It would work for movie popcorn too. 

 

 To give you a feel for the program, some of the chapters are: 

 

 Calorie Guessing - Guessing Is Better Than Counting 

 Think Weekly - Nothing Changes in One Day 

 It’s ALL GOOD - There Is No“Bad”Food 

 All About You - Only Compare Yourself to Yourself 

 

 I also really enjoyed the section on The Yo-Yo Dieting Cycle - How The Weight Loss Industry Leaves You Out of Shape and Out of Control. He describes the stages of a“control continuum”that we’ve all been on and how it’s in the best interest of the industry to keep us all stuck, confused, and trying again. It was eye-opening and infuriating to realize how many years of my life I’ve spent IN shape but OUT of control, thinking I had it all together but still totally at the mercy of Body for Life or The Zone or whatever diet I was trying to live by.  

 

 There is some enjoyable reading here and quite a few ah-has, even for me.  The Anything Goes Diet  seems to be written just for Happy Eaters. It doesn’t even require exercise. Still, there are a few things I don’t like. It’s a program. Weird complaint, I know, but I don’t like programs. I don’t want anybody telling me how to eat,  even if they’re telling me how to eat whatever I want . I’m sort of pigheaded that way. :-) There is calorie talk. I don’t like calorie talk but I know many of you have been asking for exactly that. If you’ve tried to talk to me about how many calories you should eat, you know that I just cover my ears and make la la la sounds. John Barban actually goes into detail for those who care to count, or“guess”as he encourages. I don’t really get the low calorie recipe guide. If you can eat anything you want, why would you eat low fat cheese? Ever? I suppose it comes back to“the differential”as Bethenny calls it. If you can’t taste the difference, or prefer the substitution then it makes total sense to save the calories. The 150 pages of recipes do look good (Nachos, Potato Skins, Super Bowl Chili, Spinach Dip, Apple Crumble) but I’d be fattening them up! 

 

 The Anything Goes Diet has five manuals plus a 60 day e-mail coaching sequence. It comes with: 

 

 Weight Loss Manual Social Eating Survival Guide Thinking Thin Guide Recipe Guide Success Tracker Journal (an interactive .pdf) 

 

 

 

 The Anything Goes Diet isn’t for all of us but I think it will really appeal to those who want more guidance on relaxing the food rules while getting or staying lean.  

 

 Standard disclosurey stuff: I received a free review copy of the program. If you decide to buy through my links I will receive a portion of the sale. You will receive a discount through Friday. 
 
 Post last edited Jan 18th 2011 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 26 ETANA - Posted Jan 18th 2011 
I can&apos;t believe the size of the package you are asked to buy. Wouldn&apos;t one book do it justice!

Well, I just bought Bethanny&apos;s book on amazon ... I&apos;m ready to re-read it and post her tips around the house

Thanks for the reveiw.

etana
 
 Etana, a young active 65 (Silver Spring, MD) 
 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 212 LeslieChomp - Posted Jan 18th 2011 
I will tell you where I am, and you let me know what you think would benefit me more (this plan or something like Bethenny&apos;s book) Because this is something that might be worth purchasing:

Over the past year or so, I have let myself off the&quot;diet wheel&quot;so to say, probably for the first time in 10-12 years. I ate what I wanted, without binging, what I felt like. I was injured, and for the first itme, didn&apos;t have panic attacks about not being at the gym. I relaxed! And discovered that I wouldn&apos;t balloon back up to my highest weight (30 or so pounds heavier.) This has possibly been one of the healthiest things I have ever done for myself. 

On the flip side: since November, I have been trying to lose some weight. I am currently 5-10 pounds heavier than where I had been for about 4 years. So Yes, I did gain some weight in this process... and to be honest, I always wanted to be about 15-20 pounds less than I am RIGHT NOW anyway. Currently I am about 155 pounds and 5&apos;4&quot;. Normally I am 145-150. I&apos;d like to be 135-140. Just always been like that. For the life of me, I just can&apos;t get into the&quot;intuitive&quot;mind set to LOSE that weight. I still want to have that cookie. Or I get hungry and eat. Its like, in my mind, now that I know I can eat something, I can&apos;t restrict myself long enough to see the positive effects? Does that make sense??? Maybe I am just not at that point yet with intuitive eating...

Anyway.... thoughts on some approaches or options for myself and others in my situation?

Leslie :)
 
 http://mindfullydancing.wordpress.com/ 

 http://lesliechomp.blogspot.com/ 
 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 212 LeslieChomp - Posted Jan 18th 2011 
i should say: I&apos;ve been liberated from the confines from rules and structured diets! haha... i don&apos;t want to go back....
 
 http://mindfullydancing.wordpress.com/ 

 http://lesliechomp.blogspot.com/ 
 Quote Rate My Posts Admin
Posts: 3218 skwigg - Posted Jan 18th 2011 LeslieChomp - Posted 19 Minutes Ago 
 

For the life of me, I just can&apos;t get into the&quot;intuitive&quot;mind set to LOSE that weight. I still want to have that cookie. Or I get hungry and eat. Its like, in my mind, now that I know I can eat something, I can&apos;t restrict myself long enough to see the positive effects? Does that make sense??? Maybe I am just not at that point yet with intuitive eating...

Anyway.... thoughts on some approaches or options for myself and others in my situation?

Leslie :)

 
 Have you read Bethenny Frankel&apos;s&quot;Naturally Thin&quot;yet? That changed everything for me. Nothing off-limits. Portion control. Balance. That&apos;s when I realized I can have the cookie. I can eat what I want, when I&apos;m hungry, or even if I&apos;m not hungry but it just looks fun. That&apos;s not at odds with losing weight if you also control the portion, and pick and choose what you really want instead of eating anything that&apos;s available. It made me more choosy, a picky eater who only goes for the delicious stuff, someone who won&apos;t eat it if it&apos;s not great. Total, total change of thought process. I used to turn down things that were delicious (like a dumb ass, LOL) in favor of food that was clean, boring, low-fat, on the plan. You don&apos;t have to do that to be a lean person. You just have to find a way to to take what you eat now, what you really like, and eat less of it. Maybe that means you keep the homemade chocolate chip cookies but you only have one a day (I do that). Maybe it means if you want a nice restaurant meal with satisfying portions on Friday, you deliberately keep things a little lighter on Wednesday and Thursday. Or if you have bacon, eggs and waffles for breakfast (smallish portions), you skip lunch, have a late afternoon snack, and make a point of eating some leafy green things at dinner. So you just go along doing an easygoing balancing thing, deciding where you can easily cut back and what you can&apos;t do without. If you go gonzo on one meal, no problem. You naturally eat a little less over the next few days. The key is not going overboard all the time, deliberately choosing to eat less whenever it&apos;s no big deal to do so. Don&apos;t eat the whole sandwich if it&apos;s not that great. Share the dessert. Skip the rubbery looking appetizers. Leave a few fries on the plate. It&apos;s the difference between doing that and saying:&quot;I can&apos;t have fries. I shouldn&apos;t eat dessert. I&apos;d better eat that whole sandwich now because staring tomorrow, NO MORE BREAD!&quot;:-) Know what I mean? Once you start making even subconscious rules about what you can and can&apos;t, should and shouldn&apos;t do, you overeat. If you know you can have whatever you want, whenever you want it. Then you can start choosing to have less, or to have something tomorrow or next week instead of finishing off all of it right now. There will still be pie on earth next week, so don&apos;t hurt your weight loss thinking you need more of it now. Read Bethenny&apos;s Naturally Thin book no matter what. It&apos;s been a complete game-changer for so many of us that I recommend it to everyone, even big guys who think I&apos;m totally crazy. If you&apos;ve already read Naturally Thin and want more suggestions, recipes, and guidance, particularly about calories (Bethenny doesn&apos;t mention them), Anything Goes is another step in understanding how to have the body you want AND eat what you want. Naturally Thin is like girl talk, sitting down and discussing food, weight and strategy with a friend. Anything Goes is from a nutrition and fitness expert, someone who worked in the weight loss industry for years and was totally appalled by the whole thing, someone who knows how to achieve a muscular physique and full six-pack abs while eating donuts for breakfast every morning. He has a lot of insight. I like his ability to take all the useless things we&apos;ve been told for years (1g of protein per pound of body weight, skipping meals will slow your metabolism, cardio for fat loss) and dismantle all of it. So they&apos;re covering the same subject but from different perspectives. I gained many useful ideas from each of them. Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 41 river - Posted Jan 19th 2011 LeslieChomp - Posted 9 Hours Ago 
For the life of me, I just can&apos;t get into the&quot;intuitive&quot;mind set to LOSE that weight. I still want to have that cookie. Or I get hungry and eat. Its like, in my mind, now that I know I can eat something, I can&apos;t restrict myself long enough to see the positive effects? Does that make sense??? Maybe I am just not at that point yet with intuitive eating...

Anyway.... thoughts on some approaches or options for myself and others in my situation?

Leslie :)
 If you want a cookie just eat it. Whatever extra calories you might get from the cookie the day you give in will be balanced by the less calories of the next days when finally you won&apos;t make a deal out of having a cookie or not anymore and hence you&apos;ll eat it only when you really desire it rather than all the times the artificial desire of wanting it is created in your mind because of prohibition. The sooner you have the things you want the sooner you will realize they&apos;re not a big deal, they&apos;re not that great as you think they&apos;re when you are&quot;forbidden&quot;to have them and will get have enough to be satisfied but won&apos;t gorge on them. Gorging comes from prohibition, self-regulating smart choices comes from freedom. Children who are forbidden from eating candies or more than two candies a day will go to any length to get more candies than they should. They will steal them, they will gorge when they&apos;re at one of their friends house, they will hide candies in the pockets and they won&apos;t be able to control themselves and will eat till the point of sickness as long as there are candies around like at birthday parties and such. But as long as the parents says&quot;okay kids, candies are in the drawer, you can get them whenever you want, you can eat as many as you want, you can even get stomachache from eating to many... that will teach you a lesson for the next time... now it&apos;s up to you&quot;the suddenly candies are not a big deal anymore, the children themselves will turn them down when they&apos;re offered some. Even though they thought they would eat hundreds of candies everyday as soon as the glorious day when they can eat as many as they want would come, they find themselves eating just one or going many days without having a desire for candies. They don&apos;t gorge anymore at parties, they don&apos;t steal them anymore, they don&apos;t hide them in their pocket or take advantage of friend sleepover to eat as many as they can ... simply because candies are not a big deal anymore. The prohibition made them a big deal and gave them a special aura (and probably a special test too) that they don&apos;t actually have. And these freedom vs. prohibition are true experiments that have been repeated over and over and children always respond in the same way. Say a child that washing teeth is up to him, accept the fact that he might not clean his teeth at all the first few days but once&quot;teeth washing&quot;is not longer regulated by external rules but by his self-regulation and desire to be clean and not suffer the pain of cavities, he will start washing them everyday, making sure to wash them very good and without anything telling him to do it. Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 414 Scout - Posted Jan 19th 2011 river - Posted 3 Hours Ago 
 
 And these freedom vs. prohibition are true experiments that have been repeated over and over and children always respond in the same way. Say a child that washing teeth is up to him, accept the fact that he might not clean his teeth at all the first few days but once&quot;teeth washing&quot;is not longer regulated by external rules but by his self-regulation and desire to be clean and not suffer the pain of cavities, he will start washing them everyday, making sure to wash them very good and without anything telling him to do it. 
 

Children always respond in the same way? Whoever concluded THAT doesn&apos;t actually HAVE children. And as for kids spontaneously beginning to clean their teeth regularly on their own... my family dentist would be rolling on the floor over that one. 

I&apos;m sorry, I am not trying to be mean but that&apos;s stuff taught in Psych 101 and has no bearing on the real world of parenting. Ask any parent. Heck, read any Erma Bombeck book. Kids do not give a crap about the possible pain of cavities in the future, or the harm many candies might cause them now or in the future. Kids are, in fact, physiologically disposed to prefer sweets to veggies, especially the more bitter veggies, and it isn&apos;t until much later in life that their tastebuds change and mature and are able to appreciate a much wider range of foods. Part of the responsibility of parenting is teaching your kids to eat right. Which has never, historically, been an easy thing to do, and has now become a sisyphusean task in an age where children are bombarded from all sides with unhealthy food, food images, and activities built around unhealthy food from the moment they are born.     

Furthermore, if you are never taught, or if you never seek to learn by yourself, you never WILL magically become a healthy eater. It takes time and effort and patience to teach a kid to eat veggies, and you may throw out dozens and dozens of meals in the process. When attempting to introduce a new veggie to a young child it may to appear on their plate ten times before they can actually be induced to TRY it, never mind eat the portion. And if it&apos;s prepared in an unappealing fashion it may take months or years before they can be persuaded to taste that&apos;disgusting green thing&apos;again. And kids are individuals, too, funny enough. What one child finds disgusting, another might find yummy and delish, and vice versa.  It&apos;s just NOT that simple. 

But, although it takes time and effort to teach a child to eat healthy, and takes time and effort to teach oneself to eat healthy, it can certainly be done. But for most people, it&apos;s an ongoing process, not an instantaneous thing. Very few people (if any) woke up one day and just slid into healthy eating naturally and easily. It takes some conscious thought and some work... until one day it doesn&apos;t take so much thought and work. 

 

 
 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 14 jenn - Posted Jan 19th 2011 
Thanks Scout! Great post. I couldn&apos;t imagine leaving candy within reach of my four year old. She would eat a lot of it to the exclusion of her other food. Out of sight, out of mind is the motto in our house (for all of us, actually). Halloween is a great example. She got so much candy (lots of full sized bars) her pumpkin broke. We left it out for a few days and every five minutes she asked for more candy. Usually we give in since she eats really well and eats great food. Then we put it away and she never asked again. I still have an enormous bag of halloween candy on a shelf. If I put it in a drawer and said,&quot;Ok, here&apos;s the candy everyone,&quot;it would have been gone in a few days. 
 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 211 SueG - Posted Jan 19th 2011 
Thanks for the review of Anything Goes - it does rather seem like a lot of material and I think for me, I will pass, but I can see how it may be just the ticket for someone who is trying to figure it all out.

As far as the kids and candy question goes - the answer is going to be different for everyone. I know that we never had candy in our house when I was a kid - except for Easter and Halloween, and a lot of gorging happened at those times of the year. My own kids never had to gorge because stuff was around all the time and they had plenty! They also had no cavities, unlike their mother. Some people find their equilibrium faster than others. I do think there is something to the&quot;forbidden fruit&quot;theory. My neighbors always had candy around their house and they couldn&apos;t understand my attraction to it! ha ha ha I love that I can have enough dark chocolate in my house now to fill a small closet, and have no desire to eat more than a little bit every day. Talk about freedom! And so delicious. I don&apos;t think I could have handled it 20 years ago when my oldest was 3ish...the boy who never met a vegetable he would eat - other than steamed frozen peas. The stress of getting that kid to eat what I thought he should would have sent me to a stash of chocolate in no time!

Just spent the last 2 days at a Bed and Breakfast - emphasis on the breakfast - where I ate as much of the stuffed blueberry french toast, and the Almond Joy sundae and the fruit cup and the eggs benedict and the triple berry trifle with vanilla ice cream and what all...who knew breakfast came with dessert. Now I am describing the foods offered at both breakfasts, and truth be told, I didn&apos;t finish any one thing but I ate more than half of everything (except I did eat the entire one sausage link that came with the stuffed french toast) and today I will not be eating til this afternoon, and at the moment (10 am) I am not in a hurry to eat anything. I feel fantastic, my pants didn&apos;t get any tighter, the world did not cave in and I had a wonderful time. I hate to tell you how many times at a bed and breakfast (over the last 10 years) I only barely tasted all the carby things and asked for substitutes for things. Sheesh. Life is too short for that. I am glad I learned that before I turned 80! 

As for tips to get into the Intuitive way of eating mindset - I would say that for me it was hyper attention. I would have to really block out distractions, and pay close attention to my food, how I was feeling, how it tasted - chew a million times and kind of get obnoxious about eating, for awhile. I think it would be hard to be intuitive without paying attention, and for me I had to really go overboard for awhile. It was kind of like - back in the early days of my public speaking career, learning how NOT to say OK or You Know as a filler word in a presentation. First, I had to overuse those words ( not in a public presentation of course) because then I would hear them...when they were subconscious filler words, I wasn&apos;t hearing them. Once I could hear them, it was easy to eliminate them. Once I paid attention to my food and eating, it was easy to not unconsciously shove it in. I like Geneen Roth&apos;s rule (or suggestion or whatever) of eating everything as if you are eating it in public view of others, whether or not you are. Sort of makes you pay attention.
 Quote Rate My Posts 
Posts: 137 Luthien - Posted Jan 19th 2011 
Re: The kids and candy-- definitely agree that kids need to be taught to eat healthy, they don&apos;t do it on their own. I remember kind of inwardly resenting my mom because she never bought chips or soda or twinkies (barring maybe twice a year for a party or something), stuff I was led to believe all&quot;normal kids&quot;had-- and all our bread and cookies were homemade. Now being in college I realize that those choices she made were some of the best things she could do for us. Because (for instance) I had milk instead of soda at home, I never really developed a liking for it, and have never had any problems with weight or cavities.

Based on my childhood experience, I&apos;ve decided I like my mom&apos;s approach (which I intend to take with my own kids someday): Don&apos;t make sweets or candy or soda about weight, or cavities, or even general health. For a kid those are pretty vague ideas, and though they may have a general idea of&quot;healthy&quot;it may not be enough to convince them that twinkies aren&apos;t a good lunch. What I was always told was that a few pieces of candy or cookies once in a while were okay, but I wasn&apos;t allowed to have too many or I would&quot;get sick.&quot;Kids know what sick is, and I believed my mom when she told me that because I always FELT sick immediately after eating too much candy. And really, she was right-- too much junk food couldn&apos;t have been good for my immune system or the rest of my body. It also puts the focus on health and vitality, not weight or appearance

That was kind of off the original topic. Oops. Sorry lol
 
 
 
 Next 1 2 3 Subject: Subscribe 
 Poll Answers
 (Put one answer per line.) 
Rules:

Be nice.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
This website is powered by Spruz
	</body>
</document>
