<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008604" url="http://grantlairdjr.com/wp/2004/11/09/jack_in_the_box_drive_thru/" time="2012-07-13-02:03" support="4" score="0.0073729823555999515" bingtitle="Grant Laird, Jr. Blog » Jack In the Box Drive Thru" webtitle="Grant Laird, Jr. BlogJack In the Box Drive Thru">
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>I will stay in my spot until I get my food. I ... mad because I didn’t stop at the order speaker. Fast Food restaurant got to ... Looking nice pick up #truck.... hard to find ...</description>
	<body>
		Grant Laird, Jr. Blog 
 Peace, Love, Unity, and Respect 
 Home About Archives Contact 
 
 Jack In the Box Drive Thru 
 9 11 2004 
 More than three years ago, my younger daughter Amanda and I went to Jack in the box near my house for our dinner. It was a lot of cars ahead of us and behind us at drive thru around peak time like 6:00 PM.

Normally, I would ask Amanda if she will order for me at speaker at drive thru but I never force her to do it–she’s 11 years old at this time. She didn’t want to do it so I have no problem with it. We continued stay in line till we arrived the windows where we see cashier.

As usual, I always have my note ready to order&amp;hand it to her. When I gave note to her, she took it and ordered it with no problem. Due to heavily ordering from other people behind me, they asked me to move my vehicle to front of store.

Of course, I don’t appreciate them asking me to move over there because I already wait long in line and unable to order over speaker. She got mad and told their manager–she came over and asked me to move, I told them I won’t do it in gesture. Amanda had to jump and trying to tell me what they said. I clearly made decision not to move a thing till our foods arrived.

The manager was really mad and started cussing at us–yes front of my own daughter. She wrote a note saying that she will call police if I will not move, I told them to go ahead. I felt obliged to stay and wait for my foods–simply not fair to us to wait twice longer than others while their drive thru wasn’t accessibility to me.

It felt like 10 minutes long–waiting for foods while we had this dispute. Foods finally came out and she gave them to us with no problem. She was bitching at acting ugly toward to us big time. I knew that calling police isn’t worth for little things like that.

Of course, Amanda was very upset and crying about it.

When we arrived home, I called Jack in the Box customer service right away and reported what happened. They kept saying apologized for all this inconvenience and promised me free coupons for next time. They asked if I would still go back this store again–of course, I told them I still plan to return again.

I did not return this same store for few weeks–till we finally decide to go this store again. I was surprised that those people that I had disputed with were gone. I can see they have different people and respect me when I did not want to move front of store like before.

Obviously, I got their management attention and made some changes in this store staffing. I felt good knowing that I do make the difference.

Only thing I am disappointed that they never mail me free coupons!
 
 Note: do not afraid to use drive thru all the times no matter what! My father always said to me–if they do this, I do this too! 
 
Grant W Laird Jr.

http://blog.grantlairdjr.com

Drive Thur Fast Food Restaurants Survey (survey may not work)
 http://www.deafnetwork.com/cgi-bin/dada/mail.cgi?flavor=archive&amp;id=20031007093149&amp;list=dn 

Jack in the Box Settles Bias Lawsuit
 http://www.deafnetwork.com/cgi-bin/dada/mail.cgi?flavor=archive&amp;id=20041109190805&amp;list=dn 

Jack in the Box turns down deaf applicant, draws lawsuit
 http://www.deafnetwork.com/cgi-bin/dada/mail.cgi?flavor=archive&amp;id=20040525063354&amp;list=dn 

EEOC Sues Jack-In-The-Box for Disability Discrimination
 http://www.deafnetwork.com/cgi-bin/dada/mail.cgi?flavor=archive&amp;id=20040519054003&amp;list=dn 

Jack In the Box Official website
 http://www.jackinthebox.com/ 
 
 « Plaxo Original Wedding VHS tape » 


Actions

   Comments rss   Trackback 

Informations

 Date : 9 November 2004 Categories : deaf community , general 

4 responses to“Jack In the Box Drive Thru”
 10 11 2004 LARRY (07:31:26) :
 
I totally agree about not driving up the end of the lane to wait for the food that you’ve ordered. It only makes you wait longer! I will stay in my spot until I get my food. I mean, if you wanna get rid of me, then give me my food! *wink*
 10 11 2004 Heather (09:50:44) :
 
Oh Yea, I have done that many time, and they get pissed off at me, and I just ignore them. It’s not fair that the manager told you to pull over. That’s pathelic of the manager.

I STILL doing it and I don’t care if I make the manager or supervisor mad because I didn’t stop at the order speaker.

Fast Food restaurant got to do something to make it more technology for Deaf/Hard of Hearing people during Drive Thru. Something like push button or face to face drive thru.
 23 02 2007 Grant W. Laird, Jr. Blog»Jack in the Box - Thru Drive: Revisit (16:41:28) :
 
[...] wrote about it last November 2004 (click here) and I want to share update with you guys about it two years [...]
 13 07 2009 Terry (12:10:18) :
 
Hard to understand, it took a long time to figure out that your first problem is that you are deaf or hearing challenged, why in the blazes didn’t you just say so at the start of your blog? I also don’t understand why your daughter Amanda did not want to help you out and read the note and order for you, is she challenged in some way too?

No doubt the reason you were likely asked to pull over is because the others having ordered at the speaker were likely ahead but I guess they should have handed you your tacos or whatever raw and then said, there you are now served as fast as everyone else, what else could they do?

It also seems to me that unlike the competition, The Jack has a very wide variety of vary high quality food if you do you want some plain hamburger warmed in some microwave go to you know who and I’m sure it will be fast! YUK!

over three quarters of the people in this entire world have never once tasted food as good as that and all some Americans can do is look for excuses to find fault, and no I’m not now and never was an employee of Jack In The Box!
 
Leave a comment
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 You can use these tags :&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
 
Sign Up Newsletter
 
 Your email: 
 

   
 
 Twitter 

 Tv #fios demo at #verizon store. They now give us ability to change color, font, font size, etc. Awesome! http://t.co/Xub1DR01 5 hours ago My wife katie love to read books such as #gameofthrones part two. http://t.co/WO2Q5u5l 21 hours ago #Cloudy in #arkansas near little rock. http://t.co/hYrKmYwW 2012/07/11 @SonnyWasilowski same here! Let&apos;s stay in touch. Smile! 2012/07/08 My wife and I had blast time at #louisville, KY. See you at #atlanta in 2014. #nad12 2012/07/08 
 
Cool Quote
 People are often unreasonable and self-centered. Forgive them anyway. If you are kind, people may accuse you of ulterior motives. Be kind anwyay. If you are honest, people may cheat you. Be honest anyway. If you find happiness. people may be jealous. Be happy anyway. The good you do today may be forgotten tomorrow. Do good anyway. Give the world the best you have, and it may be never enough. Give your best anyway. For you, in the end, it is between you and yourself. It never was between you and them anyway. 
Archives
 Select Month May 2011 (1) February 2011 (1) June 2010 (1) December 2009 (1) November 2009 (1) August 2009 (1) July 2009 (1) May 2009 (1) March 2009 (1) January 2009 (1) December 2008 (1) October 2008 (1) September 2008 (1) August 2008 (2) June 2008 (1) April 2008 (1) March 2008 (3) February 2008 (2) January 2008 (4) December 2007 (3) November 2007 (3) October 2007 (5) September 2007 (4) August 2007 (5) July 2007 (3) June 2007 (8) May 2007 (9) April 2007 (9) March 2007 (11) February 2007 (7) January 2007 (7) December 2006 (8) November 2006 (8) October 2006 (5) September 2006 (9) August 2006 (11) July 2006 (13) June 2006 (15) May 2006 (17) April 2006 (21) March 2006 (16) February 2006 (14) January 2006 (21) December 2005 (18) November 2005 (17) October 2005 (22) September 2005 (21) August 2005 (13) July 2005 (19) June 2005 (19) May 2005 (22) April 2005 (21) March 2005 (22) February 2005 (27) January 2005 (21) December 2004 (24) November 2004 (23) October 2004 (22) September 2004 (16) August 2004 (12) July 2004 (2) May 2004 (1) April 2004 (1) March 2004 (3) 
 
 
Counter
 
 
Meta Stuff

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org
	</body>
</document>
