<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008740" url="http://lazarusbill.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:12" support="16" score="0.02785305934565008" bingtitle="A Last Year - Bill Lagerstrom" webtitle="A Last Year - Bill Lagerstrom">
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001000" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>Bill Lagerstrom, August 2011, A short story to ... longer just a book or the movie, as a great number ... Oh, you know, I mop the floor at the local fast food restaurant.”</description>
	<body>
		A Last Year - Bill Lagerstrom
 
 
 
Visitors
 
 Tuesday, August 23, 2011 
 
 August 25, 2011 
 August 25, 2011 -  I have added a new box to the right side titled &quot;Explore Blog and Website Topics.&quot; There are two links to additional pages, &quot;Blog Format and Why This Blog&quot; and &quot;Themes.&quot;The Themes section will soon be links to all the topics on this blog and its associated website. As of now only the first three links are working. This is a work in progress and will be completed soon and updated regularly. Click on these entries and take a look. 
 
 When taking flight from the world&apos;s bondage, travel with a friend, and share the Journey 
             - Lighting Candles–      
 Once, told by my priest, thirty years ago, 
 “If there’s a candle, light it!” 
 Times habit of passing continues, but with changes– 
 The mantra today is,“If there’s a screen, turn it on!” 
 
                                                    Bill Lagerstrom, August 2011, 
 
    A short story to illustrate the pervasiveness of television screens in our culture that easily develops into an unstoppable habit– 
 
    Several years ago in Cabrini Hospital Inpatient Hospice I entered a room where an elderly extremely tall woman had died. The nurses always placed a rose in the folded hands of all who died and dimmed the lights. In this case they turned on the television to an insipid quiz show called The Price Is Right, and upped the volume. Yes, I hit the off switch immediately. 
 
    Somewhat more recently I visited a man who as I entered his room told me he was dying. He had received the news of“No hope”a few hours earlier. I sat and observed the habits of a lifetime which were solidly in place for me to see; he was watching a familiar show on the television, The Price Is Right, I listened to him for a few minutes telling me of his prognosis, one that gave hope for only a week or two before death–mostly,“It’s O.K. I understand what I was told.”A few minutes into this he realized the sound was on and he muted it. The sad part was that as I was leaving 20-30 minutes later he turned it on again. 
 
    I noticed that while the screen was lit for those first minutes his eyes kept returning to the screen every few seconds. As were talking of the things of death and dying the screen continued to flicker even as I managed to have his full attention. The screen was in hindsight, ever present, relentless. 
 
   On our way to Campobello Island this past weekend we stopped at Kippy’s Seafood Restaurant in Lubec for lunch. In the dining room a TV was on and tuned to a news channel. I found myself scanning the breaking news ribbons on the bottom or the screen whose volume was on mute. It proclaimed that some personality, a celebrity of some sort, had walked out on an interview because she was not asked the questions she wanted to answer. What concerns me is, am I so programmed to watch every lit screen, captured by the illusion that something is not to be missed? The gift is that here is something that I need to continue to work on was presented to me. 
 
   Yet, here I am in front of a screen posting this blog, because I want to do this offering, not just to pass time. A good use of the technology I am sure. 
 
   Lee and I watch British who-done-its’on the Netflix stream and from the local library’s vast collection of DVDs, as well as shows which can fall under the umbrella of healthy and wholesome entertainment. We do occasionally watch a mindless action movie which can occasionally be fun. Books and talk still seem to be up front on the to-do lists. Our local library is kept in business but what we order, probably keeping two or three librarians employed full time. The interlibrary loan system is a gift, abet we order online in front of a screen–another good use of technology. 
 
   Prime time television is not watched at all, and the news comes from PBS by reporters who do not try to entertain. Still in spite of my best efforts to avoid society’s screens I can frequently get sucked into this form of media entertainment. I see screens everywhere, airports, the back of the airplane seat in front of me, train stations, on the back of the driver’s seat in taxis in NYC, on elevators along with weather and ads, in hospital lobbies and waiting rooms as well as in every patient room, every hotel room, and the proliferation of cell phones, Ipods, etc. that grace almost every hand in some places. The list is endless, and as I type these few items rather scary. 
 
   One of the songs that was everywhere in my days in NYC in the sixties was from the musical Gypsy titled Let Me Entertain You. It came from an era when going to a movie or a show was to be entertained for a few hours and then to return to life with all in all its dimensions. This was the social contract with those who provided the masses with mostly enjoyable entertainment. Today I find myself, even here in Maine but especially in NYC, assaulted by an infinite variety of screens all begging for my attention. Of the greatest significance is that all these illuminated machines want me to buy something. 
 
   It has also been said that we no longer go to the movies, but that society in general has become the movies as more and more people live out a life of dreamed of fantasy and hopes of being something of a celebrity. I refer back to The Price Is Right where ordinary people who answer correctly about the price of something get to go on stage and play for prizes. I may have seen ten minutes of this show while channel changing this year and I am really surprised at how those chosen to play jump up and down, scream and high five everybody in sight before they play the game. Instant celebrity, a few seconds of“fame,”and a story to be told endlessly about their television appearance. I know this is supposition, but from what I have seen of this kind of enthusiasm I think I may be close to the mark. Good people to be sure, but a little misguided. 
 
   George Orwell in his book of many years ago titled 1984, wrote of a world where we are watched by Big Brother every moment of everyone’s existence. He envisioned what is close to how life is lived today with one detail not considered, we have reversed his story, now we are a society who watch“Big Brother and Big Sister”on the world’s billions of ever more pervasive screens. A rather neat twist on the tale except that it is no longer just a book or the movie, as a great number of screens that we encounter on a daily basis don’t offer us access to the OFF switch. 
 
   From my view the technology is not the problem, embracing the machines for only entertainment, 24 X 7, there is the issue as I see it. Too much of a good thing generates habit, and eventually addiction. Life now has become my newly learned desire to enjoy the moment without attachments to what only is something to pass time with. 
 
                   Peace,  Bill L. 
 
           +++++++++++++++++++++++ 

            A Few Items For Just Feeling Good 

 Click to view, with sound:     http://www.karmatube.org/videos.php?id=2337 

 A site worth seeing that is not negative news:  http://www.dailygood.org/ 

                                  How To Meditate 

 
              +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


    This last section of the blog is more technical in nature and is where I will offer the things I am working on to advance my spiritual wellbeing. Take what fits and leave the rest. 
 
    This week I undertake looking at the first tenet of the Eightfold Path, Right Understanding. Rather than my viewpoint I am offering the text I will be using for a week or two, a transcription of a talk given by Gil Fronsdal, the head teacher at the Insight Meditation Center in Redwood City California. He is a remarkable teacher and the following is well worth a careful reading. I will offer comments next week. 
 
 Right View/Right Understanding 
 
 Transcribed from a talk by Gil Fronsdal, 7/23/07 
 
   This evening, I would like to give a talk that perhaps could be called right understanding. It will be a reworking or reformulation of right understanding, also called right view. Right view or right understanding is the beginning of the eightfold path. When the Buddha described the path of practice, he started with right view and right understanding. It is right there at the beginning of Buddhism, and in a sense, all of Buddhism arises from right understanding. It is something that all the different schools of Buddhism and all the different practices have in common in the fundamental and simple way that the Buddha offered it. 
  The way that I would like to present the notion of right understanding is through a simple statement. That statement is that the means of practice should reflect the goal. The goal of Buddhist practice could be described in different ways or through different aspects. One aspect of the goal is to become peaceful, to attain a deep, abiding sense of peace, to be at peace in this world that we live in. For the means to reflect the goal means that there has to be peace in the practice—the practice itself should be peaceful. Another formulation people have used, even outside of Buddhism, is that if you want peace, be peaceful. If you want kindness, be kind. If you want compassion, be compassionate. If you want joy, be joyful. Peace, compassion, and joy are all the inner way that the goal of practice is experienced for someone who attains the goal. Subjectively it is marked by these inner qualities of peace, compassion, love, joy, and happiness. The practice should reflect that. That took me a long time to realize and understand. 
 
   The way that people practice may not be reflecting those qualities. For example, there were times when I strove, when I was greedy for some kind of attainment or some kind of result. Or there was some kind of aversion to the kind of experience I was having. I tried to push that away, to get rid of it, to not have that kind of experience. The presence of greed, aversion, or delusion does not reflect the goal. The goal of practice is to reach a place where the mind of free of greed, hate, and delusion. So in the practice of focusing on and being mindful of the breath, is there greed or aversion in the attitude we have and how we relate to the breath or how we relate to the attempt to be with the breath? No matter what our practice might be, whether it is breath meditation, loving kindness, chanting a mantra, visualization, right speech, washing dishes, working, or any activity we want to make a practice, we have to ask if it is reflecting the goal. In our relationship to it, we have to ask if there is the absence of greed and hate, or if there are some feelings of peace and ease. It does not mean that you have to be peaceful in some conventional way. Rather it means that the way you relate to your conflict or aggression or tension that you have with something reflects that you are at peace or relaxed a little about that aggression. It does not mean that you are not filled with greed, but it is about how you relate to that greed. Some things are really hard to stop doing. It is hard on a moment’s notice to decide to become peaceful in some usual, conventional way, and it’s hard on a moment’s notice to decide to let go of greed and hate. But maybe you can have a little more choice around your relationship to those things, and that is the foundation of practice, which is to find out how we are in relationship to anything. How are we in relationship to our greed, hate, and delusion, and how are we in relationship to our self-preoccupation? How are we in relationship to the path of practice? How are we in relationship to anything we do—washing dishes, doing our work, or whatever it is? 
 
   One of the ways we can relate to practice is that we can be content with the small steps of what we can do. So if we engage with meditation on the breath, maybe we are quite agitated, and it is very difficult to be with the breath. But can there be some, even just a little hint, of some peace, some ease, some acceptance, some non-conflict, some non-greed, and some non-hate? Can there be some compassion, some love, in relationship to that? Maybe at first it may be just a glimmer of peace, and whenever you have a choice to bring it up, you bring that up so that it has that quality there. Then, from that quality, something can grow. From that little glimmer or little seed that we have planted, the hope is that we can expand that and change. It is not the end of practice just to have a glimmer of peace. But can a little seed like that grow and become something much bigger? 
 
   Your practice, whatever you may do, may begin to have some quality of enjoyment, a quality of something you enjoy doing. If you are striving and pushing and demanding for something to happen in your practice, then chances are that you are not enjoying your practice, and chances are that you are destroying something inside of yourself rather than nourishing something and setting something free. 
 
   My idea of the notion that the goal should be reflected in the means is a built-in safety mechanism for dharma practice. You will not get in trouble if that is the case. You will not bury yourself in excessive zeal or aversion or conceit or self-deprecation. There are a variety of problems that can arise when you relate to the world or to the activities of the world. If you look for this quality of the means manifesting some of the goal, it will be a protection from going awry, from making the practice arduous and not enjoyable. That does not mean that practice is not sometimes very difficult, but there can still be some kind of joy there. If there is no joy in your practice, I am not sure about how much you can actually do, about how many seeds you are actually watering so that they can grow and develop. 
 
   When Lou Richmond, who is a Zen teacher here in the Bay Area, asked Suzuki Roshi:“If I do this practice, will I get enlightened?” Suzuki Roshi said,“If your practice is sincere, it is almost as good.” That’s pretty good, isn’t it? I think that is another way of saying what I am trying to say today. If your practice is sincere, then you have sincere qualities of how you are in relationship to the practice. That is actually very good, a wonderful thing. But your practice has to be sincere. If it is filled with conceit, with striving, with aversion, then it is not as good as becoming free. But if you can start having good qualities in your practice, then it is almost as good as being free, and certainly you have the satisfaction of having an enjoyable and sincere practice. You can carry that with you, and the fruits of that will follow you for a long time. 
 
   What all of this means is that a really important part of any practice that you do is self-reflection in which you become aware of the attitude that you have about how you are practicing. This includes that attitude you have as you practice. For me, this was a long time coming. I practiced for years and years before I paid attention to the attitude I had as I did the practice. For example, if the instruction is to stay with your breath, then I will try to stay with my breath. The breath seems to be the point, and by focusing on the breath, I am not noticing the attitude I have about focusing on the breath, because that is not the breath. So I can go along for a long time striving and pushing and demanding and judging myself negatively for not doing this breath meditation. I never noticed this because I was never told to pay attention to it—I was told to pay attention to the breath. But a very important part of the practice all along is to take that backward step and look at the attitude we have in relationship to what we are doing. This applies to everything we do, not just dharma practice. What is the attitude you have in relationship to everything? How we are is more important than what we do in spiritual practice, in dharma practice. 
 
   It’s nice that people find a lot of“whats”to do in their life, but I think that there is a certain kind of neurosis in California and this part of the world that proclaims that there is a right“what”out there for you: the perfect“what.” The perfect thing that you are supposed to do, like the perfect career—there is a career out there that is meant for you. There is a relationship out there that is meant for you—the perfect relationship. There is a“what”out there, and life is about finding the right“what.” What am I supposed to do with my life? Some people find wonderful“whats,”and they are lucky and it is very nice. Some people never find the right“whats”for whatever reason. It never occurred to them to look at the“how”. They can end up quite frustrated with their lives. There are some people who are blessed by never needing to find a“what.” The wisely understand either consciously or unconsciously that life is about how, how they are. They may not ever have a great, illustrious career that they are proud of and can show off at parties. People may ask,“What do you do?” “Oh, you know, I mop the floor at the local fast food restaurant.” That will not get you a lot of status at the parties. People often ask,“What do you do?” Would it not be interesting if people asked, instead,“How do you do it?” Or,“What attitude do you have towards what you do?” “How are you when you do what you do?” So for some people, they understand that, and that is what their life is about. The“what”is not so important but how they are in relationship to what they do is the important thing. I have known people who just shine, radiant people for whom how is more important than what. I know some people who are extremely poor. I know one person in this area who is poor for this area, but I think of him as the richest person I know, because his life is about how. 
 
   You might be a person who does not know if you are a“how”person or a“what”person. But even if you are looking for a“what”, Buddhist practice is much more about“how”. If you can focus on the how you are, then you will hopefully find out how to be at peace and happy and content with whatever you happen to do. Whether you find the perfect thing to do or not, or whether you find the perfect relationship or not, you will find some treasures of inner well-being and compassion and love that you can carry with you regardless of what happens around you. That is one of the goals of Buddhist practice, which is to find an independence that comes from having inner peace, inner well-being, inner security, inner fullness, or an inner knowing, that supports us, sustains us, liberates us, no matter where we go, or what we do, or whatever happens. This thing is here so that we are not looking outside of us for something, some“what,”some person, some teaching, some experience, that will prove that we are OK, or that will make everything OK for us. 
 
   One neurosis of American Buddhism is the experience neurosis, looking for that experience that will do it for you, the experience that will make it all OK.  It’s very simple. I like to think of Buddhist practice as being a very simple and perhaps even a humble enterprise. It’s not about big experiences. In the beginning it is about right understanding, and right understanding begins with a simple thing, and that is understanding what the goal is, the qualities of the goal, and then, step by step, in small, little increments, studying your attitude and seeing how you can transform your attitude so that the means reflects the goal. 
 Posted by Bill Lagerstrom at 11:24 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, August 15, 2011 
 
 August 18, 2011 
    This week there is a change to the blog - I have added a new box to the right side titled &quot;Explore Blog and Website Topics.&quot; There are two links to additional pages, &quot;Blog Format and Why This Blog&quot; and &quot;Themes.&quot;The Themes section will soon be links to all the topics on this blog and its associated website. As of now only the first three links are working. This is a work in progress and will be completed soon and updated regularly. Click on these entries and take a look. 

 
 
 
 
 Last Sunday a group of us spent four hours on Machias Seal Island off the coast of north east Maine. There were thousands of puffins all over the island and we were given a lot of time in a blind where the birds were right in front of us. It was a singularly remarkable experience as not that many get to set foot on the island. Above are two of the many pictures I took of these delightful birds.  
 Click here to listen to a single puffin voice which was amplified by dozens of puffins at a time:  http://www.box.net/shared/1ckxe2rk57i4gavtaa0a   Yes, this is a puffin! I thought they were some kind of cow! 
 +++++++++++++++++++++++ 
   This has been an interesting week in my work with Palliative Care at the hospital. Not so much for the interaction with the patients but with the new found internal freedom that I am experiencing in the time spent with the mostly dying. I am no longer experiencing any reluctance to go into any room regardless of what I see at the door. Usually if I see a lot of family and visitors with the patient I move on to the next person on my list. What I am finding is of course what I already know, which is that everyone around a very sick relative or friend also needs some affirmation that it is okay to be there and that they also need to be recognized. 
 
    The difference for me is that I now see myself not as an intruder, but as someone who has something of value to offer in what is a difficult situation. I have been doing this for a number of years now and there has been the occasional resistance to being someone with experience in this arena. At one point I found myself in the hallway with three members of a terminal patient who were listening with great care to what I had to offer in their situation. The observer in me watched as I was listened to, and saw that I had the right information that to be useful. I was supposed to be there. 
 
   I am not sure if this is entirely new for me to see this work in this way, but it seems as if a layer, a veil was lifted from my perception of events in front of me, and a clarity was present that felt different. I know that the analogy of an onion being peeled away a single layer at a time is an example of seeing more deeply the“what is”at any given moment. Usually I have only received a glimpse of the next layer when I could see in this manner–this felt as if an entire cover was no longer there and I saw, or rather had a felt sense of something new happening at the next level in the depths of my heart. 
 
   It is not important to know exactly what is happening to me internally, it is beneficial to my wellbeing to recognize when grace is present, when God is handing me a gift. There is a greater opening of the heart to receive grace when I become present to the present moment with no expectations, no pre-conceived notions of anything, without looking for the grand moment or the“I’m hot stuff”moments. I am not anyone special, only someone who is willing to put myself in the line of sight of those who are suffering in any way I can. This ability to do this is both gift and hard work, the time I have spent over the years with mentors, teachers, books, and a strong desire to be helpful in this way. 
 
   Following God’s Call to do what may seem to others as a hard labor with little or no reward is in reality not difficult at all. The only action to be learned is to take the first step, then the second, and so on until in hindsight one finds themselves way down a road that they may not have wanted to take in the first place. The first step for me was the“Yes”that I answered to the obvious Call to enter into intimacy with those needing a safe ear willing to listen to their needs. 
 
   I have been grateful this this last decade to be able to be with the dying first in NYC, and now here in Maine. I have had good teachers along with the best teachers of all–the person in the bed whenever I sat next to them. My main mentor said once that“It seems as if all the I know about compassion I learned from the dying.”I am definitely headed in the direction. 
 
   My reward? Just this, I have the willingness to show up again, and again, now without hesitation. Do I need more? No. I have found my vocation for this phase of my life coupled with the ongoing journey through the rooms of my heart, sometimes uncovering new treasure, wealth that has always been there, that which cannot be bought. 
 
 
 
 Sunset over Machais Pond, Maine 
 A story about the inward look: 
    There was once a small boy who banged a drum all day and loved every moment of it. He would not be quiet, no matter what anyone else said or did. Various people who called themselves Sufis, and other well-wishers, were called in by neighbors and asked to do something about the child.  
   The first so-called Sufi told the boy that he would, if he continued to make so much noise, perforate his eardrums; this reasoning was too advanced for the child, who was neither a scientist nor a scholar. The second told him that drum beating was a sacred activity and should be carried out only on special occasions. The third offered the neighbors plugs for their ears; the fourth gave the boy a book; the fifth gave the neighbors books that described a method of controlling anger through biofeedback; the sixth gave the boy meditation exercises to make him placid and explained that all reality was imagination. Like all placebos, each of these remedies worked for a short while, but none worked for very long.  
   Eventually, a real Sufi came along. He looked at the situation, handed the boy a hammer and chisel, and said, &quot;I wonder what is Inside the drum?&quot; 
 
 ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
   I have not had time to write my thoughts on the Third Noble Truth and this week is now jammed. Here is a short talk from a site I frequent regularly - http://www.buddhanet.net/ . Worth a look if you have been following this section of the blog. Worth a look even if you haven&apos;t. 
 
 THE THIRD NOBLE TRUTH 
 
 What is the Noble Truth of the Cessation of Suffering? It is the remainderless fading and cessation of that same craving; the rejecting, relinquishing, leaving and renouncing of it. But whereon is this craving abandoned and made to cease? Wherever there is what seems lovable and gratifying, thereon it is abandoned and made to cease. 
 
 There is this Noble Truth of the Cessation of Suffering: such was the vision, insight, wisdom, knowing and light that arose in me about things not heard before. 
 
 This Noble Truth must be penetrated to by realizing the Cessation of Suffering.... 
 
 This Noble Truth has been penetrated to by realizing the Cessation of Suffering: such was the vision, insight, wisdom, knowing and light that arose in me about things not heard before. 
 
 [Samyutta Nikaya LVI, 11] (The Teachings Of The Buddha) 
 
 The Third Noble Truth with its three aspects is:‘There is the cessation of suffering. The cessation of suffering is to be understood. The cessation of suffering has been understood.’ 
 
 The whole aim of the Buddhist teaching is to develop the reflective mind in order to let go of delusions. The Four Noble Truths is a teaching about letting go by investigating or looking into - contemplating:‘Why is it like this? Why is it this way?’It is good to ponder over things like why monks shave their heads or why Buddha-rupas look the way they do. We contemplate...the mind is not forming an opinion about whether these are good, bad, useful or useless. The mind is actually opening and considering.‘What does this mean? What do the monks represent? Why do they carry alms bowls? Why can’t they have money? Why can’t they grow their own food? We contemplate how this way of living has sustained the tradition and allowed it to be handed down from its original founder, Gautama the Buddha, to the present time. 
 
 We reflect as we see suffering; as we see the nature of desire; as we recognize that attachment to desire is suffering. These insights can only come through reflection; they cannot come through belief. You cannot make yourself believe or realize an insight as a willful act; through really contemplating and pondering these truths, the insights come to you. They come only through the mind being open and receptive to the teaching - blind belief is certainly not advised or expected of anyone. Instead, the mind should be willing to be receptive, pondering and considering. 
 
 This mental state is very important - it is the way out of suffering. It is not the mind which has fixed views and prejudices and thinks it knows it all or which just takes what other people say as being the truth. It is the mind that is open to these Four Noble Truths and can reflect upon something that we can see within our own mind. 
 
 People rarely realize non-suffering because it takes a special kind of willingness in order to ponder and investigate and get beyond the gross and the obvious. It takes a willingness to actually look at your own reactions, to be able to see the attachments and to contemplate:‘What does attachment feel like?’ 
 
 For example, do you feel happy or liberated by being attached to desire? Is it uplifting or depressing? These questions are for you to investigate. If you find out that being attached to your desires is liberating, then do that. Attach to all your desires and see what the result is. 
 
 In my practice, I have seen that attachment to my desires is suffering. There is no doubt about that. I can see how much suffering in my life has been caused by attachments to material things, ideas, attitudes or fears. I can see all kinds of unnecessary misery that I have caused myself through attachment because I did not know any better. I was brought up in America - the land of freedom. It promises the right to be happy, but what it really offers is the right to be attached to everything. America encourages you to try to be as happy as you can by getting things. However, if you are working with the Four Noble Truths, attachment is to be understood and contemplated; then the insight into non-attachment arises. This is not an intellectual stand or a command from your brain saying that you should not be attached; it is just a natural insight into non-attachment or non-suffering. 
 Peace until next week, Bill Lagerstrom 
 
 
 
 
 
    

 Posted by Bill Lagerstrom at 3:14 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Tuesday, August 2, 2011 
 
 August 4, 2011 
 Why This Blog, A Short Audio:   http://www.box.net/shared/j2mnbsjr2l 
 
    The picture above was taken by the Hubble Deep Field project where the telescope was pointed at a piece of sky that was the size of a dime held at arms length. The exposure was long and what was seen surprised not only the astronomers but everyone who saw the pictures as well. What you see are not stars but galaxies. Each point of light is a complete galaxy consisting of a billion or more stars. 
   Such is God&apos;s Creation. Overwhelming to be sure, beyond belief and comprehension indeed. Yet here we are, not only a speck compared to the vastness of the universe but to a great degree quite a few have an even smaller ego that tells them that they are the center of the cosmos. Something so small that tells us we are the most special of all that exists everywhere. Ponder the photo above and when you are ready play the video below which is an explanation of the Deep Field Project. Well worth looking at. 
 Click Here:  http://www.flixxy.com/hubble-deep-field.htm 
 +++++++++++++++++++ 
 
 What is wisdom? Perhaps it is simply honoring what is greater than ourself. 
 Perhaps it is knowing that what is greater than one&apos;s self is loving  and caring in ways we desire to embrace and know. 
 ++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
   Much of life can only be witnessed and experienced by being in quiet and allowing what is happening at any given moment to simply“be.”The question that needs to be asked is, “Who’s here?” Who is speaking and who is thinking …society, peer pressures, the voices of should and shouldn’t, or the myriad of other voices we have accumulated over the years that love to be heard knowing that there is no opposition to be presented. 
 
   For myself it was the voice of my mother telling me what to do and how to do it, as well as the mostly silent voice of my father who with only the tools he had to deal with life was largely only passing along the same non-voice to me. There I was for many years knowing it all, willing to tell anyone what I knew, and when confronted by those who knew what I did not–silent. A most pain filled existence. 
 
   Then the Navy where I became confident and competent in my moving forward in life as I had several good mentors who gave me the freedom to be who I was in the first half of life. Many successes were gained and fought for and I received a reputation for getting the job done in several careers I embarked on. 
 
   All this was surface and accomplished by following the numbers, something like the painting sets that were so popular where you put color inside the numbered shapes to match the numbers on the paints that came with the box. There was always somewhere to land in my travels as jobs and affirmations were always forthcoming from many who saw my work. 
 
   Now I find myself in the second half of life practicing going within for the needed wisdom which is leading me to a greater understanding of what my reality truly is. I no longer need a place to land as the Journey is not taken from a travelogue, no longer a planned affair. Becoming freer from attachments leaves me open to inquiry as to what is truly happening in the moment. A quiet investigation filled with curiosity and a letting be has been the lesson I am learning. 
 
   This June the old“Today is Spring and I cannot/did not see it,”left me when presented with all that I do see. The welcome mat is always out but we have to walk through the door. Repeating old patterns of behavior are no longer an option, I have taken out the mental ear plugs and listened to the music of the heart. 
 
   The coach asked his star player after he continually did only what he wanted on the field,“What is your problem! Is it ignorance or apathy?” The player responded with,“I don’t know and I don’t care!” 
 
   Knowledge that leads to right action overcomes all inability to listen and to see what God places right in front of us. 
 
    Today is the first day of the rest of my life! O.K. What is my life? Which leads me to the great questions of the day: 
 
 What is life? 
 What is the purpose of life? 
 What is the meaning of existence? 
 Who is God? 
 Why is there suffering?   etc. etc. 
 
   These are the questions we all at some time ask, and being rhetorical there is no answer that will satisfy. The more important questions are asked only in the wisdom years when we abandon the need to know direct answers. The important question: 
 
 What is reality? 
 
   The answer becomes something like: 
 
 Answer - I inquire and search for the Real. 
 Answer–What is happening, now. 
 
   Entering the answers with looking, seeing and hearing the Voice within that is recognized as our true voice, God speaking through our unique self, and the joining into co-creation with God of the Kingdom within. We are complete and whole as we are, uncovering what already is, this is the Great Journey. 
 
      Peace,   Bill Lagerstrom 
 
+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
 The discourse on the Four Noble Truths will continue next week. I got side tracked and had to leave it aside for a few days. 
 
   Another aside by way of photos. I spent the last 23 years of my work life working on major phone systems for big business in Manhattan. Here are a few shots off the web which gives some idea of my daily work environment. Add a lot of terminals for data entry and exploration to fix problems or add additional equipment and the picture becomes clearer. This may be one of the reasons I am so comfortable here in Maine as the computer rooms and floors I spent most of my time in were kept at 68 degrees to keep the equipment from frying. 
 
 
 
 Multiply this shelf by 20, 50, 80,100, stacked 5 high to get a sense of single phone system size.  This shelf is sparsely populated with cards.  
 
 Not only aisles of equipment but entire floors in buildings were filled with gear. 
 
 Data servers in one aisle. 
   Hope to hear from you soon. Bill L. 
 Posted by Bill Lagerstrom at 10:31 AM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Followers
 
Explore Blog and Website Topics
 
 Home BLOG FORMAT and WHY THIS BLOG THEMES 
 
Recommended Sites From Bill
 
 Tara Brach Audio Talks Richard Rohr Gil Fronsdal Audio Talks 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2011 (16) 
 ▼  08/21 (1) 
 August 25, 2011 
 

 ►  08/14 (1) 
 August 18, 2011 
 

 ►  07/31 (1) 
 August 4, 2011 
 

 ►  07/24 (1) 
 July 28,2011 
 

 ►  07/17 (1) 
 July 21, 2011 
 

 ►  07/10 (1) 
 July 14, 2011 
 

 ►  07/03 (1) 
 July 6, 2011 
 

 ►  06/19 (1) 
 June 23, 2011 
 

 ►  06/12 (1) 
 June 16, 2011 
 

 ►  06/05 (1) 
 June 9, 2011 
 

 ►  05/29 (1) 
 June 2, 2011 
 

 ►  05/22 (1) 
 May 25, 2011 
 

 ►  05/15 (1) 
 May 18, 2011 
 

 ►  05/08 (1) 
 May 12, 2011 
 

 ►  05/01 (1) 
 May 7, 2011 May 7, 2011  To all who offered t... 
 

 ►  04/03 (1) 
 April 6, 2011 
 
 
 
 
 Watermark template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
