<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008449" url="http://en.allexperts.com/q/Marketing-1090/2011/3/consumer-behaviour-1.htm" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="5" score="0.004411418958661321" bingtitle="Marketing: consumer behaviour, fast food restaurants, trash compactor" webtitle="Marketing: consumer behaviour, fast food restaurants, trash compactor">
			<query id="000386" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000745" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>fast food restaurants, trash compactor ... FAST FOOD RESTAURANT IS A SERVICE. Service quality is not one ... There are a number of techniques to aid in ...</description>
	<body>
		You are here:

 Home Business Small Business Information Marketing consumer behaviour 
 
 Marketing / consumer behaviour 
 
Advertisement
 
 Expert: Leo Lingham - 3/3/2011

 Question 
Using the example of fast food restaurants apply the concepts presented in the Consumption Behavior section. What implications might this analysis carry in developing business strategy for a particular restaurant?

3. Assume that you are developing an advertising program for an airline. How would you use laddering to assist in the development of the program?

4. A business is perplexed by the unexpected result of its recent advertising campaign and has turned to you for help in understanding what is going on. This new campaign was designed to increase the advertised products personal relevance to consumers by emphasizing its ability to fill previously underappreciated needs. Yet the campaign had had no noticeable effect on sales of the advertised product. Rather, it appeared to simulate the sales of competitor. Why might this have occurred

A marketing research study undertaken for a major appliance manufacturer disclosed that 30 percent of those polled plan on purchasing a trash compactor in the next three months, and 15 percent plan on purchasing a new iron. How much confidence should be placed in the predictive accuracy of these intention measurements? More generally, will predictive accuracy very across products? Why or why not?

 Answer 
Question:  Using the example of fast food restaurants apply the concepts presented in the Consumption Behavior section. What implications might this analysis carry in developing business strategy for a particular restaurant?

3. Assume that you are developing an advertising program for an airline. How would you use laddering to assist in the development of the program?

4. A business is perplexed by the unexpected result of its recent advertising campaign and has turned to you for help in understanding what is going on. This new campaign was designed to increase the advertised products personal relevance to consumers by emphasizing its ability to fill previously underappreciated needs. Yet the campaign had had no noticeable effect on sales of the advertised product. Rather, it appeared to simulate the sales of competitor. Why might this have occurred

A marketing research study undertaken for a major appliance manufacturer disclosed that 30 percent of those polled plan on purchasing a trash compactor in the next three months, and 15 percent plan on purchasing a new iron. How much confidence should be placed in the predictive accuracy of these intention measurements? More generally, will predictive accuracy very across products? Why or why not?






HERE IS SOME SOME USEFUL MATERIAL.
SOME ANSWERS HELD BACK DUE TO SPACE CONSTRAINT.
PLEASE FORWARD THESE BALANCE QUESTIONS TO MY EMAIL ID  
leolingham2000@gmail.com.
I will send the balance asap.
Regards
LEO LINGHAM
==========================================





Q. 2: Using the example of fast food restaurants apply the concepts presented in the Consumption Behavior section. What implications might this analysis carry in developing business strategy for a particular restaurant? 10 mark                  



FAST FOOD RESTAURANT  IS A SERVICE.
Service quality is not one-dimensional; it encompasses numerous factors that are important to customer satisfaction. Satisfaction basically is related to expectations and perceived delivery on these dimensions and as shown by the equation given below.
The quality of service delivery results in customer satisfaction&amp;their retention as it reinforces the perception that the value of the service received is grater than the price paid for it.
Quality is defined as the ability of the service provider to satisfy customer needs. Customer perception , service quality&amp;profitability are interdependent variable.
Even in the case of products, quality is difficult to define because it is highly dependent upon customer perception. The task is made more complicated in the case of service because of the intengible nature of service&amp;the variation in services offered to different customers.
There are several reasons why customers must be given quality service. Most important of them are

1. Industry has become so competitive that customers now have variety of alternatives. If the customers are lost, it can be extremely difficult to win back the individual.

2. Most customers do not complain when they experience problems, these customers simply opt out&amp;take their business elsewhere.
What is CUSTOMER Satisfaction?
CUSTOMER Satisfaction = function of {CUSTOMER -Expectation and Perceived delivery}
A person is said to be dissatisfied when the perceived delivery is lower than expectation; he/she is satisfied when they match; delighted when the delivery exceeds expectation and astonished when the delivery far exceeds expectation. The following equations explain these relationships.
Perceived Delivery&lt;Expectation --&gt;Dissatisfaction
Perceived Delivery = Expectation --&gt;Satisfaction
Perceived Delivery&gt;Expectation --&gt;Delight
Perceived Delivery&gt;&gt;Expectation --&gt;Astonishment
Dimensions of Service Quality:
There  are various aspects that a customer expects from different services.

1. Reliability: This refers to the ability of the company to perform the promised service dependably and accurately. Reliability is probably the single most important dimension of quality. Customers expect that companies will do what they say and they will do when they say they will do it.

2. Tangibles: This refers to the appearance of the physical facilities, equipment, personnel, and communication materials. As services are intangible, the tangibles give an impression to the customers about the quality of service they can expect from a firm. A bank in a shabby building will make the customer wonder whether their money will be safe in such a bank.

3. Responsiveness: This refers to the willingness of the employees to help customers and provide prompt service. When you go to a bank the minimum that you expect is that the employees would attend to you rather than chit-chat amongst themselves.

4. Assurance: This factor is linked to several minor factors such as competence, courtesy, credibility and security. Competence depends on the service provider&apos;s possession of the required skills and knowledge to perform the service. The politeness, respect, consideration, and friendliness of the service providers can be bundled into the term courtesy. Credibility refers to the perceived trustworthiness, believability, and honesty of the service provider. Security refers to the fact that the service should be free from danger, risk, and doubt. In sum, the assurance factor refers to the knowledge and courtesy of employees and their ability to inspire trust and confidence.

5. Empathy: Empathy refers to the caring, individualized attention the firm provides to its customers. It includes access, communication and understanding. Access refers to the approachability and ease with which the customer can contact the firm. Communication refers to keeping the customer informed in the language they can understand and listening to them. Understanding has to do with the efforts made by the service provider to know customers and their needs.
The Service Quality Gaps:
Gaps between perceived&amp;expected levels of service quality delivery result in the failure of the service provider.
These are the 5  gaps.
-The First gap does not know what customers expect.
-The second gap is between what the customer expects and what the management understands as the customers&apos; expectation from the company.
-The third gap is with reference to the management&apos;s understanding of the customer expectations and the service quality standards set by the management.
-The fourth gap is between the quality specifications and actual service delivery.
-The fifth gap is between what is communicated to customers and what is actually delivered.
It is possible to measure the gaps and take corrective actions to fill them to the extent possible. The most difficult gap to fill is the one between customer expectations and the perceived service delivery. The expectation of the customers keeps rising with every good experience. When a customer visits the service organization, he/she expects a better service than what was experienced in the last encounter.
====================================
The service marketing challenges are
-to generate re-sales
-to create a waiting list
-to create a positive word of mouth advertising
as a lot of new business is generated from satisfied customers.
WHICH MEANS THAT THERE IS NO/LITTLE GAP BETWEEN
SERVICE EXPECTATIONS AND SERVICE DELIVERY.
====================================
HOW DO YOU MATCH SERVICE EXPECTATION WITH DELIVERIES
IN PRODUCT MARKETING , WE RELY ON 4 P&apos;s
-product attributes/benefits
-pricing strategy
-place [ right / easy place to buy]
-promotions [ selected weighted mix]
--------------------------------------------------------------
IN CASE OF THE SERVICE, THE PRODUCT IS
-intangible, the greater the intangibility the more complex
the promise.
-perishable /heterogeneous, the production and consumption are often simulaneous.
IN SERVICE MARKETING, WE RELY ON 7 P&apos;s
-product service [ features/benefits]
-place [ flexibility]
-price [ flexi]
-promotions [ selected weighted mix]
-people [ ability,competent, right attitude ]
-physical evidence
-process
====================================
IN SERVICE BUSINESS,
-SERVICE MARKETING PROMOTES AND 
SERVICE MANAGEMENT GENERATES RESULTS, through
*service delivery
*service quality
*customer satisfaction/ relation  management
-service recovery
-service management audit.
=======================================
SERVICE MANAGEMENT PROVIDES SATISFACTORY SERVICE
-by designing the customer oriented business process
-cost effective service
-continuous improvements through research/development
-improving people&apos;s abilities/competences.
====================================
SERVICE MARKETING MEETS SERVICE MANAGEMENT
-by managing customer behavior
-by conducting customer research
-by managing customer expectations
-by reverse-engineering the product/service portfolio.
-by determining what service the market needs/ we can offer.
-what do we need to do to fill the gap.
=======================================
THE INTEGRITY OF PRODUCT-SERVICE DELIVERY
when the service marketing is intergrated with service management
that is ,what you promise [either explicitly or implicitily] and 
what you deliver
IN THIS CASE , &apos;&apos;INTEGRATED&apos;&apos; = &apos;&apos;INTEGRITY&apos;&apos;
There is no gap
WHICH MEANS CUSTOMER SATISFACTION,
WHICH IT TURN MEANS = SUCCESSFUL SERVICE MARKETING.
=========================================
KNOWING THE THEORY OF CONSUMER BEHAVIORS,
THE RESTUARANTS CAN TAILOR  THEIR BUSINESS
STRATEGY FOR IMPROVED SALES PERFORMANCE.
########################################################
Q. 3: Assume that you are developing an advertising program for an airline. How would you use laddering to assist in the development of the program? 10 mark                  


THE ADVERTISING PROGRAM COULD INCLUDE

1.Mission
-Sales goals
-Advertising
-objectives

2.SALES 
-Stage in PLC
-Market share and
-consumer base
-Competition and clutter
3.Advertising
frequency
4.Product
-substitutability
5.Message
-Message generation
-Message evaluation and selection
-Message execution
-Social-responsibility
6.review
7.Media
-Reach, frequency, impact
-Major media types
-Specific media vehicles
-Media timing
-Geographical media allocation
8.Measurement
-Communication
9.impact
-Sales impact



DEVELOPING AN ADVERTISING PROGRAM:

THE CRITICAL STEPS

We suggest nine steps for AIRLINEs to consider when attempting to develop their advertising programs. The steps form the acronym ADVERTISE.
1. Analyze market; 2. Define advertising objectives; 3. Verbalize key issues; 4. Establish spending level; 5. Review media alternatives; 6. Target media vehicles; 7. Invent message; 8. Start advertising; and 9. Evaluate results.
1.Analyze the Market
The initial step in developing an advertising program is analyzing the market to answer the question: &quot;What group of people am I trying to reach?&quot; This target audience is made up of potential clients and existing clients. The target may represent only a segment of the firm&apos;s overall target market if the goal of the advertising campaign is a specific audience within the firm&apos;s total market.
Advertising targets must be identified and analyzed so that the appropriate information is available for an advertising campaign. The analysis should include:
* Location and geographic dispersion of targets; * Criteria such as distribution by age, income, sex and education; and * Client attitudes regarding consuming and paying for services.
The kinds of information needed by various USERS will differ.
--------------------------------------------------
2.Define Advertising Objectives
Without clearly defined objectives, an advertising campaign is more likely to fail than succeed. Well-defined objectives act as the goal for any advertising campaign.
Advertising objectives should be worded in understandable, precise, and measurable terms. Precision and measurability are the critical characteristics that permit advertisers to evaluate the effectiveness of an advertising program subsequent to its implementation. An operational advertising objective for a given AIRLINE firm might be stated in the following manner:
&quot;Our primary advertising objective
is to increase our existing client
base by 20%.
Although stated in different ways, advertising objectives should always include a current benchmark, the direction and distance to move from that benchmark, and the length of time allotted for the objective&apos;s achievement.
3.Verbalize Key Issues
Similar to a political platform, an advertising platform consists of the key issues or selling points that an airline firm might wish to include in its advertising campaign.

4.Establish Spending Level
You should decide how much money to allocate to advertising for a specified time period. This task is difficult because it is virtually impossible to spell out the likely effects of advertising on company revenues. airline advertisers should also consider the geographic size of the target market and the distribution of client-consumers within the market when allocating advertising dollars.
There are a number of techniques to aid in determining advertising budgets including:
1. The objective and task approach; 2. The percent of revenues approach; 3. The competition-matching approach; and 4. The arbitrary approach.
The objective and task approach calls for the advertiser to determine the tasks and related budget required to accomplish the advertising objectives.
The percent of revenues approach is popular, due to its simplicity. The airlines advertiser multiplies past revenues, forecasted revenues, or some combination of the two by a percentage derived from what the firm has traditionally used, or an industry average.
Under the competition-matching approach, airlines advertisers try to mimic what the competition is doing with regard to advertising dollars. This method can result in an erroneous conclusion because the competition may have different advertising objectives, leading to an illogical match.
Finally, the arbitrary approach represents &quot;seat-of-the-pants&quot; decision-making. airlines with some advertising expertise and intuition are capable of allocating funds to advertising using this approach.

5.Review Media Alternatives
Your advertising program can utilize any of the following media:
* Television; * Radio; * Newspapers; * Magazines/Periodicals; * Direct Mail; * Business Papers; * Outdoor Displays; and * Other (e.g., mass transit displays).
While the strengths/weaknesses of each medium are beyond the scope of this article, the literature referenced at the end contains a great deal of relevant information.
6.Target Media Vehicles
The airline advertiser must develop a media plan to set forth the particular media alternative to be utilized in the advertising campaign. The primary goal is to reach the largest number of persons in the advertising target per dollar spent. Significant factors to consider when selecting a medium include:
* Size and nature of audience reached by the medium; * Cost of the medium; * Content of the advertisement; and * Location and demographic characteristics of individuals in the advertising target.
Once the advertising medium is selected, specific vehicles within that medium must be chosen. Picking a single media vehicle can be a difficult chore--consider the selection of one accounting periodical from all available accounting periodicals that sell advertising space. Cost comparison indicators can ease the burden somewhat. For example, the &quot;milline rate,&quot; a cost comparison indicator for newspapers, shows the cost of exposing a million persons to a given amount of newspaper advertisement space.

7.Invent Message
In determining the best content and form of an advertising message, the advertiser should consider the following factors:
* Nature of the services offered ; * Demographic characteristics of the people in the advertising target; * Advertising objectives and advertising platform; and * Choice of media.
8.Start Advertising
An advertising campaign requires a great deal of planning and coordination on the part of the airline advertiser. Even if the airlines turns to an agency, the execution of the advertising campaign involves cooperation from research organizations, production companies, media firms, printers, photo engravers, and commercial artists to name a few.
Detailed time schedules must be followed to ensure compliance with deadlines. The advertiser must also monitor the quality of each stage of the production of the advertisement and take corrective action, while retaining a degree of flexibility to make changes as called for during the campaign.
9.Evaluate Advertising
Although it is difficult to evaluate the effectiveness of an advertising campaign, the airlines should attempt to weigh the result. Actually, evaluations can be performed before, during, and after the campaign:
* Before--pretests of selected clients; * During--inquiring of individuals in the advertising target; and * After--tests of a sample of the advertising recipients.
The airlines firm should carefully evaluate the benefits of delivering its message to potential clients in the form of advertising. Advertising is not unprofessional; it is good business.
==================================================

Where Should I Place My Advertising?
Every month new advertising options become available. Beyond &quot;traditional&quot; media you can place ads in airports, on ski lifts and on televisions monitors in the front of grocery carts. Where you place your advertising should be guided by a simple principle: go where your target audience will have the highest likelihood of seeing or hearing it. Many advertising media work well to reach a diverse range of target consumers. There is no single medium inherently good or bad. A good medium for one product or service may be a poor medium for another. As you consider media choices look for one that fits your advertising goals, reaches your target efficiently and cost-effectively and is within your advertising budget. Based on these considerations, the following summarizes the relative advantages and disadvantages of the advertising media most frequently used by small businesses:
Internet Marketing or Online Marketing
Internet marketing, online marketing or emarketing are terms used for marketing your products or services over the Internet. Internet marketing is a great way to reach a wide, international audience at a relatively low cost. The nature of the medium allows consumers to find what they are looking for when they want, at their own convenience. It provides instant response and is very interactive. Internet marketing methods include search engine marketing, display advertising, email marketing, and interactive advertising, all completed through your website. Internet marketing can be very creative, cost effective and interactive.
Television
Television provides a means for reaching a great number of people in a short period of time. Small businesses will typically use either spot television or cable television. A spot television ad is placed on one station in one market. The number of target audience who see your ad depends upon how many viewers are tuned into the television station at a specific time. Cable advertising is placed either on a local cable television channel or on a cable network. The number of people reached by cable advertising depends upon the cable penetration and cable/channel program viewer ship in a given market.
Beyond television&apos;s reach, an additional advantage is its ability to convey your message with sight, sound, and motion. The disadvantages of television advertising are: relatively higher cost - both the terms of airtime and production, limited length of exposure, short airtime (making it difficult to present a complex or detailed message) and the clutter of many other ads.
Television ads may require multiple exposures to achieve message retention and consumer action. Also, many commercials are considered intrusive, prompting viewers to switch channels to avoid them.
Radio
Radio, like television, has the ability to quickly reach a large number of consumers. The major advantage of radio lies in its ability to efficiently target narrowly defined segments of consumers. The vast array of radio program formats lets an advertiser gear ads to almost any target audience.
Beyond this advantage, radio is commonly used by small businesses because it is relatively inexpensive (both in terms of airtime and production costs) and because deadlines for placing radio advertising are relatively short, providing an advertiser with increased flexibility. The disadvantages of radio are: an advertiser is limited to an audio message so there is no visual product or service identification, ad clutter can be high and exposure to the message is short and fleeting. Finally, similar to television, multiple exposures may be required for message retention and consumer reaction. Also, listeners may change stations to avoid commercials.
Newspapers
Newspapers permit and advertiser to reach a large number of people within a specified geographic area. Newspaper advertising has several advantages for the small business. An advertiser has flexibility in terms of as size and placement within the newspaper. Exposure to the ad is not limited, so readers can take their time with your message. Short deadlines permit quick response to changing market conditions. Disadvantages of newspaper advertising include:
  Declining readership and market penetration
  Ad space can be expensive
  Clutter of competitive advertising and a relatively short lifespan (newspapers are typically read once, then discarded), thus requiring multiple insertions.
Magazines
Magazines provide an advertiser with the means to reach highly targeted audiences. Specific groups can be reached by placing as ad in a magazine whose editorial content specializes in topics of interest to that target. This is true both of consumer and business publications. Audiences can be reached by placing ads in magazines which have well-defined geographic, demographic or lifestyle focus.
  Beyond the ability to reach specific audiences, the advantage of magazines include:
  Relatively long ad life and repeated ad exposure (magazines are typically looked through several times before discard);
  Excellent reproduction quality and pass-along value.
The disadvantages of magazines include:
  Long lead time
  Limited flexibility in terms of ad placement and format
  The potential for high costs in production and placement.
Outdoor (Billboards)
Outdoor advertising is typically used to reinforce or remind the consumer of the advertising messages communicated through other media. The advantages of outdoor advertising are:
  The ability to completely cover a market
  High levels of viewing frequency.
The disadvantages of outdoor advertising are related to viewing time. Because target consumers are typically moving, an outdoor advertisement must communicate with a minimum of words. Messages must be simple, direct, and easily understood.
Direct Mail
Direct mail advertisers use targeted mailing lists to reach highly specialized audiences. In addition to low waste in ad exposure, direct mail provides an advertiser with great flexibility in the message presentation. The disadvantages of direct mail include:
  Relatively high cost per contact
  Obtaining updated, accurate mailing lists
  Difficulty in getting the audience&apos;s attention (direct mail is often considered &quot;junk mail&quot;).
Yellow Pages
The Yellow Pages are an advertising medium that share many of the strengths of other advertising media while at the same time avoiding some of the limitations or disadvantages. As such, the Yellow Pages are best used to complement or extend the effects of advertising placed in other media. Like other media, the Yellow Pages permit an advertiser to select a well-defined geographic area, ranging from a neighborhood to an entire metropolitan area.
The advantages of the Yellow Pages are:
  Once the geography is defined, an ad has permanence, i.e., the Yellow Pages are kept as a regular reference.
  They support your other advertising by providing a convenient way for consumers to contact sources and obtain information on the products or services they desire at the time they are ready to &quot;take action.&quot;
  The Yellow pages are relatively low in cost in terms of both ad production and placement.
The disadvantages of the Yellow Pages include:
  Lack of timeliness (ads can be changed only once per year and, as a result, there is no opportunity for &quot;price advertising&quot;)
  Potential clutter in some classifications
  Not as much creative flexibility as other print media.
====================================================
Perhaps the major benefit of laddering is the insight it provides to advertising strategists. A definition of advertising communications which will permit advertising strategies to be developed from the HVM will be briefly discussed . The levels of abstraction framework, which underlie the formation of means-end chains, provide a basis for coordinating the results of laddering to advertising strategy development. That is, the perceptual constructs depicted in the HVM can be used as the basis for developing a strategy that will appeal to consumers with that particular orientation toward the product class.
The Means-Ends Conceptualization of Components of Advertising Strategy (MECCAS) in terms of five broad characteristics that correspond to the levels of abstraction conceptualization . Driving force, consumer benefit, and message elements are directly coordinated to the values, consequences, and attributes levels of the means-end model. The executional framework relates to the scenario for the advertisement the vehicle by which the value orientation is to be communicated. The specification of this tone for the advertisement is a critical aspect of strategy specification. It comes from an overall understanding of the way of perceiving the product class as indicated by a particular means-end path. As is apparent with this specification, added guidance can be given to creatives without infringing on their creativity.
The remaining and key aspect of advertising strategy specification is the concept of leverage point. Having all the other elements in mind, it is finally necessary to specify the manner by which the values-level focus will be activated for the advertisement, that is, how the values considerations in the advertisement are connected to the specific features of the advertisement.
Nonetheless, the advantages of being able to specify advertising strategy for all relevant parties management, creatives, and researcherscan be reviewed. The strategy statement itself becomes a concrete way of specifying advertising strategy alternatives. These alternatives are linked to the chains which underlie them, and thus a direct connection exists between the strategy and the perceptual orientation of the consumer. Furthermore, the MECCAS model coupled with the results from the HVM facilitate the development of several (truly different) strategies for comparison and review. Lastly, when a strategy has been se~ lected for execution, the MECCAS model provides for a better common understanding of what the final product should be. This obviously leads to the use of the MECCAS specification as the basis for evaluating the effectiveness of the advertisement.
Means-Ends Conceptualization of Components of Advertising Strategy
-Driving Force The value orientation of the strategy: the end-level to be focused on in the advertising.
-Leverage Point -The manner by which the advertising will tap into, reach, or activate the value or end-level of focus; the specific key way in which the value is linked to the specific features of the advertising.
-Executional Framework The overall scenario or action plot, plus the details of the advertising execution. The executional framework provides the vehicle by which the value orientation is communicated; especially the gestalt of the advertisement; its overall tone and style.
-Consumer Benefit The major positive consequences for the consumer that are explicitly communicated. verbally or visually, in the advertising.
-Message Elements The specific attributes, consequences, or features about the product that are communicated verbally or visually.

Technique of laddering both as an interviewing process and through subsequent analysis. It demonstrates the techniques usefulness in developing an understanding of how consumers translate the attributes of products into meaningful associations with respect to self-defining attitudes and values. The underlying theory behind the method, Means-End Theory, is discussed, as well as the elements of the means-end chains representing the cognitive levels of abstraction: attributes, consequences, and values.
The interview environment necessary for laddering to take place is given special attention along with the particular probing techniques employed in the qualitative process of laddering. Basically, the respondent has to feel as if on a voyage of self-discovery and that the object of the trip is to revisit everyday, commonplace experiences and examine the assumptions and desires driving seemingly simple choice behavior.
Several specific interviewing devices are described for eliciting product distinctions from respondents that serve to initiate the laddering process, among them the use of triads, exploring preference-consumption differences, and examining how consumption differs by occasion. The value of the occasional context, providing a concrete frame of reference to generate meaningful distinctions, is emphasized. Other techniques ~or moving the laddering interview upward when blocking occurs are also discussed and illustrated.
The analysis of laddering data is detailed noting the critical difference between this methodology and more traditional qualitative research, namely, the primary output being (structurally) quantitative in nature in the form of a hierarchical value map (HVM). In this vein, the content analysis of ladder elements is positioned as an important step in this crossing over from the qualitative to quantitative.
Detailed attention is paid to the construction of the HVM from the implication matrix, which represents the number of direct and indirect linkages between the qualitative concepts elicited during the laddering process. Five types of relations among elements are discussed, and their respective implications for constructing a HVM are illustrated.
Having the HVM to work with, the next step in transforming the output of laddering into useful information for marketing decision-making is to determine the dominant perceptual orientations. That is, all potential pathways (connections among elements) must be examined to determine their relative strength of association. Two primary considerations are specified with examples, namely, the number of relations among elements within the chain and the extent to which all elements are interconnected.
Lastly, the issue of applications is discussed referencing the key research problems of perceptual segmentation, determining the importance weights of the various components of the ladders, and the development and subsequent assessment of advertising from this value perspective. All of the application areas have in common that they depend on ladderings ability to draw out from the respondent the true basis for any meaningful connection they have to the product class.
##############################################################

 
 Questioner&apos;s Rating 

 Rating(1-10) Knowledgeability = 9 Clarity of Response = 9 Politeness = 9 Comment Thanks for excellent support with very useful materials. 


 Add to this Answer Ask a Question 
 
Related Articles

 Advertising and Marketing - Advertising 101 New&amp;#39;10-10&amp;#39; Phone Service Ad Rules Issued by FTC/FCC Advertising Definition - Business Terms Glossary - Advertising Making an Effective Marketing Plan Customer Service - What Role Does it Play in Marketing? 
 
 Marketing 


 All Answers 
 
Answers by Expert:

 Leo Lingham Kip Gienau William Siebler Joe Fournet Ashraf Nisseem Jim Gawley Shane Scherch Russel Ray BigAl Sebastien Prince Boaz Gal Glen Franklin Amy Lorenti Terri Conduff Tim Collins Steve Pywell 
 
 Ask Experts 

 Volunteer 
 
 Leo Lingham 

Expertise

I can answer questions on marketing, marketing planning,
product management, advertising, sales promotions, sales planning,
merchandising, direct marketing, and sales management.

Experience

18 YEARS WORKING MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCE IN BUSINESS PLANNING,
STRATEGIC PLANNING, MARKETING, SALES MANAGEMENT, AND ORGANIZATION DEVELOPMENT.

PLUS

24 YEARS OF MANAGEMENT CONSULTING IN STRATEGIC PLANNING,
BUSINESS PLANNING, PRODUCT MANAGEMENT, MANAGEMENT TRAINING,
AND BUSINESS COACHING.

MASTERS IN SCIENCE

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ADMINSTRATION.

 Organizations 
PRINCIPAL--BESTBUSICON PTY LTD

MANAGEMENT CONSULTING SERVICES.

 Education/Credentials 
MASTERS IN SCIENCE

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ADMINSTRATION

 
 User Agreement Privacy Policy 

©2012 About.com, a part of The New York Times Company . All rights reserved.
 
 About Us Tell Friends How to Ask How to Volunteer FAQ Tech Support Top Experts Expert Login 
 
Browse Answers:

 By Category Alphabetically 
 Find expert answers to: Find
	</body>
</document>
