<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008275" url="http://mlizcochico.com/?cat=36" time="2012-07-13-01:46" support="3" score="0.002356795756792296" bingtitle="A Simple Life » tags" webtitle="A Simple Lifetags">
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>Cup 1/2 empty or 1/2 full? 1/2 full. 15. Where ... Favorite fast food restaurant? Jollibee. 37. How many times did you ... Which store would you choose to max out your credit card?</description>
	<body>
		Home The Blogger Blogroll Disclosure Policy 
 
A Simple Life
 Sugar&apos;n spice and everything nice…that&apos;s what Liza is made of. 
Archive for the‘tags’Category
 October 6th, 2009 | liza 
 Birthdate Tag&amp;Some Awards 

I was tagged by Imelda over at My Daily Thoughts and Moods .  She wants to know what my birthdate means and here’s what I got…

 
 You Are an Idealist 
 
 
You are a natural born leader, even if those leadership talents haven’t been developed yet.

You have the power and self confidence to succeed in life, and your power grows daily.

Besides power, you also have a great deal of creativity that enables you to innovate instead of fail.

You are a visionary, seeing the big picture instead of all of the trivial little details.

 Your strength: Your supreme genius 

 Your weakness: Your inappropriate sensitivity 

 Your power color: Gold 

 Your power symbol: Star 

 Your power month: January
 

 What Does Your Birth Date Mean? 

Want to know what your birthdate means?  Grab the tag and take the quiz.

~oOo~

The following awards were bestowed upon me by Patricia over at Subjective Soup .  Thank you so much!

 

 

 

 

Tags: quiz 

 awards , tags 6 comments September 8th, 2009 | liza 
 Getting To Know Each Other&amp;Friendship Award 

I was tagged by Shy over at Simple Happy Life . Thanks Shy!  She wants to know a little more about me so here goes….


1. What time did you get up this morning? 9:10

2. How do you like your steak? Medium Well

3. What was the last film you saw at the cinema? Harry Potter and The Half Blood Prince

4. What is your favorite TV show? Lifestyle Channel shows

5. If you could live anywhere in the world where would it be? Philippines

6. What did you have for breakfast? A banana

7. What is your favorite cuisine? Japanese

8. What foods do you dislike? Hmmm, can’t think of any right now

9. Favorite place to eat? Sakura (for Yakiniku) and Sugi (for chahan and tempura)

10. Favorite dressing? Italian Vinaigrette

11. What kind of vehicle do you drive? Honda Civic. I don’t drive much, though.

12. What are your favorite clothes? Jeans or Capri and Shirt/blouse

13. Where would you visit if you had the chance? Ibiza and Rome

14. Cup 1/2 empty or 1/2 full? 1/2 full

15. Where would you want to retire? Somewhere rural, a farm or a resort

16. Favorite time of day? Night time

17. Where were you born? QC

18. What is your favorite sport to watch? Bowling, tennis, F1

19. Who do you think will not tag you back? No idea

20. Person you expect to tag you back first? Can’t think of anyone

21. Who are you most curious about their responses to this? My online friends

22. Bird watcher? Sometimes

23. Are you a morning person or a night person? night person

24. Do you have any pets? Lokii, a shih-tzu

25. Any new and exciting news you’d like to share? I’m excited about meeting Mira

26. What did you want to be when you were little? A doctor

27. What is your best childhood memory? Playing marbles, umakyat sa puno and the street games!

29. Are you married? Yes

30. Always wear your seat belt? Yes!

31. Been in a car accident? Nothing major

32. Any pet peeves? People who can’t wait for their turn

33. Favorite Pizza Toppings? Pepperoni and mushroom

34. Favorite Flower? Rose, tulips, mums

35. Favorite ice cream? green tea and strawberry

36. Favorite fast food restaurant? Jollibee

37. How many times did you fail your driver’s test? Once

38. From whom did you get your last email? Pink Fab

39. Which store would you choose to max out your credit card? Rustan’s

40. Do anything spontaneous lately? I got angry yesterday

41. Like your job? I don’t have a job

42. Broccoli? Love it!

43. What was your favorite vacation? Tokyo, Guam and Boracay

44. Last person you went out to dinner with? my family!

45. What are you listening to right now? I don’t know the title of the song

46. What is your favorite color? Red and yellow!!

47. How many tattoos do you have? None

48. How many are you tagging for this quiz? Just Shy

49. What time did you finish this quiz? 11:04 am

50. Coffee drinker? Very!!!

—–

The Friendship Award came from Windy over at Windmill on the Hill .  Windy, thank you so much both for the award and the friendship. 

 

The Friendship Blog Award above implies :

 Green: to symbolize the new buddies
 Yellow: to represent the guys who are always active
 Blue: to symbolize with high performing PR Bloggers
 Red: to symbolize that our blood is red and therefore we are all brothers.

Friendship through blogging is one of the very early sought after aims for most Bloggers. There are times when it is difficult to foster friendship through virtual reality. There are friends and there are friends. Even in life, we know that friendship is built on a lot of real life contact and considerations.

I’ve met Bloggers who are contentious, foul mouthed, hypocrites, back stabbers and they have a different agenda behind the curtain of their Blog.

So, to receive a Friendship Blog Award from David Funk is indeed precious and something to be cherished.

The Friendship Blog Award comes with a few DO’s and these are:

1. Create a post as above
2. Include a link Giver Award.
3. For colleagues who have not followed this site or not exchange links, please follow or exchange links with me.
4. Copy-paste the image to be replicated at your Blog Post.

I have not thought yet of whom to pass this on.  My recipients will follow.



 tags 2 comments July 3rd, 2009 | liza 
 We Are The World Meme 

I was tagged by Genie Princess over at Mariuca’s Perfume Gallery . Thanks GP!

 

 *Start Copy Here* 

 You do not have to be tagged to play along. The game is simple and so are the rules. 

 1. Copy from *Start Copy Here* through *End Copy Here* 

 2. Add your site(s) to the list. Just be sure to post at each site you add. 

 3. Tag as many bloggers as you like so the list keeps on growing. 

 4. Let me know your blog’s name and url by leaving me a comment HERE . I will add you to the master list. 

 5. Come back and copy the master list back to your site, often. This process will allow late-comers to get as much link benefit as the first ones in. 

 We Are The World Bloggers Master List: 

 1. Emila Yusof 2. The Other Side of Emila 3. Mariuca 4. Mariuca’s Perfume Gallery 5. Meow Diaries 11. Unlisted One 7. Spiff, the Spaceman 8. My Sweet Escape 9. Nota Nurul 10. Life’s Tapestry 11. Spontaneous Insignificancy 12. LadyJava 13. Miss Igorota 14. AnnyBoo 15. Yoon See 16. Jia’s Life 17. Nessa’s Mumblings 18. Also Mommy 19. The Walk of Life 20. Pretty Firefly 21. Untouchable EARTH 22. Baterya 23. Comedy Plus 24. Bain Cardin 25. Strawberry Milkshake 26. Turn-U-Off 27. Jom Heboh Di Sini 28. Notes by Marvic 29. Memoir Mez 30. Origena 31. Walking Newspaper 32. Nurul Aqilah 33. Bluedreamer 34. Breaking the Boundaries 35. Life According to Me 36. A Great Pleasure 37. Time Goes By 38. Kancing itu Butang 39. In my Kitchen 41. Fyzal’s Territory 40. Wiggy’s World 40. A Simple Life 41. A Taxi Ride 42. Single Life of Me 43. Little Bits of Info 44. Ode to Adrienne 45. KMP 46. You’re next! 

 *End Copy Here* 

 I would like to invite the following to join us on board: 

 Simple Happy Life 

 Christinchen’s Soapbox 

 When Life Becomes A Book 

 The Mommy Journey 

 A Taxi Ride 
 


 tags 13 comments May 14th, 2009 | liza 
 Friendship Chain Tag 

This friendship chain tag came from my friend Bluedreamer over at Top 5 . Thank you Blue for including me on this tag.

 
 ~~Begin Copy~~ 
This is the easy way and the fastest way to :1. Make your Authority Technorati explode. 2. Increase your Google Page Rank. 3. Get more traffic to your blog. 4. Makes more new friends.

Rules :
1. Start copy from“Begin Copy”until“End Copy”to your blog.
2. Put your own blog name and link.
3. Tag your friends as much as you can.

1. Picturing of Life 2. Juliana’s Site 3. Hazel-My Life, My Hope, My Future. 4. Jeanne-The Callalily Space 5. My Family is my Life 6. The Simple Life of a Baghag 7. On A Wonderful Day Like Today 8. House Everything 9. The Creativity in Me 10. Travel and Photography 11. Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow 12. You Are My Sunshine 13. Song to Remember 14. Super Blog 15. Philiippine Tv Marathon 16. Simply Blue 17. Breaking the Boundaries 18. Top Five 19. A Simple Life 20. Simple Happy Life 21. Your next

~~End Copy~~

Now tagging: Wishing on A Falling Star , A Great Pleasure , Simple Happy Life , Cacai’s Step and Journey , Mira’s Web journal , One At A Time 

Tags: friendship chain 

 tags 6 comments February 13th, 2009 | liza 
 Valentine’s Love 

I was tagged by my good friend Jean over at A Great Pleasure .  Valentine’s day is not just for couples, but also for family and friends.  Come join us in spreading the love:

 Arlene , Babette , BlueDreamer , Carmie , Entrepgirl , Gagay , Hailey , JulianaRW , Proud Mommy , Nyumix 

 
 

***start copy***

 Rules: 
1) Once you’re tagged, install the corner banner at your blog as a third party html code. (The corner banner need to stay at your blog for at least 2 weeks).
2) Post about this meme, Valentine’s Love .
3) Add your blog/s with link/s to the Valentine’s Lovers list and leave a comment at this post HERE .
3) Tag all your special friends.
4) Please remember to update your list regularly so that you would not miss out anyone in your Valentine’s Lovers list.

 Corner Banner 

 
 p/s: The wordings on this banner with automatically changed to‘Tagged with Love! xoxo’on Feb 15. 
 

&lt;style&gt;
div.OneBandSmallLeft {
position:absolute;
left:0px;
top:0px;
overflow:visible;
height:163px;
width:163px;
margin:0;
padding:0;
z-index:1000000000;
border:none;
float:none;
}

div.OneBandSmallRight {
position:absolute;
left:100%;
top:0px;
overflow:visible;
height:163px;
width:163px;
margin:0 0 0 -163px;
padding:0 0 0 0;
z-index:1000000000;
border:none;
float:none;
}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=”OneBandSmallRight”&gt;&lt;img border=”0″usemap=”#OneLinkMapSmallRight”width=”163″src=”http://i168.photobucket.com/albums/u197/jeanchia_photos/VD2009_1.png”height=”163″/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;map name=”OneLinkMapSmallRight”&gt;&lt;area shape=”poly”coords=”0,0,163,163,163,133,30,0″href=”http://agreatpleasure.com”target=”_blank”/&gt;&lt;/map&gt;

 
 Instruction to install corner banner (For blogger):
1. Go to‘Layout’, Click on‘Add a Gadget’.
2. Select‘HTML/ Javascript’, insert the html code above in the provided box.
3. Click‘Save’.

 Valentine’s Lovers: 
 1. A Great Pleasure 2. Time Goes By 3. Listen With Your Heart 4. Glossalicious 5. Wishing on a Falling Star 6. Mariuca’s Perfume Gallery 7. Simply Shinade 8. A Simple Life 9. Mommy’s Little Corner 10. Ramblings of the Phat 11. 0007 Undercover TAGMEMAWARD CAT 12. Notes by Marvic 13. Maiylah’s Snippets 14. Picture Clusters 15. This is a Miracle 16. purplefrogcat 17. Also Mommy 18. Both Sides Now 19. illusionaire 20. Candles, Crafts and Whatnot 21. The Brainy Bimbo 22. Sweet Nothings 23. Turn-u-Off 24. Chopsticks 25. My Views On My So Called Life 26. Gagay 27. Empty Streets 1027 28. Life According To Me 29. Yummy-as-can-be 30. Mom…Check Nyo 31. Everything Under the Sun 32. My Sweet Escape 33. Never Enough Stuff 34. Windmill on the Hill 35. Snapshot 36. Twinkletoe Writing Space 37. A Piece of M.I.N.D 38. Life is too short to be ordinary… 39. Our Journey to Forever 40. What a colourful life!! 41. Oh Fer Cryin’Out Loud 42. My Online Paradise 43. My Life Story 44. Moments of Colours 45. Lynn’s Chic Spot 46. Simply The Best 47. The Spirit of Blogging 48. Tales of A Pinay Single Mom 49. Simple Life 50. Hit-or-Miss 
***end copy***


 tags 4 comments Previous Entries 
Drop Here!
 
 

 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 Subscribe to A Simple Life by Email 
 Top EC Droppers 

 a new concept for a new life TriBaricas Com sucen Strategic Thinking Essentials Free Download Management Books Free Download Engineering EBooks Why Google Analytics? Al Revis Academy Bakatsuki Fashion And Costume Just One Touch 
 
Useful Resources
 Thank you cards 
 Signazon 
 Buy Ativan Online 
 Organo Gold 
 
My Blog List

 The 10 greatest love songs 
 
My Blogs

 Mommy’s Little Corner Moms…..Check Nyo Yummy-as-can-be 
 
Friends’Buttons
 
ASL Stats
 
 View My Stats 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 Earn Money Online 
Grab my badge
 
Recent Posts

 ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province Smile!–Who needs a healthy diet? Jumpstart Weight Loss MM–Signal Fire The Move To Sexy (50) 
 
Recent Comments

 Mary on ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province Denise on ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province HansHB on ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province Mathilda on ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province Leovi on ESH/SWF–Sagada, Mountain Province 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (14) June 2012 (36) May 2012 (56) April 2012 (39) March 2012 (35) February 2012 (25) January 2012 (27) December 2011 (20) November 2011 (30) October 2011 (18) September 2011 (57) August 2011 (33) July 2011 (31) June 2011 (39) May 2011 (26) April 2011 (30) March 2011 (37) February 2011 (34) January 2011 (41) December 2010 (42) November 2010 (43) October 2010 (50) September 2010 (60) August 2010 (35) July 2010 (27) June 2010 (14) May 2010 (25) April 2010 (32) March 2010 (14) February 2010 (17) January 2010 (17) December 2009 (22) November 2009 (15) October 2009 (17) September 2009 (34) August 2009 (22) July 2009 (17) June 2009 (12) May 2009 (34) April 2009 (23) March 2009 (22) February 2009 (23) January 2009 (20) December 2008 (50) November 2008 (33) October 2008 (42) September 2008 (40) August 2008 (48) July 2008 (53) June 2008 (61) May 2008 (59) April 2008 (61) March 2008 (30) February 2008 (41) January 2008 (45) December 2007 (37) November 2007 (17) October 2007 (18) September 2007 (1) 
Categories
 Select Category 7 wonders of nature about me accessories accident acne ad network advertising african love birds alcoholism angels animals anniversary arts and crafts arts and humanities auto insurance auto loan automobile automotive award awards baking banaba bank account banking and finance bar faucets bar stool beauty products beauty salon bed linen beddings and linen beddings and linens behavior being a mom blogging books burn business buying a home buzz caffeine cancer car rental car seats career cars cash advance casino cell phone amplifiers cheap finds child life insurance christmas cigars clothing collections colors communication computer computer and internet computer training computers cookies cooking cork uses cosmetic surgery counseling coupon codes credit cards cross stitching dance wear dating services death depression desserts diabetes diet dining discounts diseases do-it-yourself drug addiction earn money edible flowers education electronics embroidery employment energy booster entertainment entrecard environment equipments events exercise exercise equipment family fashion fathers’day feng shui finance find people fitness flowers food and drinks freebies Friday’s Feast friends fruits fun furniture gadgets games garage rentals garden gardening garlic gift ideas girls’clothes going green gold golf google page rank gourmet gout guns hair care hardware headache health health alert health and beauty health and fitness health benefits health tips heat stroke heath insurance herbal supplements herbs hobbies holiday holiday greetings holidays home decors home improvement hospital equipment hotels house and home how to’s human resources human rights humor illnesses industrial equipment info insomnia insurance insurance policy internet investment jet lag jewelry job finder jobs joke time junk foods karma ketchup kids kitchen aids kitchen tips languages laptop lasik surgery legal matters lighting linky love loans love makeover medical career medical equipment medical insurance medication memes men menopause message messages migraines misc mobile phones money mood booster mortgage mother-in-law motherhood mothers day movers movies Music nose bleeding nuts oatmeal obsessive compulsive occassions olive oil online bingo online games outdoor packaging paper tole parking rentals parkinson’s disease party payday loans pc games pens people and culture personal computer personality personalize pet bed petroleum pets Philippines photo hunters plants pregnancy prosatte cancer protection public service quick fix quiz rant reading real estate recipes recreation and sports recruitment rehabilitation relationships releasers repair manuals retro lamps review safety cutters sardines savings account school science and technology search engine security system services shih tzu shopping silver skin care sleep disorder sleeping difficulty smile smile file social issues social networking sites sports storage strawberry stress&amp;anxiety supplements tags technology thank you note the eighties tips tips and tricks tools toys and games transportation travel treatment trivia Uncategorized upgrade uric acid useful tips vacation vegetables watches web design web directory web hosting wedding weekend snapshot weight loss wine wine racks women women’s interest women’s month wordless wednesday yoga yogurt 
 A Simple Life 

 ESH/SWF – Sagada, Mountain Province Smile! – Who needs a healthy diet? Jumpstart Weight Loss MM – Signal Fire The Move To Sexy (50) 
 
Directory
 Her Blog Directory 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress | Elegant Touch designed by SimplyWP
	</body>
</document>
