<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008648" url="http://www.memphisdailynews.com/editorial/Article.aspx?id=36170" time="2012-07-13-02:06" support="2" score="0.0013820212476032857" bingtitle="Holley Distributors Delivers &apos;Fast-Food Car Washing&apos; - Memphis ..." webtitle="Holley Distributors Delivers &apos;Fast-Food Car Washing&apos; - Memphis Daily News">
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>Holley Distributors Delivers &apos;Fast-Food Car Washing&apos; ... Kerry Sewell can remember a time when visiting a fast-food ... the steering wheel, the system is able to pick that ...</description>
	<body>
		» Subscribe
 Today! More of what you want to know. Home | About Us | Public Notices | Public Records   Help | Your Account | Contact Us | Log In | Subscribe X User Name: * Password: * Forgot your password? Keep me logged in NAME&amp;PROPERTY SEARCH » Research millions of people and
 properties [+] 
 Name Property 
 
 
 
 
 CUSTOM LIST BUILDER » Build a downloadable list
 of prospects that meet your criteria WATCH SERVICE » Monitor any person, property or
 company [+] 
 Name Property 
 
Name:
 

Send Results to This Email:
 
 
Street Address:
 

Send Results to This Email:
 
 DATA DIRECT » Get valuable lists emailed directly
 to you NEIGHBORHOOD REPORT » Keep an eye on trends and events
 near you [+] 
Street Address:
 
 CRIME REPORT » Up-to-date reports of crimes near
 you [+] 
Street Address:
 
 
Front Page News
 Friday, Jul. 13, 2012 Thursday, Jul. 12, 2012 Wednesday, Jul. 11, 2012 Tuesday, Jul. 10, 2012 Monday, Jul. 9, 2012 
 « Back 

Go to date:
   
Search News:
   
Public Records
 Thursday, Jul. 12, 2012 Wednesday, Jul. 11, 2012 Tuesday, Jul. 10, 2012 Monday, Jul. 9, 2012 Friday, Jul. 6, 2012 
 « Back 

Go to date:
   
Search Records:
   
Public Notices
 Thursday, Jul. 12, 2012 Wednesday, Jul. 11, 2012 Tuesday, Jul. 10, 2012 Monday, Jul. 9, 2012 Sunday, Jul. 8, 2012 
 « Back 

Go to date:
   
Search Notices:
   
 Money&amp;Markets 
 Home &gt; VOL. 123 | NO. 53 | Monday, March 17, 2008 Memphis Small Business Spotlight 
 Holley Distributors Delivers &apos;Fast-Food Car Washing&apos; 


 Tweet Print | Front Page | Email this story | Comments ( ) You have entered an invalid email address
 Close To: 
 * Required 
 From: 
 * Required 
 Message: 
 You have entered an invalid email address
 Close From (email): * Required 
 
 Message: * Required 
 OPEN FOR BUSINESS: The most recent location of Car Wash USA Express has opened on Austin Peay Highway in Raleigh. -- Photo By Rosalind Guy Holley Distributors
 
 Address: 3350 Highway 309 North, Byhalia
 Owner: Ray Holley
 Phone: 662-893-4605
 Web site: www.holleydistributors.com 
Kerry Sewell can remember a time when visiting a fast-food restaurant meant time spent with family. As a child, his parents would take him to McDonald&apos;s. And back then, he said, that was a big deal.


&quot;We&apos;d get to sit at McDonald&apos;s and eat and have a big time,&quot; he said. &quot;Now, with my kids, going to McDonald&apos;s just means you&apos;re going through the drive-thru.&quot;


The car wash industry has experienced a similar evolution, Sewell said. It&apos;s what he calls &quot;fast-food car washing.&quot;


&quot;Nobody wants to get out and really wash their cars anymore,&quot; said Sewell, vice president of Car Wash Superstore, the catalog division of Byhalia-based Holley Distributors, which owns and operates 12 Car Wash USA Express locations in Tennessee, Mississippi and Arkansas. &quot;They want the same results, but they want it faster and they want to be able to do it in a way that&apos;s convenient. It&apos;s a society based on service and convenience.&quot;



 Business growth
 

As a part of that &quot;hurry up and get it done&quot; movement, the car wash industry has come up with express car wash systems that simply require driving into a tunnel and, as Sewell puts it, &quot;just sit back and enjoy the ride.&quot;


The most recent location of Car Wash USA Express recently was opened on Austin Peay Highway in Raleigh. Sewell said the response from the surrounding neighborhood has been overwhelming.


Since joining the company a year ago, Sewell has seen the express car wash concept and the catalog business take off.


Car Wash Superstore put out its sixth catalog this year, a 240-page book with specialty parts for express tunnels. The company sends the catalogs to distributors and car wash owners and operators.


&quot;It&apos;s a business that&apos;s grown in the last five years from a $900,000 company to $5.5 million that we did last year,&quot; Sewell said.


While the parent company, Holley Distributors, only focuses on development in the tri-state area, Car Wash Superstore reaches to customers in Canada, Mexico and Australia.


Through Holley Distributors, Sewell said they also work with people interested in opening their own express car washes.


The company is finishing a project in Millington, where it developed and built a car wash system for an operator who already owns a car wash in Jonesboro, Ark.


In addition to the latest store that opened on Austin Peay Highway, there are locations on U.S. 64 in Lakeland and on Goodman Road in DeSoto County.


The company is looking at a couple of other sites in Memphis to open express car wash tunnels, including one in the Elvis Presley Boulevard area.


Sewell said the company is excited about being a part of the revitalization of areas such as Raleigh and Whitehaven.


&quot;You&apos;re seeing a lot of shovels going in the ground (around Brooks Road) and a lot of new projects and new buildings coming up, and it&apos;s just going to completely revitalize the area,&quot; he said.



 Express service
 

Customers pay between $5 and $10 for an approximate 100-yard ride through the express car washes. The conveyor system has sensors that contour to the car, so it knows where the car is at all times.


&quot;There&apos;s nowhere that your car is in there that they don&apos;t know where it is,&quot; Sewell said.


Before the company opens a new car wash to the public, they test it. Sometimes, he said, they&apos;ll put a car in neutral and let it go through the tunnel.


If someone is riding through the tunnel and happens to hit the brakes or begin turning the steering wheel, the system is able to pick that up too.


&quot;There&apos;s a little roller that goes all the way through so if your car were to stop and the next roller catches on, it&apos;ll know that you stopped and it&apos;ll shut the system down,&quot; he said. &quot;Again, it knows where your car is and it knows if you&apos;re stopping your vehicle. That&apos;s not supposed to happen. So if there&apos;s anybody else who&apos;s back behind you, it stops the entire system to keep anybody from moving into your vehicle.&quot;



 Family decision
 

Sewell worked as vice president of marketing and communications for the Memphis Redbirds for nearly 10 years until he left last January to join his brother-in-law Ray Holley, who owns Holley Distributors.


Often when the two families would go on vacations together, Sewell said the topic of him joining the company came up.


Feeling like there wasn&apos;t much left to accomplish with his baseball career in Memphis and not wanting to leave the area, he finally decided to take his brother-in-law up on the offer.


&quot;So I came over to run the catalog company, and while we were doing this he had just gotten started on this express exterior tunnel concept,&quot; Sewell said.
 Follow @memphisdaily 
 Sign-Up For Our Free Email Edition 
Get the news first with our daily email
 Name * 
 Email * * 
Learn more about seminars and training events hosted by The Daily News and Chandler
 Reports.
 Get more from The Daily News Huey’s Employees Host Shoe Drive McDonald’s makes a big local hiring push Memphis Paychecks Stretch Fourth Furthest, Forbes Says News, Training&amp;Events Impact of health care reform on the Mid-South Mulroy, McDonald talk muni schools with BTH panel Kriner Cash’s superintendent contract, 1-cent gas tax approval 
 RECORD TOTALS DAY WEEK YEAR PROPERTY SALES 125 360 9,039 MORTGAGES 155 575 14,301 FORECLOSURE NOTICES 36 126 4,454 BUILDING PERMITS 196 741 23,817 BANKRUPTCIES 100 322 9,883 BUSINESS LICENSES 27 117 3,193 UTILITY CONNECTIONS 63 433 13,990 MARRIAGE LICENSES 17 75 3,225 
 
Through the Lens
 
Weekly Edition

 Issues | About 

The Memphis News: Business, politics, and the public interest.
 
Most Read Articles

 Herenton Home Listed as Short Sale by Sarah Baker on Jul 11 Poplar Transformation by Sarah Baker on Jul 9 Library Cards at Root of Voter ID Challenge by Bill Dries on Jul 10 @ 1:57P Another Round by Sarah Baker on Jul 9 Retail Transformation by Sarah Baker on Jul 12 
 
Account Info

 Log In Your Account Create an Account 

Subscribe

 Subscribe to The Daily
 News Upgrade Your Subscription 
 
About

 About Us Contact Us Privacy Policy 

Help

 Help Customer Service 
 
MemphisDailyNews.com

 Home Page Mobile Site Blog Facebook Twitter RSS
 Feed 
 
Our Services

 Public Notices Public Records Name&amp;Property Research Data Direct Watch Service Custom List Builder Crime Reports Neighborhood Reports 
 
Copyright 1995 -
 2012
 by The Daily News Publishing Co. Inc. - All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
