<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008437" url="http://whatithoughtofit.com/cristys-rotisserie-chicken-32-ave-ne-calgary/" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="9" score="0.02680771017394824" bingtitle="What I Thought of It » Review of » Cristy’s Rotisserie Chicken ..." webtitle="What I Thought of ItReview ofCristys Rotisserie Chicken, 32nd Avenue NE">
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000099" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000850" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>... out what we thought of it, then tell ... Ordering is easy. You read the big menu board above the counter, and the staff ... In my books, it’s like a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Rating System 
 Search: 
 What I Thought of It 
 Thought-full reviews of things and places 
Thought-full reviews of things and places

You&apos;ve come to the right place if you&apos;re looking for a second (or first) opinion about something. Just do a search or browse our categories. Find out what we thought of it, then tell us what you thought of it!
 
Category:

 Accommodations 
 Campgrounds Hotels / Motels 
 Eating Out 
 Bars / Pubs Coffee / Tea / Drinks Fast Food Restaurants Sweet Treats Wings 
 Food Products Products 
 Household shoes 
 Recreation 
 Attractions Movies / TV Outdoors Theater Walks / Hikes 
 Retail 
 Bookstores Department Stores Drugstores Online Shopping Secondhand Services Specialty Stores Sports / Outdoors 
 Uncategorized 
 
Archives:

 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 
 
Blogroll:

 Development Blog Documentation Plugins Suggest Ideas Support Forum Themes WordPress Planet 
 
Meta:

 RSS Comments RSS Valid XHTML XFN 
 
Extra:

 
 

 
 Cristy’s Rotisserie Chicken, 32nd Avenue NE 
 Eating Out , Fast Food 
 Cristy’s Rotisserie Chicken 
2775 32 Ave NE
Calgary AB
Phone: 403 250 2828
www.cristyschicken.com

 Critsy’s Rotisserie Chicken is a small Calgary chain with 3 locations in food courts all over the city and one sit-down place on 32nd Avenue NE. I went to the one on 32nd Avenue NE because I expected more of a sit-down restaurant.

Finding this location of Cristy’s is not difficult - it has big signs and is situated right between Boston Pizza and Arby’s. In front of the building are plenty of parking spots.

Inside, there’s an aisle in front of the ordering counter and seating on both sides of the aisle. The decor feels a bit granny-ish but is nice enough for a sit-down meal. The tables have tablecloths and are additionally covered with plastic to keep them clean.

Ordering is easy. You read the big menu board above the counter, and the staff is helpful, though a bit impatient. After you order the food is prepared and delivered to your table. In my books, it’s like a fast-food restaurant, which I guess is why you find all the other Cristy’s Chicken locations in mall food courts.

The food is good, but don’t expect restaurant food. It is fast food, done a bit more“homestyle”with cooked vegetables and home-cooked chicken. The chicken was no better than what you could pick up at the supermarket hot deli.

 Last thoughts: Cristy’s Rotisserie Chicken is an okay place to go for a fast meal or takeout. To me it’s not that special. If I’m craving chicken on-the-go I would choose Chicken on the Way (a Calgary institution) hands-down. Cristy’s is not a place I would go back to again and again.

 Food ++++ 
 Service +++
 Ambiance +++
 Washrooms +++ 
 
Posted by James on May 10, 2009

Tags: chicken , Cristy&apos;s Rotisserie Chicken , rotisserie 
 
 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name 

 Mail (will not be published) 

 Website 

 

 Please note: Comment moderation is enabled and may delay your comment. There is no need to resubmit your comment. 

 
 ©2012 What I Thought of It. All Rights Reserved. Entries RSS Comments RSS Login
	</body>
</document>
