<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008214" url="http://www.buycheapr.com/us/result.jsp?ga=us2&amp;q=citizen+citizen" time="2012-07-13-01:42" support="5" score="0.003030863199523962" bingtitle="citizen citizen" webtitle="citizen citizen - BuyCheapr.com">
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>CMP-30 MOBILE RECEIPT PRINTER - 3IN USB SER ... is high speed device for bank card, POS, fast food, restaurant ... is $8.00 for USPS Mail with delivery confirmation and ...</description>
	<body>
		SHOP RESEARCH HOME | LOGIN | ROWS 
 COMPUTER 
 Monitors Laptops Ultraportables Printers Tablet PCs Multimedia Software 
 ELECTRONICS 
 Flat Panel TVs Digital Cameras Camcorder MP3 Player GPS Devices Mobile Phones PDAs and Electronic Organizers DVD Recorder 
 SPORTS&amp;OUTDOOR 
 Bikes Treadmills Soccer Golf 
 CLOTHING 
 Women Men Shoes Luggage Sunglasses 
 KIDS 
 Toys Baby Care Car Seats Baby Carriers Cots, Cribs and Bassinets Buggies and Strollers 
 GARDEN 
 Garden Tools Pools Greenhouses 
 OFFICE 
 Fax Machines Photocopiers Office Supplies Shredders Voice Recorders and Transcribers 
 MORE... 
 
 
Results for&quot;citizen citizen&quot;
 
Filter by:

 Free Shipping 
 
 Citizen Eco Drive BJ2117 01E Wrist Watch for Men $ 419.95 - $ 521.25 COMPARE PRICES 4 Offers help Wrist Watch, Analog, Quartz, Style: Prestige, Round Face, Men&apos;s Watch heart Citizen EW073259D Watch for Men $ 165.00 - $ 225.00 COMPARE PRICES 4 Offers help Wrist Watch, Analog, Solar/Light, Style: Sport / Outdoor, Round Face, Men&apos;s Watch heart Citizen EW1264 50A Watch $ 168.75 - $ 225.00 COMPARE PRICES 5 Offers help Analog, Quartz, Style: Dress, Round Face, Women&apos;s Watch heart 
 
 Citizen Men s 200 meters 660 BJ2117 01E Eco Drive $ 419.95 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Leisure Pro help For active men and water sports enthusiasts, the Citizen Men&apos;s Eco Drive Rubber Strap 200M Watch is a high-quality timepiece with a stainless steel case and unidirectional, stainless steel bezel. The bold black dial has full chronograph function and a tachymeter with striking, sky-blue accents. Ideal for divers and outdoor adventures, the ISO-certified Citizen Men&apos;s Eco Drive Rubber Strap Watch features a metric depth display to 50 meters (164&apos;) and is water resistant to 200 meters (660&apos;). The durable rubber watch band has a stainless steel buckle and the mineral crystal window is scratch resistant for rugged wear. Powered by Japanese quartz movement and fueled by natural and artificial light, the Citizen Men&apos;s Eco Drive Rubber Strap 200M Watch functions without a battery, and features a 60-day power reserve when fully charged. Watch has a 50 mm (1.96&quot;) case with a date window. Citizen Eco-Drive is fueled by light, it never needs a battery. Eco-Drive it&apos;s unstoppable. Eco-drive technology harnesses the power heart Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth Meter Chr $ 521.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery ISO Certified Power Reserve Indicator Metric Water-resistant to 660 feet (200 M) heart Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth Meter Chr $ 521.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery ISO Certified Power Reserve Indicator Metric Water-resistant to 660 feet (200 M) heart Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth Meter Chr $ 521.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery ISO Certified Power Reserve Indicator Metric Water-resistant to 660 feet (200 M) heart Citizen Calibre 8700 Eco Drive Perpetual Calendar $ 249.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Jomashop.com help Stainless steel case with a stainless steel bracelet. Fixed stainless steel bezel. Blue dial with luminous hands and Roman numeral hour markers. Month and minute markers around the outer rim. Date appears at the 4 o&apos;clock position. Month scale appears around the outer rim. Three - 24 hours, day of the week and function. Eco-drive movement. Scratch resistant mineral crystal. Screw down case back. Case diameter: 38 mm. Case thickness: 10 mm. Push button deployment clasp. Water resistant at 100 meters / 330 feet. Functions: hours, minutes, seconds, perpetual calendar, chronograph, alarm. Citizen Calibre 8700 Eco-Drive Perpetual Calendar Mens Watch BL8000-54L. heart Citizen Eco Drive Chronograph Mens Watch AT0550 11X $ 165.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Jomashop.com help Stainless steel case with a brown leather bracelet. Fixed bezel. Brown dial with luminous hands and index hour markers. Minute markers around the outer rim. Date display appears at the 4 o&apos;clock position. Chronograph - three sub-dials displaying: 24 hours, 60 minutes and 60 seconds. Eco-drive movement. Scratch resistant mineral crystal. Case diameter: 40 mm. Tang clasp. Water resistant at 100 meters / 330 feet. Functions: hours, minutes, seconds, calendar, chronograph. Citizen Eco-Drive Chronograph Mens Watch AT0550-11X. heart Citizen Men s AT0550 11X Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 221.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Featuring Eco-Drive technology that charges in natural or artificial light, this watch #AT0550-11X from Citizen never needs a battery. A one second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes, and offers 12/24 hour time. This accessory also features a polished stainless steel case and bezel off-set by a dark brown dial and leather strap for a look that&apos;s both luxe and casual. And water resistance to 333 feet (100 meters) means you can indulge in your favorite water activities without worry. heart Citizen Men s AT0550 11X Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 225.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Featuring Eco-Drive technology that charges in natural or artificial light, this watch #AT0550-11X from Citizen never needs a battery. A one second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes, and offers 12/24 hour time. This accessory also features a polished stainless steel case and bezel off-set by a dark brown dial and leather strap for a look that&apos;s both luxe and casual. And water resistance to 333 feet (100 meters) means you can indulge in your favorite water activities without worry. heart Citizen Men s AT0550 11X Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 225.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Featuring Eco-Drive technology that charges in natural or artificial light, this watch #AT0550-11X from Citizen never needs a battery. A one second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes, and offers 12/24 hour time. This accessory also features a polished stainless steel case and bezel off-set by a dark brown dial and leather strap for a look that&apos;s both luxe and casual. And water resistance to 333 feet (100 meters) means you can indulge in your favorite water activities without worry. heart Citizen Women s EW1264 50A Eco Drive Silhouette Tw $ 168.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help The warmth of gold tones liven up this stainless steel Silhouette Watch #EW1264-50A from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drive. With its classic, uncluttered design, this elegant timepiece is ideal for work or dress wear. It features a circular gold-tone case, matching gold-tone hands and bar markers, and a convenient date display at three o&apos;clock. There&apos;s also a two-tone bracelet with intricate T-pattern weave for a distinctive look. Water resistant to 99 feet. heart Citizen Watch Women s Eco Drive Two Tone Stainless $ 225.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Macys.com help A simply perfect golden timepiece from Citizen, with built-in Eco-Drive solar power. heart Citizen Women s EW1264 50A Eco Drive Silhouette Tw $ 168.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help The warmth of gold tones liven up this stainless steel Silhouette Watch #EW1264-50A from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drive. With its classic, uncluttered design, this elegant timepiece is ideal for work or dress wear. It features a circular gold-tone case, matching gold-tone hands and bar markers, and a convenient date display at three o&apos;clock. There&apos;s also a two-tone bracelet with intricate T-pattern weave for a distinctive look. Water resistant to 99 feet. heart Citizen Ladies Silhouette Sport Two Tone White T $ 168.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help . . . . Steel Case and Bracelet with Gold Tone Accents . . White Textured Dial with Gold-Tone Hands and Markers . . Date Window at the 3 o&apos;clock position . . Citizen Eco-Drive Solar Power Technology so you never have to change a battery . . 180 Day Power Reserve when fully charge without additional exposure to light (72 Hours with average light to fully charge) . . Water Resistant to 30 Meters (100 Feet) . . Mineral Glass Crystal . . Bracelet features a Fold Over Clasp with Push Button Release . . 25mm Case Width (Approximately 1&quot;) . . heart Citizen Women s EW1264 50A Eco Drive Silhouette Tw $ 168.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help The warmth of gold tones liven up this stainless steel Silhouette Watch #EW1264-50A from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drive. With its classic, uncluttered design, this elegant timepiece is ideal for work or dress wear. It features a circular gold-tone case, matching gold-tone hands and bar markers, and a convenient date display at three o&apos;clock. There&apos;s also a two-tone bracelet with intricate T-pattern weave for a distinctive look. Water resistant to 99 feet. heart Citizen Men s AR3015 53E Eco Drive Stiletto Black $ 356.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Embolden any attire with the Citizen Men&apos;s Eco-Drive Stiletto Watch. Featuring Eco-Drive technology, this watch has been perfected to suit both the professional man and the outdoorsman. Solar powered, this watch never needs a battery and remains charged for months at a time, even in the dark. Plus, it has a sleek design. Perfect for accompanying you from weekday to weekend, this confident, all-black timepiece stands out with a silky black dial notched with hour markers for a stylish, minimalist effect. Continuing the theme, the stainless steel bezel is handsomely etched with simple hour markers. The dial&apos;s sharp hour-and-minute hands are polished and sleek, complementary the wide stainless steel band that features both matte and polished finishes. The bold linking band is built for long-last and offers quick one-hand fastening with a deployment clasp with push-button. Boasting scratch-resistant-sapphire dial-window protection and the reliability of Japanese-quartz movement, this modern man&apos;s timepiece is water resistant to 99 feet (30 M). heart Citizen Watch Men s Eco Drive Black Ion Plated Sta $ 475.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Macys.com help Hit the town in this sleek, pitch-black watch from Citizen. heart Citizen Men s AR3015 53E Eco Drive Stiletto Black $ 356.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Embolden any attire with the Citizen Men&apos;s Eco-Drive Stiletto Watch. Featuring Eco-Drive technology, this watch has been perfected to suit both the professional man and the outdoorsman. Solar powered, this watch never needs a battery and remains charged for months at a time, even in the dark. Plus, it has a sleek design. Perfect for accompanying you from weekday to weekend, this confident, all-black timepiece stands out with a silky black dial notched with hour markers for a stylish, minimalist effect. Continuing the theme, the stainless steel bezel is handsomely etched with simple hour markers. The dial&apos;s sharp hour-and-minute hands are polished and sleek, complementary the wide stainless steel band that features both matte and polished finishes. The bold linking band is built for long-last and offers quick one-hand fastening with a deployment clasp with push-button. Boasting scratch-resistant-sapphire dial-window protection and the reliability of Japanese-quartz movement, this modern man&apos;s timepiece is water resistant to 99 feet (30 M). heart Citizen Men s AR3015 53E Eco Drive Stiletto Black $ 337.50 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Embolden any attire with the Citizen Men&apos;s Eco-Drive Stiletto Watch. Featuring Eco-Drive technology, this watch has been perfected to suit both the professional man and the outdoorsman. Solar powered, this watch never needs a battery and remains charged for months at a time, even in the dark. Plus, it has a sleek design. Perfect for accompanying you from weekday to weekend, this confident, all-black timepiece stands out with a silky black dial notched with hour markers for a stylish, minimalist effect. Continuing the theme, the stainless steel bezel is handsomely etched with simple hour markers. The dial&apos;s sharp hour-and-minute hands are polished and sleek, complementary the wide stainless steel band that features both matte and polished finishes. The bold linking band is built for long-last and offers quick one-hand fastening with a deployment clasp with push-button. Boasting scratch-resistant-sapphire dial-window protection and the reliability of Japanese-quartz movement, this modern man&apos;s timepiece is water resistant to 99 feet (30 M). heart Citizen Calibre 8651 Moon Phase Ap1010 51a Eco dri $ 375.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help WELCOME ! Citizen Men&apos;s Watch Moon Phase AP1010-51A Calibre 8651 Eco-drive OVERSTOCK WATCH FROM MAJOR DEPARTMENT STORE IN NEW CONDITION IN CITIZEN BOX / WITH WARRANTY PAPERS AND INSTRUCTION MANUAL GUARANTEE 100%CITIZEN WATCH cm192 Product Features Calibre 8651 Collection. Solar Powered No Battery Required 180-Day Power Reserve When Fully Charged Charges in Sunlight or Indoors 100 Meter (330 Feet) Water Resistant Gender: Men&apos;s White Dial with silver tone hands and Roman Numeral hour markers. Moo heart Citizen BN0085 01E 300 Meter Men s Eco Drive Profe $ 243.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Leisure Pro help Citizen BN0085-01E 300-Meter Men&apos;s Eco-Drive Professional Diver Men&apos;s Strap Black Dial heart Citizen Black Dial Black Rubber Strap Mens Watch B $ 169.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Jomashop.com help Stainless steel case with a black rubber strap. Unidirectional bezel. Black dial with luminous hands and index hour markers. Minute markers around the outer rim. Dial Type: Analog. Date display appears at the 3 o&apos;clock position. Quartz movement. Scratch resistant mineral crystal. Solid case back. Case diameter: 47 mm. Round case shape. Tang clasp. Water resistant at 300 meters/ 1000 feet. Functions: hours, minutes, seconds, date. Casual watch style. Citizen Black Dial Black Rubber Strap Mens Watch BN0085-01E. heart Citizen Eco Drive Promaster Diver Men s Strap Bn00 $ 245.00 S&amp;H: $ 15.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Brand New Citizen Eco Drive Promaster Diver Men&apos;s Strap BN0085-01E BRAND: CITIZEN SERIES: ECO DRIVE (POWERED BY LIGHT&amp;NEVER NEEDS BATTERY REPLACEMENT) MODEL NUMBER: BN0085-01E UNIVERSAL PRODUCT CODE (UPC): 13205091995 MOVEMENT: QUARTZ DIAL: BLACK DIAL CASE MATERIAL: STAINLESS STEEL WITH BLACK-ION PLATING - 47 MM DIAMETER, 19MM THICKNESS STRAP / BRACELET: BLACK RUBBER CRYSTAL: NON-REFLECTIVE CRYSTAL heart Citizen Men s BN0085 01E Professional Eco Drive Wa $ 243.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Men&apos;s Eco Drive Dive watch, ISO certified with unidirectional rotating bezel and black plated accents. heart Citizen Men s BN0085 01E Professional Eco Drive Wa $ 243.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Men&apos;s Eco Drive Dive watch, ISO certified with unidirectional rotating bezel and black plated accents. heart Citizen Men s BN0085 01E Professional Eco Drive Wa $ 243.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Men&apos;s Eco Drive Dive watch, ISO certified with unidirectional rotating bezel and black plated accents. heart Citizen Women s EG2750 50D Silhouette Eco Drive Wa $ 177.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Women s EG2750 50D Silhouette Eco Drive Wa $ 177.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Dress watch, Eco-Drive solar-powered technology, Japanese quartz movement for secondary battery, Overcharging prevention feature, Polished silver-tone sword hands, Slim applied polished silver-tone baton markers at quarter-hour positions, Silver mother-of-pearl dial with polished silver-tone logo applique below twelve o&apos;clock, Slim polished silver-tone stainless steel bracelet with adjustable links and jewelry-clasp, Polished silver-tone stainless steel octagonal case, Polished steel crown, Stainless steel caseback, Mineral crystal, Water resistant heart Citizen Women s EG2750 50D Silhouette Eco Drive Wa $ 177.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Dress watch, Eco-Drive solar-powered technology, Japanese quartz movement for secondary battery, Overcharging prevention feature, Polished silver-tone sword hands, Slim applied polished silver-tone baton markers at quarter-hour positions, Silver mother-of-pearl dial with polished silver-tone logo applique below twelve o&apos;clock, Slim polished silver-tone stainless steel bracelet with adjustable links and jewelry-clasp, Polished silver-tone stainless steel octagonal case, Polished steel crown, Stainless steel caseback, Mineral crystal, Water resistant heart Citizen Men s AT4007 54E Perpetual Chrono A T Watch $ 449.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s AT4007 54E Perpetual Chrono A T Watch $ 449.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s AT4007 54E Perpetual Chrono A T Watch $ 449.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s JY0050 55L Eco Drive Blue Angels Sky $ 671.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help and chock full of innovative features, the Men&apos;s Blue Angels Skyhawk A-T Chronograph Titanium Watch from Citizen Eco-Drive combines aviator-inspired style with a sleek, sporty design. Offering a maximum power reserve of 180 days, with a low charge warning within three days of stop point, this distinctive timepiece is both reliable and up for the next adventure. It also features a durable, hardened mineral crystal, original Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on a bold black dial. With a multi-band atomic receiver that accepts signals in North America, Europe, and Asia, this efficient accessory provides both world time in 43 cities, and a perpetual calendar, making it ideal for traveling. There&apos;s also a digital display light, two alarms, 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, and a 99 minute countdown timer. Rugged, handsome, and built to last, this Citizen Eco-Drive original arrives in a gray box, along with a manual, information CD.Summary of Features: Atomic timekeeping with radio-controlled accuracy World time in 43 cities 2 alarms 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours 99 minute countdown timer Digital display light Greenwich Mean Time display Rotating slide-rule bezel Non-reflective mineral crystal Power-reserve indicator heart Citizen Jy0050 55l Titanium Blue Angels Skyhawk Me $ 448.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Here comes yet another chronograph from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drives Skyhawk Flight watch series for men - Citizen JY0050-55L! This extremely light powered Citizen men&apos;s watch comes in a titanium case with a sporting Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on the black dial. The atomic timekeeping of this Citizen Blue Angels gives precise time, thanks to its radio-controlled accuracy. This Citizen men&apos;s watch has digital display of the world time of around 43 different cities. The Citizen JY0050-55L also features 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, a 99 minute countdown timer, Greenwich Mean Time digital display. Moreover, this Citizen Blue Angels is engineered exclusively to sustain any extreme condition and last really longer! heart Citizen Men s JY0050 55L Eco Drive Blue Angels Sky $ 671.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help and chock full of innovative features, the Men&apos;s Blue Angels Skyhawk A-T Chronograph Titanium Watch from Citizen Eco-Drive combines aviator-inspired style with a sleek, sporty design. Offering a maximum power reserve of 180 days, with a low charge warning within three days of stop point, this distinctive timepiece is both reliable and up for the next adventure. It also features a durable, hardened mineral crystal, original Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on a bold black dial. With a multi-band atomic receiver that accepts signals in North America, Europe, and Asia, this efficient accessory provides both world time in 43 cities, and a perpetual calendar, making it ideal for traveling. There&apos;s also a digital display light, two alarms, 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, and a 99 minute countdown timer. Rugged, handsome, and built to last, this Citizen Eco-Drive original arrives in a gray box, along with a manual, information CD.Summary of Features: Atomic timekeeping with radio-controlled accuracy World time in 43 cities 2 alarms 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours 99 minute countdown timer Digital display light Greenwich Mean Time display Rotating slide-rule bezel Non-reflective mineral crystal Power-reserve indicator heart Citizen Radio control Skyhawk Titanium Blue Angels $ 716.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Here comes yet another chronograph from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drives Skyhawk Flight watch series for men - Citizen JY0050-55L! This extremely light powered Citizen men&apos;s watch comes in a titanium case with a sporting Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on the black dial. The atomic timekeeping of this Citizen Blue Angels gives precise time, thanks to its radio-controlled accuracy. This Citizen men&apos;s watch has digital display of the world time of around 43 different cities. The Citizen JY0050-55L also features 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, a 99 minute countdown timer, Greenwich Mean Time digital display. Moreover, this Citizen Blue Angels is engineered exclusively to sustain any extreme condition and last really longer! heart Citizen Jy0050 55l Titanium At Blue Angels Atomic $ 499.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Here comes yet another chronograph from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drives Skyhawk Flight watch series for men - Citizen JY0050-55L! This extremely light powered Citizen men&apos;s watch comes in a titanium case with a sporting Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on the black dial. The atomic timekeeping of this Citizen Blue Angels gives precise time, thanks to its radio-controlled accuracy. This Citizen men&apos;s watch has digital display of the world time of around 43 different cities. The Citizen JY0050-55L also features 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, a 99 minute countdown timer, Greenwich Mean Time digital display. Moreover, this Citizen Blue Angels is engineered exclusively to sustain any extreme condition and last really longer! heart Citizen Men s JY0050 55L Eco Drive Blue Angels Sky $ 671.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help and chock full of innovative features, the Men&apos;s Blue Angels Skyhawk A-T Chronograph Titanium Watch from Citizen Eco-Drive combines aviator-inspired style with a sleek, sporty design. Offering a maximum power reserve of 180 days, with a low charge warning within three days of stop point, this distinctive timepiece is both reliable and up for the next adventure. It also features a durable, hardened mineral crystal, original Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on a bold black dial. With a multi-band atomic receiver that accepts signals in North America, Europe, and Asia, this efficient accessory provides both world time in 43 cities, and a perpetual calendar, making it ideal for traveling. There&apos;s also a digital display light, two alarms, 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, and a 99 minute countdown timer. Rugged, handsome, and built to last, this Citizen Eco-Drive original arrives in a gray box, along with a manual, information CD.Summary of Features: Atomic timekeeping with radio-controlled accuracy World time in 43 cities 2 alarms 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours 99 minute countdown timer Digital display light Greenwich Mean Time display Rotating slide-rule bezel Non-reflective mineral crystal Power-reserve indicator heart Citizen Titanium Atomic Blue Angels Eco Drive Alar $ 619.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Here comes yet another chronograph from Citizen&apos;s Eco-Drives Skyhawk Flight watch series for men - Citizen JY0050-55L! This extremely light powered Citizen men&apos;s watch comes in a titanium case with a sporting Blue Angels insignia on its case back, and Blue Angels logo on the black dial. The atomic timekeeping of this Citizen Blue Angels gives precise time, thanks to its radio-controlled accuracy. This Citizen men&apos;s watch has digital display of the world time of around 43 different cities. The Citizen JY0050-55L also features 1/100 second chronograph that measures up to 24 hours, a 99 minute countdown timer, Greenwich Mean Time digital display. Moreover, this Citizen Blue Angels is engineered exclusively to sustain any extreme condition and last really longer! heart Citizen Men s CB0020 09E World Perpetual A T Watch $ 356.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s CB0020 09E World Perpetual A T Watch $ 356.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s CB0020 09E World Perpetual A T Watch $ 356.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Embrace the effortless style that comes with a Citizen Eco-Drive watch. Imaging never having to worry about winding a watch or making sure it has a functional battery. The perfect everyday timepiece that rarely requires your attention, wearing an Eco-Drive allows you to turn your attention to the more important things in life. heart Citizen Men s AT0880 50E Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 224.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Endless.com help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery One second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes 12/24 hour Time All stainless steel with screw-back case Water-resistant to 330 feet (100 M) heart Citizen Men s AT0880 50E Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 236.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery One second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes 12/24 hour Time All stainless steel with screw-back case Water-resistant to 330 feet (100 M) heart Citizen Men s AT0880 50E Eco Drive Chronograph Sta $ 236.25 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Eco Drive technology is fueled by light and it never needs a battery One second chronograph measures up to 60 minutes 12/24 hour Time All stainless steel with screw-back case Water-resistant to 330 feet (100 M) heart Citizen Eco Drive Perpetual Calendar Alarm Chronog $ 393.75 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at WristWatch.com help Jewelry&amp;Watches from Citizen Watch. heart Citizen Eco Drive Perpetual Calendar Alarm Chronog $ 282.58 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at JacobTime.com help Jewelry&amp;Watches from Citizen Watch. heart Citizen Eco Drive Titanium Chronograph Mens Watch $ 371.25 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at WristWatch.com help Jewelry&amp;Watches from Citizen Watch. heart ARMED CITIZEN PROPERTY OWNER WINDOW DECAL STICKER $ 3.69 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at lotz-o-goodies - eBay help Security Signs&amp;Decals heart LOT of 4 AS IS Repair Watch Citizen EW9134 51A Bul $ 79.00 S&amp;H: $ 5.35 GO TO SHOP at shopheroic - eBay help Wristwatches heart Womens Citizens of Humanity Jeans Size 26 No Reser $ 1.25 S&amp;H: $ 5.00 GO TO SHOP at jasonsentry - eBay help Jeans heart MaxineThe Senior Citizen cotton Body pillowcase or $ 18.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at knittingmaven60 - eBay help Bed Pillows heart CITIZENS OF HUMANITY Coin Pocket Jeans LINDA 068 S $ 9.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at springfield70 - eBay help Jeans heart Citizen watch band black BJ2110 BJ2115 BJ2117 BJ21 $ 39.95 S&amp;H: $ 2.50 GO TO SHOP at alol - eBay help Wristwatch Bands heart Citizens of Humanity Kelly 063 Womens Sz 24 Stretc $ 14.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at treasures*by*terra - eBay help Jeans heart RUGER Arms Makers for Responsible Citizens Metal S $ 22.22 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at shiralys - eBay help Reproduction heart The Master Spirits of the World American Citizen s $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 3.75 GO TO SHOP at siayan - eBay help Antiquarian&amp;Collectible heart Citizen Men Watch ECO DRIVE PROMASTER BJ7010 16F $ 120.00 S&amp;H: $ 10.00 GO TO SHOP at mn244lkb - eBay help Wristwatches heart New Citizen AT4027 06E Limited Edition Atomic Perp $ 499.95 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at integrity808 - eBay help Wristwatches heart Citizen Aqualand CO23 1st Generation Dive Watch $ 100.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at americangoldsilvere.. - eBay help MOST RELIABLE DIVE WATCH EVER! heart 4 Tix Philadelphia Phillies vs San Francisco Giant $ 150.00 S&amp;H: $ 10.00 GO TO SHOP at joeabernathy - eBay help Sports heart Excellent CBM 1000 CITIZEN Thermal Receipt POS Pri $ 49.99 S&amp;H: $ 12.99 GO TO SHOP at commanderscott - eBay help Other heart Assortment Of Watches 11 GUCCI CITIZEN PULSAR GENE $ 22.49 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at ccc1682 - eBay help Wristwatches heart Law Abiding Citizen 2010 Used Digital Video Disc $ 1.99 S&amp;H: $ 2.98 GO TO SHOP at gohastings - eBay help DVD, HD DVD&amp;Blu-ray heart Citizen Eco Drive JR3090 58L Skyhawk Blue Angels W $ 154.99 S&amp;H: $ 10.85 GO TO SHOP at shopatyk - eBay help Wristwatches heart Citizen Eco Drive Titanium Orca Divers 200m Mint $ 212.50 S&amp;H: $ 6.00 GO TO SHOP at baddness - eBay help Wristwatches heart Pro 2nd Gun Rights Armed Citizen Black AR15 T Shirt $ 8.65 S&amp;H: $ 1.10 GO TO SHOP at armedcitizenapparelco - eBay help T-Shirts heart WOW Rare VINTAGE CITIZEN ANA DIGI TEMP LCD ANALOG $ 51.00 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at sfvintage01 - eBay help Wristwatches heart 
 Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 NEXT 
 Bookmark Page facebook twitter 
 
Sort List By:
 Filter by Price Up to $4 $3 - $7 $6 - $9 $8 - $14 $13 - $27 $26 or more Filter by Merchant Amazon Marketplace (11) Amazon (10) Endless.com (10) eBay (6) Jomashop.com (3) Leisure Pro (2) Brand Citizen Alligator Lederwaren Age and Gender Men Women Unisex Kids Color Beige Black Blue Brown Gold 
My Favorites

Add your favorites by clicking
on the heart!


 
Offers for citizen citizen

 Citizen Men s 200 meters 660 BJ2117 01E... 
 $ 419.95 Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth... 
 $ 521.25 Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth... 
 $ 521.25 Citizen Men s BJ2117 01E Eco Drive Depth... 
 $ 521.25 Citizen Calibre 8700 Eco Drive Perpetual... 
 $ 249.00 
 
Frequently searched
 blu ray movies cr2025 ebook fossil grateful dead madonna mens watches military pocket watch proactive twilight watch watch winder watchmen 
Write a review on citizen citizen 

Your opinion is important to us!
Let us know what you think by
writing a review about this
product.
 WRITE A REVIEW 
 
©2009-2012 BuyCheapr.com 
 ABOUT US About BuyCheapr.com Terms of Use Privacy Policy Contact / Imprint Sitemap PRODUCTS 
 Computers Consumer Electronics Sports&amp;Outdoor Clothing 
 
 Kids Garden Office More... 
 REVIEWS Write a Review User Reviews Expert Reviews close 
 

How likely are you to recommend BuyCheapr.com?

Likelihood to recommend BuyCheapr.com
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Not likely at all Very Likely 
Did BuyCheapr.com meet your shopping needs?
 Yes       No 
Please tell us the reason for your score above.
	</body>
</document>
