<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008077" url="http://www.studentwebstuff.com/mis/showthread.php?t=7831" time="2012-07-13-01:08" support="2" score="0.0020531837852620365" bingtitle="Research Post: Technology Important to McDonald&apos;s ..." webtitle="Research Post: Technology Important to McDonald&apos;s - Studentwebstuff Forums">
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>... being used, the fee is charged to the credit card ... system provides a fast way to check orders for missing items ... The fast-food restaurant has decided to outsource this ...</description>
	<body>
		Studentwebstuff Forums &gt; Classes &gt; MIS -- Discussions Research Post: Technology Important to McDonald&apos;s 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Home Forums Documents Demos Contact FAQ Members List Today&apos;s Posts Search User CP 
 

 MIS -- Discussions A forum for discussing special topics related to MIS. Participation in this forum is a requirement for MIS online and MIS traditional (as well as iTV) courses. Ask questions specific to your course in your course area (see Documents for a link to all forums for your particular class). Podcasting and RSS available (podcast: http://www.studentwebstuff.com/mis/external.php?type=RSS2&amp;forumsids=11). 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Tag Search Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
   

   Thread Tools Search this Thread Display Modes 
 
  # 1   07-13-09, 08:05 PM 
 jlahman Alumni   Posts: n/a 
 Research Post: Technology Important to McDonald&apos;s Introduction

As it has been claimed over and over again, technology is extremely important to the success of every business in every industry. Technology assists businesses in improving the efficiency of their operations in order to achieve improved production. McDonald&apos;s is no different. As the economic downturn continues, McDonald&apos;s has become a dominant choice for eating out among families.

Importance of Technology

&quot;McDonald&apos;s Corporation has helped revolutionize the way restaurants use technology, (1)&quot; and the company continues to search for ways to advance their technology. In the 1950&apos;s, the fast-food chain was the first to introduce the assembly line in the restaurant industry. The company realized consumers wanted food served quickly and economically in a consistent manner. In the 1970&apos;s, the burger chain lead the &quot;industry&apos;s transition from old-fashioned cash registers to computerized point-of-sale systems that could track massive amounts of data in seconds (1).&quot; Then again in the 1990&apos;s, it was the first fast-food chain to institute touch-screen computers at the counter and in the drive-thru for easier ordering (1). This paper describes a few, more recent activities/ideas McDonald&apos;s has employed in helping it remain one of the largest fast-food chains in the world.

There&apos;s no question that the exploration of new technology is of high significance to the leaders of McDonald&apos;s. Evidence of innovation can be seen through tests the company has ran involving touch-screen self-ordering kiosks for customers, customer order centers, and mobile POS devices (1). Quote: 
 &quot;For use, [in-store] it&apos;s all about providing our customers with a great experience and technology is key. Technology has great potential to improve our business-to render ourselves more efficient, simplify operations for our crew and offer the freshest possible food within a relevant customer experience,&quot; says Dave Weick, McDonald&apos;s senior vice president and chief information officer (1). &quot;It goes without saying that there will always be room for technology in our organization; it is a linchpin for being the best we can be,&quot; Weick concludes. 
 Faster Checkout

For McDonald&apos;s, not only every minute, but every second counts when serving a customer. Customers are drawn to the eatery for fast, low cost food. The food choices are consistent at each location and combined with the easy to retrieve packaging makes the drive-thru a staple in the lives of busy workers and on-the-go families. The company first introduced electronic card payment options in 2002. It has now introduced a method to pay for orders at a rate that beats cash-based transactions. The Denver-based payment solutions provider that has helped McDonald&apos;s make this a reality is First Data, which supports the processing of credit and debit card transactions in 14,000 McDonald&apos;s restaurants nationwide (2).

After ordering-if paying with plastic-- the customer swipes their card through a dedicated terminal. User authorization is electronically requested through a secure network linked to First Data. The transaction is then approved or declined by the solution provider. Depending on the type of card being used, the fee is charged to the credit card or deducted from a bank card after approval of the card is made. A signature is not required for purchased meals under $25.00 speeding the routine even more. This whole process only takes a swift two to four seconds which is much faster than having customers fumble for dollars and cents (2).

McDonald&apos;s has expressed its appreciation of the enhancement by awarding First Data with its second annual U.S. Technology Supplier of the Year Award. The award represents a company that makes the most significant impact on and contribution to, McDonald&apos;s USA. &quot;The fast-food chain bases its decision on criteria including solutions that impact its system, and that deliver innovation and quality, and customer satisfaction and value (2).&quot; McDonald&apos;s Arch card gift-card is also supported through the First Data system (2).

AUTOBag

Another feature that has added &quot;fast&quot; to McDonald&apos;s already fast-food is the AUTOBag. Small gains in order accuracy have been realized with new technology such as digital wireless headsets, customer order displays, and timer systems. The AUTOBag helps to improve the delivery of order accuracy-after the order is taken (4).

The company was in search of a way to detect mistakes before the customer does. On average, 15% of orders are incomplete, which can be costly in terms of products and customer satisfaction. This system provides a fast way to check orders for missing items by computer. By expanding on the idea of McDonald&apos;s incredible weight consistency, weighing the order bags reveals missing items. However, since all items vary, simply adding items was not accurate enough (4).

AUTOBag&apos;s accuracy is built on a patented key dynamic algorithm. &quot;The concept is simple. Program a computer with the products and their weights, transmit the POS order information to the computer, calculate the expected order weight, weigh the order and display the results, fast (4).&quot; The AUTOBag system has many benefits including near elimination of customer complaints and up to five second faster drive-thru times. This tool has been in use at 300 McDonald&apos;s drive-thrus for six years (4).

&quot;Havin&apos; Fun&quot;

The stage between visiting as kids and taking your kids seems to be neglected in the fast-food world. Tweens seem too big for kid&apos;s meals but not big enough for the price of adult meals. However, the dollar menu mixes well with the lifestyle of a tween. In addition, McDonald&apos;s has introduced a section of it&apos;s website to McDTween, a place where tweens can go for &quot;Havin&apos; Fun (2).&quot;Visitors can make their own advertisement, watch videos, and splash people with yogurt from parfaits. A contest, which ends August 31, 2009, is also being conducted through the website with prizes including a Wii, a Nintendo DS game, or a Line Rider 2 game (3).

McInternet

McDonald&apos;s/Brazil has attempted to decrease the country&apos;s digital divide by offering free internet access to its customers. According to our text, the digital divide refers to large disparities in access to computers and the Internet among different social groups and different locations. The first country in South America to have one, Brazil, currently has a well-established presence with 600 locations.

The McInternet mission, lead by the head of IT at McDonald&apos;s/Brazil, is merely a collection of computer kiosks connected to the Internet inside the restaurant. The project&apos;s key motivation was the increase in traffic and the connection of the McDonald&apos;s brand with the younger generation and technology. Only 10% of the total Brazilian population can be considered digitally included, so this would give a chance to many customers to access the Internet for the first time.

Following the project evaluation, many benefits were revealed. According to the most recent data available, &quot;by early 2007, the McInternet project had approximately 5.7 million users logging in 600,000 monthly sessions making it the largest private Internet access network in Brazil (5). There were no incentives from the government establishing a completely private ownership of the project. A relatively small (2.5%) but significant increase in sales, promotional partnerships, an array of information about its clients, and a way to interconnect all of its restaurants were all positive outcomes of the venture.

Viva McDonald&apos;s

Lastly, one of the latest editions for the McDonald&apos;s restaurant is the new Viva McDonald&apos;s on the Las Vegas Strip. Adjacent to the Circus Circus hotel and casino, the &quot;showcase&quot; features &quot;high-tech Vegas-style touches for consumers and an updated point-of-sale system and advances cooking equipment for employees (6).&quot; The 184-seat restaurant offers wireless Internet access as well as various display screens for media access. Among the traditional features of the restaurant is a &quot;McDonald&apos;s Connect,&quot; a bilingual digital education and training system station. Training content can be downloaded instead of distributing CDs and may be the &quot;wave of the future&quot; says Brian Unger, senior vice president of McDonald&apos;s Western division. He declined to comment on development costs but declares the restaurant, &quot;was doing extremely well [in sales] out of the gate (6).&quot;

Conclusion

In conclusion, I believe each one of these expansion projects would not have been successful without the use of information systems and technology. In an industry as competitive as fast-food, every little bit of market share is important. McDonald&apos;s is always looking for more efficient ways of doing things not only to keep its current customers but to also attract new faces.

Questions:

1.) Considering the age of many McDonald&apos;s employees, I believe the technology would be fairly easy to use. Not having worked at McDonald&apos;s myself, could anyone relate or offer information on the ease of use?

2.) I thought the mentioning of the self-ordering kiosks would be neat. Do you think these would be a positive addition? Why or why not?

3.) Do you like to eat at McDonald&apos;s? Why or why not?

Resources:

1)- &quot;Innovation is on the menu: technology moves McDonald&apos;s forward.&quot; Nation&apos;s Restaurant News 11 Apr. 2005: 118-21. Business Source Premier. Missouri State University. 11 July 2009&lt; http://search.ebscohost.com.proxy.mi...ite=ehost-live &gt;.
2)- Murphy, Samantha. &quot;Happier Meals.&quot; Chain Store Age May 2009: 90. Business Source Premier. Missouri State University. 11 July 2009&lt; http://web.ebscohost.com.proxy.misso...0sessionmgr104 &gt;.
3)- Watson, Caren. &quot;McDonald&apos;s website geared for tweens with Wii contest.&quot; Jul. 9, 2009. http://www.examiner.com/x-6675-Balti...th-Wii-contest 
4)- Introduction to AUTObag. www.autobag.com 
5)- Sacchi, Alexandre, Emerson Giannini, Regiane Bochic, Nicolau Reinhard et al.. &quot;Digital Inclusion with the McInternet: Would You Like Fries with That?&quot; Communications of the ACM 52.3 (2009): 113-16. Business Source Premier. Missouri State University. 11 July 2009&lt; http://web.ebscohost.com.proxy.misso...0sessionmgr104 &gt;.
6)- Liddle, Alan. McD raises stakes on Las Vegas Strip with Viva McDonald&apos;s debut. Nation&apos;s Restaurant News, Jan. 5, 2009. Accessed through Business Source Premier. 
 
 jlahman 
 
  # 2   07-14-09, 07:16 AM 
 JDonelson Alumni   Posts: n/a 
 Regular Post Response to: McDonald&apos;s 1.) Considering the age of many McDonald&apos;s employees, I believe the technology would be fairly easy to use. Not having worked at McDonald&apos;s myself, could anyone relate or offer information on the ease of use?

Haven&apos;t a clue. I only go to McDonald&apos;s on a rare occasion...

2.) I thought the mentioning of the self-ordering kiosks would be neat. Do you think these would be a positive addition? Why or why not?

I would have to visualize them to make an accurate assessment, but my local McDonald&apos;s is not that big, so I don&apos;t know where they would fit. Also, I can&apos;t imagine many elderly customers using the kiosks.

3.) Do you like to eat at McDonald&apos;s? Why or why not?

Not particularly! But when I do eat at McDonald&apos;s it is for convenience and economic reasons. I personally think the inside of my local McDonalds should be expanded because it is just not big enough. When you go in to order lunch (because the drive thru is so backed up) there lines from customers that are waiting to order or receive their foods backs into the dining area. This is rather unpleasant. The busy and often chaotic atmosphere of McDonald&apos;s interior is not a relaxing lunch atmosphere.

I came across this article today, which is relevant for McDonald&apos;s and its use of technology to improve upon its business. Basically a new McDonald&apos;s has opened and it offers a plug in station for electric cars. The new McDonald&apos;s building is certified LEED, a certification that honors energy and environmental intiatives.

 http://www.reuters.com/article/mnGre...68188020090706 

Also something that McDonald&apos;s has used in the past related to technology and its business is RedBox. RedBox started at McDonald&apos;s although they ended up selling RedBox to CoinStar, another Kiosk company. There are still thousands of RedBox kiosks outside of McDonald&apos;s to encourage more visits to the restaurant. McDonald&apos;s might be kicking themselves today because RedBox is making a killing and threatening NetFlix in addition to traditional video stores.

Also McDonald&apos;s corporate headquarters in Illinois has received the LEED certification. The company is certainly proving they are innovative in the technology area, which is a huge reason why they are so successful today. 
 
 JDonelson 
 
  # 3   07-20-09, 09:49 PM 
 MAlford Alumni   Posts: n/a 
 McDonalds&apos; outsources its drive thru McDonalds&apos; outsources its drive thru 

Agree completely that McDonalds is on top of everything, experimenting with and implementing new technologies just to keep the biggest share in the fast food market.

However, in the research post the author, J Lahman, has missed the most current implementation of McDonalds outsourced drive thru. My post will serve as addition to Faster Checkout part, which in my case is wisely to rename to Efficient Checkout. This means that check out serves the interests of both parties: customers and McDonalds itself!

Since 2005 there have been multiple rumors and conversation about McDonalds crazy idea of outsourcing drive through. But finally this idea came true and people really have started talking about it last year. Doing the research I have found out that originally Missouri and Illinois were the areas for experimenting new technological idea, and only in late 2007- beginning 2008 it has expanded to other territories across the U.S.

The long-distance call-takers send back the orders to the restaurant via the Internet. There the restaurant employees take the cash and hand over the food.

The fast-food restaurant has decided to outsource this part of ordering process in an effort to save money and time as well as reducing mistakes. Creating call centers will speed up the process of checking out as McDonalds employees will not waste time on taking the orders, but just preparing them.

 Quote: 
 &quot;By collecting all the order taking to a single call center one order taker can actually service up to five restaurants at a time. No more standing around between orders, no more idle employees on the clock.&quot; 
 There is no surprise that it has its own drawbacks, like mixed up orders, problems with connection and especially understanding the orders. For instance, like Hawaiian restaurants utilizing Texas remote order takers, who actually need special training due to accent problems. McDonalds management stays optimistic to get to the highest level of efficiency of new call centers they dont mind dealing with some disadvantages for awhile!


 References: 
1. McDonalds To Outsource Drive Through! (2009). Retrieved July 20, 2009, from http://www.unconfirmedsources.com/index.php?itemid=758 
2. McDonald&apos;s Using Out-Of-State Workers For Drive-Through (2008). Retrieved July 20, 2009, from http://www.kitv.com/money/16607424/detail.html Last edited by MAlford; 07-27-09 at 09:54 PM . 
 
 MAlford 
 
   


 Tags mcdonald&apos;s 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 Search this Thread 
 Advanced Search 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is Off HTML code is On 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Classes   MIS -- Discussions   All MIS«Online»Forums   All MIS«traditional»Forums   Contribution Announcements General Resources   Announcements for all classes   General Documents Other Interests   Technology in the News   Business in the News   Jobs Social Forums   Chit Chat   Favorite Websites   Show off your web   Polls Forum Concerns   Questions, Problems, Comments   Testing 1 2 3 
 


 Similar Threads Thread Thread Starter Forum Replies Last Post Research Post: Project Control - An Important Project Management activity PNalla MIS -- Discussions 0 07-27-08 11:50 PM Research Post: Is JIT still important? aButt MIS -- Discussions 0 07-29-07 04:14 PM Research Post: Mcdonald&apos;s new look...Would you like a Remodel with that? JPrice MIS -- Discussions 9 06-20-06 12:04 AM McDonald&apos;s and Nintendo in Wi-Fi Deal aHaefele MIS -- Discussions 11 10-31-05 06:03 PM McDonald&apos;s Serves Up Wireless Access jgorham MIS -- Discussions 26 07-14-04 01:09 PM 


 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 06:08 PM .
 
 
 Studentwebstuff Contact - Your Studentwebstuff Home - Archive - Top 

 Powered by vBulletin®Version 3.7.3
Copyright©2000 - 2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
