<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008543" url="http://yvettetan.com/2012/04/11/salt-and-pepper/" time="2012-07-13-02:00" support="4" score="0.006129943072161211" bingtitle="Salt and Pepper « Yvette U. Tan" webtitle="Salt and PepperYvette U. Tan">
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001257" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>... logo more akin to a fast food restaurant than the ... The restaurant is named after the two most common condiments at the dinner table. ... Enter your comment here...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Yvette U. Tan 
because horror is a state of mind
 
 Home About Published Reviews Media Buy Contact 
 
Salt and Pepper
 11/04/2012 tags: food , restaurants , salt and pepper 
I’m sure many of you have seen Salt and Pepper , if not in it’s old location in Makati, in its‘new’location beside the Play and Display showroom along EDSA. It’s presence is primarily announced by a huge red and black billboard that features a jauntily drawn salt and pepper shaker, a logo more akin to a fast food restaurant than the casual dining place that it really is.

I wouldn’t have discovered it either, if I hadn’t wen assigned to write about it for Appetite magazine , who graciously let me blog about it after publication, too.

Its interiors match the billboard’s red and black, but that is where the similarity ends. The inside of the restaurant has a romantic theme, its‘patio’looking like a window display.

The restaurant is named after the two most common condiments at the dinner table. Its menu items are a mix of different cuisines, specifically Italian, Indian, Mediterranean, and Middle Eastern, all of them prepared as authentically as possible, right down to the ingredients, many of which are imported from their respective countries.

The Sample Kebab Platter (Php490) is made up of two skewers of assorted meat and veg served with salsa and really, really good yogurt sauce. The meat (beef, beef tenderloin, chicken) is juicy, the vegetables (tomatoes, onions, zucchini) beautifully blackened. While tasty on its own, pairing the kebab with the yogurt sauce really brings out the flavor of the meat. I din’t know what they mix in that sauce, but whatever it is, it is quite addictive.

 

Likewise the Chicken Tandoori (Php295), which is basted in Indian spices. Alas, it is not cooked in an axial tandoor, but that doesn’t stop it from tasting good.

 

The restaurant also serves an interesting array of pizzas, the dough made fresh and baked in a pizza oven. The Frutti di Mare Pizza is topped with assorted seafood such as fish, squid, and mussels in the half shell, the seafood tender, it’s flavors standing apart from the cheese and tomato base.

 

The Chicken Pesto Pasta (Php 390) is interesting, the dough generously layered with a savory-sweet pesto and dotted with bits of chicken.

 

Salt and Pepper serves pasta as well, some of them quite elaborate. The Seafood Linguini in Bouillabaisse Sauce (Php 295) is rich, and is filling enough to share. The pasta is thinly coated with flavorful sauce, with big servings of seafood.

 

If it’s a rice dish you’re looking for, the Nuts About Fish (Php 270) is quite interesting. Soft fish covered with a dry, nutty crust. Eating it gives one the weird sensation of trying something familiar but adventurous at the same time.

 

Salt and Pepper is a good example of a book that should not be judged by its cover. It may look informal on the outside and slightly intimidating on the inside, but the important part is that the food, of which the restaurant offers a varied, hearty selection.

 Salt and Pepper 
205 EDSA cor.
Rochester Sts.
Greenhills
Mandaluyong City
Metro Manila
(+632) 725-7454
 
Share this:
 
 Email Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 from→ Eats ←Romulo Cafe Joe Jonas is the New Face of Bench→ No comments yet 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Yvette Tan

 horror author, third world minimalist, Esquire Philippines Writer at Large
 
 Twitter Updates 

 The Time 18th-Century French Aristocrats Fled to Rural Pennsylvania mentalfloss.com/blogs/archives… 1 hour ago I want waffles. 1 hour ago 
 
Flickr Photos

 
 

 More Photos 
 
 
Categories

 Anything Goes Art Eats Interviews Minimalism Movies and Music Music News PR Travel TV Writing 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 July 2011 June 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 
 RSS - Posts RSS - Comments 
 
 Follow Blog via Email 
 
Enter your email address to follow this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 2,129 other followers

 

 
 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .

Theme: Vigilance by The Theme Foundry .
 Follow 
 Follow“Yvette U. Tan” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 2,129 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
