<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008138" url="http://www.freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/2775053/posts" time="2012-07-13-01:14" support="14" score="0.03918060290319554" bingtitle="Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act" webtitle="Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act">
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>... if you crave a taco or fried chicken from a fast-food restaurant ... like regular Oprah watchers using a green credit card ... in Illinois, which I know about) are getting put ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Republic 
 Browse · Search News/Activism 
 Topics · Post Article 
 
 Skip to comments. 
 Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act 
 ABC News ^ | Sep 7, 2011
 | Nina Terrero 

 Posted on 09/07/2011 3:34:54 PM PDT by nickcarraway 

In an ever-growing number of states, if you crave a taco or fried chicken from a fast-food restaurant, you can pay for it with food stamps.
Food stamps - known more formally as the USDAs Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program - have been in use for grocery staples, such as bread and milk, since 1934, but now, for the first time, they can be used for fast food in four states across the country.
The number of businessesincluding convenience and discount stores, gas stations and pharmaciesthat have been approved to accept food stamps has increased by a third over the course of three years from 2005 to 2010, USA Today reports, and fast-food chains are working hard to get a cut of the federal dollars in Florida, California, Arizona and Michigan.
The funds allocated to the food stamp program have increased exponentially, from $28.5 billion to $64.7 billion in that same time frame, according to USA Today, and at a time when people have less money to spend, the bump in federal dollars can mean a lot to the fast-industry.


(Excerpt) Read more at abcnews.go.com ...
 TOPICS: Culture/Society ; Extended News ; Government ; News/Current Events 
 KEYWORDS: ebt ; foodstamps ; freecheeze ; kfc ; tacobell ; welfare 
 1 posted on 09/07/2011 3:34:56 PM PDT by nickcarraway [ Post Reply | Private Reply | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
You gotta be kidding me...

 2 posted on 09/07/2011 3:38:31 PM PDT by ItsOurTimeNow (&quot;Go now. Run along and tell your Xerxes that he faces Free Men here...not slaves.&quot;) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Get the fast food chains hooked on the government teat and the federal government will really feel like it has the right to create their menus.

 3 posted on 09/07/2011 3:39:13 PM PDT by FreedomForce (Perry 2012 | Perry/Palin 2016 | Palin 2020) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway How do Mooch&apos;hell&apos;s food Nazi react to this ? 
 4 posted on 09/07/2011 3:46:12 PM PDT by Uriel-2012 (Psalm 119:174 I long for Your salvation, YHvH, Your law is my delight.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: FreedomForce 
Get ready for government approved Menus. Goodbye large fry, hello McTofu.

 5 posted on 09/07/2011 3:47:29 PM PDT by barmag25 (How many pea&apos;s we gotta eat to get out of this mess?) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 3 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Bad Move!

 6 posted on 09/07/2011 3:47:52 PM PDT by Iron Munro (Muslims who advocate, support, or carry out Jihad give the other 1% a bad name) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Sure. Why not? Just in time for 2012 elections, they’ll authorize it for liquor stores and discount cigs outlets. I was behind this woman in the grocery store check out line recently. She was buying a few measly items for her kids with food stamps, and paying cash for her carton of cigs and case of beer. while doling out the food stamps, she had the nerve to complain to the cashier about how she had“lost over a hundred ninety dollahs’”in a poker game the night before. I’m standing there with just barely enough to cover my family’s needs for the week, thinking my tax dollars permit her to blow what little money she has on gambling, beer, and cigs, but she won’t spend a dime on her kids..It was all I could do to keep from slapping her across the back of her head.

 7 posted on 09/07/2011 3:50:10 PM PDT by PowderMonkey (WILL WORK FOR AMMO) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway Yum! Brands, based in Louisville, Ky., which operates a string of restaurants that includes Taco Bell, KFC, Long John Silvers and Pizza Hut, are among those applying for inclusion in the food stamp program... 

I don&apos;t blame the Fast Food joints trying to get in on this. For many years I have seen the dead beats buying absolute garbage on my dime in grocery stores. Why shouldn&apos;t these guys get in on the act. The real problem with this is the states allowing anything more than staples to be bought. For crying out loud, I see people using debit looking cards as food stamps as not to embarrass these losers in the check out line.
 8 posted on 09/07/2011 3:51:10 PM PDT by Lazlo in PA (Now living in a newly minted Red State.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Another story, same subject:
 http://preview.tinyurl.com/3t4ygrr 

 9 posted on 09/07/2011 3:55:30 PM PDT by preacher (A government which robs from Peter to pay Paul will always have the support of Paul.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: Lazlo in PA 
Here in MN , you can gt your free cheeze on a Visa-logo welfare card. They’ve been tracked being used in Hawaii and other far-away places.

 http://kstp.com/news/stories/s1830297.shtml 

 10 posted on 09/07/2011 3:59:58 PM PDT by WOBBLY BOB (My mind is like a steel trap: rusty and illegal in 37 states.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 8 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
What happened to the food police? Salt, trans-fats, Obesity?

 11 posted on 09/07/2011 4:00:42 PM PDT by swamprebel ( proud SOB!) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Interesting math....

$85 billion (2012 US budget for food stamps) / 307 mil (US population)

$277 in food stamps for every person in the US per year.

 12 posted on 09/07/2011 4:00:48 PM PDT by nascarnation [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
So, let me get this right....we’re not only buying their food, but now we’re hiring someone to cook it for them?

WTFU America!!

 13 posted on 09/07/2011 4:05:50 PM PDT by panaxanax (0bama&gt;&gt;WORST PRESIDENT EVER.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Food stamps (or whatever one wants to call the program) should be for staples ONLY. You want someone to cook your food for you? OK, fine...GET A JOB AND PAY FOR IT YOURSELF!

You want to buy convenience foods that can be microwaved, but which cost 2-3 times what staple foods cost? OK, fine...GET A JOB AND PAY FOR IT YOURSELF!

You want to buy bottled water instead of the nearly free tap water available to 99.0% of the people in this country? OK, fine...GET A JOB AND PAY FOR IT YOURSELF!

I am SICK AND F’ING TIRED OF SUPPORTING THE SHEER LAZINESS OF OTHERS. Buy whatever you want...with your own money. Can’t afford more than staples? Sorry about that, but if we the taxpayers are supporting you, then don’t eat out, don’t buy bottled water and don’t expect convenience. It not only isn’t moral to mooch off of others like that, but we simply haven’t got the money. Don’t like that? OK, fine...GET A JOB AND PAY FOR IT YOURSELF!

 14 posted on 09/07/2011 4:11:09 PM PDT by Ancesthntr (Bibi to Odumbo: Its not going to happen.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
I have often seen people using food stamps to buy soda and other junk food. I fail to understand why food stamps can’t be restricted to healthy foods like the WIC program. Where is Michelle Obama on this issue?

 15 posted on 09/07/2011 4:14:12 PM PDT by The Great RJ (&quot;The problem with socialism is that pretty soon you run out of other people&apos;s money&quot;M. Thatcher) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: WOBBLY BOB 
A couple years ago I noticed a few people in line in front of me looking like regular Oprah watchers using a green credit card and cash, splitting their grocery bill between the two. I asked the chick at check out and she said, rolling her eyes, that it was the new food stamp cards. Got me really angry. There should be some stigma to using food stamps to encourage their use only in dire situations. Not this nonsense.

 16 posted on 09/07/2011 4:15:43 PM PDT by Lazlo in PA (Now living in a newly minted Red State.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 10 | View Replies ] To: panaxanax 
Most of the food stamp bums that I have seen appear to be too stupid to operate a microwave oven.

 17 posted on 09/07/2011 4:16:15 PM PDT by forgotten man (forgotten man) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 13 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway Why should poor Americans not be allowed access to mainstream fast food restaurants?
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
Well, that&apos;s what the enablers will say...
 18 posted on 09/07/2011 4:19:22 PM PDT by Rebelbase (Disgusted with the establishment GOP and their enablers.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
*bleep* me... I’m pissed off.

 19 posted on 09/07/2011 4:19:38 PM PDT by Ancient Drive (DRINK COFFEE! - Do Stupid Things Faster with More Energy!) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: panaxanax So, let me get this right....were not only buying their food, but now were hiring someone to cook it for them?
WTFU America!!
 
You are so far behind the curve.
EVERY Jack In The Box, Mc Donalds, Panda , ect fast food joint in Los Angeles has a huge“WE ACCEPT EBT CARDS”in the window or on the front door.
But then, so do the Strip Clubs
Illegal Aliens are receiving welfare payments under several different fake identities and the California Legislature has just banned the use of finger prints to screen out the fraudsters who have multiple identities, as opposed to the honest fraudsters who play by the rules and only collect welfare and food stamp payments under one fake identity.
 20 posted on 09/07/2011 4:26:41 PM PDT by rdcbn [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 13 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Buying Big Macs and fries with food stamps? This must be a clever Republican plot to turn liberal food nazis against government hand-outs.

 21 posted on 09/07/2011 4:37:21 PM PDT by Bernard Marx [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway Because french fries and chicken nuggets are staple food items for the vast majority of America&apos;s underclass.
 22 posted on 09/07/2011 4:37:36 PM PDT by Chuckster (The longer I live the less I care about what you think.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: FreedomForce Get the fast food chains hooked on the government teat and the federal government will really feel like it has the right to create their menus. 
That&apos;s what I&apos;d be afraid of. The current management of the Federal food stamp program is fairly lenient in philosophy, not ruling out things like soft drinks and salted snacks (they actually cite studies that point out that food stamp recipients don&apos;t spend significantly more of their food budget on those items than the average grocery shopper). But get McDonald&apos;s into the act and that might be too much of a temptation.
 23 posted on 09/07/2011 4:40:26 PM PDT by HiTech RedNeck (There&apos;s gonna be a Redneck Revolution! (See my freep page) [rednecks come in many colors]) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 3 | View Replies ] To: rdcbn 
The food stamp system is so taxed beyond proper oversight now that some food stamp recipients (in Illinois, which I know about) are getting put on express lists that don’t require a review for an entire year. If an honest person who was on the stamps gets a job he or she will tell the food stamp office to stop the benefits. Not-so-honest people will gladly accept the benefits for a year regardless.

 24 posted on 09/07/2011 4:47:00 PM PDT by HiTech RedNeck (There&apos;s gonna be a Redneck Revolution! (See my freep page) [rednecks come in many colors]) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 20 | View Replies ] To: PowderMonkey 
I see this all the time at the grocery store - an elderly widower digs out some coins to pay exact change for $15.32 or something buying staples. Her clothes are old but serviceable, the car 30 years old, etc.

Next in line is somebody driving a 35k SUV with a shopping cart literally full of steaks and poultry paying with a welfare card.

 25 posted on 09/07/2011 4:56:34 PM PDT by Freedom4US [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 7 | View Replies ] To: Freedom4US 
That’s OK, BaraqqiCare’s death panels will quickly rid the country of those“burdens”.

 26 posted on 09/07/2011 4:59:13 PM PDT by nascarnation [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 25 | View Replies ] To: Freedom4US 
Oh and BTW you’ve been out of the SUV market too long.

More like 60k these days for the ones you’re describing.

 27 posted on 09/07/2011 5:00:13 PM PDT by nascarnation [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 25 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
I thought it was bad enough when they approved the Papa Murphy’s take and bake pizzas for EBT!
“Spend”your WIC welfare $$ on the cheese and make your own damned dough!

 28 posted on 09/07/2011 5:22:22 PM PDT by GnuHere [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway and America takes another one in the........
 
 29 posted on 09/07/2011 5:23:03 PM PDT by Chode (American Hedonist - *DTOM* -ww- NO Pity for the LAZY) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway I can&apos;t say I&apos;m all that surprised by this.
Heck -- at the rate we&apos;re going, it&apos;s only a matter of time before the Federal government will allow people to use food stamps to make the monthly payments on a new GM car.
 30 posted on 09/07/2011 5:36:48 PM PDT by Alberta&apos;s Child (&quot;If you touch my junk, I&apos;m gonna have you arrested.&quot;) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
“Heres a quick list of fast food restaurants in states that already accept food stamps for restaurant meals”:

***Michigan:

Churchs Chicken

Kentucky Fried Chicken

McDonalds

Subway

Grandmas Famous Chicken

Eight Mile Pancake House

Mr. Ts BBQ

Vitos Pizza

***California:

Jack in the Box

Subway

El Pollo Loco

Papa Murphys Pizza

Florida

KFC

Taco Bell

Pizza Hut

Papa Murphys Pizza

***Arizona

Dominos Pizza

Golden Corral

Southern Cuisine

Rallys Hamburger

***BTTT

 31 posted on 09/07/2011 6:02:45 PM PDT by Dr. Scarpetta [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
I was just in Sherman Oaks, California recently and saw a carwash that accepted EBT cards.

 32 posted on 09/07/2011 6:09:31 PM PDT by Lizavetta (You get what you tolerate) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: Bernard Marx 
Does anyone think that maybe they are now trying out“eugenics”? What better way to kill off the population than to feed them pink goo chicken nuggets and non deteriorating white fried“potatoes”?

 33 posted on 09/07/2011 6:45:16 PM PDT by proudtobeanamerican1 (A house divided against itself cannot stand. Abraham Lincoln) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 21 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
ABC News exists to advance the agenda of the marxist state, without questioning, without dissent.

 34 posted on 09/07/2011 7:15:33 PM PDT by wolficatZ (Somebody once wrote&quot;Revenge is a dish that has to be eaten cold&quot;.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: Ancesthntr 
Staples only is right. I agree!

Over the Labor Day weekend it happened YET AGAIN that my husband was in line at the checkout behind someone who bought live lobsters with food stamps,while he,who works very hard,was buying cheap hamburger.

It’s sickening and a complete ripoff of the working people of this country. Why is it that people who don’t work can afford to eat better than people who do? Because the people who work are forced to pay for others to live better than they do themselves.

 35 posted on 09/07/2011 8:05:37 PM PDT by FreeDeerHawk [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 14 | View Replies ] To: FreeDeerHawk 
They probably have other sources of“cash only”income.

 36 posted on 09/07/2011 8:09:48 PM PDT by 3boysdad (The very elect.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 35 | View Replies ] To: Dr. Scarpetta 
Taxpayer funded corporate subsidies,all cleaned up as compassion for the needy.

 37 posted on 09/07/2011 8:13:14 PM PDT by FreeDeerHawk [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 31 | View Replies ] To: Ancesthntr 
The problem with your tirade is that there aren’t any jobs in the obama economy. Or did you lose sight of that fact? Even fast food isn’t hiring too much right now.

 38 posted on 09/07/2011 9:00:18 PM PDT by Catsrus [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 14 | View Replies ] To: Freedom4US 
“Next in line is somebody driving a 35k SUV with a shopping cart literally full of steaks and poultry paying with a welfare card.”

This fraud on the taxpayer has been ongoing for multiple decades. I observed the same in the early seventies...but they had the recognizable coupons, then. She had two buggies full. One was meats only, lots of steaks and pork. Then she drove away in her new Cadillac.

The wife and I both worked. We had bills to pay. Mortgage, and a clunker used car payment. No way could we afford a buggy full of meats. Much less a new Cadillac. So I wrote a letter to my congressman who passed it (they always do) to the Dept in charge of these things. The response from them was that it was probably a friend’s car who drove them to the store. But if I had evidence of fraud, please feel free to contact them, and they would look into it. That was 1973.

 39 posted on 09/07/2011 9:21:04 PM PDT by takenoprisoner (Repeal the 16th amendment . Send Islam packing to their homeland.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 25 | View Replies ] To: nickcarraway 
Prepared food used to be denying under food stamps.

 40 posted on 09/07/2011 9:21:58 PM PDT by Fledermaus (I&apos;m done with political parties. The GOP is useless. Anarchy is perferable to this CRAP!) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 1 | View Replies ] To: Catsrus 
If there are no jobs, that is heartbreaking - and believe me, I have noticed that the economy SUCKS.

However, the fact that there are few jobs to be found does not make it OK for people on aid to spend the aid money for luxuries. Fast food is a luxury - you are paying someone to cook for you. Simply put, food stamps (or whatever) should not be accepted at ANY restaurant. Nor should public assistance be able to purchase water bottles - tap water is far cheaper. To argue otherwise is to be in favor of the welfare state - and you should at least be honest about that. I don’t want to see anyone starving in the streets, and we are still well off enough to make sure that such doesn’t happen. But when I don’t have the money I simply don’t eat out. Why should unemployed people be any different?

One exception I could accept is for someone out actually looking for a job to be able to buy a sandwich or slice of pizza plus a glass of water if they’re going to be away from home for the entire day. Otherwise, they should make due or do without.

 41 posted on 09/08/2011 10:36:09 AM PDT by Ancesthntr (Bibi to Odumbo: Its not going to happen.) [ Post Reply | Private Reply | To 38 | View Replies ] 

 Disclaimer: Opinions posted on Free Republic are those of the individual
 posters and do not necessarily represent the opinion of Free Republic or its
 management. All materials posted herein are protected by copyright law and the
 exemption for fair use of copyrighted works. 
 
 Free Republic 
 Browse · Search News/Activism 
 Topics · Post Article 
 FreeRepublic , LLC, PO BOX 9771, FRESNO, CA 93794 FreeRepublic.com is powered by software copyright 2000-2008 John Robinson
	</body>
</document>
