<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008906" url="http://articles.wdbj7.com/keyword/restaurant" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="2" score="0.002698119995986882" bingtitle="Articles about Restaurant - WDBJ7" webtitle="Articles about Restaurant - WDBJ7">
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>More trouble for a man snagged at a Roanoke fast-food restaurant over the ... into a restaurant in downtown Roanoke and tried to pay the bartender with a $1 million bill.</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement YOU ARE HERE: WDBJ7 Home → Collections → Restaurant IN THE NEWS 
Restaurant
 RELATED KEYWORDS: 
 Roanoke Virginia Tech Roanoke County Lynchburg Roanoke Valley |   More 
 FEATURED ARTICLES NEWS 
 Restaurant Week kicks off in Blacksburg Monday 
 WDBJ7 Web Staff | June 17, 2012 It&apos;s an effort to get you out and about this week! Monday begins Blacksburg&apos;s first Restaurant Week. Through Sunday, June 24th, 16 restaurants are serving up dining discounts. The aim is to help you discover new restaurants, or even visit your favorite spots. Click here for more details of Restaurant Week, including which restaurants are taking part. NEWS 
 Former Hokie football standout opens new restaurant in Lynchburg 
 October 22, 2009 A former Virginia Tech and E.C. Glass football standout is getting into the restaurant business. Andre Kendrick is the co-owner of &quot;7 restaurant&quot; in his hometown of Lynchburg. Kendrick was a quarterback at Glass in the early and mid-1990&apos;s.  He signed on as a defensive back with Virginia Tech in 1996 and played a crucial role in the team&apos;s success in 1999.  Kendrick scored a touchdown that put Tech up 29-28 in the 2000 Sugar Bowl. The name &quot;7 restaurant&quot; pays tribute to the famous number 7&apos;s of sports, including Kendrick&apos;s former Hokie teammate Michael Vick. NEWS 
 Restaurant heavily damaged by fire in Grayson County 
 Web staff | April 29, 2011 A fire at a Grayson County restaurant sends customers scrambling. It broke out a little after four on Friday at Paul&apos;s Restaurant. The fire started in the back of the building. Everyone who was inside got out ok. It took three fire departments an hour to get it under control, but the place is probably a total loss. NEWS 
 Chipotle Mexican Grill Coming to Roanoke 
 Jean Jadhon and WDBJ-TV Anchor/Reporter | December 2, 2010 Chipotle Mexican Grill is coming to Roanoke.  The restaurant chain has signed a lease to open a restaurant at Towers Shopping Center where Hollywood Video used to be. The Mexican restaurant, known for its naturally raised meats and organic and locally grown ingredients, first opened in 1993 in Colorado.  The company has grown to 1000 stores nationwide since then. This is a very exciting deal we just signed, said Will Collins, director of leasing for the Rappaport Companies, the firm that handles leasing for Towers. NEWS 
 Bomb threat made to Roanoke restaurant 
 WDBJ Web Staff | November 13, 2011 A bomb threat was called in to the Smokey Bones restaurant on Valley View Blvd. Sunday evening at 5:00 p.m. Management decided to evacuate the restaurant as the Roanoke Police Department looked for any explosive devices. No explosives were found, but police are still investigating. NEWS 
 Home Cookin&apos; Restaurant on the Move 
 WDBJ Web Staff | December 12, 2010 Roanoke, Va.--- A popular restaurant is making the move to downtown Roanoke. Thelma&apos;s Chicken and Waffles is planning to move into a Market Street building. The restaurant owner wants to tear down their current location along Orange Avenue, with the hopes of signing lease papers for their new home this week. They are also planning to apply for a liquor license. The restaurant opened in 2007. BUSINESS 
 Fire shuts down Bedford restaurant 
 Hollani Davis and Anchor/Reporter | September 19, 2011 Lunchtime rush led to customers rushing out of the door of The Bedford Restaurant and Grill on Sunday. The restaurant is located off of Route 460 on West Lynchburg Salem Turnpike.     A surveillance camera in one of the offices overheated, melted and started a fire according to the owner.  The damage is mostly confined to that area but it will take a few days to get the smoky smell and soot cleaned up throughout the building. The owner hopes to have the restaurant back up and running by this coming weekend. NEWS 
 Lynchburg eateries team up for first ever &quot;restaurant week&quot; 
 Tim Saunders and Reporter/Lynchburg Bureau Chief | June 12, 2012 When Isabella&apos;s Italian Trattoria opened 13 years ago, it stood out among the city&apos;s food options: locally owned by a Lynchburg native. &quot;We&apos;re very involved in every aspect of the business, and we feel like that comes across in the way that we operate the restaurant,&quot; said Isabella&apos;s owner, Cheri Barauskas. Isabella&apos;s has more competition now than it used to. &quot;I think it&apos;s a good thing,&quot; said Barauskas.  &quot;It shows that Lynchburg has the business to support us. &quot; The city is now home to dozens of homegrown restaurants, offering everything from tapas, to German fare, and traditional American. NEWS 
 Cuban restaurant coming to Roanoke City Market 
 Justin McLeod and Reporter | July 13, 2011 A Cuban restaurant is coming to the Roanoke City Market.  It will be called Habana Cafe.  It will be located at the corner of Market Street and Campbell Avenue, across from Awful Arthurs. Habana Cafe will be a sit down restaurant with outdoor dining.  Five restaurants have now signed leases.  They include All Sports Cafe, Euro Bakery, New York Subs, and Hong Kong.  New York Subs and Hong Kong were previous tenants. The market building closed a year ago for a top to bottom renovation.  Hall&amp;Associates says three more kitchen spaces are available inside the market building.  Roger Elkin says they are in final negotiations to fill two of those spots.  Elkin says one is a pizza type restaurant.  Elkin says food vendors will begin building their restaurants next week.  The plan is to have a soft opening in mid-August.  There is a big grand opening celebration planned for Labor Day weekend. NEWS 
 Starting a Restaurant Workshop Friday in Roanoke 
 Bob Grebe and Reporter | February 21, 2011 Entrepreneur Express: The Business of Restaurants Starting and Managing a Successful Restaurant Workshop Friday, February 25, 2011 8:00 a.m. - 12:00 p.m. Registration deadline is Monday, February 21. The event will be held at the The Jefferson Center, 2nd Floor Rehearsal Hall.  The address is 541 Luck Avenue, S.W., Roanoke, Virginia Advanced registration required at: www.vastartup.org Contact City of Roanoke Economic Development 540-853-1694 or Virginia Department of Business Assistance 276-676-3768 Workshop Agenda      Welcome&amp;Overview of Workshop      Reasons Why Restaurants Fail      Steps and Resources to Launching a Successful Restaurant in Virginia      Is There a Need for your Restaurant—How to Prepare a Market Analysis      Finance Preparation/Sustaining a Restaurant      Business Owner Testimonials/Panel Discussions      Networking Break      Tax Requirements      Liability and Insurance      Marketing, Promotion, and Customer Service of a Successful Restaurant      Questions and Answers 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next ARTICLES BY DATE NEWS 
 UPDATE: Detours for Downtowner Motor Inn in Danville extended 
 Justin Ward and WDBJ7 Reporter | July 11, 2012 A detour in place for the demolition of the Downtowner Motor Inn has been extended through July 16. The City of Danville says heat and thunderstorms have delayed the demolition crew. ---------------------- A detour is in place as crews work to demolish the Downtowner Motor Inn in downtown Danville. Travel is now down to one lane of northbound traffic for the next six days. The detour brings southbound traffic from Main Street onto Market Street and then to Spring Street. Advertisement HEALTH 
 WDBJ7 Health Blog: I am a SODA Addict 
 LaRell Reynolds and WDBJ7 Blogger | July 8, 2012 Hi, my name is LaRell and I have an addiction to soda. It started when I was a young lad. I needed to drink some kind of bubbly refreshment with every meal. That need for soda at every meal expedited my now, former, obesity. I tried to stop. But, I failed. The summer before college I tried to lose weight to make an impression on my new colleagues. I did so well. I lasted a WHOLE semester without a taste of soda. Then, horror hit on a cold, eery day in January. NEWS 
 Danville Orthopedic Clinic moving into former Dan River Inc. building, bringing 40 new jobs 
 WDBJ7 Web Staff | July 6, 2012 Danville Orthopedic Clinic announced Friday that it will move into the former Dan River Inc. building, bringing at least 40 jobs to the tobacco district in Danville. A $14.5 million investment will be made into the project. Other training facilities and medical practices inside the building will be operated by the Danville Regional Medical Center. Additionally, the building will house other street-level businesses, and an adjoining building next to the river will be a restaurant. NEWS 
 UPDATE: Douthat State Park will re-open Saturday 
 Joe Dashiell and Reporter | July 6, 2012 The power is back on at Douthat State Park, and the park will reopen Saturday. However, the Camp Carson Picnic Shelter and Douthat Lakeview Restaurant will stay closed until Wednesday because of damage from a storm on June 29. ------------------------- Original story from Thursday, July 5 Friday&apos;s storm closed four of Virginia&apos;s state parks. Thursday night, just one of them, Douthat State Park in Alleghany and Bath Counties was still without power. The chippers and chainsaws are getting a workout, and all hands are helping to clear the trees that came crashing down on Friday night. NEWS 
 Rocky Mount diners appreciate &quot;The Hub&quot; restaurant opening on Sunday 
 Bryce Williams and Reporter | July 1, 2012 The Hub Restaurant in Rocky Mount opened for business today, but it certainly wasn&apos;t &quot;business as usual&quot;.   The restaurant has been a staple in the community for years and is usually closed on Sundays. But the owner decided to open today so people without power could have another dining option, since many restaurants are closed. The customer we spoke with, after he enjoyed his biscuits with gravy, was quite happy &quot;The Hub&quot; was open.   We spoke with customer Holden Mitchell. NEWS 
 Roanoke businesses forced to adjust after power knocked out 
 Melissa Gaona and WDBJ7 Reporter | June 30, 2012 Roanoke was one of many hometowns hit hard by these storms. Many businesses were left without power in the Valley View area. Businesses had to adapt without power. &quot;Sweeping floors, changing trash cans, washing dishes, getting everything ready in case we get power back on,&quot; Chris Small, Chick-Fil-A general manager said. One of the busiest areas in Roanoke took a beating, after damaging winds blew through Valley View Boulevard. &quot;I saw the trees and I&apos;ve never seen anything like this in my life, they all kissed the ground,&quot; Kathleen Hartman, a Walmart worker said. NEWS 
 UPDATE: Arrest made in attempted abduction near Virginia Tech&apos;s campus 
 Kimberly McBroom/Justin Ward and WDBJ 7 Anchor/Reporter | June 29, 2012 An arrest has been made in an attempted abduction that happened early Friday morning near the campus of Virginia Tech. 33-year-old Alex Armando Cardenas Flores of South Carolina has been charged with one count of abduction. He is being held without bond. Flores is set to appear in court on July 9. Police say Flores was employed by a contractor working at one of Virginia Tech&apos;s construction sites. According to police, a Blacksburg resident noticed a vehicle matching the suspect&apos;s description and called police. NEWS 
 Roanoke meals tax expires this Saturday 
 Elizabeth Harrington and Reporter | June 27, 2012 Roanoke city officials are keeping their promise. A 2% meals tax was passed in 2010 and it&apos;s ending on schedule this Saturday, June 30. The tax raised $9.5 million for the school system which is more than the city expected. Customers we spoke with say they didn&apos;t notice the extra 2% tacked on to their bills. &quot;Actually I was okay with it because you know I&apos;m willing to pay a little bit more for a good cause,&quot; says customer Ann Ferguson. Restaurant owners say they can count on one hand the number of people who questioned it. &quot;I think I had one guest in two years do that and they&apos;re from another city,&quot; says Table 50 owner Eric DiLauro. NEWS 
 Salem gets set to host Mitt Romney speech Tuesday 
 Bryce Williams and WDBJ7 Reporter | June 25, 2012 The stage is set in Salem for the man who wants to be the next President of the United States. Republican candidate Mitt Romney will make a campaign stop at Carter Machinery on Tuesday. Your Hometown News Leader, WDBJ7 will air Romney&apos;s speech live at noon Tuesday. You can also watch it live on our website, by clicking here . On Monday there was excitement in the air in Salem, but the people we spoke with said forget about all the pomp and circumstance, they want to hear what Mitt Romney has to say about the most important issue in their eyes, the economy. NEWS 
 UPDATE: Suspect indicted on murder charges in Danville following weekend shooting 
 WDBJ7 Web Staff | June 25, 2012 A grand jury indicted 27-year-old Larry Davis on murder charges Monday following a shooting Saturday in Danville. Davis has been indicted on charges of first-degree murder, malicious wounding, two counts of use of a firearm in commission of a felony, and discharging a weapon within 1,000 feet of school property. Davis has been charged for the shooting death of Adrian Rashad Wimbush on Saturday at Highlander Pub and Lodge. A 39-year-old woman was also shot, but was not injured badly. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next Copyright 2012 WDBJ7-TV Terms of Service | Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
