<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008564" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/gotts-roadside-st-helena" time="2012-07-13-02:02" support="1" score="0.0023656844665636357" bingtitle="Gott&apos;s Roadside - St. Helena, CA" webtitle="Gott&apos;s Roadside - St. Helena, CA">
			<query id="000525" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>Now there&apos;s probably a line; in my opinion that ... asking about my day to asking if they could clear my tray ... and prices are not what you expect from a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Gott&apos;s Roadside
 741 reviews Rating Details 
 Categories: Restaurants Burgers Restaurants Diners Restaurants Breakfast&amp;Brunch Burgers , Diners , Breakfast&amp;Brunch   [Edit] 
 933 Main St 
 St. Helena , CA 94574 
 (707) 963-3486 http://gotts.com/ Menu 1 of 229 Add Photos View All Photos Hours: 
Mon-Sun 7 am - 9 pm
 Takes Reservations: No
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Price Range: $$ 
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: No
 Good For: Lunch
 Alcohol: Beer&amp;Wine Only
 Drive-Thru: No
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: No
 Caters: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 Dogs Allowed: Yes
 First to Review Amy H. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
 Reviews (741) About This Business 
 Yelp Sponsor 
 
 
741 reviews for Gott&apos;s Roadside
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;The sweet potato fries were perfect too.&quot; In 199 reviews &quot;the western bacon blue ring burger is very very good.&quot; In 14 reviews &quot;Also have a large grassy area w/ picnic tables .&quot; In 70 reviews &quot;I&apos;m very glad we stumbled upon Taylor&apos;s .&quot; In 173 reviews &quot;Want a laid back, fast, low key lunch in Wine Country .&quot; In 42 reviews &quot;The ahi tuna burger is the stuff my dreams are made of.&quot; In 58 reviews &quot;Their Wisconsin Sourdough Burger is one of the best things...&quot; In 25 reviews &quot;Here, they use the classic thick-and-soft egg bun .&quot; In 30 reviews 
 Show more review highlights   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
741 reviews in English

 
Review from Unyime E. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 39 friends 120 reviews 

 Unyime E. 
 
Milwaukee, WI
 7/8/2012 3 Check-ins Here 
During our last Napa Valley excursion we visited Gott&apos;s three times.  With each visit, I tried a different burger (Texas, Green Chile, Western Bacon).  And with each visit, I was assured of my opinion that Gott&apos;s Roadside, unequivocally offers the best burger that I&apos;ve ever head.  ...and this is coming from a guy from Wisconsin, the nation&apos;s dairy capital! I know you Californians will want to stake a claim to that title with your &quot;happy cows&quot; and such, but that is a discussion for another time. (On a side note - It was interesting how many people brought up the Wisconsin/California bigger dairy state debate)  You&apos;ll never go wrong when the burger joint toasts the bun.  And the sweet potato fries, offered with an interesting ranch sauce, are simply outstanding.  Make sure to stop here next time you visit St. Helena, or Napa Valley in general.  And those three burgers I tried?  The Green Chile was my favorite, but you can&apos;t go seriously can&apos;t go wrong with any of them.

Gott&apos;s remains my choice for last meal before execution (I&apos;d imagine the good  taxpayers wouldn&apos;t want to fund a French Laundry request).
 
 Listed in: Wedding/Honeymoon , Eating in Wine Country. , Excellence , Hamburgers and Fries 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Katie C. 
 
 27 friends 57 reviews 

 Katie C. 
 
Napa, CA
 7/5/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I LOVE this Gotts. It really puts the other two to shame. The service and efficiency here are always fantastic.

Burgers are delic and the white pistachio milkshake is ahhhmazing. If you&apos;re feeling adventurous be sure to try the Ahi Tacos - really could live off those things.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Megan E. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 7 friends 105 reviews 

 Megan E. 
 
Longmont, CO
 7/4/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Three stars is nice. The place is very hyped for what you get. We thought the food was ok but not great.

One star off for price. I know its CA but for two, we spent $20 on burger, onion rings, and chicken tender (came with fries). Chicken was small, more nuggets than tenders (only 5) and burger was super well done, not slightly pink.

If you want food to soak up wine between tastings, try this place but its not worth a special trip.

PS. they advertise ordering online - I didn&apos;t know about that until I saw the menu but now you know, so try that and avoid a 30+ minute wait in the hot sun.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Edwin E. 
 
 60 friends 39 reviews 

 Edwin E. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 7/2/2012 
Yummy! Thanks, Guy Fieri.

Poke Taco- yummy, fish is eh-ok fresh but overall a good concept. I finished it. LOL
Fries with chives- not life changing
Turkey Burger- Juicy, loved the aioli dressing.
Bacon Burger- loved the egg bun and the juicy patty.
Chili- ehh.

Overall, for a pretty bourgeois area the price points are pretty decent.

Would I eat here again, sure.
Would I come back to Napa?  ehhhhh.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Will A. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 102 friends 393 reviews 

 Will A. 
 
Alameda, CA
 6/30/2012 1 photo 
It was worth waiting in the long line in the hot sun to get the ahi burger, the Wisconsin burger, the chocolate shake and the sweet potato fries.  All  hit the spot.  Great &quot;to go&quot;  box for the food, too.

It would be nice if they had the line form in the shade.  Staff is super friendly.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ping P. 
 
 20 friends 309 reviews 

 Ping P. 
 
East Bay, CA
 7/1/2012 
I spent the day in class at the CIA - so I was really &quot;foodied&apos; out and then we went to a private tasting at a little family owned winery and got more foodied out with wine. Top that off with champagne and more treats at Meadowood then another wine tasting..well you get the idea...had way too much fabulous food and wine.. I was sleepy, not very hungry and just wanted something simple.

We decided to hit up Gott&apos;s and we were not sorry. We sat out back and took our shoes off and kicked back in the grass. Our food was fresh, fast and incredibly good. Just what the doctor ordered.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jennifer W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 591 friends 887 reviews 

 Jennifer W. 
 
Berkeley, CA
 6/18/2012 2 photos 1 Check-in Here 
Come here to you&apos;re on your way to and from St. Helena or Calistoga. You won&apos;t regret it. It&apos;s the perfect roadside stop before you have to hop back into your oven of a car. There&apos;s a large grove of picnic tables and plenty of space under the roof. The line can look intimidating, but slap on some sunscreen and stick it out.

The hot dogs are by Let&apos;s Be Frank and the chicken is Mary&apos;s. The cheeseburger is really good. You don&apos;t have to be adventurous to get a good burger here. The texas burger was a hot mess, but delicious nonetheless. The garlic fries were just perfect. I wish I didn&apos;t have to share.

They do draft beers of the typical northern california variety as well as wine by the bottle and half bottle. Aside from the fountain drinks, there are also a selection of milkshakes. They&apos;re luxurious and made with Double Rainbow ice cream. They even serve breakfast.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (2) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Rich P. 
 
 14 friends 255 reviews 

 Rich P. 
 
Concord, CA
 7/1/2012 
Holy Cow! The lines are worth it, people!
Try the California Chicken sandwich and/or the BBQ chicken sandwich. Fries are a must, and the black and white shake was wicked good! The sourdough bread was delicious, and everything tasted VERY fresh. Like it was picked earlier that day.
I saw some people eating fish tacos, and a lot of people eating burgers. I&apos;ll have to try those next time!
Yes, it was the most I&apos;ve paid for a chicken sandwich, but when you consider what you&apos;d pay at some other places in the Napa area - it&apos;s really a very good deal.
Oh, and when they ask your name... don&apos;t be afraid to make up something funny. I told &apos;em my name was Bobo McSweatbox. Everyone there got a really good laugh out of it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Janaia R. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 25 friends 81 reviews 

 Janaia R. 
 
Albany, CA
 6/23/2012 
You KNOW their burgers must be good if there&apos;s a big line-up to order and dozens and dozens of picnic tables filled with customers eating their food.

PROS:
-The burgers are really tasty (a little on the sloppy side, oh well!)
-The line-up moves quickly, despite the long-ish looking lines
-LARGE MENU! There&apos;s something for everyone!
-Lots of seating outdoors. There are tons (and I mean TONS) of picnic tables set up outside. There is even a large covered tent area where they must set up all the picnic tables on rainy days.

CONS:
-Price. $7.99-$14.99 for a single burger? A tad expensive, but worth the experience.
-Wait time. We must have waited at least 15+ minutes for our food to be ready, the P.A. system was really hard to hear, it was a bit muffled.
-Outdoor seating only....not as nice on cold rainy days.
-Limited parking.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Adrienne H. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 335 friends 651 reviews 

 Adrienne H. 
 
Palo Alto, CA
 6/10/2012 3 photos 1 Check-in Here 
We ate at a ton of fancy restaurants in Napa, but this legendary roadside burger stand was one of my favorite meals.  We stopped in around 12:30 on a holiday weekend and encountered a pretty long line that took us about half an hour to get through to place our order.   Once we ordered, however, the food came out very quickly.

This is so much more than just a hamburger place, and we chose from an extensive menu of sandwiches, sides and shakes.  My fiance had a California chicken sandwich ($11) ( http://www.yelp.com/biz_… ), which he liked but didn&apos;t love.  I had a turkey burger ($10) sans mayo ( http://www.yelp.com/biz_… ), which was outstanding, possibly the best turkey burger I&apos;ve ever had.   The turkey patty itself was excellent but the real highlights were the fantastic egg bun (tasted a little bit like challah!) and the homemade apple-onion chutney that topped the burger.   It tasted a little bit like applesauce but sooo much better.   There&apos;s a recipe online and I think I&apos;m going to need to recreate it at home: http://www.mercurynews.c… 

We also ordered sides of onion rings ($3.99) and fries ($2.69) ( http://www.yelp.com/biz_… ).   The fries were pretty ordinary but the beer battered onion rings were phenomenal.   The shakes looked good as well, I regret not trying one.  Oh well, next time!

There is a nice area to eat out back with clean picnic tables under big umbrellas.   This will definitely be a must-stop for us on future Napa Valley visits for the great food and nice atmosphere.   Its also a good place to come if your wallet is hurting -- two people can feast for less than $30.   When we left around 1:30 the line was considerably shorter, so come at off-peak hours if you can&apos;t stand to wait.
 
 Listed in: Napa Valley 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Philip M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 6 friends 124 reviews 

 Philip M. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 6/23/2012 
Came here with coworkers after work at one of the hotel&apos;s downtown...

these are the best burgers ever. they are huge, juicy, tender and orgasmic.
Definitely get the garlic fries because Gott&apos;s is well known for their garlic fries.

right off the highway, you can&apos;t miss this place.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Golda R. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 77 friends 214 reviews 

 Golda R. 
 
Sunnyvale, CA
 6/10/2012 1 photo 
Had to try this place out based on an SF Gate article I read and also because it got 700 people on Yelp to review it.

I had the tuna melt and my husband had a burger and garlic fries. Everything tasted awesome. I have never had an open faced tuna melt with ahi as the tuna. It was fancy and yet down-right country to be eating on picnic benches.

The garlic fries are so good and the cheeseburger tasted amazing.  Next time I go back, I would love to try their shakes and ahi tacos.
 
 Listed in: Checking off the Bucket List , As seen on TV or published 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ingrid P. 
 
 12 friends 104 reviews 

 Ingrid P. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 6/11/2012 
So good, we had lunch here three days in a row.  Enough days for me to try all the fish tacos they have to offer.  The crispy raw ahi tacos are my favorite, although they&apos;re all quite good.

Le Boyf says it&apos;s the best $10 burger he&apos;s ever had.

Garlic fries:  out of this world.

I thought the white pistachio milkshake was the best milkshake I&apos;d ever had, until I tried the white pistachio malt.  THAT is the best milkshake I have ever had.

I love a good milkshake.

Other reviewers have suggested there&apos;s a long wait, but we got there just before noon on a friday, saturday, and sunday, and didn&apos;t have to wait in line at all. (When we walked by again later, there was indeed a long line -- but get there at 11.45 and avoid the crowd.)

The end to all roadside diners:  Taylor&apos;s Refresher.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ryan S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 2 friends 57 reviews 

 Ryan S. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 5/18/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Its a burger, in St. Helena

That may not sound like much but Taylor&apos;s Refresher (I cant really go on the new name, its how I&apos;ve known it for a long time) is really important.  After a week of drinking wine and really snooty, heavy, Frenchy food you need a break.

Because of that this place is on the agenda EVERY TIME we go to Napa.  Its simple stuff: burgers, fries and a shake.  Its probably just &quot;good&quot; if you compared it to any other premiumish burger joint but you cant because there arent any within miles upon miles.  Because of that, because you go there craving something as simple and salty as a burger and fries it might as well be a 5-Diamond resort.  The prices kind of remind you of a 5-Diamond resort

Youre gonna wait in a line, you just are.  You can get frustrated with it or you can realize that you have been making reservations and dealing with waits everywhere else you go in Napa, its just not so obvious.  The line moves pretty quickly though as its basically a burger stand where you order and then they call you up.

The back lawn is fantastic.  Each table has an umbrella (which comes in handy in the later parts of spring/summer) and plenty of space.  The people working there are nice and friendly despite the fact that they have to deal with people constantly asking &quot;where&apos;s my food.&quot;  It does take them a bit to get your order out the window but you have to realize this isnt McDonalds, that stuff isnt sitting back there under a warming lamp.  400 people ordered before you and they have to take care of them first.

Protip:  If you gotta tinkle they have (at least when I have been there) high-end port-a-johns across the parking lot.  The line for the main restroom can be as bad as the burger line.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Marisa R. 
 
 1 friend 11 reviews 

 Marisa R. 
 
Boston, MA
 5/20/2012 
You have to stop here at least once when you are visiting Napa. C&apos;mon, this place just screams &quot;Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives&quot;. Fieri has probably been to this place too since he is from Santa Rosa. Anyway, on summer&apos;s day with the cars on Hwy 116 whisking by and the wind in my hair, this would be a great location. Not so much when it is cold and rainy, which is what it was when I visited in March. The specialty burger of the day--an Asian inspired one--was intriguing, and especially needed after a day of wine tasting. The other burgers, however, seemed very run-of-the-mill. Nothing to write home about in any fashion. However, the garlic fries at Gott&apos;s were the best part of the meal. I wish I had the opportunity to try a milkshake, but alas I was too full from the food.

Not sure if I&apos;ll return to Gott&apos;s when I head back to Napa in the future. It may be time for another pitt stop locale. However, definitely worth a visit if it is your first time in Napa, you don&apos;t mind taking a 30 min break (wait time at Gott&apos;s was still long despite the rainy weather), and you want to try average hamburgers and above-average fries, go for it!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amy T. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 60 friends 71 reviews 

 Amy T. 
 
Davis, CA
 5/14/2012 2 photos 
Came by this drive-in when I was in Napa, there is a constant flow of customers, which was why it caught my eye. I order the jalapeno cheese burger here and a side order of garlic fries. I did enjoy the burger, but It was not worth what you were going to pay for it. I guess its within reasonable price range, since we were in napa valley. Their garlic fries are DELICIOUS! they leave a lasting impression and is definitely a great place to get them. I would also recommend their milk shakes! Its pricey but worth it! My friend order a strawberry milkshake and it was so delicious! its creamy and you can taste the strawberries! Thinking about makes me what some right now!!!

I would definitely go here if you are around the neighborhood! it is worth the wait!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Edgar M. 
 
 8 friends 3 reviews 

 Edgar M. 
 
SOMA, San Francisco, CA
 5/17/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Burgers good, nothing out of this world, but the garlic fries are great!
The $6.00 shakes are worth $3.00.
Great people working here!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brandon M. 
 
 300 friends 367 reviews 

 Brandon M. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 6/14/2012 
Because of 2 weeks of photo shoots in Calistoga, I&apos;ve been here many times because we usually finish late and I like food fast so I can go back to the hotel. They have the top ten burgers I&apos;ve ever had. Heard the tacos are great too. Have to say, the lemonade is rather weak.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Melyssa V. 
 
 60 friends 6 reviews 

 Melyssa V. 
 
Fresno, CA
 6/4/2012 
Breakfast tacos. AMAZING.
French toast was pretty delicious as well.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jen B. 
 
 3 friends 16 reviews 

 Jen B. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 5/7/2012 
After running a half marathon in Napa, my boyfriend and I planned to go to Gott&apos;s Roadside in St. Helena. We were starving, and this was a great place to solve that problem. Portion sizes are good and food is classic American burgers, fries and shakes - plus some interesting twists.

* I got: fish tacos and dulce de leche shake. The shake was really good (not overally sweet but a nice mix of ice cream and dulce de leche). The fish tacos were kind of underwhelming; instead of chunks of fish, there was 1 long strip of fish with each taco buried in the middle, which made it harder to get the fish part within each bite.

* Sweet potato fries with ranch sauce: yum; an interesting spice on top of these (or was it cheese?) made it so these didn&apos;t need ketchup.

* Boyfriend got the cheeseburger (default style is cooking meat medium well) with a vanilla malt, both which were delicious.

* Be prepared for a long line most parts of the day close to any meals; even at 11:20 on a Sunday, there was a 1/2 hour line -- but it was worth it!

* There is lots of seating in back with a bunch of picnic tables. This place is great for families with kids who need to run around (we saw a number of kids getting their energy out here).

I&apos;d definitely go back here again!

Also very convenient to the Clif Family Winery (which is where we went after having lunch here).
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Casey T. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 17 friends 67 reviews 

 Casey T. 
 
London
 UK 4/30/2012 
I have been in love with this place for years!

Raw tuna &quot;Poke&quot; crispy tacos are impressive.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Judy N. 
 
 22 friends 127 reviews 

 Judy N. 
 
Antioch, CA
 Updated - 6/16/2012 
This time around, the bf and I were just getting over from a severe case of food poisoning. So we thought this would be a good time to try out their salads.

Can I just say, SALADS--BOOOOOOOO!

What a huge disappointment!  I ordered the Chinese Chicken Salad and it was so mediocre. I&apos;ve come to expect great things from Gotts. Even if it&apos;s not to my particular taste, I expect creativity and just well-made food.  The CCS did not deliver.  It was $11 and tasted (and was sized)  like something that should have cost $5 in Safeway&apos;s pre-made fridge section.  I&apos;d much rather than a McD&apos;s salad.

The chicken in the Chinese Chicken Salad were small bits that completely lacked any flavor.  Which I found surprising because the chicken in their chicken club sandwiches we&apos;ve had in the past was stellar.  The crispy wontons also were not very flavorful and the rest of the salad was just bland lettuce with shredded cabbage, carrots, and possibly other similar veggies. The sauce might have redeemed the overall salad had it been good but it was just mediocre.  There was absolutely nothing special about this salad. I only ate a third and didn&apos;t even want to bother finishing the rest.  And the bf only managed to finish another third before he got sick of it, and we tossed the rest out.  2 stars.

The bf ordered the Chicken House Salad.  This looked almost exactly like a Caesar salad except no croutons and rather than caesar dressing, there was some half-assed vinaigrette.  This salad was better than the chinese chicken salad I had but not by much.  The chicken pieces on this one were slightly bigger than the ones on the chinese salad and they tasted better (ie. they actually had a taste) but they were so dry.

I don&apos;t understand the mediocrity of both the dressings on the 2 salads.  Gotts makes a killer special sauce for the hamburger (similar to Thousand Island) and a very good ranch (and I&apos;m not even a fan of ranch in general).  Why not use one of these as the dressing on the salad rather than the very boring, very lackluster concoctions they did use?

So Gott&apos;s salad, never again.  If you&apos;re going to opt for a salad, try the cobb or the caesar. We haven&apos;t tried either (and won&apos;t) but they&apos;ve got to be better than the 2 we did try.

On the drive back home, I opted for a Kids Meal. I was craving a burger but didn&apos;t feel that would be too smart to subject my tummy to a full-sized one so soon.  The Kids Meal comes with your choice of &quot;entree&quot;, small fries, and a small drink.  The burger was truly a &quot;kids&quot; size burger.  About the diameter of a slice of tomato (I know because the bf put a slice of tomato from his sandwich onto my burger and it fit perfectly).  And with nothing, absolutely nothing, on it.  But we asked for the special sauce, so it was all good.  The burger was small (by small, I mean TINY)--less than half the size of a regular burger maybe?) but was still delicious.

I opted for the sweet potato fries of course and portions on that were larger than expected.  And the lemonade came in a very very small cup and wasn&apos;t that great as far as lemonades go (quite watered down in fact), but at least it wasn&apos;t totally sucrosy and artificially flavored  like a lot of today&apos;s &quot;kids&quot; drinks. Overall, at around $8.50 it was a decent meal, with a little bit of everything.  I was still hungry after I finished it, but after waiting about 15 minutes, I felt full--though just barely.

Gott&apos;s has made some changes to their menu and the chicken club is no longer on it.  So the bf got the California Chicken sandwich instead.  Really, THIS is what everybody on yelp raves about?  It&apos;s all right, and the chicken is very well cooked, but it&apos;s not that special overall.  Is it the avocado that everybody gets so excited about? I notice avocado does that to people--but not to us.  Sorry, the chicken club kicked the california chicken&apos;s ass.  We thought the CA chicken would essentially be identical to the club except instead of bacon, there&apos;d be avocado.  But no, it really is a different sandwich.  The club oozed this special mayo that was sooooo good and really made the sandwich complete.  The CA chicken just had a bit of regular mayo.  It was an ok chicken sandwich but once you have their club, you really can&apos;t go back.  3 stars.  We&apos;ll have to see if we can request the club in the future even though it&apos;s off their menu.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
3 Previous Reviews: Show all» 

 5/27/2012 
Why are there not more raves about the tuna melt??

So BF and I are back on the road. I&apos;m already… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Marina V. 
 
 276 friends 94 reviews 

 Marina V. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 6/18/2012 
yummy, super quick, inexpensive and they serve wine!! :) The cheeseburger was great, the fries too. The outdoor seating is wonderful!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Dan A. 
 
 4 friends 38 reviews 

 Dan A. 
 
Vallejo, CA
 6/24/2012 1 Check-in Here 
3rd time here&amp;we&apos;re surrounded by Hollywood types... That&amp;62 bucks for decent ahi burgers, a bacon burger, fries&amp;2 drinks is a bit steep.   Of course thats to be expected in St Helena.  My seared ahi burger was good, just not fantastic, more natural flavored as opposed to being over-sauced.  Not a bad place to stop&amp;eat good ole American standards, but there&apos;s definitely better places for the food.  If you&apos;re out on the town to flaunt your style, this is your place...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ms. T. 
 
 2 friends 80 reviews 

 Ms. T. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 6/23/2012 
House smoked tri-tip sando and an espresso shake?  Hell yes, sign.me.up!!  Great little picnic table area on grass in the back.  Perfect on a beautiful day in Napa.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michelle W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 168 friends 374 reviews 

 Michelle W. 
 
Union City, CA
 4/16/2012 4 photos 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;ve never been a fan of burgers, but if all burger joints were like Gott&apos;s, I&apos;d be a lover for life. Everyone&apos;s raved about the ahi tuna (which is definitely next on my list), but I wanted to experience the main event for my first visit. The Texas burger was an instant attention grabber: jack cheese, avocado, salsa, mayo,&amp;jalapenos on a toasted homemade egg bun. Verdict?

Best burger I&apos;ve ever had.

I savored each bite of the scrumptious 1/3 lb Niman Ranch patty cooked to medium rare perfection, overflowing with the right amount of flavor and juiciness. Definitely request medium rare as opposed to their default medium well. I can&apos;t imagine getting the same taste or texture otherwise. And why aren&apos;t all egg buns made this way? Seriously, how good can a freakin egg bun be? I suppose this best kept secret is what keeps Gott&apos;s different from all the rest.

Don&apos;t miss out on the milkshakes. They even have seasonal flavors of shakes, soups, and burgers if you want a little adventure in your meal. The quality of food at this fast food joint can be easily mistaken for high end diner, crowded with drooling patrons ready to binge on one of Napa&apos;s greatest spots. It&apos;s a nice break from all the luxury and sophistication the wine country has to offer. Don&apos;t be surprised to run into a bum rush of people craving to gorge on the best of the best. Well worth the wait.

Not meant for the health-conscious with faint appetite.
 
 Listed in: Love At First Bite! 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Andrew J. 
 
 0 friends 21 reviews 

 Andrew J. 
 
Calgary, AB
 Canada 6/25/2012 3 photos 
We ordered a cheeseburger, chili cheese fries, Onion rings and fish tacos and it was all delicious!

They even allowed us to bring wine on the grounds which we had with it. They have a great setup and very comfy picnic tables...A must stop.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from T L. 
 
 0 friends 1 review 

 T L. 
 
Winters, CA
 6/24/2012 3 photos 
Get there early, good fresh burgers.  Then enjoy the great Sonoma area.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shirley N. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 41 friends 503 reviews 

 Shirley N. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 4/7/2012 1 Check-in Here 
After spending our day eating fried chicken at Addendum and wine tasting at Castello di Amorosa, it called for French fries and root beer floats in the afternoon.

The line was very short.  We ordered at the window and gave our name.  Find one of many available picnic tables.  Your name will be called twice - once for food and once again for your milkshake or float.

Both the fries and the root beer floats hit the spot. Then we drove home.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Julie P. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 167 friends 161 reviews 

 Julie P. 
 
Oklahoma City, OK
 3/25/2012 
Now there&apos;s probably a line; in my opinion that&apos;s usually a clue you&apos;re on to something! I love this little stand. There&apos;s not much I can say that hasn&apos;t already be said. The burgers, of course, are legendary, and for good reason. The fries are fantastic and the shakes superb, but for me the standout here is the service. I&apos;ve never been to a fast food place with such a contentious staff. No surprise that a St. Helena burger stand has a better team than certain white tablecloth restaurants, but it&apos;s still worth a shout out. I just appreciate them verifying your order, getting it right, and just generally being agreeable.

The picnic areas are tops in my book, and enjoying a meal here is a great way to save some money during your Napa extravaganza.
 
 Listed in: St. Helena, Napa Valley 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amit P. 
 
 15 friends 33 reviews 

 Amit P. 
 
Seattle, WA
 5/28/2012 
For a burger place, I&apos;m surprised Gott&apos;s cannot get the meat cooked per specification. Had to ask them to recook the burger meat after the kids didn&apos;t get it right the first time. Waited for another 15 minutes while they got it right.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Veronica P. 
 
 2 friends 4 reviews 

 Veronica P. 
 
San Rafael, CA
 6/12/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Driven by this place a couple of times and it has always been busy so we finally had to stop, Had the Spicy chicken, fries and the espresso bean shake...yum!! The seating area makes you feel like your on a picnic.  Will definitely stop here next time we are in the area!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from tess e. 
 
 10 friends 20 reviews 

 tess e. 
 
Berkeley, CA
 3/12/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I have made an effort to stop here every trip through the wine country and it has yet to disappoint.

Classic vibe, the kind of place I would have frequented in any era.

Tomato soup is great; garlic fries, yes please; milkshakes, I&apos;ll have banana.

You will probably have to wait a bit for your food, it will be incredibly painful to watch everyone else enjoying theirs while you can smell what the kitchen is cooking. Try not to get too grumpy.

(Note: This place *is* a little shmancy (read: pricier than you expect), and it probably would have gotten 4 stars if I wasn&apos;t over the moon for the design/set up... and possibly drunk on wine tastings)
 
 Listed in: Wine not mix it up? What to do… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (3) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Sabrina b. 
 
 47 friends 264 reviews 

 Sabrina b. 
 
Reno, NV
 Updated - 4/19/2012 2 photos 1 Check-in Here 
I dined here a few years back under it&apos;s previous name / ownership.

Quality is the same, but not totally perfect during the lunch rush.

Burgers were a tad charged on the outside. We went with a traditional cheeseburger and a bacon cheeseburger... no pickles. It&apos;s been years since I dined here so a heads up when I hold the pickles to remind me their &apos;special sauce&apos; is 1000 Island and has pickles would have been nice. I&apos;m not a pickle hater so I overcame the pickles in the sauce but def. would have preferred a heads up.

Garlic fries - sizeable portion. A bit on the oily side.

Fries - again, sizable portion. These are not oily at all. I prefer garlic fries usually but I think the standard fries are the way to go.

Diet coke with cherry - I don&apos;t know why cherry syrup makes it so much more delicious than your standard Diet cherry Coke but mmmm mmmm.

Chocolate milkshake - thick and delicious. Turns into a runny mess during a warm day but perfect if you can suck it down fast!

This will still be a must stop on our next trip I will just ask for less char on the burgers and stick to the standard fries.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
1 Previous Review: Show all» 

 5/31/2010 
This is a great stop when entertaining out-of-towners in Napa Valley. It&apos;s touristy and slightly… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Laura L. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 105 friends 185 reviews 

 Laura L. 
 
Phoenix, AZ
 3/28/2012 2 photos 1 Check-in Here 
We literally pulled off the road into the parking lot at warp speed after I mentioned the possibility of a milkshake to DH.

We must have pulled in at JUST the right time.  We only had one or two groups of people in front of us, but about 40 people got in line while we were waiting to order.

Gott&apos;s is definitely not CHEAP when it comes to milkshakes and ice cream, either.  At $5.99 for a black and white milkshake, it is a little pricey.  But the milkshake was good - no complaints here.  My grandma got a scoop of strawberry ice cream which she raved about.  It was a bargain at $2.99.

The hamburger DH ordered was delicious.  He inhaled it 4.5 seconds after offering me a bite.  I definitely recommend you get a hamburger here.  At only $6.99 for a hamburger, you&apos;re getting a great deal.

But the best thing I put into my mouth at Gott&apos;s was the garlic fries.  They were THE best garlic fries I have EVER had.  They were also a beautiful shade of parsley green.

Definitely stop at Gott&apos;s.  I know I will be back the next time I am in Wine Country.  Of course, next time we&apos;ll pull in the parking lot a wee bit slower.  ;)
 
 Listed in: Tour of Napa Valley 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from David C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 328 friends 433 reviews 

 David C. 
 
Berkeley, CA
 2/21/2012 1 photo 
I&apos;ll start by saying in terms of food, the food is definitely a solid four stars.  The price is what drops it down to three stars.  We were in the area and some local people told us we should try Gott&apos;s so we did.

Gott&apos;s is your very traditional American hamburger.  As far as I can tell, they use only the freshest ingredients.  I was really pleased with their egg buns and &apos;special&apos; sauce that rivals In-and-Out.  The restaurant is set up like a diner, and you order up front and go to get your own food when its ready.  I had a bacon cheeseburger and garlic fries.  The burger, like I said, was cooked perfectly (a bit pink in the center).  The garlic fries tasted heavenly, but were a little too greasy for my liking (I think they use extra grease on their garlic fries to get the garlic to stick to the fries).  I enjoyed my burger, but at the same time, I couldn&apos;t help but think that I could have gotten almost identical quality and size at In-and-Out or Five Guys for half the price!

PROTIP:  TRY THE AHI TUNA BURGER.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from ryan t. 
 
 80 friends 47 reviews 

 ryan t. 
 
San Jose, CA
 2/19/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Don&apos;t you just love spontaneity?? Spontaneous things lead to discoveries of hidden gems and treasures.. or the discovery of Penicillin..! So my friends and I were double dating in Napa and getting our wine tasting on and we drove by this place called Gott&apos;s Roadside, formally known as Taylor&apos;s Refresher. It was PACKED when we drove by it on our way into Napa and St. Helena, so we figured it must be good since it also looked like one of those places you see on Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives!

After our journey through the vineyards, we were dying of hunger and remembered Gotts! So we pulled in and decided to peep it out! My girlfriend and I shared the Wisconsin burger, the garlic fries and the White Pistachio milk shake! It... was... to... die... for.... The burger doesn&apos;t come in an original patty bun. It comes on like, toasted sandwich loaves and it was... OH MY GOD.. orgasmic. The barbeque sauce was dripping down my hands, I felt like I was on a commercial for Carl&apos;s Jr. or something.. or for Gott&apos;s in this case! I had the opportunity to steal some sweet potato fries from my friends and they were just as delicious as the garlic fries! If you&apos;re in Napa or St. Helena, getting your wine on and find yourself hungry, check this place out! CHEERS
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from H M. 
 
 2 friends 109 reviews 

 H M. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 4/11/2012 
It&apos;s pretty pricey for a roadside joint. That&apos;s the only thing keeping it from a solid 5.

I was impressed though. I got the tuna melt. Good food - not greasy, nor fast foodish at all.

I was even MORE impressed with the young lady who enthusiastically took our order. As we were finishing our meal, she, of her own volition, came by and offered to refill my drink mere MINUTES before they closed. (You know who you are, love. Cute, smiley girl with the Jennifer Garner dimples.) Now that&apos;s service. Hope they give you a raise. :))
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from NewTo S. 
 
 5 friends 62 reviews 

 NewTo S. 
 
San Jose, CA
 5/28/2012 
The food here is okay, but by no means phenomenal. In addition to the burgers, I&apos;ve tried the fish tacos (not bad), a Po&apos; Boy BBQ chicken sandwich (way too salty for my taste), and shrimp tacos (just alright), and chili cheese fries (I&apos;ve had better). For me, the appeal of this place is that it is simple, unassuming, reasonably priced, quick, and easily accessible in an area full of upitty wine country restaurants that require advance reservations. I recommend if you are craving a so-so diner burger or soakage, but it&apos;s not worth a trip out of your way.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Erika C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 134 friends 850 reviews 

 Erika C. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 3/8/2012 
I really wanna four star &apos;em, but Gott&apos;s didn&apos;t quite get it.

It&apos;s a cute and popular roadside stop for Napa.  My problem is not them, it&apos;s me.  And a little bit them.

Burgers are above average, but for the price range, I&apos;ve had much better burgers.  The shakes don&apos;t quite make the cut.  The fries are pretty good.  But I will never have a craving for Gott&apos;s.

Be prepared to dine with flies.  A lot of them.  Because you&apos;re outdoors.  I like the outdoors as much as the next REI customer, but not when I suddenly become a lawn aerator in heels.  And especially not with flies abuzz.
 
 Listed in: Best Burgers 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 1 to 40 of 741 ( 39 Filtered )

 |   
 Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... 
 Write a Review What&apos;s This? 
About This Business
 Provided by business 
Specialties
 
Gott&apos;s family-run kitchen serves up mighty fine breakfast, lunch and dinner eats that draw people from miles around. Artisanal and fresh ingredients, including those harvested from our St. Helena garden, transform traditional recipes into mouthwatering classics. And for those who like surprises, our ever changing menu specials promise a refreshingly new taste at every visit. Carefully selected beers and wines make eating this good even better. And in keeping with our&quot;green is good&quot;philosophy, Gott&apos;s uses recyclable, renewable, or compostable packaging whenever possible. So bring your family, bring your friends, and bring your appetite. We&apos;ll make it worth your while.

Serving up delicious breakfast daily from 7:00am-11:00am, offering egg sandwiches made with thick-cut sourdough and cage-free eggs. Breakfast tacos, yogurt parfaits, hashbrowns, french toast and locally roasted coffee.
 Flag as inappropriate View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 Gott&apos;s Roadside  575 reviews &quot;And their sweet potato fries make my mouth water.&quot; Cindy&apos;s Backstreet Kitchen  399 reviews &quot;I can&apos;t wait to come back for the campfire pie.&quot; Giugni W F&amp;Son Grocery Co  103 reviews &quot;Honey-smoked turkey with Tillamook cheddar is my favorite.&quot; Cook  153 reviews &quot;Gnocchi in gorgonzola cream sauce- Very good.&quot; Market  227 reviews &quot;Will definitely come back for the butterscotch pudding.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 Napa Valley 
Reviews from our trip over Memorial Day weekend 2012.
 Good for Groups 
Places to go if you are dining with 6 or more friends.
 As seen on TV 
Whether I seen it on the food nework or cooking channel or even Best of the bay... If any featured restaurants…
 You Lika The Wine? 
When in Napa/Sonoma (+ a couple in Livermore for fun) stop in at these places. You won&apos;t be disappointed.
 St. Helena, Napa Valley 
You guys know I love Napa- I&apos;ve finally reviewed some of my faves and put them in a list!
 As seen on TV or published 
Food Network, Man Vs. Food, Movies, magazine reviews, cnn, NY Times, etc.
 Napa Valley Day Trip 2010 
First Napa trip! It was just a day trip, but these are all the places I visited - lots of great wine and food!…
 Hamburgers and Fries 
You don&apos;t like burgers and fries!?  Why do you hate America?
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Taylors Refresher St. Helena Taylor&apos;S Automatic Refresher St. Helena Hamburger St. Helena 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 St Helena Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
