<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008904" url="http://www.gofundme.com/showthelove" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="1" score="0.0012043553918053833" bingtitle="Sarabeth Nordstrom &amp; Erin Johnston Medical Fund by Jordan Powell ..." webtitle="Sarabeth Nordstrom&amp;Erin Johnston Medical Fund by Jordan Powell - GoFundMe">
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>... laws On Feburary 11, 2012 Sarah Nordstrom and Erin Johnston were at a fast food restaurant ... insurance, and neither of the girls can afford the growing medical bills.</description>
	<body>
		The easy way to raise money online .
 Donate Sign Up Help   
Sarabeth Nordstrom&amp;Erin Johnston Medic...
   Raised: $600.00 Goal: $3,000.00       
Created by

Jordan Rudolph

206 Friends
 Contact Embed     
http://www.change.org/petitions/amend-nc-hate-crime-laws On Feburary 11, 2012 Sarah Nordstrom and Erin Johnston 
were at a fast food restaurant where they wer... more 
         
Updated posted by Jordan Rudolph 4 months ago

We&apos;ve almost reached 20% of the...
 
We&apos;ve almost reached 20% of the goal! Thanks again for your support! Both Erin and Sarabeth are forever grateful for your help!
     
Updated posted by Jordan Rudolph 4 months ago

I&apos;m completely in awe by the...
 
I&apos;m completely in awe by the amount of support we&apos;ve received around the world. Thank you everyone for helping out! Every little bit helps.
           
Created by Jordan Rudolph on February 27, 2012
   BOONE, NC Medical, Illness&amp;Healing 
About This Page
 

http://www.change.org/petitions/amend-nc-hate-crime-laws

On Feburary 11, 2012 Sarah Nordstrom and Erin Johnston 
were at a fast food restaurant where they were verbally harassed by one 
male and two females based on the perception of their sexual 
orientation. The three individuals followed them home where the male 
committed physical assault by punching Nordstrom repeatedly in the face.
 Johnston had turned away to call the police when the man attacked her 
from behind. He knocked her to the ground and repeatedly kicked and 
stomped her face and body. Nordstrom had extensive injuries including a 
broken eye socket, a broken nasal cavity, and a severely broken 
cheekbone. Johnston’s injuries included two fractured ribs, a torn 
meniscus on the left side of the jaw as well as bleeding in the joint, 
and torn cartilage in the nose. Nordstrom and Johnston did not know 
these people, had never heard of them, talked to them, etc., before this
 event.

Taking all of this into account, this assault occurred based 
solely on their perceived sexual orientation. This attack has shaken the community of Boone and Appalachian State University and has brought the issue of hate crimes to attention in North Carolina.
 
Sarabeth doesn&apos;t have health insurance, and neither of the girls can afford the growing medical bills. They would greatly appreciate any funds sent their way to assist them during this time. *All money raised will go towards Sarabeth and Erin&apos;s medical expenses. Any money left over will go to a charity of their choosing. 

Thanks so much!   
 Have Questions? Contact the Organizer:
 Contact     1 Comment 
Use Facebook to Leave a Comment

 Nothing gets posted to your wall. Only your Facebook name&amp;photo are used.
 Type your comment here... Post Comment 
by 
 
Sending out positive thoughts
for your fund raising :)! I am
seeking help for my own fund
raising, against my sexual
abuser. Yes I can win this
fight!!. 
gofundme.com/nomoreabused Any
penny is worth it. Thanks for
the support.

posted by Maxime Ano 16 days ago
 1 - 1 of 1 Comment   
Recent Donations (30)
 
$20.00

Chris Glatz

2 months ago
     
Hope you guys are all healed
up, or at least getting better
quickly! Much love from
D-town.
   
$15.00

Anonymous

3 months ago
   
$25.00

Barbara McKenzie

3 months ago
     
I hope Erin and Sarabeth
recovery quickly and are able
to heal deeply. Love to you
both.
   
$5.00

Adam

4 months ago
     
Hey girls! I met you over the
weekend at Mystery Hill.
Remember to hold your heads up
and don&apos;t let ANYONE break
your spirit. Remember, it DOES
get better!
   
$50.00

Anonymous

4 months ago
   
$5.00

Amiris

4 months ago
     
(( hug )) Stay strong in
knowing that a wonderful
caring community supports both
of y&apos;all&lt;3
   
$15.00

Beth Tucker

4 months ago
     
You are both strong,
wonderful, and inspiring
individuals. Myself and
community, although we cannot
change the circumstances, will
do our best to make whatever
improvements we can.
   
$50.00

Anonymous

4 months ago
   
$10.00

Sam Poler

4 months ago
     
We support and love you!
   
$5.00

Anonymous

4 months ago
   
 1-10 of 30 donations
 Next       
Bring your fundraising ideas to life with an online donation website from GoFundMe!
     
 “GoFundMe allows users to create their online donation page, share it with friends and family through Facebook, Twitter and email, and begin collecting money online.” 
 Be a Fan! Follow Us SIGN UP TOUR QUESTIONS CONTACT   What is GoFundMe? 
Launched on May 10, 2010, GoFundMe is a do-it-yourself online fundraising service that has helped thousands of people raise millions of dollars in online donations for the fundraising ideas that matter to them most. GoFundMe allows regular people to accomplish extraordinary things with easy-to-use personal donation websites . From exciting life events like weddings&amp;graduations to challenging circumstances like accidents&amp;illnesses, the GoFundMe fundraising software remains one of the best ways to raise money online.
 Getting Started Take the Tour! Fundraising Ideas Common Questions Sign Up Now &gt;&gt;   Yes, it really works! View Live Examples GoFundme Reviews&amp;Press Real Success Stories Ask Us a Question   Explore the Site Online Fundraising Tools Search&amp;Donate Online Online Donation Blog Partners&amp;Affiliates   Popular Articles How to Fundraise Fundraising Ideas Honeymoon Registry Online Donation Widget       ©2010-2012 GoFundMe 
Send Message To

Jordan Rudolph

206 Friends
     Your Name   Your Email   Message Type your message...     Enter Letters:         
Send Message To

Jordan Rudolph

206 Friends
   Thank You. Your message has been sent to the organizer. Return to Page         Get the Widget   Display this donation page on other websites and blogs. How it Works   GoFundMe charity fundraising is powered by FirstGiving.
	</body>
</document>
