<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008245" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/advantages-cash-drawer-opening-cash-management-19163.html" time="2012-07-13-01:44" support="1" score="0.0016284297619636107" bingtitle="What Are the Advantages of a Cash Drawer Opening for Cash ..." webtitle="What Are the Advantages of a Cash Drawer Opening for Cash Management | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="112"/>
	<description>These employees collect cash from customers, pay ... management safeguards the cash handled by the cashiers. ... The Advantages of Opening a Fast-Food Restaurant in Rural Places</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Running a Business | Money&amp;Debt | Managing Employees | Finances&amp;Taxes | Accounting&amp;Bookkeeping | Setting Up a New Business | Business Models&amp;Organizational Structure | Types of Businesses to Start | More» 
 
 » Business Communications&amp;Etiquette » Human Resources » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Advertising&amp;Marketing » Business&amp;Workplace Regulations » Business Technology&amp;Customer Support 
 
 Small Business » Managing Employees » Managers » What Are the Advantages of a Cash Drawer Opening for Cash Management 
 
What Are the Advantages of a Cash Drawer Opening for Cash Management
 by Kathy Adams McIntosh, Demand Media 

 
Companies invest in a variety of internal control measures to safeguard the company assets and ensure that financial reporting is accurate. Cash represents the most liquid owned by the company and needs the most reliable controls in place. Company management reviews all processes that involve cash handling and identifies the potential risks with those processes. One internal control used with cash handling involves the cash drawer opening. Several advantages exist for companies who control the process of opening the cash drawer.
 
Cash Management

Cash management involves knowing what level of cash the company holds in financial institutions and onsite. Companies who work directly with customers, such as cashiers, employ onsite cash management techniques. These employees collect cash from customers, pay cash to customers and maintain a level of cash on hand. Onsite cash management safeguards the cash handled by the cashiers.
 
Cash Drawer

The opening of the cash drawer provides a fundamental safeguard for onsite cash. The cashier keeps all the cash she&apos;s responsible for in the drawer. The company implements specific controls on the cash drawer. These include requiring a password to open the cash drawer or limiting the cash drawer opening to transactions that require cash handling.
 
Employee Accountability

One advantage of controlling the opening of a cash drawer involves knowing which employee to hold accountable. This process limits access of who can open the cash drawer. The company assigns each cash drawer to a specific employee. This employee enters a password each time he opens the drawer. Others cannot open the drawer. This holds the employee accountable for all transactions that involve money from the cash drawer.
 
Theft Reduction

Another advantage of controlling the cash drawer opening considers the ability to reduce theft. In stores and restaurants, cash drawers sometimes remain unattended. This leaves non-employees and potential thieves access to the cash drawer. When the company implements controls surrounding opening the cash drawer, it limits the ability for potential thieves to access the cash. This reduces the company&apos;s risk of being robbed.
 
References

 Baldwin&amp;Associates, P.C.: Cash Internal Control College of San Mateo: Accounting 121 Accounting Financial&amp;Tax: Effective Internal Control for Small Medium Businesses UC San Diego: Internal Control Practices -- Cash Baldwin&amp;Associates, P.C.: Cash Internal Control 
 
About the Author

Kathy Adams McIntosh started writing professionally in 2001. She has been published in&quot;Cup of Comfort,&quot;&quot;Community Connection&quot;and&quot;Wisconsin Christian News.&quot;Adams McIntosh belongs to the Fearless Freelancers and the Broadway Writers Guild. She earned her Master of Business Administration from the University of Wisconsin.
 
More Articles

 
The Advantages of the Direct Method of Cash Flow
 
The Advantages of Management Accounting
 
The Advantages of Opening a Fast-Food Restaurant in Rural Places
 
The Advantages of Opening a Store in a Busy Area
 
 
People Also Viewed

 Management Advantages of Small Business What Are the Advantages of Opening a Small Business? How to Increase Sales Volume on Cash Flow Advantages and Disadvantages of Opening a Production Facility in a Foreign Country The Advantages of Contracts in Project Management Cash Flow Accounting Advantages 
 
Related Topics

 Managing Employees How to Manage Restaurant Employees How to Manage Introverted Employees How to Manage Telework Employees How to Manage Employees With Different Levels of Stress 
 
 
The Web&apos;s 6 Most Influential Tech Bloggers
 
America&apos;s 9 Most Tech-Friendly Cities
 
Phone Pas: 9 Places You Should Pocket Your Cell Phone
 
10 Highest Valued Tech Companies
 
9 Gadgets You Can&apos;t Live Without
 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
