<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008603" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g37209-d103676-r8245145-Indianapolis_Zoo-Indianapolis_Indiana.html" time="2012-07-13-02:03" support="3" score="0.001538069681303127" bingtitle="Indy Zoo will not take long to see - Review of Indianapolis Zoo ..." webtitle="Indy Zoo will not take long to see - Review of Indianapolis Zoo, Indianapolis, IN - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="001206" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>... and go to a nearby fast food restaurant - as long as you have your hand stamped on the way out and keep your parking receipt, you ... source for airline seats ...</description>
	<body>
		Indianapolis Zoo reviews
 
 Home Indianapolis 
 Indianapolis Tourism Indianapolis Hotels Indianapolis Vacation Rentals Flights to Indianapolis Indianapolis Restaurants Things to Do in Indianapolis Indianapolis Travel Forum Indianapolis Photos Indianapolis Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Indiana (IN) &gt; Indianapolis &gt; Indianapolis - Things to Do &gt; Indianapolis Zoo 
 
 Back to Indianapolis Zoo 
Indianapolis Zoo: Traveler Reviews
 1200 W. Washington Street , Indianapolis , IN 46222 317 630-2001 Website 102 visitor photos Ranked #20 of 71 attractions in Indianapolis 260 Reviews Type: Zoos Activities: Viewing wildlife, Leisure education Traveler Description: The Indianapolis Zoo dares you to touch a shark or plunge even deeper into the animal world with a one-of-a-kind Dolphin pavilion. The shark touch... more » Useful Information: Activities for older children, Activities for young children Update attraction details Write a Review 
260 reviews from our community
 Visitor rating 
 Excellent 104 Very good 96 Average 48 Poor 7 Terrible 5 
 260 reviews sorted by Date Rating Batboy46 Batavia, ohio Reviewer 5 reviews Reviews in 3 cities 3 helpful votes “Indy Zoo will not take long to see” Reviewed July 27, 2007 2 people found this review helpful 
Small place, not much to look at, grounds sort of run down. The train ride is a waste of $2.25 unless you want to see the outside of service buildings and ride next to roads. Exhibits are small and mostly ordinary except for the Kodiak and Polar bears. The Dolphin show is short, maybe 15 minutes long. The dolphin viewing dome ain&apos;t a big deal. The shark touch tank is the nation&apos;s largest, for what that is worth.

 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask Batboy46 about Indianapolis Zoo This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. busymom2girls Southwest Michigan 2 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 15 helpful votes “We LOVE the Indy Zoo” Reviewed July 14, 2007 4 people found this review helpful 
We just had another FANTASTIC visit to the Indianapolis Zoo. We live about 3 hours away, but always try to make this an annual trip. Our girls - 8&amp;6 - LOVE the dolphin show. This summer we also took our niece - 10. They all were very excited to actually touch a shark in the new aquarium! They loved seeing all of the animals - we went early and got to see all of them out and doing something!

After seeing all of the animals, the girls had a ton of fun in the Enchanted Mill - bring a change of clothes for the kids. - This is NO EXTRA charge.

My husband and I love how extremely clean the zoo is and traffic really isn&apos;t that bad!

 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask busymom2girls about Indianapolis Zoo This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. mygalsal Louisville, Kentucky 1 review 3 helpful votes “A Sad Reminder that Zoos are for visitors, not animals.” Reviewed March 28, 2007 3 people found this review helpful 
My daughter and I visited the Zoo in March 2007 and the grounds were understandably still messy with fall/winter leaf debris and many of the exhibits in a state of disrepair or closed. I wish I could say that those were the only negatives that day, but far from it. The roomy Deserts pavilion housed an impressive display of Beardies, lizards and tortoises who appeared quite content. The adjoining snake room, however, housed huge snakes in the smallest of lucite/glass display boxes containing mostly ornamental trinkets and not remotely resembling a natural habitat. The dolphin exhibit and show were excellent, but sadly, the dolphins appear to have it the best in this zoo. Though I recognized immediately that many of the animal enclosures were too small and cramped, my 13 year old was the first to point it out, which speaks volumes. The impact of this was seen the most with regard to the Kodiak bear, polar bear, lion, pig, burro and wild dog exhibits. The animals were clearly depressed and their enclosures far less than adequate. The indoor enclosure area that housed the pigs, burros and Flemish giant rabbits was perhaps the saddest of all. The 8&apos; x 8&apos; pens that housed the pigs and burros were designed with solid concrete floors and nothing remotely resembling a natural existence for these animals except a minimal amount of hay in the corner for resting. I found myself in need of a reminder at this point that these animals were in a zoo and not waiting to be slaughtered. The connecting outdoor area was similarly sparse, again with a concrete&quot;roaming&quot;area that was quite depressing. These animals were clearly living meal to meal with no other quality to their existence. It is difficult to imagine that the size and design of the Kodiak bear enclosure would pass any zoologic standards for these magnificent creatures. Likewise, the polar bear exhibit was too small and lacked the necessary swimming and playing areas that Polar bears thrive on. The wild dog exhibit sign clearly explains the need of wild dogs for a large space in which to roam in order to survive, yet their enclosure was barely larger than the suburban back yard that typically houses their domestic ancestors. Though the zoo animals were alive and appeared well-fed, those were nearly the only positives that we witnessed that day. As we left the zoo my heart was sick over the living quarters of some of these magnificent animals and I found myself wanting to run back and free most of them. Though I&apos;m sure they are well cared for from a nutrition and health standpoint, is there really a point to this unless they are also emotionally content and living in conditions that closely resemble their natural habitats? Obviously, this zoo with its limited space and close proximity to downtown is in dire need of expansion with no apparent room to grow and the animals are clearly suffering as a result. Though I would like to think that the money we paid for admission was going to help rectify this situation, one has to wonder if it is indeed even rectifiable at its current location.

 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask mygalsal about Indianapolis Zoo This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. A TripAdvisor Member Champaign, IL 1 review 4 helpful votes “Fun, nice day --- (even with a teenager!)” Reviewed March 20, 2006 4 people found this review helpful 
We had a nice time. There were some exhibits closed, but if you look on the website it did tell you that.
Don&apos;t take the train ride - doesn&apos;t show anything you can&apos;t walk around and see - should be free.
Dolphin show was great - it is free, we saw 2 shows - enjoyed it very much, go downstairs at the dolphin show and see them swimming around ! Very cool. Penguins and other kritters in that hall very nice - we had a nice day - clean, etc. would recommend.

 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. A TripAdvisor Member Indianapolis, Indiana 1 review 24 helpful votes “We love it - and have some tips to share!” Reviewed January 19, 2006 24 people found this review helpful 
We love the Indianapolis Zoo! The animals are housed in nice exhibits and are very well cared for. There are many interactive exhibits for children, as well as an absolutely wonderful dolphin exhibit which allows you to literally walk beneath the middle of the pool as the dolphins swim over and around you. There are dolphin shows, educational chats with the keepers, and plenty of other activities to keep the whole family happy.

The only major drawback is the cost. Unlike most other zoos, the Indianapolis Zoo is privately owned, and receives no funding from taxpayer money. Therefore, they charge relatively high admission fees (on par with museums and similar institutions) to cover the costs of caring for the animals and grounds and paying the employees. The same is true for the amusement park rides and concessions - they help cover the zoo&apos;s operating costs, and are expensive as a result.

Our advice is to be prepared before you go, and do some planning ahead of time. We recommend the following:

Call the zoo the day before your trip to find out about the current cost of admission (it varies with the season), parking fees, operating hours (also vary with the season), dolphin show times, etc.

Also check the weather forecast - the zoo does not issue rain checks or refunds due to weather.

Plan to arrive early in the day, so you can get the most out of your visit. Not only will you get more for your money, but you (and your family) will have a much better time if you aren&apos;t feeling rushed.

Bring your own strollers for the little ones. The rental strollers are cute, but not worth the money. There are also wheelchairs and a limited number of electric scooters available for those with mobility needs.

You may wish to avoid the incredibly high cost of food and drinks by bringing your own food in a cooler. You can&apos;t bring the cooler into the zoo, but there are picnic tables just outside the admission area where you can eat, although on busy days they will be packed. Another option is to actually leave the premises for lunch and go to a nearby fast food restaurant - as long as you have your hand stamped on the way out and keep your parking receipt, you&apos;ll be able to get back in. If you still choose to eat at the zoo, check out the Cafe Flora at the White River Gardens - you&apos;ll get better quality food for the money.

Finally, if you live anywhere near Indianapolis, consider purchasing an annual membership. Members don&apos;t receive any discounts on most concessions, but you and your family can at least get free admission and parking, and depending upon the type of membership, you may be able to bring additional guests in on your card. Be sure to ask, though, about exactly who is and is not covered on the membership - they are rather strict about this, and will ask for photo ID at the membership entrance to ensure that only valid members are getting in free.

In spite of the cost issue, the zoo is otherwise fantastic and you should have a fabulous time if you keep the above in mind. Hope this was helpful!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 248-252 of 260 reviews « 1 ... 50 51 52 53 » 
Travelers who viewed Indianapolis Zoo also viewed
	</body>
</document>
