<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008510" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Designing-A-Restaurant&amp;id=257336" time="2012-07-13-01:58" support="4" score="0.0028001514941253846" bingtitle="Designing A Restaurant - EzineArticles Submission - Submit Your ..." webtitle="Designing A Restaurant">
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001031" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>After the type of food and service are identified, the next step is to hire ... Food and Drink Bill McRea</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Food and Drink Bill McRea 
 Platinum Author |   185 Articles 
 Joined: November 22, 2005 Was this article helpful? 1 1 1 
Designing A Restaurant

 By Bill McRea 
 
A good design and layout plan are necessary for having a good restaurant. Many entrepreneurs would say that their dream business will be to own their own restaurants. Restaurants are good businesses which can be very fulfilling. The mere fact that people go to your restaurant to eat is already something to cherish. It&apos;s like having people inside your house every once in a while craving for your home-baked goodies.

A successful restaurant will need a good design and layout plan. Design and layout plans are dependent on different factors which will come and influence the final decisions later on. In fact, the output of the layout plans can definitely affect the success of the restaurants. People often go to a new restaurant and they think to themselves &quot;they should have put that plant elsewhere, it obstructs the good view&quot; or &quot;I wish they hadn&apos;t put too much light in here.&quot; These are certain small things which can really add up and can end up influencing the customers to go to the other side of the street where another restaurant is calling their tummies.

After the type of food and service are identified, the next step is to hire consultants regarding the design of the restaurant. These are some of the things that you need to take into consideration when considering different floor and layout plans for the restaurant.

-Density of customers

The layout plan should be based mostly on the comfort that the people who will eat will be getting. Even fast food restaurants consider the density of people, especially in peak hours, even though it may seem that these restaurants become too crowded during lunch time. For formal dining restaurants which cater to the upper class, it maybe wise to provide more space between the tables since these restaurants don&apos;t really rely on the number of people per day. Their revenues depend on the pricing of the food items. There would be more provision for more eye candies such as furniture and art works.

-Style of service

The layout and floor plans should also be based on the type of service that the restaurant will give. Fast food restaurants and self-service restaurants would need less distance between the tables since the food won&apos;t be served there. For other restaurants which provide table service, the space between the tables is very important so as to prevent too much clutter from happening in a specific end of the restaurant.

-Type of building

The layout plan is restricted by the type of structure where the restaurant will be built. You should be able to take into consideration all the different curves and the minor details in the structure before proceeding.

-Lighting

Proper lighting is very important for every restaurant. The lighting should be able to match the mood and the type of service of the restaurant. A relaxed atmosphere can be complemented by bright lighting while serene and serious moods can be accompanied by subtler shades.

Designing the restaurant will be divided into two important parts: the dining area and the production area. The dining area is important because this is the essence of the structure of the restaurant. The people should be comfortable in eating in the restaurant and this will be determined as early as the designing phase. Studies have revealed that 50 percent of the time, people come in restaurants as pairs, 30 percent come alone while the remaining 20 percent usually come in groups.

The production area is the second major part of any restaurant. The main thing about the production area should be efficiency. The organization of the kitchen will determine the speed by which the food can be cooked and served. The production area design should take into consideration other things like space for storage, food preparation, baking, cooking, trash storage, production aisles, employee facilities and other such matters.

In hiring design consultants, the restaurant owner should always remember to put a clause of confidentiality in the contract. This is to prevent the consultants from leaking certain parts of the design to other people, especially to the competitors. This can be as simple as a single-line clause which states that everything regarding the design will be owned by the client.

These are some useful things to remember in designing. The most important thing to remember in designing a restaurant is to keep in mind the people who will be eating at the restaurant for they will be the ultimate lever of its success or failure.
 
Bill McRea is the publisher of Knowninfo a premium collection of information wesites like our huge reference on starting a restaurant business [http://restaurant.knowninfo.com/] and great eBooks like How to Start A Successful Restaurant Business . Visit our site daily for updated information, and unique products.
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Bill_McRea 
 Did you find this article helpful? 1 1 1 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Food and Drink 
 Bill McRea 
 Email Address: Subscribe Food and Drink Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Successful Website Design For Restaurants - Top 5 Features Designing Your Restaurant - Important Considerations How to Design a Restaurant Menu Designing a Restaurant to Encourage Efficiency and a Large Clientele Base Modern Designing in Restaurant Furniture Chairs and Stools How to Design a Restaurant: Aisle Space, Work Surfaces, Accessibility The Basics on How to Design a Restaurant Restaurant Interior Design - Designing a Restaurant Logo Design for Restaurants Designing a Restaurant Menu 
 
Recent Articles

 How to Eat Healthily on Your Courier Driving Jobs The Ins And Outs Of Wheatgrass Juicing - Advice Commercial Kitchen Crises: Damage Control Catering for Any Event A Quick Crash Course in Bread Machines and Why You Need One The Logic Behind Drinks Packaging Green Party Foods Easy Pumpkin Pie Crust For Thanksgiving Dinner Summer Burgers, And How To Stop Feeling Guilty Eating Them Protein - How Much Do You Need And Where to Get It? 
 
Submitted On July 31, 2006. Viewed 4,479 times. Word count: 750.
 MLA Style Citation: 
McRea, Bill &quot;Designing A Restaurant.&quot; Designing A Restaurant .
 31 Jul. 2006 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Designing-­A-­Restaurant&amp;id=257336 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
McRea, B. (2006, July 31). Designing A Restaurant .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Designing-­A-­Restaurant&amp;id=257336 Chicago Style Citation: 
McRea, Bill &quot;Designing A Restaurant.&quot; Designing A Restaurant EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Designing-­A-­Restaurant&amp;id=257336 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
