<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008365" url="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-127452.html" time="2012-07-13-01:51" support="7" score="0.007757807713854527" bingtitle="Guy sues fast food restaurants for making him fat and unhealthy ..." webtitle="Guy sues fast food restaurants for making him fat and unhealthy [Archive]  - Straight Dope Message Board">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000877" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001253" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>... lawsuits, and fast-food ... to do with eating at fast food places five times a week?&quot; Or is he just willfully ignorant? Every fast-food restaurant I&apos;ve ... not to wear a seat ...</description>
	<body>
		Straight Dope Message Board &gt; Main &gt; The BBQ Pit &gt;Guy sues fast food restaurants for making him fat and unhealthy PDA 
View Full Version : Guy sues fast food restaurants for making him fat and unhealthy 
 bernse 07-25-2002, 11:25 AM From:
http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,58652,00.html

-snip-

A New York City lawyer has filed suit against the four big fast-food corporations, saying their fatty foods are responsible for his clients obesity and related health problems.

---snip---

The lead plaintiff, 56-year-old maintenance supervisor Caesar Barber, ate at fast-food restaurants four or five times a week and blames his fatty diet for his obesity, diabetes, high blood pressure and cholesterol and the two heart attacks he has suffered.


For the love of Christ.

Before anyone starts on that obese people may have genetic problems that make them fat/eat/whatver, I have yet hear of a Whopper of Big Mac eating gene.

Eat all you want for christ sakes, but pack a fucking lunch with a carrot in it or something.

Fuck.

Welcome to the US - Where you aren&apos;t responsible for anything!!

I wonder if I can sue Vivid video for some wrist problems I have... those bastards! TroubleAgain 07-25-2002, 11:30 AM I&apos;m sure somehow those restaurants reached out and grabbed him, dragged him in, and STUFFED those burgers, fries and shakes down his throat. Giraffe 07-25-2002, 11:34 AM Heck, McDonald&apos;s even has Grimace as an example of what you&apos;ll look like if you eat there every day. What more can they do? red_dragon60 07-25-2002, 11:35 AM And they no doubt lied to him about how the fries are low-fat and non-addictive. Hopefully, when the judge throws this trite shite outta the window, nobody else will try and pull the same stunt and the US won&apos;t try a&quot;fat tax&quot;.

Part of living in America is freedom to choose what you eat. The Wrong Girl 07-25-2002, 11:40 AM This reminds me of the woman who sued the&quot;Pirates Booty&quot;food corporation because their popcorn made her go off her diet. Apparently, they mislabeled the fat content in their popcorn, so she ended up fucking up her diet by eating food she thought was healthy. Unlike this guy, she had a leg to stand on, but I still contend she shouldn&apos;t have eaten food called&quot;Pirate&apos;s Booty&quot;in the first place.

Cases like these are so annoying--you just know that this is going to be cited forever when people bring up litigious Americans and obese Americans. :( What can you do, other than sit back and watch this guy make a fool of himself. Swampwolf 07-25-2002, 12:07 PM What&apos;s really sad is, he&apos;ll probably get a decent settlement out of it. It&apos;s not like there aren&apos;t precedents for this sort of thing. Fred 07-25-2002, 12:22 PM This reminds me of an article written on fast food by my personal hero, Malcolm Gladwell. Here&apos;s a quote:


McDonald&apos;s and the other fast-food houses aren&apos;t the only purveyors of trans fats, of course; trans fats are in crackers and potato chips and cookies and any number of other processed foods. Still, a lot of us get a great deal of our trans fats from French fries, and to read the medical evidence on trans fats is to wonder at the odd selectivity of the outrage that consumers and the legal profession direct at corporate behavior. McDonald&apos;s and Burger King and Wendy&apos;s have switched to a product, without disclosing its risks, that may cost human lives. What is the difference between this and the kind of thing over which consumers sue companies every day?


And another


It didn&apos;t take the Auburn scientists long to realize that they had created something special. They installed a test kitchen in their laboratory, got hold of a McDonald&apos;s grill, and began doing blind taste comparisons of AU Lean burgers and traditional twenty- per-cent-fat burgers. Time after time, the AU Lean burgers won. Next, they took their invention into the field. They recruited a hundred families and supplied them with three kinds of ground beef for home cooking over consecutive three-week intervals--regular&quot;market&quot;ground beef with twenty per cent fat, ground beef with five percent fat, and AU Lean. The families were asked to rate the different kinds of beef, without knowing which was which. Again, the AU Lean won hands down--trumping the other two on&quot;likability,&quot;&quot;tenderness,&quot;&quot;flavorfulness,&quot;and&quot;juiciness.&quot;


Given that fast food places have the technology and ability to introduce both burgers and fries with much lower fat, but refrain from doing so, I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if this lawsuit, and ones similar to it, were successful. This isn&apos;t a caveat emptor country, folks. Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire. JohnBckWLD 07-25-2002, 12:23 PM Here we go again.

Samuel Hirsch, a NYC trial lawyer (or should I say vile liar) has started the ball rolling on a class action suit NY State against the big four fast food chains: McDonalds, Burger King, Wendys and KFC. I though Taco Bell was one of the worst, but I guess to get Pepsico in your sights you dont need to file against 2 of their chains.

The lead plaintiff, a Mr. Caesar Barbar (a very appropriate name for those of you whove read childrens stories) blamed his former 275# 510 physique and two heart attacks on Big Macs, Whoppers, Bacon Classics and the ever popular Original recipe.

Using the argument that he was conned, fooled and tricked while citing NY State laws against deceptive business practices, the now reformed junk food junkie wants his day in court and his piece of the apple pie.

The attorney, Samuel Hirsh, who refuses to say whether he contacted Barbar or vice-versa (my guess is he has one hand up Barbars ass like a ventriloquist puppet and the other waiting to snatch his wallet) is already drooling over his 1/3 cut after filing papers in Bronx County Supreme Court; which, by the way is a great venue for finding an insanely generous, completely ignorant jury.

My first question is whos next? Hostess, Drakes, Entemanns, Local pizzeria owners, proprietors of diners, tavern owners or beer distributors?

Please, this parade has got to be stopped!

The lunatics are running the asylum.

These god damn lawsuits get more and more insane, more and more frivolous, and sadly, more and more profitable. The same leeches that write and interpret the laws use them for their own profit. Hot coffee, exploding pop tarts, tobacco users, exotic dancers with plastic tits, morons who fall off ladders, assholes who cut themselves shaving, paralyzed divers, curb trippers, supermarket slippers and whiplash winnersthe gravy train has got to end.

You, the taxpayer, are paying the court expenses and the awards against municipalities.
You, the consumer, are paying for judgments against corporations that simply work their legal expenses into the price of the products you buy.
You the insured see a good part of your premium diverted right into the lawyers pockets.

The time for tort reform is now!
Let the English Rule reign supreme. Cap punitive damages.

Make the loser pay the winners (and for that matter the taxpayers) legal expenses. Dont tell me this will limit the citizens right to file suit. There are so many lawyers out there looking to make a million, theyll jump at the opportunity to file suit for legitimate claims and will even if they have to take the gamble of paying the winner in the event they lose. UrbanChic 07-25-2002, 12:44 PM &quot;I trace it all back to the high fat, grease and salt, all back to McDonalds, Wendys, Burger King there was no fast food I didn&apos;t eat, and I ate it more often than not because I was single, it was quick and Im not a very good cook,&quot;Barber said in an interview with Foxnews.com.

&quot;It was a necessity, and I think it was killing me, my doctor said it was killing me, and I don&apos;t want to die.&quot;
He&apos;s admitting he&apos;s a glutton and an idiot! Necessity, indeed. :rolleyes:
Frances Winn, a 57-year-old retired nurse, said her habit of eating at fast-food restaurants at least twice a week since 1975, caused her to go from a size 6 to a size 18, and inflicted her with hypertension, high cholesterol and a hyperthyroid problem.
Wow, eating a weeks worth of calories and fat in two days caused her to gain a tremendous amount of weight! Whodathunk it?
Israel Bradley, 59, said his ritual of eating a pound of french fries a week gave him high blood pressure, diabetes, made him obese and forces him to walk with a cane. In 1993, he passed out and had to be rushed to the emergency room because of the medical problems caused by his diet.

&quot;I got addicted to it,&quot;he said.
When his diet caused him severe medical problems he still didn&apos;t have the common sense to change his ways and he want the fast food industry to pay him for it now?

What next, will junkies be suing their drug dealer? Missy2U 07-25-2002, 01:29 PM Juanita, under the Drug Dealer Liability Act, (per http://www.modelddla.com/Explanation_of_DDLA_Market_Liability.htm ) they can in Arkansas, California, Colorado, Georgia, Hawaii, Illinois, Indiana, Louisiana, Michigan, Oklahoma, South Dakota, South Carolina, Utah and the U.S. Virgin Islands

A. Persons who may bring suit (per http://www.estreet.com/orgs/dsi/ddla1b.html#analysis )

The basis of recovery under the Act is the harm resulting from the actual use of drugs by a person. Sections 11(c) and 5(a). If the person&apos;s drug use results in a recognizable harm to the person or to other persons or entities, such persons and entities may bring suit to recover damages for the harm caused. These persons and entities include family members, injured members of the public, employers, and entities that have incurred financial loss as a result of the person&apos;s drug use. Section 6(a). The Act also allows the drug user to bring suit, albeit under more restrictive circumstances and for more limited damages, (Section 7) as is discussed later. Drastic 07-25-2002, 01:54 PM I for one hope the case goes through, and the fellow wins.

If that happens, things are looking up for my planned suit against mattress manufacturers and the companies that make computer games.

You see, sometimes I oversleep, and being late for work is very stressful for a person who prefers to be punctual. It&apos;s a proven fact that stress is unhealthy for the body, and I wouldn&apos;t have suffered it if my bed wasn&apos;t so comfortable.

Similarly, I&apos;ve been forced to develop the habit of playing computer games. The time I spend doing that could be spent improving my health via exercise. Plus, sometimes playing them causes frustration at not being able to solve a puzzle, get past a certain sequence, or whatnot, which is additional stress on a sedentary body. The negative effects of this wouldn&apos;t happen if the games weren&apos;t so addictive and fun.

I&apos;ll figure out what to sue after that once those are underway. Miller 07-25-2002, 02:10 PM And if Drastic&apos;s suit goes through, I&apos;m going after the SDMB for all the time I&apos;ve wasted here instead of pursuing a medical degree and earning hundreds of thousands of dollars treating people like Mr. Barbar. And after that, I&apos;ll sue Mr. Barbar for suing the fast food franchises, which forced them to offer healthier food, thereby depriving me of my legally-established pseudo-livliehood. And when the government finally pulls its dick out of the mouth of the trial attorney&apos;s lobby and slaps some regulations on lawsuits, I&apos;ll sue congress for depriving me of my main source of income: suing everyone I can lay my hands on! I&apos;ll be rich! Rich, I tells ya! lurkernomore 07-25-2002, 02:19 PM Caesar Barber shoulda had a Caesar SALAD once in a while.

Can we sue the lawyers for disturbing our sensibilities for these stupid lawsuits?

Can an honest lawyer if you can find one sue someone like this for defaming their profession? minty green 07-25-2002, 02:22 PM Fear not. This suit will quickly be put out of its misery, through the magic power of a motion to dismiss. c_goat 07-25-2002, 02:29 PM Hey Drastic, add me to your list of plaintiffs. I&apos;m always late to work because Sony and Intel make me play video games all night, then I can&apos;t sleep because I can only think about the games I was forced to endure. It&apos;s like a neverending nightmare. RTFirefly 07-25-2002, 03:46 PM Originally posted by lurkernomore
Can an honest lawyer if you can find one I&apos;d say we have several on this board, if the integrity they bring to debates here is indicative of how they conduct their professional lives.

Welcome to the US - Where you aren&apos;t responsible for anything!!Just because somebody files an asinine lawsuit, doesn&apos;t mean nobody&apos;s responsible for anything.

I don&apos;t have the professional background that minty brings to this discussion, but I&apos;d agree that this one has a granted&quot;motion to dismiss&quot;written all over it.
These god damn lawsuits get more and more insane, more and more frivolous, and sadly, more and more profitable. The same leeches that write and interpret the laws use them for their own profit. Hot coffee...My oh my, not that again. Here&apos;s the thread (http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?s=&amp;threadid=22459&amp;highlight=McDonalds+coffee) where we dealt with that one; she had a legit gripe. As one poster said, You mean the case where McDonald&apos;s, even though many injuries had been reported previously, still served their coffee way above a temperature that could be considered&quot;normal&quot;, and gave it to them in their cars? And then an old lady bought a cup, placed it between her legs, where it spilled out and caused third-degree burns, requiring hospitalization and skin grafts? The time for tort reform is now! Yeah, except that what&apos;s billed as&quot;tort reform&quot;amounts to capping punitive damages at the nonpunitive level in the case of large corporations.

If you want to prevent plaintiffs or their lawyers from benefiting from punitive damages, you could have them go to a third party - a charity, or the government. But to cap punitive damages is to minimize any deterrent value they might have. Coldfire 07-25-2002, 03:48 PM Well, I think this guy is dead right. I&apos;m calling my lawyer now.

Gonna sue Yamaha for causing me to get speeding tickets. :) DeadlyAccurate 07-25-2002, 03:59 PM Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire.

So, am I breaking the law if I go to the grocery store and select fresh vegetables and whole grain breads instead of stopping at McDonald&apos;s on the way home and grabbing a couple of Quarter Pounders w/Cheese? We very much have the ability to choose between safe and unsafe foods. No one made him go to fast food restaurants. I don&apos;t eat out much because it gets expensive and tiresome pretty fast. I make that choice, the same one this idiot was also able to make. bernse 07-25-2002, 04:09 PM Just because somebody files an asinine lawsuit, doesn&apos;t mean nobody&apos;s responsible for anything

Sarcasm meter just a little off today, RTF?

;) Robb 07-25-2002, 05:08 PM And when the government finally pulls its dick out of the mouth of the trial attorney&apos;s lobby and slaps some regulations on lawsuits,
I suppose then that ending the likelihood of suing the pharmaceutical industry for their defective products means we are at this point. Search for the Help Efficient, Accessible, Low Cost, Timely Health Care (HEALTH) Act of 2002 at Thomas (http://thomas.loc.gov/home/c107query.html)
The bill caps nonecoomic damages, essentially prohibits punitive damages, ends joint liabilty, and severely limits attorney fees. So, all those people damaged by Pondimin, Redux, Sulzer hip and knee implants, Rezulin and other less than helpful products can all breath a sigh of relief that Congress has their best interests at heart. (really, the bill even has a section entitled,&quot;MAXIMIZING PATIENT RECOVERY.&quot;) CnoteChris 07-25-2002, 05:19 PM I heard this on the radio today, and as soon as I got home I headed straight to the pit to see if this topic had been started yet. If it hadn&apos;t been, I was gonna sound off. I should have figured you guys were on top of it.

I agree with those before me- it&apos;s amazing, simply amazing. Where the fuck has personal responsibility gone in this country? Obviously nowhere, if people really think they have a case against a company making them fat, apparently against their will.

Amazing.

*My favorite line, omitted above-&quot;Israel Bradley, 59, said his ritual of eating a pound of french fries a week gave him high blood pressure, diabetes, made him obese and forces him to walk with a cane. In 1993, he passed out and had to be rushed to the emergency room because of the medical problems caused by his diet.

Good God almighty, a pound of fries a week! He&apos;s so fat he needs to use a cane to waddle himself up to the counter to get even more fries (Or, more precisely, I bet he uses his car, in which case he not only needs a cane, but also a shoe horn to squeeze his fat ass into the car).

And through all of this, the blood pressure, the diabetes, the fucking cane, it not only doesn&apos;t occur to him to stop stuffing his face with a pound of fries a week, but that it&apos;s someone else&apos;s fault that he does?

Amazing.


But, as one of our local radio guys has rightfully pointed out, it&apos;s only the beginning. Seeing as anti-smoking, anti-drinking, and anti-anything that people have problems with has been making the progress that it has in recent years, it was only a matter of time before the focus would turn to something else. Who better to nail than fast food. WV_Woman 07-25-2002, 05:36 PM As someone who has been fat since my day of birth, I just gotta say that I&apos;m shedding no tears for these guys.

Yeah, most of my family is fat, but mostly I&apos;m fat because I don&apos;t exercise and eat too much sugar.

It&apos;s not Wendy&apos;s fault if I eat a Frosty. sailor 07-25-2002, 06:01 PM So we can sue those that ruin our lives by making us unproductive? Boy, I have a pretty good case against all those dopers who post stuff I can&apos;t stop reading, not to mention those who disagree with me and make me type for hours. Boy, I&apos;m gonna be rich. You all just wait and see. ;) Cervaise 07-25-2002, 06:39 PM It&apos;s not Wendy&apos;s fault if I eat a Frosty.Whose fault is it when I eat a Wendy?

What? Miller 07-25-2002, 07:38 PM Originally posted by Robb

I suppose then that ending the likelihood of suing the pharmaceutical industry for their defective products means we are at this point. Search for the Help Efficient, Accessible, Low Cost, Timely Health Care (HEALTH) Act of 2002 at Thomas (http://thomas.loc.gov/home/c107query.html)
The bill caps nonecoomic damages, essentially prohibits punitive damages, ends joint liabilty, and severely limits attorney fees. So, all those people damaged by Pondimin, Redux, Sulzer hip and knee implants, Rezulin and other less than helpful products can all breath a sigh of relief that Congress has their best interests at heart. (really, the bill even has a section entitled,&quot;MAXIMIZING PATIENT RECOVERY.&quot;)

Naw, that just means the pharmaceutical companies give better head.

Congress? Out best interests at heart? The idea makes me laugh so hard I think I just ruptured something. My lawyer will contact you tomorrow to discuss damages. don&apos;t ask 07-25-2002, 07:46 PM Originally posted by Giraffe
Heck, McDonald&apos;s even has Grimace as an example of what you&apos;ll look like if you eat there every day. What more can they do?

They don&apos;t need Grimace, just look at the customers you&apos;re lined up behind. butter pie 07-25-2002, 08:21 PM They have their nutritional information for all the food on the website... the only time their food has almost given *me* a heart attack is when I saw the amount of calories and fat in it. A whole day&apos;s worth of calories for me, in one extra value meal! I lost my taste for fries pretty quick after that. Sanscour 07-25-2002, 09:14 PM This is my prediction for the next big leap in frivolous lawsuits:

Criminal Sues GOD Because of Free Will

Papers were filed today against the Supreme Being on behalf of Mr Joe Blow, a convicted felon who is serving a life sentence for murder, rape, child molestation and assault with a deadly weapon.

&quot;If God had never given me free will, I would not have turned out to be the slimey, worthless ass pumping mountain of greasy cock gristle that I am today.&quot;he said in an interview on nbc.com. He is seeking an undisclosed sum for damages.

His lawyer agrees with him completely.&quot;Mr Blow has had a hard life of killing, raping, and other serious crimes for which he should not be held accountable for. This is clearly all God&apos;s fault.&quot;

Reporters have tried to reach God several times for comment, but he could not be reached.

A jury selection begins next month.


That is my prediction
Sanscour Ringo 07-25-2002, 09:24 PM Can the secondary fat victims get in on this, too? Neurotik 07-25-2002, 09:40 PM Originally posted by Robb
Search for the Help Efficient, Accessible, Low Cost, Timely Health Care (HEALTH) Act of 2002
I think that ridiculous acronyms are a more pressing problem. I mean, seriously...&quot;Help Efficient, Accessible, Low Cost, Timely Health Care&quot;= HEALTH? My ass it does. Something needs to be done about this problem and now!!!

I&apos;m not kidding, that is truly atrocious. apotheosis 07-25-2002, 10:11 PM A couple of questions/points, in all sincerity and with no animosity:

1.) Is it safe to assume that all of you who are against this lawsuit also opposed the lawsuits against the tobacco companies? If not, why not? What&apos;s the difference?

2.) Why is alcohol (apparently) getting a free ride? I say apparently because I&apos;m not aware of any past or pending lawsuits of this sort against brewers/distillers. If there are no such lawsuits, why not? While some might still argue that cigarettes and their attending &apos;secondhand smoke&apos; haven&apos;t caused the amount of collateral damage commonly attributed to them, I&apos;d think few would dispute the connection between DUI fatalities/spousal abuse and alcohol.

3.) The McDonalds down the street from me has the nutritional information for all their products posted quite plainly on the wall right next to the front counter. Is this commonplace? I don&apos;t travel much, and I frequent McD&apos;s even less; but if it is, it&apos;d be hard to argue that they were concealing their products&apos; unhealthy nature.

TIA! Road Rash 07-25-2002, 10:23 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death



Given that fast food places have the technology and ability to introduce both burgers and fries with much lower fat, but refrain from doing so, I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if this lawsuit, and ones similar to it, were successful. This isn&apos;t a caveat emptor country, folks. Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire.

I believe that McDonalds did put out a lean burger, called McLean. It Mcsucked and did not sell.

Many fast food joints do sell grilled chicken sandwiches. Still not great, especially after adding cheese and bacon, but an option. interface2x 07-25-2002, 10:27 PM He shouldn&apos;t sue fast food restuarants because they made him fat and unhealthy - he should sue all of the people who are about to beat his ass into a bloody pulp for being such a jackass. Miller 07-25-2002, 10:35 PM I don&apos;t know about McDonalds or Burger King, but I think the guy has a case against KFC. After all, they do put a secret additive in their chicken which makes you crave it fort-nightly.



(Y&apos;all remember the days when people who fucked up their lives would just blame it on their parents?&lt;Sigh&gt;Good times. Good times.) WV_Woman 07-25-2002, 10:45 PM apotheosis:

1. I am iffy on tobacco lawsuits. On one hand, outlaw them and you&apos;re just going to have crazed nicotine freaks breaking into your house and robbing you so they can get money to take to their black market dealer. Nicotine is the most addictive substance on earth and there is no reason to think that some smokers wouldn&apos;t turn into criminals if cigs suddenly became illegal. Nobody has ever been forced to smoke, though, and the excuse&quot;I didn&apos;t know it was bad for me&quot;went out with my grandmother&apos;s generation. On the other hand, tobacco companies are big liars, always have been, they know cigs cause cancer and still they load up the nicotine to keep people addicted. I don&apos;t think a smoker in this day and age should sue because they were dumb enough to take that first drag, but I do have to admit it would be nice to see the tobacco companies REALLY get their just desserts. They make a product that kills people if you use it in the way it is intended, nuff said. Flip a coin.

2. Alcohol: no alcohol company has ever announced that alcohol is not addictive and thus can be enjoyed freely. Plus when you drink you get an immediate feedback. It can be argued that drunk drivers who go out and kill people were not using alcohol responsibly and it isn&apos;t the beer company&apos;s fault if someone abuses their products. (As opposed to smoking, where even a measly 1/4 pack a day is going to cause damage.)

3. Hi Opal!

4. McDonald&apos;s and their fast food colleagues have never, ever claimed to sell healthy food. With the exception of their salads and pansy little grilled chickens, everyone knows that the stuff they sell is loaded with carbs, calories, and grease. The *only* place I see claiming to sell healthy stuff is Subway, and even they are debatable if you are a low-carb loyalist. You&apos;d have to be a total moron, like these people in the lawsuit, to believe that you can inhale a Big Mac several times a week and it NOT end up padding your butt.

With the exception of the few fat people out there who have actual metabolic disorders, people are fat because they eat too much and don&apos;t exercise. Period.

I need to cut my weight in half, literally. When I do it, I would be extremely pissed if someone said&quot;oh, you just got lucky.&quot;*I* got to the weight I am myself, and dammit when I lose the weight, it will be ME who did it, with the help of God. Nobody but me gets the blame for me being fat, and nobody but me and God will get the credit when I lose it.

Caesar can kiss my ass. He&apos;s making all fat people look like whiny babies.

Sorry this was so long. WV_Woman 07-25-2002, 10:50 PM Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire.

Americans can&apos;t haul their butts to the grocery store and buy carrot sticks instead of Quarter Pounders?

Americans have more options as far as what they eat than many countries combined! If you want to eat healthy, you can. If you want to eat nothing but junk, that&apos;s certainly available.

Nobody forces anybody else to make bad choices. CnoteChris 07-25-2002, 11:01 PM I&apos;ll chime in and answer from my point of view, apotheosis.

1) I wasn&apos;t for the tobacco lawsuits, at least from the standpoint that the government should be involved. If individuals had legitimate and real reasons to sue, i.e. that companies were lying about the effects of tobacco, spiking their products, or doing shady things like that, then it should be pursued by either and individual or a class action type thing. Even given that, however, I still thought people who sued under the guise that they never knew smoking was harmful were full of it.

Again, my biggest problem with the tobacco lawsuits has been the involvement of the government, in whatever form. From the beginning I thought it was a shady, almost unethical means for a strapped government afraid to raise taxes finding an outside, easy, source for revenue (At the time I had no idea it&apos;d be as blatant, and completely out of control as it&apos;s turned out to be today-- in my fine state of Minnesota, I think about five percent of the judgement against the tobacco companies went back into the areas that the government said were directly affected by smoking related illnesses, etc.).

Besides, I think it opened the floodgates for the frivolous lawsuits like these that are bound to continue and spread to other areas.

2) I don&apos;t think alcohol has been getting a free ride. I think what happened with tobacco will happen with alcohol too. First, advocates make it a public safety issue, then, when public opinion has changed, and the message has been pounded home, go for the jugular and attack full on. In the case of tobacco, this has been going on for awhile. Back in the seventies it was a made a public safety issue, what with the surgeon general coming out and criticizing it and the general trend to make it a bad thing, instead of the good thing it was portrayed as. Years... many years later, the lawsuits started and, well, kinda didn&apos;t go anywhere, but they kept coming. Finally, after the years of lawsuits and the growing trend in the public that anything tobacco is bad, the government finally steps in and puts their full weight behind numerous lawsuits. Basically, the final blow.

Personally, I don&apos;t see how this isn&apos;t happening with alcohol right now. The only thing is, we&apos;re only in the later, or maybe even the middle stages, of the campaign to make it &apos;bad&apos;. Give it a couple years, or maybe ten or so, and I bet the lawsuits start and eventually, sometime down the road (And IMHO, sooner rather than later), the government will step in and attack these companies as well.

The result, I presume, will be about the same- revenue generated from people who can least afford it. Essentially a regressive tax framed in the context that its a public health issue, when in reality it isnt- its a tax.

Again, my humble opinion.

3) Ive seen those nutritional flies too, and not just at Mickey D&apos;s. If you read them, and only have a cursory understanding of nutrition, those things are pretty frightening, especially if you make that your one and only source for food. Only an idiot would do that.

Those same kinds of warnings- different though they are- didn&apos;t do a damn bit of good for the tobacco companies, did they? Tars Tarkas 07-25-2002, 11:18 PM They already did it to alcohol, we got an amendment, lots of crime, and then another amendment. The last thing i want to see is a McAmendment. Sterra 07-25-2002, 11:32 PM Resident doper sues Coke, a SDMB member, and keyboard manufacturers over damage to his keyboard

When asked about this he said&quot;I just had so much luck with suing the other guy over the defamation of my screen name that I thought this just might work&quot;

Tonight at 11 apotheosis 07-25-2002, 11:58 PM WV_Woman, CnoteChris, thanks for the responses.

Personally, I&apos;m kinda conflicted over the whole mess...as both a teetotaler and a smoker (crazed nicotine freak :D), it&apos;s difficult to take either side on the issue without feeling like a hypocrite, so I appreciate outside opinions on the matter. Jurhael 07-26-2002, 12:17 AM I&apos;m fat as well. It&apos;s a combination of being predisposed to a stocky body, eating the wrong things and not excersizing. I&apos;m not gonna lie about that. I just think that weight problems are more multi-faceted than people seem to think.

&quot;Americans can&apos;t haul their butts to the grocery store and buy carrot sticks instead of Quarter Pounders?&quot;

The key is time. Many people, because of working long hours, don&apos;t have the time to cook, so even if they COULD go to the supermarket instead of a McDonald&apos;s, it would simply save them time if they went to a fast food place. This is especially true if they have children. Is this always a legit excuse though? Nope. Does it apply to eveyone who frequents fast food places? Nope. It&apos;s just something that needs to be considered.

One other problem (and this is with all foods) is that people are indeed either not told EVERYTHING about what&apos;s in what they eat and drink. I mean, did you know that Starbucks uses pus for their milk?

Early on the brisk morning of March 1, Debbi Shoval and her partner stood outside of a neighborhood Starbucks and handed out leaflets.

Shoval explained that there are several complaints against Starbucks. The first: Most Starbucks still use milk from cows that have been injected with rBGH -- Monsanto&apos;s sketchy bovine growth hormone -- which unnaturally forces cows to produce more milk. The resulting milk contains bacteria, antibiotics and pus.

That&apos;s right. Pus.

(http://www.corpwatch.org/news/PND.jsp?articleid=2170)

I don&apos;t think that&apos;s in their nutritional files...and that&apos;s just Starbucks. Don&apos;t get me started on say...KFC (http://www.igc.org/solidarity/atc/99Lyons.html), McDonald&apos;s (http://www.mcspotlight.org/) and the like.

So, even if the companies (not just fast food) DO give info on their products, they clearly don&apos;t tell you everything, so even if there IS a choice, it isn&apos;t quite as much of a choice as people like to think.

As for me, I rarely eat at fast food places anymore and I NEVER go to Starbucks. As for the guy, he can go fuck himself. It looks to me like he&apos;s all he&apos;s got anyway! Despite the fact that companies are faaaaar from innocent, any assnugget with a microbrain can see that Fast Food=BAD FOR YOU. If he were being lied to, like some people filing similar lawsuits because they were told that their fries would have vegetable oil instead of animal fat when it turned out to be the latter, then I can see it. But, I think it&apos;s just finger pointing on his part and I think it&apos;s sad.

Now, I&apos;m gonna sue the SMDB, Livejournal, my web host, the ENTIRE internet, my sony playstation, my video games and ramen noodles because I&apos;m a chubby! :b capacitor 07-26-2002, 12:24 AM The difference is that the tobacco companies flat out lied about the tobacco products causing ailments. In front of Congress, with a straight face. Add the admission of addiction-inducing additives to cigarettes, and they will pay for the lie practically forever.

The fast food chains made no such claims, except probably for the breaded chicken, that the foods are 100 percent healthy. Tars Tarkas 07-26-2002, 12:49 AM The milk pus is from Mastitis infections, which cows with rBGH added are at a higher risk for. Farmers counter with massive antibiotics, so the pus level is probably only slightly higher. Dairies will not accept milk with high Somatic cell counts (pus). I assume pus is in all milk, as some cow will probably be infected on the farm and not noticed yet when milked, and the ratio of pus to milk is not high enough to raise alarms. (anyone who has worked in a grocery store knows that food has all sorts of nasty crap in it).

What you need to be worried about is two-fold. First, rBGH works by stimulating the cow via Insulin-Like Growth Factor 1 (IGF-1). Humans also use IGF-1, and the two are biochemically identical. IGF-1 stimulates cell division, and can survive pasteurization and digestion, and will be absorbed via the intestine. This could lead to increased cell division, which may cause tumors to form. Evidence is still shakey but scary. Problem 2 is the massive amount of antibiotics in the milk. Milk is supposed to be checked for that, but not all antibiotics fall under the checklist and many get by inspection. Increases in antibiotics in your food can lead to weakening of your immune system, and increase suseptability to diseases. That is a BAD thing.


rBGH links (some of these might be slightly biased sites)
http://www.sierraclub.ca/national/biotech/bghback.htm
http://www.argonet.co.uk/users/john.rose/rbgh.html
http://www.sumeria.net/anim/bgh.html
http://www.lightparty.com/Health/DangerBGHMilk.html CnoteChris 07-26-2002, 12:51 AM Boy, that&apos;s a real conundrum capacitor.

I mean, couldn&apos;t it be argued that Mickey D&apos;s, Burger king, et al, all hid the dangers of fat, sodium, and what have you, from the public out of a fear that the truth would hurt sales?

They knew it was bad, and not only didn&apos;t they do anything to stop it, they promoted it.

In a sense, isn&apos;t that what the tobacco people did- negate the real risk?

I also wonder about that in terms of the addiction thing. Again, couldn&apos;t it be argued that Coke, Pepsi, and the others, put an addictive ingredient- caffeine- into their product to boost sales, even when they knew it was harmful?

Where&apos;s the liability for that?

In both of those cases, I can actually see where people could make an argument, especially when the precedent has been made.

I guess that&apos;s why I&apos;m troubled with the precedent to begin with-- once you open that door, it&apos;s a bitch getting it closed. RexDart 07-26-2002, 01:40 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
This reminds me of an article written on fast food by my personal hero, Malcolm Gladwell. Here&apos;s a quote:

&lt;snip quote about lean vs. fat beef&gt;

Given that fast food places have the technology and ability to introduce both burgers and fries with much lower fat, but refrain from doing so, I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if this lawsuit, and ones similar to it, were successful. This isn&apos;t a caveat emptor country, folks. Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire.

Ummmm....have you been to a grocery store lately? There are alot of ground beefs you can buy. I find 74%, 80%, 90%, and 96% lean. Notice if you will the price per pound of those ground beef purchases. The 96% surely tastes much better to me. Far less of it cooks off when I grill or skillet the burger, it retains its weight after cooking much better. It&apos;s more expensive because it&apos;s harder to produce, it&apos;s that simple.

Now consider the McDonald&apos;s quarter-pounder. Much of that cooks off, so that the 1/4 pound of beef turns into a smaller burger than 1/4 lb. of my 96% lean ground beef turns into when cooked. Since 74% beef is far less expensive (at least $1 per pound less expensive at the grocery store) than 96% beef, this is a cost factor that impacts the cost of the burger. Frankly, 96% lean ground beef is a luxury that a few people can afford because they have nice monthly incomes that allow them to budget an extra $10-20 dollars into their ground beef grocery purchases per month. (I&apos;ve lived on some rather tight food budgets before, and am doing so currently, and the 74% beef remains one of the single most cost-effective meal options available for people who cannot live on Ramen noodles alone.)

Suppose that McDonald&apos;s were to switch to 96% lean ground beef. Their burgers would be more expensive, albeit tastier and larger, and they would no longer retain the market position of being the low-cost lunch option that they presently are for most of us. Do you suppose to dictate to stockholders and other investors what their policy should be, though it&apos;s their money on the line not yours?

If you want 96% lean, this is a luxury in which you are free to indulge by purchasing the beef at your local store and preparing it yourself. You know what you&apos;re getting at McDonald&apos;s, it&apos;s your choice to go there. If you want a lean burger, go to a better restaurant and buy it. Or brown bag your lunch. The cost of production is a fact of life, not something for you to wave your hand and say&quot;this should be different.&quot; Typo Negative 07-26-2002, 02:40 AM Originally posted by apotheosis
A couple of questions/points, in all sincerity and with no animosity:

1.) Is it safe to assume that all of you who are against this lawsuit also opposed the lawsuits against the tobacco companies? If not, why not? What&apos;s the difference?

I am 100% against the tobacco lawsuits. I am a former smoker. I used my freewill to light up. And when it got bad, I used my freewill, and a lot of perserverence, to stop.

But I knew that smoking was bad for me when I started. And I was 10 years old. I knew the risks. IMO, anyone who says they didn&apos;t know that smoking had health risks is lying through their fucking teeth. Same with this suit. These asshats are lying. They KNEW what they were doing. Typo Negative 07-26-2002, 02:42 AM Originally posted by minty green
Fear not. This suit will quickly be put out of its misery, through the magic power of a motion to dismiss. Could you expound on this a bit? RexDart 07-26-2002, 04:27 AM Originally posted by spooje

Originally posted by minty green
Fear not. This suit will quickly be put out of its misery, through the magic power of a motion to dismiss
Could you expound on this a bit?

Well, even without seeing the complaint yet, I smell our old friend 12(b)(6). Pretrial motion for failure to state a claim for which relief can be granted. If this is federal court.

If it&apos;s state court, fear not, there&apos;s a state law in the state&apos;s rules of civil procedure that functions just like 12(b)(6), it might even be more strict than the FRCP.

From the synopsis provided, it looks like it could only possibly be a negligence or products liability action. Since I don&apos;t take products liability until the fall semester, I can&apos;t say for sure what the merits of the action are under that theory. I can say that such unorthodox civil actions that lack much support in case law are prime candidates for a 12(b)(6) dismissal. PunditLisa 07-26-2002, 07:10 AM I am opposed to the tobacco lawsuits, alcohol lawsuits, and fast-food restaurant lawsuits. Know the risks and then live your life.

Personally, I think we should file a class action lawsuit against law schools for not capping their enrollments and thus creating a glut of lawyers. Lawyers are constantly trying to create a new revenue stream because there are too many of them. ralph124c 07-26-2002, 08:00 AM This lawsuit breaks new ground! With this filing, the jury will be asked to believe:
-McDonald&apos;s customers are too stupid to make rational decisions
-personal responsibility does not exist
-your own gluttony should be rewarded
I think the suit should be expanded to include:
-the advertising agencies that make the fast-food ads-they should show the obese customers that result from consumption of fast food!
-the cities that granted permission for the fast food pushers to operate
-the doctors, who should have advised their obese patients against eating the fastfood
Really, I am overjoyed..I hope this will expand to the point where the courts will be clogged. Then the whole rotten legal system will grind to a halt. Then we can seriously consider the wisdom of tort reform. I also think that (akin to the anti-gun lagislation) that we should have a&quot;bg mack buyback program&quot;-the government should pay people to sell their big mac burgers to the government. That shopuld reduce the availability of thei deadly fast food! Maeglin 07-26-2002, 08:43 AM IMO, anyone who says they didn&apos;t know that smoking had health risks is lying through their fucking teeth. Same with this suit. These asshats are lying. They KNEW what they were doing.

You&apos;d be surprised.

My grandparents are extremely close friends of the former CEO of Philip Morris and his wife. Both of them are chain smokers. Both of them are highly intelligent people. Yet both of them insist that they have been unfairly persecuted for years, because smoking does absolutely no harm whatsoever to a smoker&apos;s health.

YMMV. Typo Negative 07-26-2002, 08:56 AM Your GP&apos;s are chainsmokers? Or the CEO and his wife.

If your GP&apos;s are as old as my GP&apos;s, than that is more understandable. However, if you under the age of 60..... Maeglin 07-26-2002, 09:03 AM The CEO and his wife are both chainsmokers. They are in their 70s. DeadlyAccurate 07-26-2002, 09:55 AM I see the future:

Scenario One

McD Clerk: I&apos;m sorry, sir, but I can&apos;t sell you a burger and fries. Would you like a salad and a grilled chicken sandwich instead?

Customer: What?! Why not?

McD Clerk: You&apos;re obese, sir. McDonald&apos;s can&apos;t risk the liability of letting you get any fatter.

Customer: What right do you have to dictate what I eat?

McD Clerk: I&apos;m sorry, sir. Would you like that salad and sandwich?

Scenario Two

Customer: I&apos;d like a large chocolate shake, please.

McD Clerk: Here&apos;s a small chocolate shake. That&apos;ll be $1.39.

Customer: But I wanted a large shake.

McD Clerk: Yeah, but you look like you&apos;re packing on a little weight. A small shake would be better for you.

Customer: But I&apos;ve lost fifty pounds in the last year. I wanted to treat myself on my birthday! I was skimping for the last two days to be able to afford this treat.

McD Clerk: Sorry, ma&apos;am. McDonald&apos;s has to protect itself from overweight people who might sue us if we let them buy from us. Beadalin 07-26-2002, 09:55 AM Is anyone else reminded of this Onion article? I laughed when it first came out, but as usual, the satire&apos;s so sharp it becomes real life soon.

Hershey&apos;s Ordered to Pay Obese Americans $135 Billion (http://www.theonion.com/onion3626/hersheys_pay_obese.html) RTFirefly 07-26-2002, 10:50 AM Originally posted by apotheosis
A couple of questions/points, in all sincerity and with no animosity:

1.) Is it safe to assume that all of you who are against this lawsuit also opposed the lawsuits against the tobacco companies? If not, why not? What&apos;s the difference?i) IMHO, it&apos;s reasonable to regulate products that are both harmful and physically addictive more stringently than those that are just harmful (e.g. Big Macs) or just addictive (e.g. coffee).

Physical addiction substantially reduces one&apos;s ability to make a free choice to abandon use of the harmful product.

ii) Many Americans got addicted to cigarettes at ages when they legally had no business making the choice to start smoking. (I know I&apos;m gonna hear about this, but why should cigarettes be any different from sex?)

This was helped along by a certain amount of marketing aimed at kids - IIRC, this was documented by the stuff discovered in the tobacco companies&apos; files. And many of us are old enough to remember Joe Camel.

At any rate, when these people got to the age when they were legally entitled to decide whether to risk addiction to tobacco, they were already addicted, so the free-choice element was already gone.

This doesn&apos;t happen with cheeseburgers, which are at most psychologically addictive, and even that depends on your definition. While I am dead set against the right of companies to direct advertising at kids for stuff that&apos;s bad for them, the reality is that the kids can learn new habits once they&apos;re 18; it&apos;ll just be harder than it would have been otherwise.

iii) The tobacco companies lied about the dangers of their product, as other posters have pointed out. Their execs stood up in front of Congress, raised their right hands, and swore that their products weren&apos;t addictive. That they knew otherwise also came out in discovery. They lied about other dangers of their product over the years too.

It&apos;s not an affirmative defense to say,&quot;you shouldn&apos;t have believed us, because lots of other people were telling you we were lying.&quot;

As has been said already, MickeyD&apos;s makes no health claims about its products.
2.) Why is alcohol (apparently) getting a free ride? I say apparently because I&apos;m not aware of any past or pending lawsuits of this sort against brewers/distillers. If there are no such lawsuits, why not? While some might still argue that cigarettes and their attending &apos;secondhand smoke&apos; haven&apos;t caused the amount of collateral damage commonly attributed to them, I&apos;d think few would dispute the connection between DUI fatalities/spousal abuse and alcohol.Alcohol got hit earlier, and in another way - at the retail level. Bartenders who kept on serving their customers after they were obviously sloshed, and didn&apos;t try to take their car keys from them, got sued by the survivors of people who got killed by the drunk drivers.

The survivors won. That&apos;s why you see all sorts of beer-company ads mentioning drinking responsibly, using designated drivers, and all that.

About a decade ago, Ted Kennedy and Strom Thurmond united on a bill to ban alcohol advertising from the public airwaves. Unfortunately (IMHO, anyway), it didn&apos;t pass.

3.) The McDonalds down the street from me has the nutritional information for all their products posted quite plainly on the wall right next to the front counter. Is this commonplace? I don&apos;t travel much, and I frequent McD&apos;s even less; but if it is, it&apos;d be hard to argue that they were concealing their products&apos; unhealthy nature.I don&apos;t do much fast-fooding these days, so I&apos;m not sure about the big posters in the fast-food joints. But they will all make the nutritional info available to you on request, generally on a little flyer you can take home with you. And of course, it&apos;s on their websites. So if anyone wants to know, all they have to do is ask.

Which was definitely not the case with Big Tobacco for all those decades.

So I think the distinctions between tobacco&apos;s situation and the fast food industry&apos;s, are many and strong. I have to regard it as complete bullshit that&quot;it happened to tobacco, so Burger King and Taco Bell are next.&quot; wireless 07-26-2002, 11:17 AM QUOTE]Originally posted by lurkernomore
Caesar Barber shoulda had a Caesar SALAD once in a while.[/QUOTE]

Yeah, but do you know how many calories are in a Caesar Salad?
(About 400 in a Wendy&apos;s Caesar Side Salad with Dressing, see http://www.wendys.com/nutrition_guide.pdf)

Note: this doesn&apos;t mean I support this CoS lawsuit.

P.S. Bernse, your last little comment had me laughing out loud at the office. I think it&apos;s worth a shot. BottledBlondJeanie 07-26-2002, 01:37 PM Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.

It seems to me that many people on this board assume that more than a small percentage of overweight people are not responsible for their weight--they can&apos;t help but eat those bad things or that even if they eat good things an exercise they can still be overweight.

Weird. BottledBlondJeanie 07-26-2002, 01:44 PM Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.

It seems to me that many people on this board assume that more than a small percentage of overweight people are not responsible for their weight--they can&apos;t help but eat those bad things or that even if they eat good things an exercise they can still be overweight.

Weird. DeadlyAccurate 07-26-2002, 02:00 PM Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.

Well if it is, that makes the lawsuit even more ridiculous. He might as well sue his parents for having the genetics to pass such a condition on to him.

From the abcnews.go.com article:
Caesar Barber, 56, a maintenance worker who weighs about 270 pounds and stands 5-foot-10, claims McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Wendy&apos;s and KFC jeopardized his health with their greasy, salty fare.

The man in question blames his obesity on eating bad foods. Why should we not do the same? DeadlyAccurate 07-26-2002, 02:02 PM Rereading your post now, I&apos;m not sure if I was just whooshed or not. Miller 07-26-2002, 02:10 PM Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.

So, there&apos;s a genetic abnormality that makes someone eat a pound of McDonald&apos;s french fries every week? brainychick 07-26-2002, 04:20 PM Originally posted by Giraffe
Heck, McDonald&apos;s even has Grimace as an example of what you&apos;ll look like if you eat there every day. What more can they do?

Good one!!! Can I borrow it?

Still learning how to eat more responsibly myself, and I need all the motivation I can get. ultrafilter 07-26-2002, 04:23 PM Originally posted by BottledBlondJeanie
Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.

It seems to me that many people on this board assume that more than a small percentage of overweight people are not responsible for their weight--they can&apos;t help but eat those bad things or that even if they eat good things an exercise they can still be overweight.

Weird.

I&apos;ve read this post five or six times, and I still can&apos;t make heads or tails of it. It looks like the first and second paragraphs are making contradictory assertions. Jeanie, could you explain what you&apos;re trying to say here? WV_Woman 07-26-2002, 05:57 PM The CEO and his wife are both chainsmokers. They are in their 70s.

And we know what sticklers for telling the truth tobacco CEO&apos;s are.

Do you REALLY think a CEO of a tobacco company is going to tell you&quot;of course cigarettes make you sick&quot;?

There is no way you can have a brain and NOT know that inhaling smoke into your lungs, which are created to inhale air only, is harmful to your health.

This CEO buddy is lying through his teeth. What they do best. Giraffe 07-26-2002, 06:11 PM Originally posted by brainychick
Good one!!! Can I borrow it?

Of course!

Although, upon further reflection, I&apos;ve decided that the prosecution will probably call Grimace as a witness to attest that McDonald&apos;s has been promoting obesity all along. (&quot;Before Ronald offered me a job, I was a friggin&apos; smurf! I was a size -3! Now look at me! I look like a bean bag!&quot;)

And then the Hamburgler to prove that McDonald&apos;s encouraged people to steal fast-food hamburgers if they couldn&apos;t afford to pay for them, just to maintain their addiction. Robble robble. Squish 07-26-2002, 10:46 PM Tobacco, alcohol and now fast-food lawsuits: I&apos;m against them all.
1) Tobacco: I&apos;m a&quot;nicotine freak&quot;also. My entire extended family smokes, yet even so my father told me when I was a teen-ager,&quot;I hope you never start smoking because it&apos;s almost impossible to quit.&quot;I have books from the late 19th century which take it as a given that smoking is unhealthful. I don&apos;t think it&apos;s quite the demon it&apos;s viewed as now, but any body who starts smoking knows--and knew way back when--that it wasn&apos;t good for you.
2) I can understand suing the drunk driver, but not suing the bar or bartender who served him. They&apos;re not anybody&apos;s mommy.
3) Nobody has to go to a fast food (or, rather, junk-food) joint. You can pick up reasonably healthy items that don&apos;t require cooking at the supermarket.

I&apos;m getting disgusted with the obese; not with the fact that they are obese--that&apos;s their choice--but with the constant whining about it.&quot;Society isn&apos;t fair!&quot;&quot;I can&apos;t find clothes in my size!&quot;&quot;It&apos;s somebody else&apos;s fault that I&apos;m fat!&quot;Good gods, put down the tub of ice cream and get off the damned couch, already! WV_Woman 07-27-2002, 12:05 AM I can get with you on the whining about society being unfair and blaming other people. However, it IS a pain in the ass to find clothes. And considering there is a fashion industry out there who wants every penny they can get, they would be smart to listen to the millions and millions of fat people out there and design decent clothes.

Just because we&apos;re fat doesn&apos;t mean we don&apos;t want to look as good as possible, and it doesn&apos;t mean that we don&apos;t have money to spend.&quot;Fat&quot;money will spend just as well as&quot;thin&quot;money last I checked. Fred 07-27-2002, 01:26 AM Americans can&apos;t haul their butts to the grocery store and buy carrot sticks instead of Quarter Pounders?


WV_Woman: I&apos;m afraid that I&apos;ve been misinterpreted. I was saying that Americans aren&apos;t generally able to choose between a product that kills people by the millions and a product that does the exact same thing that is exponentially less dangerous. For example, Americans can&apos;t haul their butts to the grocery store and buy carrot sticks with an expiry date in the twentieth century for a lower price than ones coding next week. The government regulates the food industry - dangerous food is illegal, even in the home of the free.


I believe that McDonalds did put out a lean burger, called McLean. It Mcsucked and did not sell.


Road Rash: You are partially correct, sir. The McLean burger did not sell. But the reason it did not sell is emphatically not because it was an inferior product. In fact, as I&apos;ve already shown, it was superior to regular burgers in every way, including taste. The quality of a product doesn&apos;t translate into sales: the marketing does. Think New Coke, friend. The answer lies in the marketing. People are trained since birth (like Pavlov&apos;s dogs, only without bells) to make a correlation between how good a food is for you, and how good it tastes. Why else would people believe Cod Liver Oil is good for you? We&apos;ve been programmed to believe that it&apos;s impossible for a burger to both taste great and be less filling - Oops, less fattening. The fact that the McLean was marketed as a Lean burger spelled its doom. Had McDonald&apos;s merely switched from their regular burgers to the lean kind, dollars to doughnuts say no one would have been able to tell the difference.

Rex Dart: Maybe I&apos;m taking crazy pills here, but personally, I have a problem with a company trading millions of human lives for profit margins. I mean, is it me?

That aside, man, your whole post is based on a few false premises. Chiefly among them is your bizarre belief that McDonald&apos;s is a low cost meal option. You tell me you&apos;ve been on a tight budget. If this is really so, I can&apos;t imagine how you&apos;d justify claiming that McDonald&apos;s, or any other restaurant, is a&quot;low cost lunch&quot;. Anyone who&apos;s ever had to scrimp should know that making your own lunch is a zillion times less expensive. How on earth could you believe otherwise? Do you really believe that people will flock away from McDonalds in droves if their Quarter Pounder Meals are twenty cents more expensive? That&apos;s insane! Rick 07-27-2002, 02:37 AM Originally posted by WV_Woman
apotheosis:

1. Nicotine is the most addictive substance on earth

Cite please? I keep hearing smokers say that smoking is more addictive than heroin. Now it has been elevated to the most addictive substance on earth. I thought that crack that can hook with one joint was more addictive.
{personal story}
When I was growing up both of my parents smoked. A lot. My dad was three packs a day of unfiltered Camels (My smoking friends tell me that this is the last step before people start injecting nicotine into their veins.) My mother was a lightweight at only about 2 1/2 packs of Kools or Salems a day. In 1956 the state of California put an extra penny tax on a pack of cigs. Both of my parents, independently of each other, decided to quit. They both quit cold turkey. Neither one of them ever smoked again. Now unless someone can show me a junkie that has quit smack cold turkey because his pusher put in a one penny price increase I&apos;m not buying the more addictive/most addictive arguement.

&quot;I didn&apos;t know it was bad for me&quot;went out with my grandmother&apos;s generation.
Your mother and Grandmother must have been child brides. As late as the mid to late fifties You could turn up ads like&quot;More doctors smoke Camels than any other brand!&quot;(The family went to a 50&apos;s cafe the other week, this exact ad was posted on the wall)
So there are smokers out there right now who could have started during this time. After all IIRC the first surgeons general&apos;s warning didn&apos;t come until 1962.
Don&apos;t get me wrong, I wish tobacco was on the endangered species list ralph124c 07-27-2002, 07:49 AM If the court rules that fast food causes addiction to fast food, will the government consider obese people to be disabled? Then the other travesty (THES&quot;Americans With Disabilities Act&quot;will take effect-Caeser will get government funded housing, wheelchair etc.). Also, will&quot;detox&quot;centers for the fast food&quot;addicts&quot;be st up?
This is wonderful..it should be called the&quot;lawyers employment act&quot;!! Jules4love 07-27-2002, 06:22 PM What&apos;s really sad is, he&apos;ll probably get a decent settlement out of it. It&apos;s not like there aren&apos;t precedents for this sort of thing.



and then he&apos;ll eat more fast food, have his 3rd heart attack and die!!!! Fred 07-28-2002, 04:35 PM Rex: I was incorrect about my&quot;20 cents more expensive&quot;burger, thing. Here are the actual numbers:

A Pound of Medium Ground Beef bought at cost is $2.39
A Pound of Extra Lean Ground Beef bought at cost is $2.80
A difference of $0.41.

Let&apos;s assume that a regular burger at a fast food restaurant is 2 oz. The price difference between a 2 oz Medium GB burger and a 2 oz XLean GB burger is 5 cents. Factor in the fact that less XLean GB is required to make the same amount of burger, and the price difference drops to 4 cents.

Do you seriously believe that a difference of four cents is in any way a factor in the fast food companies&apos; refusal to make their product less dangerous? ralph124c 07-28-2002, 07:15 PM ..and to paraphrase Ebeneezer Scrooge, he should die now and decrease the surplus population! He alone is responsible for his condition, and should take the consequences!
Bah, Humbug!! Beagle 07-28-2002, 11:09 PM When my friend who travels a lot - thus necessitating a lot of fast food - had a heart attack at age 35 I was considering filing a lawsuit like this one. I could not bring myself to be part of the problem and he was not that interested in pursuing it. Oh man, if this lawyer makes a billion dollars like the tobacco lawyers did, I am a moron.

There is NO significant difference between this lawsuit and the tobacco lawsuits. Addictive? Food is essential.

Next, or already in progress: alcohol, SUVs, sports cars, scuba gear, skis, swimming pools, etc... [Cue&quot;Beautiful World&quot;by Devo]

&quot;We&apos;re coming out!&quot;- Al Pacino in Devil&apos;s Advocate&quot;We&apos;re already out in force!&quot;- Beagle Typo Negative 07-29-2002, 01:36 AM Originally posted by BottledBlondJeanie
Interesting how all of you can see that this is ridiculous lawsuit, but YOU DON&apos;T KNOW IF HIS OBESITY IS DUE TO SOME GENETIC/METABOLIC ABNORMALITY. You actually blame him for his problem.
Actually, I blame him for blaming others for his problem. And for using the court to try to extort money for it. Typo Negative 07-29-2002, 01:49 AM Originally posted by Rick
Cite please? I keep hearing smokers say that smoking is more addictive than heroin. Ask, and ye shall recieve!
http://www.nida.nih.gov/researchreports/nicotine/nicotine2.html#addictive
http://www.rcplondon.ac.uk/pubs/books/nicotine/2-physical.htm
http://www.emedicine.com/med/topic1642.htm
One from the Univeristy of Minnesota (http://www1.umn.edu/perio/tobacco/nicaddct.html)Nicotine is:
1000 X more potent than alcohol
10-100 X more potent than barbiturates
5-10 X more potent than cocaine or morphine

http://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/sgr_1988.htm WV_Woman 07-29-2002, 06:25 AM small hijack ...

I definitely believe that nicotine indeed is the most addictive substance on earth, but how come some people can smoke and never get addicted and others are hooked after the first one?

I used to smoke back in 1998. It wasn&apos;t an every day thing, I would basically buy a pack, smoke &apos;em all in oh, 2 days and then not smoke again for another 3 weeks or so.

I enjoyed smoking but I never&quot;needed&quot;a cigarette, ya know? WV_Woman 07-29-2002, 06:26 AM On second thought, maybe for some people to get addicted to nicotine it takes regular exposure to it.

I&apos;m not going to test this, though, although there are times I *really* want a cigarette. TwistofFate 07-29-2002, 05:09 PM Sorry, how abot we get someone in here who actualy quit both Cigarettes and a Narcotic and they can tell us which was harder. Wether something is more potent does not make it more addictive. BottledBlondJeanie 07-29-2002, 05:46 PM To further explain my smart ass comment, I was attempting to make a point that lots of folks on this board usually defend overweight individuals and are VERY critical of blaming overweight folks for their weight. Mind you some poiints of view re this issue deserve to be smacked-down, but it appears that it&apos;s not ok to blame someone for being overweight. Yet here, everyone is doing so, yet no ones getting falmed for doing so, it just seems weird to me...

FYI, the bad genes/bad metabolism reason is usually the most cited reason, but I feel that this does NOT account for a majority of overweight people. Giraffe 07-29-2002, 06:29 PM BBJ, it&apos;s rude to assume that a random overweight person is that way by choice, due to eating too much or lack of exercise, as other factors may play a role. So, to mock someone who is overweight is ignorant and cruel, as you have no way of knowing anything about them, including why they are overweight.

In this case, you have a guy who is proclaiming&quot;I&apos;m fat because I eat way too much fast food! And it&apos;s not my fault!&quot;He is telling us that he&apos;s overweight due to overeating of extremely fatty, unhealthy food, and yet at the same time, saying his obesity is not his fault. To me, this is synonymous with&quot;Wow, I&apos;m stupid! Pay me!&quot;

There is a big difference between mocking someone because they are obese, and mocking someone who is obese because they are stupid. BottledBlondJeanie 07-29-2002, 06:42 PM How do you feel then about an obese person loading their plate up with every fried goody in the world, is it ok to then assume that person is overweight because he/she eats too much? Look everyone&apos;s body deals differently with food, but I am simply not going to assume that a majority of overweight people have a reason for it other than too much intake and too little calorie burning. Yes there are exceptions, but when I see an overweight person eating 3 times the amount of his/her caloric intake in one sitting, I&apos;m gonna call a spade a spade. I blame those individuals for their obesity.

But here, well yes, he overeats, he admits it, we acknowledge that and we blame him. Other instances on this board where this had been postulated the person received a mighty painful smackdown...including me. Giraffe 07-29-2002, 08:01 PM You can assume whatever you want about someone. Just keep it to yourself. The smackdown you describe happens when people feel the need to mock people for being overweight in a public forum.

Even if their weight is their fault, overweight people have the right to complain about how much it sucks to be heavy in our society. Our society treats overweight people very badly. This is unfair. Why is it OK to mistreat someone because they like KFC too much? Yes, many people could eat better, exercise and thereby avoid the abuse, but the abuse shouldn&apos;t be dished out in the first place.

In this thread, the guy is not being mocked for being overweight. He is being mocked for blaming his weight on the restaurants where he freely ate fatty food on a regular basis, with predictable results. He would have been mocked just as much if he tried to sue Coca Cola for drinking ten liters of soda a day and getting cavities. Beagle 07-29-2002, 09:34 PM Giraffe: He would have been mocked just as much if he tried to sue Coca Cola for drinking ten liters of soda a day and getting cavities.

Good one. *scribbling furiously* Coke has LOTS of money. JohnBckWLD 07-29-2002, 10:01 PM From the anti-trial lawyer group Citizens Against Lawsuit Abuse (http://www.stopclassactionabuse.com/)The cost of lawsuits in the U.S. amounts to a&quot;lawsuit tax&quot;of $1,200 for every man, woman and child in America. This is the cost added to the price of goods and services that you pay for as a result of litigation, settlements and liability insurance.
It&apos;s high time those of us who are sick and fucking tired of this shit these attorneys (and their irresponsible, greedy clients) clog up our courts with pay the freight.
I&apos;m calling for a class action suit against these abusers of the system.

Let&apos;s see:
7 years (statute of limitations) X $1,200 X all 280 million persons in the US = $2,385,600,000,000.

Divided by those who we&apos;ll sue:

1 million US attorneys and their lecherous clients

For a grand total of:

$2,385,000 out of the nose of each and every on &apos;em.

That oughta break em, or at least hit em where it hurts.

I want my $8,400 to come from either Ralph Nader or Johnnie Cochran. Squish 07-29-2002, 11:44 PM Originally posted by WV_Woman
I can get with you on the whining about society being unfair and blaming other people. However, it IS a pain in the ass to find clothes. And considering there is a fashion industry out there who wants every penny they can get, they would be smart to listen to the millions and millions of fat people out there and design decent clothes.

Just because we&apos;re fat doesn&apos;t mean we don&apos;t want to look as good as possible, and it doesn&apos;t mean that we don&apos;t have money to spend.&quot;Fat&quot;money will spend just as well as&quot;thin&quot;money last I checked.
Try being an overweight Goth! I went up two sizes and now buying Goth over the &apos;net is a struggle--but it&apos;s my own fault! If I got out of this chair and walked down the three flights of stairs, out the door and walked a half-mile or so every day like I used to, I&apos;d be back down to a size I could find easily.

Now, L.L.Bean, for one, makes attractive, well-made, long-wearing clothes in a very wide range of sizes at great prices. So if you&apos;re not into extremely trendy or niche styles, you do have options.

I&apos;ve seen an obese acquaintance throw catalogs across the room in a fit of rage because a dress she liked wasn&apos;t available in 2X--and then follow her evening ritual (she did this every single night) of sitting on the couch in front of the TV, chowing down on a two-pound bag of candy. Sorry, people like that get zero sympathy from me. Typo Negative 07-30-2002, 01:24 AM Originally posted by TwistofFate
Sorry, how abot we get someone in here who actualy quit both Cigarettes and a Narcotic and they can tell us which was harder. Wether something is more potent does not make it more addictive. It&apos;s been 15 years since I last got loaded. It&apos;s been 12 years since I last smoked.

Quitting smoking was a little harder. When I kicked dope, I was still able to smoke, which took a little of the edge off.

Both are tough, but possible if that&apos;s what you want to do. Tars Tarkas 07-30-2002, 02:05 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
[BDo you seriously believe that a difference of four cents is in any way a factor in the fast food companies&apos; refusal to make their product less dangerous? [/B]

Police: LOOK OUT, He&apos;s got an 80% lean Hamburger Patty!!! Go for cover!!

by your logic, Paper should be made illegal unless it is in spherical form, after all, papercuts affect dozens of ameicans each day. We must end this scourge now!! I&apos;m launching a multi-billion dollar lawsuit against Mead and 3M, on behalf of all paper-cut victims out there!!!


You know, you can drive PAST the McDonalds and go to the health food store and eat some tofu. It is possible! Why should i suffer because some Chowderhead can&apos;t keep his greasy mitts away from the fries? Typo Negative 07-30-2002, 02:43 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Do you seriously believe that a difference of four cents is in any way a factor in the fast food companies&apos; refusal to make their product less dangerous? Their products are not dangerous.

The danger was in the irresponsible use by some customers.

You are not in any danger to your health if you order a Big Mac and fries. Only if you make it the cornerstone of your diet.

We need to be clear on this point. RexDart 07-30-2002, 02:50 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Rex: I was incorrect about my&quot;20 cents more expensive&quot;burger, thing. Here are the actual numbers:

A Pound of Medium Ground Beef bought at cost is $2.39
A Pound of Extra Lean Ground Beef bought at cost is $2.80
A difference of $0.41.


Ummm, I don&apos;t think so. I buy 73% ground beef for about $1.39 per pound at the grocery store, sometimes as low as $1.19 or even lower in&quot;family pack&quot;sizes. The pound in my refrigerator right now, that I just checked, is $1.39. Surely McDonald&apos;s is getting it cheaper than I am. I don&apos;t know what you&apos;re using for your figures there. The price on the 96% sounds about right though. Maybe McD&apos;s could get that a little less expensively too, but then again maybe not. Are the suppliers for fast food chains prepared to deal in large quantities of lean beef? Maybe, maybe not. Is it available in quantities as large? Maybe, maybe not.

Anyways, it&apos;s enough of a price difference retail to significantly impact my grocery shopping. Factoring in the markup that McD&apos;s surely charges, and I can&apos;t see how it wouldn&apos;t translate into a price difference that would also impact me. For me, the difference between 73% and 96% beef is about $1.60 per pound. That translates, for me, into 40 cents per burger (presuming I make 1/4 lb burgers). What that might translate into for McD&apos;s has got to be closer to that figure. Boo Boo Foo 07-30-2002, 06:21 AM Guys, an Aussie&apos;s viewpoint?

Well, it&apos;s winter down here at the moment, and blow me down if it wasn&apos;t so cold the other day that I saw a Lawyer walking down the street with his hands in his OWN pockets... The Ace of Swords 07-30-2002, 11:12 AM Feh, I wouldn&apos;t get too worried about it if I were McDonalds. Barber&apos;s lawyer was on Crossfire doing his demagogue impression.

&quot;Fast food companies don&apos;t tell it&apos;s customers about the fat content!&quot;

Here Begala, pauses, presumably blinded by the stunning ignorance.

&quot;What!? They have it posted at every McDonalds!&quot;

Extended befuddlement by the dimwitted lawyer.

&quot;Um, but it&apos;s all the way in the back!&quot;

Whatever. Fred 07-30-2002, 11:32 AM Tar, your analogy was so inane and idiotic that it doesn&apos;t merit a response. And yet... I worry. I worry that people won&apos;t be able to see it for the abject stupidity that it is. After all, you couldn&apos;t. Otherwise, why would you have posted it? So I will explain to you the difference between paper cuts and heart disease: heart disease kills people.

spooje, I agree that careless behaviour causes fast food to become dangerous. But I don&apos;t see how careless behaviour, even repeated careless behaviour over a long period of time, warrents a death sentence. The changes that I suggest will save lives. Millions of lives. And that&apos;s why I support the changes that I support.

Rex, I should have pointed out that all figures are in Canadian dollars. However, regardless of what you think, and regardless how much you pay, that is what the grocery store that I used to obtain those figures pays for ground beef. $0.41 is the actual difference in price, at cost, in Canadian dollars.

Note that I was referring to a 4 cent increase for a regular burger, not a quarter pounder. The difference in price for a quarter pounder would be, using the at cost figures that I got from the grocery store, 10 cents. I stand by my earlier statement that these price differences, implemented while switching to a better tasting and better for you product, would go pretty much unnoticed.

Out of curiosity, can you show me what your grocery stores pays from Medium and XLean ground beef? Typo Negative 07-31-2002, 01:21 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
spooje, I agree that careless behaviour causes fast food to become dangerous. But I don&apos;t see how careless behaviour, even repeated careless behaviour over a long period of time, warrents a death sentence. The changes that I suggest will save lives. Millions of lives. And that&apos;s why I support the changes that I support.The behaviour does not warrent a death sentence. Neither does it amount to a big payday.

You want healthy food served to the public? You think the public will buy it? Then open yourself up a food joint. I don&apos;t think we should tell fast food joints how to run their businesses simply because some of their customers are in fact the lowest common denominator.

If I want fat, greasy, tasty food, that is my right. And McDonalds, if they want my business, is entiltle to profit from that. If I want healthy food, I go somewheres else.

As I see it, this is not a health issue. It&apos;s a personal responsibilty issue. Do you take responsibilty for your actions? I bet you do. I know I do. Why shouldn&apos;t Cesar Barbar????

Look, whatever happened to him, it&apos;s not McDonalds fault. Therefore, they shouldn&apos;t pay this guy a dime. Tars Tarkas 07-31-2002, 01:50 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Tar, your analogy was so inane and idiotic that it doesn&apos;t merit a response. And yet... I worry. I worry that people won&apos;t be able to see it for the abject stupidity that it is. After all, you couldn&apos;t. Otherwise, why would you have posted it? So I will explain to you the difference between paper cuts and heart disease: heart disease kills people.


And yet both are preventable by being careful. But i guess its just easier to sue and blame others. And yet... I worry. I worry that people won&apos;t be able to see it for the abject stupidity that it is. After all, you couldn&apos;t. Otherwise, why would you have posted it? So i will explain to you personal responibility: Taking responsiblilty for your own actions. Fred 07-31-2002, 01:55 AM You seem to be arguing two things here, spooje.

1. The fast food industry has the right to kill people with its product, as long as people aren&apos;t forced to use it.

2. The individual in this case is responsible for his own state.

I emphatically disagree with point number one. Point number two is more complicated.

I don&apos;t buy for one second the&quot;I was tricked into thinking burgers are healthy&quot;excuse. However, anyone who doesn&apos;t believe that the fast food industry both encourages and enjoys the profits from persons such as Mr. Barbar purchasing their product to an unhealthy extent is fooling themself. Without such persons, the fast food industry would lose, literally, shitloads of money1. The fast food industry has profited off this man&apos;s self-destruction, but moreover, the industry could have made changes to prevent not only this case, but millions and millions of others just like it. For knowing the danger of their product, refusing to reduce the risks associated with the product, and for encouraging the use the product in a dangerous manner, they are responsible, if not wholly then partially, for the health issues discussed in this suit.

This statement assumes that a shitload is a 10 pound bag of manure, and that said the money the fast food industry would lose is equal to the amount of money in multiple shitloads filled with thousand dollar bills Typo Negative 07-31-2002, 02:04 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death

1. The fast food industry has the right to kill people with its product, as long as people aren&apos;t forced to use it.

Straw man.

The product doesn&apos;t kill. There is nothing inherently dangerous about the product. NOTHING.

It is only the irresponsible use that results in harm. And the fast food joints have no control over that. And they shouldn&apos;t. Fred 07-31-2002, 02:14 AM Tar: here&apos;s another difference between papercuts and heart disease that you&apos;re obviously too stupid to grasp.

Heart disease is a natural consequence of using fast food the way the fast food industry wants consumers to use it. Papercuts are accidents that bear no relationship at all to the way 3M wishes paper to be used.

I can continue, if you want. Feel free to copy and paste this post and change a few words around, if you feel you can&apos;t manage making up sentences of your own. Tars Tarkas 07-31-2002, 02:19 AM dea: So the fast food industry controls your life? are you a slave? have you no free will? Do you always do what the fast food industry says to do? are you that gullible? did you know gullible isn&apos;t in the dictionary? are you too stupid to understand personal responsibility, or are you too busy calling your lawyer trying to sue McD&apos;s yourself? Fred 07-31-2002, 02:30 AM It is only the irresponsible use that results in harm. And the fast food joints have no control over that.


This is demonstrably incorrect, spooje. Fast food restaurants do have control over whether&quot;irresponsible&quot;use of their product results in harm. I&apos;ve made that point time and again, and you&apos;ve never chose to debate it before now. But since you have, I&apos;m interested in your opinion: What prevents fast food joints from changing their product so that it is less dangerous to those that use it often? Rex pretty much abandoned his bizarre statement that it would ruin the&quot;low cost&quot;benifit of fast food lunch, and didn&apos;t really come up with another reason. I&apos;m curious as to where you are coming from on this.

By the way, I thought your bit about an average joe being able to open a fast food restaurant that can effectively compete with the likes of McDonald&apos;s and Burger King was pretty funny. Unless you were serious, in which case your optimism is admirable, to say the least. Fred 07-31-2002, 02:38 AM You know, Mr. Tarkas, I give myself a moment before I hit&quot;Submit Reply&quot;to imagine what wild and fantastic way you plan on misinterpreting my post. To your credit, you have always managed to surprise me. To answer your questions, in order:

No. No. You shouldn&apos;t ask a question containing a negative -- it&apos;s confusing. For example, I could answer either&quot;No, I have no free will,&quot;Or,&quot;No, I do indeed have free will&quot;; even though I answered&quot;No&quot;both times, the answers were opposite. No. No. Trick Question in the form of&quot;Have you stopped beating your wife&quot;, and again with the negative in the question. Whatever fallacy it is when one is given an either/or choice in which other options are available. Typo Negative 07-31-2002, 03:04 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
I&apos;m interested in your opinion: What prevents fast food joints from changing their product so that it is less dangerous to those that use it often? [What prevents them? Nothing.

Do you know of something that CANNOT be abused? Any food or beverage that will not cause problems if over-indulged.

Is alcohol bad? We know there are problems when people consume too much. Should it be outlawed? Or diluted to &apos;safer&apos; level? Or should we expect people to use responsilbly and hold them accountable when they don&apos;t?

Those people that use it too often and whine about it ARE THE PROBLEM. They chose to use it. And they probably chose to live sedentary lifestyles also. If they wanna eat junk and be couch potatoes, I got no problem with that. It&apos;s a free country. But just don&apos;t blame anyone for the results.

I like McDonalds food. It tastes good to me, just like it is. And it&apos;s convenient. And they seem to be making money. An all around good situation. I don&apos;t eat it that often. That seems to be the key. Moderation

Answer me this. Why make them change because of the actions of morons? And that&apos;s what these particular indivuals are. Morons. They make fast food the cornerstone of their diet and they think they are victims???? NO. They&apos;re morons!!!We shouldn&apos;t be making changes to save these people from themselves. We should be expecting them to take responsibilty for their own lives. If we do that, America will be a better place. Typo Negative 07-31-2002, 03:06 AM OK, the 3rd paragraph was added in after the 4th.

I meant to be referring to the people who eat the fast food and whine about it.

My bad. lurkernomore 07-31-2002, 07:00 AM Gee, the manufacturers want us to use their product all the time. Let&apos;s see - the hamburgers at Mickey Ds are ground beef. The people who sell it probably want us to eat it six times a day. Protect the people! Ban it! Prohibition on beef! Make vegetarianism a legal requirement!

Potatoes are fine for you if they are baked - ban deep fryers! Sell cooking oil only in very small quantities, enough for a stir-fry, but not deep fat frying! No more than 2 oz. a bottle, and restrict people to 3 bottles a week for a family of 5!

Big Brother is watching OUT for you. DeadlyAccurate 07-31-2002, 09:21 AM I&apos;m going out to eat tonight. I&apos;m going to order onion soup with provolone cheese broiled on top and dinner rolls with real butter. I might even get an order of fried mushrooms if they have them. Then, I&apos;m going to come back home and call my lawyer and sue the hell out of the restaurant for daring to serve me food like that. I mean, how could they? Don&apos;t they know that real butter has cholesterol? Aren&apos;t they aware of the number of calories in fried mushrooms? What right do they have to profit off of my arteries? D_Odds 07-31-2002, 09:52 AM If you&apos;re going to improve the health profile of a big mac, it&apos;s not just the beef. Out go the cheese and special sauce (no, I don&apos;t want to know what&apos;s special about it, thank you). Then you&apos;ll have to do away with fries, as they&apos;re worse than the burgers nutritionally.

What next? Sugary drinks? 7-11 better downsize their Big Gulps. Baskin-Robbins, Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s, Friendly&apos;s and Mr. Softee better start rationing. Do we mail people a weekly coupon for their ice cream allotment?

I&apos;m sorry grim, you&apos;re suggestion doesn&apos;t even begin to solve the problem. The problem is over-consumption. IMNSHO, if Mr. Barber were addicted to pizza, which are not dominated by the big chains, there wouldn&apos;t be a lawsuit because there wouldn&apos;t be a payout. Unless, of course, he only ate Pizza Hut.

Convenient or not, no one forced him to eat fast food. When the weight started packing on and he had his first heart attack, perhaps he should have let the clue stick smack him rather than avoiding it for two more. His fault, completely. He actively avoided good nutritional information and remedying solutions to his condition.

If anyone is going to try fast food joints and drink manufacturers, I would suggest parents of children with type 2 diabetes. Targeting advertising to a more susceptible population and working to provide the product at every turn, while legal, is altogether evil in my book. Hamadryad 07-31-2002, 10:38 AM I think the thing that kills me are the people arguing that some people just don&apos;t have TIME to eat healthily!

Uh? Do you go to the store to buy soap? Toilet paper? Toothpaste? Then you can pick up food there, get up 15 minutes earlier and make your damned lunch.

It&apos;s not the responsibility of fast food places to serve healthy food. It&apos;s the responsibility of individuals to eat healthy food.&quot;I just don&apos;t have TIII-YIIIIME!&quot;is both untrue AND lazy.

I am eating greasy microwave popcorn. I could be eating raw spinach. I even LIKE raw spinach. But I&apos;m not going to sue the goddamned grocery store for selling me the popcorn.

Christ, people. I can&apos;t believe there are folks in here arguing for the right to LAY GODDAMNED BLAME. What happened to personal accountability? lurkernomore 07-31-2002, 10:56 AM Originally posted by Hamadryad
What happened to personal accountability?


It&apos;s politically incorrect. Next buildings will have court-mandated wider doors, so fatasses like this guy can get in without greasing their hips. Giraffe 07-31-2002, 11:33 AM Originally posted by lurkernomore
It&apos;s politically incorrect. Next buildings will have court-mandated wider doors, so fatasses like this guy can get in without greasing their hips. Ah, the mandatory potshot at political correctness. That&apos;s the real problem -- PC nazis who won&apos;t let us mock the fatties. They want everyone to be fat, because they think being fat and lazy is better.

Don&apos;t worry -- at the same time we widen the doors, we&apos;ll also put the doorknobs lower, so shitheads like you don&apos;t have to pull their heads out of their asses to enter the building. Fred 07-31-2002, 11:58 AM spooje, this statement by you:


What prevents them [from controlling whether irresponsible use of their product causes harm]? Nothing.


is in direct contradiction to this one, also by you:


The fast food joints have no control over that [whether the irresponsible use of their product causes harm]


Perhaps I&apos;m misinterpreting you. Which statement is the one you believe?

Also, alcohol is a bad example for you to bring up, being as how it&apos;s heavily regulated in distribution, advertising, taxation, etc. If you are saying that alcohol is anagolous to fast food, I assume you support the same heavy regulations for fast food.

lurkernomore, I don&apos;t know if you&apos;ve noticed this, but someone already did the&quot;Take Fred&apos;s comments to an absurd extreme -- with exclamation points!!!&quot;bit. Tar Tarkas did it way back on page two.

D_Odds, you seem to be confusing&quot;All&quot;with&quot;Part&quot;. These statements in particular


If you&apos;re going to improve the health profile of a big mac, it&apos;s not just the beef.
...
I&apos;m sorry grim, you&apos;re suggestion doesn&apos;t even begin to solve the problem.


Actually, if you&apos;re going to improve the health profile of a hamburger, the beef is as good a place to start as any. The fact that there are other components to a burger is irrelevent to the fact that changing to a healthier patty makes the entire burger healthier. My suggestion does even begin to solve the problem -- does it solve the problem completely? No. But it begins too. Your statements are completely incorrect.

Hamadryad:


It&apos;s not the responsibility of fast food places to serve healthy food.


I never said it was. My position is that it should be the responsibility of fast food places to serve food that doesn&apos;t cause millions of deaths. Do you disagree with this point?

On a sidenote, I find it interesting that in all the talk of&quot;responsibility&quot;and&quot;accountability,&quot;while I have no problem laying blame on Mr. Barbar for his condition, I have yet to see a single other person discuss the&quot;responsibility&quot;or&quot;accountability&quot;that the fast food industry has for their own product, except to claim that the industry isn&apos;t responsible at all for the product it sells. Responsibility isn&apos;t an all or nothing game, especially when it comes to torts. The courts regularly rule that the defendant was not wholly responsible, but rather a certain percent. The question here is, what percent, if any, is the fast food industry responsible for Mr. Barbar, and those like him. I&apos;m willing to concede that it isn&apos;t 100%. Are you guys willing to think about the fact that it might not be 0%? D_Odds 07-31-2002, 12:25 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
D_Odds, you seem to be confusing&quot;All&quot;with&quot;Part&quot;. These statements in particular

Actually, if you&apos;re going to improve the health profile of a hamburger, the beef is as good a place to start as any. The fact that there are other components to a burger is irrelevent to the fact that changing to a healthier patty makes the entire burger healthier. My suggestion does even begin to solve the problem -- does it solve the problem completely? No. But it begins too. Your statements are completely incorrect.

I&apos;ll concede an inch (and no more). It begins to solve the problem, but only in the same way that banning .22 calibre bullets would begin to solve the problem of gun violence.

I never said it was. My position is that it should be the responsibility of fast food places to serve food that doesn&apos;t cause millions of deaths. Do you disagree with this point?
Whole-heartedly. You take this to the ridiculous extreme (which is what will happen if such a statement is proven true and there are contingency fees to be made) and then there will be no cars on the road. After all, despite all the safety advances that are made, they are still responsible for millions of deaths. Yes, hold the car makers liable if they sell an intentionally defective product (Firestone&apos;s tires on Ford Explorers). Hold McDonalds liable if it sells contaminated food due to sloppy handling procedures. But we don&apos;t hold car makers because an idiot slams it into a wall or another car at 100mph, even though they could conceivably cap maximum speed. It&apos;s an abuse of a product. Just as is basing your nutritional requirements on a diet of Big Macs and french fries. IMO, a person would have to [i]actively avoid information about nutrition not to know that a fast food diet is bad for oneself.
On a sidenote, I find it interesting that in all the talk of&quot;responsibility&quot;and&quot;accountability,&quot;while I have no problem laying blame on Mr. Barbar for his condition, I have yet to see a single other person discuss the&quot;responsibility&quot;or&quot;accountability&quot;that the fast food industry has for their own product, except to claim that the industry isn&apos;t responsible at all for the product it sells.
See above. By your reasoning, then cheap ground beef and french fries and Twinkies and any other nutritionally void food should be removed from supermarket shelves also.
Responsibility isn&apos;t an all or nothing game, especially when it comes to torts.
At least one point we can agree upon. Just not to it&apos;s application in this proposed litigation. artemis 07-31-2002, 12:34 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
My position is that it should be the responsibility of fast food places to serve food that doesn&apos;t cause millions of deaths.

Grim, you seem to be operating under a fundamental misconception - that there is such a thing as&quot;healthy&quot;food. There isn&apos;t.&quot;Healthy&quot;food does not exist! Any food eaten in excess can cause serious problems. A McDonald&apos;s hamburger, eaten occasionally, provides valuable protein, carbohydrates, fats, and other nutrients. Eaten in excess, it may result in health problems - but so will any other food you can name, even celery. Should we require grocery stores to put warning labels on celery -&quot;WARNING! Overconsumption of this food product will lead to serious disease, at it is practically devoid of nutrients! Consume at your own risk!&quot;?

And as for your argument that fast food causes health problems if used the way the fast food companies would like consumers to do - so what? The casino down the road from my house would absolutely LOVE it if I were to spend 8 hours a day, every day, playing their slot machines - but if I do so, and subsequently have too little money left to pay my rent and get evicted as a consequence, it&apos;s MY fault, not theirs. The local shopping mall would also be delighted if I spent this month&apos;s rent on clothes, DVDs, ect., instead of sticking to my budget. Responsible adults control their own behavior, rather than allowing others to regulate it. The man bring this lawsuit is an adult, not a child - and is therefore it is his responsiblity to choose a healthy diet to follow, the same way he must be responsible for making other choices with serious repercussions (such as wearing condoms when having sex, fastening his seatbelt when driving his car, following the prescription directions when taking medications, etc.) That&apos;s what it means to be an adult. artemis 07-31-2002, 12:44 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
[On a sidenote, I find it interesting that in all the talk of&quot;responsibility&quot;and&quot;accountability,&quot;while I have no problem laying blame on Mr. Barbar for his condition, I have yet to see a single other person discuss the&quot;responsibility&quot;or&quot;accountability&quot;that the fast food industry has for their own product, except to claim that the industry isn&apos;t responsible at all for the product it sells. Responsibility isn&apos;t an all or nothing game, especially when it comes to torts.

All right, I&apos;ll address it. The fast food industry DOES have a responsibility to inform consumers of the contents and nutritional value of their products - a responsibility which they&apos;ve already met by providing nutritional information (including total calories in each item, the percentage of calories one serving of said item occupies in a 2000 calorie/day diet, and the percentages and amounts of protein, carbohydrates, fat, and sodium in each item). They&apos;ve ALREADY provided consumers with the information needed to make sensible choices with regards to consuming their products - and that&apos;s where their responsibility ends. If the consumer chooses not to use that information, that&apos;s the consumer&apos;s choice - and the results of that choice are the consumer&apos;s responsibility, not the fast food restauraunt&apos;s. Hamadryad 07-31-2002, 12:49 PM &lt;wholly inflammatory remark&gt;
I should sue the grim spectre of red death for the death of my brain cells....&lt;/WIR&gt;...the idea that every place everywhere that sells anything remotely harmful should be liable for the stupid misuse of their products makes me feel stupider. The mere idea that McDonald&apos;s could be held remotely responsible for a supposed adult&apos;s weight gain (and subsequent health problems) is so far-fetched as to be almost incomprehensible.

We can sue ANYONE. You didn&apos;t lock up the Clorox and Baby Junior dies from drinking it? It&apos;s not YOUR fault for not locking it up...sue the hardware store that sold it to you. Your best friend skidded on a sharp turn in the rain and died? Sue the DOT - Division of Highways for not researching more wet-slip-resistant paving materials. It&apos;s THEIR fault. Baby Junior survived the Clorox incident, but he&apos;s flunking Algebra? Sue the school system for not requiring peer-group promotion. Baby Junior miraculously graduates from high school, joins the Army, and gets killed in a knife fight in an off-base bar? Sue the Army for not keeping track of him.

Taking a logical idea to an illogical extreme? Yeah. So&apos;s suing a greasy fast-food joint for making you fat and unhealthy.

Someone should sue this guy&apos;s lawyer for criminal negligence. Through his inability to say&quot;no&quot;to a possible fat paycheck, he&apos;s encouraging this guy&apos;s mental instability. Fred 07-31-2002, 12:53 PM I&apos;ve always felt that the car industry was a better analogy to the current situation, and I&apos;m glad you brought it up. I&apos;m glad because it suits my position better than it does yours.

Car makers are required by governmental regulations to make their products as safe as possible. Car manufacturers can not, for example, save costs by not installing seatbelts in their car. Even better for me, the automotive industry takes into account the irresponsible use of their product, and makes changes to minimize the dangers thereof. Considering your belief that the two industries are analogous, why shouldn&apos;t the fast food industry do the same? lurkernomore 07-31-2002, 12:55 PM Originally posted by Giraffe
Ah, the mandatory potshot at political correctness. That&apos;s the real problem -- PC nazis who won&apos;t let us mock the fatties. They want everyone to be fat, because they think being fat and lazy is better.


No, the PC&quot;everyone is a victim&quot;credo. People have to take responsibility for their actions. If you eat a lot of fried foods, you are probably going to be fat. That was the choice you made when you went there for lunch every day. It&apos;s a result of your own actions. No one forced you to go there. I have several fat friends, who admit honestly they are fat because THEY EAT TOO MUCH!! I didn&apos;t say anything against fat people, just the it&apos;s-your-fault-I&apos;m-fat people.

Oh, who mentioned&quot;lazy&quot;? Are you stereotyping fat people as lazy? Giraffe 07-31-2002, 01:14 PM Who said people don&apos;t have to take responsibility for their actions? Have you heard some massive outcry that we&apos;ve all missed? How does this lawsuit in any way relate to political correctness?

Whining about political correctness as a debate position is the pathetic strawman copout of mentally incompetent assholes. Fred 07-31-2002, 01:22 PM artemis, now you&apos;re just being silly. There&apos;s no such thing as&quot;health food&quot;? That statement is so demonstrably false I&apos;m not even going to try to discredit it. IN addition, There&apos;s an obvious difference between eating fast food to excess and eating, say, celery to excess: One&quot;excess&quot;is eating twice a week. The other&quot;excess&quot;is eating a pound a meal. You&apos;re not honestly trying to tell me you can&apos;t see the difference there.

Oh by the way,


The man bring this lawsuit is an adult, not a child - and is therefore it is his responsiblity to choose a healthy diet to follow, the same way he must be responsible for making other choices with serious repercussions (such as wearing condoms when having sex, fastening his seatbelt when driving his car, following the prescription directions when taking medications, etc.) That&apos;s what it means to be an adult.


(bolding my own), did you really mean to include this as an example? Because it&apos;s pretty foolish of you to do so.

Hamadryad, you realize that if you throw one more false analogy at me, you get a free gift? Your analogies are false because in every case the product you mention is used in the way opposite to the manufacturers/person you plan on suing&apos;s intent, whereas eating fast food&quot;in excess&quot;is the obvious intent of the fast food industry. I&apos;ve said this over and over and over again. Do you need me to say it one more time? I guess I will have to:

You will not make any valid points by non sequiter analogies that, other than the fact that they involve harm to a person, have nothing to do with the situation at hand. This will never, ever, ever, work. Stop it. Hamadryad 07-31-2002, 01:36 PM &quot;You will not make any valid points by non sequiter analogies that, other than the fact that they involve harm to a person, have nothing to do with the situation at hand. This will never, ever, ever, work. Stop it.&quot;

The higher up you get on that horse, the more adorable you become. Maybe it&apos;s the view up the nostrils that I find so maddeningly appealing.

Okay. You go to a store. You buy a cubic zirconium. When you get it home, have it appraised, and it&apos;s a cubic zirconium, do you sue the store from which you bought it for selling you a cubic zirconium when you would have preferred a diamond? No. Because you did not BUY a diamond. You bought a cubic zirconium.

McDonald&apos;s (or Taco Bell or Long John Silver&apos;s or Wendy&apos;s or....) has never claimed to be a purveyor of healthy foodstuffs. They do offer salads, should you require a lower-fat alternative to their usual fare. It&apos;s not as tasty as a 20-piece McNuggets with extra hot mustard sauce and a Gawddamn Big Fries, but it is food and it is fast and McDonald&apos;s has it.

I don&apos;t recall any point in time at which McDonald&apos;s has tried to pretend that they do NOT deep-fry their fried foods, or that their sauces are in the same GALAXY as low-fat...except on specific foods (a couple of which have been mentioned in this thread).

There are places where lower-fat alternatives to fast food can be had, should fast food be necessary...one of which is the grocery store.

It&apos;s pretty much a given that deep fried foods are very fattening, and has been for many years. I have no cite, but I can&apos;t imagine anyone leaping to the conclusion that&quot;fried in fat = less fat.&quot;

Therefore, if one eats a deep-fried food at a place which is known to serve food that is high in fat, one cannot claim that one unknowingly partook in foods that were high in fat.

As the Franchise Wars have yet to take place, and McDonald&apos;s does not have control over the nation&apos;s take-out food supply, I think it can be assumed with some measure of assurance that this man knowingly and deliberately ate excessively of foods which were bad for him, even though an alternative was available to him.

I don&apos;t think there&apos;s any way a reasonable person could expect that the store in question be held responsible for his subsequent debilitation. D_Odds 07-31-2002, 02:09 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
I&apos;ve always felt that the car industry was a better analogy to the current situation, and I&apos;m glad you brought it up. I&apos;m glad because it suits my position better than it does yours.

Car makers are required by governmental regulations to make their products as safe as possible. Car manufacturers can not, for example, save costs by not installing seatbelts in their car. Even better for me, the automotive industry takes into account the irresponsible use of their product, and makes changes to minimize the dangers thereof. Considering your belief that the two industries are analogous, why shouldn&apos;t the fast food industry do the same?
I do believe the two industries analagous. The auto industry does everything mandated by law to make a safe product. Some companies go above and beyond (Volvo).

McDonalds and BK do everything required by law to make a safe product. In terms of cleanliness, quality of food, rotation and handling, both go to extremes (at the corporate level) to maximize both use and safety.

Does every SUV have a rollover cage? No. Could it? Yes. Does that make the auto manufacturers liable for every rollover. Not unless the overall design is unsafe.

Do fast food producres use the leanest beef? No. Could they? Yes. I&apos;d argue the leanest beef does not make the best burgers (too dry), but neither does the fattiest. Is the overall design unsafe...?

I believe we differ in opinion on that last question. Fatty foods are not in and of themselves unsafe. That is my contention. Abuse of fatty foods is, just like driving a car 100 mph is. Even though the car goes 100 mph, you don&apos;t have to drive it that fast, and it isn&apos;t the manufacturer&apos;s fault when you do. Or do you propose making the case that no car should be made that can top 70 mph? Even though overconsumption of fatty foods can lead to serious health problems, it should not be the manufacturers fault that you overconsume.

That&apos;s my story, I&apos;m sticking with it. Fred 07-31-2002, 02:11 PM I like the diamond analogy better. But I still feel it&apos;s flawed. Personally, I believe that a company has a higher responsibility to the public at large if their product causes millions of deaths.


McDonald&apos;s (or Taco Bell or Long John Silver&apos;s or Wendy&apos;s or....) has never claimed to be a purveyor of healthy foodstuffs. They do offer salads, should you require a lower-fat alternative to their usual fare. It&apos;s not as tasty as a 20-piece McNuggets with extra hot mustard sauce and a Gawddamn Big Fries, but it is food and it is fast and McDonald&apos;s has it.


The point I&apos;m trying to make is that a lower-fat alternative that is tastier than a Whopper/Big Mac with Supersized fries exists. The fast food industry refuses to make this product available. I have a major ethical problem with that, as everyone in this thread should.


As the Franchise Wars have yet to take place, and McDonald&apos;s does not have control over the nation&apos;s take-out food supply, I think it can be assumed with some measure of assurance that this man knowingly and deliberately ate excessively of foods which were bad for him, even though an alternative was available to him.


Again, the alternative is not available to him, as I have stated above. Note also that I have always referred to the fast food industry as a whole, rather than hilighting a specific chain. Hamadryad 07-31-2002, 02:17 PM &quot;The point I&apos;m trying to make is that a lower-fat alternative that is tastier than a Whopper/Big Mac with Supersized fries exists. The fast food industry refuses to make this product available.&quot;

As was pointed out, they did make this product available (the McLean Deluxe). It sold very, very poorly. They stopped selling it.

Apparently not enough people were making the responsible choice to eat it...much like this yahoo did not make the responsible choice to NOT repeatedly eat heartily of foods which were quite obviously high in fat.

So it looks like it&apos;s this guy&apos;s (and people like him) fault after all. Go figure. Hamadryad 07-31-2002, 02:26 PM &quot;The fast food industry refuses to make this product available. I have a major ethical problem with that, as everyone in this thread should.&quot;

Wait...what? I should find it unethical that fast food joints don&apos;t stock healthy food? Unethical? I honestly do NOT understand what you mean. Should I also find it unethical that they do not carry food specifically for those who keep kosher or have other religious dietary requirements? Is it unethical that they don&apos;t carry desserts suitable for diabetics?

I really don&apos;t understand what ethics have to do with it. Should we also be after the movie theaters, on ethical grounds, since they only serve over-priced high-fat high-sugar treats?

I&apos;m at a loss, here. Fred 07-31-2002, 02:33 PM McDonalds and BK do everything required by law to make a safe product.


It is my position that the law is woefully inadequate, given the extent of the problem. I believe that law suits, such as this one, are the only way that an individual can effectively pressure the fast food industry to make their product exponentially less dangerous.

As for your aside, I must direct you to my first post, in which I point out that the lean ground beef indicated beat regular ground beef in every category, including&quot;juiciness&quot;.


Abuse of fatty foods is [where the danger lies], just like driving a car 100 mph is.


Again, I must point out that the automotive industry is forced by law to include safety measures that protect the lives of car owners, even those car owners that drive irresponsibly. Why shouldn&apos;t the fast food industry do the same? Tars Tarkas 07-31-2002, 02:45 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
I like the diamond analogy better. But I still feel it&apos;s flawed.


Nice pun


Personally, I believe that a company has a higher responsibility to the public at large if their product causes millions of deaths.


Cite for the millions of deaths please, and make sure it proves conclusively that their deaths were entirely caused by eating at fast food restarants and not due to not exercising and living unhealthy lifestyles. Fred 07-31-2002, 02:53 PM Hamadryad, I&apos;ve already addressed the Mclean Burger. Here it is again, from page 2.


Road Rash: You are partially correct, sir. The McLean burger did not sell. But the reason it did not sell is emphatically not because it was an inferior product. In fact, as I&apos;ve already shown, it was superior to regular burgers in every way, including taste. The quality of a product doesn&apos;t translate into sales: the marketing does. Think New Coke, friend. The answer lies in the marketing. People are trained since birth (like Pavlov&apos;s dogs, only without bells) to make a correlation between how good a food is for you, and how good it tastes. Why else would people believe Cod Liver Oil is good for you? We&apos;ve been programmed to believe that it&apos;s impossible for a burger to both taste great and be less filling - Oops, less fattening. The fact that the McLean was marketed as a Lean burger spelled its doom. Had McDonald&apos;s merely switched from their regular burgers to the lean kind, dollars to doughnuts say no one would have been able to tell the difference.


Taa daa!

I dunno what to tell you about the ethics, thing, though. I mean, Company refuses to change product that kills millions so that product no longer kills millions. Seems simple to me. Darwin&apos;s Finch 07-31-2002, 02:56 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Car makers are required by governmental regulations to make their products as safe as possible.

No, they aren&apos;t. They are required to meet certain minimum safety standards. Everything else is gravy.

Similarly, fast food restaurants are required to meet certain minimum requirements, as set forth by the FDA (for the food, and handling standards thereof -- this includes making available upon request nutritional information for each product sold) and whatever local health agencies the restaurant may have to answer to (for the condition of the restaurant itself).

Accepting responsibility for what people do with the car once they get it, or the food once they get it, is not part of either&apos;s requirements. JellyfishRhythm 07-31-2002, 03:02 PM I&apos;m not sure if i missed it, but is there a cite grim that any of these products cause millions of deaths? Fred 07-31-2002, 03:02 PM You&apos;re right of course, Mr. Tarkas. I have been cheating. Add the words&quot;is a major contributing factor to&quot;before any death figures I&apos;ve quoted in thread. Fred 07-31-2002, 03:21 PM You are also correct, Sir Finch. As safe as possible was an exagerration. Replace that with my later statement,&quot;the automotive industry is forced by law to include safety measures that protect the lives of car owners, even those car owners that drive irresponsibly.&quot;This was what I intended to say. artemis 07-31-2002, 03:32 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
artemis, now you&apos;re just being silly. There&apos;s no such thing as&quot;health food&quot;? That statement is so demonstrably false I&apos;m not even going to try to discredit it.

No, I am not being silly - there is no such thing as&quot;health food&quot;. There is merely food. There issuch a thing as a healthy diet and lifestyle - but ANY type of food, consumed in reasonable quantities, can be included as a part of a healthy diet.

IN addition, There&apos;s an obvious difference between eating fast food to excess and eating, say, celery to excess: One&quot;excess&quot;is eating twice a week. The other&quot;excess&quot;is eating a pound a meal. You&apos;re not honestly trying to tell me you can&apos;t see the difference there.

No, I do not see the difference there - overconsumption of either item leads to serious health problems. Excess is excess. Or are you seriously trying to argue that a person MUST consume fast food twice a week? Is there some sort of law requiring this that I&apos;m unaware of? I haven&apos;t eaten any fast food in weeks - how can I possibly have managed such a feat? Could it possibly be that I excercised my responsibility as a mature adult and chose different food items?

Oh by the way, (bolding my own), did you really mean to include this as an example? Because it&apos;s pretty foolish of you to do so.

No, it&apos;s not - it&apos;s merely using the same reasoning that you&apos;re applying to fast food consumption and applying it to another food item that can also be misused. People HAVE gone on strange food binges, such as&quot;all grapefruit&quot;diets, or eating a pound of carrots a day - by your logic, they should be able to sue the grocery stores for their resulting health problems.

Hamadryad, you realize that if you throw one more false analogy at me, you get a free gift? Your analogies are false because in every case the product you mention is used in the way opposite to the manufacturers/person you plan on suing&apos;s intent, whereas eating fast food&quot;in excess&quot;is the obvious intent of the fast food industry.

The manufacturer&apos;s intent is irrelevent in this case - it doesn&apos;t matter how badly the fast food industry may want people to consume their foods&quot;in excesss&quot;, as they have no ability to compel people to do so. You are prefectly free to make other foood choices, and there is NOTHING McDonalds can do to stop you, however much they might like to.

And as for your analogy to cars and Federal regulations - car manufacturers are NOT required to make vehicles&quot;as safe as possible&quot;- because such a standard can never be met. They ARE required to meet certain minimun safety regulations that the government imposes; they are free to add additional safety features if they wish (and some, such as Volvo, do), but this is not a requirement. That situation is exactly analagous to the regulation of the fast food industry, which MUST comply with laws regulating the safe handling and storage of food, and MUST supply the consumer with nutritional information about their products - but are not required to go any further (although they are certainly free to alter their menus in whatever way they wish - and will do so if consumer demand is high enough). pldennison 07-31-2002, 03:38 PM The point I&apos;m trying to make is that a lower-fat alternative that is tastier than a Whopper/Big Mac with Supersized fries exists. The fast food industry refuses to make this product available. I have a major ethical problem with that, as everyone in this thread should.

Horsefeathers. The fact that another product exists does not obligate any restaurant to sell it, any more than the existence of Gardenburgers obligates them to sell it to me, a vegetarian. You know what my solution is? Take a wild guess. I don&apos;t eat at fast food places. Unless I want a shake, or some fries.

The product is available, it just isn&apos;t available at a burger joint. You can go into a grocery store, however, and buy all you want, and take home and cook and eat as much as you want. The fast food industry isn&apos;t keeping it off the market, they just aren&apos;t selling it. How anyone can argue otherwise with a straight face baffles me.


Again, the alternative is not available to him, as I have stated above.

But you&apos;re simply, and laughably, incorrect. This guy doesn&apos;t live in the hinterlands of central Wyoming or something. He lives in New York Farkin&apos; City, in the Bronx. There is hardly a shortage of eatieries in New York, fer cryin&apos; out loud. He could eat anywhere he wanted, or cook for himself.

You&apos;ll notice that he isn&apos;t suing Mike&apos;s Burger Joint or Steve&apos;s Hot Dog Hut -- he&apos;s going after four particular chains with deep, deep pockets.

The idea that he could be 56 years old and not be aware that fatty foods were bad for you -- after having two heart attacks!-- is ludicrous, and I hope to heaven the jury realizes that. Americans have been inundated with bad news about fat, cholesterol and fried foods for around 30 years now! Was this guy living in a cave on Mars with his eyes closed and his fingers in his ears? When he started to get fat, did he ever think,&quot;Wow, I wonder if it has something to do with eating at fast food places five times a week?&quot;Or is he just willfully ignorant?

Every fast-food restaurant I&apos;ve ever been in has the nutritional information posted on a big poster right by the counter. Burger King has for years touted their burgers as healthier than the competition&apos;s because they are flame-broiled rather than fried. You can see the freaking kitchen from the counter, with the fries bubbling away in fat and the grease-covered grill. If this guy is not simply an opportunist looking for a buck, he may be functionally retarded. Fred 07-31-2002, 04:10 PM Actually, artemis, this statement


Oh by the way, (bolding my own), did you really mean to include this as an example? Because it&apos;s pretty foolish of you to do so.


was referring to the fact that you included seatbelts as an example of adult responsibility, when, in fact, most places have mandatory seat belt laws.

I note that both you and Darwin&apos;s Finch spotted the same flaw in my reasoning vis a vis the automotive industry. I accept that I was in error.

I wish to state that I&apos;m not particularly wedded to this suit in particular. In fact, if you&apos;ll notice, I&apos;ve never said one word in support of it. I believe the idea that Mr. Barbar was somehow bamboozled into believing fast food is healthy is very silly indeed. I&apos;m looking, instead, at the fast food industry as a whole. And, under strictly Libertarian principles, I don&apos;t have a leg to stand on. However, it&apos;s not a libertarian country. We do, in fact, have drug laws, seat belt regulations, and other governmental actions that exist to protect people from their own irresponsible behavior. The fast food industry shouldn&apos;t be exempt from these regulations. Giraffe 07-31-2002, 04:21 PM Just to butt in here, grim spectre, are you seriously arguing that selling the McLean doesn&apos;t count as trying to sell a healthy alternative (which people didn&apos;t want) because the name let people know it was good for them? McDonald&apos;s has a responsibility to not only sell healthy food but trick people into eating it? Should they have called it the McStroke to fool people into thinking it was bad for them so they&apos;d eat it? Fred 07-31-2002, 04:40 PM No, Giraffe. I&apos;m not. I merely explained why the McLean failed, because certain persons were offering the false statement that it failed because it didn&apos;t taste good. I&apos;m saying that the failure of the McLean can not and should not be misconstrued as a valid obstacle to the replacement of the existing product with a product that isn&apos;t so dangerous. Giraffe 07-31-2002, 05:52 PM Why not? It didn&apos;t sell the first time. How many failed products does it take before a company is allowed to continue selling what the public wants, even if it is bad for them?

Personally, I think the fast food industry sucks -- the food is both unhealthy and nasty-tasting. However, there is obviously a demand for it. Most people like fatty food. I too would like to see healthier fast food available, but I don&apos;t think litigation is even a remotely fair way to accomplish it. When a majority of people want to eat healthier fast food, the restaurants will quickly adapt. We&apos;re not there yet. D_Odds 07-31-2002, 08:21 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
No, Giraffe. I&apos;m not. I merely explained why the McLean failed, because certain persons were offering the false statement that it failed because it didn&apos;t taste good. I&apos;m saying that the failure of the McLean can not and should not be misconstrued as a valid obstacle to the replacement of the existing product with a product that isn&apos;t so dangerous.

grim (may I call you Fred?), you haven&apos;t come close to proving the danger to anyone but yourself.

If your proof is acceptable, then every ice cream parlor needs to be immediately shut down. Potato chips and twinkies become black market items.

Fast food places do not self-regulate. Like the auto manufacturers, they have tons of safety regulations with which they must comply. Perhaps one day, the guvmint will say 80% lean is too little, up it to 85%, just like seatbelts went from an extra to a required device. Or maybe BK will learn how to properly market a leaner burger (do you think both haven&apos;t given these ideas lots of thought?) that does indeed taste better. Sure you have a study you quoted from Auburn. I&apos;ve something even better. As an amateur chef, I&apos;ve experimented with the full gamut of lean ranges, plus I&apos;ve read/watched professional chefs&apos; choices: neither the leanest or the least lean is best, flavor-wise, in personal taste tests or to professionals. I&apos;d rather go for turkey burgers than ultra-lean beef burgers. There&apos;s a reason rib-eyes and shell (NY strip) steaks are generally regarded as better than filet mignon. Fat contents (the marbling). There&apos;s a reason more than a few establishments serve a bacon-wrapped filet (mmm, pork fat on tender, very lean beef). Just because Pepsi kept touting their blind taste tests doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s actually better than Coke.

McLean didn&apos;t sell. My guess is McDonald&apos;s thought it did well enough in the test market to go national, where it flopped. If you want to blame marketing, go ahead. But would simply switching to leaner beef absolve McDonalds of all blame?

Consider:
Big Mac: 590 calories, 34 grams fat (11 saturated)
2 patties: 234 calories, 18 grams fat (7 saturated)
special sauce:
Supersize FF: 610 calories, 29 grams fat (5 saturated) D_Odds 07-31-2002, 08:38 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
No, Giraffe. I&apos;m not. I merely explained why the McLean failed, because certain persons were offering the false statement that it failed because it didn&apos;t taste good. I&apos;m saying that the failure of the McLean can not and should not be misconstrued as a valid obstacle to the replacement of the existing product with a product that isn&apos;t so dangerous.

grim (may I call you Fred?), you haven&apos;t come close to proving the danger to anyone but yourself.

If your proof is acceptable, then every ice cream parlor needs to be immediately shut down. Potato chips and twinkies become black market items.

Fast food places do not self-regulate. Like the auto manufacturers, they have tons of safety regulations with which they must comply. Perhaps one day, the guvmint will say 80% lean is too little, up it to 85%, just like seatbelts went from an extra to a required device. Or maybe BK will learn how to properly market a leaner burger (do you think both haven&apos;t given these ideas lots of thought?) that does indeed taste better. Sure you have a study you quoted from Auburn. I&apos;ve something even better. As an amateur chef, I&apos;ve experimented with the full gamut of lean ranges, plus I&apos;ve read/watched professional chefs&apos; choices: neither the leanest or the least lean is best, flavor-wise, in personal taste tests or to professionals. I&apos;d rather go for turkey burgers than ultra-lean beef burgers. There&apos;s a reason rib-eyes and shell (NY strip) steaks are generally regarded as better than filet mignon. Fat contents (the marbling). There&apos;s a reason more than a few establishments serve a bacon-wrapped filet (mmm, pork fat on tender, very lean beef). Just because Pepsi kept touting their blind taste tests doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s actually better than Coke.

McLean didn&apos;t sell. My guess is McDonald&apos;s thought it did well enough in the test market to go national, where it flopped. If you want to blame marketing, go ahead. (I didn&apos;t try it, but I haven&apos;t eaten a fast food burger in over a dozen years. I remember exit polls on the local news showing consumers harping on taste, but it was long ago and it might just be fuzzy memory). But would simply switching to leaner beef absolve McDonalds of all blame?

Consider:
Big Mac: 590 calories, 34 grams fat (11 saturated)
2 patties: 234 calories, 18 grams fat (7 saturated)
special sauce: 104 calories, 11 grams fat (2 saturated)
Supersize FF: 610 calories, 29 grams fat (5 saturated)

Let&apos;s say you knock 10 grams of fat and the resulting 90 calories off of a Big Mac. Those fries are still going to clog your arteries tighter than a ant&apos;s butt. It would be equivalent to ensuring that autos have breaks capable of stopping on a proverbial dime and ignoring tire tread.

Lastly, I couldn&apos;t find on either McDonald&apos;s or Burger King&apos;s site the lean ratio for their burgers. Unless someone has solid data, the assumption being made is that it is the lowest. How would your assertion change if it weren&apos;t? Also, KFC is included in the suit. That&apos;s fried chicken, leaner than beef but cooked in the least healthy way possible. Are they also unethical? Are the purveyors of ice cream and Twinkies unethical? Fred 07-31-2002, 10:44 PM You know what&apos;s bizarre? While I was sitting on this computer, I was getting replies faster than I could keep up with -- it didn&apos;t help that I was involved in a wicked difficult game of Freecell (#25034, for the curious). As soon as I step out for a delightful night on the town with my CPF, bam! Only two replies. Strange. It&apos;s almost as if you&apos;re all figments of my imagination. *dons tinfoil hat* Ahh, at peace again.

Anyways... back to the point at hand.


grim (may I call you Fred?), you haven&apos;t come close to proving the danger to anyone but yourself.


Go ahead and call me Fred -- on a side note, I find it weird to be called anything but Fred on a message board; kind of like how I feel funny when the SO calls me by my real name instead of&quot;honey.&quot;in any case, the danger to myself is yet to be seen. I found that after I gave up fast food for a few months (in an effort to save money of all things... listening, Rex? :)), the effect of eating fast food is a feeling of fundamental unhealthiness coursing through my body. Maybe it&apos;s psychosomatic. *shrug* In any case, I stopped eating fast food more than once in a blue moon. The danger isn&apos;t to me: it&apos;s too people that eat it on a regular basis, and are in the habit of doing so. I would think that the correlation between the regular consumption of fast food and health risks has been proven to your satisfaction. Unless you disagree?


Just because Pepsi kept touting their blind taste tests doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s actually better than Coke.


I&apos;d say that although preference differs from person to person, Pepsi can indeed say that more people like Pepsi than like Coke by taste alone. Of course, in the real world, things are more complicated. I&apos;ve always said that if Diet Soda really does taste exactly like the regular, as every Diet Pop commercial from time immemorial has stated, they should just replace them. The fast food industry has the opportunity to do the same: replace their extremely unhealthy products (burgers and fries) with merely unhealthy ones, thereby saving lives. And the kicker is that no one would be able to tell the difference. The problem lies in the fact that they have no impetus to do so.

You know, I find your&quot;Solve the whole problem or don&apos;t do anything at all&quot;approach bizarre. Why not take some steps? Better to improve a little than not at all, in my view.

Special Director&apos;s Commentary Edition Post

I notice I&apos;ve said the word&quot;Bizarre&quot;a total of a gazillion times during the course of this thread: pretty much once a post (Twice in this particular post). I attribute this frequency to Bill Murray&apos;s character in The Royal Tenenbaums, which I watched recently. Typo Negative 08-01-2002, 01:51 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Hamadryad, I&apos;ve already addressed the Mclean Burger. Here it is again, from page 2.Road Rash: You are partially correct, sir. The McLean burger did not sell. But the reason it did not sell is emphatically not because it was an inferior product. In fact, as I&apos;ve already shown, it was superior to regular burgers in every way, including taste
Taa daa!

How could you possibly demonstrate that it&apos;s taste was superior??? You do know that taste is a largley subjective measure? That what tastes good to you might not taste good to me? Some folks like broccoli. I find it vile and nausiating.

And ya know what? I had me one of them McLean burgers. AND IT SUCKED. I did not like, and it was the last that I ever purchased. So what you have demonstrated has been your opinion, which counts as much as any other, and not fact.

I went to McDonalds the other day. Had a couple of sausage biscuits. And you know what? I feel fine! I was not harmed in any way! Imagine that. But then again, I ate in reasonable moderation. I guess that&apos;s the key, huh? maybe they should put warnings up:&quot;products should only be consumed in reasonable moderation&quot;.

No, fuck that. I don&apos;t want to live in a country that caters to morons, idiots and weasels. I want to live in a free country, where I can get a greasy-ass Big Mac if I want one. A country where I will be responsible for the girth if I should happen to eat one at every meal.

There are places that serve the &apos;healthy&apos; fare you want to force McDonalds to serve. And my friend, you are free to go and eat there to your heart&apos;s content. But the government should not require us to eat there. It should each persons choice.

Anyone who sues a fastfood company for making them fat is a fucking liar, and should be ashamed of him/herself. Such a person is loathsome. If I ever meet one, I will tell him so. Blaming others for what you did is as low as it gets. And THAT is what we are talking about here. Tars Tarkas 08-01-2002, 02:13 AM He probably means it did better in taste tests. I bet the Arch Delux did as well, and that creation is roasting in the hell it deserves as well. I&apos;m not about to try to find those statistics, as i can barely get Yahoo to show up on search engines. As for the rest of your (spooje) post, i agree.

And BTW, i can vouch that Rex wasn&apos;t eating much fast food this past week, but maybe he is now, since he got paid. Fred 08-01-2002, 07:00 AM How could you possibly demonstrate that it&apos;s taste was superior??? You do know that taste is a largley subjective measure? That what tastes good to you might not taste good to me? Some folks like broccoli. I find it vile and nausiating.

And ya know what? I had me one of them McLean burgers. AND IT SUCKED. I did not like, and it was the last that I ever purchased. So what you have demonstrated has been your opinion, which counts as much as any other, and not fact.


Actually, it&apos;s not my opinion at all. I&apos;ve never even had a McLean burger. But I find your assertation regarding&quot;Taste is subjective so no definitive statement can ever be made regarding the relative worth of food products,&quot;um, bizarre. I&apos;m sure there&apos;s someone out there who likes the taste of dog shit. But I feel confident saying Rice Krispies taste better than dog shit, even though tast is subjective. I know how much you hate disclaimers -- are you going to force me to explain that by tastes better I mean that the majority of people in a blind taste test prefer the taste? Because I can, if you want. But maybe you want to live in a country where I don&apos;t have to do something so patently rediculous.

Speaking of that, perhaps you also want to live in a country in which you can decide whether or not to wear a seat belt, and be responsible for the consequences thereof. A country in which you can not wear a helmet on a motorcycle, and be responsible for the consequences. A country in which you can abuse whatever substances you want, and be responsible for the consequences. A free country. I hope you find this country, and when you do, send me a postcard.

By the by, you never cleared up your contradictory statements. Again, did I misinterpret you? Hamadryad 08-01-2002, 07:05 AM I still just don&apos;t understand why fast food restaurants should be ethically bound to serve nutritious food, any more than clothing stores should be ethically bound to stock clothes in larger sizes, or bars should be ethically bound to serve health shakes. I agree that it would be awfully nice if all of these places did these things, as it would be more convenient to shop, eat out, and go to bars if they did...but as alternatives are readily available I don&apos;t know how it&apos;s an ethical issue.

You want an ETHICAL issue? Adults can choose what and when they eat. School children are getting pizza and soda for lunch every damned day, and the administrators don&apos;t want to remove the soda machines because they bring in so much desperately needed money. My kid is being whored out to sell wrapping paper every year because the schools can&apos;t afford supplies - hell, I have to PROVIDE his supplies. (Why, I believe this is the topic for another thread.)

You want to argue an ethical dietary issue? Talk about school cafeterias. McBurgerWendyFriedSilver&apos;s menus are not issues of ethics. Typo Negative 08-01-2002, 07:39 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
-- are you going to force me to explain that by tastes better I mean that the majority of people in a blind taste test prefer the taste? Correction. The majority of those who participated in the test. Which may not be such a large sample. I often wonder just who participates in these tests. And even if they, in a taste test enviroment say&quot;yeah, that&apos;s a lot better&quot;, doesn&apos;t mean they will buy the thing when it&apos;s put on the menu. Speaking of that, perhaps you also want to live in a country in which you can decide whether or not to wear a seat belt, and be responsible for the consequences thereof.Can you be thrown to the pavement at 60 MPH from eating a Big Mac? No? Then it&apos;s not a great analogy. But since you ask. Yes, I think seat belts should be optional. I wear them. But if somebody wants to disregard them, they should be able to, and pay the consequences A country in which you can not wear a helmet on a motorcycle, and be responsible for the consequences. A country in which you can abuse whatever substances you want, and be responsible for the consequences.You&apos;re darn tooting! What a great fucking place this would be. A much better place. Freedom, and no whiney ass maggots claiming to &apos;victims&apos; when they are, in fact, idiots who should have known better.

I made no contradictory staements. You haven&apos;t shown that the food is harmful. And you know what? Cesar barbar isn&apos;t going to ba able to show it either!! Ya know why? Because fast food from the big 4 isn&apos;t all that he&apos;s abusing. Listen to his argument.&quot;They damaged me by making the food so enticing&quot;!
:rolleyes: :rolleyes:

You want to make fast food joints responsible for this asshole&apos;s health. I want to make this asshole responsible for his decisions that he made with his own freewill.

If you eat at a fastfood joint every now and then, and eat sensibly, you&apos;ll be OK. Typo Negative 08-01-2002, 07:40 AM Christ, I previewd and still made mistakes.

I suck. artemis 08-01-2002, 08:32 AM Originally posted by Hamadryad
You want an ETHICAL issue? Adults can choose what and when they eat. School children are getting pizza and soda for lunch every damned day, and the administrators don&apos;t want to remove the soda machines because they bring in so much desperately needed money. My kid is being whored out to sell wrapping paper every year because the schools can&apos;t afford supplies - hell, I have to PROVIDE his supplies. (Why, I believe this is the topic for another thread.)

You want to argue an ethical dietary issue? Talk about school cafeterias. McBurgerWendyFriedSilver&apos;s menus are not issues of ethics.

Exactly! People develop thier food prefernces early in life - so why are schools ENCOURAGING the consumption of a poor diet by serving fast-food type meals in the school cafeteria? If people grow up eating more balanced meals, they don&apos;t find greasy fast food nearly as appealing, and are far less likely to consume it to excess.

I find this lawsuit ridiculous - but believe that attempts to keep fast food franchises out of schools is a laudible one. Of course, that requires that adults be willing to pony up enough money so the cafeteria can prepare nutritious meals that the children will actually EAT... For a society that supposedly &apos;cares about kids&apos;, we do a lousy job of showing it!

I also have no problems with the idea of restricting or eliminating fast food advertising directed at minors, for the same reasons that we don&apos;t allow cigarette companies or brewers to advertise to them (although they are free to advertise to adults). Keep kids from developing a taste for the stuff, and most of the problems are solved. Typo Negative 08-01-2002, 08:37 AM I will agree that the fast food should NOT be in the school cafeteria. Hamadryad 08-01-2002, 08:48 AM &quot;Keep kids from developing a taste for the stuff, and most of the problems are solved.&quot;

Unfortunately this requires parents to actually take some responsibility for their kids...and as fewer adults are willing to take responsibility for THEMSELVES, the kids are going downhill too.

From this week&apos;s&quot;Newsweek&quot;:&quot;What changes have you made?&quot;booms Ludwig, as a 226-pound 10-year-old squeezes into his small examining room. The boy proudly describes how he&apos;s stopped eating cookies and slowed down on chips since his last visit.Why were his parents (or guardians, if that is the case) letting him eat all of these cookies and chips? My kids are stuck with carrots for a snack right now. They may bitch and whine and complain, but because I am their parent and not their buddy, I&apos;m going to make sure they have healthy food.

In my decidedly less-than-humble opinion, this lawsuit is not remotely about a fast food joint&apos;s responsibility to change the food they sell; it&apos;s about alleged adults who don&apos;t want to take responsibility for their own irresponsible behavior.

I&apos;m in the process of weaning myself off of fatty foods. I&apos;m making myself eat carrots or spinach when I&apos;m munchy. I want to make cookies and brownies and cupcakes. I want to take the easy way out and make microwaved buttery popcorn all the time...but because I understand that as an adult it is my responsibility to take care of my health, I am doing it.

And yeah, I have unhealthy habits - I smoke, for instance - but I&apos;m not immature and irresponsible enough to think that it&apos;s 7-11&apos;s fault for selling me the cigarettes, or Philip Morris&apos;s fault for making them, and I don&apos;t think either of them has an ethical responsibility to stop. ralph124c 08-01-2002, 08:50 AM Just as with cigarettes, we will tax fast food-the tax shall be levied according to the caloric content of the item-say $5.00 for a BIg Mac, and $2.20 for a small order of fries. The money will go into the general fund, and shared out (stolen) among the states, upon the basis of population, with at least 33% going to the courageous lawyers who are valiantly protecting us from our own stupidity!
I can forsee many benefits to this approach-we will have all kinds of money to spend on anti-fast food commercials, educational programs, etc. Besides, the lawyers need to make an honest living!What with law school SO expensive, they need a way to recoup their investment!
Welcome to 21st century America-its as if the inmates are running the looney bin!:eek: Typo Negative 08-01-2002, 09:39 AM Nope. it still supposes that it&apos;s somebody else&apos;s responsibilty.

No taxes, no lawsuits, dammit. JohnBckWLD 08-01-2002, 12:51 PM In 1991, a judge (i.e. a politcally connected lawyer)filed suit in the Bronx after claiming to have been injured after driving through a pothole in Manhattan. A Bronx jury awarded him $1.7 million.

The way I see it, Babar&amp;Letchowitz are headed for big-time payday. Theyll both be dining at the 21 Club and will never have to eat another Quarter-Pounders or Big Mac. If a Judge can steal a $1,700,000 windfall what are 2 heart attacks worth? Gotta be at least $6,000,000. RexDart 08-01-2002, 09:34 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death


Rex pretty much abandoned his bizarre statement that it would ruin the&quot;low cost&quot;benifit of fast food lunch, and didn&apos;t really come up with another reason. I&apos;m curious as to where you are coming from on this.


I by no means abandoned it. Perhaps you have an hour for your lunch break. Perhaps you&apos;re willing to spend 30 minutes of that hour in commute, so that you can go to your home and enjoy a low-cost meal. If not, then you&apos;re stuck with restaurants. As that goes, McDonald&apos;s is low-cost. You can get a filling meal for $4 at McDonald&apos;s, and in 5 minutes of your life. So you can spend the otehr 55 minutes hanging out, listening to The Radio Factor, Limbaugh, or The Dan Patrick Show, whichever you prefer. In the field of lunchtime meals, McDonald&apos;s is clearly a low-cost meal option.

Have you ever spent $10 at the&quot;flare&quot;restaurants for a burger and fries and coke? Well,&quot;goodbye, Ruby Tuesday&quot;, they cost me double digit dollars for lunch and took most of it away while I waited. McDonald&apos;s is an excellent low-cost option. Yes, I can make 2 meals out of 49 cents in spaghetti and $1.50 in Ragu, but I can&apos;t make the time magically appear in which to go home for it. If you are so inclined to limit yourself to brown-baggin&apos; it, then enjoy your daily ham/roastbeef/turkey.

By the way, I thought your bit about an average joe being able to open a fast food restaurant that can effectively compete with the likes of McDonald&apos;s and Burger King was pretty funny. Unless you were serious, in which case your optimism is admirable, to say the least. referring to Tars Tarkas

Oh, I&apos;m sorry, I guess I just pictured those restaurants in my head. They must have been a frickin&apos; mirage. Somebody better tell the guys who own the Maid-Rite in Brookfield that they don&apos;t exist. I guess that Cheese-Rite (loose-meat sandwich with cheese) I ordered was a figment of my imagination. I bet they&apos;ll find the philosophical works of Goodman, Derrida, and Putnam quite interesting as a starting point.

Lunchers are the big take for fast food. It&apos;s a fact. They aren&apos;t on the web yet, AFAIK, but years of demographical studies in the food service industry have demonstrated this time and again. My father is a senior advertising executive specializing in the food industry, I myself worked for a summer in that aspect of the advertising enterprise.

Lunchers want food quick and cheap. Anybody can provide that. Name recognition is a lower factor. Quick cheap burger places like Rally&apos;s and Backyard Burger have gotten good lunchtime market penetration with their no-dine-in very-fast-food restaurants. The market will determine how this issue plays out. If a company comes along marketing their equally speedy burgers, but 96% instead of 73%, at 40 cents (American) more, then we&apos;ll all find out won&apos;t we? You don&apos;t expect someone to open up such a business as a public service do you? You realize they have to make some money to pay back the loan they took out to start the business, right? Nobody owes you a 96% lean burger, if you want it you can pay for it. Otherwise, stay the heck out of my business when I choose to buy a 73% burger from a relatively inexpensive lunchtime restaurant. Fred 08-01-2002, 10:10 PM I made no contradictory staements. You haven&apos;t shown that the food is harmful. And you know what? Cesar barbar isn&apos;t going to ba able to show it either!! Ya know why? Because fast food from the big 4 isn&apos;t all that he&apos;s abusing. Listen to his argument.&quot;They damaged me by making the food so enticing&quot;!


spooje, I&apos;ve posted quite a lot in this thread, so it&apos;s more than understandable that you&apos;ve missed a few things I&apos;ve said. This entire paragraph, for example, has been answered before it was even posted -- like time travel! Here&apos;s where I pointed out your contradictory statements, and asked for clarification:


spooje, this statement by you:



quote:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

What prevents them [from controlling whether irresponsible use of their product causes harm]? Nothing.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------



is in direct contradiction to this one, also by you:


quote:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

The fast food joints have no control over that [whether the irresponsible use of their product causes harm]

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------



Perhaps I&apos;m misinterpreting you. Which statement is the one you believe?


and here is where I talked about my opinion of Mr. Barbar


I wish to state that I&apos;m not particularly wedded to this suit in particular. In fact, if you&apos;ll notice, I&apos;ve never said one word in support of it. I believe the idea that Mr. Barbar was somehow bamboozled into believing fast food is healthy is very silly indeed. I&apos;m looking, instead, at the fast food industry as a whole. And, under strictly Libertarian principles, I don&apos;t have a leg to stand on. However, it&apos;s not a libertarian country. We do, in fact, have drug laws, seat belt regulations, and other governmental actions that exist to protect people from their own irresponsible behavior. The fast food industry shouldn&apos;t be exempt from these regulations.


I addressed this statement:


And even if they, in a taste test enviroment say&quot;yeah, that&apos;s a lot better&quot;, doesn&apos;t mean they will buy the thing when it&apos;s put on the menu.


here:


The McLean burger did not sell. But the reason it did not sell is emphatically not because it was an inferior product. In fact, as I&apos;ve already shown, it was superior to regular burgers in every way, including taste. The quality of a product doesn&apos;t translate into sales: the marketing does.


I realize it&apos;s hard work to keep up with all the posts I&apos;ve made, and I fully understand the fact that you missed these points. But other than that, I&apos;m afraid you and I are simply going to have to disagree. Apparently, our disagreement doesn&apos;t stem from different perspectives on this particular situation, but rather from different perspectives on the world in general. You obviously wish you lived in a more Libertarian country. I don&apos;t. If we are to debate on anything, it should be on this, much larger issue; as it stands, our disagreement over the fast food industry is merely symptomic of differing political opinions, and, as such, we will never be able to see eye to eye on the issue.

Hamadryad, as with spooje, I believe that what we have here is a much larger difference of opinion. My belief is that it is unethical for a company to profit off the deaths of millions, no matter what the industry. You do not. Again, the fast food issue is merely one part of a much larger disagreement, and as such, I&apos;ll not waste any more time debating it with you.

ralph124c: The whole&quot;inane hyperbolic exageration -- with exclamation points!!!!&quot;has been done. Twice. This is a fast moving message board, man. You gotta move quickly, or else you&apos;ll always be third in line. It also helps have an original thought. Fred 08-01-2002, 10:38 PM Originally posted by RexDart

I by no means abandoned it. Perhaps you have an hour for your lunch break. Perhaps you&apos;re willing to spend 30 minutes of that hour in commute, so that you can go to your home and enjoy a low-cost meal. If not, then you&apos;re stuck with restaurants. As that goes, McDonald&apos;s is low-cost. You can get a filling meal for $4 at McDonald&apos;s, and in 5 minutes of your life. So you can spend the otehr 55 minutes hanging out, listening to The Radio Factor, Limbaugh, or The Dan Patrick Show, whichever you prefer. In the field of lunchtime meals, McDonald&apos;s is clearly a low-cost meal option.


Bolding my own. I&apos;ll say it one more time: bizarre. First of all, you&apos;re talking two different things: speed, and money. I never debated that fast food wasn&apos;t fast, so we&apos;re down to one. Of course fast food is a low cost option in a hypothetical world where restaurants are the only places where food exists. It would have been the polite thing to do to let me know that you were referring to this magical world filled with unicorns and where brown bagged lunch is the work of science fiction way back when we started debating this topic.

I feel it&apos;s important to bring up the fact that your theory on cost had two important points:

Point Number A: Fast Food is a low cost alternative.
Point Number B: The increase in burger price of 40 cents would bankrupt the fast food industry because fast food would no longer be the low cost alternative (Your exact words were&quot;they would no longer retain the market position of being the low-cost lunch option that they presently are for most of us&quot;).

I&apos;m willing to concede that in a hypothetical restaurant only world, fast food is a low cost option. However, I&apos;m checking on the calculator, and $4 plus $0.40 is still less than&quot;double digit dollars for lunch&quot;at a flare place; plus, it&apos;s faster! Geez, Rex, maybe I should step out of the way and let you do battle with your own position?

&quot;If you are so inclined to limit yourself to brown-baggin&apos; it, then enjoy your daily ham/roastbeef/turkey.&quot;

Most people searching for a low cost option do have to limit themselves to brown baggin&apos; it. As someone who has alledgedly been on a tight budget, I would have thought this would have been obvious to you.

Finally, according to you, people searching for a low cost restaurant option are limited to fast food places. I hate to tell you this, but that&apos;s supposed to be the position of fast food lawsuit proponents, not opponents. Fred 08-01-2002, 10:51 PM Oh, for the love of Pete! I forgot your completely absurd independent restaurant statement!


Oh, I&apos;m sorry, I guess I just pictured those restaurants in my head. They must have been a frickin&apos; mirage. Somebody better tell the guys who own the Maid-Rite in Brookfield that they don&apos;t exist. I guess that Cheese-Rite (loose-meat sandwich with cheese) I ordered was a figment of my imagination. I bet they&apos;ll find the philosophical works of Goodman, Derrida, and Putnam quite interesting as a starting point.


You mean the Maid-Rite franchise that spans the MidWest? The Maid-Rite franchise that was founded 76 years ago? Oh, yeah, that&apos;s an excellent example of how I could create a successful burger joint that could compete with the Big Chains. After all, if Maid-Rite could fight off the The Terminator (you remember, the one McDonald&apos;s sent back in time to kill the franchise before it could get off the ground -- the first McDonald&apos;s wouldn&apos;t be founded for another 20 years), surely I can too!

I&apos;m sure there are examples of fast food stores that aren&apos;t McDonald&apos;s somewhere... you just picked the shittiest example imaginable, outside of&quot;Burger King&quot;. D_Odds 08-01-2002, 10:58 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
I believe that what we have here is a much larger difference of opinion. My belief is that it is unethical for a company to profit off the deaths of millions, no matter what the industry. You do not. Again, the fast food issue is merely one part of a much larger disagreement, and as such, I&apos;ll not waste any more time debating it with you.
Fred, as I hope we&apos;re still on typing terms, I&apos;d like to say that this just doesn&apos;t register with me either. Either that or all cars must go, and let&apos;s not even mention motorcycles. Of course, guns are right out (not that I&apos;d complain). What next - kitchen knives and baseball bats? Oh, and don&apos;t forget to launch a cruise missile at the Hershey factory.

Even given the poor nutrition profile of fast food, they are not killing anybody. Looking at the nutritional data (sorry I didn&apos;t link it before, but it&apos;s at www.mcdonalds.com somewhere), a full-grown adult with a moderate activity level and otherwise healthy diet could eat a Big Mac daily with no ill effects. Fast food alone, just like a gun, does not kill anybody; rather it is a complex combination of lifestyle factors in which fast food plays a part (with the gun, the lifestyle factor is the ability to point it at another human being and pull the trigger). Calling their business unethical is like calling Leatherface&apos;s chainsaw salesman evil for selling to his best customer. Fast food can&apos;t quiz their patrons&apos; health profiles to know who is safe and who isn&apos;t. It&apos;s not their place to say,&quot;Please present your notarized cholesterol card before I serve you.&quot;

Lastly, I&apos;d like to re-refer to this:We do, in fact, have drug laws, seat belt regulations, and other governmental actions that exist to protect people from their own irresponsible behavior. The fast food industry shouldn&apos;t be exempt from these regulations. Yet people still do drugs, drive recklessly, etc. McDonalds and Burger King post nutritional information and the FDA food pyramid and people still gorge. And again, they are not exempt from safety regulations to insure that their food genuinely doesn&apos;t kill anybody.

Oops, I know I said lastly above, but Fred could you post a link to the study you quoted back on page one (I&apos;m pretty sure I didn&apos;t see one). Thanks. As I said, personal experience and the opinion of professional chefs contradicts the findings. Besides, if selling leaner burgers might give one of the three an edge based on flavor (such as McD&apos;s has w/ their fries), don&apos;t you think one of them would have jumped all over it?

Rex, you left out the option of brown-bagging it. I know not everyone works where there is a fridge and microwave available, but it&apos;s a much cheaper, more viable option for any who do. Also, I found a healthier meal at Blimpies or Subways to be as quick and as cheap and more satisfying. To each his own.

(P.S. grim on preview, I see you are back on the leaner burger argument. I think that&apos;s the weakest argument you&apos;ve made, but to each his own. Note above, I agree with the brown-bag option) RexDart 08-01-2002, 11:30 PM grim spectre, my position is merely that the fast-food joints are the low-cost alternative for lunchtime dining. Yes indeed, I&apos;ve brownbagged it many a time. (Though consider that the cost savings isn&apos;t all that much....one can only make about 5 lunch-sized sandwiches from a pound of sliced deli meat, so that&apos;s about $1 per sandwich...not far off from the Wendy&apos;s Jr. Bacon Cheeseburger at 99 cents.) That was fortunate for me, since there was a refrigerator in the break room. Not always the case I assure you.

You can extrapolate whatever or however you wish. My argument is only that the fast-food chains are in direct competition with the sit-in joints (or the pricier joints with a drive-thru option like Fazoli&apos;s) for the lunchtime dollars. If McDonald&apos;s were to decide tomorrow to switch to 96% lean ground beef and raise their prices 40 cents per 1/4 lb burger, do you think the public would welcome such an arrangement? Do you think people would just pay the extra 40 cents, or would they go elsewhere? I suspect many people would disagree with the move. People would say,&quot;Well, the old burger was fine by me, why couldn&apos;t they just keep that on the menu and offer the leaner beef for extra?&quot;

As for the McLean, I thought that was a veggie burger, am I mistaken? The only time I tasted a veggie burger was by accident, at a cookout. I didn&apos;t know it was a veggie burger, bit into it, and thought&quot;Oh my god, this burger is aboslutely awful, something is definitely wrong here.&quot;I had to spit the contents of my mouth into the garbage can in front of several people, it was that bad. Fred 08-01-2002, 11:45 PM Hold the presses!

Does McDonald&apos;s really claim that someone can eat a Big Mac meal a day with no ill effect? Because if so, this lawsuit has been handed a giant gift.


Calling their business unethical is like calling Leatherface&apos;s chainsaw salesman evil for selling to his best customer.


Um, yes, it is. If chainsaw manufacturers were making serious profit by selling their product as a murder weapon, to the extent that the chainsaw industry actively encouraged using chainsaws to murder people, I sure as hell would have an ethical problem.

But perhaps chainsaws aren&apos;t the best example.


Yet people still do drugs, drive recklessly, etc.


Surely you aren&apos;t suggesting that the fact the people break the law is an argument against that law? The fact that a law doesn&apos;t prevent all instances of a behaviour means the law is worthless? Hell, people still murder, steal, etc. but you&apos;d hardly argue for those laws to be repealed.

The article quoted in my first post can be found here (http://gladwell.com/2001/2001_03_05_a_fries.htm) Bryan Ekers 08-01-2002, 11:49 PM I have a solution, too.

Give the fat lazy clown a settlement placed in trust, then tattoo the phrase&quot;ADULT RESPONSIBILITY ABDICATED&quot;, or ARA, on his forehead. From that moment on, he will be protected from entering into any form of contract, including purchases over $1. He obviously can&apos;t handle the responsibility of adulthood, so he should be placed into a subclass of citizens that must be proteced from themselves and others; a perpetual childhood, as it were.

When encountering an ARA, one must be kind and polite, while understanding that the ARA has no opinions of significance and should be viewed with a mix of tolerance and forebearance. After all, they don&apos;t understand what they are doing or saying and that causes have effects.

Poor, poor people. Fred 08-01-2002, 11:50 PM Though consider that the cost savings isn&apos;t all that much....one can only make about 5 lunch-sized sandwiches from a pound of sliced deli meat, so that&apos;s about $1 per sandwich...not far off from the Wendy&apos;s Jr. Bacon Cheeseburger at 99 cents.


Man, you should have had me around when you were trying to cut costs, Rex: I would&apos;ve saved you a bundle. If you&apos;re on a tight budget, the deli isn&apos;t the best place to go for sliced meats. It&apos;s much cheaper to go to the cooked counter in the meat department of a grocery store.


Do you think people would just pay the extra 40 cents, or would they go elsewhere?


Basically, would people rather pay 40 cents more, or 7 dollars more? That&apos;s an easy one, Rex. Typo Negative 08-02-2002, 01:49 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death


My belief is that it is unethical for a company to profit off the deaths of millions, no matter what the industry. OK, lets see a damn cite that says they have profited from , or in any caused the deaths of millions.

Statements like this do not help your case. QueenAl 08-02-2002, 08:21 AM Grim, you seem to think that the fast food chains are deliberately killing off their customers. Why the hell would they do this? Their managers don&apos;t sit in the boardroom discussing the latest death rates from heart-attacks, rubbing their hands in glee and rejoicing over the fact that more of their client base is dead. They&apos;re not choosing how to make their burgers out of some vindictive spite against people who love fast food.

You contend that McDonald&apos;s et al would love it if everyone ate at their restaurants six times a week. Not true, if they want to keep their client base in the long-term - which they do. They are big commpanies that can make big, long-term plans. Fast food companies make no profit from people having heart-attacks and being sworn off fast food. They make their best profits from people eating a couple of times a week at their restaurants, eating otherwise well, and living long enough to keep on doing this in the long-term. And not suing them.

All these companies want to do is make more money. That&apos;s it. They don&apos;t care how they do it, not in the slightest. I imagine you don&apos;t disagree with this. So if they could make more money by making and marketing leaner products, they would do so. The reason they can&apos;t make more money in this way is that people do not go to fast food restaurants for a healthy option - they go because they want fast food! If the big chains all started making leaner burgers, would people stop eating there? Quite possibly - and soon enough rivals would spring up selling the fatty burgers that people seem to want.

Recently I have been trying to gain some weight. I detest fatty food, hate the taste of it and don&apos;t see why people do like it, but I need to put on a few pounds. So this week, in addition to my regular healthy diet, I ate a McDonald&apos;s in order to get a lot of calories relative to the mass of the food. I also switched from the diet soda* I&apos;ve been drinking for years to full-strength, because that&apos;s a very efficient method of delivering calories to your body. In my case, fast food is good for me. If there was suddenly no high-fat option available at the fast-food restaurants, would I be within my rights to sue them for not providing me with alternatives that, for me, are healthier?

Of course I wouldn&apos;t. I could, if necessary, go and buy build-up shakes at the health-food store (I don&apos;t because I dislike the taste of them) or get fattier beef at the gorcery store and make my own burgers. I have options just as this litigant does.


*I&apos;m sure you&apos;re aware of this, but if all soda was made diet, as you suggest, there would be an outcry from the significant number of people who don&apos;t want to put aspartame or other artificial sweeteners in their system. Fred 08-02-2002, 11:37 AM Originally posted by spooje
OK, lets see a damn cite that says they have profited from , or in any way caused the deaths of millions.

Statements like this do not help your case.

From the article quoted in my first post:


As many Americans now die every year from obesity-related illnesses--heart disease and complications of diabetes--as from smoking.


Regarding Trans Fats, from the same article:


The average American now eats a staggering thirty pounds of French fries a year... in 1990, in the face of public concern about the health risks of cholesterol in animal-based cooking oil, McDonald&apos;s and the other major fast-food houses switched to vegetable oil. That wasn&apos;t an improvement, however. In the course of making vegetable oil suitable for deep frying, it is subjected to a chemical process called hydrogenation, which creates a new substance called a trans unsaturated fat. In the hierarchy of fats, polyunsaturated fats--the kind found in regular vegetable oils--are the good kind; they lower your cholesterol. Saturated fats are the bad kind. But trans fats are worse: they wreak havoc with the body&apos;s ability to regulate cholesterol.

According to a recent study involving some eighty thousand women, for every five-per-cent increase in the amount of saturated fats that a woman consumes, her risk of heart disease increases by seventeen per cent. But only a two-per-cent increase in trans fats will increase her heart-disease risk by ninety-three per cent. Walter Willett, an epidemiologist at Harvard--who helped design the study--estimates that the consumption of trans fats in the United States probably causes about thirty thousand premature deaths a year.


Just because I want more than one source, here (http://www.gnc.com/health_notes/Food_Guide/Trans_Fats.htm) is some more information about Trans Fats.


Among the most important dietary changes in protecting arteries from atherosclerosis is avoiding foods that contain trans fatty acids (margarine, some vegetable oil and many processed foods containing vegetable oil). Increasingly, the importance of avoiding trans fatty acids is being accepted by the scientific community. Leading researchers have recently begun to view the evidence linking trans fatty acids to markers for heart disease as unequivocal.


Also, about obesity


Obesity generates $117bn in annual medical bills and triggers 300,000 premature deaths each year.


Surely you don&apos;t disagree that the Fast Food industry is more than partially responsible for the increase in obesity?

Do you really need me to explain where the fast food industry gets money from? In case you didn&apos;t realize, it&apos;s from selling fast food. And if that fast food is a major contributing factor to a condition that causes 300,000 premature deaths each year, then they are profitting from death. Again, this is pretty obvious to me.

QueenAl, you are flat wrong. And very optimistic, which can sometimes be admirable. Just not in this case. I never said that the fast food industry wants to kill people, or that they take pleasure in doing so. They simply don&apos;t care. This is an industry that switched products to a more deadly version, in order to give the impression of making the product more healthy.


You contend that McDonald&apos;s et al would love it if everyone ate at their restaurants six times a week. Not true, if they want to keep their client base in the long-term - which they do. They are big commpanies that can make big, long-term plans. Fast food companies make no profit from people having heart-attacks and being sworn off fast food. They make their best profits from people eating a couple of times a week at their restaurants, eating otherwise well, and living long enough to keep on doing this in the long-term.


Flatly wrong, and easy enough to disprove. Let&apos;s do the math.

6 meals a week x 52 weeks a year x 45 years x $5 a meal = $70,200

2 meals a week x 52 weeks a year x 70 years x $5 a meal = $36,400

These numbers show that the fast food industry makes nowhere near the profit off people who eat in their restaurants 2 times a year, even if those people eat fast food for 25 more years. In fast, for the profits to equal, our hypothetical person would have to eat fast food 2 meals a week for 135 continuous years.


All these companies want to do is make more money. That&apos;s it. They don&apos;t care how they do it, not in the slightest. I imagine you don&apos;t disagree with this.


I don&apos;t. And that&apos;s my ethical issue. Caring only about making money and not caring who suffers in order for you to get it is practically the definition of unethical. QueenAl 08-02-2002, 12:30 PM I don&apos;t. And that&apos;s my ethical issue. Caring only about making money and not caring who suffers in order for you to get it is practically the definition of unethical.

No, it is practically the definition of the free market. In general, it works, because we do have choice - if they don&apos;t provide what we want to buy, we&apos;ll go somewhere else, so they provide what we want. And it seems we want fatty hamburgers. The McLean failed. You contend this is because of lack of advertising, which I find mildly offensive: it implies that people will only eat what they&apos;re told (through adverts) to eat, like mindless pigs being led to the swill trough. Do you really have such a low opinion of American consumers that, in your opinion, they cannot exercise free choice?

In fast, for the profits to equal, our hypothetical person would have to eat fast food 2 meals a week for 135 continuous years.

Only because you&apos;re counting every single year from birth onwards. Not only do young children have different nutritional requirements than adults, they don&apos;t have as much choice about where they eat as adults do - it depends where their parents take them. If you only add up the figures from the age of 18, the figures fit quite easily. A consumer living to the age of 40 and eating 6 times day from about the age of 18 (at $1560 per year), spends the same amount ($34,320) as ($520 per year) to the age of 84. The longer-lived, healthier, not obese person also has a higher chance of having a family and creating more little consumers.

Perhaps I shouldn&apos;t even have brought that up - as others have pointed out, the businesses&apos; intentions are largely irrelevent.

Obviously eating lots of fast food, without the context of a balanced diet, contributes to obesity. But that&apos;s your own dumb luck for choosing to eat lots of fast food.

Again, I point out that I currently have a reason to prefer the fattier burgers: if you replaced all the fattier burgers with leaner ones, you would be depriving me of options in exactly the same way that you contend Mr Barber is deprived. Where&apos;s the ethics there, if only obese people get the choice? artemis 08-02-2002, 12:31 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
QueenAl, you are flat wrong. And very optimistic, which can sometimes be admirable. Just not in this case. I never said that the fast food industry wants to kill people, or that they take pleasure in doing so. They simply don&apos;t care. This is an industry that switched products to a more deadly version, in order to give the impression of making the product more healthy.


Aren&apos;t you omitting something rather important here? The reason that the fast food companies made the switch to partially-hydrogenated vegetable oil products is because at that time, those products were believed to be healthier. They weren&apos;t simply acting to&quot;give an impression of a healthier
product&quot;- to the best of anyone&apos;s knowledge at that time, the product WAS healthier! The companies were acting to satisfy consumer demand for healthier food - which later studies showed is actually worse for you. They behaved no differently than all those people who switched from using butter to using margarine, and who completely gave up eggs because they were supposedly&quot;high in cholesterol&quot;. And since the general public STILL doesn&apos;t fully realize the dangers of partially-hydrogenated vegetable oils, the companies would catch hell if they switched from the&quot;safer&quot;(in the public&apos;s mind) vegetable oil products they&apos;re using now to the supposedly&quot;unsafe&quot;(in the public&apos;s mind - but probably actually safer, given current scientific knowledge) stearic acid they originally used. Tars Tarkas 08-02-2002, 12:50 PM As many Americans now die every year from obesity-related illnesses--heart disease and complications of diabetes--as from smoking.


All this tells me is that Americans are lazy bums. How does that equate paying them millions? Smoking is just mentioned due to a political agenda. I ate a hamburger once, i demand 50 billion dollars! This thread makes me read, i demand $40 million from Grim to repair eye damage caused by reading his posts. Using his logic, i deserve it, after all, why should Grim keep posting when he knows that reading computer screens may damage people&apos;s eyes if they do it for long term. Such negligance. ::shakes head::

As for independent fast food places, i live in San Francisco, we have a trillion restaraunts featuring food from every ethinic group on earth and a few new ones the wackos in this town made up. There are more independent fast food places in this town than i can mention, despite having only lived here for 4 months and running into a small percentage. they do exist! (dry land is not a myth, i&apos;ve seen it!) bernse 08-02-2002, 02:14 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death


Surely you don&apos;t disagree that the Fast Food industry is more than partially responsible for the increase in obesity?


Absolutely.

For the love of god, it is a free country. If you can prove to me that eating a big mac is going to hurt you (unless of course you have some exisiting medical condition) you might have a point.

Otherwise, maybe we should sue the cattle industry as liver is very high in iron, and eating too much of that can be bad for you too. Heck! While you&apos;re at it, sue the pork industry. Ribs are bad for you too (if you eat them EVERY FUCKING DAY!!!) Hey! Here&apos;s another! Maybe sue the Ford family for Henry&apos;s mistake of perfecting the production line. Without it burgers, meat, food in general wouldn&apos;t be affordable.

Grim, surely you can&apos;t disagree that Henry Ford is at least partially responsible for obesity? Hell! He even made cars more common so people couldn&apos;t get exercise! Those poor people were hopeless once affordable automobiles came on the market!!

:rolleyes: Fred 08-02-2002, 02:50 PM Bernse, the rediculous hypothetical -- with exclamation points!!!!!!!!! has been done. In fact, me explaining that a poster isn&apos;t the first to attempt that particular brand of debate has also been done. Three times now.

Attention World: No matter how many times someone abuses the phrase&quot;by that logic&quot;to envision some completely rediculous hypothetical (!!!!!!) that bears no relationship to the current discussion, it will never magically become a good point. It will always be shit, no matter how many times it&apos;s repeated. This means you, Tars Tarkas.

Now I&apos;m not going to explain why you and bernse are huge idiots for even attempting to score points off that tactic. I&apos;m a busy man, involved in a very tough game of Freecell (#13272). I don&apos;t have time to explain to every moron that wanders into the thread exactly how moronic they are. From now on, valid points only, please.


Originally by artemis
And since the general public STILL doesn&apos;t fully realize the dangers of partially-hydrogenated vegetable oils, the companies would catch hell if they switched from the&quot;safer&quot;(in the public&apos;s mind) vegetable oil products they&apos;re using now to the supposedly&quot;unsafe&quot;(in the public&apos;s mind - but probably actually safer, given current scientific knowledge) stearic acid they originally used.


So what your saying is, in order to mislead the public into believing they are offering a healthier product, the fast food industry refuses to switch to safer product? Oh, well, when you put it that way, there&apos;s nothing wrong with that at all.


I&apos;m kidding.

QueenAl, are you offering this statement up as if it makes sense?



quote:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
I don&apos;t. And that&apos;s my ethical issue. Caring only about making money and not caring who suffers in order for you to get it is practically the definition of unethical.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No, it is practically the definition of the free market.


Because it doesn&apos;t. Your statement is a total non sequiter, as whether something is&quot;free market&quot;or not bears little relation to its ethical value.


Only because you&apos;re counting every single year from birth onwards.


Wrong. I was using the numbers from this actual case. Mr. Barbar claimed he started eating fast food&quot;sometime in the 50s&quot;. I assumed it was 1957, simply because 45 is a nice round number. Your assumption of starting at 18 and stopping at 40 is a complete hypothetical, thought up solely to make the numbers fit your particular theory. As such, I reject your numbers as useless. Even if they were correct, which they demonstrably aren&apos;t, given the choice between $30,000 now, and $30,000 40 years from now, it doesn&apos;t take an MBA to choose now. artemis 08-02-2002, 03:39 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
[So what your saying is, in order to mislead the public into believing they are offering a healthier product, the fast food industry refuses to switch to safer product? Oh, well, when you put it that way, there&apos;s nothing wrong with that at all.


I&apos;m kidding.

No, what I am clearly saying is that the fast food industry has responded to the public&apos;s mistaken impression that partially-hydrogenated vegetable oils are a&quot;healthy&quot;product. And the public didn&apos;t come by that impression due to the machinations of the fast food industry - no siree, that one can be blamed on many years of&quot;experts&quot;such as the American Heart Association and the American Cancer Society advising people to use these products in place of&quot;dangerous&quot;ones such as butter. Advice the public was bombarded with from the late 60s through the early 90s. And it takes YEARS to reverse the effects of such public advertising campaigns, so it&apos;s no surprise that so many people are still unaware that partially-hydrogenated oils are not as good for us as those&quot;experts&quot;previously thought. When the public begins to flex the power of their wallets to choose fast food franchises that don&apos;t use these products, the industry will respond and phase them out. They&apos;ll have to - or they&apos;ll go out of business.

And yes, the public IS capable of doing that, even while continuing to eat fast food. All that&apos;s required is to go to Subway instead of McDonald&apos;s. So don&apos;t keep whining about how victimized the public is by the terrible fast food industry. People are choosing to eat those products because they LIKE them, not because they&apos;re unthinking automatons being manipulated by this monstrous, near-omnipotent industry you keep portraying in your posts. The sad truth is that many people don&apos;t particularly care about making healthy dietary choices - either in the grocery story or when eating out - until their health is damaged, and then it&apos;s too late. And they never will. Pleasure now wins out over pain later. The public isn&apos;t the simply the victim - it&apos;s the problem. QueenAl 08-02-2002, 03:40 PM QueenAl, are you offering this statement up as if it makes sense?

quote:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
I don&apos;t. And that&apos;s my ethical issue. Caring only about making money and not caring who suffers in order for you to get it is practically the definition of unethical.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

No, it is practically the definition of the free market.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------



Because it doesn&apos;t. Your statement is a total non sequiter, as whether something is&quot;free market&quot;or not bears little relation to its ethical value.

Well, actually, it does. I also elaborated on that statement, if you remember.

But no, fuck this. I am not going to debate any further with someone who not only uses logic from beyond the looking glass, but throws insults around like a kid in a playground. When you call the people who disagree with you morons - as only the most obvious of a number of insults you throw around - this is where I step out of the discussion. Tars Tarkas 08-02-2002, 03:55 PM Oh, but its fun, QueenAl! Grim shoots of insults and illogic so often he should change his username to Old Faithful! And i Like exclamation points!!!! but besides that, I fail to see Grim&apos;s logic in supporting this lawsuit based on&quot;unhealthy&quot;food that is knowledgably given to customers. Why can&apos;t it be expanded to other things? This lawsuit itself is an expansion of the Gun and Tobacco lawsuits, what magic powers suddenly give the order&quot;No more expansion, because you are a moron&quot;when this is discussed? Sure, the tobacco people lie to congress, but Mcdonalds tells us their food is bad! And we love it!! Pass the Fries!!! bernse 08-02-2002, 04:03 PM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Bernse, the rediculous hypothetical -- with exclamation points!!!!!!!!! has been done. In fact, me explaining that a poster isn&apos;t the first to attempt that particular brand of debate has also been done. Three times now.

Attention World: No matter how many times someone abuses the phrase&quot;by that logic&quot;to envision some completely rediculous hypothetical (!!!!!!) that bears no relationship to the current discussion, it will never magically become a good point.

Unfortunately, precident has a nasty habit of effecting laws and peoples decision. So, yes, it is has a relationship. Whether you like it or not.

I AM THE grim spectre of death. These ridiculous arguments have no relationship whatsoever to the ridiculous argument I am making. That makes it unimportant to the ridiculous argument at hand.

If you had your mind even open just&lt;&gt;this much, you&apos;d see that the exact argument you are using against myself and others would have been thrown out if I someone made the ridiculous argument that 1 year ago McDonalds would be getting sued because its burgers are not good for you. This whole lawsuit is ridiculous to the extreme.

And yes, I read that you are not&quot;supporting&quot;it, but you sure seem to be doing your best to give it credibility when it has none, at least none with those of us in the crowd without tinfoil hats or crooked lawyers. Is MacDonalds good for you? Of course not. Is coca-cola good for you? Of course not. Are Pork Rinds good for you? No. Are these companies criminally responsible for making products that aren&apos;t good for you and they know it? No. Why? Because nobody is forcing anyone to patronize their products.

Once again, back to the very, very first post. Welcome to the US - Where you aren&apos;t responsible for anything. A bit of an over-generalization of course, but that is exactly what it boils down to. Caesar is so fucking lazy he can&apos;t make himself a sandwich (or whatever) and chose of his own free will to eat fast food 5 times a week. He chose to. He chose to give himself a lifestyle where he would be prone to heart-attacks and obesity. And he is not prepared to take the blame himself. That is the whole basis of this entire thread. Everyone knows, even Caesar that eating hamburgers and fries 5 times a week = BAD FOR YOU. It is nobody elses fault than his alone.

Now, go back to your exciting freecell game. Jadis 08-02-2002, 05:40 PM I&apos;m getting tired of this. Fred needs to learn the concept that correlation != causation (funny, there&apos;s a thread about this going on here (http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?s=&amp;threadid=127424), maybe he ought to check it out). Engaging in behavior that increases your risk of a specific outcome is leagues away from the conclusion&quot;activity X causes Y&quot;.

Listen. Heart disease and obesity have causes that are far more complex than whether or not you went to McDonald&apos;s a few times too often. Eating a Big Mac is not inherently unhealthy. Eating a Big Mac per day is not inherently unhealthy. Eating a Big Mac every single day in combination with scarfing pints of Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s in front of the TV at night, getting no exercise, drinking a pot of coffee every day and leading a stressful life might lead you to heart disease. Might.

Yes, overconsumption of a poor diet increases your risk for both obesity and heart disease, but to distill that one action down to the *cause* of those health problems is ludicrous, and going one step further to blame the restaurant that sold you high calorie food is even moreso.

I&apos;ll say it one more time (and it has been said repeatedly in this thread, but you choose to repeatedly ignore it)....no single food item is inherently unhealthy. Food is nothing more than a combination of nutrients that your body breaks down and uses for energy. How you choose to feed yourself is only one small factor in a much larger picture of the way you choose to live the rest of your life outside of your food choices.

Want an anecdote? My sister lives to eat buffalo wings. Absolutely loves them. By every nutritionist&apos;s guidelines of&quot;healthy&quot;food, buffalo wings are in the cellar and digging furiously. Do you know what? She eats wings probably 4-5 times a week. Want her health profile? She&apos;s 5&apos; tall and weighs approximately 120 lbs. While I don&apos;t know her body fat percentage, I know that it&apos;s in the athlete range for women. She&apos;s all muscle. Do you know why? Because she rides a few hundred miles a month on her road and mountain bikes. She runs. She rock climbs. She competes in adventure races. Her blood pressure is perfect and her total cholesterol is around 140. In other words, she can dump thousands of calories of high fat food into her body because.....wait for it.....she makes responsible choices about her lifestyle overall that mitigate her&quot;poor&quot;food choices. If she slacks off on her exercise and continues to stuff wings down her gullet, she doesn&apos;t sue the restaurant who sold them to her. See how easy that is? She takes responsibility for her health.

Honestly, I&apos;m baffled that there&apos;s a single person out there besides this guy&apos;s lawyer that actually believes that this case has some merit. Unbelieveable. Fred 08-02-2002, 10:02 PM Originally posted by QueenAl


Well, actually, it does. I also elaborated on that statement, if you remember.



No, it is practically the definition of the free market. In general, it works, because we do have choice - if they don&apos;t provide what we want to buy, we&apos;ll go somewhere else, so they provide what we want. And it seems we want fatty hamburgers.


You described the free market, rather than the ethics. If you believe that no company that operates in the free market can ever be unethical, I can debate you on that point. I&apos;m sure you&apos;re not alone in holding that opinion, it&apos;s just not one I agree with.


When you call the people who disagree with you morons - as only the most obvious of a number of insults you throw around - this is where I step out of the discussion.


I&apos;m sorry you&apos;re leaving. I found your opinion valuable, and the points you raised cogent. I would like to point out that I&apos;m not in the habit of calling everyone I disagree with a moron: you&apos;ll note that I never insulted the vast majority of those whose position is opposite to my own. I&apos;m frustrated by the belief that creating a bizarre hypothetical that bears little relation to the situation at hand is somehow a valid debating strategy, and this frustration translated into uncalled for harshness.

In addition, I feel like I should apologize for coming across as condescending -- not just to you, but to everyone in this thread who has brought up valid points that contradict my own opinions (especially, among others, RexDart). Although it&apos;s no excuse, I&apos;ve been feeling more than a little over my head in this thread. More than a little overwhelmed. As soon as I finish one reply, I begin another. Now, after spending some time away from this thread and able to put things in perspective, I have come to regret my poor attitude. I can see why this seems like a lame excuse for the shortness of temper that I&apos;ve shown, but perhaps you are feeling forgiving this evening. I&apos;m a good guy if I&apos;m not snarling like a cornered animal. I swear. :)

bernse, I was mean to you. It was uncalled for. With that behind us, I seriously don&apos;t understand this statement:


Unfortunately, precident has a nasty habit of effecting laws and peoples decision. So, yes, it is has a relationship. Whether you like it or not.


Perhaps some clarification is in order? Also,


If you had your mind even open just&lt;&gt;this much, you&apos;d see that the exact argument you are using against myself and others would have been thrown out if I someone made the ridiculous argument that 1 year ago McDonalds would be getting sued because its burgers are not good for you. This whole lawsuit is ridiculous to the extreme.


I&apos;m not sure to which argument you are referring to. By necessity, I&apos;ve been kind of leap-frogging all over this thread; I&apos;ve espoused quite a few points, and I&apos;m not sure quite which one you are referring to here.

Tars Tarkas: Man, oh man. I hope that one day you and I can overcome the emnity that has been formed between us in this thread. I fully accept my responsibility for creating a large portion of that emnity.


This lawsuit itself is an expansion of the Gun and Tobacco lawsuits, what magic powers suddenly give the order&quot;No more expansion, because you are a moron&quot;when this is discussed?


I realize now that it was counter-productive to sling insults instead of explaining what the differences are between your hypothetical paper lawsuit and any possible lawsuit against the fast food industry. I&apos;ll attempt to do so now.

- Paper cuts are only tangentially related to the use of paper. Health issues are directly related to the regular consumption of fast food. Specifically, I&apos;m referring to the relationship between the health issue and the way the product is marketed.
- Paper cuts are an infinitely less serious health issues than obesity.
- A healthier version of paper that only changes paper with regards to health issues, not any other primary characteristic, does not exist.

The only similarities that I can see between your hypothetical paper lawsuit and the fast food lawsuit is that both involve a company, a person, and an alledged tort. Are there other similarities that I am missing, that would make the analogy more apt?

-------


I thank everyone for having patience with me (or not, as the case may be) over the course of this thread. I understand how frustrating it can be to attempt to converse with someone who&apos;s opinion runs counter to what you believe to be unavoidable fact. I&apos;d love to continue this discussion, but I&apos;m going on vacation for the next week or so. When I come back, either the thread will be dead, or powered by pure astonishment at my position, and it&apos;s stupidity thereof. I doubt even I will be able to wade through a week&apos;s worth of hostile replies, so I guess this is goodbye. So long, folks. Typo Negative 08-03-2002, 01:46 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death

From the article quoted in my first post:


quote:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

As many Americans now die every year from obesity-related illnesses--heart disease and complications of diabetes--as from smoking.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------


I&apos;m sorry. I meant a cite that actually supports what you allege. You said that the fast food joints profit from millions of deaths. And imply that they cause those deaths.

Here is the point of out contention.

You:&quot;This food is causing obesity and people are dying because of it. It&apos;s the fast food industries fault. Because God knows, if weren&apos;t for them, their would be no obesity. Mr Barbar would be svelte were it not McDonalds heinous act of providing tasty food.&quot;.

Me:&quot;Horsefeathers. Some people are over consuming and have poor health. Others are not over consuming, enjoying the food, and leading healthy lives. So obviously, you cannot prove causation. Those that over consume and blame others for that are the bottom of the fucking barrel, and the world would be a better place without them, as well as those who apologize for them and rationalize what they do.&quot;

Again, can you show that a McDonalds meal, by itself, causes any health disorders? And notice I did not say a McDonalds meal, eaten every freaking day, or 3 times a day. Because then we are not talking about the meal, but the abuse by the consumer. D_Odds 08-03-2002, 06:14 AM Originally posted by the grim spectre of red death
Does McDonald&apos;s really claim that someone can eat a Big Mac meal a day with no ill effect? Because if so, this lawsuit has been handed a giant gift.


No, McDonalds doesn&apos;t say that, nor did I claim that McDonalds said that. What I said wasLooking at the nutritional data (sorry I didn&apos;t link it before, but it&apos;s at www.mcdonalds.com somewhere), a full-grown adult with a moderate activity level and otherwise healthy diet could eat a Big Mac daily with no ill effects. I did not, in any way, mean to imply that this was an official McDonalds stance. What I said was that Big Macs could be eaten frequently (w/o the french fries) as part of an otherwise overall healthy lifestyle.

I noticed, from your linked article, that it wasn&apos;t the lean beef that one buys in the grocery store. It was modified for purposes of the test so that it doesn&apos;t dry out. I said that store-bought lean mean is too dry, and they agreed. Of course, none of us knows the additional cost of adultering the beef, so these cost analyses presented thus far are moot. World Eater 09-05-2003, 06:46 AM The case has been thrown out a second time!

Wooooohooo!

The judge said they can&apos;t refile either.

http://www.cnn.com/2003/LAW/09/04/mcdonalds.suit/index.html ralph124c 09-05-2003, 07:12 AM We all know that the leagl industry is sizing up the fast-foodindustry, as a source of potentially profitable litigation. I think the lawyers should extend the lawsuits to:
-the alcoholic beverage industry (becoming an alcoholic shortens your life)
-the candy industry (dental caroes and obesety result from consumption of candy)
-the suntanning industry (suntans cause skin cancer, and the availblity of tanning booths convincespeople that they are&quot;safe&quot;
The way I see it, there is more than enough litigation to go around..we&apos;ll have to build more court houses though! Earthworm Jim 09-05-2003, 07:34 AM &quot;If a person knows or should know that eating copious orders of super-sized McDonald&apos;s products is unhealthy and may result in weight gain,&quot;[U.S. District Court Judge Robert] Sweet wrote in January,&quot;it is not the place of the law to protect them from their own excesses.&quot;
I love this man. World Eater 09-05-2003, 10:31 AM Yeah what&apos;s up with this thing called&quot;common sense&quot;having a place in our courts? World Eater 09-05-2003, 10:31 AM Yeah what&apos;s up with this thing called&quot;common sense&quot;having a place in our courts? musicguy 09-05-2003, 11:49 AM Originally posted by Fred
Americans do not have the ability to choose unsafe products if they so desire.

You mean like tobacco and alcohol?

Speaking of which, people sue the tobacco companies due to health problems when they are engaging in a legal, yet harmful, activity. And in most cases, they are perfectly aware of the dangers beforehand.

While this lawsuit is ridiculous, how different is it from a person claiming that they didn&apos;t know that cigarettes will give you heart disease? GaWd 09-05-2003, 12:35 PM While this lawsuit is ridiculous, how different is it from a person claiming that they didn&apos;t know that cigarettes will give you heart disease?


It&apos;s not different, but those suits were fucking lame too.

I should say, that there was a difference in the cig cases. The majors difference was that outsiders had gotten a hold of internal memos that stated exactly the opposite of what they said publicly regarding the addiction and dangers of smoking cigarettes.

Still fucking dumb though. I&apos;m a smoker. I understand that if I don&apos;t quit smoking that it will kill me. Where&apos;s the lawsuit?

Sam vBulletinv3.7.3, Copyright2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
