<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008136" url="http://lvswan.org/BCC_Archive_2008.htm" time="2012-07-13-01:13" support="1" score="0.0008418241857260018" bingtitle="Clark County Zoning Commission Agenda Archive 2008" webtitle="Clark County Zoning Commission Agenda Archive 2008">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="162"/>
	<description>TAB Approved with Zone Change to C-1 1. Trash ... any request for a standards change up to the County ... will be required for the fast food restaurant; any change in ...</description>
	<body>
		THE SOUTHWEST ACTION NETWORK

Clark County Zoning Commission Agenda Archive 2008

These are applications heard by the Zoning Commission which were of interest to SWAN
 
     The complete agenda results and Notices of Final Action can be found on the Clark County Web Site agenda page about a week after the hearing. A &quot;live stream&quot; in real time broadcast of the Zoning Commission proceedings is now available on Clark County cable TV station Channel 4. A live broadcast can also be viewed on the Clark County web site. Click on Channel 4 or go to the Agenda page. An archived video of the Zonning Commission proceedings is now available online at the Clark County web site the same evening as the meeting (see the link below). It is possible to view individually heard applications. These are only available for about a year. You may also call the Current Planning desk the next day to inquier about the results of applications.

       These are only the applications that came before the Planning and Zoning Commissions that SWAN was concerned with. For a complete record of the recent   Notices of Final Action  on all items that came before the Planning and Zoning Commissions follow the above link.
 
 ZONING COMMISSION 12-17-08

25. ZC-1029-03 (ET-0271-08) - SOUTHWEST INVESTMENT AND MGMT, ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE SECOND EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office and Professional) Zone and C-1 (Local Business) Zone for a commercial center. Generally located on the south side of Cougar Avenue (alignment), 300 feet east of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file). BW/dg/nd
TAB held no applicant
HELD - 01/21/09 - for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

27. UC-1055-08 - STRIP REAL ESTATE ONE, LLC, ET AL:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a High Impact Project; 2) a resort hotel with 300 hotel rooms; 3) increase building heights; 4) public areas including all casino, retail, restaurant, meeting and convention center areas, back-of-house areas, and parking structures; 5) associated accessory and incidental commercial uses, buildings, and structures; and 6) deviations to development standards.
DEVIATIONS for the following: 1) reduce on-site parking and loading spaces; 2) allow alternative means of access for accessory uses in conjunction with a resort hotel; 3) encroachment into airspace; and 4) all other deviations as shown per plans on file.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a resort hotel/casino with a mid-rise tower; and 2) all other accessory and incidental buildings and structures for a resort hotel project on 15.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) (AE-65) (AE-70) Zone. Generally located on the west side of Las Vegas Boulevard South and the north side of Arby Avenue (alignment) within Enterprise. BW/dk/dr
HELD - 01/21/09 - per the applicant for FAA determination.
TAB approved with conditions:
1. Signage and lighting Design Review as a public hearing.
2. Applicant will abide by FAA building height recommendations
3. The applicant will brief the TAB on the traffic plan.

43. ZC-0964-08 - GRAGSON BUFFALO WINDMILL, ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 4.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a supper club; 2) reduce the separation from supper club to a residential use; 3) a convenience store; 4) reduce the separation from a convenience store to a residential use; 5) reduce the setback from a convenience store to section line street; 6) a car wash; 7) reduce separation from a car wash to a residential use; 8) a service station; 9) reduce the separation from a service station to a residential use; and 10) reduce the setback from a service station to section line street.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center. Generally located on the west side of Buffalo Drive and the south side of Windmill Lane within Enterprise (description on file). BW/kk/nd
HELD - 01/21/09 - per the applicant.

53. WS-0976-08 - WORLDMARK THE CLUB:
APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to allow non-standard commercial driveway access (reduced throat depth) from an arterial street (Las Vegas Boulevard South).
DESIGN REVIEW for a guard shack on 15.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the southwest corner of Las Vegas Boulevard South and Wigwam Avenue within Enterprise. BW/dk/dr
APPROVED
Current Planning
Remove guard shack when Las Vegas Boulevard South is widened to its full width adjacent to this parcel;
TAB Approved with an additional condition-the guard building will be removed if Las Vegas Blvd is built out to the full right-of-way.
The staff was concerned with the throat depth if Las Vegas Blvd was fully built out. This would leave less than 10 feet of driveway. The applicant suggested a solution which became the additional condition for this application.

54. TA-0538-08 - G.C. GARCIA:
AMENDED TEXT AMENDMENT to amend Table 30.44-1, Chapter 30.44 of the Unified Development Code to allow bed and breakfast (previously requested as a senior hostel) as a use within the County. ab
HELD - No Date - per the applicant.
Staff Recommendation Denial.
TAB Denied
Title 30 specifically prohibits transient commercial use of residential development for remuneration in all residential zoning districts, or in any miscellaneous zoning district. A Bed and Breakfast would be a transient commercial use of a single family home. The requested change would establish a use that would be considered transient in nature and should be classified as a hotel, motel, or other similar use. Those uses are allowed in C-2, M-D, M-1, U-V, and H-1 zones. Allowing this use will undermine the provision in the code prohibiting transient commercial use in areas designated for residential use. This type of transient use, Bed and Breakfast, within a residential urban area would be disruptive to the residential character of the neighborhood. Currently, the stipulation that a Bed and Breakfast is allowed only within Community District 5 was to allow for services in rural areas where there are no hotels or motels and demand is much lower. The intensity of hotels or motels in the rural areas is not desirable. The Bed and Breakfast provision in Community District 5 is seen as a way to provide services where there are none currently. This text amendment would allow for the potential of Bed and Breakfast within the R-E zoning district for the entire County.
The TAB felt this Text Amendment would hinder the control of short term party house rentals.

ZONING COMMISSION 12-3-08

10. UC-0973-08 - FIVE ACRE PARCEL INVESTOR, LLC:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) retail center; 2) convenience store; 3) reduce the setback from a convenience store to a residential use; 4) reduce the setback from a service station to a residential use; 5) reduce the separation from an automobile maintenance facility to a residential use; 6) reduce the separation from an automobile repair facility to a residential use; and 7) permit overhead doors to face a public street.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) alternative street landscaping; 2) non-standard commercial driveway access and separations.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS of a zone change (ZC-0269-05) requiring a minimum 10 foot wide landscaping along rights-of-way; and of a zone change (ZC-1584-98) requiring the following: 1) no loading areas adjacent to or visible from Ford Avenue; 2) no loading docks within 100 feet of a residential use; 3) on-site lighting to consist of low-sodium, inward directed features to be included in each design review; 4) A-1 landscaping along all major street frontages; 5) B-2 landscaping along minor street frontages; 6) A-2 landscape buffer adjacent to any existing residential developments; 7) master studies to address the entire 91 acre development prior to the issuance of any permits or subdivision mapping, whichever occurs first; and 8) 30 feet for Ford Avenue west of Edmond Street and a portion of a knuckle at Edmond Street.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail center with a convenience store, service station, and auto repair facility on 4.3 acres in an M-D (Designed Manufacturing) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of Blue Diamond Road and the west and east sides of Edmond Street within Enterprise. BW/dg/nd
APPROVED
Current Planning
Design review as a public hearing on final plans to review the architectural compatibility and consistency of the retail center;
Gasoline canopy to have similar architectural elements and enhancements on the columns and canopy of the convenience store and retail center buildings;
Cross access as depicted on the easterly parcel per plans;
Since the adjacent parcel to the west may develop with similar intensity of uses, provide cross access with parcel to the west;
Enhanced paving at all access points;
Signage to be a design review as a public hearing;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that loading spaces per Title 30 are required and will be addressed on any subsequent design review; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 30 feet for Ford Avenue along APN 176-13-801-047 and associated spandrel;
Construct full off-sites;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Signs to be set back 10 feet from the right-of-way and maintain clearance from the site visibility zones;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval.
TAB APPROVED per staff conditions
Many of the Waivers of Conditions are a result of previous BCC conditions for a defunct project on this property. The applicant presented pictures from another project as an example of the building design for this project. The staff recommended a design review as a public hearing due to the lack of specific plans on file with the county. The TAB agreed with this assessment by the staff.

25. UC-0909-08 - R&amp;S;ST ROSE, LLC:
HOLDOVER USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a High Impact Project; 2) a mixed-use development including residential condominiums, hotel rooms, retail, commercial, and accessory and incidental uses; and 3) increase building height.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a mixed-use development consisting of residential, commercial and required open space; and 2) manmade decorative water features on 38.1 acres in a U-V (Urban Village - Mixed Use) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of St. Rose Parkway and the east side of Spencer Street within Enterprise. BW/dk/es
APPROVED
Current Planning
Signage and lighting as a public hearing;
A Development Agreement as agreed upon by the applicant to mitigate impacts of the project including but not limited to issues identified by the technical reports and studies, and issues identified by the Board of County Commissioners (grading, excavation, de-watering, and underground utility permits may be issued prior to the approval of the Development Agreement);
Manmade decorative water features to be interactive with no water accumulation on the surface;
Design review as a public hearing on any significant changes to the plan;
Design review on any building elevation changes from plans on file;
Civil Engineering
Compliance with NZC-0976-04;
Dedicate any additional right-of-way on Jeffreys Street and Spencer Street to accommodate any additional turn lanes;
Redesign the driveway located on St. Rose Parkway to accommodate 24 foot ingress and egress lanes;
Redesign the driveway located on Spencer Street to remove the pork chop and first median;
Coordinate trails along St. Rose Parkway with the City of Henderson and the Nevada Department of Transportation.
TAB Approved with condition for public design review for lighting and signage. The TAB added a note of concern about amount of traffic this project will generate and the lack of effective mass transportation.
One of the three key elements required for MUD to work is effective mass transportation. The transportation element to make MUD work is an above or below ground mass transportation system. The increased population in the MUD developed areas will choke the road system. Busses, in any form, require roads and will become snarled in the auto traffic. Currently, there are no plans within Clark County to build an above or below ground transportation system.

26. ZC-0912-08 - BERMUDA BUILDING, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.9 acres from C-P (Office and Professional) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for an office/retail building. Generally located on the southwest corner of Warm Springs Road and Bermuda Road within Enterprise (description on file). BW/gc/dr
APPROVED
Current Planning
Reduction to C-1 zoning;
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning; Move the trash enclosure to the northwest corner of the site;
Civil Engineering
Drainage study update and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance.
TAB Approved with Zone Change to C-1
1. Trash container to the NW portion of the property.
2. Lighting to comply with current Title 30 lighting standards.
The TAB felt the C-2 zone was too intense for the neighborhood. Tavern and 24-hour operations were opposed by the neighbors. Also, the applicant could not tell the TAB what tenants would require a C-2 zone to operate. With the lack of clarity on tenants and the neighborhood opposition, the TAB concluded C-1 was a better fit for this corner. If this project should fail and the C-2 zone was in place, it could lead to a 24-hour convenience store operation which the neighbors do not want.

27. ZC-0952-08 - DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LTD:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 5.1 acres from M-1 (Light Manufacturing) Zone and R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to M-1 (Light Manufacturing) Zone.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce parking 2) eliminate landscaping; and 3) off-site improvements (excluding paving).
DESIGN REVIEW for an equipment storage facility. Generally located on the south side of Gomer Road, 315 feet east of Redwood Street (alignment) within Enterprise (description on file). SB/ar/mh
TAB Held, no applicant
HELD - 01/07/09 - for the applicant to attend the Enteprise Town Board meeting.

35. WS-0607-08 - SANSONE 215 RAINBOW, LLC:
HOLDOVER AMENDED WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce the separation requirements between 2 freestanding signs (previously notified as increase the height of a freestanding sign).
DESIGN REVIEW for a comprehensive sign package in conjunction with a proposed professional office complex and parking garage on 5.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-60) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts. Generally located on the north side of Raphael Rivera Way and the west side of Montessouri Street within Spring Valley. BW/jr/dc
APPROVED
Current Planning
A minimum separation of 270 feet;
Removal of monument signs along Montessouri Street;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any new signs proposed on the site will be required to go through a design review process; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Forward edge of sign to be set back from the right-of-way or future right-of-way.

42. ZC-0964-08 - GRAGSON BUFFALO WINDMILL, ET AL:
HELD - 12/17/08 - per the applicant.

44. ZC-1039-08 - USA:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone in a MUD-3 Overlay District to R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone with a Residential Neighborhood Preservation Overlay District I (RNP-I) designation. Generally located on the southeast corner of Lindell Road and Pebble Road within Enterprise (description on file). BW/rs/mh
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedications, off-site improvements, technical traffic, and drainage studies with future development of the parcel.
This item is the result of 18 months work by the neighborhood. The neighbors wanted to prevent incompatible uses before a project was proposed. The change to remove commercial uses from the property required the following steps:
1. The Enterprise Land Use Plan needed to be changed from Commercial Neighborhood to Rural Neighborhood Preservation land use.
2. The Mixed-Use-Development overlay needed to be removed.
3. The state imposed H-2 zone district needed to be changed to RE.
4. The RNP-1 overlay be applied to the property.
The neighborhood was concerned about how the county had designated this property. The concern was the property could be developed as commercial with as little as 10 ft separation to a 35 ft high building. It has established residential on three sides. Two of the those sides are current in the RNP-1 overlay and this piece will square off the corner.

51. VC-0842-08 - RHODES RANCH, G.P.:
HOLDOVER APPEAL VARIANCES for the following: 1) allow more than one sign per street frontage; and 2) increase the allowable square footage for signage.
DESIGN REVIEW for an entry sign for a master planned community on approximately 13.8 acres in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community. Generally located on the northwest corner of Durango Drive and Rhodes Ranch Parkway within Spring Valley. SB/rk/lgp/co
APPROVED
Major Project - Planning
No floodlights, spotlights, or any other similar lighting shall be used to illuminate the signage;
Illumination to be low-level lighting with ground mounted fixtures;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Major Projects Engineering
Maintain site visibility zone.

58. ORD-1315-07:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to allow electronic off-premise signs (billboard conversions); and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.08, 30.16, 30.36, 30.44, 30.72, 30.76 and 30.80 30.08.030, 30.72.040 and 30.76.060; Tables 30.16-10, 30.16-17 30.44-1 and 30.80-1; to allow electronic off-premise (billboard) sign conversions and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD - 01/21/09 - per the BCC.

59. HOLDOVER ORD-1419-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to Amend Title 30 of the Clark County Code to clarify and revise regulations regarding Community Residences; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.08, 30.16, 30.44; Section 30.08.030; and Table 30.16-17.5 and 30.44-1; to revise regulations for community residences (group homes), to provide an administrative process for the approval of specified applications and make other corrections and clarifications as necessary; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

60. ORD-1555-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to expand the boundaries of the Mixed-Use 2 Overlay District onto parcels 162-22-501-004 thru 005; 162-22-502-003 thru 004; 162-22-510-001; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Appendix G. Map 15a, to amend the Mixed-Use Overlay District map: and provide for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 11-19-08

6. DR-0982-08 - WCP LAKE HILLS ASSOCIATES, LP, ET AL:
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail/pharmacy in conjunction with an approved mixed-use development on a portion of 6.5 acres in a U-V (Urban Village - Mixed Use) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the northeast corner of Blue Diamond Road and Buffalo Drive within Enterprise. BW/jt/mh
APPROVED
Current Planning
Provide arch reveals on north exterior elevation walls and EIFS cornices along the north elevation rooflines to match architectural features on the south, east, and west elevations;
Provide a cover for the trash enclosure that incorporates design features and colors found on the building;
Provide enhanced paving in an east/west direction across the drive-thru lane located at the southwest corner of the building, and pedestrian access to the sidewalk along Buffalo Drive at this location to enable continued pedestrian circulation as depicted on the approved pedestrian circulation plan for UC-1326-07;
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-0362-06;
VS-0755-06 is to record prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Additional right-of-way dedication of flaring may be needed at Buffalo Drive and Blue Diamond Road.
TAB Approved, deleted staff condition #3
The TAB deleted the following:
Provide enhanced paving in an east/west direction across the drive-thru lane located at the southwest corner of the building. Also, pedestrian access to the sidewalk along Buffalo Drive at this location to enable continued pedestrian circulation, as depicted on the approved pedestrian circulation plan for UC-1326-07.
The TAB felt the enhanced paving would be visually more pleasing, but it has several problems. The rough surface produces a higher level of tire noise. It is difficult to walk on with a cane or walker and it chips and cracks along the edges.

10. ZC-1029-03 (ET-0271-08) - SOUTHWEST INVESTMENT AND MGMT, ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE SECOND EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office and Professional) Zone and C-1 (Local Business) Zone for a commercial center. Generally located on the south side of Cougar Avenue (alignment), 300 feet east of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file). BW/dg/nd
Held, no applicant at TAB
HELD - 12/17/08 - for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

17. UC-0909-08 - R&amp;S;ST ROSE, LLC:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a High Impact Project; 2) a mixed-use development including residential condominiums, hotel rooms, retail, commercial, and accessory and incidental uses; and 3) increase building height.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a mixed-use development consisting of residential, commercial and required open space; and 2) manmade decorative water features on 38.1 acres in a U-V (Urban Village - Mixed Use) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of St. Rose Parkway and the east side of Spencer Street within Enterprise. BW/dk/es
HELD - 12/03/08 - per staff.

23. WS-0812-08 - J3 DECATUR, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increased freestanding sign height; and 2) increased sign area.
DESIGN REVIEW a comprehensive sign program in conjunction with a shopping center on 3.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-60) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of the 215 Beltway and the west side of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise. RR/dg/nd
APPROVED
Civil Engineering
Signs to be set back from the rights-of-way and maintain clearance from the site visibility zones.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS WAS WITHDRAWN.

30. ZC-0964-08 - GRAGSON BUFFALO WINDMILL, ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 4.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a supper club; 2) reduce the separation from supper club to a residential use; 3) a convenience store; 4) reduce the separation from a convenience store to a residential use; 5) reduce the setback from a convenience store to section line street; 6) a car wash; 7) reduce separation from a car wash to a residential use; 8) a service station; 9) reduce the separation from a service station to a residential use; and 10) reduce the setback from a service station to section line street.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center. Generally located on the west side of Buffalo Drive and the south side of Windmill Lane within Enterprise (description on file). BW/kk/nd
HELD - 12/03/08 - per the applicant.

36. UC-0841-08 - SUNRISE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
APPEAL USE PERMIT for a communications tower.
DESIGN REVIEW for a communications tower and associated equipment on a portion of 1.8 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone. Generally located on the southeast corner of Fort Apache Road and Cactus Avenue within Enterprise. SB/mh/mh
APPROVED
Current Planning
Tower to be a monopine in design;
Applicant is advised that this approval also includes all future antennas proposed in conjunction with this tower, provided all future antennas are determined to not be visually obtrusive to this area, and that in order to construct this tower, building permits must be obtained for this tower prior to building permits being issued for any other communication tower within a radius of 600 feet otherwise additional land use applications may be required; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.

46. HOLDOVER ORD-1419-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to Amend Title 30 of the Clark County Code to clarify and revise regulations regarding Community Residences; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.08, 30.16, 30.44; Section 30.08.030; and Table 30.16-17.5 and 30.44-1; to revise regulations for community residences (group homes), to provide an administrative process for the approval of specified applications and make other corrections and clarifications as necessary; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD - 12/03/08 - per the BCC.

47. HOLDOVER ORD-1430-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to remove the Mixed-Use Overlay District designation from parcel 176-24-501-001; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Appendix G. Map 15a, to amend the Mixed-Use Overlay District map: and provide for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED

ZONING COMMISSION 11-5-08

21. ZC-0912-08 BERMUDA BUILDING, LLC: TAB Approved with Zone Change to C-1
1. Trash container to the NW portion of the property.
2. Lighting to comply with current Title 30 lighting standards.
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.9 acres from C-P (Office and Professional) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for an office/retail building. Generally located on the southwest corner of Warm Springs Road and Bermuda Road within Enterprise (description on file). BW/gc/dr
HELD - 12/03/08 - per the applicant.
The TAB felt the C-2 zone was too intense for the neighborhood. Tavern and 24-hour operations were opposed by the neighbors. Also, the applicant could not tell the TAB what tenants would require a C-2 zone to operate. With the lack of clarity on tenants and the neighborhood opposition, the TAB concluded C-1 was a better fit for this corner. If this project should fail and the C-2 zone was in place, it could lead to a 24-hour convenience store operation which the neighbors do not want.

26. NZC-0982-04 (ET-0334-07) - HURLEY, STEVE&amp;DONNA:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 2.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone for a plant nursery.
USE PERMIT to review outside storage for a plant nursery to be located in front of the building. Generally located on the north side of Gomer Road and the east side of Fort Apache Road within Enterprise (description on file). SB/sc/dc
HELD - 12/03/08 - per the applicant.

30. WS-0812-08 J3 DECATUR, LLC: TAB Approved: the Design Review. TAB Denied: the Waivers of Development Standards
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increased freestanding sign height; and 2) increased sign area.
DESIGN REVIEW a comprehensive sign program in conjunction with a shopping center on 3.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-60) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of the 215 Beltway and the west side of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD - 11/19/08 - per the applicant. WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #1 AND #2 WERE WITHDRAWN.
The purpose of the CMA Overlay District was to establish a set of site and design standards for this unique, geographic area and achieve a predictable quality of architectural and site design with an emphasis on a unified and enhanced streetscape. One of the most important elements in ensuring enhanced streetscapes, especially along prominent rights-of-way, is signage. Therefore, the development of the overlay district included an emphasis on minimizing the visual impact of on-premise signage.
The Board&apos;s intent in adopting the sign height regulations was to also minimize the concentration of vertical massing along the 215 Beltway in order to enhance the visual aesthetics, minimize vehicular distraction, and improve traffic safety. Several requests have been considered by BCC for increased sign height. Six requests have been denied, with a seventh and eighth request being withdrawn prior to the BCC consideration. During the BCC hearing on the prior requests, there was substantial discussion regarding maintaining the intent and integrity of the established standards. There have been several approvals for increased freestanding sign heights, but those individual circumstances were unique and the BCC clearly articulated those circumstances during the public hearings.
The applicant stated they would like to see the sign standard changed to permit taller and larger signs. The TAB opinion is the applicant will have to take any request for a standards change up to the County Commissioners. The TAB agreed with the staff analysis and voted to deny the Waivers of Development Standards.

44. CP-1024-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing and approve, adopt and authorize the Chairman to sign a resolution amending the Clark County Transportation Element Map 1.3 to remove Pebble Road from Fort Apache Road to Hualapai Way as a 100 foot arterial and reduce the first 660 feet of Pebble Road west of Fort Apache Road from a 100 foot major arterial to an 80 foot collector.
APPROVED.

51. ORD-1430-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to remove the Mixed-Use Overlay District designation from parcel 176-24-501-001; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Appendix G. Map 15a, to amend the Mixed-Use Overlay District map: and provide for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD - 11/19/08 - per the applicant.

ZONING COMMISSION 10-22-08

9. ZC-1407-02 (ET-0241-08) - ALL FOR ONE FAMILY TRUST, ET AL:
AMENDED ZONE CHANGE SECOND EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 4.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone to construct a shopping center.
USE PERMIT to reduce the separation required between a residential use and on-premise consumption of alcohol (previously not notified). Generally located on the northeast corner of Buffalo Drive and Robindale Road within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD - 01/07/09 - for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting 12 Nov 2008.
There are questions about the placement of a building on the property and the ability to obtain a permit for alcohol consumption due to a church nearby.

29. ZC-0819-08 - UNITED STATES OF AMERICA:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 15.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to P-F (Public Facility) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) library; 2) auditorium; 3) service center/storage; 4) offices; 5) automobile/truck fueling; 6) automobile/truck washing; and 7) automobile/truck storage. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane, 325 feet west of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file). APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning.
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication/grant to include 4.5 feet for Santoli Avenue, additional right-of-way along Windmill Lane to accommodate detached sidewalks and associated easements;
Construct full off-sites;
Drainage study and compliance;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control.

48. WS-0653-08 BOUQUET, INC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce setback, and 2) allow a drive-thru talk box to face residential development.
DESIGN REVIEW for a commercial building with drive-thru restaurants on 0.8 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the west side of Maryland Parkway, 150 feet south of Pyle Avenue within Enterprise.
HELD - No Date - per the applicant. Applicant is advised that renotification fees will be required prior to this item being placed on an agenda; and that this application will expire if more than 6 months elapse from the date of this meeting without a request by the applicant for a new hearing.

61. ORD-1430-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to remove the Mixed-Use Overlay District designation from parcel 176-24-501-001; and direct staff accordingly.An ordinance to amend Title 30, Appendix G. Map 15a, to amend the Mixed-Use Overlay District map: and provide for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED - public hearing 11/05/08.

72. ORD-1266-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Cactus Land Development, LLC for a commercial development (Cactus and Jones Shopping Center).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Cactus Land Development, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the west side of Jones Boulevard and the south side of Cactus Avenue within the Northeast quarter (NE1/4) of Section 35, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 10-8-08

7. UC-157-82 (ET-0219-08) LARSON, MEL AND MARILYN: TAB approved
USE PERMIT THIRD EXTENSION OF TIME to review a heliport and a helicopter repair facility on a portion of 4.1 acres in an H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of Larson Lane, 300 feet east of Las Vegas Boulevard South within Enterprise.
This item generated considerable discussion. The staff has requested a five year review due to development in the area. This site has provided facilities for medical helicopters since 1982. The site provides maintenance facilities and crew quarters. The TAB felt this is an essential life saving service to the community and should not be squeezed out by future development. The TAB agreed with the applicant to make this Use Permit permanent.
It must be noted that the Staff has not found any documented complaints or issues that would adversely impact the immediate area due to the continuing operations of this heliport.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Six months to apply for the necessary use permit, with corresponding planning report and FAA approval, on the 2.4 acre parcel directly to the west (APN# 191-08-801-007) that is currently being used for this heliport;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that a Record of Survey may be needed concurrently with the submission of the use permit for the parcel that has frontage on Las Vegas Boulevard South; and that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with previous conditions.
Department of Aviation
Applicant must file Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) Form 7480-1, &quot;Notice of Landing Area Proposal&quot; with the FAA, per 14 CFR Part 157, to address the additional property;
Applicant must comply with all heliport planning report requirements described in Table 30.44-1 &quot;Heliport&quot; of the Code.
Applicant is advised that all helicopter noise complaints and inquiries regarding operations from this facility will be forwarded to the operator of this heliport.

19. NZC-0736-08 2.5 ACRES DEAN MARTIN, LLC:
TAB Denied: This application is premature in view of the Enterprise Land Use Plan update currently underway.
PC Action - Approved
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) service station; 2) convenience store; 3) reduce the separation from a convenience store to a residential use; and 4) reduce the separation from service station to a residential use.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce the height setback ratio from a residential use to commercial buildings.
DESIGN REVIEW for the following: 1) a service station; 2) a convenience store; and 3) a shopping center. Generally located on the west side of Dean Martin Drive and the north side of Cactus Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
Architectural treatments are to be applied to the north and east elevations of the convenience store building to include some additional features, such as but not limited to, color contrasted overhead trellis features, screen walls with architectural features, an awning above door, dimensioned contrast treatment around door and windows, window features added, landscaping accents, building facade treatments, and linear and horizontal column off-sets in the buildings that extend outward;
Upper portions of west and north elevations of commercial building to be enhanced with additional reveals and horizontal and vertical protruding elements contrasted to the building;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must be completed within 3 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication of 40 feet back of curb for Dean Martin Drive and 50 feet back of curb for Cactus Avenue and associated spandrel;
Dedicate and construct a right turn lane on the north leg of Dean Martin Drive and Cactus Avenue;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, traffic study to address no left turn;
Dedicate and construct a bus turnout on Cactus Avenue according to Regional Transportation Commission standards and Clark County Civil Engineering;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal.

34. CP-1024-08* TAB approved
A proposed amendment to the Clark County Transportation Element to remove Pebble road as a 100 foot arterial from 660 feet west of Ft apache Road to Hualapai Way. The first 660 feet of Pebble Road west of Ft Apache to be reduced to an 80 foot collector.
This amendment will allow for the development of the westernmost RNP in Enterprise. The 100ft Pebble right-of-way had cut the RNP in half. It is interesting to note the applicants commissioned their own traffic study to convince the county that the 100 ft right of way was not needed.
INITIATED.

36. ORD-1266-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Cactus Land Development, LLC for a commercial development (Cactus and Jones Shopping Center).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Cactus Land Development, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the west side of Jones Boulevard and the south side of Cactus Avenue within the Northeast quarter (NE1/4) of Section 35, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED - public hearing 10/22/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 9-17-08

6. UC-1045-06 (ET-0218-08) - AMERICAN CHILD CARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
USE PERMIT FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to review a child care facility on 1.2 acres in a C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone and a C-1 (Local Business) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Robindale Road, 265 feet west of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise. BW/gc/nd 
APPROVED
Current Planning
Until September 6, 2010 to review as a public hearing to address concerns about traffic problems that may impact the use;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with previous conditions.
ATTACHMENT: uc104506-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0254858.DOC
TAB approved with conditions
There was a discussion about the traffic flow in and out of the property and the effect it would have on Robindale. The TAB felt that a two year review was required to look at the traffic situation and would provide information about how well the current plans met the needs of the neighborhood.

13. ZC-0769-08 - UNITED STATES OF AMERICA:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify a 10.2 acre portion of a 50.0 acre site from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to P-F (Public Facilities) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for a school. Generally located on the southeast corner of Chartan Avenue and Star Lily Street within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Provide 10 foot wide landscape strip along the entire western property line;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 30 feet for Chartan Avenue, and 60 feet for Starr Hills Avenue along the east boundary with the design of the connector/curve to be approved by Clark County Traffic Engineers and Development Services;
Construct temporary Clark County approved turnaround at the termination of the unnamed road;
Construct full off-sites;
Traffic study and compliance;
Drainage study and compliance;
Detached sidewalks will require right-of-way dedications to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control.
ATTACHMENT: zc076908-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0254956.DOC
TAB approved
There was a discussion about the traffic flow in the area of the school. Currently, Star Lily is a dead end beyond the school property. A representative of Southern Highlands stated they are working on a drainage project that would allow Star Lily to become a though street. The street layout in the school vicinity makes the possibility of gridlock a real possibility.

21. UC-0703-08 - SOUTHERN HIGHLANDS CASINO RESORT:
HOLDOVER USE PERMITS for the following: 1) additions and modifications to a previously approved resort hotel; 2) increase the number of resort condominium units; 3) all associated accessory and incidental uses; and 4) deviations to development standards.
DEVIATIONS for the following: 1) reduce on-site parking; 2) reduce the height/setback ratio adjacent to an arterial street (St. Rose Parkway and Interstate 15); and 3) all other deviations as shown per plans on file.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) redesign of a previously approved resort hotel; 2) 5 resort condominium towers; and 3) all associated accessory and incidental uses and structures on 109.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the west side of Las Vegas Boulevard South and the north side of St. Rose Parkway within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Coordinate with Clark County Fire Department and Las Vegas Metropolitan Police Department for communication equipment and public safety facilities;
Recalculate obligations under the existing standard development agreement (PFNA) for everything approved up to UC-1947-05;
Any additions to the project in excess of what was approved for UC-1947-05 to be calculated under the standard development agreement (PFNA) adjusted to inflation, and shall be considered a development agreement and not a standard PFNA;
Provide a pedestrian realm along existing and future Frank Sinatra Drive right-of-way;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that approval of this application does not constitute or imply approval of a liquor or gaming license or any other County issued permit, license, or approval; approval of this use permit only approves any relaxed standards that depart from the development and improvement standards required by Title 30 provided such relaxed standards completely comply with the approved plans on file; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with the Development Agreement with Clark County;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Traffic study to also address: a) the dedication and construction of bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards, b) any additional right-of-way dedications to Clark County as required by the traffic study to accommodate any physical improvements and pedestrian volumes generated by this project, c) any additional rights-of-way required for storage lanes, d) the required width of all public walkway segments so that a minimum Level of Service &quot;C&quot; or better, is maintained with NDOT acceptance for St. Rose Parkway, e) turnover analysis for the porte-cochere and recommendation of mitigation measures as applicable, f) on-site circulation; participation in the cost of possible future improvements impacted by the projects generated traffic, g) cost participation in a pedestrian grade crossing at the intersection of Las Vegas Boulevard South and St. Rose Parkway, in addition, the developer to maintain a queuing area for the escalator and grant any easements or required right-of way to accommodate the pedestrian grade separation structures;
Traffic impact mitigation plan to be reviewed by the staffs of the Regional Transportation Commission, Freeway and Arterial System of Transportation (FAST), Clark County Traffic Management Division, Clark County Civil Engineering Division, and Nevada Department of Transportation;
Developer to install communications infrastructure of the Freeway and Arterial System of Transportation (FAST) along the entire length of the project&apos;s frontage on Las Vegas Boulevard South and NDOT concurrence along the frontage of the St. Rose Parkway;
Developer to dedicate right-of-way and construct exclusive right turn lanes at all projects driveways;
Signs to remain a minimum of 10 feet from right-of-way and maintain clearance from site visibility zone;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval for any St. Rose Parkway related issues;
Compliance with ZC-0681-01, ZC-1363-05, and ZC-0805-05;
Right-of-way dedication to now include 35 feet back of curb for Bruner Avenue with flaring at the intersection of the driveways and Las Vegas Boulevard South;
Right-of-way dedication to include a total width of 170 feet from the section line west including associated spandrels and grant a minimum of 15 feet for a pedestrian access easement for a total width of 185 feet;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval no longer needed;
Applicant to dedicate and construct a minimum 60 foot wide frontage road with the location to be approved by Clark County Public Works or enter into an agreement with Clark County for the future dedication and construction of the frontage road prior to final map approval or issuance of building permits.
Department of Aviation
Applicant is required to file a valid FAA Form 7460-1, &quot;Notice of Proposed Construction or Alteration&quot; with the FAA, in accordance with 14 CFR Part 77, or submit to the Director of Aviation a Property Owners Shielding Determination Statement and request written concurrence from the Department of Aviation;
If applicant does not obtain written concurrence to a Property Owner&apos;s Shielding Determination Statement, then applicant must also receive either a Permit from the Director of Aviation or a Variance from the Airport Hazard Areas Board of Adjustment (AHABA) prior to construction as required by Section 30.48 PART B of the Clark County Unified Development Code.
Applicant is advised that the FAA&apos;s determination is advisory in nature and does not guarantee that a Director&apos;s Permit or an AHABA Variance will be approved; FAAs airspace determinations (the outcome of filing the FAA Form 7460-1) are dependent on petitions by any interested party and the height that will not present a hazard as determined by the FAA may change based on these comments; and that the FAAs airspace determinations include expiration dates and that the separate airspace determinations will be needed for construction cranes or other temporary equipment.
ATTACHMENT: uc070308-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0255122.DOC

24. WS-0653-08 - BOUQUET, INC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce setback, and 2) allow a drive-thru talk box to face residential development.
DESIGN REVIEW for a commercial building with drive-thru restaurants on 0.8 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the west side of Maryland Parkway, 150 feet south of Pyle Avenue within Enterprise. B
HELD - 10/22/08 - per the applicant.
ATTACHMENT: ws065308-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0253505.DOC

31. WS-0609-08 - CIELOS EDGE, LLC.:
HOLDOVER APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce driveway throat depth for a commercial shopping center.
DESIGN REVIEW for a commercial center which includes 5 commercial buildings and area that will be reserved for future development on 10.4 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located on the northeast corner of Buffalo Drive and Cactus Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
2 years for review on hours of operation;
Hours of operation limited to 7:00 a.m. to 11:00 p.m. on all buildings except Building B;
Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
Design review as a public hearing on lighting and signage;
Design review as a public hearing on all drive-thrus and queing;
Any waivers of development standards to be heard by the Board of County Commissioners;
Building D to be limited to bank use only, or remove drive-thru from east property line for any other use which is proposed;
No drive-thru speaker boxes along east side of Building D;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Major Projects - Engineering
Traffic study to address no left hand turns on Cactus Avenue and Buffalo Drive;
Traffic study to the Board of County Commissioners if left hand turns are required;
Compliance with ZC-1877-04;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Queuing analysis for Building A and Building D pad sites.
ATTACHMENT: ws060908-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0253342.DOC

32. AG-1153-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners receive and file the report on the Major Land Use Plan Update Schedule; and direct staff as needed.
MAJOR LAND USE PLAN UPDATE SCHEDULE
1. 2008-09 Spring Valley current plan adopted 11/17/2004 - (start date summer 2008)
Enterprise current plan adopted 12/08/2004 - (start date summer 2008)
2. 2009-10 Sunrise Manor current plan adopted 09/07/2005 - (start date fall 2009)
Winchester/Paradise current plan adopted 08/03/2005 - (start date summer 2009)
3. 2010-11 Northeast Plan current plan adopted 09/06/2006 - (start date summer 2010)
DIRECTED..
ATTACHMENT: AG-1153-08.pdf

33. HOLDOVER CP-0808-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing and approve, adopt, and authorize the Chairman to sign a resolution amending the Comprehensive Plan by adopting the certified draft of the Lone Mountain Land Use Plan.
ADOPTED - as amended
ATTACHMENT: CP-0808-08.pdf

38. ORD-1156-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to update various regulations in the Clark County Unified Development Code (Title 30); and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.04, 30.08, 30.16, 30.24, 30.32, 30.36, 30.44, 30.48, 30.52, 30.56, 30.60, 30.64, 30.68, 30.80, Appendices E and F, Sections 30.04.040, 30.08.030, 30.16.210, 30.32.030, 30.36.080, 30.48.290, 30.48.830, 30.52.055, 30.52.100, 30.60.020, 30.60.025, 30.60.050, 30.64.030, 30.68.030 Tables 30.16-3, 30.16-6, 30.16-7, 30.16-8, 30.16-9, 30.16-11, 30.16-17, 30.16-18, 30.24-1, 30.44-1, 30.56-2, 30.60-1, and 30.80-4 and establish a new Section 30.56.095 to revise and update various land use requirements and procedures and make corrections and clarifications as appropriate; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED - as amended.
ATTACHMENT: ORD-1156-08.pdf

ZONING COMMISSION 9-3-08

19. ZC-0047-08 - NORCOTT, JAMES T., ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a convenience store with gasoline pumps; 2) on-premise consumption of alcohol (tavern); and 3) office building with a managers unit. Generally located on the west side of Dean Martin Drive and the north side of Gary Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
WITHDRAWN.
TAB Denied at original hearing. The item was held at the BCC so that the applicant could meet with the neighbors. No meeting has been held. This item will be HELD again at the BCC until Commissioner Woodbury can be present on 9/17/2008.
ATTACHMENT: zc004708-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0242275.DOC

21. ZC-0622 -08 - PHD TEN, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 4.6 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone and C-2 (General Commercial) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Design Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEW for a motel with kitchens in rooms. Generally located on the southeast corner of Blue Diamond Road and Quarterhorse Lane within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Any proposed use will be a public hearing design review;
Expunge ZC-0841-03;
Provide an intense landscape buffer along the south property line;
Windows along the south elevation to be opaque;
Building(s) to be oriented to screen the pool from adjacent residential development;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include a 25 foot radius spandrel at the southeast corner of the intersection of Quarterhorse Lane and Blue Diamond Road;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval.
DESIGN REVIEW WAS WITHDRAWN.
ATTACHMENT: zc062208-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0253497.DOC
TAB approved zone change to C-2: the Applicant withdrew the design. Any new design will be subject to a Public Hearing.
The subject parcel was split between H-2 and C-2 zoning. Because it was a single piece, the H-2 could not be down-zoned to C-1, since the other half was already C-2. There was some neighborhood confusion about this, but after considerable discussion most of the residents seemed to understand the distinction.

25. UC-0703-08 - SOUTHERN HIGHLANDS CASINO RESORT:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) additions and modifications to a previously approved resort hotel; 2) increase the number of resort condominium units; 3) all associated accessory and incidental uses; and 4) deviations to development standards.
DEVIATIONS for the following: 1) reduce on-site parking; 2) reduce the height/setback ratio adjacent to an arterial street (St. Rose Parkway and Interstate 15); and 3) all other deviations as shown per plans on file.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) redesign of a previously approved resort hotel; 2) 5 resort condominium towers; and 3) all associated accessory and incidental uses and structures on 109.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the west side of Las Vegas Boulevard South and the north side of St. Rose Parkway within Enterprise.
HELD - 09/17/08 - per the applicant.
TAB Approved.
Due to the slower economy, this project will now be developed in phases. The current Use Permit applies to the first phase.

30. ZC-1282-06 (WC-0203-08) - DURANGO STATION, INC:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring intense landscape buffer along the west and south property line to buffer the adjacent residential development on approximately 71.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone, and an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the MUD-2 and CMA Design Overlay Districts in the Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community. Generally located between the 215 Beltway and Maule Avenue on the west side of Durango Drive within Spring Valley.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
Provide an 8 foot high decorative screen wall from Maule Avenue north, past the retail service yard/ trash dock pending Las Vegas Valley Water District approval;
If wrought iron screening option is implemented, then internal to site screen service areas and central plant from west property line;
Landscaping as shown on plans;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
ATTACHMENT: zc128206-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0254642.DOC
Rhodes Ranch residents might want to check this one (and 31/32 below) out. You can obtain documentation from the county web site as described above.

31. UC-0726-08 - DURANGO STATION, INC:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) modifications to a previously approved resort hotel/casino; 2) addition of an office and retail plaza with incidental commercial uses; and 3) deviations to development standards.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) final plans on a previously approved resort hotel/casino with ancillary uses; and 2) for an office and retail plaza consisting of 8 buildings with associated structures and water features on approximately 71.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone, and an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the MUD-2 and CMA Design Overlay Districts in the Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community. Generally located between the 215 Beltway and Maule Avenue on the west side of Durango Drive within Spring Valley.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
Non-public hearing design review for the pedestrian flow and connectivity between some of the parking areas and the different elements of the project;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Major Projects Engineering
Update drainage study and compliance;
Update traffic study and compliance;
Full off-sites to include paved legal access;
Right-of-way dedications to include dedication and construction of third travel lane along Beltway frontage road;
Sign a License And Maintenance Agreement for any non-standard improvements within right-of-way;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to final map technical review;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards.
ATTACHMENT: uc072608-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0254226.DOC

32. WT-0727-08 - DURANGO STATION, INC:
WAIVER to reduce throat depths for driveways in conjunction with a proposed resort hotel/casino with ancillary uses on approximately 71.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone and an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the MUD-2 and CMA Design Overlay Districts in the Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community. Generally located between the 215 Beltway and Maule Avenue on the west side of Durango Drive within Spring Valley.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Engineering
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 1 year of approval date or it will expire.
ATTACHMENT: wt072708-a-bw.pdf
ATTACHMENT: P0254083.DOC

37. CP-0808-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing and approve, adopt, and authorize the Chairman to sign a resolution amending the Comprehensive Plan by adopting the certified draft of the Lone Mountain Land Use Plan.
HELD - 09/17/08 - per Commissioner Maxfield.
. The proposed changes to the Lone Mountain Land Use Plan were apparently changed at the PC in opposition to resident recommendations, and the current map is not acceptable to the residents. This is important to all of us, because the process was altered to remove the citizens voices. SWAN will follow-up and keep everyone informed.

ZONING COMMISSION 8-20-08

12. UC-0577-06 (ET-0170-08) - WALTERS, LARRY R.&amp;MARIETTA;:
USE PERMIT FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to review a horse riding/rental stable.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase the number of horses; and 2) reduce the lot area.
DESIGN REVIEW for a horse riding/rental stable on 2.1 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone. Generally located on the northwest corner of Cameron Street and Eldorado Lane within Enterprise. BW/gc/dc
HELD - 01/07/09 - for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting. Applicant is advised that renotification fees will be required prior to being placed on the agenda.

14. ZC-0561-02 (ET-0148-08) - WARM SPRINGS JONES 25 INVESTMENTS, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE SECOND EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify an approximate 15.0 acre portion of a previously approved 20.0 acre site from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for a retail center in the Pinnacle Peaks Concept Plan Area. Generally located on the southeast corner of Jones Boulevard and Warm Springs Road within Enterprise. BW/lgp
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
Until August 4, 2014 to complete to coincide with the Pinnacle Peaks Concept Plan;
TAB had changed the complete date to August 4, 2011

19. WS-0699-08 - ARBY JONES 4 02, LLC&amp;RAINS;1992 TRUST:
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to allow a loading area adjacent to a right-of-way (Arby Avenue) without a minimum 6 foot high decorative masonry wall.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail center and convenience store on 2.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the southeast corner of Jones Boulevard and Arby Avenue within Enterprise. RR/jt/nd
WITHDRAWN - without prejudice

22.ZC-0683-08 - KENNEDY FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 5.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for a future commercial development. Generally located on the west side of Bermuda Road and the south side of Neal Avenue (alignment) within Enterprise (description on file). BW/kk/mh
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area;
Enter into a cross access, ingress/egress agreement with the parcel to the south if uses are of a similar use and intensity;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 100 feet to 50 feet transition for Bermuda Road, 30 feet for Fairfield Street, 30 feet for Neal Avenue, and associated spandrels;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
Drainage study and compliance;
Construct full off-sites;
Coordinate off-sites with City of Henderson;
Detached sidewalks will require right-of-way dedications to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.
TAB had Approved as C-1

23. ZC-0689-08 - PJ D&amp;D;HOLDINGS, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (AE-60) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) (AE-60) Zone for a future commercial development. Generally located on the east side of Gilespie Street, 350 feet south of George Crockett Road within Enterprise (description on file). BW/dg/dr
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that the existing septic system is in violation of Southern Nevada Health District (SNHD) regulations as a building was constructed without SNHD approval and appears to be over the septic system; and that the property owner must abandon the existing septic system per SNHD regulations and the site must be connected to municipal sewer.
Civil Engineering
Traffic and drainage studies will be addressed with development of this site;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Vacation to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal.

28. ZC-0616-08 - ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 8.4 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a shopping center; and 2) a Project of Regional Significance.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a hotel including accessory and incidental uses; and 2) a shopping center. Generally located on the northeast corner of Dean Martin Drive and Agate Avenue within Enterprise (description on file). BW/gc/dr
WITHDRAWN. Although the BCC approved this request at the meeting, subject to a reduction to C-P and C-1 zoning, the Board&apos;s action was not final since the applicant subsequently submitted a withdrawl letter prior to the end of the reconsideration period.

29. VS-0617-08 - ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL:
HOLDOVER VACATE AND ABANDON a portion of right-of-way being Agate Avenue located between Dean Martin Drive and Interstate 15 in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file). BW/gc/dr
APPROVED
Current Planning
Satisfying utility companies&apos; requirements;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that the recording of the order of vacation in the Office of the County Recorder must be completed within 2 years of the approval date or the application will expire.
Civil Engineering
Drainage study and compliance;
Drainage study and plans to also address potential vacation of Agate Avenue;
Applicant to acquire concurrence from the owner of APN 177-20-204-003;
Revise legal description, if necessary, prior to recording.

32. NZC-0415-08 -KOROGHLI FAMILY TRUST:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 4.3 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for increased building height.
DESIGN REVIEW for a hotel. Generally located 265 feet north of Serene Avenue and 600 feet east of Eastern Avenue within Paradise (description on file). BW/rs/dc
DENIED.

33. NZC-0505-08 - CORONADO LAND, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 3.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to M-D (Designed Manufacturing) Zone.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) offices as a principal use; 2) experimental laboratory; 3) increased building height; and 4) a day care facility.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) alternative landscaping; 2) reduce setbacks; 3) day care facility not on a collector or arterial street; and 4) off-site improvements (streetlights).
DESIGN REVIEW for an office and warehouse with laboratory and day care facility development. Generally located on the west side of Placid Street and the north and south sides of Arby Avenue (alignment) within Enterprise (description on file). BW/dg/dr 
APPROVED
Current Planning
Property owner must abandon the existing septic system on both parcels according to Southern Nevada Health District (SNHD) regulation and connect to municipal sewer available with 400 feet of both parcels;
Floor plan, plumbing fixtures and plan of operation for the day care facility must be approved by SNHD Childcare Plan Review (759-1258);
Design review as a public hearing on substantial changes;
Design review as a public hearing on final plans for the daycare facility with special emphasis on the location of the outdoor play area and any associated impacts to the existing residential to the south;
All lighting to be low level with any light source to be shielded with full cut-off fixtures (light lens not visible) along the west and south, as long as the single family residences are functioning as residential;
Floodlights, spotlights, or any other similar lighting shall not be permitted to illuminate buildings along the west and south, as long as the single family residences are functioning as residential;
No wall signage on any building elevation facing west or south, as long as the single family residences are functioning as residential;
Specific landscaping and setbacks along west and south per plans on file with every effort to be made to retain the existing, mature trees that are currently along the south property line;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must be completed within 3 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Construct full off-sites, excluding streetlights;
Traffic study and compliance;
Drainage study and compliance;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Reconstruct any unused driveways with off-sites.
Fire Department
Provide a fire/emergency access plan with minimum turn radius of 28 foot interior and 52 foot exterior.
Department of Aviation
No building permits shall be released for the project prior to the Department of Aviation notifying Zoning Plan Check that the applicant has received all necessary airspace approvals;
Applicant is required to file a valid FAA Form 7460-1, &quot;Notice of Proposed Construction or Alteration&quot; with the FAA, in accordance with 14 CFR Part 77, or submit to the Director of Aviation a Property Owners Shielding Determination Statement and request written concurrence from the Department of Aviation;
If applicant does not obtain written concurrence to a Property Owners Shielding Determination Statement, then applicant must also receive either a Permit from the Director of Aviation or a Variance from the Airport Hazard Areas Board of Adjustment (AHABA) prior to construction, as required by Section 30.48 PART B of the Clark County Unified Development Code.
Applicant is advised that the FAAs determination is advisory in nature and does not guarantee that a Directors Permit or an AHABA Variance will be approved; FAAs airspace determinations (the outcome of filing the FAA Form 7460-1) are dependent on petitions by any interested party and the height that will not present a hazard as determined by the FAA may change based on these comments; and that the FAAs airspace determinations include expiration dates and that the separate airspace determinations will be needed for construction cranes or other temporary equipment.

45. UC-1447-07 (WC-0183-08) - RED HOT CORNER LLC, ET AL:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a use permit requiring the applicant to complete activities and remove equipment and materials within 120 days (90 days to crush materials and 30 days to remove materials) in conjunction with a temporary batch plant and temporary construction storage on 3.9 acres in an R-T (Manufactured Home Residential) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Dale Avenue, 1,100 feet west of Las Vegas Boulevard South within Enterprise. BW/dg/mh
WITHDRAWN - without prejudice.

53. WS-0609-08 - CIELOS EDGE, LLC.:
APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce driveway throat depth for a commercial shopping center.
DESIGN REVIEW for a commercial center which includes 5 commercial buildings and area that will be reserved for future development on 10.4 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located on the northeast corner of Buffalo Drive and Cactus Avenue within Enterprise. BW/rk/lgp/co
HELD - 09/17/08 - per Commissioner Brager

57. CP-1554-07:
That the Board of County Commissioners hold a public hearing on Item #1 of the 2007 Annual Amendment of the Enterprise Land Use Plan, then direct staff accordingly.
APPROVED.

60. CP-1024-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners initiate the amendment process for an amendment to the Transportation Element Map 1.3 to remove Pebble Road from Fort Apache Road to Hualapai Way as a 100 foot arterial and add the first 660 feet of Pebble Road west of Fort Apache Road as an 80 foot collector.
INITIATED.

61. ORD-1022-08:
That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to allow gravel pits within the M-2 zoning district subject to a special use permit; and direct staff accordingly.An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44, Table 30.44-1 and Appendix G Map 11; to allow gravel pits and related uses within the M-2 zoning district subject to special use permit processing and to establish regulations for rock crushing facilities and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 8-6-08

4 UC-0726-06 (ET-0178-08) STAR TOWERS, LLC:
USE PERMITS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to commence the following: 1) resort condominiums; and 2) increase building height.
DESIGN REVIEW for a resort condominium complex with associated accessory uses on 4.8 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the east side of Las Vegas Boulevard South, 300 feet north of Pebble Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning: Until July 5, 2010 to commence;

10. VS-0617-08 ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL
HELD 08/20/08 per the applicant.

11. ZC-0616-08 ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL:
HELD 08/20/08 per the applicant.

18. ZC-0622 -08 PHD TEN, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 4.6 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone and C-2 (General Commercial) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Design Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEW for a motel with kitchens in rooms. Generally located on the southeast corner of Blue Diamond Road and Quarterhorse Lane within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 09/03/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting 27 Aug 2008

20. NZC-0527-08 - WINDMILL DURANGO, LP:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 14.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone to
CRT (Commercial Residential Transition) Zone.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for alternative landscaping and screening.
DESIGN REVIEW for an office center. Generally located on the south side of Windmill Lane,
660 feet east of Durango Drive within Enterprise (description of file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
The maxim parking lot pole height will not exceed 20 feet from the ground to the top
of the light;
The buildings will be designed to blend with the residential neighborhood, all
buildings to be single story, stucco, with pitched tile roofs;
Developer agrees to make every reasonable effort to adhere to the grading/drainage
plans originally presented to immediate neighbors and SWAN, subject to Civil
Engineering requirements, the preliminary grading plans show a maximum floor
elevation of 2721.5 feet MSL;
Design review as a public hearing will be required for significant changes to the
preliminary grading/drainage plans;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision
mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure
necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the
area;
Design review as a public hearing on any significant changes;
Design review as a public hearing on signage;
Maximum lot coverage of 25%, as proposed on plans;
No vehicular access to Gagnier Boulevard or Camero Avenue;
All lighting to be low level with any light source to be shielded with full cut-off
fixtures (light lens not visible);
Floodlights, spotlights, or any other similar lighting shall not be permitted to
illuminate buildings;
Monument signage only, regardless of any other uses which may be permitted in the
CRT zoning district;
No wall signage on any building elevation facing east or any elevation facing south
for the five buildings located on the south portion of the property;
Maximum building height of 28 feet;
Specific landscaping and setbacks along east and south per plans on file;
Enhanced paving as presented on plans;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be
justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must be
completed within 3 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic
analysis with Civil Engineering approval;
Construct full off-site improvements on Windmill Lane and sign restrictive
covenants for non-urban rural street standards on Camero Avenue;
Detached sidewalk will require the vacation of excess right-of-way and grant
necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control,
or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements
in the right-of-way;
Design and location of gates to be approved by Development Services Civil
Engineering.
Fire Department
Provide a fire/emergency access plan with minimum turn radius of 28 foot interior
and 52 foot exterior.

29. WS-0653-08 BOUQUET, INC:
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following:
1) reduce setback, and
2) allow a drive-thru talk box to face residential development.
DESIGN REVIEW for a commercial building with drive-thru restaurants on 0.8 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the west side of Maryland Parkway, 150 feet south of Pyle Avenue within Enterprise.
HELD 09/17/08 per the applicant
TAB Denied
The plans show a one story, 19 foot 4 inch high, 4,500 square foot commercial building separated into two, 2,250 square foot restaurants with drive-thru. Each restaurants drive-thru window and squawk box is located opposite of each other with the 9 foot wide drive-thru lanes forming a circle around the building. One squawk box is located less than 40 ft from the nearest residence. The delivery area meets county code; however, it cannot handle a tractor trailer without blocking the drive through lanes.

34.UC-0477-08 LAND HARBOR, LLC:
HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMIT for a communications tower.
DESIGN REVIEW for a communications tower on 1.3 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates
Residential) Zone. Generally located on the west side of Valley View Boulevard, 330 feet south of Silverado Ranch Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED

36. TA-0538-08 G.C. GARCIA:
HOLDOVER TEXT AMENDMENT to amend Table 30.44-1, Chapter 30.44 of the Unified
Development Code to allow senior hostel as a use within the County.
STAFF DIRECTED TO PROCEED AND REWRITE

40. ORD-1022-08: That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to allow gravel pits within the M-2 zoning district subject to a special use permit; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44, Table 30.44-1 to allow gravel pits and related
uses within the M-2 zoning district subject to special use permit processing and to establish
regulations for rock crushing facilities and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED public hearing 08/20/08.

41. ORD-0982-08: That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to consider
adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with CFT Lands, LLC for a future residential
development (Highlands Ranch Unit 8).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with CFT Lands, LLC for a proposed
residential development generally located on the northeast corner of Jones Boulevard and Serene Avenue within the northwest quarter (NW1/4) of Section 24, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED public hearing 08/20/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 7-16-08

10. UC-0262-06 (ET-0157-08) HIGHLANDS RESORT, LLC:
USE PERMITS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME
APPROVED

15. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
HOLDOVER MAJOR PROJECT PUBLIC FACILITIES NEEDS ASSESSMENT to address issues of concern to Clark County for a master planned community (Rhodes Ranch) on approximately 1,548.0 acres in various zoning districts. Generally located on the west side of Durango Drive between the 215 Beltway and Pebble Road within Spring Valley and Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
The master developer entering into a development agreement to address issues identified in the public facilities needs assessment (PFNA);
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.

16. UC-0575-08 - SOLEIL LV, LLC:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) kitchens within guest rooms; 2) increase building height; and 3) a Project of Regional Significance.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; and 2) allow non-standard driveway access (including reduced throat depth).
DESIGN REVIEW for an expansion to a hotel condominium/timeshare development on a portion of 24.2 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-60&amp;AE-65) Zone. Generally located on the east side of Las Vegas Boulevard South and the south side of Arby Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED

17. TM-0110-08 - TAHITI VILLAGE PHASE III:
TENTATIVE MAP for a commercial subdivision consisting of 571 hotel condominium units on 5.3 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-60&amp;AE-65) Zone. Generally located on the east side of Las Vegas Boulevard South and the south side of Arby Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED

22. ZC-0564-08 CLARK COUNTY DEPARTMENT OF AVIATION:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 15.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (AE-65) Zone to P-F (Public Facility) (AE-65) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for a federal national weather station, monitoring devices, communication equipment with antennas and associated components, security fencing, paving, equipment and fuel for launching operating air balloons with electronic radiosonde instruments. Generally located east of Polaris Avenue (alignment) between Robindale Road and Mesa Verde Lane (alignment) within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED

28. ZC-0616-08 ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 8.4 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a shopping center; and 2) a Project of Regional Significance.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a hotel including accessory and incidental uses; and 2) a shopping center. Generally located on the northeast corner of Dean Martin Drive and Agate Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 08/06/08 to renotify.

29. VS-0617-08 ROCKY-G LIVING TRUST, ET AL:
VACATE AND ABANDON a portion of right-of-way being Agate Avenue located between Dean Martin Drive and Interstate 15 in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 08/06/08 per the applicant.

42. WS-0602-08 MGROUP VEGAS II, LLC:
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for street landscaping.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS of a zone change (ZC-1393-02) requiring the following: 1) storefronts to face streets; 2) undulating berms a minimum of 3 feet in height shall be placed in the landscape buffer; and 3) buildings shall be arranged to screen parking adjacent to the public right-of-way.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 2.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone.
Generally located on the southwest corner of Warm Springs Road and Lindell Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Landscaping to be provided in the easement if the Southern Nevada Water Authority allows it;
All lighting to be low level with any light source to be shielded with full cut-off fixtures facing existing or planned residences;
Flood lights, spot lights, or any other similar lighting shall not be permitted to illuminate buildings facing existing or planned residences;
No wall signage on any building elevation facing existing or planned residences;
Light poles not to exceed 14 feet in height;
Drive-thru facilities and stacking lanes should be screened by a combination of landscaping, architecturally treated meandering low walls, expanded canopy areas from the main building, and/or architectural elements protruding outward from the building over the drive aisle at varying heights to create the effect that the drive-thru is part of the building by extension or design features;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that block wall along west property line must be decorative; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-1393-02.

54. UC-0477-08 LAND HARBOR, LLC:
APPEAL USE PERMIT for a communications tower.
DESIGN REVIEW for a communications tower on 1.3 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone. Generally located on the west side of Valley View Boulevard, 330 feet south of Silverado Ranch Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD 08/06/08 per the applicant.

55. TA-0567-08 PETERSON MANAGEMENT, LLC:
TEXT AMENDMENT to amend Table 30.44-1, Chapter 30.44 of the Unified Development Code to allow gravel pits in an M-2 (Industrial) Zone.
DIRECTED with Laughlin and Sunrise Manor being exempt.
Enterprise TAB Denied

61. ORD-0888-08: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to consider adoption of a Development Agreement with Rhodes Ranch General Partnership, A Nevada General Partnership for a 1,548.0 acre development (Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community).
An ordinance to adopt the Second Amendment to the Development Agreement with Rhodes Ranch General Partnership, A Nevada General Partnership for an approximate 1,548.0 acre development generally located on the west side of Durango Drive between the 215 Beltway and Pebble Road within the boundaries of the Towns of Spring Valley and Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

62. DA-0521-08 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
HOLDOVER DEVELOPMENT AGREEMENT containing outlines, rules, and guidelines for the orderly development for a master planned community (Rhodes Ranch) on approximately 1,548.0 acres in various zoning districts. Generally located on the west side of Durango Drive between the 215 Beltway and Pebble Road within Spring Valley and Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
Until July 2, 2028;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.

ZONING COMMISSION 7-2-08

5. DA-0521-08 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
HELD 07/16/08 per the District Attorney
10. DR-0553-08 SAHARA-LINDELL LLC:
DESIGN REVIEW for an office/retail complex on 0.7 acres in a C-1 (Local Business) Zone. Generally located on the west side of Bermuda Road, 200 feet south of Silverado Ranch Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
The south and west property lines one row of trees planted 20 feet on center with a 10 foot wide landscape area;
Design review for any significant changes to plans;
Any illuminated signs to be oriented away from adjacent residential development;
Except for solar power generating equipment, all rooftop mounted mechanical equipment to be screened from the adjacent residential development;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that all light sources shall be shielded and directed downward at all times to prevent adverse impacts to adjacent residential uses; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.

14. UC-0544-08 AMERICAN CHILDCARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
USE PERMIT for accessory structures (shade structures) not compatible with the principal structure.
DESIGN REVIEW for shade structures on 1.1 acres in a C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone and a C-1 (Local Business) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Robindale Road, 250 feet west of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.

15. UC-0545-08 AMERICAN CHILDCARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
USE PERMIT for accessory structures (shade structures) not compatible with the principal structure.
DESIGN REVIEW for shade structures on 0.9 acres in a C-P (Office&amp;Professional) (AE-60) Zone in the Russell Road Transition Corridor. Generally located on the north side of Russell Road, 415 feet east of Eastern Avenue within Paradise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.

41. UC-0384-08 BLUE DIAMOND SOUTHEAST CORNER&amp;DURANGO ROCK, LLC:
HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) reduce the separation from a convenience store to a residential use; and 2) reduce the separation from an automobile maintenance facility to a residential use.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center including a convenience store with gasoline sales and an automobile maintenance facility on 4.3 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the southeast corner of Durango Drive and Blue Diamond Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Gas canopy design and materials per plans on file;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that a separate land use application will be required for the fast food restaurant; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-1364-06.

43. VS-0424-08 CJH DEVELOPMENT, LLC:
APPEAL VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County located between Giles Street and Haven Street and between Windmill Lane and Shelbourne Avenue in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in a MUD-4 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
Satisfying utility companies&apos; requirements;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that the recording of the order of vacation in the Office of the County Recorder must be completed within 2 years of the approval date or the application will expire.
Civil Engineering
Drainage study and compliance;
Revise legal description, if necessary, prior to recording.

45. TA-0538-08 G.C. GARCIA:
TEXT AMENDMENT to amend Table 30.44-1, Chapter 30.44 of the Unified Development Code to allow senior hostel as a use within the County.
HELD 08/06/08 per the applicant.

49. CP-0741-08: That the Board of County Commissioners initiate the adoption process for an amendment to the Transportation Element Map to remove Wigwam Avenue as a Collector with an 80 foot right-of-way from Hualapai Way to Durango Drive.
INITIATED.

50. ORD-0888-08: That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to consider adoption of a Development Agreement with Rhodes Ranch General Partnership, A Nevada General Partnership for a 1,548.0 acre development (Rhodes Ranch Master Planned Community). 
An ordinance to adopt the Second Amendment to the Development Agreement with Rhodes Ranch General Partnership, A Nevada General Partnership for an approximate 1,548.0 acre development generally located on the west side of Durango Drive between the 215 Beltway and Pebble Road within the boundaries of the Towns of Spring Valley and Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED public hearing 07/16/08.

53. ORD-0870-08: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Warm Springs and Durango Partners, LLC for a commercial development (Warm Springs and Durango Commercial Project).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Warm Springs and Durango Partners, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the north side of Warm Springs Road, 300 feet west of Durango Drive within the southeast quarter (SE1/4) of Section 5, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Spring Valley and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 6-18-08

18. ZC-0474-08 EDMOND WINDMILL HOLDING CO., LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 5.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to R-3 (Multiple Family Residential) Zone for a future residential development. Generally located on the southeast corner of Levi Avenue and El Camino Road (alignment) within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area; 
 Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 30 feet for Levi Avenue, 30 feet for El Camino Road, and associated spandrel;
Irvin Avenue dedication/vacation to be addressed with future plans;
Drainage study and compliance;
Construct full off-site improvements.

44. UC-0384-08 BLUE DIAMOND SOUTHEAST CORNER&amp;DURANGO ROCK, LLC:
APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) reduce the separation from a convenience store to a residential use; and 2) reduce the separation from an automobile maintenance facility to a residential use.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center including a convenience store with gasoline sales and an automobile maintenance facility on 4.3 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the southeast corner of Durango Drive and Blue Diamond Road within Enterprise.
HELD 07/02/08 per the appellant.

46. AG-0867-08: That the Board of County Commissioners directs staff to begin the process of updating the Enterprise Land Use and Development Guide.
STAFF DIRECTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 6-4-08

3. DR-0290-08 RAINBOW MAULE, LLC:
AMENDED HOLDVOER DESIGN REVIEW for a comprehensive sign program (previously notified as a freestanding sign) in conjunction with a shopping center on 1.4 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts. Generally located on the southeast corner of Maule Avenue and Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that the final design of the wall signs may require a further design review if the plans submitted do not meet the criteria of the CMA Overlay District; and applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Forward edge of sign to be set back from the right-of-way and remain clear of site visibility zone.

4. DR-0291-08 RAINBOW 215, LLC:
AMENDED HOLDVER DESIGN REVIEW for a comprehensive sign program (previously notified as a freestanding sign) in conjunction with a shopping center on 3.2 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts. Generally located on the northeast corner of Rainbow Boulevard and Maule Avenue within Enterprise.
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that the final design of the wall signs may require a further design review if the plans submitted do not meet the criteria of the CMA Overlay District; applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Forward edge of sign to be set back from the right-of-way and remain clear of site visibility zones.
Fire Department
Provide a fire access plan in accordance with 2005 Clark County Fire Code, with minimum turn radius of 28 foot interior and 52 foot exterior.

29. NZC-0227-08 ROBINDALE ACRES, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 3.1 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to M-D (Designed Manufacturing) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a mini-warehouse facility; and 2) recreational vehicle and boat storage. Generally located on the north side of Robindale Road, 1,260 west of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED

30. DR-0429-08 COUNTY OF CLARK (AVIATION):
DESIGN REVIEW for landscaping and screening revisions to an approved parking lot on 20.5 acres in a P-F (Public Facility) (AE-65) Zone. Generally located on the east side of Gilespie Street, 300 feet north of Warm Springs Road within Enterprise.
WITHDRAWN without prejudice.

32. UC-0294-08 SHAMROCK/SUNSET, LLC:
HOLDOVER USE PERMIT for a Project of Regional Significance.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) roll-up doors on a kiosk; 2) alternative parking lot design; 3) alternative building design; and 4) alternative screening.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 19.3 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-70) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road and the east side of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that 15 feet of landscaping is required along the 215 Beltway; certain uses are not permitted in the airport environs and certain other uses will require a special use permit; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-1476-02;
The driveway on Jones Boulevard is to be right-in/right-out only;
Relocate bus turnout farther to the west as approved by the Regional Transportation Commission.
Fire Department
Provide a fire access plan in accordance with 2005 Clark County Fire Code, with minimum turn radius of 28 foot interior and 52 foot exterior.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #1 AND #3 WERE WITHDRAWN WITHOUT PREJUDICE.

33. UC-0399-08 LOS REYES CORPORATION:
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) reduced separation from residential use for outdoor dining; and 2) not maintain a 48 inch wide pedestrian access way around the perimeter of the outdoor dining area.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) alternative landscaping; and 2) reduced parking.
DESIGN REVIEW for outdoor dining in conjunction with a previously approved restaurant within a retail building on 1.2 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone. Generally located on the south side of Silverado Ranch Boulevard and the east side of Fairfield Avenue within Enterprise.
WITHDRAWN without prejudice.

38. WS-0417-08 AMERICAN CHILD CARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) allow an increase for combined wall/retaining wall height; and 2) reduced throat depth in conjunction with an approved day care facility on 1.2 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone.
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a use permit (UC-1325-06) requiring an 8 foot high block wall to be constructed as a buffer along the east side of the property to comply with Title 30 buffer wall standards, existing block wall on the adjacent property to the east to remain as is. Generally located on the northeast corner of Valley View Boulevard and Conn Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Per plans on file;
Existing block wall on the adjacent property to the east to remain as is;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that an intense landscape buffer is required along the east property line per conditions of UC-1325-06; any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Revise plans to reflect the standard 25 foot minimum throat depth.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #2 WAS WITHDRAWN.

58. HOLDOVER CP-1554-07: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing and approve, adopt, and authorize the Chairman to sign a resolution amending the Comprehensive Plan by adopting an annual amendment to the Enterprise Land Use Plan. 
APPROVED as amended.

Enterprise Land Use Amendment Results
CP-1554-07: This item was heard by the BCC on Jun 4, 2008 with the following results:
1. APN 176-13-501-004 and 010 (BW) TAB Approved as Residential Low (R-L) at 3.5 units/acre. BCC Approved as R-L.
From P-F (Public Facility) to R-S (Residential Suburban at 8 units/acre).
Located on Southwest corner of Windmill Lane and Edmond Street.
The staff proposal for R-S (8 units/acre) was opposed by ten residents who had a petition with 39 signatures. The residents&apos; position was that the property borders the RNP-1 and should be more of a buffer than the proposed R-S land use. The adjacent property to the west is R-L, to the south is RNP-1 (at 2 units/acre) and to the east is R-2. The TAB agreed with the residents that R-L was an appropriate buffer for the RNP-1. The BCC concurred with the TAB.
The BCC felt the RNP-1 needed additional protection afforded by this property. The other factor considered was the lack of infrastructure in Enterprise and the need to keep residential density down.
2. APN 177-19-407-003 (BW) TAB Approved as Commercial Neighborhood (C-N). BCC Approved as C-N.
From P-F (Public Facility) to C-N (Commercial Neighborhood)
Located on the Northwest corner of Arville Street and Silverado Ranch Boulevard
This property was originally slated to be part of the Nevada National Guard Armory. However, the property was not incorporated by the armory, and the owner would like the opportunity to develop the land. The TAB and BCC agreed that Commercial Neighborhood is an appropriate land use for this location.
3. APN 176-24-501-001(BW) TAB no action: one abstention for conflict of interest left the TAB short of a quorum. TAB comments were favorable to the change BCC Approved as RNP-1 with direction to remove MUD overlay
From CN (Commercial Neighborhood) to RNP-1 (Rural Neighborhood Preservation)
Located on Southeast corner of Pebble Road and Lindell Road.
This piece is bordered on the east and south by RNP-1. North across Pebble is R-2 housing. The RNP-1 status and the R-2 housing were actions taken by the BCC after the previous Enterprise Land Use Amendment was adopted. This amendment squares off the corner of the RNP on a lot that would pose difficulties for any commercial development due to lack of access. While the TAB could not vote on this item the board members did express their agreement with this proposed use. The BCC concurred with the TAB opinions. 
It is necessary to remove the MUD overlay from this property. The MUD overlay permits high density housing to be built on the property even though the land use plan now shows RNP-1. A developer could apply for a MUD project and the project could not be blocked by the BCC. The MUD overlay is equal to a zone district and is considered a conforming zone change which must be granted to the applicant. The BCC decisions would be limited to design review and density of the project if the MUD is not removed.
4. APN 176-21-601-020 and 023 (BW) TAB Approved as C-N. BCC Approved as C-N
From RNP-1 (Rural Neighborhood Preservation) to C-G (Commercial General)
Located on Southwest corner of Agate Avenue and Buffalo Drive
The property owners requested this change. The two properties are next to C-G and are no longer viable for residential use. In addition, the property fronting Buffalo has a driveway which exits directly onto Buffalo. There is no other exit option from the property due to the house size. The TAB agreed with the property owner&apos;s assessment. The BCC concurred.
5. APN 176-35-501-003 and 004 (SB) TAB Denied. BCC Approved as C-N
From R-H (Residential High) to C-N (Commercial Neighborhood)
Located on Southwest corner of Mann Street and Cactus Avenue
The property owner has requested a five acre lot be changed R-H to C-N. There were several adjacent residential property owners opposed to this land use change. The property is orientated north/south with the longest frontage along Mann Street. Directly to the east is a single family home development which would be sandwiched between two commercial developments if item # 6 (APN 176-35-501-032) is approved. The TAB felt this commercial development would be detrimental to the established residential neighborhood to the east. Also, the orientation of the property would likely increase commercial traffic on Mann Street, a local access road.
The BCC felt this property would have less impact on the resident to the east as a commercial project. R-H is a very intense use with a considerable impact on the neighborhood.
6. APN 176-35-501-032 (SB) TAB Approved as C-N. BCC Approved as C-N.
From R-S (Residential Suburban) to C-N (Commercial Neighborhood)
Located near Southwest corner of Cactus Avenue and Jones Boulevard
This fifteen acre property is bordered by a five acre commercial property to the east. There were several adjacent residential property owners opposed to this project. However, the TAB felt this corner is an excellent place for a 20 acre commercial center, particularly since there is little commercial in the area. It would require the cooperation of two property owners to develop all 20 acres as a single unit. The corner of two major roads would be a preferred location for additional commercial, helping reduce traffic along Cactus and Jones.
This project was opposed by a large number of residents from Southern Highlands and surrounding neighborhoods. Commissioner Brager commented on the number of protest cards sent in and the lack of area residents present at the BCC hearing. This is a case where the BCC was looking for direct resident input to their decision, but unable to obtain any.
7. APN 176-25-601-017 (SB) TAB Approved as O-P. BCC Approved as O-P.
From R-M (Residential Medium) to O-P (Office Professional)
Located on Northwest corner of Pyle Avenue and Decatur Boulevard
This property is bounded on the north and west by an American West development. As a single 2.5 acre piece, it is unlikely to be developed as residential. The O-P is an appropriate use next to residential.
8. APN 176-35-501-020, 033, 034 and 035 (SB) TAB Approved as Residential Medium (R-M). BCC Approved as R-M
o From R-S (Residential Suburban to R-H (Residential High)
o Located West of Jones Boulevard and South of Cactus Avenue
This item generated a lot of discussion and opposition from several adjacent residents. The TAB felt R-H would not fit the pattern of development in the area and could cause additional traffic problems. The R-M with a PUD development would allow the owner a number of development options. For example, the NV Power right-of-way through part of the property could be used for open space as part of a PUD.
There were three different opinions on how to designate the land use on this property. Option one was all Residential High, the second option was all Residential Medium and the third option was Residential High along Jones and the rest Residential Suburban. The BCC agreed with the TAB assessment. The R-M provides a transition to the commercial to the north. It also allows the land owner to work around the NV Power Company right-of-way with sufficient density to make the project viable.
9. Text change TAB Approved BBC Approved
Adds additional detail to the definition of Gateway in the Enterprise Land Use Plan.

59. CP-0741-08: That the Board of County Commissioners initiate the amendment process for an amendment to the Transportation Element Map to remove Wigwam Avenue as a Collector with an 80 foot right-of-way from Hualapai Way to Durango Drive.
INITIATED.

63. ORD-0711-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance revising the separation requirements for check cashing facilities; and direct staff accordingly. 
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.16, and 30.44, Tables 30.16-4, 30.16-7 and 30.44-1 to revise and update check cashing separation requirements and procedures; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

64. ORD-0681-08: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Somphone&amp;Khoury, LLC for a commercial development (Wigwam Center). 
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Somphone&amp;Khoury, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the northeast corner of Rainbow Boulevard and Wigwam Avenue within the northwest quarter (NW1/4)) of Section 14, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 5-21-08

25. ZC-0339-08 CASTRO, JUVENCIO B.&amp;SOCORRO S.:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.9 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for a future commercial development. Generally located on the north side of Silverado Ranch Boulevard and the east side of Arville Street within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Design review as a public hearing on all final design plans;
Cross access and parking easement to the north and east;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include flaring transitions on Silverado Ranch Boulevard and Arville Street in accordance with Standard Drawing 201.1;
Drainage study and compliance;
Construct full off-site improvements;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus-turnout and/or passenger loading/shelter area in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.

33. ZC-0236-08 STATE OF NEVADA:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.7 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to P-F (Public Facility) Zone.
USE PERMITS for a public facility including the following 1) major training facility; 2) automobile and truck maintenance, paint and body, and repair facilities; 3) warehouse; 4) fuel storage yard; 5) outside storage; 6) truck stop; 7) truck and automobile car wash; 8) offices; and 9) related commercial and industrial accessory uses.
DESIGN REVIEW for public facility (readiness center) buildings, offices, truck and vehicle repair facilities, fuel storage, warehouse, outside storage, and accessory uses on 50.0 acres. Generally located on the west side of Arville Street between Silverado Ranch Boulevard and Serene Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Design review as a public hearing for any significant changes to the plans;
A master plan for the ultimate development of the entire readiness center armory shall be prepared by the applicant and reviewed and approved by staff within 2 years and is to include future anticipated land uses, site visual screening, perimeter wall installation, landscaping, storage areas, public street and infrastructure improvement time table estimates, potential future buildings for all associated parcels that may become part of this complex;
Building colors to match or be complimentary to existing structures on site;
Construct a solid decorative split face wall on top of an earth berm with the overall height of the berm and wall not to exceed 12 feet in height, adjacent to the south side of Serene Avenue that matches the existing wall on site with tree and shrub pockets approximately every 30 feet;
Landscaping and automatic irrigation system to be installed along Serene Avenue frontage between the right-of-way and wall;
Civil improvement plans for this phase of construction to reflect a fire hydrant along Serene Avenue, as needed, pursuant to utilities plans with an emphasis on fire suppression near the exterior boundaries of the refueling area;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Design review for the entire property is to be in compliance with ZC-0887-05;
The re-zoning of these two par

41. NZC-0248-08 WARM SPRINGS JONES 25 INVESTMENTS, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 8.4 acres from C-2 (General Commercial) Zone to M-D (Designed Manufacturing) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for an office/warehouse and retail center in the Pinnacle Peaks Concept Plan area. Generally located on the south side of Warm Springs Road and the west side of Westwind Road within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Major Projects Planning
A resolution of intent to expire on November 6, 2010;
Move all trash enclosures to north end of the buildings;
Southerly most rollup doors for Buildings 2 through 5 to be designed no larger than 12 feet by 12 feet to limit the potential impacts on future tenant uses and remain closed during business hours of operation;
All exterior light sources on south side of project to have shielded, downcast lighting; 
 No wall or pole lighting above 12 feet on the south side of project;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.
Major Projects Engineering
Clark County Fire Department approval for all turn-arounds;
Right-of-way dedication to include 30 feet for Westwind Road and associated spandrels;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Construct full off-sites to include paved legal access to all entrances;
VS-0071-07 to be recordable prior to final map technical review submittal;
Enter into cross access agreement with parcel to the west.

42. WT-0247-08 WARM SPRINGS JONES 25 INVESTMENTS, LLC:
WAIVER to reduce throat depths in conjunction with an office/warehouse and retail center on 8.4 acres in an M-D (Designed Manufacturing) Zone in the Pinnacle Peaks Concept Plan area. Generally located on the south side of Warm Springs Road and the west side of Westwind Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects Engineering
All applicable standard conditions for this application type;
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time, and that this application must commence within 1 year.

46. UC-0294-08 SHAMROCK/SUNSET, LLC:
USE PERMIT for a Project of Regional Significance.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) roll-up doors on a kiosk; 2) alternative parking lot design; 3) alternative building design; and 4) alternative screening.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 19.3 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-70) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road and the east side of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD 06/04/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

57. HOLDOVER AG-0258-08: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing to determine whether a Default of Section 4.03 of the Development Agreement between Mountains Edge, LLC and Clark County has occurred and if necessary, to direct staff on any methods to be used to resolve this default..
HELD 08/20/08 per the applicant.

68. HOLDOVER ORD-0177-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to amend Title 7, Chapter 7.08, Section 7.08.045 of the Clark County Code to add the requirement that all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist limit their hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., providing for an exemption to the hours of operation requirement for all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist with an existing license as of the date of the enactment of this ordinance, and providing for an exemption to the hours of operation requirement for all massage establishments licensed prior to the enactment of this ordinance that are approved for a change in and/or transfer of interest of ownership subsequent to the enactment of this ordinance, and providing for other matters properly relating thereto.
An ordinance to amend Title 7, Chapter 7.08, Section 7.08.045 by adding the requirement that hours of operation of all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist shall be limited to 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., adding the provision that all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a license massage therapist with an existing license as the date of this ordinance shall be exempt from the requirement to limit the hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., and adding a provision that all massage establishments licensed prior to the enactment of this ordinance that are approved for a change in and/or transfer of ownership in accordance with Title 6, Chapter 6.04, Section 6.04.070 of this code subsequent to the enactment of this ordinance are exempt from the requirement to limit hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., and providing for other matters properly relating thereto.
ADOPTED as amended.

69. HOLDOVER ORD-1713-07: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance modifying regulations for massage establishments; and direct staff accordingly. 
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44 Table 30.44-1 to modify requirements for massage establishments and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED as amended.

70. HOLDOVER ORD-0178-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance revising the separation requirements for check cashing facilities; and direct staff accordingly. An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44, Table 30.44-1 to revise and update check cashing separation requirements and procedures; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
WITHDRAWN.

ZONING COMMISSION 5-7-08

14. ZC-0081-08 BD PARCEL HOLDINGS, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.2 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for future commercial development in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Blue Diamond Road, 100 feet east of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
WITHDRAWN.

15. ZC-0236-08 STATE OF NEVADA:
HELD 05/21/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

26. NZC-0982-04 (ET-0334-07) HURLEY, STEVE&amp;DONNA:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 2.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone for a plant nursery. 
USE PERMIT to review outside storage for a plant nursery to be located in front of the building. Generally located on the north side of Gomer Road and the east side of Fort Apache Road within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 11/05/08 per staff.

28. UC-0304-08 HOLLAND, MARJORIE:
USE PERMIT for a veterinary clinic.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for reduced setbacks.
DESIGN REVIEW for a veterinary clinic that is not architecturally compatible with residential development within 200 feet on 1.0 acre in a C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the northwest corner of Wigwam Avenue and Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Design review as a public hearing for any significant changes;
Landscaping per plans on file;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-0111-07;
Traffic study not required, but Development Services Civil Engineering approval of driveway location, dimension, and design.

37. ZC-1476-02 (WC-0080-08) SHAMROCK/SUNSET, LLC:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring that the parcels listed in ZC-1476-02 and ZC-1165-07 be combined to obtain a contiguous site in conjunction with a proposed office park in a C-2 (Commercial General) (AE-65&amp;AE-70) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the northeast corner of Jones Boulevard and the 215 Beltway within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.

46. ORD-0548-08: That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance revising the separation requirements for check cashing facilities; and direct staff accordingly. An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.16, and 30.44, Tables 30.16-4, 30.16-7 and 30.44-1 to revise and update check cashing separation requirements and procedures; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
WITHDRAWN.

57. HOLDOVER ORD-0177-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to amend Title 7, Chapter 7.08, Section 7.08.045 of the Clark County Code to add the requirement that all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist limit their hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., providing for an exemption to the hours of operation requirement for all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist with an existing license as of the date of the enactment of this ordinance, and providing for an exemption to the hours of operation requirement for all massage establishments licensed prior to the enactment of this ordinance that are approved for a change in and/or transfer of interest of ownership subsequent to the enactment of this ordinance, and providing for other matters properly relating thereto.
An ordinance to amend Title 7, Chapter 7.08, Section 7.08.045 by adding the requirement that hours of operation of all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a licensed massage therapist shall be limited to 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., adding the provision that all massage establishments, massage businesses, chair massage businesses and massage offered on the premises of state licensed providers of health care by a license massage therapist with an existing license as the date of this ordinance shall be exempt from the requirement to limit the hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., and adding a provision that all massage establishments licensed prior to the enactment of this ordinance that are approved for a change in and/or transfer of ownership in accordance with Title 6, Chapter 6.04, Section 6.04.070 of this code subsequent to the enactment of this ordinance are exempt from the requirement to limit hours of operation from 8:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m., and providing for other matters properly relating thereto.
HELD 05/21/08 per staff.

58. HOLDOVER ORD-1713-07: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance modifying regulations for massage establishments; and direct staff accordingly.
An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44 Table 30.44-1 to modify requirements for massage establishments and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD 05/21/08 per staff.

59. HOLDOVER ORD-0178-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance revising the separation requirements for check cashing facilities; and direct staff accordingly. An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapter 30.44, Table 30.44-1 to revise and update check cashing separation requirements and procedures; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD 05/21/08 per staff.

ZONING COMMISSION 4-16-08

16. ZC-0236-08 STATE OF NEVADA:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.7 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to P-F (Public Facility) Zone.
USE PERMITS for a public facility including the following 1) major training facility; 2) automobile and truck maintenance, paint and body, and repair facilities; 3) warehouse; 4) fuel storage yard; 5) outside storage; 6) truck stop; 7) truck and automobile car wash; 8) offices; and 9) related commercial and industrial accessory uses.
DESIGN REVIEW for public facility (readiness center) buildings, offices, truck and vehicle repair facilities, fuel storage, warehouse, outside storage, and accessory uses on 50.0 acres.

Generally located on the west side of Arville Street between Silverado Ranch Boulevard and Serene Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 05/07/08 for the applicant to return to the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

19. NZC-1488-07 BELTWAY VIEW, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 10.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for increased building height.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center. Generally located on the south side of Wigwam Avenue and west side of Durango Drive within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No access to Bonita Vista Street;
A 6 foot high block wall along Cougar Avenue;
No access to Cougar Avenue;
A maximum building height of 32 feet to the top of the parapet and 37 feet to the top of the roof;
Site lighting to consist of a combination of pole mounted lights and bollard lighting, pole mounted lights will be 14 feet tall with motion sensors, exterior building lighting to consist of custom and standard wall sconces, recessed up-lights, and accent lighting, all lighting will be shielded or directed to prevent lighting from shining onto residential uses, the applicant is to prevent any adverse lighting impacts to adjacent residential uses through several means including: cut off shields, screens, or baffles on all pole mounted lights;
Landscaping along all street frontages to be elevated to reduce headlight impact on adjacent residences, options are: 1) a decorative low-profile masonry wall less than 36 inches high with landscaping, or 2) a self-stabilizing 3 foot high berm with a 1 foot rise for every 3 feet of horizontal distance and landscaping;
Design review as a public hearing for lighting and signage;
Primary access on Durango Drive;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area;
Design review as a public hearing for any significant changes to the site plan or design;
Architectural treatments are to be applied to the rear of Buildings B and D to include, but not be limited to, colored contrasted overhead trellis features, screen walls with architectural features, building facade treatments, and linear and horizontal off-sets in the buildings;
Enhanced paving is to be provided at the vehicular entrances to the center and extended along the walkways throughout with pedestrian realm elements added such as benches, seating areas, architectural artistic figures, and tables in the public areas;
??Block walls are to be decorative on all sides or masonry in design to match the center; 
 Increased landscape setback along Cougar Avenue to a minimum of 10 feet of depth from edge of the sidewalk and install 36 inch box trees every 20 feet on center;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must be completed within 3 years of approval or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Install Stop signs at Durango Drive and Wigwam Avenue;
One larger access on Wigwam Avenue with a revised plan to be approve by staff;
In lieu of Wigwam Avenue dedication of 35 feet to back of curb, Clark County will amend the Transportation Element to remove this portion of Wigwam Avenue west of Durango Drive, when amended Wigwam Avenue to be dedicated at 30 feet to back of sidewalk and the applicant to grant and construct a 10 foot equestrian trail easement between sidewalk and landscape, landscape requirement along Wigwam Avenue will then be 10 feet but will be placed back of trail;
Right-of-way dedications to include 45 feet back of curb for Durango Drive, 35 feet back of curb for Wigwam Avenue, 30 feet for Cougar Avenue, 30 feet for Bonita Vista Street and associated spandrels;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards.
40. ORD-0439-08: That the Board of County Commissioners introduce an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Rainbow Robindale Center USA, LLC for a commercial development (Rainbow Robindale Plaza).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Rainbow Robindale Center USA, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the southwest corner of Rainbow Boulevard and Robindale Road within the southeast quarter (SE1/4) of Section 10, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
INTRODUCED public hearing 05/07/08.

45. ORD-0409-08: That the Board of County Commissioners consider an ordinance to update various regulations in the Clark County Unified Development Code (Title 30); and direct staff accordingly. An ordinance to amend Title 30, Chapters 30.08, 30.12, 30.16, 30.36, 30.40, 30.44, 30.48, 30.56, 30.60, 30.64, 30.72 and Appendix F, Sections 30.08.030, 30.16.210, 30.16.230, 30.16.240, 30.36.080, 30.40.290, 30.48.070, 30.48.170, 30.48.190, 30.48.200, 30.56.040, 30.60.040, 30.60.090, 30.72.040, 30.72.070, Tables 30.12.-1, 30.16-4, 30.16-9, 30.16-15, 30.16-20, 30.44-1, 30.60-1 30.64-1, and 30.72-1; to revise and update various land use requirements and procedures and make corrections and clarifications as appropriate; and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
HELD - 05/07/08 per Commissioner Woodbury.

46. ORD-0378-08: That the Board of County Commissioners conduct a public hearing on an ordinance to consider adoption of a Standard Development Agreement with Blue Diamond Southeast Corner, LLC and Durango Rock, LLC for a commercial development (Mountain Trails Commercial Development).
An ordinance to adopt a Standard Development Agreement with Blue Diamond Southeast Corner, LLC and Durango Rock, LLC for a proposed commercial development generally located on the southeast corner of Blue Diamond Road and Durango Road within the northwest quarter (NW1/4) of Section 21, Township 22 South, Range 60 East within the boundaries of the Town of Enterprise and providing for other matters properly related thereto.
ADOPTED.

ZONING COMMISSION 4-2-08

9. UC-0356-06 (ET-0046-08) TWENTY TWO TWENTY TWO, LLC:
USE PERMITS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to commence the following: 1) resort condominiums; 2) increase building height; 3) retail sales and service; and 4) on-premise consumption of alcohol.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce the height setback ratio adjacent to an arterial street (Las Vegas Boulevard South).
DESIGN REVIEW for a resort condominium complex with commercial uses on 10.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on northwest corner of Las Vegas Boulevard South and Agate Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Until May 17, 2011 to commence;
Applicant to perform a record of survey to determine underlying title rights in relationship to &quot;as built&quot; improvements on Las Vegas Boulevard, a Transportation Study shall identify the necessary improvements in relation to the determination of necessary rights-of-way;
Right-of-way dedication for Las Vegas Boulevard South to accommodate a proportionate share of a 100 foot half street;
Compliance with all other conditions of UC-0356-06;
Execute and sign a License and Maintenance Agreement for any non-standard improvements within right-of-way;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval and concurrence is no longer needed.

11. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
HELD 05/21/08 per the applicant.

20. ZC-0081-08 BD PARCEL HOLDINGS, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.2 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for future commercial development in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
Generally located on the south side of Blue Diamond Road, 100 feet east of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 05/07/08 per the applicant.

21. UC-0181-08 BD PARCEL HOLDINGS, LLC, ET AL:
USE PERMIT to allow a shopping center.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; 2) reduce setbacks; and 3) alternative landscaping.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 3.6 acres in an H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the east side of Decatur Boulevard and the south side of Blue Diamond Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Explore cross access to the property to the east;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair share contribution to a public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of lack of necessary public services in area;
Applicant to apply for a commercial zone change within 2 years;
Building exits that face residential property are emergency exits only;
Design review as a public hearing for signage;
Lighting facing residential will be boxed, shielded, and downcast;
Increased building height allowed on one decorative element shown on the design review;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include up to 60 feet to back of curb for Decatur Boulevard with necessary transitions and any additional dedication for turn lanes as required in the traffic study, 30 feet for Ford Avenue, and related spandrels;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval;
Construct full off-site improvements to include dedication and construction of a combination bus turnout and entrance on Blue Diamond Road, and an exclusive right turn lane into the entrance on Decatur Boulevard;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
Traffic study to also address design and location of driveways to be approved by Development Services Civil Engineering;

22. ZC-0176-08 P2SA EQUITY, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 3.6 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) allow on-premise consumption of alcohol (supper club); 2) reduce the separation from on-premise consumption of alcohol to a residential use; and 3) reduce the separation from outside dining to a residential development.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) alternative landscaping; 2) increase building height; and 3) allow access to a residential local street.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center. Generally located on the south side of Warm Springs Road and the east side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
2 years to commence and review the outside dining;
Reduce wall adjacent to supper club from 41 feet to 36 feet, and include a sound-absorbing material;
No audio on the outside portion of the supper club;
Design review as a public hearing for signage;
Lighting facing residential to be boxed, shielded, and down cast, use 15 foot lighting poles on the south side of the property;
Highest point of the building to be 41 feet, parapet to be 37 feet;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that land use applications will be required in the future for any live entertainment activities; and that signage as depicted on plans may require a subsequent land use application.
Civil Engineering
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
Drainage study and compliance;
Driveway widths to be a maximum 40 feet and align driveway on Warm Springs Road with driveway to the north;
Reconstruct any unused driveways with full off-sites;
Signs to remain a minimum of 10 feet from right of way and maintain clearance from site visibility zone.
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards.
Department of Aviation
No building permits shall be released for the project prior to the Department of Aviation notifying Zoning Plan Check that the applicant has received all necessary airspace approvals;

36. UC-1447-07 RED HOT CORNER LLC, ET AL:
HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) temporary batch plant; and 2) temporary construction storage on 3.9 acres in an R-T (Manufactured Home Residential) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Dale Avenue, 1,100 feet west of Las Vegas Boulevard South within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Applicant to complete activities and remove equipment and materials within 120 days, (90 days to crush materials and 30 days to remove materials);
Payment of relocation costs in the amount of $5,000.00 to Ms. Peterson, entire amount to be paid prior to the issuance of any permit for, or commencement of, rock crushing operation with written proof of payment submitted to Clark County Current Planning Department, care of Mr. Jason Allswang;
Proper permits for operation to be obtained;
No extension of time to be accepted;
All activities limited to 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday;
Private bond to be in place by Monday, February 25, 2008;
Provide 30 day status report to the City of Henderson, staff (administrative review by staff), and the neighboring property owners;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that compliance with the noise provision per Title 30.68 is required, and that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.

47. ORD-0409-08: INTRODUCED public hearing 04/16/08.
48. ORD-0378-08: INTRODUCED public hearing 04/16/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 3-19-08

22. WS-0998-05 (ET-0410-07) MERCURY DEVELOPMENT, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to commence the following: 1) reduce the 3:1 height setback ratio adjacent to a residential use (south property line); and 2) permit balconies to overlook a residential use in conjunction with a proposed hotel condominium development.
DESIGN REVIEW for a hotel condominium development on 2.5 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the east side of Giles Street and the south side of Shelbourne Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Until January 18, 2010 to commence;

26. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce parking; and 2) allow access from a local residential street.
DESIGN REVIEW for office buildings. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
5 year review on parking;
Basement area to be restricted to storage and gym facilities;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication of 30 feet for Haven Street;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Re-construct any unused driveways with full off-sites;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Applicant to grant a minimum of 20 foot private access and utility easement to the owner of Assessor Parcel Number 177-09-401-016;
Applicant to also acquire a notarized consent from the owner of Assessor Parcel Number 177-09-401-016.

33. ZC-0047-08 NORCOTT, JAMES T., ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a convenience store with gasoline pumps; 2) on-premise consumption of alcohol (tavern); and 3) office building with a managers unit. Generally located on the west side of Dean Martin Drive and the north side of Gary Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 09/03/08 per the applicant. Applicant is advised that renotification fees will be required.

34. ZC-0150-08 SUNSET SOUTHWEST, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from C-1 (Local Business) (AE-65) Zone to M-D (Designed Manufacturing) (AE-65) Zone.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to eliminate the requirement for a sidewalk along the 215 Beltway Frontage Road.
DESIGN REVIEW for an industrial park on 21.6 acres in an M-D (AE-65&amp;AE-70) (Designed Manufacturing) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road, 835 feet east of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file). 
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that a signage package must be submitted as a design review; and that if a sidewalk is required along the 215 Frontage Road, the site design must still comply with 30.48.660(7).
Civil Engineering
Apply for and have approved a waver of conditions for ZC-1476-02 in order to allow combining of parcels into 2 separate parcels prior to building permits or final map approval which ever comes first;
Right-of-way dedication as required for 215 Frontage Road by Public Works Design Engineering, and termination of Westwind Road as approved by Clark County Development Services and Department of Aviation;
Apply for and have approved a vacation of Wagon Trail Avenue west of Westwind Road or dedicate Wagon Trail Avenue through the site;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Traffic study to also address the design and location of driveways;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way. /dc
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS WAS WITHDRAWN.

37. NZC-0037-08 RAMEZAN LARKI ABBASI:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
USE PERMIT for an automobile rental facility in a C-1 zone.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for alternative parking lot design.
DESIGN REVIEW to convert a single family residence to an automobile rental facility.
Generally located 200 feet east of Gilespie Street and 300 feet north of Warm Springs Road within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must be completed within 3 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Construct driveway according to Uniform Standard Drawing #224;
Driveway to be a maximum width of 40 feet.

44. ZC-0300-06 (WC-0405-07) DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
45. WS-1484-07 DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
46. TM-0016-08 MOUNTAINS EDGE PHASE ii:
ALL APPROVED

49. UC-1447-07 RED HOT CORNER LLC, ET AL:
HELD 04/02/08 per the applicant.

50. AG-0257-08: That the Board of County Commissioners redesignate unimproved right-of-way along the Mardon Avenue alignment, commencing east of Cameron Street and west of Rogers Street along the Mardon Avenue alignment for approximately 4,350 square feet, to a park and trail use to be used in conjunction with and incorporated in to the Western Trails Equestrian Park, located at the southwest intersection of Warms Springs Road and Rogers Street within Enterprise; if approved, authorize the Chairman to sign the Resolution and consider other matters property related thereto.
APPROVED.

55. ORD-0262-08:
56. ORD-0263-08:
57. ORD-0288-08:
ALL INTRODUCED public hearing 04/02/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 3-5-08

17. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
HELD 04/02/08 per staff.

30. ZC-1122-07 CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
AMENDED HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.9 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce setbacks (previously not notified); and 2) reduce landscaping (previously not notified)
.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail and office building. Generally located on the northeast corner of Durango Drive and Wigwam Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Prior to construction, applicant to build an 8 foot high block wall along the east property line to buffer the residents during and after construction;
The building will be placed on the west property line facing inward to the parking lot;
All lighting shall be below 8 feet in height to prevent any spillover onto the adjacent property;
Landscaping shall be minimized along Wigwam Avenue to maintain a line of sight across the property when the tenants are closed;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Drainage study and compliance;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Full off-sites and detached sidewalk shall be provided along Wigwam Avenue unless the Trail Plan requires a trail which conflicts with providing full off-sites and the detached sidewalk;
Detached sidewalk will require granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus-turnout and/or passenger loading/shelter area in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards;
Additional right-of-way dedication will be required for Durango Drive to 50 feet to back of curb with 54 foot spandrel;
Driveway widths are required to be 32 feet minimum with throat depths to be 40 feet; 
Coordinate the construction, design, and location of the RTC bus turnout with the property to the north.

35. ZC-0247-03 (WC-0021-08) AMERICAN CHILD CARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring decorative split face block wall along the west boundary of the office project which shall be 10 feet in height in conjunction with an approved child care facility on 1.1 acres in a C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone and a C-1 (Local Business) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Robindale Road, 330 feet west of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Provide PAL lighting, if feasible;

43. UC-1418-07 MILANO RESIDENCES, LLC:
APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) reduced setbacks for a hotel; and 2) kitchens in guestrooms.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) permit clear windows of a hotel facade to overlook single family residential yards; and 2) reduce setbacks for a hotel from a single family residential use.
DESIGN REVIEW for a condominium hotel on a portion of 2.4 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Cactus Avenue, 300 feet east of Bermuda Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Design review as a public hearing for all signage to ensure compliance with residential protection standards and sign lighting;
Applicant will install on east side of building at all garage openings a 10 foot wide by 8 foot high decorative block wall for line of sight and noise reduction factors;
Applicant will install exterior shutters on all east windows to prevent line of sight to adjacent propertys back yards;
All windows on buildings east face will nto be capable of being opened more than 4 inches;
Applicant will plant 36 inch box Cypress trees on 5 foot centers along propertys east property line and maintain, if trees die, applicant will replace them;
Applicant will record CC&amp;Rs;prohibiting daily or weekly rentals, other than through a time-share regime, must be members of or sponsored by the share holders with no off-site rentals;
Enhanced paving at project entry;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.

48. VS-1469-07 ARIES HOLDINGS, LLC:
VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County between Miller Lane (alignment) and Warbonnet Road, and between Blue Diamond Road and Agate Avenue in an H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
Satisfying utility companies&apos; requirements;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that the recording of the order of vacation in the Office of the County Recorder must be completed within 2 years of the approval date or the application will expire.
Civil Engineering
Apply for and have approved waiver of conditions on ZC-0001-07 and ZC-0535-05;
Vacation to record concurrent with VS-0002-07 and VS-0543-07;
Vacation to record prior to any building permit issuance;
Revise legal description(s), if necessary;
Drainage study and compliance;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval of access to Blue Diamond Road;
Cross access to be addressed with any future zone change.

ZONING COMMISSION 2-20-08

11. WS-0998-05 (ET-0410-07) MERCURY DEVELOPMENT, LLC:
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to commence the following: 1) reduce the 3:1 height setback ratio adjacent to a residential use (south property line); and 2) permit balconies to overlook a residential use in conjunction with a proposed hotel condominium development.
DESIGN REVIEW for a hotel condominium development on 2.5 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-4 Overlay District. Generally located on the east side of Giles Street and the south side of Shelbourne Avenue within Enterprise.
HELD 03/19/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

16. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce parking; and 2) allow access from a local residential street.
DESIGN REVIEW for office buildings. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 03/19/08 for the applicant to work with Civil Engineering and the neighbors.

17. ZC-1122-07 CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.9 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail and office building. Generally located on the northeast corner of Durango Drive and Wigwam Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 03/05/08 to rewrite/renotify.

18. ZC-1458-07 KHUSROW ROOHANI FAMILY TRUST:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 5.0 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a mixed-use development in a C-1 zone; 2) increased height; and 3) increased density.
DESIGN REVIEW for a mixed-use development on 10.0 acres in a C-1 zone.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS of a zone change (ZC-1180-01) requiring the following: 1) full off-site improvements; and 2) right-of-way dedication to include 30 feet for Rosanna Street. Generally located on the south side of Warm Springs Road, 285 feet west of Rainbow Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
2 years to commence the use permits and design review;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area;
All trees to be a minimum of 24 inch box;
There shall be a 5 foot wide detached sidewalk on Warm Springs Road with a minimum of 5 feet of landscaping on either side of the sidewalk;
In addition to landscaping required pursuant to Clark County Code Title 30, there shall be at least 30, twenty foot tall skinned Mexican Fan Palm trees planted within the landscape area along Warm Springs Road;
In addition to landscaping required pursuant to Clark County Code Title 30, there shall be at least 2, twenty foot tall Date Palm trees planted on each side of the driveway off Warm Springs Road;
There shall be 36 inch box Mondel Pine trees or other non-deciduous trees planted 15 feet on center within the landscape area along Mardon Street;
All rock located in the landscape buffer areas shall be at least medium aggregate decorative rock in a color that matches the color used on the exterior of the commercial buildings;
There shall be no more than one freestanding sign which shall not exceed 30 feet in height inclusive of architectural features and shall be architecturally compatible with the development of the mixed-use project incorporating tile roof accents and/or ledge stone accents;
Monument signage not exceeding 8 feet in height is allowed;
The use of an electronic reader board on any sign or building is prohibited;
There shall be a design review as a public hearing on any changes;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that the use permit and design review must commence within 2 years of approval date or they will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with VS-1402-07;
Right-of-way dedication to include 50 feet at the east property line with a transition to 45 feet to back of curb for Warm Springs Road and 25 feet back of curb for Mardon Avenue;
Construct full off-sites;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
Drainage study and compliance;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts, including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
All applicable vacations to recordable prior to final map submittal.
Department of Aviation
At the initial sale of the unit, the purchaser must sign a one-page document regarding noise disclosure and such document must be recorded on the property;
Applicant must record a stand-alone noise disclosure form against the land, and provide a copy of the recorded document to the Clark County Department of Aviation;
Applicant must provide a copy of the recorded noise disclosure form to future buyers/renters, separate from other escrow documents, and provide a copy of the document to the Clark County Department of Aviation;
Applicant must provide a map to future buyers/renters, as part of the noise disclosure notice, that highlights the project location and associated flight tracks, provided by the Department of Aviation when property sales/leases commence;
Incorporate an exterior to interior noise level reduction of 30 decibels into the building construction for the habitable space if exceeds 35 feet in height or 25 decibels into the building construction for the habitable space if 35 feet or less in height;
Passive activity areas, designed for the quiet and peaceful enjoyment by the residents, must be enclosed.
Applicant is advised that the Federal Aviation Administration will no longer approve remedial noise mitigation measures for incompatible development impacted by aircraft operations which was constructed after October 1, 1998; and that funds will not be available in the future should the residents wish to have their buildings purchased or soundproofed.

20. ZC-0047-08 NORCOTT, JAMES T., ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a convenience store with gasoline pumps; 2) on-premise consumption of alcohol (tavern); and 3) office building with a managers unit. Generally located on the west side of Dean Martin Drive and the north side of Gary Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 03/19/08 per the applicant.

28. ZC-1490-07 POST 215, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.3 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for a parking garage in the CMA and MUD-3 Overlay Districts.
USE PERMIT to increase building height.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; 2) reduce setbacks; and 3) landscaping and screening requirements.
DESIGN REVIEW for a parking garage. Generally located on the north side of Post Road, 350 feet east of the 215 Beltway within Spring Valley (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
Pedestrian realm per Section 30.48;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 25 back of curb for Post Road, 30 feet for Seelinger Street and associated spandrel;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
Drainage study and compliance.
USE PERMIT, WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS, AND DESIGN REVIEW WERE WITHDRAWN WITHOUT PREJUDICE.

29. NZC-1470-07 THE STRATTON GROUP:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 5.1 acres from U-V (Urban Village - Mixed Use) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a hotel; 2) shopping center; 3) drive-thru restaurant;
and 4) tavern. Generally located on the west side of Quarterhorse Lane, 200 feet north of Blue Diamond Road within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair-share contribution toward public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of the lack of necessary public services in the area;
Design elements for commercial space are to be accented into the final drive-thru restaurant facility;
North and west elevations of are to be architecturally treated similar to the south and west elevation of commercial and retail building with cornice break-ups and color contrasted;
Roof mounted equipment is to be screened by parapet roof on all buildings and not seen from residential areas or adjacent commercial areas;
24 hour security cameras on the rear of the buildings;
Auto related businesses, dealerships, auto parts, repair, or maintenance are prohibited;
Buildings will be finished on all 4 sides;
Landscaping along Quarterhorse Lane, as shown on plans;
Lighting of the parking lot will be directed so there is no overspill on the residences but safely illuminates the parking lot;
No outside speakers except for the drive thru restaurant reader board;
Post No Overnight Parking for Trucks 41 Feet and Greater signs;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that the hotel setback from Quarterhorse Lane is to be a minimum of 20 feet from front property line or a waiver of development standards is required.
Civil Engineering
Throat depth must a minimum of 65 feet or as approved by the traffic engineer;
Right-of-way dedications to include 25 feet back of curb for Quarterhorse Lane, 25 back of curb for Agate Avenue and associated spandrel;
Construct full off-sites;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
Provide paved legal access from Blue Diamond Road;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval.

36. ZC-0300-06 (WC-0405-07) DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring a minimum 10 foot wide public street landscape buffers in conjunction with residential development on approximately 82.0 acres in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) P-C (Planned Community Overlay) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located between Erie Avenue and Starr Avenue and east of Buffalo Drive within Enterprise.
HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

37. WS-1484-07 DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) allow non-standard private street improvements; 2) allow non-standard improvements for the location of residential driveways; 3) reduce internal street off-set; 4) increase wall height; and 5) increase the length of a dead end street (cul-de-sac) in conjunction with residential development on approximately 94.6 acres in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) P-C (Planned Community Overlay) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located between Erie Avenue and Starr Avenue, and east of Buffalo Drive within Enterprise.
HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

38. TM-0016-08 MOUNTAINS EDGE PHASE II:
HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

43. WS-1232-07 CHURCH GOOD SAMARITAN LUTHERAN:
HOLDOVER APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for alternative landscaping on 4.2 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone. Generally located on the south side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Gagnier Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Landscape berm is no longer required on Gagnier Boulevard;
No landscaping is to be provided on the south and west sides of the property;
A 4 foot high combination stone and wrought iron fence shall be installed along the south property line and along Gagnier Boulevard with the northern 30 feet closest to Windmill Lane to match the existing wall/fence on the east side of Gagnier Boulevard;
A block wall is not required on the west property line;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.

44. WT-1455-07 - CHRISTOPHER HOMES:
APPEAL WAIVER of the requirement to provide street lighting along a public residential street within the Southern Highlands Master Planned Community. Generally located on the south side of Dancing Winds Place and the west side of Southern Highlands Parkway within Enterprise.
HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

ZONING COMMISSION 2-6-08

9. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce parking; and 2) allow access from a local residential street.
DESIGN REVIEW for office buildings. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 02/20/08 per the applicant.

20. WS-1646-05 (ET-0382-07) BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to commence and permit landscaping within the right-of-way.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail building on a portion of 7.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of Blue Diamond Road and the west side of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Until December 7, 2009 to commence;

21. WS-1370-07 BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce the trash enclosure setback; 2) alternative landscaping; and 3) reduced driveway separation.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS of a waiver of development standards (WS-1646-05) requiring the following: 1) landscaping per plans on file; and 2) any outside public address system or speakers along the north and northwest portion of the property shall have amplification restricted to the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 7.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the northwest corner of Blue Diamond Road and Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Landscaping to be 10 feet on center;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-1669-02 and WS-1765-05;
Update traffic study to address the new design, increase in building square footage and the additional drive thru restaurants;
Nevada Department of Transportation approval for any non-standard improvements within the right-of-way.
Department of Aviation
No building permits shall be released for the project prior to the Department of Aviation notifying Zoning Plan Check that the applicant has received all necessary airspace approvals;
Applicant is required to file a valid FAA Form 7460-1, &quot;Notice of Proposed Construction or Alteration&quot; with the FAA, in accordance with 14 CFR Part 77, or submit to the Director of Aviation a Property Owners Shielding Determination Statement and request written concurrence from the Department of Aviation;
If applicant does not obtain written concurrence to a Property Owner&apos;s Shielding Determination Statement, then applicant must also receive either a Permit from the Director of Aviation or a Variance from the Airport Hazard Areas Board of Adjustment (AHABA) prior to construction, as required by Section 30.48 PART B of the Clark County Unified Development Code.
Applicant is advised that the FAA&apos;s determination is advisory in nature and does not guarantee that a Director&apos;s Permit or an AHABA Variance will be approved.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #1 WAS WITHDRAWN.

22. VS-1468-07 CFT LANDS, LLC:
HOLDOVER VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County located between Oleta Avenue (alignment) and Serene Avenue, and between Jones Boulevard and Westwind Road (alignment), and a portion of right-of-way being Jones Boulevard located between Oleta Avenue and Serene Avenue, and a portion of right-of-way being Oleta Avenue located between Jones Boulevard and Westwind Road (alignment) in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED

23. WS-1467-07 CFT LANDS, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce lot area; 2) increase wall height; and 3) reduce street off-set.
DESIGN REVIEW for a single family residential development on 17.3 acres in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change (ZC-0353-05) requiring right-of-way dedication of 30 feet for Duneville Street. Generally located on the east side of Jones Boulevard and the north side of Serene Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
Provide additional pedestrian access points to Jones Boulevard and to the adjacent park to the east;
Provide a 20 foot wide landscape buffer with two off-set rows of medium trees, 24 inch box in size, with shrubs to cover 50% of the landscape area with detached sidewalks along Jones Boulevard;
Provide a disclosure statement to each purchaser of homes regarding the existence of a gravel batch plant located across Jones Boulevard, diagonal from this site; 
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedications to include 45 feet back of curb for Jones Boulevard, 35 feet back of curb for Serene Avenue, and associated spandrels;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards;
Lots adjacent to the Oleta Avenue alignment cannot be constructed until the temporary access easement is relinquished.

ZONING COMMISSION 1-16-08

18. ZC-1122-07 CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.9 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail and office building. Generally located on the northeast corner of Durango Drive and Wigwam Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 02/20/08 per the applicant

34. WS-1646-05 (ET-0382-07) BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to commence and permit landscaping within the right-of-way. 
DESIGN REVIEW for a retail building on a portion of 7.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the north side of Blue Diamond Road and the west side of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD 02/06/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting and work with neighbors.

35. WS-1370-07 BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
HOLDOVER WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce the trash enclosure setback; 2) alternative landscaping; and 3) reduced driveway separation.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS of a waiver of development standards (WS-1646-05) requiring the following: 1) landscaping per plans on file; and 2) any outside public address system or speakers along the north and northwest portion of the property shall have amplification restricted to the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.
DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 7.1 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the northwest corner of Blue Diamond Road and Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD 02/06/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting and work with neighbors.

38. ZC-0799-02 (ET-0354-07) - EQUITY HOLDINGS MANAGEMENT, LLC:
HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE SECOND EXTENSION OF TIME to reclassify 2.5 acres from an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to CRT (Commercial Residential Transition) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Pebble Road and the west side of Bermuda Road within Enterprise (description on file).
APPROVED
Current Planning
Until December 18, 2011 to complete;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with previous conditions

41. VS-1468-07 CFT LANDS, LLC:
VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County located between Oleta Avenue (alignment) and Serene Avenue, and between Jones Boulevard and Westwind Road (alignment), and a portion of right-of-way being Jones Boulevard located between Oleta Avenue and Serene Avenue, and a portion of right-of-way being Oleta Avenue located between Jones Boulevard and Westwind Road (alignment) in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant.

42. WS-1467-07 CFT LANDS, LLC:
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce lot area; 2) increase wall height; and 3) reduce street off-set.
DESIGN REVIEW for a single family residential development on 17.3 acres in an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change (ZC-0353-05) requiring right-of-way dedication of 30 feet for Duneville Street. Generally located on the east side of Jones Boulevard and the north side of Serene Avenue within Enterprise.
HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant.

47. ZC-0511-01 (WC-0367-07) SUNSET V, LLC, ET AL:
HOLDOVER WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring 30 feet of dedication for Bronco Street from Sunset Road to Wagon Trail Avenue in conjunction with a proposed automobile sales complex on 54.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-65) (AE-70) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road and the east side of Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) within Enterprise. 
HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant

48. VS-1348-07 SUNSET III, LLC, ET AL:
HOLDOVER VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County located between Sunset Road and the 215 Beltway, and between Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) and Bronco Street (alignment), and portion of a right-of-way being Sunset Road located between Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) and Mann Street (alignment) in an C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-65) (AE-70) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant.

55. UC-0931-07 HOPE BAPTIST CHURCH&amp;HUONG THI LE:
HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMIT for a place of worship.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to allow attached sidewalks where detached sidewalks are required.
DESIGN REVIEW for a place of worship on 7.1 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone. Generally located on the northwest corner of Gilespie Street and Pebble Road within Enterprise.
APPROVED-
Current Planning
The north parcel to be used for a parking lot only and not for any structures or events;
Design review as a public hearing on Phase II;
Intense landscape buffer on the north property line of the north parking lot;
Signage to be installed on the parking lot advising users that the surrounding area is an RNP and allows horses;
Design, construction, and location of the playground to be addressed with the design review for Phase II;
Add sound mitigation measures around the playground;
Parking lot lighting to be low impact and on a timer;
Chain/bollard light weight gate at the entrance to Gilespie Street;
Landscaping per plans;
Move the playground to location as shown on plans;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Right-of-way dedication to include 40 feet for Gilespie Street;
Construct full off-sites;
If detached, sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Driveways to be a minimum 32 feet with curb returns;
Reconstruct any unused driveways with full off-sites;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal.
Fire Department
Provide a fire/emergency access plan with correct turn radius of 28 foot interior and 52 foot exterior.

58. UC-1098-07 ROSE STREET REALTY, ET AL:
HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) a place of worship; and 2) increased building height.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce the height/setback ratio to a residential use; 2) allow access on a residential local street; and 3) reduce parking.
DESIGN REVIEW for a place of worship on 9.8 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone. Generally located on the east side of Lindell Road, 330 feet south of Agate Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
5 years to commence;
No bell or audible sounds from the bell tower;
Cut-off light fixtures, motion sensors on lighting when feasible;
Building heights with the exception of the bell tower not to exceed 35 feet;
Limit outdoor activities to daylight hours;
No full time daycare;
No K thru 12 school;
No events in the parking lot;
No renting out the parking lot;
Design review to address lighting;
Seating capacity to be a maximum of 1,000 people;
Primary access is to be from Lindell Road;
Design review as a public hearing;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time.
Civil Engineering
Traffic study to include the entire RNP to be submitted and reviewed with the design review;
Rural road standards along Mohawk Street;
No Parking signage to be installed along Mohawk Street adjacent to the property;
Work with Public Works on traffic calming measures in the area;
Off-sites to be reviewed with the traffic study and design review;
Right-of-way dedication to include 35 feet to back of curb for Lindell Road and 25 feet to back of curb for Mohawk Street;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.
Fire Department
Provide a fire/emergency access plan, in accordance with 2005 CCFC.
WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS AND THE DESIGN REVIEW WERE WITHDRAWN.

61. VS-1120-07 SBH LOT OPTION, LLC:
HOLDOVER APPEAL VACATE AND ABANDON a portion of right-of-way being Agate Avenue located between Jerlyn Street and Pioneer Avenue (alignment) in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone within Enterprise (description on file).
WITHDRAWN without prejudice.

62. WS-1110-07 MONTE NOVELLA LLC:
APPEAL WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) allow non-standard improvements for the location of residential driveways; and 2) allow a reduction in driveway length on 5.0 acres in an RUD (Residential Urban Density) P-C (Planned Community Overlay) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located on the south side of Cactus Avenue, 330 feet east of Buffalo Drive within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Engineering
CC&amp;Rs;to state that 10 foot driveways cannot be used for parking;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #2 WAS WITHDRAWN.

66. WS-1232-07 CHURCH GOOD SAMARITAN LUTHERAN:
HOLDOVER APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for alternative landscaping on 4.2 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone. Generally located on the south side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Gagnier Boulevard within Enterprise.
HELD 02/20/08 per the applicant.

ZONING COMMISSION 1-2-08

8. WS-1401-07 WINDMILL PARTNERS LLC:
WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to increase building height in conjunction with an approved retail development.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS to delete all conditions of a zone change (ZC-0448-06) (see list on file) on 4.4 acres in a C-1 (Local Business District) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane, 290 feet east of Bermuda Road within Paradise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
2 years to commence the waiver of development standards;
A separate design review as a public hearing will be required for any construction not shown on the original plans or subsequently approved plans;
Maximum height of the structures will be limited to 36 feet (save and excepting the communications tower, which measures approximately 80 feet), measured separately from finished grade adjacent to each structure;
Developer agrees that until completion of construction of the two buildings that are currently approved, it will meet with the neighbors on a regular basis to discuss any issues that may arise;
Developer shall construct a new block wall (boundary wall) on the projects north property line at a height of not less than 8 feet measured from the highest point on either side of the boundary wall, provided the owners of the residential uses abutting such boundary wall agree in writing to grant rights of access needed to construct said boundary wall, and to the extent permitted by applicable laws, including that allowance will be made for gates or other access features required by utility companies;
Developer will construct a planter box south of the boundary wall that is at least 3 feet deep, 10 feet wide, and in which will be planted a minimum of 24 inch box trees of the species Pinus Eldarica (Mondel Pine) or such other tree species as developer and each adjacent residential property owner may otherwise agree upon in writing, which trees will be planted 10 feet on center;
Developer will apply to vacate Battista Lane from existing pavement south of Windmill Lane, construct a new zone boundary wall across the vacated area and remove asphalt from vacated area;
Developer shall not permit any restaurants operating within the project to create an odor nuisance;
Trash enclosures to be located as shown on the approved plans;
Leases will include a provision that there will be no deliveries through the fire code doors at the back of the in-line building, but employees access will be allowed through the rear doors of the building;
Lights in the rear in-line will be shielded so that they will not directly illuminate the neighboring residential properties;
Landscaping will be professionally installed and professionally maintained, any accumulation of trash in rear of center affecting any adjacent residences will be promptly removed when called to the attention of the developer;
Developer will maintain responsibility for pest and rodent control over the entire property;
Applicant will provide 3 loading spaces, as required by the approved plan;
All applicable standard conditions for zone change and waiver of development standards application type.
Applicant is advised that signage is not a part of this application; and that outside dining is a conditional use in a C-1 zone.
WAIVERS OF CONDITIONS #19, AND #24 THRU #30 WERE DENIED.

24. ZC-0511-01 (WC-0367-07) SUNSET V, LLC, ET AL:
HOLDOVER WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring 30 feet of dedication for Bronco Street from Sunset Road to Wagon Trail Avenue in conjunction with a proposed automobile sales complex on 54.0 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-65) (AE-70) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road and the east side of Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) within Enterprise.
HELD 01/16/08 per the applicant.

25. VS-1348-07 SUNSET III, LLC, ET AL:
HOLDOVER VACATE AND ABANDON easements of interest to Clark County located between Sunset Road and the 215 Beltway, and between Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) and Bronco Street (alignment), and portion of a right-of-way being Sunset Road located between Torrey Pines Drive (alignment) and Mann Street (alignment) in an C-2 (General Commercial) (AE-65) (AE-70) Zone in the MUD-3 and CMA Design Overlay Districts within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 01/16/08 per the applicant.

26. ZC-1341-06 (WC-0373-07) CLARK COUNTY:
WAIVER OF CONDITIONS of a zone change requiring right-of-way dedication of 30 feet for Le Baron Avenue on a portion of 74.5 acres in a P-F (Public Facility) Zone. Generally located on the south side of Le Baron Avenue and the west side of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise. 
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Civil Engineering
Applicant to vacate the full 60 foot alignment of Le Baron Avenue from Jones Boulevard to the easterly right-of-way line of the Union Pacific Railroad.

27. DR-1384-07 CLARK COUNTY:
DESIGN REVIEW for a public facility (public works campus) on a portion of 74.5 acres in a P-F (Public Facility) Zone. Generally located on the south side of LeBaron Avenue and the west side of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Current Planning
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Civil Engineering
Compliance with ZC-1341-06 and ZC-1341-06 (WC-0373-07).

30. VS-1120-07 SBH LOT OPTION, LLC:
HOLDOVER APPEAL VACATE AND ABANDON a portion of right-of-way being Agate Avenue located between Jerlyn Street and Pioneer Avenue (alignment) in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) (RNP-I) Zone within Enterprise (description on file).
HELD 01/16/08 per the applicant.

31. WS-1176-07 GRASSO FAMILY TRUST:
HOLDOVER APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for reduced lot size in conjunction with a single family residential subdivision on 8.7 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone and an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone. Generally located on the east side of McLeod Drive, 200 feet north of Eldorado Lane within Paradise.
HELD 01/16/08 per the applicant.

32. TM-0280-07 GRASSO FAMILY TRUST:
HOLDOVER APPEAL TENTATIVE MAP for a subdivision consisting of 52 single family residential lots on 8.7 acres in an R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone and an R-2 (Medium Density Residential) Zone. Generally located on the east side of McLeod Drive, 200 feet north of Eldorado Lane within Paradise.
HELD 01/16/08 per the applicant.

33. WS-1247-07 SCHNIPPEL FAMILY L.P.; ET AL:
APPEAL WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; and 2) reduce the garage setback to a drive aisle.
DESIGN REVIEW for 360 condominium units in conjunction with a multi-family project on 20.0 acres in an R-3 (Multiple Family Residential) P-C (Planned Community Overlay District) Zone in the Mountains Edge Master Planned Community. Generally located on the east side of Buffalo Drive, 660 feet south of Cactus Avenue within Enterprise.
APPROVED
Major Projects - Planning
3 story buildings located per plans;
12 month renters moratorium after initial sale of condominiums (added to CC&amp;Rs;);
Maximum of 10% rental rate after initial sale of condominiums (added to CC&amp;Rs;);
Speed humps throughout site as a traffic calming device;
Provide 8 feet deep driveway depth on loop road;
Provide an intense landscape buffer along the north, south, and east property lines;
All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
Applicant is advised that any change in circumstances or regulations may be justification for the denial of an extension of time; and that this application must commence within 2 years of approval date or it will expire.
Major Projects - Engineering
Have approved a 3-point turning analysis of egressing vehicles from garages prior to final map technical review submittal.

34. AG-1622-07: That the Board of County Commissioners receives a report on a possible annual amendment to the Enterprise Land Use Plan, a non-action informational item.
Report Received and staff given direction.

36. CP-1664-07: That the Board of County Commissioners initiate the amendment process for an amendment to the Transportation Element to add a 60 foot right-of-way collector street as a frontage road between Le Baron Avenue and existing Frank Sinatra Drive.
Initiation approved.

ZONING COMMISSION 4-2-08

9. UC-0356-06 (ET-0046-08) TWENTY TWO TWENTY TWO LLC:
     USE PERMITS FIRST EXTENSION OF TIME to commence the following: 1) resort condominiums; 2) increase building height; 3) retail sales and service; and 4) on-premise consumption of alcohol.
     WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to reduce the height setback ratio adjacent to an arterial street (Las Vegas Boulevard South).
     DESIGN REVIEW for a resort condominium complex with commercial uses on 10.0 acres in an H-1 (Limited Resort and Apartment) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on northwest corner of Las Vegas Boulevard South and Agate Avenue within Enterprise.
     APPROVED Until May 17, 2011 to commence;

11. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
     HELD 05/21/08 per the applicant.

20. ZC-0081-08 BD PARCEL HOLDING, LLC:
     HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.2 acres from H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone for future commercial development in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
Generally located on the south side of Blue Diamond Road, 100 feet east of Decatur Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
     HELD 05/07/08 per the applicant.

21. UC-0181-08 BD PARCEL HOLDINGS, LLC, ET AL:
     USE PERMIT to allow a shopping center.
     WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; 2) reduce setbacks; and 3) alternative landscaping.
     DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center on 3.6 acres in an H-2 (General Highway Frontage) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District. Generally located on the east side of Decatur Boulevard and the south side of     Blue Diamond Road within Enterprise.
     APPROVED
Explore cross access to the property to the east;
Enter into a standard development agreement prior to any permits or subdivision mapping in order to provide fair share contribution to a public infrastructure necessary to provide service because of lack of necessary public services in area;
Applicant to apply for a commercial zone change within 2 years;
Building exits that face residential property are emergency exits only;
Design review as a public hearing for signage;
Lighting facing residential will be boxed, shielded, and downcast;
Increased building height allowed on one decorative element shown on the design review;
Right-of-way dedication to include up to 60 feet to back of curb for Decatur Boulevard with necessary transitions and any additional dedication for turn lanes as required in the traffic study, 30 feet for Ford Avenue, and related spandrels;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval; 
Construct full off-site improvements to include dedication and construction of a combination bus turnout and entrance on Blue Diamond Road, and an exclusive right turn lane into the entrance on Decatur Boulevard;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
Traffic study to also address design and location of driveways to be approved by Development Services Civil Engineering; 
Nevada Department of Transportation approval required.

22. ZC-0176-08 P2SA EQUITY, LLC:
     ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 3.6 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District.
     USE PERMITS for the following: 1) allow on-premise consumption of alcohol (supper club); 2) reduce the separation from on-premise consumption of alcohol to a residential use; and 3) reduce the separation from outside dining to a residential development.
     WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) alternative landscaping; 2) increase building height; and 3) allow access to a residential local street.
     DESIGN REVIEW for a shopping center. Generally located on the south side of Warm Springs Road and the east side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
     APPROVED
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
2 years to commence and review the outside dining;
Reduce wall adjacent to supper club from 41 feet to 36 feet, and include a sound-absorbing material;
No audio on the outside portion of the supper club;
Design review as a public hearing for signage;
Lighting facing residential to be boxed, shielded, and down cast, use 15 foot lighting poles on the south side of the property;
Highest point of the building to be 41 feet, parapet to be 37 feet;
Applicant is advised that land use applications will be required in the future for any live entertainment activities; and that signage as depicted on plans may require a subsequent land use application.
Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
Drainage study and compliance;
Driveway widths to be a maximum 40 feet and align driveway on Warm Springs Road with driveway to the north;
Reconstruct any unused driveways with full off-sites;
Signs to remain a minimum of 10 feet from right of way and maintain clearance from site visibility zone.
If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards.

36. UC-1447-07 RED HOT CORNER, LLC, ET AL:
     HOLDOVER APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) temporary batch plant; and 2) temporary construction storage on 3.9 acres in an R-T (Manufactured Home Residential) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Dale Avenue, 1,100 feet west of Las Vegas Boulevard South within Enterprise.
     APPROVED
Applicant to complete activities and remove equipment and materials within 120 days, (90 days to crush materials and 30 days to remove materials);
Payment of relocation costs in the amount of $5,000.00 to Ms. Peterson, entire amount to be paid prior to the issuance of any permit for, or commencement of, rock crushing operation with written proof of payment submitted to Clark County Current Planning Department, care of Mr. Jason Allswang;
Proper permits for operation to be obtained;
No extension of time to be accepted;
All activities limited to 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday;
Private bond to be in place by Monday, February 25, 2008;
Provide 30 day status report to the City of Henderson, staff (administrative review by staff), and the neighboring property owners;

47. ORD-0409-08: INTRODUCED public hearing 04/16/08.
48. ORD-0378-08: INTRODUCED public hearing 04/16/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 3-19-08

22. WS-0998-05 (ET-0410-07) MERCURY DEVELOPMENT, LLC:
     APPROVED: Until January 18, 2010 to commence;

26. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
     HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 1.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-P (Office&amp;Professional) Zone.
     WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) reduce parking; and 2) allow access from a local residential street.
     DESIGN REVIEW for office buildings. Generally located on the north side of Windmill Lane and the west side of Haven Street within Enterprise (description on file).
     APPROVED
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
5 year review on parking;
Basement area to be restricted to storage and gym facilities;
Right-of-way dedication of 30 feet for Haven Street;
Construct full off-sites;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
Drainage study and compliance;
Re-construct any unused driveways with full off-sites;
Vacate any unnecessary rights-of-way and/or easements;
Any applicable vacations to be recordable prior to building permit issuance or applicable map submittal;
Applicant to grant a minimum of 20 foot private access and utility easement to the owner of Assessor Parcel Number 177-09-401-016;
Applicant to also acquire a notarized consent from the owner of Assessor Parcel Number 177-09-401-016.

33. ZC-0047-08 NORCOTT, JAMES T., ET AL:
     HOLDOVER ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-2 (General Commercial) Zone in the MUD-3 Overlay District.
     DESIGN REVIEWS for the following: 1) a convenience store with gasoline pumps; 2) on-premise consumption of alcohol (tavern); and 3) office building with a managers unit. Generally located on the west side of Dean Martin Drive and the north side of Gary Avenue within Enterprise (description on file).
     HELD 09/03/08 per the applicant. Applicant is advised that renotification fees will be required.

34. ZC-0150-08 SUNSET SOUTHWEST, LLC:
     ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 2.5 acres from C-1 (Local Business) (AE-65) Zone to M-D (Designed Manufacturing) (AE-65) Zone.
     WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS to eliminate the requirement for a sidewalk along the 215 Beltway Frontage Road.
     DESIGN REVIEW for an industrial park on 21.6 acres in an M-D (AE-65&amp;AE-70) (Designed Manufacturing) Zone in the CMA Design Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Sunset Road, 835 feet east of Jones Boulevard within Enterprise (description on file).
     APPROVED
No resolution of intent and staff to prepare an ordinance to adopt the zoning;
Applicant is advised that a signage package must be submitted as a design review; and that if a sidewalk is required along the 215 Frontage Road, the site design must still comply with 30.48.660(7).
Apply for and have approved a waver of conditions for ZC-1476-02 in order to allow combining of parcels into 2 separate parcels prior to building permits or final map approval which ever comes first;
Right-of-way dedication as required for 215 Frontage Road by Public Works Design Engineering, and termination of Westwind Road as approved by Clark County Development Services and Department of Aviation;
Apply for and have approved a vacation of Wagon Trail Avenue west of Westwind Road or dedicate Wagon Trail Avenue through the site;
Drainage study and compliance;
Traffic study and compliance;
Traffic study to also address the design and location of driveways;
Construct full off-site improvements;
Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights and traffic control which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.

37. NZC-0037-08 RAMEZAN LARKI ABBASI:
     ZONE CHANGE to reclassify 0.5 acres from R-E (Rural Estates Residential) Zone to C-1 (Local Business) Zone.
     USE PERMIT for an automobile rental facility in a C-1 zone.
     WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for alternative parking lot design.
     DESIGN REVIEW to convert a single family residence to an automobile rental facility. Generally located 200 feet east of Gilespie Street and 300 feet north of Warm Springs Road within Enterprise (description on file).
     APPROVED

44. ZC-0300-06 (WC-0405-07) DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
45. WS-1484-07 DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
46. TM-0016-08 MOUNTAINS EDGE PHASE ii:
     ALL APPROVED

49. UC-1447-07 RED HOT CORNER LLC, ET AL:
     APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following: 1) temporary batch plant; and 2) temporary construction storage on 3.9 acres in an R-T (Manufactured Home Residential) Zone in the MUD-1 Overlay District. Generally located on the south side of Dale Avenue, 1,100 feet west of Las Vegas Boulevard South within Enterprise.
     HELD 04/02/08 per the applicant.

50. AG-0257-08:
     APPROVED.

55. ORD-0262-08:
56. ORD-0263-08:
57. ORD-0288-08:
     ALL INTRODUCED public hearing 04/02/08.

ZONING COMMISSION 3-05-08

17. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
     BCC Approved

30: ZC-1122-07 - CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
TAB approved Zone Change and Design Review: Denied the     Waiver of Development Standards.
     1) reduce setbacks (previously not notified); and
     2) reduce landscaping (previously not notified).
     BCC Approved zone change and design review after it was established that the trail right of way is on the south side of Wigwam (not the north).
     The staff report on this project recommended denial of the waiver of development standards. Their opinion is it sets a poor precedent to allow waivers of developmental standards on the lead project at this corner. Projects that follow on would seek similar waivers. The result is an area where Title 30 standards were not followed. The TAB felt county Title 30 standards should be maintained and the project be designed within these standards. The county did not clearly communicate Title 30 standards during the application process which resulted in several project changes. However, the TAB opinion was this was not sufficient reason to grant a waiver of developmental standards. This project may have to be downsized to fit on the property and meet the code requirements. Two items that could impact this project are the trail dedication that is now required on Wigwam and the moving of underground vaults required by the dedication of additional right-of-way by the county.

35: ZC-0247-03 (WC-0021-08) - AMERICAN CHILD CARE PROPERTIES, LLC:
TAB approved with one recommendation:
     1. Lighting is added to the wall for nighttime safety.
     BCC Approved with nighttime lighting.

43. UC-1418-07 MILANO RESIDENCES, LLC:
     Appeal was withdrawn upon verification of PC NOFA APPEAL USE PERMITS for the following:
     1) reduced setbacks for a hotel; and
     2) kitchens in guestrooms.
     WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following:
     1) permit clear windows of a hotel facade to overlook single family residential yards; and
     2) reduce setbacks for a hotel from a single family residential use.
     DESIGN REVIEW for a condominium hotel on a portion of 2.4 acres in a C-2 (General Commercial) Zone. Generally located on the north side of Cactus Avenue, 300 feet east of Bermuda Road within Enterprise.

48. VS-1469-07 ARIES HOLDINGS, LLC:
     BCC Approved

ZONING COMMISSION 2-20-08

11. WS-0998-05 (ET-0410-07) MERCURY DEVELOPMENT, LLC:
     HELD 03/19/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting.

16. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
     HELD 03/19/08 for the applicant to work with Civil Engineering and the neighbors.

17. ZC-1122-07 CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
     HELD 03/05/08 to rewrite/renotify.

18. ZC-1458-07 KHUSROW ROOHANI FAMILY TRUST:
     APPROVED with many conditions
     2 years to commence the use permits and design review;
     All trees to be a minimum of 24 inch box;
     There shall be a 5 foot wide detached sidewalk on Warm Springs Road with a minimum of 5 feet of landscaping on either side of the sidewalk;
     In addition to landscaping required pursuant to Clark County Code Title 30, there shall be at least 30, twenty foot tall skinned Mexican Fan Palm trees planted within the landscape area along Warm Springs Road;
     In addition to landscaping required pursuant to Clark County Code Title 30, there shall be at least 2, twenty foot tall Date     Palm trees planted on each side of the driveway off Warm Springs Road;
     There shall be 36 inch box Mondel Pine trees or other non-deciduous trees planted 15 feet on center within the landscape area along Mardon Street;
     All rock located in the landscape buffer areas shall be at least medium aggregate decorative rock in a color that matches the color used on the exterior of the commercial buildings;
     There shall be no more than one freestanding sign which shall not exceed 30 feet in height inclusive of architectural features and shall be architecturally compatible with the development of the mixed-use project incorporating tile roof accents and/or ledge stone accents;
     Monument signage not exceeding 8 feet in height is allowed;
     The use of an electronic reader board on any sign or building is prohibited;
     There shall be a design review as a public hearing on any changes;
     Compliance with VS-1402-07;
     Right-of-way dedication to include 50 feet at the east property line with a transition to 45 feet to back of curb for Warm Springs Road and 25 feet back of curb for Mardon Avenue;
     Construct full off-sites;
     Traffic study and compliance, project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering Division approval;
     Drainage study and compliance;
     If required by Regional Transportation Commission, dedicate and construct right-of-way for bus turnouts, including passenger loading/shelter areas in accordance with Regional Transportation Commission standards;
     Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
     Applicant must provide a copy of the recorded noise disclosure form to future buyers/renters, separate from other escrow documents, and provide a copy of the document to the Clark County Department of Aviation;
     Applicant must provide a map to future buyers/renters, as part of the noise disclosure notice, that highlights the project location and associated flight tracks, provided by the Department of Aviation when property sales/leases commence;
     Incorporate an exterior to interior noise level reduction of 30 decibels into the building construction for the habitable space if exceeds 35 feet in height or 25 decibels into the building construction for the habitable space if 35 feet or less in height;

20. ZC-0047-08 NORCOTT, JAMES T., ET AL:
     HELD 03/19/08 per the applicant. TAB approved the zone change as CRT: Denied the Design Review.

28. ZC-1490-07 POST 215, LLC:
     ZONE CHANGE was APPROVED, USE PERMIT, WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS, AND DESIGN REVIEW WERE WITHDRAWN WITHOUT PREJUDICE.
     Design review as a public hearing on final plans;
     Right-of-way dedication to include 25 back of curb for Post Road, 30 feet for Seelinger Street and associated spandrel;
     Construct full off-sites;
     Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;

29. NZC-1470-07 THE STRATTON GROUP:
     APPROVED
     Design elements for commercial space are to be accented into the final drive-thru restaurant facility;
     North and west elevations of are to be architecturally treated similar to the south and west elevation of commercial and retail building with cornice break-ups and color contrasted;
     Roof mounted equipment is to be screened by parapet roof on all buildings and not seen from residential areas or adjacent commercial areas;
     24 hour security cameras on the rear of the buildings;
     Auto related businesses, dealerships, auto parts, repair, or maintenance are prohibited;
     Buildings will be finished on all 4 sides;
     Landscaping along Quarterhorse Lane, as shown on plans;
     Lighting of the parking lot will be directed so there is no overspill on the residences but safely illuminates the parking lot;
     No outside speakers except for the drive thru restaurant reader board;
     Post No Overnight Parking for Trucks 41 Feet and Greater signs;
     All applicable standard conditions for this application type.
     Applicant is advised that the hotel setback from Quarterhorse Lane is to be a minimum of 20 feet from front property line or a waiver of development standards is required.
     Throat depth must a minimum of 65 feet or as approved by the traffic engineer;
     Right-of-way dedications to include 25 feet back of curb for Quarterhorse Lane, 25 back of curb for Agate Avenue and associated spandrel;
     Detached sidewalks will require the granting of necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control;
     Provide paved legal access from Blue Diamond Road;

36. ZC-0300-06 (WC-0405-07) DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
     TAB denied, HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.
37. WS-1484-07 DANVILLE LAND INVESTMENTS, LLC:
     TAB denied, HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.
38. TM-0016-08 MOUNTAINS EDGE PHASE II:
     HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

43. WS-1232-07 CHURCH GOOD SAMARITAN LUTHERAN: HOLDOVER APPEAL WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS
     APPROVED
     Landscape berm is no longer required on Gagnier Boulevard;
     No landscaping is to be provided on the south and west sides of the property;
     A 4 foot high combination stone and wrought iron fence shall be installed along the south property line and along Gagnier Boulevard with the northern 30 feet closest to Windmill Lane to match the existing wall/fence on the east side of Gagnier Boulevard;
     A block wall is not required on the west property line;

44. WT-1455-07 - CHRISTOPHER HOMES: APPEAL WAIVER
     HELD 03/05/08 per the applicant.

ZONING COMMISSION 2-06-08

9. ZC-0970-07 DAVIS BROTHERS INVESTMENTS, LLC:
     HELD at the BCC per applicant.

21. WS-1370-07 BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
     BCC Approved with the withdrawal of Waiver 1. BCC stipulated that speakers should be placed away from residences, and sound absorbing material used.

22. VS-1468-07 CTF LANDS IIC:
     BCC Approved: Oleta to be kept open for access to Jones from the east.

23. WS-1467-07 CTF LANDS IIC:
     BCC Approved: Duneville vacated per request from Parks. Westwind will become N/S route.

ZONING COMMISSION 1-16-08

13. MP-0994-07 RHODES RANCH, G.P.; ET AL:
     HELD 03/05/08 per staff.

16. ZC-0623-07 PEBBLE PINES LLC:
     APPROVED: Design review as a public hearing for any future changes to the plans; Pedestrian realm and landscaping in substantial conformance to plans; Right-of-way dedication to include 45 feet to back of curb for Pebble Lane, 60 feet for Mann Street or demonstrate legal access to Assessor Parcels APN 176-23-501-012 and APN 176-23-501-013, and related spandrels; Drainage study and compliance; Traffic study and compliance; Project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval; Traffic study to also address driveway location, dimension, and design; Construct full off-site improvements; Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.

18. ZC-1122-07 CHINSUK KIM FAMILY TRUST ET AL:
     HELD 02/20/08 per the applicant.

34. WS-1646-05 (ET-0382-07) BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
35. WS-1370-07 BLUE DIAMOND PLAZA, LLC:
     HELD 02/06/08 for the applicant to attend the Enterprise Town Board meeting and work with neighbors.

38. ZC-0799-02 (ET-0354-07) - EQUITY HOLDINGS MANAGEMENT LLC:
     APPROVED: Until December 18, 2011 to complete;

41. VS-1468-07 CFT LANDS LLC: VACATE AND ABANDON
42. WS-1467-07 CFT LANDS LLC: WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS
     HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant.

47. ZC-0511-01 (WC-0367-07) SUNSET V, LLC, ET AL:
48. VS-1348-07 SUNSET III, LLC, ET AL:
     HELD 02/06/08 per the applicant.

55. UC-0931-07 HOPE BAPTIST CHURCH&amp;HUONG THI LE:
     APPROVED:
     The north parcel to be used for a parking lot only and not for any structures or events;
     Design review as a public hearing on Phase II;
     Intense landscape buffer on the north property line of the north parking lot;
     Signage to be installed on the parking lot advising users that the surrounding area is an RNP and allows horses;
     Design, construction, and location of the playground to be addressed with the design review for Phase II;
     Add sound mitigation measures around the playground;
     Parking lot lighting to be low impact and on a timer;
     Chain/bollard light weight gate at the entrance to Gilespie Street;
     Landscaping per plans;
     Move the playground to location as shown on plans;
     Right-of-way dedication to include 40 feet for Gilespie Street;
     Construct full off-sites;
     If detached, sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way;
     Drainage study and compliance;
     Driveways to be a minimum 32 feet with curb returns;
     Reconstruct any unused driveways with full off-sites;

58. UC-1098-07 ROSE STREET REALTY, ET AL:
     5 years to commence;
     No bell or audible sounds from the bell tower;
     Cut-off light fixtures, motion sensors on lighting when feasible;
     Building heights with the exception of the bell tower not to exceed 35 feet;
     Limit outdoor activities to daylight hours;
     No full time daycare;
     No K thru 12 school;
     No events in the parking lot;
     No renting out the parking lot;
     Design review to address lighting;
     Seating capacity to be a maximum of 1,000 people;
     Primary access is to be from Lindell Road;
     Design review as a public hearing;
     Civil Engineering:
     Traffic study to include the entire RNP to be submitted and reviewed with the design review;
     Rural road standards along Mohawk Street;
          No Parking signage to be installed along Mohawk Street adjacent to the property;
     Work with Public Works on traffic calming measures in the area;
     Off-sites to be reviewed with the traffic study and design review;
     Right-of-way dedication to include 35 feet to back of curb for Lindell Road and 25 feet to back of curb for Mohawk Street;
     Drainage study and compliance;
     Traffic study and compliance;
     Project may qualify for an exception to the traffic analysis with Civil Engineering approval;
     Construct full off-site improvements;
     Detached sidewalk will require dedication to back of curb and granting necessary easements for utilities, pedestrian access, streetlights, and traffic control, which may require a vacation of excess right-of-way or execute a License and Maintenance Agreement for non-standard improvements in the right-of-way.
     WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS AND THE DESIGN REVIEW WERE WITHDRAWN.

61. VS-1120-07 SBH LOT OPTION, LLC:
     WITHDRAWN without prejudice.

62. WS-1110-07 MONTE NOVELLA LLC:
     APPROVED
     CC&amp;Rs;to state that 10 foot driveways cannot be used for parking;
     WAIVER OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS #2 WAS WITHDRAWN.

66. WS-1232-07 CHURCH GOOD SAMARITAN LUTHERAN:
     HELD 02/20/08 per the applicant.

ZONING COMMISSION 1-2-08

30. VS-1120-07 SBH LOT OPTION, LLC:
     Held 01/16/08 per the applicant.

33. WS-1247-07 SCHNIPPEL FAMILY L.P.; ET AL:
     APPEAL WAIVERS OF DEVELOPMENT STANDARDS for the following: 1) increase building height; and 2) reduce the garage setback to a drive aisle.
     APPROVED
     3 story buildings located per plans;
     12 month renters moratorium after initial sale of condominiums (added to CC&amp;Rs;);
     Maximum of 10% rental rate after initial sale of condominiums (added to CC&amp;Rs;);
     Provide 8 feet deep driveway depth on loop road;

34. AG-1622-07: That the Board of County Commissioners receives a report on a possible annual amendment to the Enterprise Land Use Plan, a non-action informational item. Report Received and staff given direction.
	</body>
</document>
