<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008615" url="http://www.dailyfinance.com/2011/12/05/mcdonalds-turns-on-a-dime-to-beat-san-franciscos-happy-meal-la/" time="2012-07-13-02:04" support="1" score="0.0012044694839691255" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s Turns On a Dime to Beat San Francisco&apos;s Happy Meal Law ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s Turns On a Dime to Beat San Francisco&apos;s Happy Meal Law - DailyFinance">
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>When San Francisco outlawed free toys with meals ... their child at a Mc Donald&apos;s or any other fast food restaurant? ... Got bad credit? Card issuers want you; Where have all the ...</description>
	<body>
		AOL MAIL 
 You might also like:  AOL Jobs ,  AOL Real Estate  and  More 
 


 DailyFinance 
 Home Saving 
 Savings Experiment Consumer Ally Economizer Family Money College Finance Fantastic Freebies 
 Spending 
 Credit Cards Credit Reports Debt Retail Technology 
 Investing Planning 
 Power of Planning Retirement IRA Center Calculators Insurance Banking 
 Taxes 
 Tax Center Tax Tools&amp;Resources 
 Jobs 
 Search Jobs Get Career Advice 
 Real Estate 
 Homes for Sale Mortgages 
 Questions or Feedback ? 
 
McDonald&apos;s Turns On a Dime to Beat San Francisco&apos;s Happy Meal Law
 By Alyce Lomax, The Motley Fool Posted 10:45AM 12/05/11 Posted under: McDonald&apos;s , Retail , Stocks in the News , Food Share 
 A Happy Meal without a toy is, well, just a meal. However, McDonald&apos;s ( MCD ) has found a clever way to keep peddling Happy Meals in San Francisco, despite the city&apos;s having outlawed free promotional toys with meals that fail to meet certain nutritional requirements.

The trinket-banning law went into effect Thursday, and here&apos;s McDonald&apos;s response: Parents will have to request the toys, which will add an extra dime to Happy Meal prices. McDonald&apos;s will then donate those dimes to the Ronald McDonald House of San Francisco. (McDonald&apos;s Ronald McDonald House program provides support to families of sick children, as well as basic medical and dental care in some communities.)

Believe it or not, McDonald&apos;s Happy Meals actually do meet the law&apos;s requirement of having less than 600 calories. (They contain 500 calories.) The issue is that Happy Meals fall short of the law&apos;s standard for fruit and vegetable quotas. The San Francisco Department of Public Health doesn&apos;t count french fries as a vegetable.
 
McDonald&apos;s critics are correct to raise awareness of such matters as marketing to children and health issues with popular fast-food fare. However, picking on Happy Meals is a bit joyless, not to mention insulting to the entire concept of parental choice in kids&apos; diets.

Although CNN quoted San Francisco City and County Supervisor Eric Mar acknowledging parental responsibility amid America&apos;s childhood obesity epidemic, he also mentioned fast-food companies&apos; benefiting from kids&apos; &quot;pester power.&quot; I&apos;m not sure what it says about America&apos;s future if &quot;pester power&quot; might be considered too &quot;powerful&quot; to combat.

McDonald&apos;s has found a way to preserve the toys and parental choice, and it&apos;s not even seeking to profit off the nominal fee it&apos;s now charging for the toys to avoid providing them &quot;free.&quot; The fast-food giant may have made a brilliant checkmate here -- and has certainly painted its overzealous critics in a negative light.

 Motley Fool analyst Alyce Lomax does not own shares of McDonald&apos;s .


 Get info on stocks mentioned in this article :
 MCD Manage Your Portfolio 
 
 
From Our Partners:
 More Articles on AOL Real Estate More Articles on AOL Jobs 
More On DailyFinance:
 Junk Food: The Pariah That&apos;s Replacing Tobacco Why Mickey Mouse Is Shaping Up on Childhood Obesity Olympic Chief Bites Tongue on McDonalds, Coke Sponsorships 
 Tagged: free toys , FreeToys , Happy Meal , Health , law , McDonald&apos;s , nutrition , Ronald McDonald House Charities , san francisco , SanFrancisco 
 Share Getty Images 
 CLOSER TO A BAILOUT? FHA&apos;s Mortgage Delinquencies Soar - CNNMoney Dimon Faces Round Two Before Congress - FOXBusiness HEALTH CARE REFORM: 5 Investing Scenarios of Obamacare Ruling - InvestorPlace The Biggest Sign of a China Bubble - The Motley Fool THE FED&apos;S SUMMER SEQUEL: Operation Twist 2 - IBTimes How to Stomp Out Pesky Travel Fees - CBS MoneyWatch FedEx Earnings Don&apos;t Deliver - 24/7 Wall St. 
 
Add a Comment
 Sign in» Add a Comment Type your comment here *0 / 3000 Character Maximum Submit 256 
336 Comments
 Filter by: Newest Oldest ekarydas 
Yeah for Mc D&apos;s!!!!! The triumvant of Disney, Coke and McD&apos;s is slowly but surely turning the tummy&apos;s and the hearts of billions into American Rose Colored Glasses Wearing Clones. Good? Bad? Not sure if it even matters. Slowly but surely just as the ice carved out the Grand Canyon, our&quot;American&quot;style of optimism, ( watch Little House on the Prairie, or Star Trek if you don&apos;t get it) will become the&quot;Standard&quot;. People GET REAL there is a mickey D&apos;s on the ChampsÉlysées!! They have Disney! and they guzzle Coke! There are many there who are horrified but you can&apos;t stop the tide. Big Brother? Maybe. But I&apos;m tired of the gloom that is so pervasive, especially our two coasts, but particularly in the north east. Give me a little Pollyanna! I want to picnic in the shadows of bushes carved into amimation characters, listening to the piped in music (Its a Small World After All) while eating McNuggets, Big Mac&apos;s and Fries, with a Super Sized Coke ( diet for me LOL!!). Afterward we can all join hands and sing the Coca-cola Holiday ( see I can do PC) Song,&quot;If I Could Give the World a Coke.&quot;Then you&apos;re all invited to my place to watch EVERY Christmass movie ever made. A few doses of make believe ala&quot;Disney,&quot;and some good old McD&apos;s might be the only way to a common ground and with a few waves of the Fairy Godmother&apos;s wand
maybe we can&quot;all just get along.&quot;
 December 07 2011 at 3:21 PM Report abuse Permalink +1 rate up rate down Reply cpo1514 
So how is the Mc Lib food store doing????? Any IPO ??? Thought so.... tough to do ... easy to cry&amp;carry a sign....what do the occupiers eat??? JAIL FOOD in SF,,,,
 December 07 2011 at 10:44 AM Report abuse Permalink +1 rate up rate down Reply maa2626 
7$ tax on all drive thru food, if you get out and walk in no tax. 7$ to the money owed china.
 December 06 2011 at 6:28 PM Report abuse Permalink rate up rate down Reply obliterait 
lOTS OF INSECTICIDE ON THOSE VEGIES AND FRUITS
 December 06 2011 at 6:19 PM Report abuse Permalink rate up rate down Reply 1 reply to obliterait&apos;s comment savemycountry911 
so we may as well eat the fat and sugar.
 December 06 2011 at 8:21 PM Report abuse Permalink +2 rate up rate down Reply pomonaaj 
Why is everyone giving Mc D a hard time. They make burgers and fries. They never said they were going to be a health resaurant. They are not force feeding this stuff to you either.
 December 06 2011 at 5:07 PM Report abuse Permalink +6 rate up rate down Reply 1 reply to pomonaaj&apos;s comment savemycountry911 
I like the woman who told the interviewer,&quot;If I wanted healthfood, I&apos;d go to the healthfood store.&quot;
 December 06 2011 at 8:01 PM Report abuse Permalink +1 rate up rate down Reply rchris5453 
Love it ! CA. is willing to cut off it&apos;s nose to spite it&apos;s face at any time and for no reason ! As a result of this short sighted Liberal approach to everything, the entire state is bankrupted ! You can thank your representatives for this starting with Pelosi, Finestein, Boxer, Sanchez, Brown and a host of others with no clue ! You have voted for them for years starting in local governments than moving on to the state and then to national positions and got screwed all the way. You now have to live with the results of your ignorance.
 December 06 2011 at 4:58 PM Report abuse Permalink +7 rate up rate down Reply 1 reply to rchris5453&apos;s comment savemycountry911 
There must be something in the water in California.
 December 06 2011 at 8:02 PM Report abuse Permalink +1 rate up rate down Reply csmjwoody 
What a great move by Mc Donald&apos;s. Obesity in America&apos;s and other countries children is not caused by Mc Donapd&apos;s but the lazy people wh refuse to admit their own choices are the real cause. When a parent goes into a store and buys mainly junk food because they are to damm lazy to plan and cook for themselves and their children they get fat children and they themselves become couch potatoes because it hurts them to move for a little exercise. Years ago when I worked at a Mc Donald&apos;s the only people I saw there on a regular basis were the elderly who came in early in the morning for coffee and visiting with their friends. The majority drank only coffee while they sat and chatted. The majority of parents cannot afford to feed their children at Mc Donald&apos;s on a regular basis like the guy who ate every meal there and supersized for 30 days intentioonally to gain weight for an article. What children eat all day long at home and, their grandparents, and other places they go including the meals fed to them at school are the cause of the obesity along with not being active children. Cut the time spent playing games on the couch, watching television and just plain being lazy and they will lose the weight because an active child will burn off the calories they pick up by a visit to Mc Donald&apos;s when parents are in town shopping and cannot go right home or the occassional stop when they travel on a weekend. Who do you know that would spend between $15.00 to $20.00 everyday to feed their child at a Mc Donald&apos;s or any other fast food restaurant? I don&apos;t know who these idiots in San Francisco are but I would bet they are responsible for something else that was bad for the people of America. Namely Pelosiitis.
 December 06 2011 at 4:53 PM Report abuse Permalink +10 rate up rate down Reply David 
Typical for California. A state that issue&apos;s Pot card&apos;s oh, sorry (Medical Marijuana) card&apos;s to anyone that want&apos;s one more or less. Please don&apos;t come back with the pain and disability crap...But they want to stop kid&apos;s from getting a toy in their in their meal.....I think these people need to stop smoking to much (medicine)... Do Californian&apos;s realizr that most of the country do consider them more or less NUTCASE&apos;S? Now that&apos;s not for ALL, just nutcase&apos;s like these....
 December 06 2011 at 4:38 PM Report abuse Permalink +9 rate up rate down Reply wuzzy1959 
The obesity problem in children is not McDonald&apos;s, Jack in the box or any fast food chains fault it is the PARENTS fault. It is the parents responsibility to keep an eye on what their children eat. If parents would cook at least 3-4 meals a week at home there would be no problem. I know some people are thinking well I work all day and I am tired when I get home and fast food is so much easier. Well guess what my parents worked when I was growing up and we at 95% of our meals at home.
 December 06 2011 at 4:27 PM Report abuse Permalink +9 rate up rate down Reply mindbender48 
Well now we know for sure, McDs just want your money they are not interested in providing a healthier meal for kids. I guess I had my last McDonalds and I ate ther at least three to fur times a week with the breakfasts or lunch. Goodby McDonalds
 December 06 2011 at 4:25 PM Report abuse Permalink -12 rate up rate down Reply 2 replies to mindbender48&apos;s comment Courtney 
Did you not read the article the toy is an option and the dime you pay for the toy is going to their charity
 December 06 2011 at 4:52 PM Report abuse Permalink +7 rate up rate down Reply 1 reply to Courtney&apos;s comment cpo1514 
Courtney... reading is an obstacle for these lefties.... doesn t fit the agenda. Comphrension is a real obstacle... doesnt get taught in any public school...Need pictures of fat&amp;thin folks you know.... the freedom to choose???? (point&amp;chose, pass&amp;fail) Socialism&amp;99% do nothings...
 December 07 2011 at 10:38 AM Report abuse Permalink +2 rate up rate down savemycountry911 
McDs has salad and apple slices. Get those if you are a healthfood nut.
 December 06 2011 at 8:03 PM Report abuse Permalink +3 rate up rate down Reply Load more comments 
 manage My Portfolios


 Track Your Investments Here! 
See why so many people use the DailyFinance portfolio tool as the cornerstone of their investing strategy.
 Sign In or Register Now advertisement 
Most Popular Stories

 1 
 New McDonald&apos;s CEO&apos;s Grand Plan Involves a Lot of Chicken 
 2 
 Brides Say &apos;Yes&apos; to Selling Their Dress ... Before the Wedding! 
 3 
 Get the Best Bargain on Perfect Pillows -- Savings Experiment 
 4 
 The LIBOR Scandal Explained in One Simple Infographic 
 5 
 Ousted Duke Energy CEO Earns Up to $44.4 Million for a Few Hours Work 
 
 
DailyFinance Wire

 Merchants May Win the Right to Charge Credit Card Users More A Farewell to Marvin Traub: The Retail Genius Who Changed How You Shop Olympic Chief Bites Tongue on McDonalds, Coke Sponsorships 8 Things to Never Keep in Your Wallet 8 Signs Your Identity Has Been Compromised Listen Up, Ladies: Tips for Closing the Financial Gender Gap New Jobless Claims Fall Sharply to Four-Year Low 
 More DailyFinance Stories 
Newswire
 AP CNN 24/7 WallSt 
 China&apos;s economic slowdown painful despite... Appeals court tosses antitrust claim over ATM... Possible pilot shortage raises safety concerns Summary Box: Yahoo shareholders grill interim... All eyes on JPMorgan as banks report earnings Ex-investigators for HP sentenced in fraud case Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight... 
 
 Young dad, $15,000 in credit card debt 30-year mortgage rate falls to record 3.56% Why health care costs keep rising 700,000 homeowners no longer underwater New foreclosures jump 9% in second quarter $400,000 portfolio, too many holdings Homes lost for as little as $400 in back taxes 3 tuition bills, only $35,000 saved 
 More from CNNMoney 
 24/7 Wall St. Closing Bell — July 12, 2012: Markets Continue Slide on No Signs of Easing Cheniere Lands $3.4 Billion Credit Facility to Build Natural Gas Export Facility US Drought Worsens Despite Some Rain Gambling Revenues Continue to Fall in Nevada Can Activist Investors Fix Procter&amp;Gamble? Take A Poll!!! Groupon Shareholders Stuck Where They Are, CEO&amp;All Boeing Gets Order for 150 Planes from United Groupon, Zynga at Post-IPO Lows 
 More from 24/7 Wall St. 
Follow Us

 Facebook Twitter RSS To Go 
 
Compare Mortgage Rates
 Mortgage Rates by Zillow 
Headlines From DailyFinance Partners
 
 BEWARE JPMORGAN&apos;S PROFIT Stocks falter on global growth fears,... Wells Fargo in $175M unfair lending... 
 More CNNMoney.com 
 Sale considered of ING Japanese unit Yahoo acknowledges attack by hackers Peregrine probe eyes accounts in Iowa 
 More Financial Times 
 Markets Await JPMorgan &apos;Whale&apos; Report,... China&apos;s 2012 Growth May Be Slowest... More Americans Think Rich Deserve Their... 
 More from CNBC.com 
 5 Reasons China&apos;s Problems Signal... Why It Pays to Delay Social Security The Case for European Blue Chips 
 More at SmartMoney 
 Five Steps to Effective Investing as a... Estimate Cost of Utilities on Your Next... Blah Job Stats Deliver Lovely Mortgage... 
 More Fox Business 
 How to stop unwanted robocalls Consumer Reports Index: Americans... Who serves the best pancakes? 
 More from Consumer Reports 
 
 Company PAYS You To Go On Vacation...A... Mitt Romney&apos;s Own 2002 Testimony... Worn By Team USA But Made In China? 
 More from Huffington Post 
 Big Oil Sees Big Growth for Renewable... 2012 Maryland Clean Energy Summit Don&apos;t Ban Coal for Electricity... 
 More from AOL Energy 
 Peyton Manning&apos;s $5 Million Denver... Wells Fargo to Pay $125 Million to... David Hoffman of Marin County, Calif.,... 
 More from AOL Real Estate 
 Ex-Wet Seal Managers Claim The Company... Yoga Teacher Gets Fired After Glaring... Customer Service Rep Allegedly Tells... 
 More from AOL Jobs 
 DailyFinance 
Business News

 Main Autos Books Charity Columns Crime Food Green Media People Travel Jobs Real Estate 
 
Personal Finance

 Debt Insurance Credit College Finance Retirement Recalls Taxes 
 
Investing

 Portfolios Media Credit Stocks in the News ETF&apos;s Earnings 
 
Our Partners

 Tech News Small Business Real Estate 24/7 Wall St Autoblog 
 
 DailyFinance Sitemap | Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Trademarks | HELP | Advertise With Us 

©Copyright 2012 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
