<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008980" url="http://www.theblacksheeponline.com/article/how-to-tackle-ocean-shitty" time="2012-07-13-02:23" support="1" score="0.0015946860758311115" bingtitle="How to Tackle Ocean Shitty - The Black Sheep Online" webtitle="How to Tackle Ocean Shitty - The Black Sheep Online">
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>... be a block from Dumsers, the grossest looking fast food restaurant ... parents also come in handy- they love to throw a ... here&apos;s a shout out to all my hot pants now in storage.</description>
	<body>
		Features 
 All Articles Downloaders Full Issue Entertainment Interviews Movies Music Sex Sports Top 10 Videos 
 Nightlife 
 Alcohol Reviews Bar Grids Drinking Games Party Pics Shoutouts 
 Submit 
 Article Ideas Job App Party Pics Shoutouts Videos 
 

 
 Clemson College of Charleston Delaware Florida Florida State Georgia Illinois Illinois State Indiana Iowa Iowa State Kentucky Lousiana State Michigan Michigan State Minnesota North Carolina Ole Miss Penn State South Carolina VCU Virginia Virginia Tech Western Michigan 
 
 Travel Blog: Awful Souvenirs What You Can Do Without Power Real World Problems: The Truth About Graduating Top 10: People To Avoid At the Gym Monogamy: Is There Such a Thing? 
Browse :
 Latest | Popular 
How to Tackle Ocean Shitty
 

Although Ocean City, Maryland should never be labeled a“classy”vacation spot, being there sure does make you feel like a classy person in comparison to everyone else inhabiting its borders. Whether it’s witnessing those-who-should-remain-fully-clothed flaunting tramp stamps or bikers shouting obscenities at you, OC bears the trashiest of the trash. Beach weekers crowd the motels and beat down houses with blacked out kids, sloppy mothers stumble through Seacrets hoping to be 18 again and slimy old men creep on tweens roaming the boardwalk with henna tattoos. 

 

Despite the well known reputation and nickname“Ocean Shitty,”this tourist spot still draws families from all over the east coast. Although the tattoos, cheap vodka and belly fat are endless, there is a way to take on Ocean Shitty with some dignity, while still having a good time. 

 

 Stay in your parent’s beach condo  

If you’re lucky enough to have parents who love a nice cold beer after body surfing in the ocean or while enjoying a summer read in the sand, you’re lucky enough. Because that means as soon as the funds are available, they’re buying an ocean front condo for the fam. Even though the condo may be next to the Castle in the Sand hotel where all the red neck alcoholics go to get away from their kids and get wasted every weekend, it’s a beachfront condo all the same. Mine happens to also be a block from Dumsers , the grossest looking fast food restaurant that’s been clogging trailer park toilets since 1978. If you can block out the obnoxious motorcycle noise and drunken idiots roaming the streets, OC does have some gems that will make your time worth the trouble. Just so long as you can take shelter in the condo. 

 

 Avoid the crowds  

Waiting for a table at a less than satisfactory chain restaurant is no fun with bratty kids back talking to their winey, loud parents and watching a teenage couple eat each other’s faces with more piercings than you can count. Instead, opt for a non-chain restaurant like On the Bay and go at an off time. Instead of hitting up Seacrets on its busiest, trashiest night, opt for a couple bottles of wine and a moonlight walk on the beach with your friends or significant other. Instead of hitting up happy hour at 5, bring chips and guacamole down to the beach with a cooler of yuenglings and beach chairs. Check out the surfers who take over the beach after the lifeguards leave (unfortunately a few of them will sport beer bellies that disable them from balancing on the board, but that’s even more entertaining). 

 

 Use your friends 

Got a friend with a beachfront mansion in Bethany? Or a cousin with jet skis on the bay? The best part about OC is that everyone you know vacations there. It is extremely crucial to not only gather with friends while at the beach, but also to &quot;politely ask them&quot; for their prime landscape and resources. Jet skis, boats, pools, hot tubs, guest rooms, you name it. Or maybe your friend is bar ending at The Turtle- free drinks anyone? Friend’s parents also come in handy- they love to throw a good crab feast. 

 

Although some people in this beach town are an embarrassment to the human race, they are sure to bring entertainment to you and your vacationing pals. The conversations sparked by their lifestyle choices are all a part of the Ocean Shitty experience, which is never a boring time. 


 

June 29, 2011 | By Stephanie Wight Tag Cloud: Delaware Featured Articles 
Delaware Articles You Might Like

\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\
 
 Top 10: Places to Study 
 
 Getting to Know the Techno Bus Driver 
 
 Not Real Life 
 
Featured Articles You Might Like

\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\
 
 Top 10: Reasons You Should Have Watched USA Women&apos;s Soccer 
 
 Great Bros In History: Abroham Drinkin’ 
 
 Scaring off the Rebound 
 
Stay Connected
 Follow @theblacksheep99 
Drinkage
 
 Weekly Beer Geek: Crisp Apple Hard Cider 
 
 Weekly Beer Geek: Lake Erie Monster Imperial IPA 
 
 Booze Review: Monaco Vodka Cocktails 
 Subscribe with facebook 
Vocab
 
Egregarious
 
The act of being funny and affable to the point of awkwardness.
 
Samantha had to break up with Julian because of his egregarious nature. The final straw was when he fondled Jessica’s breast because Jessica playfully asked him to.
 
Party Pics
 
Most Recent Shoutouts
 
Illinois

To the girls of 504, 

These past two years have been the greatest times of our lives. The noise violations, the 50&apos;&apos; flatsc...
 
Illinois

Dear Mike &quot;Motor Boater&quot; Rottar,

Good job on your internshit, now its time for you to return to being drunk, obnoxiously lo...
 
Western Michigan

Howdy virgin girl from sexless in the city lets get super weird
 
Illinois

Dear Hotdog boy from the Haus stall,
 I&apos;ve been patiently waiting in the Firehaus bathroom with a package of fresh hot dogs ...
 
Michigan State

Jonathan, we found your one hitter in the tent this morning. Good luck with the disc golf tournament!
 
Illinois State

Many try to copy Fat Jacks Draft Selection, all have Failed!
 
Western Michigan

Dear ex roommate. You still owe me $50 for that microwave you stole on your way out. It&apos;s been four months, dude. Hurry it up....
 
Illinois

To the manager at penn station you have the hugest breasts ive ever seen before. I would like to c then.
Xoxo the philly chee...
 
Illinois

To the nice couple that walked me home when I broke my wrist, lost my jacket, phone, and keys, Thank you. And sorry I tried pu...
 
Illinois State

Word to the drunks out there, leave the bouncer alone. We don&apos;t want to talk to you. 
Regards, Gavin
 
Illinois

To Blaise @ Clys,
Idk if your gay, bc u are a Pike, but after about raping me on the dance floor and begging to come back to...
 
Illinois

To the DJ that spins at Firehaus on Thursday: You can&apos;t clap along to every song and you need to lay down some beats that make...
 
Michigan State

Dear dodgers fan from San Fran,
I still love you. Also, Giants are way better. 
Love,
Girl who shares your bed every Saturd...
 
Illinois

To all of fans of Illinois Athletics, stop being so obnoxiously arogant. Our athletics that matter Football/Basketball have ac...
 
Illinois State

Dear dumb girl who stole my fake. You&apos;re a bitch. Seriously. Sincerely, I just want to party.
 
Western Michigan

Shoutout to my favorite Ginger Paige O&apos;Shea!
 
Michigan State

To the DJ at Ricks last Saturday... Wearing expensive headphones does not make you an artist. Just play the songs for more th...
 
Michigan State

Owning a dragon pillow pet is not acceptable for a grown man to have on his bed. Hide that shit.
-Eggz
 
Virginia Tech

First day of class... gloomy days ahead fellow hokies... here&apos;s a shout out to all my hot pants now in storage. Think I might ...
 
Michigan State

Hey girl, let&apos;s just call you M. I can&apos;t believe you gave yourself up to me COMPLETELY SOBER after telling me you weren&apos;t a sl...
 
 Home About Us Contact Us Advertise 
 
 Mobile Campus Jobs Terms of Use 
 © 2011 theblacksheeponline.com 
 Tweet
	</body>
</document>
