<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008274" url="http://www.toolkit.com/small_business_guide/sbg.aspx?nid=P01_0380" time="2012-07-13-01:46" support="4" score="0.0033998532445225892" bingtitle="Business Owner&apos;s Toolkit: How to Quantify Your Goals" webtitle="Business Owner&apos;s Toolkit: How to Quantify Your Goals">
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>Eventually, you&apos;ll probably want to put those goals together in the form of a ... If you&apos;re opening a fast-food restaurant, to say that you want to be bigger than McDonald ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign Up My 
 Toolkit   
 
 
 
 Home Small Business Guide Business Tools Podcast News Toolkit Store 

 
Small Business Guide
 
 Premium 
 Membership
 
Register to become a Toolkit Premium Member for 
 only $39/year.
Pick any three:

 Business Book Library Corporate Forms Library Financial Planning Toolkit Government Forms Library Legal Forms Library SEO Audit Toolkit 411 Toolkit Publicity Pack 
 
 Free 
 Membership
 Register to become a Business 
 Owner&apos;s Toolkit Member for free!

 Learn More 
 

 

 Toolkit Newsletter sign up

Enter your e-mail address:
 

 
 Small Business Guide
 Thousands of pages of information and tools to help you start, run and grow your business.


Check out the Table of Contents .
 
 Business Tools
 
 Asset Protection Business Finance Employee Management And more... 

 Learn More 
 DirectoryM Local Guides   All Guides 
  Alabama 
  Alaska 
  Arizona 
  Arkansas 
  California 
  Colorado 
  Connecticut 
  DC 
  Delaware 
  Florida 
  Georgia 
  Hawaii 
  Idaho 
  Illinois 
  Indiana 
  Iowa 
  Kansas 
  Kentucky 
  Louisiana 
  Maine 
  Maryland 
  Massachusetts 
  Michigan 
  Minnesota 
  Mississippi 
  Missouri 
  Montana 
  Nebraska 
  Nevada 
  New Hampshire 
  New Jersey 
  New Mexico 
  New York 
  North Carolina 
  North Dakota 
  Ohio 
  Oklahoma 
  Oregon 
  Pennsylvania 
  Rhode Island 
  South Carolina 
  South Dakota 
  Tennessee 
  Texas 
  Utah 
  Vermont 
  Virginia 
  Washington 
  West Virginia 
  Wisconsin 
  Wyoming 
 Business Card Exchange Legal Services Quote Center 
 Promote your business and network with other business owners. [Learn More] 
 Keyword: Industry: State:   Accounting/Finance Advertising/Public Relations Arts/Entertainment/Publishing Banking/Mortgage Clerical/Administrative Construction/Facilities Customer Service Education/Training Engineering/Architecture Healthcare Hospitality/Travel Human Resources Insurance Internet/New Media Law Enforcement/Security Legal Management Consulting Manufacturing/Operations Marketing Non-Profit Pharmaceutical/Biotech Real Estate Restaurant/Food Service Retail Sales Technology Telecommunications Transportation/Logistics Other (Specify) AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT D.C. DE FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY 
 Need 
 legal assistance? Rocket Lawyer can help. We’ve partnered with them to 
 provide you with access to legal information, software, free legal forms and 
 more. 
 
 Vendor Price Quotes 

Get Free quotes from leading vendors. No obligations. [ Learn 
 more ] 
 Categories: 
 Select a Vendor/Service Answering Service Call Center Services Credit Card Processing Website/E-Commerce Design Factoring Services Fulfillment and Distribution Incorporation Services List Brokers Payroll Services Business Phone Systems POS Systems Search Engine Optimization Services Telemarketing Warehousing/Storage Services 
 
 Small Business Guide     Starting Your Business     Do You Have What It Takes?     What Are Your Goals?     How to Quantify Your Goals Share 
 this!     Print      Share this article 
                            
 Close [x]   
 
 Back Index Next 
 
How to Quantify Your Goals
 
Quantifying your goals can be a long process. You&apos;ll have to gather a lot more information before you&apos;re ready to set specific targets. Eventually, you&apos;ll probably want to put those goals together in the form of a business plan .

 Guidelines 

But before we move on to the process of getting that information, let&apos;s take a look at some of the guidelines you should follow when quantifying your goals:

 Be specific Establish targets that can be easily measured, and use numbers as targets whenever possible. For example, you may set a goal of selling your goods or services across a particular number of counties or states, having a certain number of employees, or reaching a particular level of sales. Tie those numbers to specific time frames (within six months, within two years, within 10 years, etc.). Be realistic Having high expectations is great, but make sure that you establish targets that are reasonable and potentially achievable. If you&apos;re opening a fast-food restaurant, to say that you want to be bigger than McDonald&apos;s within six months is not realistic. Be aggressive You can be realistic and still aim high. Don&apos;t set goals that are too easily achieved; also, set both short-term and long-term goals. If, after six months in business, you accomplish all of your goals, then what? Don&apos;t sell yourself short; if you want to be bigger than McDonald&apos;s within 20 years, go for it. Be consistent Beware of inadvertently setting inconsistent goals. For example, a goal of growing fast enough to have three employees within two years might be inconsistent with a goal of earning a particular amount of money if the cost of adding the employees ends up temporarily reducing your income below the target level. There is nothing wrong with having both goals. Just be aware that the potential conflict exists, and establish priorities among your goals so that you&apos;ll know which ones are most important to you. 

 Getting Started. 

Some people have a hard time setting goals because they just don&apos;t know where to start. If that applies to you, try this exercise. Start with an easily quantifiable goal. Start with the amount of money you&apos;ll need to earn in order to cover your living expenses since, no matter what, you&apos;ll need to make enough to make ends meet. Only when you have met that need can you begin to look to other goals.


 
 
In the Business Tools area is a living expenses form that you can use to set your first goal. It will help you establish what your family&apos;s financial needs are, so that you can set realistic business financial goals.
 
 

 

 
 Back Index Next 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Contact | Terms | Privacy | Copyright | About Us | Advertising | Media Kit 

© 1995- 2012 Toolkit Media Group. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
