<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008373" url="http://www.hotfrog.com.au/Products/Restaurants/NSW/SURRY-HILLS" time="2012-07-13-01:51" support="3" score="0.005934051190996487" bingtitle="Restaurants in SURRY HILLS - Hot Frog - Your Australian Business ..." webtitle="Restaurants in SURRY HILLS">
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000693" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001258" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>Simple yet elegant Italian food put on the menu board ... we are committed to serving up the finest cup of ... Pizzareia Italian Restaurant Pizza Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Login Login using 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Restaurants in SURRY HILLS
 Restaurants   New South Wales   SURRY HILLS (188) 1 - 40 of 188 businesses results Sponsored links Surry Hills Restaurants 
 Special Occasion? Find Restaurants in Surry Hills with Yellow Pages® 
 www.yellowpages.com.au/ Surry - Hills Sugarcane Restaurant 
 Experience Our Delicious South East Asian Menu. Group Bookings. Sydney. 
 www.sugarcane restaurant .com.au/ Restaurants Surry Hills 
 Book Restaurants in Surry Hills Free, Instant&amp;Earn Reward Points 
 www.dimmi.com.au/ Surry _ Hills CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design 
Surry Hills, NSW
 0414 609 182 
CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design has been designing quality shops, cafes, restaurants , bars and clubs within budget for over twenty years. CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design is an accepted shop designer within all major…
 
 Restaurant Design Cafes Pubs Bar Design 
 Your Order Corporate Catering Sydney 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9281 5114 
Your Order offers a simple and easy to use ordering platform linking Australia&apos;s Largest Corporate businesses.
 
 Catering Service Caterers Gourmet Catering Catering 
 Cheeky Food Group 
Surry Hills, NSW
 1300 785365 
…or conference theme. Amaze yourselves as you sizzle, flambé and sauté your way into creating your very own restaurant. You’ll laugh, bond, relax and have fun as you whip up a magnificent feast to eat and enjoy together…
 
 Caterers Catering Functions cooking lessons 
 Vini 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9698 5131 
Simple yet elegant Italian food put on the menu board daily. Over 25 Italian wines available by the glass. Weekly regional dinners on Tuesdays.
 
 Italian Restaurant dinner lunch Functions 
 Thai Tha Poh Takeout Restaurant 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 (02) 96992829 
Busy, friendly Thai restaurant with spectacular and reasonably priced food. Mains $12 - $17. 10% discount for takeaways. This is one fast and faboulous eatery, although there are no shortcuts with the food... Read the r…
 
 Thai Restaurant Takeout Takeaway 
 Bridget Flowers&amp;Event Design 
Surry Hills, NSW
 0418 968 240 
Bridget designs and creates unique flowers for Weddings, Corporate, Restaurants , Hotels, Cafes, Offices and Any Event. Working in the Hospitality and Event Industry for over 16 years,Bridget offers her clientsexperience…
 
 Wedding Catering Food Catering Food&amp;Catering Restaurants&amp;Hotels 
 Be Mine Bar And Restaurant 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02)93604070 
&quot;New Orleans food is as delicious as the less criminal forms of sin.&quot; (Mark Twain, 1884) Savour genuine New Orleans style cuisine in the fun loving, relaxed, yet sophisticated atmosphere of Be Mine Bar Restaurant where…
 
 International Restaurant Restaurant Menus Bar Restaurant dinner 
 Casapueblo Restaurant 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9319 6377 
Great food, excellent value and friendly casual atmosphere is what we are all about.  We are open Thursday to Saturday after 6.30pm. Tapas banquet is our specialty and it is ideal for groups as you will savour over 15 d…
 
 Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Services 
 Booking Angel 
Surry Hills, NSW
 1300 367 148 
Leading online reservation system by Booking Angel. Click here to learn about the best online restaurant reservation system
 
 Restaurant restaurant reservations Restaurant Bookings 
 Buzz Consulting 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9699 2444 
Ads We do it with a magical mix of professionalism, enthusiasm, ten years experience and knowledge plus a sprinkle of glamour and style thrown in to spice things up The BUZZ girls take the bull by the horns an…
 
 Food Celebrities Entertainment Alcohol 
   BILLS 
Surry Hills, NSW
 + 61 2 9360 4762 
There are many people for whom a trip to Sydney is not complete without a visit to one of Bill Granger&apos;s restaurants . Breakfast at bills has become a sydney institution
 
 Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets Food&amp;Beverage Services Cuisine 
 Medina Apartments&amp;Hotels 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 9356 1000 
Medina Apartment Hotels are located in 19 city locations across Australia.  Medina offer a selection of 1, 2&amp;3 bedroom apartments as well as studio rooms.
 
 Theatre Restaurants rooms Hotel Packages Studio Rooms 
 The Mint Partners 
Surry Hills, NSW
 +61 2 9331 8115 
PR and Public relations. The Mint Partners specialise in strategic lifestyle communications producing outstanding results for clients. The team is led by Brett Galvin and Genevieve Taubman (Campbell)
 
 Chefs Beverage Wine Semillon 
 Taste Baguette Group 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 92817228 
At taste we are committed to serving up the finest cup of coffee
 
 Baguette Coffee Bread 
 Grant Cusack 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02)9280 4310 
Grant Cusack&amp;Associates give advice and assisitance in respect of any matters pertaining to the Liquor Act and Regulation,Gaming and Regulation and Associated Acts as well as Council applications and Land&amp;Enviroment…
 
 Wine Bars Venues liquor licence Gaming Machines 
 BENCHMARQUE Hospitality&amp;Event Recruit… 
Surry Hills, NSW
 02 9036 1800 
BENCHMARQUE is a specialist provider ofcasual staffingand permanent recruitment solutions to Sydney&apos;s Hospitality&amp;Event industry. Established since 2005, we continue to “ raise the bar”  with the highest standards…
 
 Party Supplies&amp;Services Catering Service Wedding Catering Catering Services 
 Medina On Crown Executive 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 8302 1000 
All the space of an apartmentâ?¦with hotel service! Find the best online deals, offers and packages across Australia. Book now on the official Medina site.
 
 Theatre Restaurants rooms Hotel Packages discount hotel 
 Morgans Hotel 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 +61 (0)2 8354 3444 
Positioned in the heart of Sydney, close by The Rocks, The Morgan Hotel is the ideal base from which to explore Australia&apos;s most vibrant city
 
 Boutique Hotel Hotel 
 Printtle&apos;s 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9698 5777 
Printtle&apos;s is the online presence for Australia&apos;s finest textile decoration studio (est. 1987). Serving Australia with printed t-shirts, custom hoodies, jackets, business shirts; restaurant, cafe and catering uniforms;…
 
 Restaurant Cafe Catering Hospitality 
 Mg Rover On Crown 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 (02) 9383 9383 
Car manufacturers
 
 Australian Restaurants Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets Food&amp;Beverage Services 
 Singapore Heritage Restaurant 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 8354 0800 
For those craving a sensual dining experience, Singapore Heritage Restaurant is the destination. Owned and run by flamboyant bodybuilding chef Alvin Koh, the catchphrase of the restaurant is &quot;renouncing immortality for…
 
 Banquets Restaurant Menus Restaurant Furniture dinner 
 Kai Food Styling 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 0409 032 224 
kai is a creative chef, food stylist and food industry professional. European trained, with 20 years experience in the united kingdom, germany and australia. He offers a wealth of experience and expertise in all food as…
 
 Restaurant Menus Restaurant Equipment Caterers Wedding Catering 
 Pot Belly Catering 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9280 3700 
 Party Supplies&amp;Services Party Services Caterers Restaurant 
 Cafe Mint 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9319 0848 
 Cafes Cafe mint 
 Longrain Surry Hills 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 (02) 9280 2888 
 Continental Restaurants Bars 
 Toast Cafe 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 92802615 
 
 Savage Wine Catering 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9332 2344 
 Restaurant Catering Wine 
 Dine By Design 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 9319 6336 
 Wedding Catering Restaurant Design Concert Entertainment Christmas Events 
 Telstra Corp 
Surry Hills, NSW
 02 9332 2344 
 Theatre Restaurants City Guide Food Guide sports travel 
 XO 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9360 7007 
 Rockpool 
 Restaurant Assiette 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9212 7979 
 
 Fuel Bistro 
Surry Hills, NSW
 (02) 9383 9388 
 bistros 
 Tabou 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 (02) 93195682 
 Mexican Restaurant 
 Marque 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 (02) 9332 2225 
 Australian Restaurants 
 Wood&amp;Stone Wood Fired Pizza 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 9319 6925 
 Pizzareia Italian Restaurant Pizza Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant 
 Juice And Java Cafe 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 93182960 
 
 Elephant Jump Asian Kitchen 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 96989119 
 
 Aporter No 1 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 03 95309745 
 
 Madam Char Char 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 93804411 
 
 Nua Exotic Thai 
SURRY HILLS, NSW
 02 83540123 
 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (188) 
 Related keywords 
 Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets Food&amp;Beverage Services Fast Food Catering Accommodation Cafes Holiday Accommodation Chinese Restaurant Italian Restaurant 
 Restaurants by suburb 
 Ult, NSW RUSHCUTTERS BAY, NSW ELIZABETH BAY, NSW CHIPPENDALE, NSW REDFERN, NSW DARLINGHURST, NSW Queen Victoria Building, NSW DARLING HARBOUR, NSW POTTS POINT, NSW HAYMARKET, NSW MOORE PARK, NSW WOOLLOOMOOLOO, NSW BARANGAROO, NSW ERSKINEVILLE, NSW PADDINGTON, NSW NEWTOWN, NSW KINGS CROSS, NSW KENSINGTON, NSW ZETLAND, NSW CIRCULAR QUAY, NSW EDGECLIFF, NSW BEACONSFIELD, NSW STANMORE, NSW BALMAIN EAST, NSW CENTENNIAL PARK, NSW CAMPERDOWN, NSW BROADWAY, NSW DAWES POINT, NSW WOOLLAHRA, NSW BONDI JUNCTION, NSW PYRMONT, NSW LILYFIELD, NSW Walsh Bay, NSW DARLING POINT, NSW ROZELLE, NSW Petersham North, NSW GLEBE, NSW BALMAIN, NSW BIRCHGROVE, NSW Dbl By, NSW MILSONS POINT, NSW Peters, NSW ROSE BAY, NSW KIRRIBILLI, NSW SYDENHAM, NSW PETERSHAM, NSW MARRICKVILLE, NSW WAVERLEY, NSW MCMAHONS POINT, NSW DOUBLE BAY, NSW QUEENS PARK, NSW DARLINGTON, NSW LAVENDER BAY, NSW LEWISHAM, NSW KINGSFORD, NSW ULTIMO, NSW ROSEBERY, NSW RANDWICK, NSW MARRICKVILLE SOUTH, NSW WAVERTON, NSW EAST SYDNEY, NSW Crs Jnali, NSW N Syd, NSW BELLEVUE HILL, NSW TEMPE, NSW Sydney International Terminal, NSW HABERFIELD, NSW WOOLWICH, NSW ST PETERS, NSW DRUMMOYNE, NSW DULWICH HILL, NSW MASCOT, NSW NEUTRAL BAY JUNCTION, NSW GREENWICH, NSW RUSSELL LEA, NSW CREMORNE, NSW BONDI, NSW BRONTE, NSW NORTH SYDNEY, NSW CLOVELLY, NSW 
 Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
 BENCHMARQUE Hospitality&amp;Eve… 

 
 
 BENCHMARQUE Hospitality&amp;Eve… 

 CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design 

 Vini 

 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design 06-Mar-2011 Printtle&apos;s 04-Jul-2009 Your Order Corporate Catering Sydney 04-Sep-2008 BENCHMARQUE Hospitality&amp;Event Recruit… 06-May-2008 Singapore Heritage Restaurant 25-Mar-2008 Bridget Flowers&amp;Event Design 27-Feb-2007 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search enquiry 
Most popular
 
 BENCHMARQUE Hospitality&amp;Eve… CS Retail&amp;Commercial Design Thai Tha Poh Takeout Restaura… Cheeky Food Group Printtle&apos;s Singapore Heritage Restaurant 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business.
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of use Privacy policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.8.004 )
	</body>
</document>
