<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008095" url="http://horseandhomes.com/faq.html?tag=cup" time="2012-07-13-01:11" support="5" score="0.0033689754564095583" bingtitle="Horse and Homes - FAQ" webtitle="Horse and Homes - FAQ">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>... thank you for your help - also i want to pay ... to make Jell-o, and I need to add some cups of water to make it ... you ever see someone steal a drink at a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Horse and Homes 
 
Menu:
 
 Main Menu 
 Articles Blogs Links FAQ Photo Gallery Videos Products Jobs Downloads Contact 

 
About

Horse property and horse homes related informatio and resources.
 
Gallery

 
 
Tag Cloud

 cup 2010 Cup soccer song world kirko cartoon gummibär football gummibar bangz humor animation Drank how waka Mundial Africa yt:quality=high 2girls1cup new Music official video 
 
 


 


Check frequently asked questions about Cup

 Open Question: Did I eat enough today? 

I had an egg omlette and 2 slices of brown toast
 
cup of tea
 
chicken curry with rice and potato - it was freshly made.
 

A smoothie with half a chopped fresh carrot, a piece of ginger, tiny handful of spinach, pure carrot juice, cucumber juice, a little orange juice and some plain low fat yoghurt and a couple of blackberries.
 

A bowl of nesquick

12 Jul 2012, 4:02 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: What do I need to edit text in recipes from magazines.? 

I clip recipes from magazines, scan them and keep them (jpeg.) I want to be able to edit these recipes, add text e.g. 1/2 cup sugar, not 1 cup or add a note. I have Microsoft Word 2010 and Windows 7. Can someone tell me what I need in order to do this? Thank you kindly.

12 Jul 2012, 3:59 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Is it weird to put ice in your cup of milk? 

A coworker of mine today put some ice cubes in her glass of milk. I told her I thought it was weird and that I didn&apos;t know anyone that did that. She says that people in her family do that and she thinks it is a Mexican thing. I told her I have some Mexican friends on my soccer team that I would ask about that later. Maybe it reminds her of icecream? I don&apos;t know, I&apos;m not sure how creamy the milk is.

12 Jul 2012, 3:56 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: What kind/size of bra should I get? 

I&apos;m wearing a 34A Victorias secret PINK push up. The back goes way up on my shoulder blades and the front cups won&apos;t stay down to support me. The straps are just fine... What size or type should I receive? Thanks.

12 Jul 2012, 3:55 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Candle safety please help!!!? 

I want to leave a candle burning for a day
It&apos;s in like a glass cup thing
Is it dangerous if I&apos;m out the home and it reaches the bottom
What happens when it reaches the bottom
Can I do it safely?

12 Jul 2012, 3:54 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Is this a healthy meal I ate? Please Please Answer.? 

Ive been struggling with nutritions, the right way to eat. 
But Ive clip my portions and increase my metabolism...
I just ate 1/4 cup of rice, 5-6 slices of sliced turkey and a pretty big handful of lettuce with Balsamic Vinegar ( its healthy, I looked at the nutrition facts on it)

12 Jul 2012, 3:54 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: When Spurs win the league next season .....................? 

Which supporters will be most upset , Arsenal or Chelsea ?

I mean , if AVB can win a CL and FA cup double for Chelsea without even being there , imagine how good he&apos;ll be at Spurs when he&apos;s actually there .

every over bar the shouting !

12 Jul 2012, 3:48 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: THE ALTERNATIVE TO TAMPONS! (It&apos;s not pads!)? 

Before I start, this is a perfectly acceptable question, as I am searching for those same me.

Yes, today I&apos;m ditching chemical infested tampons for a fairly new AMAZING product, by the name of &quot;mooncupUK&quot;!

For those who don&apos;t know, the mooncup is one of many brands of menstrual cups. 
The aim of a menstrual cup is to catch the blood in a soft and flexible cup, the alternative to a tampon.

Here are some reasons why I adore my mooncup!:

Mooncups can be used by women of every ages: from when you just start your period, to later on once you have had kids.

There are 2 sizes: 
size A: for those over 30 and for those who have given birth. 
size B: for those below 30 and for those who have not given birth. 
(I&apos;m 15 and I adore my mooncup so far!)

In many ways, a mooncup is safer than a tampon, giving no risk of TSS, and containing no dioxins. 
They are environmentally friendly, and although they cost alot, they are re-usable for each period, and cost much less in the long run (having to buy more tampons or pads each period.)

It may look massive, but once folded correctly for insertion, it&apos;s about the size of a tampon applicator.

What I find very convinient and re-assuring is that the mooncup is placed VERY low down in the vagina, so you don&apos;t have to worry about it getting lost. I had to trim the stem quite a bit actually for it to be low enough!

It also has measurements on the side if the cup, so you can keep track of how much you have been bleeding. It also comes with a cute little bag!

every the information you need will be on their website:

www.mooncup.co.uk

There will be diagrams on how to fold it, insert it, take it out, ect. 
You also have the opportunity to ask the experts about anything you are concerned about.

I find that I have to change a mooncup much less than a tampon, and that it&apos;s good not to carry around every these tampons or pads around with me.

You may find this disgusting, but it&apos;s the future, and these are 100 times better than tampons.

If your a swimmer or a dancer ect, you could just wear one for those and then go back to pads after.

There are LOADS of good reviews on mooncup, and I strongly reccomend these to everybody, especially teens - periods are so much better with these!

WHO IS NOW INTRESTED IN ONE OF THESE? : ) or who owns one already ?

Ps, if you have any more questions about girl stuff or anything, feel free to email me at: adamsgeorgie@yahoo.co.uk. 
(don&apos;t worry, I&apos;m generally interested in helping other teens with new products or advice, and I won&apos;t ask for any personal info : ) )

12 Jul 2012, 3:47 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Had my first ultrasound and the doctor told me my baby had no heartbeat and I was going to have a miscarriage.? 

From my last &quot;known&quot; period I should be 9 weeks and 5 days. My periods are really irregular though. So at my very first doctors appointment they didnt do a physical exam, make me pee in a cup or do any bloodwork. They did an ultrasound right off the bat and told me that I am measuring at 8 weeks and 2 days. He also told me he couldnt find a heartbeat and that I was going to have a miscarriage because there was no heartbeat and it was measuring at 8 weeks when i should be 9. I asked if there was a chance that maybe I was actually 8 weeks because my periods are weird so that would make ovulation weird and he said no that HE can look a heartbeat at 6 weeks. I have had no signs of miscarriage at every. No bleeding, no cramping, nothing. Is it possible that maybe it was too early to look my babies heartbeat? I am thinking about waiting 1 - 2 weeks and getting a second opinion or calling the doctors office back and telling them I want them to do bloodwork to be sure.

12 Jul 2012, 3:45 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: I need to lose weight!? 

I am 12 years old and will be 13 years old on december 14th and i need to lose wait im 160lbs currently and i am very embarrest and so far today i did a mile and a half and 100 sit ups i have eat 2 eggs for breakfast and my liquids include 2 glasses of milk and 2 glasses of mountain dew and probly half a glass of h20 and for lunch i hate a dish of speghetti and prbly 5 or 6 freeze pops and for dinner i eat a dish of speghetti and probly 2 cups of veggies and 3 strawberries! can someone please nicely give my an idea of the calories i should eat and a breakfast,lunch , dinner and snack i dont nessecarily want a diet i want an appropriate meal plan and an appropriate exercises i should do a week or a day also tell me how much soda juice and sweets i can eat and drink thanks so much1

12 Jul 2012, 3:36 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Who will win the FA Cup next season? 



12 Jul 2012, 3:31 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: I&apos;M LOOKING FORWARD TO MY PERIOD . . .? 

Before I start, this is a perfectly acceptable question, as I am searching for those same me.

Yes, today I&apos;m ditching chemical infested tampons for a fairly new AMAZING product, by the name of &quot;mooncupUK&quot;!

For those who don&apos;t know, the mooncup is one of many brands of menstrual cups.
The aim of a menstrual cup is to catch the blood in a soft and flexible cup, the alternative to a tampon.

Here are some reasons why I adore my mooncup!:

Mooncups can be used by women of every ages: from when you just start your period, to later on once you have had kids.

There are 2 sizes:
size A: for those over 30 and for those who have given birth.
size B: for those below 30 and for those who have not given birth.
(I&apos;m 15 and I adore my mooncup so far!)

In many ways, a mooncup is safer than a tampon, giving no risk of TSS, and containing no dioxins.
They are environmentally friendly, and although they cost alot, they are re-usable for each period, and cost much less in the long run (having to buy more tampons or pads each period.)

It may look massive, but once folded correctly for insertion, it&apos;s about the size of a tampon applicator.

What I find very convinient and re-assuring is that the mooncup is placed VERY low down in the vagina, so you don&apos;t have to worry about it getting lost. I had to trim the stem quite a bit actually for it to be low enough! 

It also has measurements on the side if the cup, so you can keep track of how much you have been bleeding. It also comes with a cute little bag!

every the information you need will be on their website:

www.mooncup.co.uk

There will be diagrams on how to fold it, insert it, take it out, ect.
You also have the opportunity to ask the experts about anything you are concerned about.

I find that I have to change a mooncup much less than a tampon, and that it&apos;s good not to carry around every these tampons or pads around with me.

You may find this disgusting, but it&apos;s the future, and these are 100 times better than tampons.

If your a swimmer or a dancer ect, you could just wear one for those and then go back to pads after.

There are LOADS of good reviews on mooncup, and I strongly reccomend these to everybody, especially teens - periods are so much better with these!

WHO IS NOW INTRESTED IN ONE OF THESE? : ) or who owns one already ?

Ps, if you have any more questions about girl stuff or anything, feel free to email me at: adamsgeorgie@yahoo.co.uk.
(don&apos;t worry, I&apos;m generally interested in helping other teens with new products or advice, and I won&apos;t ask for any personal info : ) )

12 Jul 2012, 3:30 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Please Help me with my chemistry Pre-Lab Assingment!? 

A studen determined the calorimeter constant of the calorimeter, using the procedure described in theis module. the student added 50.00 mL of icy water to 50.00mL of heated, distilled water in a styrofoam cup. the initial temperature of the icy water was 21.00 C and the hot water, 29.15 C. the maximum temperature of the mixture was found to be 24.81C. assume the dnesity of water is 1.00 g mL^-1 and the specific heat is 4.184 g^-1 K^-1.

1. Calculate the heat lost by the hot water?
2.Calculate the heat gained by the icy water?
3.Calculate the calorimeter constant, using the delta t of the icy water?

12 Jul 2012, 3:27 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: How to eat healthy when parents don&apos;t cook healthy food? 

ok so im trying to lose weight by August 20. i dont really eat healthy my mom doesnt cook healthy always buying soda&amp;everything. she doesnt let me pick what to buy at the grocery store.. i have spoke to her about how i wanna lose weight and if she could buy healthier foods but she just doesnt want to and she said i dont need to lose weight, honestly i feel i could lose some im 4&apos;11&amp;130 Ibs. i dont have time to learn to cook or workout. im going to join dance class in september again tho because it used to help me keep weight off, but i want to lose some weight before school starts in august. 

I dont have that much money so i cant just go o the store and buy groceries. and i dont really have other family members to help me, and my friends just dont understand !! the only thing i nhave thats probably ok is alim quick, but i want a healthy good meal. is there like a meal i could probably run to the store&amp;buy thats already cooked but i just put it in the microwave or something?? im also going to try to squeeze in 10-20 minutes on the elliptical everyday&amp;do some sit ups as well. so does anyone know how i can fix my problem on how to receive healthy meals or something simple to eat but healthy? i drink 8 cups of water a day no soda. and what i have been doing lately since my mom isnt cooking healthy i just eat smaller portions but i just need to fin d a way to receive healthy meals!

12 Jul 2012, 3:27 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Churchs pool party?a bikini? 

Okay so I&apos;m 14 and my churches youth group is having a pool party.In the email thing that they sent my parents it says (dress appropriately) does that mean I shouldn&apos;t wear a bikini ?My friends mom who&apos;s in the church organization thing won&apos;t allow her daughter to wear a bikini when there&apos;s boys.(my parents don&apos;t care).does that mean I shouldn&apos;t?idk if any of my other girl friends are wearing bikinis because they&apos;re not answering their phones.lol btw I&apos;m a d-cup and my bikini is a normal one I got from hollister.I can&apos;t go out and buy a coverup or one piece.or borrow a one piece from somebody.I&apos;m getting nervous because I don&apos;t know what they&apos;ll say :P the parties tomorrow

12 Jul 2012, 3:26 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: My dog licks her nose/sucks on her tongue often, and has an upset stomach; what should I do for her? 

Originally, I thought her sucking on her tongue was a puppy thing, like a toddler thumb-sucking, but she&apos;s persisted to do it every the way to now, coming on 3 years of age this year. She used to lick her genitals a lot when she was a puppy, but now licks her nose instead. Her nose often looks too wet, with droplets of clear liquid gathering. She really can&apos;t help herself, I&apos;ve held her mouth closed when trying to clip her facial fur, and feel her try with every her might to stick her tongue out to suck on it, and usually bites a notch in it doing so. I&apos;ve stuck a snug muzzle on, and she does the same thing, only she starts frantically clawing at the muzzle and cries loudly. Her tummy often growls, and I look her give a &quot;baby barf&quot;, looking like she pukes into her mouth and then swallows it. She&apos;s been doing this quite a while. Recently, her dry food brands were switched too quick, and the vet said she has gas, so I have to put her on a chicken broth diet for a few days.

It&apos;s a very irritating sound when she licks her nose repeatedly; her nose seems to be turning from black to a pinkish brown down the middle, where she licks it. Like I said, she also ends up biting a notch into her tongue as she tries licking her nose while barking or doing some other activity like running. I also started finding her licking the furniture... specifically the wooden table legs. She&apos;s a pound or two over weight (I brought her down from about four pounds over weight, she&apos;s only 13 inches tall), so I feed her two thirds a cup of kibble in the morning, and a fourth in the afternoon to control her weight better.

12 Jul 2012, 3:24 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Can someone please convert this? 

What is 400 gm 50 gm and 200 gm converted to cups

12 Jul 2012, 3:19 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: How to get rid of pimples and redness ? 

I have oily sensitive and acne prone skin. And yestersay I put some epsom salt and water in a cup and dipped it with a cotton ball to reduce redness and kill some acne and one red bump came to a head and the other did as well but the redness did not subside ! I have a party to go to tomorrow and theres this girl that likes me and shes going as well, last week the redness wasnt really.noticeable and I didnt have these pimples ! What should I do ? Omg I hate my skin, tea tree oil ?? Ice ?? What something that keeps the redness from.the scarring and pimples down ! also the pimples have a head... DONT TELL ME TOOTHPASTE

12 Jul 2012, 3:18 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Will Chelsea even finish above ARSENAL...? 

...The PL is not a cup, where you can just defend your way through it... and wish to receive a bit of luck in a semi... (where the best player in the world misses a pen and countless other chances) then win the final on penalties..

No.. the PL doesn&apos;t work like that... you can&apos;t win on penalties...

I don&apos;t look how Chelsea will be THAT different from last season... just older..
tOuz: Says the Liverpool fan from the USoff*****g&apos;A&apos;... sometimes, you really arrive across as stupid..(im closer to Liverpool than you are hun)☺

12 Jul 2012, 3:17 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: PLEASE PLEASE help me rewrite this one sentence.? 

(I added more to it, my intention was not to fool you. help me add better detail of actions. i need to add more actions, I want Catherine to be nervous but mad. And tiffany to be mad about the past. They are talking while sitting inside a prison) 

Catherine saw Tiffany sitting with her arms crossed. They both reached for their phones on the side of the glass


 She smiled at Tiffany, noticing how tangled her hair looked. “Got enough snooze?”
“Why are you here?” She asked with a growl.
“I want to know why … you did what you did!”
“Because I can.”
“You kidnapped us and almost killed Jean. What the hell did we do to you?”
“You don’t remember?” She pulled down her collar low revealing a heart shaped mole. “Remember now?”
“Oh my god, it’s you.”
“Yeah, it’s me Kendra you’re old pal.”
“Why would you do that to us?”
“I did almost kill you so fine, I’ll tell you.”
“Go ahead and tell me then.”
“I went to your birthday when you just turned eleven. I was tardy and you and your little friends were playing stupid games, like Truth or dare. When it was Jean’s turn she dared you to set my tree home on flame. And you did it. You knew I went up there to receive your gift!”
“W-what makes you think it was me?” Catherine asked with a stutter.
“I talked to a girl at your party, she told me who did what during the truth or dare game that’s how I know you and Jean burned up my tree home. So don’t deny anything.”
Catherine put her elbows on the table, her fingers went through her possess hair. “Okay look, I didn’t know anyone was there Kendra.”
“I was in one of the rooms, there was a flame by the door so I couldn’t receive out. I inhaled too much smoke and I blacked out. I was burned really bad on one side of my body,” she said grumbling. 
She looked down at her fingers then up at her. “Sorry-”
“I should have set you two on flame when I had the chance!”
Catherine picked up her purse. “I have to go.”
Tiffany faked a gasp. “That’s it?”
“I am sorry that you got hurt, I set the trash on flame than I threw a cup of water on it. I just wanted Jean to look the flame from my home.”
“Just so you could look wild in front of your friends. That is unhappy!”
“Goodbye Tiffany. I mean Kendra.”

12 Jul 2012, 3:13 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: question about garage sale food? 

I was thinking about selling brownies individually wrapped in Saran wrap and chocolate chip cookies also wrapped at our garage sale, but my mom is convinced that they will go bad very quickly in the heat. It is supposed to be about 98 degrees tomorrow. Will they go bad? If so what are some ideas were I could keep them chilly but still visible? How much should I charge? I was also thinking of having ice water and maybe lemonade in pitchers and charge for a cup. Is this a good idea, or would I be better off just buying a bargain brand pack of pop or water (although I would only have 1 flavor of pop available) and putting them in a cooler? How much should I charge for either of these options? Is there anything else I should offer? Thanks :)

12 Jul 2012, 3:12 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Did I eat too much today? 

Hey:) I&apos;m female, 18, 5&apos;6&apos;&apos;, and 119-120 pounds. Here&apos;s what I&apos;ve eaten today:

half of an egg white veggie omelette
90 calorie every natural whole wheat vegan muffin
tiny banana
1/2 cup fat free cottage cheese
4 ounce ground chicken patty
green salad

Then I got the munchies and ate:
a piece of homemade banana bread
probably about 2 and a half tablespoons of natural peanut butter
a Kashi oatmeal cookie
and a handful of almonds

I feel like this is way too much:/ what do you think?

Thanks!

12 Jul 2012, 3:08 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Writing a parody about the NHL to Don&apos;t Stop Believing...Ideas? 

This is to the tune by Journey... Don&apos;t cease Believing! It is about how the NHL started, and what it is like today. This is what I have so far: (to the tune of the tune)

Just some hockey players, playing in Canada, took the midnight train to Toronto.
Just some hockey players, playing in the United States, took the midnight train to Toronto...
A player, in a stupid suit, the odor of sweat and some cheap __________? In the league they can share the rights, it goes on and on and on and on.
The Rangers, waiting, to hold Lord Stanley&apos;s Cup. The Devils don&apos;t want to play the Kings.

This is just my first draft so not only do I want you to give me ideas on what to change/add to what I already have, but also help me with the relax of the tune! THANKS!

Rules:
1) Has to follow the tune theme (Current NHL)
2)Has to follow the tune of Don&apos;t cease Believing

12 Jul 2012, 3:07 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: is it bad to drink 8 cups of water a day? 



12 Jul 2012, 2:50 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Weight Loss Tips That Work? 

Tips that work on losing weight.?
I&apos;ve been on a diet for a month now.I&apos;m currently 145 pounds. I started my diet, weighing 145 pounds.


Breakfast:
tiny bowl special k cereal, or a whole grain cereal, a splash of soymilk, a handful of strawberries.
One Yoplait.

Lunch:
Usually a fresh fruit smoothie, made with only water and fruit.

Snacks:
Apple.
Grapefruit.
Raspberries.

Dinner:
A spinach salad with the Wish Bone Salad Spritzer dressing, with onions on top.
Sometimes I&apos;ll have a Morning Star burger with mushrooms and onions, 
and sometimes I&apos;ll make Tofurkey wraps that have red bell peppers, onions, spinach, and limes on them. 

I work out an hour-two hours a day.
I follow either one or two &quot;weightloss&quot; videos and I use the Wii to track how long I run, usually 15-20 minutes, and do the hulu hoop session for ten minutes.

In this past month, I have seemed to receive even bigger, and not lost anything.
Is there anything I could do differently?

5+ bottles of water a day. 5+ cups of tea a day.

My daily diet is usually less than 800 calories. I can&apos;t really survive off of &quot;less food.&quot;

12 Jul 2012, 2:42 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: What is the average bra size for a 13 year-old girl? 

I am 13 years old and just went looking for my first bra. The lady working at the store gave me the smallest possible size, a 32 double A, but it was really too big. I was surprised because I am pretty tall. So I couldn&apos;t find a bra that wasn&apos;t too big, and I&apos;m 13 years old. I think that every girl in my class wears a bra, but I can&apos;t even find one that fits! I don&apos;t actually feel bad about this because I like being flat-chested, but out of curiosity what is the average cup size for a 13 year old girl?
Yeah the band fit alright (the 32 part), but every the cups were too big.

12 Jul 2012, 2:32 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: What food to sell at a garage sale? Pricing too? 

I was thinking about selling brownies individually wrapped in Saran wrap and chocolate chip cookies also wrapped at our garage sale, but my mom is convinced that they will go bad very quickly in the heat. It is supposed to be about 98 degrees tomorrow. Will they go bad? If so what are some ideas were I could keep them chilly but still visible? How much should I charge? I was also thinking of having ice water and maybe lemonade in pitchers and charge for a cup. Is this a good idea, or would I be better off just buying a bargain brand pack of pop or water (although I would only have 1 flavor of pop available) and putting them in a cooler? How much should I charge for either of these options?Is there anything else I should offer? Thanks :)

12 Jul 2012, 2:30 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: How to reduce acne redness ? 

I have oily sensitive and acne prone skin. And yestersay I put some epsom salt and water in a cup and dipped it with a cotton ball to reduce redness and kill some acne and one red bump came to a head and the other did as well but the redness did not subside ! I have a party to go to tomorrow and theres this girl that likes me and shes going as well, last week the redness wasnt really.noticeable and I didnt have these pimples ! What should I do ? Omg I hate my skin, tea tree oil ?? Ice ?? What something that keeps the redness from.the scarring and pimples down !

12 Jul 2012, 2:21 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Kraft macaroni and cheese help!? 

Hey, so im 14 and on a diet, my parents are working till tardy tonight about 11pm. Its dinner time and im starving and I went to the kitchen but we have like nothing to eat (we go shopping tomorrow) the only thing we had is my sisters junk food, ( which i dont eat because im on a diet) but every that was there was kraft macaroni and cheese. Is it okay if i eat this on my diet!? It will be within my calorie limit so i wont overeat, but im hungry and i cant wait till 11. Is this okay?

Also, the box says a serving is 1 cup prepared, what is that dry?

12 Jul 2012, 2:18 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Lesbian selfish&quot;preference&quot;(about breast)? 

I don&apos;t care about boobs size - I never did. If I adore the girl, then that&apos;s enough. I have very tiny boobs (AA cup, maybe almost A cup) and I&apos;m ok with it. But, I don&apos;t know really why, I feel more comfortable with a bigger breasted girl. But I didn&apos;t want to be greedy - my boobs are tiny. I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s because the chemistry would be bigger? Can someone try to explain me?
The question isn&apos;t about my boobs
Yes, I&apos;m actually only attracted to femmes...

12 Jul 2012, 2:17 pm | click here to view more 

 Resolved Question: What are dinner ideas for a pescetarian? 

I&apos;m currently making a fish felet with fresh broccoli and a half cup of brown rice. 1.) is this a good meal for a peacetarian? 2.) what are some ideas for a dinner or luch that I could make for myself? Things you should probably know:
1.) my parents don&apos;t buy me any extra stuff for me
2.) I&apos;m 13
3.) my parents are on a primal diet which means they eat meat and only meat. Never beans. Never bread. Which makes this difficult for me. So something simple that I could find in my cabinets please! 
P.S. This is my first real pescetarian dinner I useually just snack on healthy things every day. But I want to make sure I&apos;m healthy! Thankyou

12 Jul 2012, 2:06 pm | click here to view more 

 Resolved Question: How many cups are in 96 ounces? 



12 Jul 2012, 2:06 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Style for short girls? 

I&apos;m 17, 4&apos;11&quot; (almost 5 foot! So close!), I&apos;m really skinny (90 something pounds, but with B cup boobs) and I have great taste in clothes, that is, what looks good on other people-tall people. My style is defined as punk or rocker chic but what cuts of clothes can I wear? I know I can&apos;t wear high waisted shorts but I don&apos;t know what I can wear..

12 Jul 2012, 2:03 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: 13 year old girl with chest pains ???? .? 

I&apos;m a 13 year old girl, I have been getting chest pains, it started two weeks ago ever since I keep getting them they last about 15-20 minutes each I receive about 2-3 every 2 days, last nights my left shoulder was hurting and I had hee cups every day today and it felt tight around my abdominals, sometimes I feel out of breath when I do tiny things such as do my hair, walk around and go up the stairs, I am quite fit and healthy and don&apos;t smoke or drink what&apos;s wrong with me ?.

12 Jul 2012, 2:03 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Are three cups of coffee too dangerous for costochondritis? 



12 Jul 2012, 2:01 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: I am 22 years old and my whole family is either a c or a DD in cup size so why am i almost flat chested ? 

I can barly fill an A cup size, I have had 3 kids and after each kids i went to a C cup but then shrunk down smaller than i was before. Is there any thing i can do to lift my hormone levels to receive them to grow bigger in at least one cup size.

12 Jul 2012, 1:58 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: I need some medical help? 

I am 21 (22 in a few weeks) and a female. I have been getting my period every 3 months or so, I am nauseous every the time, I have been having stomach problems and pain in my abdomine. The last period I got (after 3 months of not having one) was extremely light, like literally only a few extremely tiny pink dots. I have been also getting a lot of gas if this means anything. I was wondering if there is something severly wrong here? My doctor doesn&apos;t do any tests besides make pee in a cup for a pregnancy test, which doesn&apos;t even make sense since I have never had sex. She says she thinks I have polycystic ovary syndrome, but she never checked, she just guessed and didn&apos;t refer me to gynocologist or anything like that. She&apos;s a new doctor for me so maybe she doesn&apos;t know me enough to care yet. I called a gynocologist today to make an appointment but they are booked until Mid September, I called other places and they said November! I have never been to gynocologist before so I guess new patients receive screwed. I posted a similar question like 5 or 6 months ago but got no serious responses. Are these symptoms of something specific? Should I be worried? Thank you.

12 Jul 2012, 1:57 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Is My Diet Healthy and Good For Reducing Body Fat? 

I&apos;m 19 years old and trying to reduce my body fat percentage, but I&apos;m living away from home for the summer to do research, so I try to receive the healthiest (low calorie) food options here. Here&apos;s my diet: 

Breakfast: English muffin (nothing added to it) and 1 cup of coffee (with a little milk added)

Lunch: Salad with grilled chicken, onions, tomatoes, Italian dressing and a bottle of water

Post-Workout: 1 scoop protein powder mixed with 1 bottle water

Dinner: 6 inch sweet onion chicken teriyaki sub (From Subway). It&apos;s on 9 grain wheat bread and has some teriyaki chicken, lettuce, onions, tomatoes and sweet onion sauce. Here&apos;s the link: http://www.subway.com/menu/product.aspx?CC=USA&amp;LC;=ENG&amp;MenuTypeId;=1&amp;MenuId;=35&amp;ProductId;=4

Suggestions? Look good?

12 Jul 2012, 1:54 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: can you sub cream cheese for sour cream? 

Here&apos;s the recipe... 
It sounds like a good experiment...My daughter is almost 1 and I&apos;m trying to learn to cook..

4 chicken breasts 
1 (10 ounce) cream of mushroom soup 
1 teaspoon hidden valley ranch dressing mix 
1/4 cup milk 
1/4 cup sour cream 
2 tiny potatoes, sliced thin (optional) 
Directions:
1Place chicken breasts in crock pot. Mix soup, teaspoon of mix and milk in a tiny bowl. Pour over chicken. Add potatoes if desired.2Cook on high for 1 hour. Cook on low for 3 to 4 hours until chicken is tender. During last 15 minutes of cooking time, stir in sour cream.3Note: Soup and dressing mix provides some salt to recipe. But if using potatoes, add salt and pepper to taste.

12 Jul 2012, 1:49 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Pan American Volleyball cup 2012? 

are there any live links to watch the womens volleyball matches in mexico in the Pan Am Cup?
I want to watch them but cant find any links anywhere. please help if you can! thanks

12 Jul 2012, 1:47 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Soccer is popular in USA or not really? 

I KNOW SOMETHING ABOUT THE YOUR TRADITIONS SPORTS

THE MOST POPULAR SPORT IS BASEBALL

THEN THE FOOTBALL

THE THIRD IS BASKETBALL


BUT THE SOCCER??


DO YOU look THE WORL CUP OF SOCCER?


IN LATIN AMERICA IS THE MOST POPULAR


AND THE WORLD CUP IS A PARTY
WORLD CUP

12 Jul 2012, 1:31 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Is butter actually bad for you? 

I always have i&apos;d say a light scraping of Clover Butter Lighter on my sandwich.

I have a pretty balanced and healthy diet for a 13 year old i&apos;d say.

I usually have: Breakfast: medium sized bowl of oatmeal

Lunch: sandwich, sometimes i have a banana sandwich, couple times a week, other times it&apos;s some lettuce and chicken or something. (with some butter)

Dinner: just anything really, whatever what&apos;s in the freezer or whatever my mum makes, usually pretty healthy but if not i&apos;ll have some salad with it.

Snacks: I usually only have fresh fruit or yogurt, sometimes i&apos;ll have a biscuit, like a couple digestives or a couple ginger nuts to go with a cup of tea, but not very often. 1-2 times a week.
probably doesn&apos;t make a difference but it&apos;s wholemeal bread I use

12 Jul 2012, 1:29 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: what is a good pineapple and rum drink? 

Im making cups out of pineapples and would like some ideas on some good drinks to put in them, maybe using the pineapple, and something simple... thanks

12 Jul 2012, 1:25 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Opinion on this meal plan.? 

This is what I ate today.
BF- 
1 cup blueberries
Half of a turkey sandwhich, no cheese, just turkey and mustard.

Lunch-
Cucumber slices (with skin)
two tblsp salsa (storebought) 
10 grape tomatoes
4 cups water

dinner-
One medium square eggplant parm (frozen storebought) Two inches each side
1 cup salad (No dressing)

Snack
4 cups popcorn (air popped)

30 minute cardio

12 Jul 2012, 1:13 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: why doesnt my wii game work? 

about 2 years ago i got 2010 fifa world cup south africa on wii and it worked fine for a few months but then one day i tried to play it and it just froze before even getting to the start screen. After a week it still wouldnt work so i got the same game again and that one did the same thing. So I took it into a game store and played it on their wii and it worked fine so there must be something wrong with my wii consol. It just doesnt like that game for some reason. every my other games are fine. I just remembered i had the game so i thought id ask if there was anyway i could receive it to work again.
If you icy that would be great.

12 Jul 2012, 1:09 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: any body console me by giving advice? 

i am 30 and male.any one who looks at me say i am very slim,my height is 165cm and my weight is exactly 42 kg,since 10 years i have this weight and I AM FROM SOUTH ASIA.so i am very depressed about my body,when i go to the mirror i look at my self and receive so disappointed.the other thing i hate hearing the people saying me you are very slim then i receive totally mental down.since 10 years i smoke now since 2 years i am a heavy smoker i smoke about 20 cigrts per day.even i repent on my past too much,i think always about my past and sometimes i feel like crying.i can not snooze till 2 am sometime 4 or 5 am,then i sob alone in my bed i have a alone life in abroad away from my beloved family.now i am always sick last year i suffer from a very bad pain in my heart,now this year i have stomach pain DIVERTICULOSIS already i visited doctors.i am very disappointed in my life about getting sick too very frequently.i can cease smoking too when i try to give somoking up i fell so bad and unhappy.even few months ago i satarted to gain some weight by eating 4 times a day only one week and i felt so bad after eating a lot like nausea,then i went to doctor he said very easily don t eat too much and your weight does not gain.but why i am so ugly,no one cares of me because i am so slim?why i can not gain some weight??i should tell that i had a very bad past because of so many things,specially because of a girl.the other thing my familly background,it was not so bad but we had too many difficulties in our tiny familly.i have sleeplessness so in the night with the thought of sleeping i go to bed at 12 mid night then till 2 or 3 am more than 15 times i urinate this is very troublesome getting up ang going to toilte,each time i urinate only about 20ml even without drinking water.now i am waiting for a colonoscopy 0n 23rd regarding my stomachache.i am a very social person like to giggle always but if somebody around me even does any bad thing i am so excited then i think about that more than one week like this why the people are so and so many questions hurting in me in my head.any body please spend your valuable time to help me a bit to receive rid of these difficulties,if you need i will again write if there is some thing missed.the other thing i can not eat as soon as i wake up i drink a cup of coffee and smoke some times when i have my first meal of the day it is around 2 pm.then dinner at around 9 or 10 pm,in between a bun and many coffees.what should i do?since 2 months now i drink about 2 l of water.i don t like alcohol now but one year ago i used to drink 2l beer per day ending was putting me to bed having a heart pain..okay please write me to receive rid of this bad life.thank you every..
actually i have almost every night night mare.these are very terrified,what i think so badly i have in the night as a night mare...

12 Jul 2012, 1:06 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: wrong cup size bra???? 

hi,
today i bought 4 bras because they were on sale. i bought 34a (im tiny :( ) because that&apos;s what i thought i was.
i got them home and tried them on and they are quite tight along the top bit of the bra. the cups sort of dig into my boobs and if i turn to the side you can look it digging in and it looks like &quot;overspill&quot;

would this be the wrong cup size? should i go up to a B?
the band is ok and so are the straps, its just the cup?

theres also no where in town i can receive measured professionally :/ ive tried doing it myself online but they every say different. sometimes im a 32a, sometimes a 34b...

12 Jul 2012, 1:04 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Help getting pregnant? 

My partner and I plan to start trying to concieve next month. (we&apos;re same-sex partners) I was wondering if anyone had any tips? So far I am aware that I should be taking Prenatal and Multivitamins before I start trying to concieve and that a 5ml syringe is okay to use for insemination. I guess my question is after my donor ejaculates into a cup, and does it matter what nice of cup, how do I keep it room temperature and what steps should I take when going through the insemination process.

12 Jul 2012, 1:04 pm | click here to view more 

 Open Question: Does wearing a too big bra make your breasts looks smaller? 

I used to be a 36DD bra size. I recently lost weight and now I&apos;m a 34DD. I only have 36DD bras and I can&apos;t receive any new bras until the weekend. I wore my one bra today and my breasts look very tiny. The bra itself feels too big on my back and around my breasts. Could it just be that my breasts look tiny because they&apos;re not being supported properly? I understand that my breasts are smaller because a 34DD is equal to a 36D, which is one strap and cup size smaller than 36DD (a Victoria&apos;s Secret employee explained that to me), but they look extremely tiny to me and when I tried on the 34DD bra, they didn&apos;t look that tiny, so I feel they should be bigger. Thanks for any help!

12 Jul 2012, 12:59 pm | click here to view more 

 Resolved Question: Will I lose weight if I do this? 

I am a 17 year old Female 5&apos;8 and trying to lose weight to meet Air Force requirements. I am a senior in high school, so i dont have long to lose the weight that I need to lose.I need to know if I will keep losing weight if I continue this and stay consistent. 

Breakfast:
1 tiny apple
1 slice of Whole Grain toast
1 tbsp peanut butter
2 bottles of water

Dinner:
1 cup green beans
1/2 harvestland chicken breast( boneless skinless no preservatives)
1 bottle of water

I do 50 jumping jacks 5 times a day 
Walk/run/run a 1 mile+ every evening. 
I also continue to drink water throughout the day.

I know I need to work on push ups and sit ups, and improve my running distance in order to join the AF. 
Any other tips for weight loss, nutrition and exercise are appreciated. Please, don&apos;t be rude.

12 Jul 2012, 11:05 am | click here to view more 

 Sample content 

This is a sample item inserted using the custom content feature presented by SteadyNiche. Please, read the software documentation to know how to use this feature.

| click here to view more 

 Another sample 

This is another sample item inserted using the custom content feature presented by SteadyNiche. Please, read the software documentation to know how to use this feature.

| click here to view more 

 

 
 
 
 
©2008 Horse and Homes. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy . Design by Andreas Viklund
	</body>
</document>
