<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008734" url="http://www.morgancountycitizen.com/?q=node/18567" time="2012-07-13-02:12" support="2" score="0.0034334462946150317" bingtitle="Law Enforcement: October 6, 2011 | Morgan County Citizen Online" webtitle="Law Enforcement: October 6, 2011 | Morgan County Citizen Online">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>... being while the three persons were at a fast food restaurant. ... his residence and removed three $1 bills and change ... attacked a woman, destroyed an island counter in a ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe or
Renew Online
Click Here 
Site Search
 
News&amp;Features
 
 Top Stories More News&amp;Features Letters to the Editor Editorials Sports Local Color Police Reports Chalkboard Ledger Daily Apple Religion Obituaries Paid Announcements 
 Anniversaries Births Birthdays Engagements Weddings Cards of Thanks In Memory 
 Earthbound Retrospective Front Pages News Briefs Community Legals 
 

 
 Local Shots 

 Contact Us 

 Subscribe or Renew 

 Online Classifieds 

 Advertise Here 

 Login 
 
Navigation
 
 Calendar of Events News BLOG! Photo Galleries 
 
 July 12, 2012 706-342-7440 
 

 Home 
Law Enforcement: October 6, 2011
 Submitted by editor on Fri, 10/07/2011 - 14:16. 
 Police Reports 
 
Madison Police Department

•On Sept. 30 a shoplifting complaint was filed at an Eatonton Road drug store after a woman reported that she observed a white female enter a restroom. The woman said she noticed that the woman left the restroom 15 to 20 minutes later. The woman investigated the restroom and observed empty packages hidden under a trash can liner in the restroom. The employee said the store had recently had shoplifting incidents where a suspect entered the restroom, removed the items from their packages and discarded the empty packages under the trash can liner. The employee immediately called 911 and searched the store for the suspect. The suspect had left the premises but, reports state, the store was able to identify her because she had purchased a prescription and hair care products prior to the incident.

•On Oct. 1 a larceny complaint was filed at an Eatonton Road location after a woman reported that a man had returned the wrong pistol to her after she had loaned him the weapon a year ago. According to reports, the woman said she had loaned the man a SigArms P239 handgun because the man was homeless and living in his vehicle. The woman said she loaned the man the weapon for his personal protection. The man has since acquired a residence, the woman said, and attempts to retrieve the weapon had failed. The man did, however, return a SigArms 229 to the woman. The man told police that he had initially pawned the woman’s pistol and when he went to retrieve the weapon from an Athens pawn shop he was told that the weapon had been sold to a Macon gun dealer. The man then went to Macon and retrieved the weapon but realized later he had purchased the wrong gun. The gun was seized by police as evidence and an investigation continues.

•On Oct. 1 a burglary complaint was filed at a Foster Street residence after a woman reported that someone had broken a screen on her bedroom window and entered the residence. The woman reported that she was missing a $200 gold ring and three gold necklaces valued at $110.

•On Oct. 2 a larceny complaint was filed at a Carriage Lane location after a woman reported someone had taken her sixth grade daughter’s cell phone from her backpack. The complainant said when she called the cell phone provider she was told the phone was in use. The woman was able to track the phone to a Billups Street location. She has attempted to contact the person with the phone but has had no return contact. The phone is a green Samsung valued at $100.

•On Sept. 30 a larceny complaint was filed at an Eatonton Road department store after a woman reported that she had left her purse at the store. Reports state that the purse was returned but $300 was missing from the purse.
•On Oct. 2 a damage to property complaint was filed at a Micha Way location after a woman reported that someone shot the front windshield of her 1998 Honda Civic with a BB gun. The woman said she had knowledge of three or four juveniles in the area that had been shooting BB guns. An officer also spoke with a second woman who reported that while her 2009 Dodge Avenger was parked at Orchard Grove apartments someone had shot the rear passenger window of her vehicle with a BB gun.

•On Oct. 1 Darian Monae Brown, 17, Rutledge, was arrested and charged with possession of marijuana after an officers responded to a suspicious vehicle call at a Green Meadows location. According to reports, the officer arrived and noticed a Honda Accord occupied by three females. The officer also reported that there was a smell of burnt marijuana coming from the vehicle. The officer was giving a suspected marijuana cigarette by Brown and, reports state, Brown told the officer the suspected marijuana was hers.

•On Sept. 29 a burglary complaint was filed at a West Washington Street location after a man reported that someone had gained entry to his business and removed a State of Georgia tax refund check ($798) and a silver Apple iPod valued at $100. In a related report, offices responded to a Madison pawn shop after the owner of the shop informed officers that he was in possession of an iPod he thought might have been stolen. Officers were able to secure the iPod and identified as the same one stolen from the business. They also identified a man who completed a pawn ticket for the item.

•On Sept. 30 a harassment complaint was filed at an Eatonton Road location after a woman reported that another woman and a man known to her had made threatening statements regarding the woman’s future well-being while the three persons were at a fast food restaurant.
•On Sept. 25 Tanner Carter Jensen, 18, Madison, was arrested and charged with possession of marijuana and a noise violation after a vehicle he was driving on South Main Street was stopped for a noise violation. According to reports, consequent to the stop an officer located a book bag that allegedly contained suspected marijuana in a vile, a grinder containing suspected marijuana, a bong, a scale, a lighter and a gas mask. Four other occupants in the vehicle were released after Jensen allegedly told the officer the items belonged to him.

•On Sept. 28 Christopher Marvin Walker, 35, Madison, was arrested and charged with possession of marijuana after an officer responding to a loud music complaint at an Eatonton Highway motel noticed a small plastic bag of suspected marijuana and a pipe in the room rented by Walker.

•On Sept. 26 a burglary complaint was filed at a Harper Street location after a man reported that on Sept. 23 someone had entered his residence and removed three $1 bills and change from a bowl inside his bedroom closet. The man said on Sept. 26 someone forced entry into the bedroom and again took change from the bowl. Estimated amount taken is $175.

•On Sept. 27 a burglary complaint was filed at a Four Lakes Drive location after a man reported that someone had entered his residence and removed three firearms. The weapons are .357 revolver with cracked handles, a Savage .22 caliber rifle and a Remington .308 rifle.

•On Sept. 22 a dog bite complaint was filed at a Commerce Street location after a woman reported that while she was walking down Commerce Street a Chow dog chained to a tree bit her. An officer responded and reported that the dog was aggressive towards both the officer and a Madison animal control officer. The dog was removed from the residence and placed into quarantine.

Morgan County Sheriff’s Office

•On Oct. 1 a battery and simple battery complaint was filed at a Greensboro Road location after a man reported that while he was at a bonfire party at a Greensboro Road residence he was attacked. According to reports, the man told authorities that a man engaged in a fight at the party with another man. During this fight, reports state, the complainant said two other men also began to beat on one of the men in the fight. The complainant said he attempted to break up the fight and the three men turned on him, striking him in the head, kicking him while he was on the ground and forcing him into the fire. The man’s girlfriend reported that during the fight the men also threw her on top of her boyfriend and that someone broke a bra strap. The complainant was treated at Morgan Memorial Hospital for lacerations and burns. Investigators noted that at the party site there were multiple beer cans strewn around the fire. Investigators have identified the three men allegedly involved in the altercation but were not able to make contact with the men at the site. An investigation into the incident continues.

•On Sept. 30 an information report was filed at a Centennial Road, Rutledge, location after a woman reported that her former boss had called her repeatedly after she quit and had driven both by her house and to her house and continued to make phone calls. The woman said she quit her job at a convenience store at 7 a.m. and left a key to the store. The complainant said after she quit a woman from the store began calling her cell phone at 7:45 a.m. and continued to do so even after they were told to stop. The woman said she quit accepting the calls and the store’s owner drove past her house and then set in front of her house and called again. The store owner told authorities that the incident was a misunderstanding and that they had been calling to discuss the incident and make arrangements to pay the complainant for hours worked.

•On Sept. 30 a simple battery complaint was filed at a Estes Road, Rutledge, location after a woman alleged that her son had spent the previous night drinking and driving her van. The woman said when the son arrived home an argument ensued regarding gas money for the van. The woman said the son also pushed her down and broke her back. An officer reported arriving at the house and locating the woman in a bedroom. She was transported to Newton Medical Center. The son told officers when he arrived home that morning he and his mother had argued regarding money and the use of the van. The son said that he attempted to get away from the mother but the mother broke down his bedroom door. The son also said the mother requested that the son strike her so that she could have him sent back to prison. The son said he located a check in the house made out to his father but that the mother had endorsed the check. The son also alleged that the mother had been taking heavy doses of prescription medication. The son said he collected the check and left the residence and took the check to the father at a Newborn location. The son said he had his probation address moved to the father’s residence and he would no longer be living with the mother.

•On Sept. 29 a theft by taking complaint was filed at an Athens Highway residence after a man reported that someone had taken a 1998 Honda 300 ATV. The man told authorities that the ATV had been parked in an open-air shed on the property. It was valued at $500.

•On Sept. 28 a identify fraud complaint was filed at a East Magnolia Loop location after a man reported that he had received an email from someone in Nigeria requesting his personal bank account information so that they could deposit $10,500,000 into his bank account. The man said he also received an email allegedly from the FBI accusing him of taking the money to fund terrorist activities. The man said he has not received $10,500,000 from any party and that he did not have an account with the bank the Nigerian person identified.

•On Sept. 26 Rose Mary Stone, 52, Bishop, was arrested and charged with obstructing or hindering someone making an emergency phone call after a man alleged that during an argument Stone had taken the phone after he called 911 and threw it into the yard. The man said he and Stone had been drinking when the fight erupted and he alleged that she had broken several windows in the house during the argument. Stone allegedly told the officer she threw the phone in the yard because she did not want police involved in the altercation because they“had better things to do than deal with (the ) argument.”

•On Sept. 26 a harassing phone call complaint was filed at an East Dixie Highway, Rutledge, location after a woman reported that despite a protective order, her ex-husband had been calling her several times and hanging up the phone. The woman said that while the calls were restricted, she recognized the ex-husband’s voice.

•On Sept. 25 Albert Carrasco Fernandez, 27, Rutledge, was arrested and charged with simple battery, cruelty to children and terroristic threats and acts. According to reports, Fernandez allegedly became enraged and allegedly attacked a woman, destroyed an island counter in a kitchen, destroyed dressers in a bedroom, threw clothing items on the floor, threw a candle stick at a woman and broke her finger and retrieved a can of gasoline and lighter and threatened to burn the house down with all occupants inside. The woman alleged that Fernandez had been drinking prior to the argument.

•On Oct. 2 a burglary and criminal damage to property complaint was filed at a Mission Road location after a man reported that someone had gained access to the building by prying open an exterior door. Reports state that several offices in the building were ransacked and that a security camera was damaged. Officers obtained a video of the burglary and have been able to identify a suspect. The complainant reported that this is the second time since 2010 that the establishment had been burglarized.

•On Sept. 28 a criminal trespass report was filed at a Turner Road, Madison, location after a man reported that a truck driver attempting to turn around near the complainant’s property backed over a corner fence post. The complainant estimated repair costs at $250.

•On Sept. 28 a carrying weapons within school safety zones complaint was filed at Morgan County High School after an administrator at the school contacted authorities regarding a 15-year-old male student with a knife. A deputy met with the administrator and the student and observed a folding knife with a two inch blade in the student’s book bag. The knife was confiscated and a juvenile complaint report was filed against the student.

Printed in the October, 6 2011 edition
 »
 Login or register to post comments 
 Advertisers Interested in advertising here? 
©2007 Morgan County Citizen, All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
