<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008702" url="http://blog.greensherpa.com/index.php/personal-finance/super-size-your-savings-at-fast-food-restaurants/" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="6" score="0.013866753451588732" bingtitle="Super Size Your Savings at Fast Food Restaurants « Cash Flow ..." webtitle="Super Size Your Savings at Fast Food RestaurantsCash Flow Sherpas |  A Personal Finance Blog By GreenSherpa">
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000958" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>To promote eating healthy and take better control of your finances, next time you make a quick stop at a fast food ... I&apos;m too risk adverse to do a credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Greensherpa personal finance tools–Go there now&gt;&gt; 
                                          
 Home Company News Deals Family Budgeting Frugal Giving Goals Other Personal Finance Student Life Tips&amp;Tricks 
   Home / Personal Finance / Super Size Your Savings at Fast Food Restaurants… 
Super Size Your Savings at Fast Food Restaurants
 Aug 24th 2010 by Poranee Arthayukti Share 
“Would you like to supersize that?”  This is a phrase we often hear when we order our food at fast food restaurants.  The term originated from McDonald’s Super size trademark and has become commonly used when ordering food.  Although the campaign to promote larger sized orders has been removed, the extra large sizes are still available on the menu.

The success of this campaign resulted in other fast food restaurants following in McDonald’s footsteps in order to stay competitive.  To “supersize” your order means to make your order EXTRA large, extra large French fries (7 ounce) and extra large soft drinks (42 ounce).  Considering the fact that fast food is unhealthy, most people fall for this marketing campaign because they believe that they are receiving more  bang for their buck. But have you thought about how much money you could actually save by NOT supersizing your order? 

 Lets take a look at the price comparison between the “small” order vs. the “supersize” order from 4 different fast food chained restaurants. 

 1. McDonalds 

 Most popular meal: Big Mac Sandwich

Small (or regular) order: $ 5.79

Calories: 1270

 Nutrition Facts 

To upgrade combo:

Large: $ 0.64

Calories: 1520

 Note: The regular order at McDonald’s is a medium 

Calculation of savings (in dollars) if you were to NOT upgrade your combo at McDonald’s three times a week

 Saving per week: (3 x 0.64) = $1.92 

 Saving per month: (4 x 1.92) = $7.68 

 Saving per year: (12 x 7.68) = $92.16 

 

 2. Burger King 

Most popular meal: Double Whopper Sandwich

Small (or regular) order: $ 4.89

Calories: 1470

Add Cheese: $0.50

Total calories: 1520

 Nutrition Facts 

To supersize combo:

Large: $ 0.80

Calories: 1890

Calculation of savings (in dollars) if you were to NOT upgrade your combo plus chee se at Burger King three times a week

 Saving per week: (3 x 1.30) = $ 3.90 

 Saving per month: (4 x 3.90) = $ 15.60 

 Saving per year: (12 x 15.60) = $ 187.20 

 3. Jack in the Box 

 Most popular meal: Jumbo Jack Sandwich w/ cheese

Small (or regular) order: $4.07

Calories: 1185

 Nutrition Facts 

To supersize combo:

Large: $ 0.89

Calories: 1745

Calculation of savings (in dollars) if you were to NOT upgrade your combo at Jack in the Box three times a week

 Saving per week: (3 x 0.89) = $ 2.67 

 Saving per month: (4 x 2.67) = $ 10.68 

 Saving per year: (12 x 10.68) = $ 128.16 

 4. Carl’s Jr. 

Most popular meal: Famous Star Sandwich with Cheese

Small (or regular) order: $5.25

Calories: 1069

 Nutrition Facts 

To supersize combo:

Large: $ 0.89

Calories: 1550

Calculation of savings (in dollars) if you were to NOT upgrade your combo at Carl’s Jr. three times a week

 Saving per week: (3 x 0.89) = $2.67 

 Saving per month: (4 x 2.67) = $ 10.68 

 Saving per year: (12 x 10.68) = $ 128.16 

 

If these savings aren’t enough to convince you to not supersize your order, chew on this: many people don’t realize that the regular or small sizes on the menu are already more than half of the average calories that we need to eat per day.  And that is only from one meal!  The recommended daily calorie intake varies depending on your age, but for average adults it is 2000 per day for women and 2500 per day for men.  To find out more about the number of calories your body needs each day and tips on how to live a healthier lifestyle, check out the U.S Department of Health&amp;Human Services website. Just because you feel like you can get more food by adding a little less than a dollar doesn’t mean you should.  One of the interesting findings that I was not aware of before is the fact that McDonald’s “regular” size is already a “medium”, they actually don’t have a “small” size (other than the kid’s size).

To promote eating healthy and take better control of your finances, next time you make a quick stop at a fast food restaurant you should think twice when asked, “would you like to supersize that?”
 Share | 

 
 
 
 
Author : Poranee Arthayukti
 My Website | | 
 Articles from Poranee Arthayukti 
Poranee is currently a senior at University of California, Santa Barbara. She has interest in a career in public relations and event planning. She believes that a successful person is not just someone who is sharp-witted when it comes to making money but someone who is able to manage their finance effectively.
 
Related Posts


Related posts:

 4 Easy Ways to Reduce Dining Out Expenses 10 Little Ways to Save Money Every Day 8 Money Savings Items For The Home Sherpa Picks: Savings, Shopping, and More Grocery Challenge Week 2 Update 

 
 
 Bucksome 
I never supersize because of the money but now it&apos;s also because of health.
 Olivia aka the frugal Bohemian 
I often get the kid&apos;s meals at fast food places. Perfectly satisfactory. Plus you get a toy to give away! And why not split a &quot;regular&quot; meal with someone? A 42 oz of (refillable) soda is enough for a small army.
 
 blog comments powered by Disqus   Search
	</body>
</document>
