<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008764" url="http://www.ehow.com/donate-used-items/" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="1" score="0.00047963793067340893" bingtitle="Donate Used Items - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Donate Used Items - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Those who need to ship boxes to Canada may ... An invoice is an itemized bill that lists ... aspects of our culture referred to as &quot;throw away&quot; culture. Fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Discover the expert in you.
 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 More eHow 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Culture&amp;Society Donations Donate Used Items 
 
Donate Used Items

 
 RSS 
 How to Get Companies to Donate Items for Rehabbing a House 
Whether a home was destroyed in a natural disaster, or a struggling family can&apos;t afford to fix a leaky roof, those in desperate of home repair often turn to charitable organizations for help. Non-profit organizations that help to rehabilitate homes typically rely on donations from companies and corporations to provide the material needed to fix up the home. If your organization needs donations, write polite and concise donation letters to several local and/or national companies asking for the specific items you need well in advance of the planned hone rehabs.
 How to Donate Items to St. Jude 
St. Jude Children&apos;s Research Hospital is a medical facility that provides care to children battling cancer or other debilitating diseases. It also performs research. The organization&apos;s main mission focuses on conducting research to help prevent, treat and cure childhood illnesses. St. Jude primarily accepts monetary donations to help fund research, patient hospital costs and other areas of need. If you want to make a contribution to St. Jude&apos;s, several options are available to show your support.
 How Can I Make a Small Altar for My Grandma Here at Home? 
Altars have been used in public and private places for as long as recorded history. They provide a sacred place to worship as well as a place to honor and remember loved ones. By collecting and displaying items such as photographs and letters that reflect the person being remembered, the ritual of creating an altar can be one way of honoring the life of another person. Each altar is a unique expression of the person being remembered.
 How to Write a Benediction for a Ceremony 
A benediction is a blessing said over a person or a group of people at a time in their lives when they need grace. Therefore, the person who speaks the blessing is not only saying kind words; he is inviting a change to occur. Benedictions are often said at times of transition in people&apos;s lives, such as a graduation, wedding or baptism. Though a benediction is usually said by a clergy member, an individual can also provide others with their own blessing composed for the occasion.
 What Is the Meaning of White Magic? 
White magic is known as the opposite of black magic. White magic is used for good purposes by performing spells that help people in various ways,while black magic is used to harm people. White magic is the counter practice to evil and is conducted through several common means.
 How to Make a Caddo Stone Axe 
Native American Caddo tribes were concentrated in east Texas, but their range included Louisiana, Arkansas and Oklahoma. The environment they inhabited was the piney forests, which provided them with material for homes, weapons and tools. Axes were part of the Caddo toolbox that enabled them to fashion the wood from the forests into objects for everyday life or help them produce food from their fields or hunting trips. Seemingly primitive tools like axes used by the Caddo actually take technique and knowledge of the proper materials. Axes can be constructed today using the methods of the Caddo.
 Types of Japanese Scarves 
Japanese scarves range from the simple design and function of Tenugui head scarves to the elaborately detailed, highly stylized Maru Obi. Made from a variety of fabrics, including silk, cotton and brocade, Japanese scarves can feature a single color or employ ancient dyeing techniques and intricate embroidery work and textures to produce a one-of-a-kind scarf.
 How to Be an Altar Server in the Catholic Church 
The tradition of the server in the Catholic church goes back many centuries. Older people may still refer to &quot;altar boys,&quot; though this term has been replace by server, as girls, women and men may also perform this service. The admission of girls to the role is relatively recent, and the bishop of the diocese still makes the decision on this. It is considered an honor in the Catholic church to be a server. However, it is important that the person wants to do this, as it requires both reverence and commitment.
 How to Donate Used Campers in Hunt Valley, Maryland 
Most charities accept vehicles as a donation. Donating your old car or camper has become a popular way to give. It allows charities to make money by reselling your vehicle and you are able to get rid of your old clunker while receiving a tax deduction. Different charities have various requirements. Some charities require that you have title for your camper, but not all charities have that requirement. Your used camper does not have to be in running condition, and charities nationwide will come and pick it up.
 How to Conduct a Jean Drive 
A jean drive can provide clothing for families in need while also serving as a good community event. Collect jeans of all colors, styles and sizes for homeless shelters, schools, food pantries or places of worship to distribute at the beginning of the school year, in cold weather or during holidays. With just a little planning and a few well-placed donation bins, you can gather used jeans that will provide clothing for people of all ages.
 How to Build a Prayer Altar 
Building a prayer altar is a deeply spiritual and personal experience. Whether you practice a form of organized religion or you are simply a spiritual person, a prayer altar can be a meaningful way to pay worship to a respected spiritual figure or seek inner peace. You may also chose to create an altar to commemorate the passing of a loved one. Whatever your reason may be, you can create a prayer altar to provide a peaceful and sacred space for yourself.
 The Pros of Eyeglasses 
Eyeglasses are made up of frames and corrective lenses in order to improve a person&apos;s ability to see. With contact lenses and corrective eye surgery becoming more popular, less people are wearing eyeglasses. Before purchasing eyeglasses, it&apos;s important to be aware of the possible benefits, including eye protection and fashion accessory.
 Sources of Fountain Pen Ink 
Fountain pens are accessories as well as writing instruments. Many are works of art in their own right and even simple, cheap fountain pens are often very elegant. If you do a lot of writing, fountain pens are often much more comfortable to use than even the best roller ball because you can use such a light touch with them. However, fountain pens need special ink that is rarely available in most office supply stores.
 How to Mail Electronics With USPS 
Mailing valuable items through USPS can seem like a daunting task; it makes many people feel nervous. Knowing that anything can happen during the delivery process can make you may feel unsure of your packing abilities. Along with shipping insurance, proper packaging, and a tracking number, you can make sure that your package arrives at its destination safely. USPS also offers a service where they pick up your packages from your home, saving you the hassle and time of going to the post office.
 How to Live a Minimalist Lifestyle 
Minimalism, despite a reputation for frugality and self-denial, can lead to the simplification of everyday life. People who believe material things represent happiness often cannot see the chaos such &quot;stuff&quot; creates. Living a minimalist lifestyle not only removes physical clutter but also frees the mind of confusion and distraction in this complicated world. The objective, notes Leo Babauta in &quot;The Simple Guide to a Minimalist Life,&quot; is to streamline or downsize possessions so they reflect quality over quantity. Minimalists strive for simplicity in both thought and action to realize contentment.
 How to Be a Minimalist in Alaska 
Alaska has a network of homesteaders. It&apos;s a place where minimalist philosophies are common. The state attracts people from all over the U.S. because of its open spaces and sense of independence from the rest of the country. If you want to get away from the hustle and bustle, or cut down on complexity in your life, join others with the same dream in Alaska. But be sure that you are prepared for the difficulties a spartan lifestyle can present in a cold climate.
 Iconic Items From the 80s 
The 1980s, the era of early MTV and Ronald Reagan, ushered in some unforgettable fashion trends, as well as items that are firmly a part of 80s culture. Women&apos;s hair went short, a la Molly Ringwald, and big, a la Linda Evans. Guys grew their hair big and long and fashion trends included acid-washed jeans, leg warmers and the quirky accessories associated with Cyndi Lauper and a young Madonna. People still listened to cassette tapes and vinyl records as compact discs slowly entered the scene in the late 1980s, and young people especially occupied themselves with the iconic 80s toy,…
 How to Donate Blankets to Project Linus 
Project Linus is a volunteer organization that supplies blankets to children who are trauma victims, ill or simply in need. The blankets and afghans must be new or handmade. Any volunteer who makes blankets to donate to Project Linus is a &quot;blanketeer.&quot; Blanket dontations are received by a chapter coordinator. Each state in the U.S. has at least one chapter of Project Linus.
 Social Impacts of Incinerators 
Large-scale incineration is a waste-disposal method that serves as an partial alternative to landfills. Many countries, including the United States, use incinerators because they require much less land space than landfills and are sometimes more cost-efficient. However, incinerators often have other social impacts, both positive and negative, that can be controversial.
 The Negative Effects of Tokenism 
Tokenism is the practice of doing the bare minimum to meet requirements. This can apply to the inclusion of minority groups in schools, organizations or workplaces, and to minimal compliance with laws and regulations, such as environmental rules. In both instances tokenism can have negative effects on both the targeted group or idea and on the majority organization.
 How to Donate Bible Materials 
Ministries and charitable organizations often accept used or unneeded Bible materials from individuals or churches. Sometimes these include old Vacation Bible School curriculum, worn-out Bibles, outdated periodicals, sermons on DVD and literature. Depending on the organization to whom you are giving -- you may or may not be able to donate all of your used Bible materials -- as they might not have a use for them. Check that the denomination or beliefs exhibited in the materials you are donating align with the organization&apos;s beliefs before sending them, as they might not be able to use materials that contradict their…
 What Are the Practices of Black Magic? 
Black magic is the theme of many Hollywood productions, but Hollywood doesn&apos;t always get the facts right. In fact, black magic is part of the trinity of magic (black, white and grey). Ancient religions, as well as modern religions all over the world, mention the uses of black magic as well as the consequences.
 How to Go About Shipping a Bushel of Peanuts From Florida to Arizona 
The USDA has strict guidelines for people who want to send food through the mail. Since peanuts are not a perishable food, shipping a bushel of peanuts from Florida to Arizona does not require much preparation. Depending on the size of your package, you may need to use a private shipping company like UPS. The United States Postal Service will only ship packages up to 108 inches long. Packages heavier than 70 lbs. cannot be mailed through USPS.
 How to Bless Holy Oil 
Religion is heavily based on ritual and symbol. In the Catholic and Anglican churches, holy oil is one substance with ritualistic and symbolic value. Consecrated oils are used in anointing the sick, in church services, on Maundy Thursday (a Lenten holiday), and on other occasions. Both the Old Testament and the New Testament make reference to the sanctity and value of holy oils. Consecrating oil for religious purposes is a simple but solemn procedure.
 Religious Items and Gifts 
All around the world, religions of all sorts include items specific to their religion. Each of these items, whether designed for spiritual inspiration or commemoration, is geared toward helping its owner progress within his religion, and is often greatly appreciated when received as a gift. While many may think of images and statues when they consider religious items, there is actually a much larger variety of religious gifts you might give to someone.
 The Effects of Negative Energy Clearing 
Energy in the metaphysical arena focuses on that which is perceived in form as well as invisible presences and states of being. Walk into a room after the boss has screamed at an employee and you will experience an uncomfortable force even though the scene is over. Visit the site of a tragic event and you can&apos;t help but notice residual sadness. Negative energies include anything that creates discomfort, heaviness and the breaking of harmony. Positive energy is more aligned with inner knowing and the accompanying sense of freedom, innocence and true joy. Sources of negative energies can be cleared…
 Black Magic Tips 
The practice of black magic dates back to the year 50,000 B.C., where prehistoric man used drawings as a form of magic. Although controversial, practitioners of black magic believe its spells hold great power that can be used to manipulate relationships and health. Critics of black magic warn that the practice of spells can have negative consequences for both the practitioner and the recipient.
 Roles of Archbishops in 1154 to 1189 
Over the course of history, England has seen the role of its archbishops shift dramatically. Before the emergence of the Anglican Church, Catholic bishops commanded the religious authority in Britain, though the English monarchs greatly abhorred their influence. In mid 12th century the English monarchy proved an unstable yet ambitious force which relied upon and coveted the power of the archbishops.
 How to Bless Fire Equipment 
Blessing fire equipment is a sacramental way to grant protection. In the Protestant and Catholic faiths, praying over people and objects are ways to communicate with God and ask for direct blessings. The work of firefighters is an extremely dangerous profession, and blessing both workers and equipment provides a religious means of requesting a safety only God can provide. Anyone from firehouse chaplains to community members can bless firefighters and equipment.
 How to Make a Stone Ax 
The stone axe was an all-purpose utility tool and a lethal weapon throughout the Stone Age. Early societies used stone axes to chop wood, crush nuts and seeds and to fight with in battles. The versatility of the stone axe is surpassed only by its relative ease of construction. You can make it in the comfort of your own back yard. Make a stone axe as a household decoration, an accessory to a Halloween costume or just as an exercise in primitive survival.
 How to Donate Used Medical Equipment in Little Rock, Arkansas 
Extra walkers, mobility aids, crutches or even first aid equipment should not be sitting around gathering dust. This equipment is expensive and often used temporarily. Little Rock, Arkansas, residents with gently used medical equipment have a few local options to donate equipment for those who can&apos;t afford it. Review donation options and check with programs, because needs can change. If you&apos;re donating to a 501(c)3 organization or religious organization, ask for a receipt showing the fair market value of your donation. You can then deduct it on your taxes.
 How to Run a Clothing Give Away 
As many as 600,000 families in the United States are homeless and could use your help. If you&apos;ve ever wanted to give back to the community, one of the easiest ways to help is to organize a clothing giveaway. You can start by looking in your own closets and then get your community involved as well.
 How to Donate Handicapped Equipment in Cape Cod, Massachusetts 
Handicapped equipment is sometimes necessary after a period of illness or severe injury. However, these type of temporary disabilities often lead to owning handicapped equipment that is no longer needed. You may be looking to donate a gently used wheelchair, crutches or any other type of assistive device. Hospitals and medical supply stores do not usually accept used equipment, but there are other organizations in Cape Cod, Mass., that may.
 What Items Were in the Ark of the Covenant? 
The Ark of the Covenant signified the presence of God. This large chest, made of acacia wood, was built to hold three items of religious importance. Some religious scholars have claimed that they have uncovered the location of the Ark, they have produced no evidence. However, archaeologists are still searching for the Ark of the Covenant, in hopes of unlocking its contents and providing concrete evidence of our faith.
 How to Donate PICC Sleeves 
PICC-lines are peripherally inserted central catheters that are put into the arm typically for chemotherapy, feeding and antibiotics. Patients who have a PICC-line may have trouble with daily activities, which can be remedied by a PICCsleeve. PICCsleeves are covers made of material that can stretch over the PICC-line for comfort and concealment. As of April 2011, PICCsleeves are designed just for users with an elbow area PICC-line. You can give patients access to more daily activities by donating excess PICCsleeves to charitable organizations in your area.
 How to Critique an Event 
Organizations hold events for many reasons, including raising funds or bringing members together. It is not unusual for some organizations to hold the same event year after year. Critiquing the event provides a means to evaluate the event and helps event organizers make improvements in the future. Using designated evaluators to conduct the critique will help ensure that all aspects of the event are evaluated. By saving critiques and comparing them to subsequent years, an event organizer can determine whether he is producing better events. Critiquing an event takes some organization, but it is not difficult.
 Items of Brass Used in Worship 
Brass is a durable semi precious metal that is inexpensive and easily accessible. You can find brass all around you, in homes, office buildings and in churches. Brass hardware and accessories can be ornate, decorative, or shaped into functional items such as plates, cups and bowls. When it comes to places of worship, the denomination does not matter. Brass can be throughout many churches, synagogues, temples and worship centers, both indoors and out.
 How to Comply With the Made in the USA Standard 
After New York&apos;s World Trade Center was attacked in 2001, many people in the U.S. became more concerned about buying products that were made in the USA. The Federal Trade Commission, or FTC, requires that companies comply with certain standards before marking their goods as being &apos;Made in the USA.&apos; Legal action is taken when companies are found to be mislabeling items, but it is not overly difficult to comply with these standards as long as you are aware of the requirements and are following them to the best of your ability.
 How to Donate Used Eyeglasses in Sedgwick County, Kansas 
Sedgwick County, Kansas has a sophisticated recycling and donation program coordinated with organizations and businesses throughout the area. Donating used eyeglasses is Sedgwick is a simple and straightforward process. Consider giving away all used items you possess -- from eyeglasses to cell phones and clothes -- so others can put them to good use.
 How to Get Free Donations 
Free donations are the base for many events. If you&apos;re organizing a fundraiser for your child&apos;s school, for example, donations can serve as prizes or you can sell them for a direct profit. Or you run a nonprofit organization and need donations of equipment or materials to help the group keep going. Whatever the cause, getting those free donations to roll in can make or break your project.
 How to Support an Infant in an Orphanage 
Infants in orphanages rely on the employees, volunteers and the money that comes from generous donors. You can help to support an infant in an orphanage by donating money, goods and your time. With your support, you can give an infant a chance at a fruitful life.
 How to Donate Used College Textbooks 
Your old textbooks can be donated to help students both at home and abroad. They can also be used to support your local public library in its next book sale. Save your textbooks from the landfill by donating them to students who can use the knowledge inside them.
 The First Items Used to Give Tattoos 
The history of tattooing stretches back more than 5,000 years. Mummies of many different cultures bear varied designs applied in various ways, yet the basic function of all tattoo tools is to channel ink under the skin to create permanent designs. While the tattooed bodies of individuals are often found, the tools used to make these marks can be harder to uncover. Much of the information about early tattooing tools is pieced together from archaeological findings and cultures that have retained their ancient ways.
 How to Donate Scarves 
Scarves and warm clothing are in short supply for some families in winter months. Many organizations accept gently used items to distribute throughout the year. Whether the scarves you would like to donate are handmade or sit folded in your closet, they can be put to use quickly through donation to both local and national charity groups.
 How to Donate Used Bibles 
Most Christian families have a tendency to accumulate multiple Bibles over time as gifts, church awards and lesson planning tools. While paring down bookshelves, make sure any extra Bibles are put to good use through donation. Many individuals and organizations are eager to pass these books to those who do not own a single Bible of their own. Contact people you know personally or larger organizations to ensure your old Bible receive a new home.
 Items Used for the Egyptian Mummification Process 
Belief in the afterlife was an important element of ancient Egyptian culture. The Egyptian concept of the afterlife required preserving the body of the deceased as well as possible. This style of preservation, called mummification, was so advanced that modern scientists have learned much about how ancient Egyptians lived by examining their dead.
 How to Donate Religious Items 
Old bibles, crosses, prayer cards and other religious items can accumulate in a cabinet and get covered in dust. When you come across these items months or even years later, you might find that you have more than you want to keep. Instead of getting rid of extra items or putting them back to collect more dust, donate them to local institutions that will put them to use.
 Items That Would Be Found in a Tomb or Pyramid 
Ancient Egyptians, Mayans and Aztecs buried people --- mainly pharaohs, kings, high officials and those from rich and influential families --- in pyramids and tombs. Other parts of the world have traces of similar structures for the burying of significant and even common people in various cultures. Tombs and pyramids, especially in the most widely known Egyptian pyramids, have already withstood thousands of years of existence. They reflect the history, culture and mysteries of the ancient world.
 How to Donate Used Jeans With Holes 
Used jeans with holes are fashionable and can be a hot item for consignment stores and charitable organizations. However, some jeans with holes are not appropriate to donate so take a few minutes to check the quality. You can also re-fashion a pair of jeans into a cute skirt, shorts or place extra holes in appropriate places for a more fashionable look.
 How to Make the Linus Project No Sew Fleece Blankets 
Project Linus, named after the blue-blanket carrying &quot;Peanuts&quot; character, is a nonprofit organization that distributes good quality, clean, new homemade blankets to children in need. Project Linus accepts donations of only homemade blankets, as the organization states that it believes handcrafted items are more heartfelt. If you lack the time or ability to knit, crochet or sew a blanket, the organization will accept a simple no-sew fleece blanket.
 How to Calculate Volume of a Cauldron 
When working a spell that may require very specific measurements, you will want to make sure that your cauldron will be able to contain your brew. Certain herbs and other ingredients can be rare or expensive, so you will want to be prepared with the right-sized cauldron. Finding the volume of your cauldron will let you know just how much room is available, and if it will suit your needs for a particular preparation.
 How to Donate Used Jigsaw Puzzles 
Donating used jigsaw puzzles to charity is one way to give them new life. Many large charities operate stores that resell donated items at a fraction of the price of what they cost new. Other charities give donated items to those in need. If the charity can provide you with a tax receipt, you can deduct the value of the donated jigsaw puzzles on your tax return, giving you a small financial benefit to go along with the positive feeling you&apos;ll get from helping the less fortunate.
 What Items Were Buried With Mummies? 
To the ancient Egyptians, death was not the end, but rather the beginning of a new existence in the afterlife. Through the process of mummification, rich Egyptians and pharaohs believed they could live forever in the realm of gods and deities. Ancient Egyptians were hesitant to begin their new existence without bringing a few of their possessions with them to the afterlife, however. It was believed that whatever a person was buried with would travel with them into the afterlife. Due to thousands of years of grave robbing, most of what archeologists know of what Egyptians were buried with comes…
 Donated Items Needed for the Military 
Soldiers in war zones often feel disconnected from their lives back home. Care packages remind troops that they are being thought of and sending one is an easy way to show support for the troops. The military provides basic necessities, but the little things civilians may take for granted are not always available. If you would like to remind a soldier that someone cares, then donate an item that is in demand.
 How to Ship Media Mail by USPS 
If your items follow the requirements, shipping them via USPS media mail is an economical alternative to using first-class or priority mail due to the lower per-pound rates. Follow a simple step-by-step process to send media mail packages easily and quickly.
 How to Phrase Positive Affirmations 
The phrase &quot;thinking positively&quot; pretty much sums up what a positive affirmation is. It&apos;s a statement used to bring about positive life changes. Those who use positive affirmations believe that they reprogram the subconscious to allow for self-improvement and success. When phrasing affirmations, it&apos;s important to use wording that will weaken negative beliefs you have about yourself and help you bring about your desired results.
 How to Renovate a Warehouse Into a Church 
Depending on the condition of the warehouse, you could have your work cut out for you. The first things you should have inspected are the structure of the warehouse, the plumbing, and the electrical system. Hire professionals to make any adjustments to these structures as it can be dangerous to try to achieve this part of the project on your own. Have any light fixtures and bathroom components such as sinks and toilets, installed as soon as possible. These conveniences will be necessary or at least appreciated when you begin the other parts of the renovation.
 How to Help Poor Children in the U.S. 
In the United States, one out of every four children is listed as living below the poverty level. Many of these individuals go hungry each day, and they don&apos;t have the essential supplies that they need to succeed in school. Children and their families are the fastest growing homeless population in the United States. They currently account for 40 percent of the homeless population, according to the Hearts and Minds organization. To help these children, you can donate to local charities, or you can donate items to national charitable organizations for distribution.
 How Can I Get Organized? 
The pace of modern life can sometimes make you feel you need a personal assistant just to make it to the end of the day. The truth is, though, many people would benefit from taking a long, hard look at how they organize their affairs. Making small changes to the way you plan your daily life can pay dividends. Instead of hiring a virtual assistant or getting a housekeeper to take the pressure off, think about how you can make things easier for yourself.
 How to Donate Blankets to the Water Street Rescue Mission 
Water Street Ministries administers the Water Street Mission in Lancaster, Pennsylvania. A charity based on Christian values, this mission is the largest homeless shelter in the city. The mission seeks to go beyond merely providing temporary shelter. It offers programs aimed at helping clients find jobs and permanent housing. The Water Street Mission accepts donations of all kinds, including food, toiletries, clothing and blankets. It prefers blankets that are at least a twin size or larger.
 Where to Donate Used Items in Denver, Colo. 
Denver, Colo., has many thrift stores that accept donations. You can donate new and used items, which the thrift stores will sell at reasonable prices. Charities often operate thrift stores and use the profits from their stores to help their communities. Thrift-store donations also provide an environmental benefit. Large items, such as furniture and vehicles, usually end up in landfills or junkyards, even when still in working condition. Your donations may be tax deductible.
 Places to Donate Used Cars 
Many people know that charities all over the country accept donations in the form of monetary contributions and even donations such as furniture and clothing, but many do not know that they can donate a used vehicle to charity as well. Vehicle donations are accepted by a variety of charities all over the country, providing donors with an income tax deduction and charities with vehicles to donate to the needy or sell at auctions to use the proceeds to fund charitable organizations. Donors with used cars can donate by contacting a local charity, signing over the title of the vehicle…
 Items Found in Egyptian Mummy Tombs 
Excavations of tombs from ancient Egypt provide a fascinating look at daily life in Egypt, both for commoners and royalty, and of ancient Egyptian views on death and the afterlife. Specific features of tombs, the types of objects found in them and the treatment, adornment and dress of mummies all speak to the the station, beliefs and even personalities of the dead.
 Items That Are Made From Whale Bone 
Whale bone, also called &quot;baleen,&quot; has been used to create products for human enjoyment more so than as items of necessity. A craft known as &quot;scrimshaw&quot; became a slang term used to identify anything made during the free time of sailors, so many of the items made from whale bone are given this name. Accessory products, as well as clothing and tools, were once made from whale bone, but the endangerment of whales today has made this a less-prominent practice.
 How to Donate the Use of Commercial Property in Mesa, Arizona 
Donating unused or under-performing commercial property to a charity or a not-for-profit organization in Mesa, Arizona, is great way to help individuals in need of assistance. A residual benefit is that you, as the owner, can quickly realize tax breaks and other financial incentives. Whether you want to hand over ownership of your commercial real estate or just want to make your property accessible to groups or organizations on a more limited basis, helping others by providing access to your commercial buildings can make a real difference to those in need.
 How to Donate Auction Items 
Silent auctions are held to generate funds at charity events. Because the items are donated, any money taken in from the sale of an item is mostly profit for the organization throwing the event. Donating an auction item is relatively simple in most circumstances, as long as you do a bit of research on your organization and find an item that will do well at auction.
 How to Donate a Used Sink 
Remodeling your home is an opportunity to get rid of some old items in favor of new, updated versions. If you are remodeling your kitchen or bathroom and decide to update your sink, you may consider donating it to someone in need instead of disposing of it. Since kitchen and bathroom sinks are often expensive, many people may benefit from a sink that is in great working condition. Whether you donate your sink to a person or a charity, it gives you a chance to get rid of your sink and help someone less fortunate.
 How to Donate Used Tennis Shoes 
Most people toss out their tennis shoes at the first signs of wear, but often, the shoes are still perfectly functional. If you are concerned about the environment, enjoy helping others, or need to de-clutter your closet, you can donate your used tennis shoes to a number of different charities rather than sending them to a landfill. Even if your tennis shoes are ancient, stained and falling apart, you can keep your shoes out of the garbage and keep the planet a little greener by sending them to a shoe-recycling organization.
 How to Donate Used Stuffed Animals in Pennsylvania 
By donating used stuffed animals you are helping children that really need and value them. Your kids may lose interest in their stuffed animal toys as they grow up. In such cases, if the stuffed animals are in good condition, consider donating them instead of shutting them up in your cupboards and leaving them to gather dust. If you are in Pennsylvania and are thinking of donating your kids&apos; stuffed animal toys, there are a number of places to help you.
 How to Donate Used Running Shoes 
After taking a look at your shoe rack or cleaning out a closet, you may find you have more shoes than you could ever possibly wear. Instead of throwing out your old running shoes and sneakers, consider donating your shoes to one of the many organizations that appreciates donations of footwear. When you donate your old, gently worn shoes to an organization, you are doing much more than making more space in your closet; you are changing the world.
 How to Donate Pet Medications 
Perhaps your pet has passed away or no longer needs to take medication. As a result, you are left with new or partially used pet medications. Instead of disposing of the medication, you can donate it to a local animal shelter. Animal shelters and rescue organizations are always looking for cash or donations of supplies for the animals they treat and house. Donating pet medication helps other pets, contributes to a community organization and keeps medication out of the landfill.
 How to Kosher the Kitchen for Passover 
Every part of one&apos;s home is supposed to be cleaned for Passover, but the kitchen is of special importance because it is where chametz, or forbidden leavened products made from wheat, oat, barley, spelt and rye, are prepared. Traditionally, most surfaces can be prepared for Passover; however, you may wish to contact a local rabbi for more information about surfaces like granite and glass, as customs vary.
 How to Make a Cheap Parade Float 
Parade floats are a tradition for some events. Unfortunately, making a parade float can be a difficult and expensive endeavor. As such, it pays to know how to save as much money as possible and to assemble your parade float with as little strain on the pocketbook as you can. You&apos;ll have to get creative with your solutions sometimes, but creativity should be par for the course for a float.
 How to Donate Surplus Medical Supplies 
Hospitals, health care facilities and medical companies often need to discard surplus medical supplies due to various reasons. Whether it is new technology that renders your equipment obsolete or regulatory requirements that deem you discard existing supplies, you can put your surplus medical supplies to good use through donation. From free clinics in your local community to charitable organizations serving developing countries, there are a lot of places where your excess supplies can make a difference to the quality of health care people receive.
 How to Help Supply a Food Bank 
During tough times, charity organizations are hit especially hard. With individuals concerned about taking care of themselves and their families, they have fewer resources to donate to charity. Food banks are a prime example; when economic distress increases, the supplies in their larders often decrease. But there are many things you can do to get their stockpiles back up, whether you have a great deal of resources, or just a little bit of imagination.
 How to Get Something That&apos;s Been Flushed Down the Commode 
The idea that something important to you might be flushed down the toilet may sometimes seem laughable, but it&apos;s a fairly common occurrence. If you&apos;re unlucky enough to have this happen to you, then you may have a few options for retrieving what was flushed. However, toilets are meant to convey waste to somewhere far away, and they usually do that job very well. So you might be out of luck.
 Promotional Associations 
A promotional association is a group or organization designed to connect businesses and help them reach their target audiences. A company can promote its product or service by distributing items, usually imprinted with the company name, to potential customers. The items can be used as part of a specific marketing campaign or a general way to increase product awareness.
 How to Give a Cat Access Through a Baby Gate 
If you have both cats and small children, you may find yourself with a small dilemma. Blocking the children from certain areas of the home with a baby gate could end up closing in your family&apos;s felines as well. If you think about the differences in ability and size of your cats, you can discover a simple solution to this problem.
 How to Survive Culture Shock 
You may be an expat, an accompanying spouse or a student studying abroad. People going abroad often find it difficult to adjust to their host country. Culture shock is the feeling of disorientation that you experience when you leave the familiarity of your home and find yourself in the midst of new surroundings, a strange language and a stranger way of life. While the sound of a new place and the opportunity of change may seem inviting initially, the reality hits once you are actually into it. It may not be possible to make yourself immune to culture shock, but…
 How to Get Someone to Donate a Used Box Truck 
Charities often have to pick up items and deliver them places, such as donated food to distribute to needy people in soup kitchens and pantries, or furniture, clothing and other goods for the poor. If your charity needs to make a lot of pickups and deliveries, you might determine that you need a used box truck. When there isn&apos;t enough money in your budget to buy a truck, you will want to get someone to donate one.
 The Different Types of Skids 
A skid is another term used for a pallet used in freight transport. It is made of a base to which you can tie items securely. Unlike standard pallets, skids usually don&apos;t have a bottom deck for added security when transporting very heavy items and are smaller in size. Trucking companies commonly charge shipping clients by the skid.
 How to Donate Cashmere Sweaters 
Few things beat the comfort and softness of a cashmere sweater. If your sweaters no longer fit or are a bit out of style, donate them to a worthy cause. Before you pack up your sweaters and bring them in for donation, inspect them for holes and tears. If they&apos;re small enough, you can repair them yourself or take them to a tailor. If the tears are large, you can reuse the material for homemade pillows, stuffed animals, scarves or other crafts projects.
 How to Donate Used Eyeglasses in Kennett Square, Pennsylvania 
The Lions Club International has 45,000 clubs in more than 200 countries that provide services such as recycled eyeglasses to those in need. According to the Lions Club International website, 153 million people have uncorrected refractive errors. Most of these vision problems are quickly diagnosed and easy to treat with corrective eyeglasses. The Lions Club collects millions of eyeglasses each year and recycles them for just pennies. The Kennett Square, Pennsylvania Lions Club participates in this charity program.
 How to Donate Items to Goodwill 
Goodwill Industries is a nonprofit organization that has been helping people for more than a hundred years. Goodwill accepts tax-deductible donations from the public and sells the items in one of Goodwill&apos;s 2000 stores. Proceeds are used to help people in need by providing employment services such as training, further education and job placement. Goodwill accepts a variety of donations, including furniture, appliances, electronics, clothing, shoes and even vehicles. If you have any household items that you no longer use or need, you can help others by donating them to your local Goodwill organization.
 How to Help America&apos;s Poor 
Although the definition of &quot;poor&quot; is different amongst Americans, individuals and families who are unable to provide food, clothing and adequate shelter are all around us. As of 2005, the U.S. Census Bureau found that 37 million Americans were classified as poor in the United States. Day-to-day life for those individuals and families can be hard, but ways to help are easy and make our society a better place in the process.
 Things You Can Make From a Long Leather Coat 
A budget-friendly method of adding new items to your wardrobe is altering an old piece of leather coat into something new or into many new items, depending on the size of the coat. Working with leather, however, requires special consideration as it is a challenging fabric. Use appropriate cutting tools for optimal results. Ensure your sewing machine supports tougher fabrics.
 How to Donate Disability Equipment 
Donating medical equipment can provide much needed help to people who might not otherwise be able to afford it. Whether you wish to donate new or used equipment, you can find charity thrift stores, hospitals or care agencies that will accept your donation and even refurbish it for reuse. You can donate to organizations that help people internationally as well as local charities. Some will even provide pick-up at your house, making donation even easier.
 Places to Donate Office Equipment 
If you are no longer in need of your office equipment and don&apos;t know where to go to get rid of it, utilize these free donation services to take care of your dilemma. Not only does the recipient have the items to use, the office equipment is kept out landfills to be reused again. Donation facilities are located in your city and will accept any office equipment that is reusable.
 How to Donate Used Bunker Gear 
The protective clothing that firefighters use is known as bunker gear or turnout gear. This term generally includes items such as jackets, trousers, gloves and boots; in some cases, it may refer to protective equipment as well. After a few years of use, the bunker gear may start showing signs of wear, rendering it unfit for use by personnel actively involved in firefighting. It may be usable, however, in certain other situations such as training. Rather than disposing of used bunker gear, consider donating it.
 How to Donate Postage Paid Envelopes 
Postage-paid envelopes are not usually the first item on anyone&apos;s donation list. People often think of clothes, food or financial donations. But organizations and individuals have postal needs, and a wide variety of deserving recipients can make good use of postage-paid envelopes. Underfunded public service agencies, non-profit organizations and low-income individuals may need postage-paid envelopes.
 What Are the Advantages of Flail Shredding? 
Flail shredding is a term that refers to a specific type of mower. These mowers, which have blades that turn vertically rather than horizontally, are called flail mowers or flail shredding mowers. There are a number of distinct advantages to using these machines, whether you&apos;re landscaping a large or small property.
 Importance of Using Serving Utensils 
Serving utensils may not be the first thing you think of when considering food quality and good hygiene, but their importance extends into several aspects of service in locations ranging from the family dinner table to the cafeteria.
 How to Write a Social Responsibility Statement 
Many corporations have social responsibility statements. The statements outline the company&apos;s definition of corporate responsibility, and how they partake. Social responsibility for most companies means integrating public interest into the business model by self-regulating and following all legal and ethical guidelines. Social responsibility can also mean being proactive and working to solve community problems and eliminating corporate actions that cause harm or negatively impact the public, even if those actions are legal. A social responsibility statement is written for the public and employees of the company.
 How to Donate Used Bikes 
Donating your used bike can bring joy and happiness to needy, low-income individuals. Consider donating your used bike to a reputable local charity or program in your community. According to the International Bicycle Fund, if you want to donate your bike for repair, reuse and recycling, it is usually most practical and cost effective to donate it to a local program.
 How to Donate Used Electric Wheelchairs in Denver, Colorado 
Many charitable organizations rely on donations from individuals to help meet their mission and serve their clients. Nonprofits accept cash donations, but many organizations also accept product donations. Used electric wheelchairs may be donated to many types of nonprofit organizations in Denver. The organizations will then give the wheelchairs to people who may not be able to afford such equipment themselves. Wheelchair donations allow nonprofits to extend their services to a greater number of people.
 Enclosed Trailer Ideas 
Enclosed trailers are used for a variety of activities, from item storage to carrying tools for those who work on the move. Regardless of the purpose for the trailer though, chances are it&apos;s meant to store something -- and there are a lot of options that trailer owners have to maximize the storage potential.
 How to Donate Winter Coats in Gurnee, Illinois 
Maybe you&apos;ve decided that you&apos;ve had it with the long, cold winters in Illinois or maybe you have a house full of kids that outgrew their winter coats before they could wear them out. Either way, you&apos;ve decided to help out less fortunate people this year and donate a winter coat - or several - to someone in need. Fortunately, for both you and those in need of winter coats, there are several places in Gurnee where you can make your donation.
 Pranks to Play on Sleeping People 
A sleeping friend or family member provides ample opportunity to pull off a funny, memorable prank that everyone can laugh at later. There are countless funny pranks you can do on someone who is sleeping, but some of the best include shaving cream, using makeup and changing the time on house clocks. When planning your next prank think outside the box, be creative and find inspiration from regular household items.
 Problems With Silicone Spray&amp;Screen Printing 
Screen printing, or silk screening, is a very old method of creating images on flat or relatively flat mediums. Screen printing is done in both industrial as well as private settings for a number of products, including clothes, posters, signs and other items. Silicone sprays are advertised for use in some screen printing operations, but they also can cause problems with the process.
 How to Run a Fundraiser Dinner 
Raising funds for charities and non-profit organizations is a continual process. The act of generating revenue can become taxing at times when one tries to come up with different avenues to pursue in order to raise money. One option for a fundraiser is a charity specific dinner. Organizing and running a fundraiser dinner takes pre-planning and a focus on details. The event should be planned well enough in advance to ensure that the maximum amount of people can and will attend.
 How to Donate Used Shoes in Los Angeles 
Styles change, and for those who update their wardrobes accordingly, old shoes can start to gather. Children also outgrow shoes that can still be worn. If you have used shoes to donate, programs exist where donations are accepted for charitable purposes. Throughout Los Angeles, programs are in place to provide needy recipients with older or used shoes.
 How to Donate a Used Hospital Bed 
You&apos;ve come into possession of a hospital bed for some reason or other and are looking to get rid of it. Before tossing it out on the street and thus creating more trash in the world, look into donating it. There are many charitable organizations that will accept hospital beds as well as other hospital equipment, and such donations are often tax-deductible. Donating the bed to family or friends, homeless shelters or international charitable organizations are just some ways to dispose of your hospital bed responsibly.
 Blacksmith Shop Tools 
A blacksmith is a craftsman who works with iron and steel. In the past, the blacksmith was an important figure in many communities. The blacksmith and his assistants used a variety of specialized tools to create weapons, utensils, household goods, tools and other items. While blacksmiths are not as prominent as they once were, blacksmithing is a popular hobby, art and handicraft.
 How to Send Boxes Overseas 
One place where it is clearly evident that our planet is getting smaller is in the realm of overseas shipping. Not only does the U.S. Postal Service ship overseas, but it has several competitors in the private sector that are all vying for the opportunity to ship your precious little gift to France, Australia, Hong Kong or wherever you deem necessary. Most residents live close enough to a shipping office that a visit to these places is not a big inconvenience. And a few of the companies will even come by and pick your item, if you live in a…
 How Can I Donate to Goodwill? 
Rather than throwing out items in your house or garage that you may not need anymore, donate the items to Goodwill. Goodwill Industries International accepts a variety of donations, and 83 percent of revenue generated from donations goes into funding Goodwill&apos;s employment and training programs. Whether you have old toys, clothes, furniture or even a car, donating those items to Goodwill is easy.
 How to Donate Small Bottles of Shampoo&amp;Soap 
Those little bottles of shampoo, lotion and other toiletries you receive in your hotel room are often a convenience if you&apos;ve forgotten your own. However, if you don&apos;t use them or only use a small amount, you can donate these sample-size items to various charities. For many poor families, purchasing soap and shampoo is secondary to buying food. In developing or war-torn countries, these items are difficult to obtain. Women&apos;s and homeless shelters need toiletries for people having a tough time.
 What Is Gum Arabic Used For? 
Gum arabic is a natural gum made from the hardened sap of the Acacia seyal and Acacia senegal trees that grow from Senegal to Somalia on the African continent. This is the best area for harvesting Gum arabic.
 How to Donate Used Equipment 
Charitable donations take many shapes and sizes - from computers and household electronics to office, medical and sports equipment. By the same token, different non-profit organizations accept different donations, based largely on what they have identified to be in need. While the Salvation Army and Goodwill Industries, for example, might be looking for clothes, food or office equipment, Recycles.org could be targeting computer equipment. A good launching point is Freecycle.org, an online network that matches donors with non-profits within given communities.
 How to Donate to Troops in Iraq 
Thousands of U.S. citizens are in other countries serving with the military. Many people know at least one person who has served overseas, whether it be a friend or family member. Care packages and letters are popular gifts that are given to our troops every day by friends, family and even strangers. As of 2010, about 50,000 troops are stationed in Iraq. Donating a letter, money or care package is possible through Give2TheTroops, an organization that organizes, collects and sends donations. Items donated to Give2TheTroops are tax deductible.
 How to Donate Used Electronics 
Donating your used electronics is a great way to provide help for needy or low-income members of your community. According to the United States Environmental Protection Agency, donating used electronics extends the lives of valuable products and keeps them out of the waste stream for a longer period of time and also allows schools, nonprofit organizations and lower-income families the ability to obtain equipment that they otherwise could not afford.
 How to Send Care Baskets to Marines 
Marines deployed overseas do not have access to all of the comforts of home and sometimes not even some of the necessities of home. Whether you know a particular Marine personally, you can still send a care package to wherever she is deployed to let her know you care. There are quite a few things to keep in mind before sending your package that will help make the process easier for you and for the Marine receiving your care package.
 How to Feed Kids in Africa 
Many children in Africa are malnourished due to extreme poverty and a lack of readily available food. According to Food4Africa, one in ten infants will die in Africa within the first 12 months of life due to malnutrition and starvation.
 How to Donate Used Phones 
According to ReCellular, &quot;one in three Americans will replace their cell phones this year, adding to the 500 million unused phones currently waiting to be discarded or recycled.&quot; If you have a new cell phone and want to dispose of your old one, there are many options available. You can recycle the phone, send the phone to a soldier, or donate the phone to domestic violence victims or seniors so they can dial 911 in case of an emergency.
 How to Identify Tin Plating 
Tin plating has been a common practice in the past for electronic components, including pieces used in satellites, according to ieeexplore.ieee.org. However, tin plating can create problems when it forms whiskers or small juts of tin that look like narrow slivers. The plating can cause problems in tight, closed-in spaces. Many companies identify tin plating on parts to replace them before they cause a problem.
 How to Donate Used Prescription Glasses 
When you are an eyeglass wearer, there are a number of reasons to change your glasses. It could be that your prescription has altered or maybe you just want a new style. The problem that you are then faced with is what to do with the glasses that you no longer use. In the United States and around the world there are people who are unable to afford the luxury of a pair of glasses for themselves. With the help of charitable organizations and donations made by eyeglass wearers, underprivileged men, women and children have an opportunity to see clearly.
 Zacharias Janssen&apos;s Cell Theory 
Zacharias Janssen played an important role in the development of cell theory, through his development of the first primitive microscope, according to the University of Miami’s Department of Biology.
 How to Ship Boxes to Canada 
Those who need to ship boxes to Canada may feel overwhelmed about going through the whole process. They may feel that it will cost them a lot of money to ship the boxes. Knowing what you are shipping and who you are shipping to is important because it will save you money on shipping costs. First, you should know how to prepare your boxes for shipping before you send it. Learn the basics of shipping before determining how to send your boxes. Then determine how you want to ship your boxes to Canada.
 How do I Donate Hospital Supply Surplus? 
If you have a job that has left you with some excess hospital supplies, or if you have just been taking care of someone sick, that surplus of goods can be donated to people in need. Both national and local health-related charitable organizations that accept donations of surplus hospital supplies exist throughout the United States. Donating your extra hospital supplies not only helps someone in need, but it can also qualify you for a tax write-off for the donation.
 The Effect of TV Commercials 
TV commercials are an interesting psychological phenomenon. Not only do they sell products, they are an important socializing instrument, promoting conformity and encouraging consumerism on a subconscious level. They do so by combining entertainment with long-term product branding.
 Pros&amp;Cons of Incinerators 
Incinerators have long been debated by environmentalists as well as all concerned stakeholders. Whatever the side of the debate you lean toward, it is clear that the country has a massive amount of trash that needs to go somewhere. In addition, there are some definite pros and cons to using an incinerator. Learn about some of the leading arguments for and against the use of incinerators.
 How to Donate a Massage Bed in Cape Cod 
If you are closing down a spa, or if you have a massage bed in your home that you no longer want, you can donate the massage bed. In Cape Cod, a variety of organizations accept massage bed donations. Massage beds are not just for spas, but can be used by organizations such as Cape Cod schools or care facilities. You can find local and national organizations in the Cape Cod area for your donation. In fact, you may even be able to claim the massage bed donation on your taxes as a write-off.
 How to Donate Unused Print Cartridges 
If you&apos;ve recently purchased a new printer, you might have some unused ink cartridges lying around that you can&apos;t use anymore. Rather than selling them or throwing them away, why not donate them to a worthy cause? Ink cartridges are expensive, and there are many people and organizations that would love some free ink. By donating these ink cartridges rather than tossing them, you will be getting rid of your clutter and helping someone else in the process.
 Fire Rescue Tools 
The tools a fire department needs depends on the location, size and scope of the department and the community it serves. A small-town volunteer department, for example, will have very little use for air lift houses or air lift pads; however, a big-city department may use them all the time. Items like rescue saws, jaws of life and individual fire axes will be found in most departments of any size.
 How to Donate Baby Supplies 
It would be a shame to throw out usable baby clothes and supplies after your little ones outgrow them. Teen mothers, homeless families and babies overseas may be thankful for these supplies. If you are feeling like being extra empathetic, spend 20 or 30 dollars to buy some new items to give to these charities. Not only will the recipients benefit--so will you!
 How to Donate Plastic Bottle Caps 
According to the Clean Air Council, &quot;Americans throw away 2.5 million plastic bottles every hour.&quot; To compound this problem, people who do recycle plastic bottles, often cannot find a recycling program that will accept plastic bottle caps, so they end up throwing the caps in the trash. You may have to do a little investigating, but there are organizations that encourage the public to donate plastic bottle caps to their cause.
 Where Can I Donate Used Medical Equipment? 
Non-profit agencies throughout the United States collect used medical equipment to refurbish and provide to those in need. Repaired and refurbished used medical equipment is provided to seniors, children and others who could not otherwise afford necessary equipment.
 How to Donate Shoe Boxes 
In recent years, the concept of donating shoe boxes has become the norm. For example, many nonprofit organizations accept shoe box donations for contribution efforts to feed the needy and send care packages to overseas troops. School districts accept shoe box donations for student art projects and community contributions. Thrift stores and fleas markets accept shoe box donations for incoming inventory and to display merchandise. Donating shoe boxes to family and friends frees up space in your house while providing them with craft ideas.
 How to Donate Soccer Shoes 
When young soccer players continue to play the game for several years, parents can find themselves surrounded by sports equipment their children no longer use. While the equipment may be in fine condition, its original owner may have outgrown the jersey, shin guards, or cleats. Donating used sports equipment and apparel, such as soccer shoes, removes clutter from your garage and gives other children to enjoy the game.
 Chinese Playground Games 
Many Chinese playground games have a very long history, dating back decades and in some cases centuries. They are entertaining yet inexpensive games, with few if any props required that cannot be handmade using items around the house. Yet these games can help to develop a child’s physical and mental skills and social interaction.
 How to Donate Used Refrigerators 
If you are replacing the appliances in your kitchen, there is no need to toss out your old used refrigerator. Instead, you can donate that used refrigerator to a local charity. There are both national-level and local-level charities that accept used furniture donations. The charity will either sell the used refrigerator in one of its thrift stores or put it in a shelter or home that is in need of a refrigerator. If the charity sells the used refrigerator, the money will typically be used for any programs the charity offers.
 How to Donate a Dining Set in Connecticut 
Donating furniture is a great way to not only see an unnecessary item in your household put to good use, but to ensure it goes to someone in need. Often families may need furniture, but cannot afford to buy it due to other critical expenses, such as food, shelter or medicine. If you have a dining set that you no longer need, or are not using, there are numerous ways to donate it in Connecticut and get it to someone who will benefit from your generosity.
 How to Donate Used Televisions 
If you are upgrading your television to a big-screen TV, you may not want to keep around your smaller, used television. As long as your used television still works, you don&apos;t have to throw it out. Instead, you can donate your used television to a local charity in your area. When you make a used-television donation to a charity that happens to be a registered non-profit, you can actually claim your donation on your taxes for a write-off.
 How to Donate Electronic Testing Equipment 
After years of service, electronic testing equipment can become worn and may malfunction, leading to improper disposal. Often times, out-of-date test equipment is stored away, to make room for modern equipment. You can donate these old or malfunctioning devices to local organizations, who can refurbish and resell them to the public and benefit from the proceeds.
 Recovery After a Fire 
A fire is one of the most devastating things a person or family can go through, particularly as a homeowner. If not brought under control quickly, a fire can destroy everything a person has, leaving him or her with a long road to recovery. Government agencies, insurance and charities can help make that road less difficult.
 The Difference Between a Seal and a Stamp 
Both &quot;stamp&quot; and &quot;seal&quot; have multiple definitions, though in many contexts the two words are interchangeable. A seal is, according to &quot;The Free Dictionary,&quot; a &quot;die or signet having a raised or incised emblem used to seal an impression on a receptive substance such as wax or lead&quot; or &quot;the impression so made.&quot; A stamp, more generally, is defined in the same source as an &quot;implement or device used to impress, cut out, or shape something to which it is applied&quot; or an &quot;impression or shape formed by such an implement or device.&quot; Both words can also refer to the…
 Uses for Old Toilets 
With so many people concerned about the environment, many are looking for new ways to reuse something that would otherwise be discarded at a dump. One item that is particularly difficult to recycle is an old toilet. It can be difficult to decide what to do with one other than just throwing it away. Fortunately, there are other options.
 How to Donate a Futon 
Futons typically have a frame and mattress, which can make them difficult items to donate. Some charities will not accept futons at all because they do not accept mattresses. Do not let that discourage you, though, because some charities, including some Goodwill locations, will take both the futon frame and the mattress, as long as they are in good condition. If you make your donation to a charity with tax-exempt status, you can even claim the fair market value of the futon on your taxes.
 Types of Pyramids in Egypt 
The ancient Egyptian burial rituals were elaborate and complicated. Pharaohs and lesser officials constructed pyramids for their eternal resting places. Over time, pyramids grew larger and more complex with rooms for daily items necessary for the occupant to use in the afterlife. The development of pyramids was an evolutionary process and changed from one type to another.
 How to Pack Cookies to Send to Iraq for the Soldiers 
A deployed soldier treasures the wonderful boxes of baked goods sent from loving people at home. There is nothing worse than a soldier getting a bag full of smashed cookies. They can look more like bread crumbs or cereal than cookies. To a soldier baked goods from home are just heavenly. Packing them carefully is easy and only takes a little bit of extra time and effort. Having a happy soldier on the other end will make it all worth your time.
 How to Donate Used Dental Equipment 
In the 21st century, a variety of organizations can facilitate your desire to donate used dental equipment---nationwide medical organizations, religious organizations or organizations on the state level. Your donation can help dentists in developing countries or dentists who work in clinics that assist low-income people.
 How to Donate Goods to Vietnam Vets 
If you have clothing or other household goods you no longer need or want, you can donate those items to Vietnam Vets through the Vietnam Veterans of America (VVA). The organization has a donation program set up specifically for goods. Donations made through this program are tax deductible. As of April 2010, the program does pickups in 30 states. In other states, donations must be taken to a VVA-affiliated thrift store, some of which may offer pickups to limited areas.
 How to Donate Kitchen Items 
Many charitable or non-profit organizations welcome the donation of kitchen items. Properly documented charitable donations are tax-deductible. Before deducting such donations from your taxes, you must determine the market value, taking into consideration the items&apos; condition and age.
 How to Calculate Postage for Australian Post 
Tired of electronic communication and plan to send a letter the traditional way, via postal service? If currently residing in Australia, plan to send any communications via the Australia Post. The Australia Post provides regular and expedited services.
 How to Donate Used Building Materials 
There are a few organizations that accept the donations of used building materials. They then generally sell these donated materials to the public at a tremendously discounted rate. Retailers, contractors as well as individuals in the community can all make donations. Donating your used building materials is a great way to be socially and environmentally responsible by keeping good, used materials out of landfills and waste streams.
 Break Room Clean-Up Etiquette 
Break rooms in the workplace are communal areas. It is important to consider your co-workers when using the break room and to consider how you would want them to treat the area for your benefit. There are some simple rules that should be applied to the break room to make it convenient and useful for all and to ensure that the short time for the break can be enjoyed.
 How to Donate a Used Motorcycle 
Donating a used motorcycle is a great way to help an important charity and receive a sizeable tax donation. Local and national charities exist that accept motorcycle donations--whether the motorcycle works or not. Many of these charities will pick the vehicle up from your home, making the donation process relatively simple for those who want to give.
 How to Donate a Used Sofa 
Donating a used sofa is a relatively simple way to positively impact your community. Many people and families are unable to afford new furniture, and donating your used sofa can make a tremendous difference in their lives. By utilizing national and local charitable organizations, including web-based organizations, you can fairly easily donate a used sofa to someone in need.
 How to Get Donations for a Fundraiser 
Fundraiser donations may include supplies, staffing, prizes and related elements to help the event operate efficiently. Donations can reduce your fundraising expenses and help local businesses expand their community outreach efforts. Learn how to get donations for a fundraiser by using the collective efforts of your organization and local resources.
 How to Create a Free Invoice Online 
If you are a business person who plans to extend products and services to customers on credit, you must get familiar with the invoicing process. An invoice is an itemized bill that lists the products you sent to a customer and asks for payment by a certain date. The invoice contains a set of terms for the customer to meet. If you&apos;re pressed for time, there are a few methods you can use to create invoices online quickly for free.
 How to Donate Used Bicycles 
Although you may know that you can donate a car to charity for a tax deduction, you might not know that you can donate a used bicycle to charity and get a tax deduction. Local and and even international charities accept used-bicycle donations. Overseas, that unwanted bicycle in your garage could help someone get to work. Donating your bicycle, wherever it winds up, is easy to do.
 How to Donate Medical Supplies to Third World Countries 
Third World countries often lack the financial means and access to medical supplies necessary to sustain or improve the quality of life. For many who live in a Third World or underdeveloped country, medical care for checkups or even an illness is a luxury instead of a right. If you have medical supplies and want to donate to a Third World Country, it is imperative that you follow these steps to make sure that your donation is given to those in need and that you follow Internal Revenue Service guidelines.
 How to Donate Used Goods in New Jersey 
More than 10 million individuals donated used clothing, furniture, and household items to the Salvation Army alone in a single year. Charitable organizations typically resell your donations in a thrift store, and use the proceeds to fund programs to help the needy. Donating used goods not only helps those who are less fortunate than you, but can also be claimed as a tax deduction, thus lowering your tax bill. Here are ways you can donate items you no longer want in the state of New Jersey.
 How Do Picnic Coolers Work? 
Given its features, a picnic cooler is a perfect alternative to the traditional picnic basket or lunch bag.

Picnic coolers come in different styles and sizes---depending on the specific needs of each user. There is a wide array of designs available for picnickers, backpackers, mountaineers, travelers, students and employees who bring their own food to work.
 How to Live Frontier Style 
Frontier life in the late 1800s was a hardscrabble, lonely, back-breaking existence, far from the cozy picture often painted in movies and television shows, says PBS, which produced the &quot;Frontier House&quot; series. Little thought was given to comfort as settlers concentrated on basic survival, and more than half gave up their claim before five years had passed, a &quot;proving up&quot; period the government required before the land became theirs. One man posted this on the door of his abandoned shanty, &quot;One hundred miles to water. Twenty miles to wood. Six inches to hell. God bless our home. Gone to live…
 How to Donate Used Goods to AMVETS 
AMVETS, American Veterans, is a charity organization that helps not only veterans and their families, but also nonmilitary individuals, by providing a thrift store that sells clothing, household goods and other items. The services that AMVETS provides to veterans and their families is free and executed by officers accredited by the Department of Veterans Affairs. There are two ways to donate your used goods to AMVETS---by taking the items into one of the organization&apos;s stores or by having the company come and pick up the items at your home or business.
 Types of Compactors 
In our modern, technologically advanced world, there are aspects of our culture referred to as &quot;throw away&quot; culture. Fast-food restaurant packaging, single-use cans and paper towels are good examples of items that are manufactured to be used and then thrown in the garbage. Because of the amount of waste this generates, both businesses and individuals often find themselves in need of compactors to force their refuse into smaller, more manageable chunks.
 How to Create a &quot;Missing&quot; Sign 
Something you love and cherish has gone missing? Perhaps a loved pet. Not sure how to let others know or how to get them to contact you? Create a &quot;Missing&quot; sign. These signs are predominantly posted when a person or pet has gone missing, but you can utilize these types of signs for almost any type of missing item.
 How to Mentor Children of Incarcerated Parents in Your Neighborhood 
When a child&apos;s parents are incarcerated, it causes her to feel alienated, afraid, hopeless and angry, even if the child is living with relatives or in a foster home. Whether you operate your own mentoring agency or you&apos;re a concerned neighbor who wants to help the children of incarcerated parents, there are ways to do this. If you have children, you can invite the child over for dinner on the weekends and have her play with your children.
 How to Donate Military Items 
Donating military items is an easy way to support the troops and the less-fortunate of your country. With particular military items, such as journals or personal histories, donating them to museums or similar institutions is a generous way to assist in keeping a collective memory, as well as in educating civilians about military life and war.
 How to Donate Sewing Material 
Donating unwanted sewing material is a good way to reduce the size of your fabric stash---and help people in need at the same time. Many organizations, such as Care Wear Volunteers, which is dedicated to providing handmade baby items to hospitals, are centered around sewing for those in need. Nursing homes and hospitals often have sewing groups that make lap quilts for long-term patients, while many home economics and art teachers would be delighted to receive fabric donations.
 Home Owners Association Budget Checklist 
Prior to creating a budget it is a good idea to create a checklist to ensure that all items are accounted for and everyone in the budget-making process has had an opportunity to review and comment. The checklist should be in a format that is easy to read, print and distribute so that there is full accountability and ability to edit.
 How to Make Hawaiian Salt 
True Hawaiian salt is made by native Hawaiian families and never sold for a profit. The process of making the salt is long and tedious; however, the result is a pure salt that holds nutritional and sacred value. Alaea, which is red volcanic clay, is added to the salt during the final stages of salt making. Hawaiian salt contains trace minerals that are beneficial to the body. It also makes an excellent rub for foods such as pork and fish, and when used as a marinade results in very tender, well-flavored meat.
 How to Donate Stuffed Bears 
Donating bears to a charitable organization or for a holiday gift drive is a wonderful thing to do. Many children are not as fortunate as others are, and every child deserves to have a lovable toy. You may donate a gently used stuffed bear that your child or yourself has owned, or you can purchase a new one to give to someone in need. Either way, you can donate knowing a child has received a treasured gift.
 What Is the Meaning of Rag&amp;Bone Shop? 
A Rag and Bone Man is a British occupational term used to describe an individual who collects discarded items (or refuse) for resale. Although the traditional Rag and Bone Man is no longer active in the United Kingdom, Rag and Bone Men were common throughout the 19th century and even during the first half of the 20th century.
 How to Donate Used Home Disability Equipment 
Whether with a change in home health medical treatment or the passing of a loved one, many people must find a way to dispose of any used home disability medical equipment not rented or on loan from a medical equipment supplier or through a medical insurance program. Recycling the equipment by donating it to an individual or charitable organization for distribution to people in need is often considered the best disposal method unless the equipment was custom designed (for example, custom-fit body braces). Finding an individual or organization to donate to isn&apos;t difficult and only requires that you reach out…
 How to Eulogize a Loved One 
Eulogies are offered as a retrospective of a deceased person&apos;s life and often pay tribute to that&apos;s person&apos;s accomplishments and those he has influenced. They play an important part of a memorial service or funeral and are often given by people who knew and shared in the person&apos;s life, including colleagues, co-workers, and family members. While emotionally taxing, writing and delivering a eulogy need not prove as difficult as it might seem, as long as you keep a few key ideas in mind when crafting and approaching the recital of your speech.
 Weight Room Etiquette 
When using gym equipment in a public place, it is important to be considerate of others. You should always conduct yourself the way you would expect those around you to behave.
 How to Donate Used Cars to Troops 
Your vehicle donation could make a huge difference in the life of a soldier in the United States Armed Forces. It&apos;s a great way to say thank you and to give a little something back to the men and women who have fought for our country and our freedom. Donating your car will also provide you with a sizable tax deduction on your federal tax return.
 How to Donate Coats to Dry Cleaners 
With so many people in need in America, donating gently used clothes is a charitable way to help out. Donating clothes is a very rewarding deed that can also be written off as a tax credit. Donating is not time consuming and is a convenient way to clean out your closet. Many dry cleaners accept donated items such as pants, shirts and coats, and you can make a difference is many people&apos;s lives.
 How to Donate a Gas Grill 
If you have a gas grill that&apos;s in good working order but you no longer need it, there&apos;s no reason to throw it away. Instead, donate it to a local charity or nonprofit organization. Donating a gas grill to a nonprofit is tax deductible, so be sure you get a receipt when you make your donation.
 How to Make a Spirit Stick 
Spirit sticks are often used in camp environments as tools for encouraging teamwork and creativity. Groups win the chance to carry the spirit stick after winning challenges. At the end of the camp session, the group of campers that has won the most challenges and displayed the best sportsmanship wins the stick.
 Black Magic Vs. White Magic 
Magic has been around for centuries, but the fear of magic has resulted in many horrible atrocities, most notably the Salem witchcraft trials. Magic is unnerving to many people, yet the difference between black and white magic is the first step to understanding.
 How to Arrange a Kitchen Counter 
Because of constant use, a kitchen counter can easily become messy and chaotic. A cluttered counter will discourage you from cooking and fully enjoying your kitchen. If you have this issue, set aside a day to properly organize the space. The final arrangement of your kitchen counter will largely depend upon its shape and size. But if you want it to be an efficient working area, there are a few concepts you should keep in mind no matter how your counter is shaped.
 The History of Metal Fabrication 
Any time that one form of metal is manipulated or changed into another form, it is called &quot;fabrication.&quot; Metal fabrication is primarily used in industry, jewelry arts and crafts, and technological areas. It is a generally accepted belief that metal was discovered before people began to write and was first used to make tools and weapons such as arrowheads. Metal fabrication processes and techniques are also scientifically referred to as metallurgy.
 How to Organize a Front Entrance Closet 
The front entrance closet is often the last door you open before you leave the house, and the first door you open after you come home. It is a place to store everything you need to go outdoors, such as coats and scarves, as well as common household items like pet food and tools. Many front entrance closets also have shelving at the top for storage.
 Hot Bar Solder Process 
Soldering is a process that&apos;s used to attach two items with a bonding agent called solder (pronounced sauder). Solder can be made of different compositions, but often it will contain silver or lead, along with bronze and other metals that will bond strongly. Lead solder will melt at a lower temperature than silver solder, but it&apos;s also softer and easier to break. Traditional soldering is done by melting a wire of solder so that it connects two materials. While hot bar soldering achieves the same result, it does so through vastly different means.
 How to Donate Used Exercise Machines 
Many of us have old pieces of exercise equipment lying around the house taking up much needed space. We may have purchased the equipment after making a New Year&apos;s resolution to shed unwanted pounds. Or it may have simply been left behind when our children left home to go to college. There are many ways to donate used exercise or sports equipment. Here are a few ideas to get you started.
 How to Make a Stone Hand Axe 
Stone hand axes are bifacial (tool with two working surfaces) stone tools used by early humans from c. 2.6 million through c. 30,000 years ago (Lower and Middle Paleolithic eras). 

Stone hand axes are made through lithic reduction. Lithic reduction is the process of using a hard object, usually a hammerstone, on a softer stone to remove flakes of the core stone until the desired form is achieved.
 How to Get Businesses To Donate Items For A Raffle Fundraiser 
Raffles can be a great way to raise funds for a non profit group or project. Items for the raffle can usually be obtained free by asking area businesses for donations. Asking for donated items is a lot easier then asking for money because not only can you give the business free advertisement but the process is a lot easier for the business.
 Equipment Soldiers Want or Need for Iraq 
Throughout Iraq, soldiers are in need of equipment necessary to complete their mission and to make daily life more bearable. According to a number of reports and aid agencies, this equipment can be supplied by care packages or by pressuring the Pentagon to outfit the troops adequately.
 The History of Deseret Industries in Sacramento 
Deseret Industries is a non-profit organization that was established by Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints (LDS). Sacramento, California is the location for one of the 40-plus stores across the United States.
 Silver Plate vs. Sterling Silver 
Sterling silver objects contain silver and another metal, which helps the object retain its shape, since pure silver is soft and easily shaped. Silver-plated items, compared to sterling objects of the same size, are heavier. Sterling silver is an investment that retains value, whereas silver-plated items lose their value quickly.
 How to Donate Useful Items to Shelters for Abused Women and Their Children 
To honor National Domestic Violence Awareness Month (October), many people may find a desire in their heart to make a difference. Since nearly 2 million women are abused by their intimate partner each year (not to mention the effects on their innocent children), chances are high that you know someone victimized by domestic abuse, or have been in an abusive relationship yourself this article . This article will give detailed information on how to go about making donations of goods and services which will directly benefit battered women and their children in your local area.
 How to Donate Used Soccer Jerseys 
Donating used soccer jerseys can make a world of difference for youth in poverty. Soccer is one of the most popular sports on the planet, and many kids in under-developed countries are in desperate need of soccer gear and resources to be able to enjoy the beautiful game. Donating used jerseys to charitable organizations is tax-deductible, and you will get the satisfaction of putting a smile on the face of an aspiring athlete in need.
 Items Used in Benediction Catholic Ceremony 
Just a few items are used in Benediction, a Catholic ceremony where the Blessed Sacrament, the Body of Christ, is exposed before the congregation for adoration, prayer and reflection. 

Benediction of the Blessed Sacrament can be used as a separate rite or as part of prayers or the Stations of the Cross. Benediction normally begins with singing. The priest makes the sign of the cross over the faithful, offering a blessing to the congregation, and then returns the Blessed Sacrament to the Tabernacle where it is safely kept. 

Several items are used consistently during the Catholic ritual of Benediction.
 The Role of Economics 
On September 11, 2001, the U.S. Federal Reserve sent out a one-line statement simply announcing that it was open for business, even after the collapse of the World Trade Center in New York City. That statement was released to prevent economic repercussions of the attack from ventilating through U.S. financial systems.

The use of economic theories and tools is what can get an economy back on track if things head south. Typically, a government with a strong economy is also strong politically, and a country&apos;s economy must be healthy for the country to remain healthy.
 How Can I Make Money for My Church? 
Nonprofit organizations such as churches are generally limited to the income provided by parishioner offerings. Often, this support is just enough to cover minimum operating expenses. As a result, churches must explore other ways of generating funds for ministry activities, community outreach and additional expenses. Work closely with the church office and applicable committees to determine how much money is needed and which members can help.
 Latex vs. Memory Foam Mattresses 
As technology has advanced, traditional, spring mattresses have begun to become outdated. The revolution that was begun with Posturpedic foam, developed by NASA, has continued with the creation of other types of memory and latex foam. However, before a person decides which type of mattress they want to purchase, they should do a little bit of research as to which one may best fit their needs.
 VBS Kingdom Capers Decorating Ideas 
LifeWay Christian publishers developed the Kingdom Capers Vacation Bible School (VBS) theme in 2003. This VBS program, subtitled &quot;Cracking the Character Code,&quot; takes children through a journey of spy games and mysteries as they build character traits. If your church is using the Kingdom Capers theme this year, try some creative ideas for decorating your VBS location to bring visual interest to the fun and lessons.
 How to Begin Living a Minimalist Lifestyle 
Some people seek a minimalist lifestyle because of the economy or because of stress. regardless, there&apos;s never a better time to simplify and minimize your life than now. When most people assess their lives, they come to realize that there are some things that wouldn&apos;t really be missed if they were gone. Minimalism is not about suffering. Rather its intent is to bring a practical clarity to your life. Here are some things to get you started.
 Help for Kids in Need 
Seeing a child in need of clothing, food, love or a family can be heartbreaking and move you to reach out and try to make a difference. Regardless of your resources in terms of time or money, there are many ways you can positively influence the lives of children in need. Options include simple donations, volunteering, fostering and adopting. No offering or involvement is too small or too big to make a difference.
 Why are Termites Attracted to Ink? 
Termites are small, pale insects that live in colonies not unlike ants. They&apos;re usually found in dirt or living inside wood. Also like ants, termites have a caste system, with a single queen, soldier termites, worker termites and young. Termites&apos; main food source is cellulose, the material that plants, and especially wood, are made from. In nature, this is used to break down dead wood into nutrients that plants can use, but there are other problems. Termites can be extremely damaging to houses, furniture, fences and other items that are made from their favored food source. An additional factor that…
 How to Build an Ancestor Altar 
Many Neo-Pagans incorporate worship or honoring of the Ancestors into their practice--Asa Tru, for instance, and those who work to re-create the pre-Christian Roman religion, just to name a couple. There are many cultural and historical precedents for the practice. In Vietnam, an ancestor altar is prominently displayed in nearly every home. In America today, whether it&apos;s formally part of a Pagan identity or not, spending a few minutes at an altar or shrine dedicated to one&apos;s ancestors can bring comfort, inspiration, and peace amidst daily craziness.
 How to Donate Contact Lenses 
If you have contact lenses that you no longer need, you might consider donating them. Unopened and unexpired contact lenses can often be returned to the doctor or store they were purchased from but if you like the idea of donating them you can give them to the international human rights organization MADRE. MADRE partners with sister organizations in Afghanistan, Nicaragua, Columbia, Iraq, Guatemala, Kenya, Mexico, Palestine, Peru, Sudan and Panama to assist in creating long-term solutions for women&apos;s health problems.
 Etiquette for Monogramming 
Monogramming is a wonderful way to personalize any gift, from jewelry to clothing to linens. It is important to understand certain conventions when monogramming for individuals or couples. Please keep in mind that these are only guidelines and can be outweighed by personal preference.
 How to Donate Used Items in Delaware 
Various agencies and charities in the state of Delaware accept donations of used items. In addition to the many nonprofit organizations that accept donations, privately run, for-profit establishments may also welcome used-article donations. Some of these businesses may pay the donor for his contribution, or they might offer to trade a service for a donation. There are music stores, for instance, that might offer discounted music lessons for a student&apos;s used guitar.
 How to Donate Used Luggage 
Is your basement or attic filled with old pieces of used luggage? Clear the clutter and help a good cause by donating your used luggage. There are charities and organizations that can put used luggage to good use. Clean it up and clear it out, and people will benefit from your generosity. You can even take a tax deduction for your donation.
 How to Wear Mala Beads 
Mala beads are prayer beads used by Buddhists and Hindus to help them count repetitions of prayers or mantras, much like devout Catholics will use a rosary to count their prayers. There are usually 108 beads in a Mala strand, and the beads are usually made of sandalwood, seeds or semi-precious stones like jade or amethyst. If you use Mala beads for prayer, chanting or devotion away, you might need to take them with you as you go about your day, but wearing them may not be the option you should take.
 How to Donate Used Stuffed Animals in Michigan 
If you have some gently used stuffed animals around your house that you no longer have a use for, consider donating them to a charity in Michigan. There are plenty of Salvation Army centers across the state that would be more than happy to find a new home for your stuffed animals. It is easy to do, and rewarding when you know that your stuffed animal may help comfort a child in need.
 How to Donate to a Nursing Home 
Nursing homes provide care for people who are not able to care for themselves. Most nursing homes are for older people whose families can no longer care for them, but there are also nursing homes for younger adults with physical and/or mental challenges. Donating to a nursing home helps these often-neglected people as well as the often-underpaid people who care for them.
 How to Read a Full Libra Horoscope 
Though small, daily Libra horoscopes can provide brief, useful tidbits for those who follow their astronomy, a full horoscope can provide a wealth of information. This more complete Vedic reading gives deeper insight into the present realities of a particular astrological sign, but getting the full benefit of this horoscope is something best achieved through a more complete understanding of the Libra.
 Facts About Toxic Waste 
Toxic waste, often called hazardous waste, is any waste material that is harmful to the environment, including animals, humans and plant life. Toxic waste is often the byproduct of industrial or chemical processes, but many common items can also be hazardous. Toxic waste can pollute air, water and land, and cleanup of toxic waste sites is an expensive and timely process.
 The History of Cloisonne Ornaments 
Throughout the centuries, Chinese culture has given so much to the world. From the invention of gunpowder and paper making techniques to the wealth of appreciation for music and and unique art, there is always something new and interesting to discover. One of these facets is the art style of cloisonne.
 How to Donate Used Wheelchairs 
Many insurance and disability plans allow patients to purchase new wheelchairs on a regular basis. However, thousands of people in the United States who need wheelchairs are not insured and do not have access to low-cost wheelchairs. Donating used wheelchairs is an easy way to help people with disabilities save hundreds or thousands of dollars, not to mention a lot of frustration. Many organizations will pick up your old wheelchair or pay to ship the wheelchair at no cost to you.
 How to Hold a Fountain Pen 
Fountain pens were developed more than 100 years ago before pen makers developed the simpler ballpoint pen. Relatively expensive, fountain pens may nonetheless be stylish in appearance and make writing easier. A business or home office desk may have one on display. Although they are still used today, practice may be required to write with one.
 How to Make a Funeral Memory Board 
It&apos;s a bittersweet responsibility to make a funeral memorial board, and you want it to be perfect. The object of a funeral board is to celebrate the life of the deceased, and is best accomplished by gathering photographs and memorabilia that will bring the memory of the person to mind for each visitor who pays his respects at the funeral home. With some deep thought and insightful advice, you can make a funeral memory board that will live in the memories of all who come to celebrate the deceased&apos;s life.
 How To Braid Celtic Rope 
A Celtic Rope features a braided design filled with spirals and swirls. This see-through design usually uses six different ropes. Metals and wires are common materials used when creating a Celtic rope item but rope, yarn and leather are also included. The Celtic Rope design can vary from the complex Celtic Knots or simple loops.
 How to Donate Used Mobility Power Chairs 
More families are finding themselves the owners of a mobility chair used by an elderly relative. These assistive devices provide independence during rehabilitation or when knees or legs finally fail. Once the owners have no further need for them, the mobility power chair can be donated. Recycle yours by donating it to those who have no access to new chairs.
 How to respond to a Freecycle ad 
Freecycle is an online message board where people can post ads for items that they want to give away for free. Everything on Freecycle is entirely free, and there is a certain etiquette involved in both posting and answering ads on Freecycle. It is up to the poster to provide real information about the product and when and where it needs to be picked up at. The interested party has a different set of rules.
 How to Earn The Safety Sense Try It 
Earning the Girl Scouts Try-It&apos;s can be a very creative and rewarding experience for both the girls and the leaders! To earn this badge you can follow along in the Girl Scout Try-It Handbook and also implement some of these ideas.
 About Donations for Nonprofits 
Nonprofit organizations rely heavily on donations to fund their work. Because there are so many worthy causes, it can be overwhelming deciding which organizations should receive your support. By thoroughly investigating each charity, you can be assured that you are selecting an organization that does work you admire in a fiscally responsible way.
 How to Value Non-Cash Donations 
You can place a monetary value on your non-cash donations. Unused household items and clothing are commonly donated to second-hand stores or non-profit organizations. In order to claim a tax-deductible donation on your tax return, you must value your items and donate to a non-profit organization. Some items may not qualify for a tax deduction, but your donation will still help those in need.
 How to Make Your Goodwill Donation Worth It 
Lots of people expect their donations to Goodwill to be put to good use, but this is not always the case. Make your donation worth it by learning what to donate, and what to leave at home.
 Helping the Needy 
Do something to help the needy today. Many people fall on hard times. They can’t take care of their families properly or pay the bills. Some people cannot even go to the doctor when very sick. As fellow human beings, it&apos;s our responsibility to help these people. There are needy people in every state, city and town. Whatever your resources, you can make a difference. Helping the needy doesn’t always involve giving money. Find a way that’s right for you. Get busy lending a hand. Show your love for your fellow man, and make someone smile!
 How to Fundraise Effectively 
Fundraisers go on every day so it is entirely possible to have a worthwhile cause but not get the necessary funds for it. In order to fundraise effectively you must think outside the box and create something new and different to get your charity noticed.
 How to Celebrate the Fall Equinox 
The fall equinox is the point in time when the sun crosses the equator, making daylight and darkness approximately twelve hours each. As symbol of balance and harvest, the fall equinox has been celebrated throughout history in many cultures and nations. Modern celebrations often focus on the same elements of harvest, balance, and gratitude, and can be adapted easily to fit individual circumstances and desires.
 How to Plan an 80s Theme Party 
Who knew the 80&apos;s could be so much fun? With an entire generation of preppies and punk rockers teetering on the age of forty, 80&apos;s theme parties are growing in popularity. Here you will learn how to easily plan an 80&apos;s theme party that will be both fun and memorable, regardless of your age.
 How to Attend Milwaukee&apos;s German Fest 
Germanfest is held the last weekend of July, Thursday through Sunday, at Milwaukee&apos;s Lakefront on the Maier Festival Grounds. There are different types of entertainment and German culture to be experienced for all ages and the entire family. Bring a group of your friends from work; entertain business associates or the family, but don&apos;t miss all that Milwaukee&apos;s Germanfest has to offer.
 How to Become a Minimalist 
Becoming a minimalist can help you reduce stress. Imagine living in your home with much less clutter and mess. Your home would be easier to clean and take less time to clean. You only need the essentials in your home in order to live comfortably. Becoming a minimalist is not about giving up things that you need. It&apos;s about keeping only the essentials, and not keeping anything you do not need. It can be quite liberating to become a minimalist. You will also save a lot of money, because you won&apos;t be spending your hard earned cash on unnecessary items.…
 How to Live Like a Minimalist 
Living like a minimalist simplifies life and makes it easier to focus on the important things. Having a lot of clutter around is stressful. Simplifying the living environment by being a minimalist is good for the soul and conducive to peace of mind. Avoiding mindless purchases that clutter up the home also helps you maintain your budget.
 How to Adopt a Soldier 
Deployed U.S. soldiers are of course supported by the U.S. government, however there are many items that are in short supply, or that they do without. Personal hygiene items, clothing, certain foods, and entertainment are among the many things that civilians can help provide to our soldiers. Adopt a Soldier programs help get needed items, and comfort items, to soldiers overseas. The U.S. Department of Defense is not permitted to take donations, so the following is a guide to the simplest way to Adopt a Soldier through a legitimate charity organization.
 How to Clear Negative Energy 
It&apos;s essential for growth and happiness to surround your self with positive energy. For this reason, it&apos;s necessary to perform cleansing rituals. Sometimes it will be obvious when an area needs to be cleared, like when you have a dispute or a car accident, and other times you&apos;ll need to use your intuition and trust your feelings.
 How to Use Time Efficiently 
The management of time can create more time to manage. Every day people waste minutes that turn to hours. If you feel that there isn&apos;t enough time in the day to get everything done, then perhaps a few changes in priorities are in order. You can easily learn to use time efficiently with very few changes in your daily life.
 How to Light the Shabbat Candles 
Lighting the candles for Shabbat is one of the few Mitzvot that only a woman can perform. It is by lighting the candles that the woman of the house signifies that her household is ready for Shabbat and invites the Sabbath in.
 How to Buy Lederhosen 
Lederhosen, a traditional German boys&apos; shorts that were popular until the 1950s, are made from durable leather or suede and often have suspenders and ornate embroidery. Today, lederhosen are worn by children, men and even women and come in a variety of designs.
 How to Cultivate Donors 
It&apos;s not enough to ask for a donation and then send a form thank-you letter if you want your donors to be loyal. Baby Boomers, Generation Xers and Millennials are coming into their own in philanthropy and they want and deserve more. With multiple nonprofits offering different solutions to the world&apos;s problems, you&apos;re in competition whether you like it or not. Follow these steps to successfully cultivate your supporters.
 How to Make a Sympathy Wreath 
A sympathy wreath is another way to express sympathy to a grieving family. Wreaths are typically displayed on a stand during the funeral service or at a gravesite. There are many ways to make a sympathy wreath personal and at home.
 How to Donate to a Thrift Store 
Donating items to a charitable thrift store lets you clear out old items that are no longer useful while giving you a tax write off. Follow these steps to donate.
 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
