<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008731" url="http://blogs.e-rockford.com/comingsandgoings/2008/02/08/colorlab-launches-first-us-retail-outlets-in-chicago/" time="2012-07-13-02:11" support="1" score="0.0019309356519294487" bingtitle="Colorlab launches first U.S. retail outlets in Chicago – Comings ..." webtitle="Colorlab launches first U.S. retail outlets in ChicagoComings and Goings - Rockford, IL - Rockford Register Star">
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>This includes its flagship store at 857 W. Armitage, as well as the cosmetics counter ... new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant ... Leave a Reply Cancel reply</description>
	<body>
		Site Print archives Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Jobs 
 Cars 
 Homes 
 Classifieds 
 Apartments 
 Coupons 
 Subscriber Services 
 Home News Obituaries Business Sports Entertainment HealthyRockford Insight Rockford Woman Special Sections 
 
 Facebook Twitter Mobile E-mail headlines Local Loop Calendar Newspaper Ads Newspaper Archives Contests Contact Us 

 Your Town Public Safety Schools Real Estate Transactions Nation/World Celebrations Calendar 

 Real Estate Transactions Face of Business On the Move Say Cheese Star 60 Markets Stocks 

 Hoops Preps College Sports Bears IceHogs Twitter 

 Movies Music&amp;Arts Food&amp;Dining My Last Bite Life&amp;Style; Georgette Braun Will Pfeifer Twitter Calendar Contests 

 Health care jobs Health Directory 

 Problem Tracker Submit letter or guest column Opinions What You&apos;re Saying Blogs Bruce Quast Cartoons Videos 

 Facebook Twitter 

 Local Loop Reader Content Daily Deals People Living Spaces Branded Content 
 Comings and Goings Keep track of the latest business openings and closings. Whether it&apos;s a new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant closing down or a progress report on a major development, you&apos;ll find all the latest bits of information here. See something while you&apos;re out and about? Leave a comment or send an e-mail to business@rrstar.com and we&apos;ll check it out. Read more Follow @mlwestphal Skip to content 
Colorlab launches first U.S. retail outlets in Chicago
 Posted on February 8, 2008 at 3:20 am by Tweet 
Rockford-based Colorlab Custom Cosmetics is holding the official launch of its first U.S. retail stores—in Chicago—on Feb. 12.  This includes its flagship store at 857  W. Armitage, as well as the cosmetics counter at Macy’s at 111 N. State St.  The company also has a cosmetics counter at Macy’s in San Francisco at Union Square.

The U.S. retail locations opened in December 2007, but this month marks the official launch event, said Justine Markese, senior brand manager for Colorlab.

The company, founded in 1996 by Mary  Swaab, launched retail cosmetics counters in Paris in 2005, and in London in 2006.

Colorlab cosmetics are customized at the counter for each individual customer, by hue and formulation, like a cosmetics lab at the counter.  Because they’re customized on-site with the customer, they’re not available online but only by purchasing them in person, said Markese.

Before the Chicago and San Francisco stores, the only other way people could get the cosmetics in the U.S. was by appointment at the company’s headquarters in Rockford at 1112 5th Ave.  They still can do that by calling 815-965-2001 to to make an appointment.

While the company has plans to roll out retail locations in other markets as well,“we were very happy we got to start in our own backyard in Chicago,”said Markese.“It was important to start (the U.S. retail enterprise) in Chicago, because it was close, and we could hold its hand.”
 This entry was posted in Uncategorized . Bookmark the permalink . ← Q Nails Spa opens in Machesney Park Shoppers can browse CherryVale products via mobile phone → 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via email. You can also subscribe without commenting. 
 
   
Search This Blog
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Red Mango yogurt shop opening in Machesney Park BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Kochi Japan restaurant opening next week in Rockford Salon open at Stewart Square Pacemaker grocery store adds fuel pumps in Poplar Grove 
 
Recent Comments

 Norma on Closure of Ello Furniture is end of an era Jeff on BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Patti V. on Molly’s Attic hosting grand opening Saturday in Roscoe Martink on Gray’s Foods grocery store on Auburn Street closing Anna Carlson on Olive oil store opening in Loves Park 
 

 
Recently Shared
 
 
 Melissa Westphal’s Stories 

 X-ray films stolen from Rockford&apos;s SwedishAmerican Closure of Auburn Street driving facility angers local officials Rockford driver&apos;s license facility moving over needed upgrades Illinois cemetery industry hit with new licensing rules Americans boost charitable giving in 2011 
 
 
Archives
 Select Month December 2011 (4) November 2011 (5) October 2011 (8) September 2011 (8) August 2011 (9) July 2011 (12) June 2011 (13) May 2011 (9) April 2011 (6) March 2011 (16) February 2011 (17) January 2011 (10) December 2010 (10) November 2010 (9) October 2010 (12) September 2010 (8) August 2010 (14) July 2010 (12) June 2010 (4) May 2010 (5) April 2010 (8) March 2010 (6) February 2010 (4) January 2010 (10) December 2009 (7) November 2009 (8) October 2009 (5) September 2009 (6) August 2009 (1) July 2009 (5) June 2009 (6) May 2009 (1) April 2009 (2) March 2009 (7) January 2009 (8) December 2008 (3) November 2008 (10) October 2008 (8) September 2008 (11) August 2008 (1) July 2008 (1) April 2008 (7) March 2008 (5) February 2008 (6) January 2008 (5) December 2007 (9) November 2007 (11) October 2007 (3) 
Categories
 Select Category Business move  (2) Cherry Valley  (1) Coming  (26) Going  (5) Health  (1) Machesney Park  (1) Restaurants  (12) Retail  (22) Retail expansion  (5) Retail move  (4) Rockford  (3) Uncategorized  (160) 
Tags
 Select Tag Business move (3) closings (51) Expansion (3) openings (99) Restaurants (12) Retail (12) Subscribe to Posts    Subscribe to Comments Marketplace • Classifieds • Find Rockford jobs • Cars • Homes • Coupons Site services • Subscribe • Place an Ad • Buy a photo reprint • Newspaper Archives • Weddings/Engagements • Anniversaries Your Town • Belvidere • Boone County • Cherry Valley • Loves Park • Machesney Park Your Town • Rockford • Rockton • Roscoe • South Beloit • Winnebago County Submit content • Calendar listing • Letter to the Editor • Press release • News tip Our sites • BusinessRockford.com • Go.rrstar.com • HealthyRockford.com • RockfordWoman.com • RockfordHomeOnline.com • RockfordWheels.com • m.rrstar.com 
 Contact us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | About our Ads 

Rockford Register Star |
 99 E. State St. Rockford, IL 61104

Copyright©2006-2012 GateHouse Media, Inc. Some Rights Reserved.

Original content available for non-commercial use under a Creative Commons license, except where noted.
 SEO by eLocalListing | Advertiser profiles | RadarFrog Merchant Directory
	</body>
</document>
