<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008536" url="http://saferschoolcanteeninmalaysia.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:00" support="1" score="0.00197715982424463" bingtitle="My opinion about Malaysia School Canteen" webtitle="My opinion about Malaysia School Canteen">
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>... the ministry and dept of education for me to collect ... School can control the menu that had been offered ... such as fancy cafe or family, ethnic, fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		My opinion about Malaysia School Canteen
 
 Involve in food service industry as an academician. This blog is an overview about Malaysian public school scenario from the author perspective. 
 
Total Pageviews
 
 Sunday, December 18, 2011 
 
 Gunnerz Enterprise: TABLET CANDIES HORSE MILK 
 Gunnerz Enterprise: TABLET CANDIES HORSE MILK : I would like to introduce the FIRST candies based on Horse milk.  I surely recommended this product because I do take it as daily supplement and really give me energy and in terms of my gastrointestinal problems were settled. My children really love it and it surprise me that they really love it and much more energetic.. surely like a horse. hahahha! 
 If you are interested.. please have a look at this blog. http://gunners-noni.blogspot.com .. Posted by saidatul afzan at 7:12 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Tuesday, July 12, 2011 
 
 Should we blame the school canteen operators fully on food poisoning cases? 
 Hello,

Quite sometime for me to write something here...almost 6 months! Time is running so fast...why didnt i updating my blog, well the reasons are busy getting approval from the ministry and dept of education for me to collect my data in school canteen.. then i need to get the Headmaster approval to enter the school... too many hassle things to do... and got demotivated with too many reasons from the schools ( not all) although i am just doing my preliminary study where i am trying to get feedback from the food handlers, to know do they understand my questionnaire...

Let me tell you what had i done within 6 month of silence from blogging.. First, i had to develop my questionnaire with my supervisor.. most of the questions were adapted from people who had done their research related to my study..But it takes almost 3 months doing the corrections and seeing my beloved supervisor to get her approval.. Once, i got the approval i need to get the approval from the headmaster to enter the school canteen. One of the reason is that the canteen is in the school area.. it is not wise and can be arrested by the school guard if i just barge in the school (just joking)..Once i did get the approval from the headmasters, my first impression was that the canteen operator or owner will give full commitment.. Well they dont welcome you actually but have to because the headmaster said so but when i did talk to them and hear about their problem that they are facing... the canteen operators were giving a commitment although they hesitate to let their foreign workers to answer my questionnaire... I persuaded the owner and got at least one person. then i knew why they tried to avoid their workers to participate.. no thyphoid injection and didnt attend hygiene course (No wonder!) which is compulsory before you can be a food handler..

One of the canteen operator did complain to me regarding her situation experiencing closing the canteen business for 2 weeks because there were 4 students complained getting stomach ache and their teacher assumed they got food poisoning. The teacher reported to the headmaster immediately and this case was reported directly to the Department of education..So it had become chaos, when all the related agency such as the health department and their CSI team came to investigate the canteen.. The canteen had to be closed for 2 weeks because it is under investigation either the food from the canteen caused the students to get food poisoning...Back to the students, they were taken to the hospitals for thorough check up regarding their stomach ache.

So what happened to other students and teachers who had not been affected with the food borne diseases? The canteen was closed... so where should they get their food and drinks if the canteen was not functioning...Do you know where they get their food and drinks, the canteen operator that had been investigated had to open a table outside the canteen premises by request from the school to sell food and drinks to the students and teachers...Dont you think it is much riskier selling food that are cooked somewhere and sold on open table sort of like a hawker stall.. dont you think this will risk the students getting food poisoning much more easier...??

From the scenario above... what do you think? This is a true story and experienced by a canteen operator... Oh! The outcome of the investigation... The canteen is clean and got A grade.. the canteen operator open the canteen as usual... how about the students that were sent to the hospital? Well, they actually didnt get food poisoning.. just normal stomach ache...


P.S: will start collecting data this july with south zone (Malacca)... Hope things going smoothly insyallah.. Posted by saidatul afzan at 7:14 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Wednesday, January 26, 2011 
 
 TRANSFORMATION OR TRANSFORMERS AUTOBOT?? 
 Hi, 

 Happy belated New Year and Happy Coming Chinese New Year to Malaysian chinese and around the world to whom that celebrate CNY.. Its a new year and a new day and January is passing by... time is just like a machine gun... 

 I am struggling building my questionnaire for the food handlers that i am going to collect my data at 4 zones that i stratified randomly as samples which will cover Kedah, Selangor, Pahang and Melaka states.. Why just 4? Well, each state represent each zones: North, East, West and South... Well, in term of monetary also is limited and time contraints... Oh! gosh...With God permission (Insyallah) i will start this coming March...hope things go as it plans... 

 I can feel the tense of making this questionnaire because i am losing a lot of time ( a lot of holiday maaa such as CNY etc...-holiday is family day)  ...and i am struggling to come out with ideas what i want to present at Jacksonville, Florida on November 2011 although i hv 10 months to go... but the closing date to submit my proposal is on 15th February 2011.. Aaaahhhhhh!     I want to be there... never been there before... ;p  huhuhu.... 

 But thinking of making good deeds for my nation (Hahhaha!) I have to move on... Life have to go on... although a lot of obstacle coming through...what a lonely journey for me BUT i am glad that with my precious 2 daughters and a son have given me joy and hope that what Mommy is doing right now is for the best of them in the future... Love you all...Opss sorry to my dear Hubby that is very supportive... 

 Continue back on the topic.... from my observation, there are lots of new primary school coming up... and the canteen also quite impressive... (Just my observation from far).. Base on my lack of experience in observing from far not using binocular.. the canteen is much better than before... 

 No worries, my friend.. i am going to start collecting data soon. Hoping that the Ministry of Education send the approval letter for me to visit... (still waiting).. maybe i will attach pic on the recent school canteen but i cannot reveal all because as suppose it will betray my research ethics...(what a nerd!) hehehe... 

 Well as i mention before.... hope that our school canteen in Malaysia is not going to be stagnant... I wish with my effort and other researchers that have interest in school canteen will help to make it better and safer... 

 Let us transform ourselve for a better life or better become a transformer autobot??...am i right?? for sure NO....you may say that what the H*LL am i talking about... please place a forgiveness on my statement  ;p which you should know that my level of thinking is miserable... 


 P.s: if you ask me why am i doing this silly research.. well i have kids... they are going to school one day... Hope that they can get good and safe meals (comfort food)  although they are at schools... we as working parents hope the best for them although we have a very short time to be with them... Do you know that children spend more time at school than at home... same as us laa ... 

 take care Posted by saidatul afzan at 8:31 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Tuesday, October 26, 2010 
 
 Auditor- General&apos;s 2009 Report on Poor Food served in School 
 
Tuesday October 26, 2010 - Star Online

School kids served poor food


 
POOR children in some schools are being served unbalanced meals while others are eating meals prepared 18 hours in advance, said the Auditor-General’s 2009 Report.
The Education Department issued a notice of periodic monitoring to two schools for serving sardine sandwiches with no sardines and chicken porridge with no chicken.
Two schools in Perak cancelled their contracts with caterers because they continued to flout meal regulations.
Dieticians from the Health Ministry said the meals served under the supplementary food programme (RMT) meant for children from poor families could lead to malnutrition.
The Education Ministry has prepared a guide which lists 20 menu choices to be served under the RMT.
The guide also says the meals must include meat and vegetables to ensure a balanced diet for the children.
The meals, which consist of one main dish, a drink and a fruit must be prepared and served five times a week by a school-appointed caterer...........
 http://thestar.com.my/news/story.asp?file=/2010/10/26/nation/7298263&amp;sec=nation 

 A-G&apos;s Report: Poor schoolchildren served unbalanced meals 
 

 Published: Monday October 25, 2010 MYT 8:42:00 PM 
 
 By SHAUN HO/ Star Online 

KUALA LUMPUR: Poor children in some schools are being served unbalanced meals while other schools are serving food prepared 18 hours earlier, the Auditor-General&apos;s Report 2009 said.The state Education Department issued a notice of periodic monitoring to two schools for serving sardine sandwiches with no sardines and chicken porridge with no chicken.
Two schools in Perak cancelled their contracts with caterers because the caterers continued to flout meal regulations although the matter was brought up by the schools.
Dietitians from the Health Ministry said the meals, served under the additional food program (RMT) meant for children from poor families, could cause the children to be malnourished.

The Education Ministry has prepared a guide which lists 20 menu choices to be served under the RMT.

The guide also controls ingredients of the food, which must include meat and vegetables, to assure a balanced diet for the children and this must be followed closely by the caterers.

The meals consist of one dish, a drink and a fruit item which must be prepared and served five times a week by a school-appointed caterer.
SK Jernang in Batang Padang, Perak was found to have been serving beef curry that was cooked and stored 18 hours before it was served to students. The caterer gave the excuse that the school was far from the premises and there was not enough time to cook the food on the same day.

The Audit Department said the ministry should come up with an alternative measure that would allow caterers to prepare and serve the food on the same day it is served.An audit at the school also found that it was only serving four daily breakfasts instead of five.
The school did not give an explanation why it did not serve all five meals. An audit on the school last July also found that it was only serving plain fried beehoon without any meat or vegetables. The serving of fruit with the meal was also less than required (a slice of apple instead of half an apple).
The A-G&apos;s Report also said some schools were found to be preparing their RMT meals in unsanitary conditions because they did not have proper food preparation areas.

 http://thestar.com.my/news/story.asp?file=/2010/10/25/nation/20101025205015&amp;sec=nation 



 My comments; 
 
 
 T his column is reporting on supplementary food programme (RMT). This program is to help the malnourished students from the poor family.. The food is subsidized to the student RM1.80 per head every day.. The food contractor will get a lump sum of amount paid by the Ministry of Education.. The problem here is not about there is no guidelines or well balanced menu been offered.. The problem are monitoring and supervising food contractor on preparing the food for the students . Most of the food contractor actually gain their profit from here... the school authority give all their trust to the food contractor without any hesitation because the school admin and teachers have abundant of workloads to be done rather than just supervising on the food been prepared by the food contractor.. Sometimes, the food contractor will give different food to the teachers compared to what they prepared for the students..  
 Imagine that the food contractor prepared fried noodles without any vegetables and meat as ingredients but just added fermented soy sauce and blended anchovies as substitute... the profit making of the fried noodles are more than 200%.. So what should we do especially the parents.. we cannot hope on the teachers...so to whom should we blame on this cause... Mostly people will blame 120% to the food contractors... which their contract will be terminate immediately BUT that do not solve the problem..Food contractor are business people too, they always think of how to make money especially in a captive market which the customers are limited to a certain number.. 
 
 
 That is why as i stated in my last post on the Wishing List...Parents, teachers, school admin and Ministry have to work together to provide a better food to the students.. not just for the RMT program but to all. Maybe it&apos;s time for us to have a paradigm shift on the school canteen management. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Posted by saidatul afzan at 12:14 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Friday, October 22, 2010 
 
 My comment on this post about canteen food for school children 
 I like to comment a bit on this issue posted by Borneo Post Online.. It is just from my perspective why this issue is consider stale but need attention...My comments are highlighted in PINK. 

 Better canteen food for school children 

 http://www.theborneopost.com/?p=67748&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter 

Posted on October 10, 2010, Sunday by Borneo Post Online

THE sale of junk food at school canteens is an old issue–first brought up by the Nutrition Society of Malaysia as far back as 1980 and highlighted periodically over the last 20 years.

Regrettably, little improvement has been made despite ample guidelines for school authorities and canteen operators to follow. All depends on the School authorities and it is not compulsory to the canteen operators to sell healthy foods.. 
Health Minister Datuk Seri Liow Tiong Lai has warned that continued selling of unhealthy food and snacks in schools could lead to the nation raising future generations of overweight students and obese grown-ups.
He urged operators to abide by the revised 1985 School Canteen Guidelines (SCG), jointly prepared by the Ministries of Education and Health. Enforce by whom?? 
There is no denying schooI canteens are still selling fried and high-calorie food. Although some are considered“appropriate”under the updated SCG, dieticians nowadays do not encourage their consumption by children and suggest replacing them with more nourishing meals.
The drawback is most children tend to shun healthy food probably because they are not as tasty with less or no sugar, salt and preservatives added. Healthy food doesnt mean tasteless... it should be well balance.. Canteen operators are left with no choice but to revert to the less healthy but“more sellable”stuff. Do they care? No.. they are just thinking about profit making.. 

As one operator pointed out, no fried chicken, no business.Many children also dislike eating health-giving vegetables and usually leave them untouched on the plate. How about fruits? Vegetable can be substitute with fruit, right? Apparently, these youngsters are not educated on nutrition–why it’s important to separate the kernel from the husk. If children are taught early to appreciate it’s the eating habit that makes or breaks their health, they are likely to be more selective about what eat to stay healthy. Not only the children need to be educate about nutrition.. The teachers, parents and food contractors also need to be educate about the importance of healthy food too.. 
According to nutrition experts, there is no good or bad food–only good or bad diets.
“Health problems are caused not just by a specific food but rather the obsesogenic (obesity-causing) environment where food is omnipresent. Mechanisation is also causing people to be more sedentary.
“These all lead to chronic diseases like obesity, diabetes, hypertension and heart disease,”explained Associate Professor Dr Poh Bee Koon, head of Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia’s Department of Nutrition and Dietetics. I agree... School can control the menu that had been offered.. once the students were introduce with healthy food... one day they will accept it...Like what Jamie Oliver had done in UK school canteen, he introduced well balanced menu.. 
She pointed out that while school canteens were not entirely to blame, they were still the main suppliers of daily food for school children and, thus, had an important role in promoting good eating habits.
A most common mistake among parents is packing their children off to school without breakfast. Studies have shown one in three kids do not get any breakfast everyday. That&apos;s why school canteen actually play an important role to provide well balanced menu to the children..They are captive market.. 
Dr Poh advised giving schoolchildren, not used to eating early in the morning, at least a nutritious drink—even better a slice of bread or a bowl of cereal. According to research, children who do not have breakfast tend to perform below those who do.

As the search for the perfect diet (if there is any) remains elusive, people, generally, can eat what they like but a diet with less unhealthy food is the key. And since Nature dictates that penalty should follow excess, everything should be taken in moderation. Even if something is good, too much of it can be bad.

Wholesome diets are important to the development of a robust and healthy society. Government agencies and NGOs such as consumers’movements should campaign actively to drive home the importance of nutritious sustenance. That&apos;s is why i stated in my wishing list.. we need school canteen association.. 


This calls for more than just asking fast food chains to cut sugar, salt and fats. The campaign must be multi-pronged with healthy dieting as the core message to especially the younger generation. Manufacturers of food and drinks and eateries catering to both the public and schools should also make the effort to acquire a proper understanding of nutrition.
Assunta Hospital dietician manager Ho Shiau Fen has a very sound cooking tip to offer—use garlic and onions to add taste to food instead of seasoning products such as salt and sugar high in fat content. She also said there are no better substitutes to obtaining full nutritional benefits than from natural food sources. Cook from scratch say NO to instant food.. 

As society becomes more affluent, people tend to seek out the good life. Healthwise though, over-indulgence can exact a heavy price. Indeed, for efficiency and productivity, we can ill-afford a nation of fat and unhealthy people. By right, diets should improve with guidebooks so easily obtainable these days. But heaps of literature alone will not eradicate bad eating habits. As with other similar issues, nothing much will change (for the better) with lax enforcement or a laissez-faire attitude. ;p 


 Just my one cent.. Posted by saidatul afzan at 6:23 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Wednesday, October 20, 2010 
 
 Wishing List For Our Food service School In Malaysia 
 I&apos; m back.. 


 I am quite surprise that there are people outside there paying a visit to my blog..Hahaha.. why am i laughing? well i am not the blog expert, not a guru of any theory but just a normal person like others.. But i appreciate to any of you that read my blogs and give their comments..Thank you.. 
 Maybe people not a Malaysian will wonder why did i give bad comments about my country&apos;s school canteen.. Well, if you googling or yahooing try to type school canteen.. if type school canteen Malaysia.. there will be stories telling about food poisoning happened here and there... But if you type school canteen in australia.. you will see a lot of topic about healthy food, school canteen association, how to keep up a good school canteen operation and when you type singapore school canteen.. you can get to know their policies and how they practice healthy eating... 
 That is why i have a Wishing List.. 
 I wish that Malaysia Public School Canteen should have: 
 1. School canteen association (School Admin, teachers and parents as committee) not just PTA (PIBG) 2. Indoor school canteen 3. Using the commercial equipment not household equipment 4. Use cycle Menu for children not static menu...example: Nasi Lemak everyday 5. Food service officer in each District - monitoring on contracts, operations, training,menu and prices 6. Education background and skills for Food Contractors and Food Handlers 7. Vending machines such as fruit juice, crackers, breads and plain water.. not soda or chocolates 8. On going training for the food handlers in school not just one shot training conduct by Ministry of Health 9. Better Infrastructure for the school canteen kitchen: Drainage is always a problem, Dont just use a dustbin! 10. A good kitchen management manual as a guidelines and references not just a purpose of just needed one 
 At the moment, that is my wishing list... hope in the future.. there is a difference.. Posted by saidatul afzan at 10:03 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Wednesday, November 11, 2009 
 
 Knowledgeable and Skillful Food Handlers In School Canteen.. Compulsory Or Not?? 
 
 Hello everyone, 
 Have you seen any of the food handlers in school canteen wearing exactly or similar to the picture? Ok, you have the answer... 
 
 Today i would like to discuss about food handlers. According to Malaysia Food Act 1983 (Food hygiene regulation 2009), a food handler is defined as &quot;any person involved in a food business who prepares,serve, touch, package the food including drinks and handle kitchen and dining equipments,utensils, plates etc&quot;. So basically we have to understand that any person who are knowledgeable or not about food can be in the food business including school canteen.. Do you think preparing food for captive market at a fixed price is something easy to be handled especially for the customer who need to eat a well balanced diet for their growth? the answer is NO... 
 Since 2010, all food handlers are compulsory to attend food safety course if not that person can be fine at a certain amount..the fee to attend for the course is estimated below RM50. There are more than 100 qualified trainers appointed by the Minister of Health Malaysia.So, check their certification is it valid or not.... But for food business people who have more than 5 workers.. they will said it is costly.. Why do they say that.. because they are thinking about profit making... They never think of the risk that they put into.. especially to the children.. The trust that the school and the parents have on them... They never think about social responsibility... Why do this happen? Why must they become so selfish.. We are paying for their food but they never think of the risk that they are facing.. with a small investment to the workers to attend the course will actually help the food handlers to understand why they should carry out the good hygiene practices if not .. they just do what they thing is right although what they are doing is actually wrong and risky..The answer is the need for knowledge, knowledge, knowledge... 
 As a food handler especially in school canteen, we need to have at least a basic knowledge or skill in food handling . Why do i say so... this is because the food handlers should prepare the food that the customers need to have NOT only what the customers want to have... But now, we can see that most of the canteen just offering based on the limited budget to gain more profit from this captive market.. Who are the captive market... the students especially the primary students.. Getting fried noodles that only have noodles with soyabean ketchup with no chicken meat, very rare to find vegetables... What do the children gain from eating that fried noodles?? Just to fill up their tummy not in term of nutrition value at all.. 
 Some of the food contracter just leave the job 100% to the food handlers, some of them totally not from malaysia... I am not saying the outsider coming to malaysia is not good but basically their background are not well educated and need a full supervision. In my opinion, we can have any type of people but by having a good experience, skills and education background will help to generate a better food service operation in schools. 
 My comments is not concluded to all the primary schools in Malaysia.. but the most sad things usually happened is in the government school. Why do this happen.. we have ways to choose food contractors. But why do we overlook this small things.. especially in term giving a healthy balance meals for our children..For example: Some of the Chinese school,such as for standard one and two students, the parents have to pay for a month in advance and they can choose the menu for their children.Surprisely, the food that had been prepared in the canteen is well balanced. 
 Its time for our school food service especially in primary school to have a paradigm shift.. The food service system need to have a better operating system for a well balanced meal for our children that spend almost 75% of their time in schools.. Not only our children can be excellence in education but also build up a healthy lifestyle for a better living... 
 Posted by saidatul afzan at 12:24 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
School food service in Malaysia
 This blog is just a point of view from a malaysian that would like to see a better food service management in school canteen especially in rural area... Static menu, unequipped kitchen equipment, improper table and chairs (bench).. Why are our children are not treated well same as we are concern with their education..we sent them to tuition to get straight A&apos;s but we didnt care about what they eat...where they eat and how they eat...





 
Popular Posts
 
 Knowledgeable and Skillful Food Handlers In School Canteen.. Compulsory Or Not?? Hello everyone, Have you seen any of the food handlers in school canteen wearing exactly or similar to the picture? Ok, you have the answe... Auditor- General&apos;s 2009 Report on Poor Food served in School Tuesday October 26, 2010 - Star Online School kids served poor food POOR children in some schools are being served unbalanced meals while o... This is my 1st blog Salam and greetings to all who visit my blog.. This is my 1st attempt to have my own blog although there are thousands of bloggers out ther... Our School foodservice is stagnant... Why do i say that our school food service is stagnant especially in rural area..1st the environment of the canteen is the same since 30 yea... My comment on this post about canteen food for school children I like to comment a bit on this issue posted by Borneo Post Online.. It is just from my perspective why this issue is consider stale but nee... Should we blame the school canteen operators fully on food poisoning cases? Hello, Quite sometime for me to write something here...almost 6 months! Time is running so fast...why didnt i updating my blog, well the r... Wishing List For Our Food service School In Malaysia I&apos; m back.. I am quite surprise that there are people outside there paying a visit to my blog..Hahaha.. why am i laughing? well i am not ... TRANSFORMATION OR TRANSFORMERS AUTOBOT?? Hi, Happy belated New Year and Happy Coming Chinese New Year to Malaysian chinese and around the world to whom that celebrate CNY.. Its a ... Gunnerz Enterprise: TABLET CANDIES HORSE MILK Gunnerz Enterprise: TABLET CANDIES HORSE MILK : I would like to introduce the FIRST candies based on Horse milk. I surely recommended this ... 
 
Followers
 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2011 (3) 
 ▼  December (1) 
 Gunnerz Enterprise: TABLET CANDIES HORSE MILK 
 

 ►  July (1) 
 Should we blame the school canteen operators fully... 
 

 ►  January (1) 
 TRANSFORMATION OR TRANSFORMERS AUTOBOT?? 
 
 

 ►  2010 (3) 
 ►  October (3) 
 Auditor- General&apos;s 2009 Report on Poor Food served... My comment on this post about canteen food for sch... Wishing List For Our Food service School In Malays... 
 
 

 ►  2009 (3) 
 ►  November (1) 
 Knowledgeable and Skillful Food Handlers In School... 
 

 ►  October (2) 
 Our School foodservice is stagnant... This is my 1st blog 
 
 
 
My Profile
 saidatul afzan SHAH ALAM, Selangor, Malaysia An academician focusing on foodservice management especially School Canteen.Doing my Phd study on school canteen in Malaysia focusing on food risk management View my complete profile 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
 
Pages
 
 Home 
 
 Awesome Inc. template. Template images by molotovcoketail . Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
