<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008106" url="http://www.popularmechanics.com/home/skills/4284709" time="2012-07-13-01:11" support="3" score="0.0023963566550581437" bingtitle="Types of Skills Everyone Should Know – Video – Top 100 ..." webtitle="Types of Skills Everyone Should KnowVideoTop 100 Important Skills - Popular Mechanics">
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="55"/>
	<description>To confirm that the hitch is secure on the ball, lift the rear ... car; let it idle for 10 minutes, then crank the dead car. Remove the cables in reverse order ...</description>
	<body>
		/ Give a Gift / Customer Service / Promotions / Blogs / Video / / 

 Try: Hottest Cars / Best DIY Tips / Greatest Gadgets Ever Automotive 
 Road Test Auto News DIY Auto Motorcycles Alternative Fuel Jay Leno&apos;s Garage Saturday Mechanic YouTube Show 
 
Featured Stories
 
 6 Common Tire Myths Debunked 
 
 The Evolution of the Convertible 
 Technology 
 Gadgets Aviation Engineering Military Digital Hollywood DIY Tech Your DIY Tech Workshop 
 
Featured Stories
 
 How to Build the Ultimate Laptop Desk 
 
 How to Build a Backyard Water Rocket 
 Science 
 Energy Earth and the Environment Space Health Mythbusters 
 
Featured Stories
 
 Why Does NASA Grows Sunflowers in Space? 
 
 Whats in the Earths Core? 
 Home How-To 
 Projects&amp;Plans Home Improvement Tools Reviews Skills Lawn and Garden 
 
Featured Stories
 
 How to Rid Your Yard of Mosquitoes 
 
 The Tools That Every Man Wants 
 Outdoors 
Featured Stories
 
 How to Swim Like a Champion 
 
 Gear Up With These Kayaking Essentials 
 
 Recreation Sports Survival This is My Job 
 DIY Central     Homepage / Home How-To / Skills / 100 Skills Every Man Should Know: The Instructions (With Videos!) 
100 Skills Every Man Should Know: The Instructions (With Videos!)

Brains and charm are fine, but a real guy needs to know how to do real stuff. After months of debate among PM&apos;s expert editorsand a preview of 2008&apos;s ultimate DIY list now you can explore how to perform life&apos;s essential skills, broken down in 10 categories for the competent manplus 20 tools you need to own. Did we leave anything outor included a skill you don&apos;t think is worthy? Scroll down and click through for tips, then sound off in our chat , or take PMÂs interactive DIY quiz to see how you measure up against the MythBusters and more TV know-it-alls .
 By The Editors Email Print Comments Share September 25, 2008 3:19 AM 
Automotive
 1 | Handle a blowout 
 
&quot;Instead of hitting the brakes, maintain your speed,&quot; says Eric Espinosa, executive director of the Maryland-based National Institute of Vehicle Dynamics. Sudden changes of speed can compromise what structural integrity the tire may still have. Steer gently for the same reason. With things fully under control, slow gradually and pull over to the shoulder.

 2 | Drive in snow 
 
Use snow tires on all four corners. (On nondriving wheels, they maintain traction and prevent spinouts during braking or steering.) Tall, narrow tires have more contact pressure than wide ones do, so they&apos;re better at cutting through snow down to pavement. Apply throttle sparingly to keep the wheels from breaking loose. Traction is poorest at near-freezing temperatures, when the pressure of the tires melts snow or ice into a thin, slick film of water.

 3 | Check trouble codes 
 
Baffled by that annoying Check Engine light? Plug the scan tool into the OBD II port, a 16-pin connector under the dash. If you get a code, write it down to compare next time the light comes on. Some codes, called pending codes, don&apos;t turn on the light, but will still flunk you at inspection time, so scan before your next smog check.

 4 | Replace fan belt 
 
Cut off the old belt with a knife. Inspect for possible causes of failure, such as misaligned pulleys, rubber buildup in the grooves or a worn-out tensioner spring. If everything checks out, install the new belt by unloading the idler pulley and slipping it into place. (Check the owner&apos;s manual; the belt routing can be complex.)

 5 | Wax a car 
 (Photograph by Corbis) Park the car in the shade, or work after sunset to keep hot sunshine off the paint. Wash the car thoroughly with a cleaner that won&apos;t strip off old wax, as household detergent does. Rub the wax on in a circular motion, one panel at a time. Give it a few minutes to haze up, then buff off with terry cloth or microfiber polishing cloths.

 6 | Conquer an off-road obstacle 
 Off-roaders know to lower tire pressure when rock-crawling to improve grip over rocks and sand. Don&apos;t forget to air up when you hit the pavement. It comes down to tire placement. Think: Rubber first. Approach the rock or ledge slowly, using first gear and low range in the 4wd system. Aim the driver&apos;s side tire (or passenger&apos;s side, depending on the obstacle&apos;s location) for the rock or ledge at a slight angle, so the rubber hits before the bumper or fender. Once the tire finds traction and begins to pull the vehicle up, raise your sightline to see farther down the trail. If the tires spin, don&apos;t floor it. Instead, ease off the gas slightly and saw the wheel back and forth, which helps the tires hunt for traction.

 7 | Use a stick welder 
 Alex Tocco, Welding Instructor, Lincoln Electric, Cleveland, Ohio (Photograph by Michael Nemeth) &quot;Stick welding is one of the simplest and most inexpensive ways to get into welding,&quot; Tocco says. (Some handymen prefer wire, or MIG, welding because it&apos;s faster.) The first step in stick welding: Set the amperage for the electrode size and metal thickness. To strike the arc, brush the electrode against the workpiece as if striking a match. Hold the electrode at a 45-degree angle to the center of the joint and drag it along at a 15- to 20- degree lead angle, Tocco says. Maintaining a consistent arc of 1/8 in. or less, move the electrode slowly, so that the molten pool at the end of the electrode washes evenly into both pieces of metal.

 8 | Hitch up a trailer 
 
To confirm that the hitch is secure on the ball, lift the rear of the tow vehicle a couple of inches with the trailer tongue jack. Cross the breakaway chains under the tongue to prevent it from dragging on the pavement in case of a breakaway. To save yourself repeated trips to the rear of the trailer to check lights, turn on both the running lights and four-way flashers simultaneously.

 9 | Jumpstart a car 
 
Use the red cable to connect the batteries&apos; positive (+) terminals. Clip the black cable to the live battery&apos;s negative (-) terminal, but don&apos;t touch the other end to the dead battery&apos;s negative terminal. Instead, clip it to anything metal that&apos;s connected to the engine. Start the live car; let it idle for 10 minutes, then crank the dead car. Remove the cables in reverse order, making sure they don&apos;t touch each other or either car. 


 1-9: Car Skills 10-13: Emergencies 14-42: Home Skills 43-47: Medical Myths 48-50: Military Know-How 51-56: Outdoor Skills 57-59: Primitive Skills 60-64: Surviving Extremes 65-75: Teach Your Kids 76-80: Tech Skills 81-100: Workshop Tools THE LIST: All 100 Skills THE CHAT: What&apos;d We Miss? THE QUIZ: Get Your PM Score THE CELEBS: How Do You Match Up? 
 
 Your DIY Tech Workshop 15 DIY Workshop Tips from the Mythbusters Popular Mechanics 3D Workshop : Where DIY Comes To Life How to Revitalize Your Workshop : DIY Guy Outdoors Survival Strategies And Gear 6 Workshop Router Secrets: DIY Guy 
 
Advertisement
 
 Post a comment 
 CONNECT WITH POPULAR MECHANICS: Featured Video Giveaways 
 Win A Lehr Propane Powered Outboard Motor 
 See All Giveaways More From Popular Mechanics 
 Best New Cars For 2013 100 Hottest Cars of All Time 10 Jobs You Can Do With A Multitool Your Year-Round Plan for the Perfect Lawn The Quick and Easy Guide to Fertilizing Your Lawn 
 From Our Partners 
 QUIKRETE. What America&apos;s Made Of. Spray Nine, one product nine uses. Bosch DistancePlus filters keep oil clean-longer. 
 
Automotive

 Using Nitrogen in Car Tires Is Synthetic Oil Better? New Electric Cars Best Tire Brand Comparison 
 More 
Technology

 Best iPod FM Transmitter How to Make a Speaker Hard Drive Data Recovery Underwater Digital Cameras 
 More 
Science

 UFO Movies Survival Kit Checklist Bomb Shelters Wind Turbine Design 
 More 
Outdoors

 DIY Solar Panels Powerful Handguns: Smith&amp;Wesson Barefoot Running Green Design 
 More 
Home How To

 How to Build a Smoker How to Build a Shed How to Install Drywall How to Build a Fence 
 More 
DIY Central

 Plans for Building a Pergola Bookshelf Plans How to Make Beer Suspended Ceiling 
 More 
Most Popular

 Tennis Serve World&apos;s Largest Cruise Ship Winterize Your Boat How to Hang a Picture Frame Ab Machines That Work 
 
Features

 Apple TV Reviews Painting Tips Raised Garden Beds Home Inspection Checklist Automotive News 
 Try: Hottest Cars / Best DIY Tips / Greatest Gadgets Ever 
About
Popular Mechanics

 About Us Press Room Privacy Policy Your California Privacy Rights Terms of Use Site Map Contact Us Community Guidelines Advertise Online About Our Ads 
 
Popularmechanics.com

 Automotive Technology Science Home How-To Outdoors DIY Central 
 STUFF MEN LIKE How to Build a Car Home Inspection Checklist Diesel Truck Reviews DIY Solar Panels Science Fiction Movies Cadillac CTS Review Dodge Charger Review Synthetic Oil Review Most Fuel Efficient Cars Easy Recipes for Men How to Make Pancakes from Scratch REVIEWS Honda CR-V Review Car Reviews Tuxedo Styles and Reviews Upcoming Movies 2012 Zero Turn Mowers Raised Garden Beds Vizio TV Reviews Ford Focus Review Mens Hairstyles Microsoft Surface Organic Foods HOW TO How to Tie a Tie How to Grow a Beard Pro Painting Tips How To Videos How to Build a Shed How to Iron Painting Kitchen Cabinets How to Make Beer How to Install Drywall Shirt and Tie Combos New Cars 2012&amp;2013 TRENDING Kia Soul Review Automotive News Camaro Review Presidential Candidates 2012 SUV with Best Gas Mileage Best Life Quotes Geothermal Heating New iPad 3 Summer Songs 2012 Mens Fashion Super Foods 
©2012 Hearst Communication, Inc. All Rights Reserved. Being Green / Why did I get this ad? 
 Connect with Facebook Popular Mechanics on Twitter @PopMech Sign up for Popular Mechanics&apos;s free newsletter!
	</body>
</document>
