<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008724" url="http://www.blackrivercountry.net/dining/" time="2012-07-13-02:11" support="2" score="0.002013959616405972" bingtitle="Dining | | Black River FallsBlack River Falls" webtitle="Dining | Black River FallsBlack River Falls">
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Or, grab a quick bite at a convenient fast-food restaurant. Whatever your taste, you’ll find a place to eat in ... tables; one 3 card poker table; one 4 card poker table ...</description>
	<body>
		Black River Falls, Wisconsin—The Northwoods—closer to home.
 Skip to content 
 Lodging 
 Hotels and Motels Bed&amp;Breakfasts Cabins and Lodges Campgrounds 
 Dining Attractions Recreation 
 ATVing, UTVing and Single Track Motorcycling Boating, Canoeing&amp;Kayaking Disc Golf Fishing Golf Hiking Horse Trails Hunting Mountain Biking Recreation Areas Redrock Trail Rides Scuba Diving Skiing&amp;Winter Sports Snowmobiling 
 Retail&amp;Services Community 
 Area Churches Area Schools Black River Falls Public Library Employment Information History Relocating to the Black River Falls Area News Links 
 Events 
 Calendar of Events Karner Blue Race – 5K-10K-Half Marathon Oktoberfest 
 Chamber Info 
 Business Directory FAQs About Chamber Membership Board of Directors and Chamber Staff Why should you join? Ready to join? Annual Dinner Fern Helbling Scholarship Order Your Mural Print Now 
 
 
Dining   
 
Enjoy fresh baked goods, great sandwiches and burgers, steaks, fish fries and great hospitality in the Black River Falls area. Sit down to a hearty dinner at one of the area’s supper clubs. Have a country-style breakfast at a friendly diner. Or, grab a quick bite at a convenient fast-food restaurant. Whatever your taste, you’ll find a place to eat in the Black River Falls area.
 
Search by type of restaurant:
 Select Restaurant Catering Restaurants Taverns 
Airport Lounge

 Contact W9944 Airport Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-4080

Daily lunch and dinner specials–ATV trail access
 
Bev’s Saddle Mound Tap

 Contact Email 
 N8376 Pray Road Pray, WI 54466 Phone: (715) 884-7355

 “Where Good Friends Meet”Daily food specials; open 7 days a week; Monday thru Friday 11am to ?; Saturday&amp;Sunday 8am to ? Serving breakfast; Friday Fish&amp;Shrimp; Saturdays Steak Night; Monday Homemade Pizzas. Join us for good food, beverages&amp;just plain old fashioned fun.
 
Burger King

 Contact Website |  Email 
 909 State Hwy 54 Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-2900

 Serving Breakfast Daily at 6:00 and open until 10:00 pm. Indoor play area.  Bus/truck parking.
 
Castle Hill Supper Club

 Contact Website |  Email 
 N9581 US Hwy 12 Merrillan, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 333-5901

 Since 1942, Castle Hill has been renowned for its USDA Choice Aged Steaks, Scrumptious Seafood,&amp;Plump and Juicy Broasted Chicken along with our Warm Smiles, outstanding service and an atmosphere like nowhere else.

So Join us tonight for our Nightly Celebration of great food, wonderful wine&amp;Memorable Times Only at Castle Hill Supper Club – Jackson County’s “Premier” Steak and Seafood House!
 
Club 95 Supper Club

 Contact Website |  Email 
 101 Sand Prairie Road Hixton, WI 54635 Phone: (715) 963-3191

 Club 95 has been known for great food&amp;friendly service since 1962. Banquet&amp;meeting facilities for 35-400 people. Famous for their nightly specials. They feature a Friday night seafood buffet. Sat. is Prime Rib special. Catering available. Open Wed-Sat. evenings.
 
Cozy Corner Tavern

 Contact Email 
 43 Main Street Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-2651
 
Culver’s of Black River Falls

 Contact Website 925 Commerce Street Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-3000

 We serve delicious made to order hometown favorites. The Butterburger&amp;fresh frozen custard served in a clean friendly atmosphere is what we stand for.
 
Dairy Way, LLC

 Contact Email 
 111 Gebhardt Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 896-5648

 Offering ice cream specialties, burgers, baskets, malts and more. (Open seasonal May- Sep)
 
Doc’s Bunkhouse

 Contact Website |  Email 
 N11702 Elker Rd Merrillan, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 964-8010

 Welcome to the best place to camp and ATV in central Wisconsin! We offer a family friendly campground with something for people of all ages. We have a bar and restaurant that is open seven days a week. There is a mud pit and play area for your ATV as well as access to both Clark and Jackson County ATV trails. Ride right from your camper, tent or cabin to the trails! Our activities include volleyball, mini golf, swimming and horse shoes.
 
First&amp;Last Chance, LLC

 Contact N5090 State Hwy 27 Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-3121

Stop down for great food, fun&amp;drinks! Open Tuesday through Sunday 9:00 a.m. to close. Serving sandwiches&amp;pizza from 11:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m. everyday. Specials: Tuesday–Nachos 5-8pm; Thursday–Tacos; Friday–Fish Fry 5-8 pm. Happy Hour from 3-6pm Tuesday through Friday; Saturday Noon–2pm; Bloody Mary Sunday School every Sunday from 9-Noon. Call to book your next party–they will host weddings, reunions, birthdays, etc. Stop on down for a game of pool or darts. Call for entertainment schedule. Special Events: Annual Feed–2nd Saturday in August, Project Christmas Fund Raiser. Members of Abate.
 
Ho-Chunk Gaming Black River Falls

 Contact Website |  Email 
 W9010 Hwy 54 East Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (800) 657-4621

 Ho-Chunk Gaming Black River Falls is nestled in the beautiful Jackson County Forest near Black River Falls, Wisconsin. This modern facility offers the very best in gaming with over 600 reel and video slot machines; six blackjack tables; one 3 card poker table; one 4 card poker table; one Ultimate Texas Hold’em table; one Roulette table and a 500-seat bingo hall. Ho-Chunk Gaming Black River Falls is sure to have the game for you. W9010 Highway 54 East, Black River Falls. (715) 284-9098, (800) 657-4621. Website: www.ho-chunkgaming.com .
 
Jackson County Tavern League

 Contact Website |  Email 
 101 Sand Prairie Road Hixton, WI 54635 Phone: 715-963-3191

 

The Tavern League of Wisconsin is a non-profit trade association dedicated to serving the needs of the retail beverage alcohol segment of the hospitality industry in the State of Wisconsin. The League exists to provide services to members that are not available to them as individuals and to use the collective strength of its membership to accomplish, as a group, goals that cannot be accomplished alone. The League provides their members with services such as legislative and governmental relations, legal information, educational services and promotes the industry on behalf of its membership.
 
KFC

 Contact Website 609 N Water Street Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-4575

 All you can eat buffet with over 30 items, plus full menu. Easy access to I-94. Open 11am-9pm.
 
Lake Arbutus Pavilion, LLC

 Contact Website |  Email 
 N9501 Thunderbird Ln Hatfield, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 333-7465

Roller skating rink and Diner open Wednesday-Sunday from 10am–10pm. Old fashioned sodas, shakes, malts and beer.
 
Lake Arbutus Resort&amp;Sports Bar

 Contact Website |  Email 
 N1035 Riviera Avenue Hatfield, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 743-4553

 Located in scenic Hatfield Wisconsin, Lake Arbutus Resort offers the perfect get away. Our modern cabins are available year-round and range in sizes to accommodate family fun, 4-wheeling, snowmobiling, hunting or a quiet couple getaway. Our RV Park is right on the water (next to the Tiki Bar). Included on the resort grounds is a modern convenience store with 24 hour gas, deli, bakery, and gift shop.

Lake Arbutus offers excellent opportunities for fishing and recreation, while also offering beautiful scenery. Spend the day on the lake or at Lake Arbutus Sports Bar and Grill watching the latest sporting events. Enjoy a relaxing cocktail at the Tiki Bar. Stop by the newly opened camp store for all you’re sporting and fishing needs. End the day in the relaxing atmosphere during dinner at the Stonesthrow Bar and Grill. Whether spending a day on the lake or enjoying the town of Hatfield, your stay is sure to be enjoyable.

We are located on County Road J at Park Entrance in Hatfield.
 
McDonald’s Restaurant

 Contact Website 850 Hwy 54 East Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-5538

 Since 1955, we’ve been proud to serve the world some of its favorite food. And along the way, we’ve managed not just to live history, but create it:  from drive-thru restaurants to Chicken McNuggets to college credits from Hamburger U and much more. It’s been quite the journey, and we promise this is just the beginning-we’ve got our hearts set on making more history.
 
Molly’s Rude Awakening

 Contact Website |  Email 
 13 County Road A Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-JAVA (5282)

 MRA is a specialty beverage retailer. It offers both hot&amp;cold drinks in a convenient&amp;time effective way. It provides its customers the ability to drive up&amp;order their choice of a custom-blended espresso drink, freshly brewed coffee, or other beverages. Seasonally, MRA will add beverages such as apple cider, hot chocolate, frozen coffees, and more. MRA can also cater any event you are planning with any of your favorite drinks. We will also offer free wireless internet.
 
Northwoods Resort

 Contact Website |  Email 
 W8215 County Rd J Hatfield, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 333-6600

 Located in scenic Hatfield, Northwoods Resort offers the perfect get away. Our modern cabins are available year-round and range in sizes to accommodate family fun, 4-wheeling, snowmobiling, hunting or a quiet couple get away. Included on the resort grounds is a modern convenience store with 24-hour gas, gift shop, restaurant with full bar. Lake Arbutus is within walking distance. Full-service RV camping available.
 
Orange Moose Bar&amp;Grill

 Contact Website |  Email 
 600 Oasis Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-9471

 The Orange Moose Bar&amp;Grill is located at the Best Western Arrowhead Lodge&amp;Suites in Black River Falls. The Orange Moose Bar&amp;Grill serves some of the finest Angus Beef Steaks in Wisconsin and don’t forget about the Friday Fish Fry or Saturday Prime Rib. Come casually off the snowmobile&amp;ATV trails or get dressed up to impress that special someone. On-site banquets or off-site catering available. Restaurant open daily 11am-10pm. Bar open daily 11am.
 
Perkins Family Restaurant

 Contact Website N6209 Oasis Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-2223

 There’s always something new cooking at Perkins! Mammouth Muffins baked fresh daily* KidPerks * A variety of delicious breakfast, lunch&amp;dinner entrees. Last but not least, certainly don’t forget the pie!
 
Re-Pete’s Saloon&amp;Grill

 Contact Website 300 Gebhardt Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-3322

 The areas newest dining experience and sport bar. Stop in at Re-Pete’s in Brockway to enjoy the great food and fun atmosphere.  Great selection of delicious foods from burgers, wraps&amp;salads to Friday night fish fry&amp;Prime Rib specials.
 
Rozario’s

 Contact Email 
 42 N 1st St Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-0006

 Rozario’s offers the best home-made Italian food, including pizza, pasta and sandwiches. Stop in for some superb food, refreshments and great conversation in a welcoming atmosphere.
 
Sand Creek Brewing Company

 Contact Website |  Email 
 320 Pierce Street P.O. Box 187 Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-7553

 In the heart of Black River Country, you’ll find the Sand Creek Brewing Company, one of the best and most respected small breweries in the Midwest. Black River Country has a long history of beer making. The building that houses the Sand Creek Brewing Company began as a brewery in 1856. The Sand Creek Brewing Company carries on that long tradition, brewing an impressive line-up of beers, as well as hard lemonade. The brewery is located at 320 Pierce Street. Tours of the brewery are free and offered every Friday afternoon at 3pm. From May through September, tours are also offered from 3-9pm. Other times can be arranged if you call ahead. Tasting room and gift shop available 8am-4pm, Mon-Fri. Tours are also available by appointment.
 
Skyline Golf Course Bar&amp;Grill

 Contact Website |  Email 
 612 N 11th Street Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-2613

 Skyline Golf Course is the premier golf course in West Central Wisconsin. The 18 hole track offers a variety of challenges for every level of golfer. The front side has significant changes in terrain and the possibility for challenging pin placements on what can be lightening quick greens.

The Second nine is cut out of a pine forest and requires a player to hit accurate tee shots to small landing areas. Skyline has long been known for its beauty whether enjoyed in Spring, Summer or Fall.
 
Stones Throw Supper Club

 Contact W8210 County J Hatfield, WI 54754 Phone: (715) 333-2603

The Stone’s Throw has quickly earned a reputation for being one of the area’s most popular restaurants. Tim&amp;Lana are committed to providing you with a high quality dining experience. The Stones Throw offers a variety of menu choices featuring steaks, seafood, prime rib&amp;more than you bargained for burgers as well as an excellent Friday Night Fish Fry. If you’re hungry for adventure, one of Tim’s creative specials is sure to please.
 
Sunset Tavern

 Contact Email 
 N5890 State Hwy 54 Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-9345
 
Tenba Ridge Winery, LLC

 Contact Website |  Email 
 N27587 Joe Coulee Road Blair, WI 54616 Phone: (608) 525-2413

 From high atop a ridge in rural Trempealeau County sits one of Wisconsin’s most enjoyable winery experiences. With our unique Alsace-inspired grape wines and a variety of fruit wines, Tenba Ridge is the perfect spot to sip, sample and sit as you take in the view of thousands of picturesque acres of bluffs and fields.

Winemaker John Gill follows in the footsteps of his great-grandfather John Francis Gill, who ran a family wine and sheep business in the Alsace-Lorraine area of Germany in the late 1800s before coming to America.

John tries to emulate the methods and materials that would have been available to his great-grandfather more than 100 years ago, making wine in small batches of three to six gallons.

Varieties include Apricot, Blackberry, Blueberry, Cabernet Sauvignon, Cherry, Cranberry, Elderberry, Gewurztraminer, Muller Thurgau, Peach, Plum, Raspberry, Strawberry, Syrah, Pinot Noir, Vinifera grape, Zinfandel and white Zinfandel.

Guests may sample up to six wines for free. After you sample, purchase a glass or a bottle of your favorite and sip while you relax and enjoy the view. Bring a picnic lunch or snacks and make it an afternoon. Experience the gracious living of Tenba Ridge Winery.
 
The Mocha Mouse

 Contact Website |  Email 
 500 Oasis Road Black River Falls, WI 54615 Phone: (715) 284-2541

 Visit our shop for a great selection of Wisconsin cheese, meats, beer, wines&amp;gift items. Enjoy gourmet coffee or hand-dipped ice cream treats. OPEN DAILY.

Open: 6:30am-8pm
Restaurant open: 11am-7:45pm
 
Wetlands Restaurant Pub&amp;Catering

 Contact Website |  Email 
 701 Yogi Circle Warrens, WI 54666 Phone: (608) 378-2510

 Located in Three Bears Lodge in Warrens, WI. Fine dining feel at just the right price. Kids menu, Starbucks Coffee and Sweet Shop. Meetings, weddings, parties…you name it, we can do it!“One stop shopping”is here to make planning an event hassle free!
 Black River Area Chamber of Commerce 120 N. Water Street Black River Falls , WI 54615 
 chamber@blackrivercountry.net 

 Contact Us 
 
 Follow us on Twitter or Find us on Facebook 
 
Powered by Pilch&amp;Barnet
	</body>
</document>
