<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008304" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/san-antonio/102247-let-them-keep-change-not-san-2.html" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="33" score="0.09470071990216977" bingtitle="Let them keep the change or not (San Antonio fast food places ..." webtitle="Let them keep the change or not (San Antonio fast food places)? (West: sales, credit) -  Page 2 - City-Data Forum">
			<query id="000021" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001383" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001194" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... reach behind them and grab a bag, rip the receipt ... the picturess of your desired items, choose condiments ... New fast food restaurant (StoneOak Pkwy &amp; Bulverde), San Antonio ...</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; U.S. Forums &gt; Texas &gt; San Antonio Let them keep the change or not (San Antonio fast food places)? (West: sales, credit) 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 2 of 5 &lt; 1 2 3 4 5 &gt; 
 
 
 
   06-21-2007, 05:49 PM 
 OzzyRules Senior Member   2,440 posts, read 3,826,759 times Reputation: 767 
 You should report it to management when that happens. Even if it&apos;s just a few pennies which I couldn&apos;t care less about, it&apos;s very poor customer service.

What I like is the opposite, like when they owe you 47 cents but they just give you the full 50 cents. That&apos;s good service. 
 
 
 
 
   06-21-2007, 06:24 PM 
 slaleman you catch more files with honey...   Location: San Antonio, TX 545 posts, read 1,266,142 times Reputation: 192 
 See, I&apos;ll tip at Sonic because they&apos;re running to food to you as opposed to just handing it out the window or over the counter. I worked at Wendy&apos;s when I was in high school and college, busted my butt all the time, cleaned all the nasty stuff, worked really late closing shifts, hell I even mowed the grass from time to time, and never expected a penny more from the customers than they were supposed to pay. And I only started out at $3.35/hr.

Now, when I ran pizzas in college, I did expect a little tip...not much. I always hoped to average out to $1 per delivery at the end of the night. It was a college town, and I knew as a college student myself that it wasn&apos;t easy to scrounge up the cash for pizza AND beer.

But, come on, setting out a tip jar at the Chinese pickup place, or an ice cream joint...that&apos;s a little much. I&apos;m sorry if I sound like a jerk here, but if you have to live on minimum wage, that&apos;s your problem. As an educator, I see kids all the time who have the potential to go places if they&apos;d just apply themselves the tiniest bit, but I see them years later working at Mickey D&apos;s because it&apos;s ALL THEY CAN DO. I don&apos;t feel sorry for them, and I&apos;m sure as hell not going to tip them to push some buttons, turn around and grab my Big Mac.

Let the flames begin.... 
 
   06-21-2007, 06:45 PM 
 sapphire Your POV usually makes me LOL   13,086 posts, read 15,434,186 times Reputation: 4226
	</body>
</document>
