<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008238" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/12/a_restaurant_kid_tax_sounds_go.php" time="2012-07-13-01:44" support="1" score="0.0018689211477348874" bingtitle="A Restaurant Kid Tax or Ban? Sounds Good To Me! - Miami ..." webtitle="A Restaurant Kid Tax or Ban? Sounds Good To Me!  - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>Mom would pick up the toy, and the child would do ... Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short ... Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   In the Fast Laine 
A Restaurant Kid Tax or Ban? Sounds Good To Me!
 By Laine Doss Thu., Dec. 1 2011 at 10:08 AM Categories: In the Fast Laine 
 Pin It 
 
 
​ There&apos;s been recent buzz over a buffet restaurant in the UK that tacked on a three pound fee because a woman&apos;s baby stroller was taking up space. According to the London Evening Standard , another woman at the same restaurant was also charged a fee for her six month old.

Media backlash was so bad that the restaurant issued a formal apology on its website stating that &quot;COSMO is a very family-friendly restaurant and we pride ourselves on making children and parents feel valued - which is why we serve thousands of families every single week. The Minimum Charge Policy is intended for toddlers who eat but not as much as a child. It was and never will be intended as a charge for Prams or for babies.&quot;

Remember the story of McDain&apos;s restaurant in Pennsylvania? They made the Wall Street Journal when they decided to instate a six years and older age limit for children at their restaurant.

The other day one of my friends posed a question on Facebook. Apparently she had watched as a woman changed her baby&apos;s diaper in a restaurant booth. Is this normal behavior, she pondered? Most said it was disgusting...but a few parents said &quot;what are ya gonna do?&quot;


 While dining at one of my 
favorite restaurants in New York on a recent trip, my husband and I sat 
down to a very late lunch. A family came in - man, woman, child around 
five. The bored kid started throwing around stuffed animals. Mom would 
pick up the toy, and the child would do it again. This lasted a few 
minutes..until the toy hit me in the head. I walked over and told the 
parents they needed to curtail their kid. Their response was, &quot;She&apos;s a 
child.&quot;

Just last weekend, I was at Schnebly&apos;s Redland Winery in South Miami-Dade. It&apos;s an annual tradition 
to go for a tasting and buy some fruit wine to send to folks up north - 
sort of an alcoholic version of sending oranges from Florida. As we 
were halfway into our tasting, the woman next to us placed her five 
month-old infant on the bar. Like that was fine. A baby on a bar. 
Yesterday evening, I tripped on a stroller as I was leaving a restaurant
 at 10 p.m. What&apos;s a baby doing out at 10?

I&apos;m tired of kids running around and screaming in restaurants and bars, 
kicking the back of my seat in an airplane, and generally ruining my 
day. And guess what? It&apos;s not the kid&apos;s fault -- it&apos;s the parents!

I don&apos;t even get why you would want to take a child to a fancy 
restaurant, anyway. The kids are bored (unless they&apos;re being occupied by
 some portable device -- usually without headphones), they don&apos;t like 
the food (ask a kid whether they want the foie gras or 
mac n&apos; cheese), and they annoy everyone. Including the parents who 
usually have to either take the child out between bites or pretend to 
ignore the wailing and screaming because their $50 steak is getting cold
 and they&apos;re going to enjoy it, damn it!

I don&apos;t have kids. I do have dogs. And I take Harry out for the 
occasional beer -- at a dive bar. If he barks, he goes home. End of 
story. Wish parents of human children felt the same way.

I would like to see babies and children in a special soundproofed cabin 
in the back of an airplane, and I would totally love to see a surcharge 
added onto a restaurant for bringing your child. Maybe that would stop 
people from toting kids to restaurants altogether.

Don&apos;t think kids would ever be banned from restaurants and flights? That&apos;s what smokers said, too.

Look, I have nothing against your kid. But I don&apos;t want to see you 
breastfeed or change his diaper in a restaurant. I don&apos;t want my $100 
meal interrupted by a beanie baby crashing into my skull, or my intimate
 conversation stifled by the wails of a distressed and bored toddler. If
 your child is too young to have manners, that&apos;s no excuse for you . Have
 the manners for him. And if neither of you can behave? Might I suggest Chuck E. Cheese. 

Here&apos;s a video of a parent acting worse than his child. See what we mean?
 


 Follow Short Order 
on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 

 
Location Info
 
Venue



Map
 
 Schnebly Redland&apos;s Winery 

30205 SW 217th Ave., Homestead, FL

Category: General 
 
 2 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 children in restaurants , COSMA Restaurant , McDain&apos;s Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Forget Sanchez, he is the reason that many restaurants are coming up with the policy of no kids.
 
If you are getting dirty looks it is not because your kids are behaving !!!!! You seem like one of those&quot;I am right&quot;and to hell with the rest of you.
 
Sorry but I have very rarely been bothered by other adults in a nice quality restaurant. Me thinks you exaggerate way too much.
 
Too clear for those without common sense, of which there are many.
 
Sounds like one of the parents that ignore their kids behavior in a restaurant
 
But then as we can see parents yell discrimination so it is much better to have a policy.
 
What people need is the notion of being considerate and not&quot;I am entitled&quot;. If your child bothers others you have been inconsiderate. Unfortunately after a while of having parents not being considerate, people want the children gone because they are fed up.
 
Your 6-year-old has an iPad?
 
Again, there&apos;s a difference between&quot;wild creatures of the forest&quot;and an accidental kick on a chair. The only examples you were able to come up with in your story are of such inconsequential nature --a stroller in the way, a stuffed toy that hit you by accident-- that it&apos;s obvious the only reason you don&apos;t seem to grasp the difference it&apos;s because of some irrational sense of entitlement and a disdain for kids in general. A normal person doesn&apos;t get fazed by those small things, much less compose a diatribe wishing for the banishment of a large part of the population to imaginary soundproof cabin sections and Chuck E&apos; Cheese&apos;s. Perhaps you should consider something else than blogging, so you can afford a private jet and a private chef.
 
So allowing children to act like wild creatures of the forest is OK and we all have to deal when your child grabs at stuff at the market, screams a torturous wail at the restaurant, or kicks my seat on the plane?  If I can teach my dog to sit - you can teach your child basic manners.
 
&quot;If someone is giving you diry looks and snide remarks because of your children -- maybe you should take into consideration that maybe something is amiss with your child&apos;s behavior or where your child is is inappropriate.&quot;Or maybe you just act like a confident individual and ignore the whiny full-size babies who apparently believe they were came to the world via immaculate conception.

Kids are kids, they are not pint-size adults and they should not be expected to act like they are. If you can&apos;t deal with it it&apos;s not my problem.
 
If someone is giving you diry looks and snide remarks because of your children -- maybe you should take into consideration that maybe something is amiss with your child&apos;s behavior or where your child is is inappropriate.
 
In a restaurant, what I&apos;m entitled to or not it&apos;s up to the proprietor, not you.

Besides, you aren&apos;t talking about&quot;temper tantrums&quot;which are disruptive no doubt, but also not the usual and constant behavior of kids. You are talking about tripping on a stroller, a baby at a bar--which BTW, Schnebly&apos;s is not exactly an speakeasy, it&apos;s a plantation--and a stuffed animal that hit you by accident. There isn&apos;t exactly a conspiracy of kids to make you suffer.

It seems to me you are one of those people who just can&apos;t stand kids. You see a kid in a place you deem inappropriate, you start looking for reasons to dislike what the kid and the parents are doing. A kid may not be louder than an adult&apos;s loud conversation, or worse, being on the phone. A toy accidentally thrown at your head is not more annoying than a grown up knocking your chair by mistake. But because it&apos;s a kid you somehow believe it gives you permission to judge the parents. That&apos;s fine, but parents also have the right to patronize places they like and where they--and their money--are welcomed.If I went by the imaginary rules of people like you, I would have been condemned to a decade of family restaurants and no travel. Thanks, but no thanks. I don&apos;t let my kid run wild in restaurants or planes, but I&apos;m also not intimidated by dirty looks or snide remarks.
 
agree. though traditional power lunch places should obviously not be a child&apos;s playground.
 
Totally correct and a fabulous idea.
 
You&apos;re not entitiled to have your child have a temper tantrum during my dinner. Unless you&apos;re picking up the check.
 
Next time the moron behind you blows his horn repeatedly for you to move up a few feet in traffic, and you are two seconds from beating him with a tire iron, think of the poor slob in seat 12b trapped next to a screaming child in seat 12c. Better yet, how about you and the wife on date night trying to hear one another over the wails of that same child at the next table? Maybe parents should act as adults and give some thought to where they take their behaviorly challenged children. Just a thought.
 
Nothing to pad blog views like bringing up kids in restaurants and airplanes. Where to start? Have you seen McDain&apos;s? That only qualifies as luxury dining in the boondocks. I would never bring a kid to The Forge or Prime 112, but even high end places (in price) can be welcoming for kids. My son has been enjoying Michael&apos;s Genuine almost as long as the place have been opened, for example. There&apos;s outdoor sitting, and indoors the dim is so loud you&apos;ll be hard pressed to hear the child next table. Besides, it&apos;s downright stupid to compare kids with smoking, a nasty and filthy habit that has direct consequences to the health of others.

I agree with Frodnesor; adults have bothered me much more both in restaurants and in airplanes. And whiny adults whinning about kids usually get put in their place. You are not alone in the world, while you are entitled to certain courtesies, the rest of us including parents are just as entitled. Rent a private room or a private jet if you can&apos;t stand a little discomfort.
 
Under certain circumstances children can be like second hand smoke. Need I say more?
 
A simple solution to this equation is thus: 

   A. If child is accompanying adult, go to a child friendly restaurant.

   B. If adult is without child, go wherever you want.

No brainer if the adult has common sense.
 
Yes, but when the dollar amount gets higher it generally means you&apos;re buying into the whole package...the food, the ambiance, the service - even the lighting, the wine list, the bathrooms, the candles, and the quality of the linens on the table come into play. So when a screaming child interrupts my gorgeous date night with my husband I am more pissed off and its exponentially more inappropriate than in, say, Chili&apos;s at 5:00 p.m.
 
That is my point.  Rude behavior is rude behavior regardless of what your meal cost.  There was no need to add the cost of your meal.
 
If the meal were a buck I still wouldn&apos;t want to hear a child screaming.
 
What a ridiculous article.  So kids should not be able to eat out or travel?  Are they allowed out of the house?  What if you were walking in deep thought and heard a pesky kid yelling outside?

I have a 6 year old (who eats much more than mac and cheese) and he has been going out to eat with me since he was a baby.  I don&apos;t tolerate bad behavior, and I even make him put the volume down on his iPad...

Who gives a $hit how much your meal cost.  If the meal would have been $50, would the behavior been any less annoying?
 
Ahem to that!
 
I have two kids, but I can totally see your point. For the most part I agree with you. When my husband and I get a sitter, the last thing I want to hear is someone else&apos;s kid. The only solution is for restaurant managers to grow a pair and ask the offending parties to behave or leave. That way those of us who have taught our children manners, aren&apos;t penalized.
 
Just about every incident of bad behavior I&apos;ve seen by a child has been equaled by bad behavior of adults. I don&apos;t want my $100 meal interrupted by their inane tone-deaf prattle, their obnoxious drunken guffaws, their annoying tapping and shoving of the banquette, their grotesque plastic surgery disasters (which have provided a lot more cleavage display than breastfeeding in restaurants, though I suppose not all of it undesirable), either.

Rudeness is rudeness, at any age. But kids won&apos;t learn how to eat and behave in restaurants if they&apos;re not given the opportunity.

Smoking on airplanes (and in restaurants and bars) is a health issue. It&apos;s got nothing to do with how much you enjoy your flight.

There should be a tax on adult writers whining like babies over kids in restaurants.
 
Dinner at a nice place, yes, a fee because the kids should be left home with the babysitter.  Otherwise you are affecting others dining experiences.

Lunch?  Kids should be expected.
 

TotalComments: 28
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Tobacco Road
 View Ad | View Site 
Flip Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
Trio on the Bay
 View Ad | View Site 
Gordon Biersch
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 The Next Rendition of the Harding Dinner Series; Menu for Balloo and Zapata &quot;Dinner With Friends&quot; Developer Gil Dezer To Knock Down a Miami Institution Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
