<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008423" url="http://travel.yahoo.com/p-travelguide-18947008R-fazolis-i" time="2012-07-13-01:53" support="1" score="0.002637711107577324" bingtitle="Fazoli&apos;s - Waco, Texas - Yahoo! Travel" webtitle="Fazoli&apos;s - Waco, Texas - Yahoo! Travel">
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>When I heard a voice I gave my order, the next ... want to eat before they pull up to an order window at a fast food restaurant??? ... will not go there again and I will tell ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Travel 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Travel Ideas 
 Travel Articles Beach Family Golf Honeymoon National Parks Ski Summer Weekend Winter 
 Travel Guides Book a Trip 
 Deals Flights Hotels Car Rental Vacations Cruises Specials Vacation Rentals 
 My Travel 
 My Profile My Trips Create a Trip TimeTraveler 
 Visit Britain Disney Travel 
 Walt Disney World Resort Disneyland Resort Disney Cruise Line Aulani Resort, Hawai&apos;i Disney Vacation Club Adventures by Disney 
 
 
 Travel Guides Explore Trip Plans 
 Search Yahoo! Travel Search Welcome! Please sign in. Home Airport: Unavailable Edit»     Change Home Airport Enter a city or airport code to find your home airport. SUBMIT Loading... You must sign in to change your home airport. You must sign in again to change your home airport. SIGN IN We&apos;re sorry, your airport could not be saved. Please try again in a few minutes. We&apos;re sorry, there was a problem. Please try again in a few minutes. Please re-enter a city or airport code and select an airport from the list to continue.     SHARE   PRINT Facebook Twitter Delicious StumbleUpon Home &gt; Travel Guides &gt; United States &gt; Texas &gt; Waco &gt; Waco Restaurants &gt; Fazoli&apos;s Waco 
 OVERVIEW HOTELS VACATION RENTALS THINGS TO DO RESTAURANTS TRIP PLANS MAP DEALS 
   
 Fazoli&apos;s , Waco
 5201 W Waco Dr, Waco, TX 76710           AVERAGE USER RATING Cuisine: Italian Restaurants Contact: (254) 776-1324 Visit Website View more information on Yahoo! Local No Photos Available Image Search» See all Waco Restaurants»   Map   Add to Trip     Loading... Interactive Map of Waco, TX       Expand Full List Show Fewer Results     Refresh Map Items Reset Map Map Refresh On? 
By keeping map refresh on, you will see new search results as you move the map.
 Yes, keep on No, turn it off Updating Map         WRITE A REVIEW   
Yahoo! User Reviews
 Reviews for Fazoli&apos;s: 1           AVERAGE OVERALL RATING           USER RATING By A Yahoo! Contributor , 9/18/09 We visited this restaurant today and got treated reallly stupidly. When we pulled up to the order placing area outside of the place and placed our order, no one responded right away. When I heard a voice I gave my order, the next thing I knew someone came on and asked me for our order. I told them that I had already ordered and was informed that they did not have my order. I gave it again and drove forward to the delivery window. I asked them why I received such poor customer service and they advised me that I was dealing with a recording that is used to warn them that someone is there. What the Hell kind of customer service is this anyway? Why did I have to give my order twice? Does your company think that people are too stupid to know what they want to eat before they pull up to an order window at a fast food restaurant??? I will try your establishment one more time and if I am treated with the low respect again, I will not go there again and I will tell everyone I come in contact with about the poor service I received and let them know that you guys think people are stupid and have to be baited to eat something other than what they wanted. If you want to respond to this message, you can reach me at knight2965@yahoo.com. If I hear nothing I will be convinced that you do not care about your customers. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem Loading... Loading...     
Explore the Waco, TX Travel Guide
 
Popular Attractions in Waco, TX 

 Cameron Park Zoo Cottonwood Creek Golf Course Scruffy Murphy&apos;s Irish Pub Waco Water Park Design House, The Suspension Bridge and Riverwalk Richland Mall Don&apos;s Humidor McCulloch House Spirit of the Rivers 
 
Popular Hotels in Waco, TX 

 Quality Inn And Suites near University Waco Fairfield Inn Suites Waco North Comfort Inn and Suites Waco Victorian Inns Waco Hampton Inn Waco Residence Inn Waco Knights Inn Waco Courtyard Waco Americas Best Value Inn BEST WESTERN Old Main Lodge 
 
Popular Cities near Waco, TX 

 Dallas, TX Austin, TX Fort Worth, TX Arlington, TX Killeen, TX Irving, TX College Station, TX Grapevine, TX Garland, TX Plano, TX 
 Suggest an Attraction Suggest a Hotel     
 Waco Tx Hotels Hotels 
Best Rates On Hotels &amp;Motels Search By City And Save Today.
 www. HotelsByCity .com Waco Hotels 
Find Hotels in Waco , TX . Book Direct&amp;Save up to 40%.
 Hilton .com/Waco Hotels in Waco , TX 
Great Rates at Hotels in Waco , TX . Book Online or Call Today!
 Hotels-Rates .com 
     
Yahoo! Users Voted
 Top tags for Fazoli&apos;s, Waco  ()  ()  () No entries yet. Vote on what it&apos;s best for... See additional tags for this restaurant   VOTE       Available in the App Store     
 Not the right restaurant for you? View similar restaurants: 
 
In this neighborhood
 Kettle Restaurant Cathay House Chick-Fil-A Wingstop Chick-Fil-A 
Same cuisine
 Olive Garden Baris Carino&apos;s Italian Domino&apos;s Pizza Domino&apos;s Pizza Browse all Waco restaurants»     Submit a change or correction for this restaurant       Home &gt; Travel Guides &gt; United States &gt; Texas &gt; Waco &gt; Waco Restaurants &gt; Fazoli&apos;s Travel Ideas Travel Articles Beach Family Golf Honeymoon National Parks Ski Summer Weekend Winter Travel Guides Travel Guides Explore Trip Plans Book a Trip Deals Flights Hotels Car Rental Vacations Cruises Specials Vacation Rentals My Travel My Profile My Trips Create a Trip TimeTraveler Other Yahoo! Services Downloads Yahoo! Travel: Your best choice for cheap airline tickets , hotels , and other great deals!     Suggest a Hotel or an Attraction *Terms&amp;Conditions: Savings calculation is based on Flight + Hotel vacation package bookings for a 3 month period for 2 adults with a 2+ night length of stay compared to price of the same components if booked separately during same period. Savings will vary based on origin/destination, length of trip, travel dates and selected travel supplier(s). Savings not available on all packages.

 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Copyright/IP Policy - About our Ads Portions copyright©2012 Y! TimeTraveler App for iPhone - Timed Travel Made Possible -   
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
