<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008200" url="http://www.socialanxietysupport.com/forum/f26/would-you-be-embarrassed-if-you-worked-at-a-fast-94426/" time="2012-07-13-01:41" support="1" score="0.028536870531680227" bingtitle="Would you be embarrassed if you worked at a fast food place ..." webtitle="Would you be embarrassed if you worked at a fast food place? - Social Anxiety Forum">
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>I personally couldn&apos;t work at a fast food place ... matter. in the case of working in a fast food ... Imagine what they think of me, ordering that type of food!</description>
	<body>
		X 
 Download the SAS Android App 

Or switch to mobile version of the forums 
 X 
 Download the SAS iPhone App 

Or switch to mobile version of the forums 
 
 Social Anxiety Support 
 
 Home Social Anxiety Disorder 
 What is Social Anxiety? Causes Seeking Treatment Medication Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy Self-Treatment Liebowitz Social Anxiety Scale 
 Therapy 
 Overview Find a Therapist Online Therapy 
 Groups 
 Overview Find a Group Telephone Groups 
 Treatment Reviews 
 Psychotherapy Medication Supplements Audio Therapy Programs Books Other Treatments 
 Community 
 Forums Chat Stories eGroups Blogs Join SAS 
 
 Help/FAQ Log In Join SAS What You Must Think of Me: A Teenager&apos;s Firsthand Experience with Social Anxiety 
 Forums Chat eGroups Blogs Members FAQ Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 Join the SAS community   
 
   Social Anxiety Forum &gt; Recovery &gt; Coping With Social Anxiety Would you be embarrassed if you worked at a fast food place? 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 
 Thread Tools 
 07-12-2010, 11:08 AM  # 1 ( permalink ) Family Guy  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Jun 2010 Location: Quahog, Rhode Island Gender: Male Age: 18 Posts: 215 
 

 Would you be embarrassed if you worked at a fast food place? The reason why I&apos;m asking this is because I work at Dairy Queen. I&apos;m only 16 and there&apos;s not a lot of places avaible for teenagers to work. It&apos;s not like I&apos;m in my 30&apos;s or 40&apos;s working there. Anyways, when I see customers, and especially people I recognize from school, they usually look at. Of course my mind automatically thinks the worst and thinks that they are thinking negatively about me. Sometimes they look and laugh and talk with there friends...but of course they could be laughing or talking about something else...idk. This makes me sorta depressed and I can&apos;t stop thinking to myself,&quot;what could they possibly be thinking of me?&quot;It&apos;s driving me crazy!

I mean, what would you think of a person that goes to your school, and you see them working? Do you think negatively of them, or surprised, or happy for them, or what???

Can anyone relate or give out some advice?   
 
 07-12-2010, 11:21 AM  # 2 ( permalink ) NVU  
  
 Status: Cynic Join Date: Jul 2010 Location: Liverpool, UK Gender: Male Age: 21 Posts: 326 
 

 A job is a job to me, if it pays it&apos;s all good At the end of the day someone has to do it. I personally couldn&apos;t work at a fast food place, not because it&apos;s embarrassing but because I wouldn&apos;t be able to deal with how many people are in and out and the social demand. __________________
 
 Life is for each man a solitary cell whose walls are mirrors. 
 - Eugene O&apos;Neill 
 
Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/deandavo   
 
 07-12-2010, 11:23 AM  # 3 ( permalink ) millenniumman75  
  
 Status: Super Moderator Join Date: Feb 2005 Location: Dayton, OH Gender: Male Age: 37 Posts: 78,576 
 

 Been there, done that. I worked at McDonald&apos;s (near a mall!) for three summers and a winter break - 19, 20, and 21 years of age. __________________
 millenniumman75 
You are a success story waiting to happen!
Live and let live VACUUMS more than a Hoover....
Live and HELP live is better!

 TROLL ALERT STATUS: 
 CHAT AND FORUMS -&gt; BERT 
 (warnings/infractions can be issued) 


 WATCH WHAT YOU TYPE!   
 
 07-12-2010, 11:31 AM  # 4 ( permalink ) shadowmask  
 Status: User Requested Permanent Ban Join Date: Jun 2009 Gender: Male Age: 26 Posts: 5,877 
 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Family Guy 
I mean, what would you think of a person that goes to your school, and you see them working? Do you think negatively of them, or surprised, or happy for them, or what???
 
 There&apos;s no reason they&apos;d be thinking negatively of you. You&apos;re making money and they aren&apos;t, if anything they should be jealous. When I was in school, almost all of my classmates who had jobs either worked at Mcdonalds or KFC, and nobody thought any less of them, I promise. It&apos;s an entry level position which is pretty much all a teenager can get. I think you should be happy for yourself that you have the initiative to hold down a job despite still being in school and having SA. That requires a lot of strength, especially at your age.   
 
 07-12-2010, 11:35 AM  # 5 ( permalink ) Jessie203  
  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Feb 2008 Posts: 2,936 
 

 Long as I was going to go to school/going to school, no I would not care.
You&apos;re 16.. some people your age havn&apos;t even got their first jobs yet.. chicks will dig it, ask you for free ice cream lol __________________
 
All the time they lie to me they suffocate
All the time they&apos;re suffering
So when will it end?   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:05 PM  # 6 ( permalink ) cubanscorpio  
  
 Status: Meandering Join Date: Jun 2010 Location: NC Gender: Male Age: 27 Posts: 682 
 

 i think this is a common symptom of SA -- feeling bad when other people laugh cuz you make it a negative thing about you. i do it to. i guess the problem here is giving credit to other people and not enough to the self. if you believed in yourself and accepted your decisions as good, you wouldnt care if ppl laughed because as long as you&apos;re ok with it, it&apos;s fine. what other people thought wouldn&apos;t matter.
in the case of working in a fast food restaurant.. you&apos;re a teenager and you&apos;re making money for youself. as long as you think thats good thing, thats all that should matter. other peoples opinions should not even be a factor. __________________

 &quot;And I know what I have to do now. I gotta keep breathing. Because tomorrow, the sun will rise. Who knows what the tide could bring?&quot;   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:09 PM  # 7 ( permalink ) Paragon  
  
 Status: Big Damn Hero Join Date: Apr 2010 Location: UK (England) Gender: Male Age: 26 Posts: 726 
 

 I&apos;ve done that and yeah i felt the same way about it for a while. But at the end of the day it&apos;s work, you&apos;re earning money and anyone who&apos;s done it knows it&apos;s usually hard work with horrible managers for little pay, so they shouldn&apos;t look down on you. I definitely wouldn&apos;t. And people who do can go to hell   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:09 PM  # 8 ( permalink ) BetaBoy90  
 Status: User Requested Permanent Ban Join Date: Jan 2010 Age: 22 Posts: 4,310 
 

 Yeah I&apos;d definitely be embarassed about it, well only if people could see me working, like the drive thru speaker or a cashier. But I would say my first job was even more embarassing, or at least close, I worked at a grocery store as a buggy boy/cart pusher for over 3 years. I had to wear a stupid vest and push carts through heat, rain and snow and yeah dirty job and extremely mind numbingly boring.   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:11 PM  # 9 ( permalink ) BetaBoy90  
 Status: User Requested Permanent Ban Join Date: Jan 2010 Age: 22 Posts: 4,310 
 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by millenniumman75 Been there, done that. I worked at McDonald&apos;s (near a mall!) for three summers and a winter break - 19, 20, and 21 years of age. 
 So you&apos;re the one he kept spitting in my burgers....   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:29 PM  # 10 ( permalink ) MrBBB  
  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Jun 2010 Location: Savannah, GA Gender: Male Age: 43 Posts: 85 
 

 The only restaurant experience I have had is as a bus boy and I hated it. After that I went for mostly outdoor jobs like landscaping. You don&apos;t have to deal with people, you get a good tan, and a good physical work out. The only downside (if you live in a cold state) is that you have to find other work during the winter, or collect unemployment for a few months.   
 
 07-12-2010, 12:53 PM  # 11 ( permalink ) layitontheline  
  
 Status: i like my old leaf. Join Date: Aug 2009 Gender: Female Age: 23 Posts: 3,693 
 

 If I was 30, yes. You&apos;re 16 and have a job? That&apos;s great. Nothing embarrassing about that at all. And Dairy Queen rocks. Hit me up with an oreo blizzard.   
 
 07-12-2010, 01:03 PM  # 12 ( permalink ) poeticinjustice  
 Status: Agoraphobic Anxietist Join Date: Jul 2010 Location: Pennsylvania Gender: Female Posts: 165 
 

 I work at McDonald&apos;s. I hate working there, but it&apos;s hard work and and I am not embarrassed by it. However, the persona attached to working there, especially around my area, is misleading and can be a little embarrassing. __________________
 Love is the only way to Justice   
 
 07-12-2010, 01:09 PM  # 13 ( permalink ) ShyViolet  
  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Nov 2003 Gender: Female Age: 32 Posts: 2,515 
 

 There&apos;s no shame in working at a fast food place, especially at your age. It&apos;s probably the most common type of job amongst teenagers. I&apos;m sure a lot of 16-year-olds have never had a job before, so be proud of yourself. When I was a teenager and saw my peers at their workplaces I felt bad about myself for not working too.   
 
 07-12-2010, 01:23 PM  # 14 ( permalink ) lostinlife  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Jun 2010 Posts: 148 
 

 You can tell a lot about a person from how they treat service people. If someone looks down on you for working at a fast food place, it&apos;s their problem not yours. A job is a job, it doesn&apos;t define who or what a person is. You&apos;re doing good honest work and should feel proud that you can hold down a job in this economy.   
 
 07-12-2010, 02:15 PM  # 15 ( permalink ) jennifer1105  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: May 2010 Age: 23 Posts: 75 
 

 A job is a job is a job. I&apos;m 21 years old and I work in a buffet seating people and ringing people up...sure, I am better than that buy I need the money. Plus, you&apos;re onl;y 16 where else are you going to work at your age? __________________
 
   
 
 07-12-2010, 02:21 PM  # 16 ( permalink ) Darren07  
  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Sep 2009 Location: Miami, FL Gender: Male Age: 23 Posts: 174 
 

 I worked at Burger King when I was 16/17 and it wasn&apos;t too bad (although my SA wasn&apos;t nearly as bad as it is now). It&apos;s not too bad; you get free food (which you get sick of after a week, literally) and girls do like the fact that you&apos;re not some lazy bum sitting at home mooching off his parents. Maybe into my 30s if I worked there perhaps I would be, but even when I see older folks working at fast food joints I can&apos;t bring myself to judge them because I dont know their situation.   
 
 07-12-2010, 02:31 PM  # 17 ( permalink ) Monroee  
  
 Status: Circus Freak Join Date: Aug 2009 Location: USA. Gender: Female Age: 21 Posts: 3,172 
 

 No. Through high school, and even now, I see people I know (as in know who they are from school) working at fast food places and grocery stores. I&apos;M the one is who embarrassed. Because they are making money at a job and I&apos;m not, just spending money on greasy food. Imagine what they think of me, ordering that type of food!

My point. With SA, we direct everything to ourselves. It doesn&apos;t matter what side of the counter we are on, we&apos;ll make up some self-conscious fear. Its in our nature, our disease. So no, there is nothing odd about a teenager at a fast food place. Thats usually where people start out. And no, in reality, they are not laughing at you for working at an ordinary place. Its all the SA, man.   
 
 07-12-2010, 02:37 PM  # 18 ( permalink ) DuncanThaw  
  
 Status: gnomely Join Date: Jun 2009 Age: 30 Posts: 228 
 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by jennifer1105 A job is a job is a job. 
 

I don&apos;t see the point in judging anyone for the job that they do. People spend way too much energy worrying about being judged, or judging others.

Fast food service seems like difficult work for which you&apos;re not compensated very well. I have never done it, but it seems like it would be a daily torment. So the extent of my judgment towards people who do it is,&quot;sheesh, your job sucks and I wish that you were paid better, and I do hope that you find something better because this is some seriously soul-crushing rubbish&quot;. I don&apos;t even want to bother complaining about a problem with an order because it&apos;s not like their pay compensates them adequately for conflict resolution/problem-solving, though they&apos;re expected to do it on a daily basis.

I see some comments that it&apos;s fine if you&apos;re a teenager, but not if you&apos;re older. But food service workers I see range in age from teenagers to quite old, with many in the young adult to middle-age range. It bothers me that anyone would suggest that they should feel embarrassed about it. Very few people have jobs which are ideal in the sense of personal fulfillment; fast food is just more visible and less well-paid than most.

I wish it were otherwise, but most people are just doing what they have to in order to get by. __________________
 I had no time to Hate -
Because
The Grave would hinder Me -
And Life was not so
Ample I
Could finish - Enmity -

Nor had I time to Love -
But since
Some Industry must be -
The little Toil of Love -
I thought -
Be large enough for Me -

-- Emily Dickinson   
 
 07-12-2010, 02:57 PM  # 19 ( permalink ) Loretta  
 Status: SAS Member Join Date: Jul 2010 Posts: 32 
 

 I have nothing but respect for anyone who is working any job, regardless of age. I&apos;m turning 23, have just graduated from college, and have yet to find the courage to seriously pursue ANY job. I&apos;m scared of what people will think if/when I get an entry-level job. I, personally, refuse to work in food service, unless it&apos;s a coffee shop--there&apos;s way too much of a stigma on college graduates flipping burgers.

But I can&apos;t imagine why anyone would look down on a 16-year-old working in fast food. That would be like looking down on a 16-year-old for being a new driver. Working in entry-level jobs, especially fast food, is kind of a rite of passage in high school (one I never undertook). If any of your peers are laughing at you (which I seriously doubt they are), just think: in a few years, they might find themselves scrounging for entry-level jobs because they don&apos;t have any work experience, while you&apos;re moving up in the world because you do.   
 
 07-12-2010, 03:00 PM  # 20 ( permalink ) Logan X  
 Status: User Requested Permanent Ban Join Date: Feb 2004 Posts: 7,979 
 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by layitontheline If I was 30, yes. 
 Exactly. If i worked at a fast food place at 37, i would be so ashamed. I think i would beg on the streets before accepting work in those type of places, unless they offer me a janitor position. Thats acceptable work for a dude my age.   
 
 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 &gt; 
 

 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are Off Pingbacks are Off Refbacks are Off Forum Rules 
 
 
 


 Similar Threads Thread Thread Starter Forum Replies Last Post Fast Food? mezzoforte General Discussion 107 03-05-2012 08:11 AM Fast Food? NotRealName Nutrition, Supplements and Exercise 6 05-07-2010 12:03 AM Fast Food Zeddicus Voting Booth 23 04-08-2009 09:23 PM Working at a fast food place - bad for anxiety? WintersTale The Work Place 16 01-04-2009 09:03 AM Favorite Fast Food Place aviator99 Voting Booth 43 05-07-2008 03:11 PM 

 All times are GMT -7. The time now is 04:41 PM . Archive - Top Powered by vBulletin®©2000-2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
SEO by vBSEO 3.6.0©2011, Crawlability, Inc.
Hosted by Nimbus Hosting . 
 Home Social Phobia Therapy Groups Treatment Reviews Mobile Apps Forums 

 About SAS Disclaimer Terms of Use Privacy Policy Contact Us Help/FAQ 

Copyright©2012 Social Anxiety Support
	</body>
</document>
