<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008769" url="http://www.catering.basterfieldonline.com/product_info.php/deep-fat-fryer-electric-countertop-unit-c60-modular-range-p-163" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="3" score="0.0066652671651929" bingtitle="Fryers Deep Fat Fryer Electric | Countertop Unit | C60 Modular Range" webtitle="Fryers Deep Fat Fryer Electric | Countertop Unit | C60 Modular Range">
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>Service Line; Fast Food Restaurant Equipment; Counter Top Equipment; Cooking Equipment ... Preparation Tables | Work Tables; Refrigeration Equipment; Utensils | Condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Catering Medical Building Processing 
 
 +27.11.822.9991 Contacts Sitemap 
 
 About 
 Company Overview Vision&amp;Mission Procurement Solutions Contacts Privacy Policy Conditions of Use 
 Products 
 Catering Equipment Medical Equipment Building Products Processing Equipment 
 Contacts 
 Contact Us Request Quotation Locate Us Twitter Facebook 
 Networking 
 Twitter Facebook Contacts 
 Navigation 
 Homepage Medical Equipment Medical Equipment Building Products Processing Equipment Contacts Request Quotation Sitemap 
 
 
 
 
 CALL US NOW

+27.11.822.9991
 
 
REQUEST QUOTATION 
 

 
 
 Request a quotation on a product or a non-standard product 
 
 
 
 
QUICK SEARCH 
 

 
 
   

 Go To Advanced Search 
 
 
 
 
OUR PRODUCTS 
 

 
 
 
 Pressure Cookers | Pressure Canners Service Line Fast Food Restaurant Equipment Counter Top Equipment Cooking Equipment Bratt Pans | Tilting Frying Pans Stoves | Ovens Boiling Pans Griddles | Fry Tops Ranges | Stovetops Fryers Distribution Equipment Hot Holding Equipment | Cold Holding Equipment Beverage Equipment Trolleys | Mobile Units Preparation Tables | Work Tables Refrigeration Equipment Utensils | Condiments | Smalls 
 
 
 
 
 
NEW PRODUCTS 
 

 
 
 
 E23140 Bain Marie Type Counter Top Model (CT) 
 
 Request Quotation 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home » Catering Equipment » Cooking Equipment » Fryers 

 
 
 
 
 Deep Fat Fryer Electric | Countertop Unit | C60 Modular Range Request Quotation 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Click on image(s) to enlarge 
 
 
 
 
 

 Specifications&amp;Available Models: (show / hide)

 
 Product Code Dimensions Type Pan Volume Basket Dimensions Element Ratings Electrical Loading Gross Volume Weight C60100SPF W400mm x D600mm x H265mm Single Pan 1 x 8Lt 190mm x 280mm x 100mm 1 x 7.5kW 380V, 3~, 50Hz 0.11m 3 20kg C60100DPF W600mm x D600mm x H265mm Double Pan 2 x 8Lt 190mm x 280mm x 100mm 2 x 7.5kW 380V, 3~, 50Hz 0.16m 3 39kg 

Body, paneling and wells made of stainless steel.
Stainless steel basket.
Suspension mechanism for the oil to leak down after the frying.
Controlled by thermostat.
Equipped with 1 basket in each well.
Drainage tap.
 Request Quotation 
 This product was added to our online catalog on Wednesday 28 September, 2011. 
 
 To view downloadable product documentation you may need to get the latest version of adobe acrobat reader . 
 
 
 
 Share this on Facebook Add this to Google Bookmarks Share this on Twitter Shat this on Digg! Share this on Reddit Share this on del.icio.us Share this on StumbleUpon Share this on Technorati Share this on Blinklist Share this on DesignFloat 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 *Specifications subject to change without prior notice. 
 
 
About
 
 Company Overview Vision&amp;Mission Procurement Solutions Contacts Privacy Policy Conditions of Use 
 
Products
 
 Catering Equipment Medical Equipment Building Products Processing Equipment 
 
Contacts
 
 Contact Us Request Quotation Locate Us Twitter Facebook 
 
Navigation
 
 Homepage Catering Equipment Medical Equipment Building Products Processing Equipment Contacts Request Quotation Sitemap 
 
 Follow us Like us Contacts 
 
Basterfield
 
 +27.11.8229991 (tel) +27.11.8229988 (fax) sales@basterfield.co.za 
 
 

Supported browsers?
 
 Privacy Conditions Webmaster 
 Copyright©2011 Basterfield Engineering (Pty) Ltd .
	</body>
</document>
