<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008563" url="http://www.dietriffic.com/2008/03/26/25-easy-breakfast-ideas-for-the-bleary-eyed/" time="2012-07-13-02:01" support="3" score="0.0037023283007579532" bingtitle="25 Easy Breakfast Ideas - Healthy Eating Tips - Dietriffic.com" webtitle="Breakfast Ideas: 25 Easy Breakfast Ideas To Make You Perform Better — Healthy Eating Tips">
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... reasons to not forgo this important meal ... changed of life style, people used to eat a toast or just cup of ... on making healthier choices at the fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home About Contact BMI Chart Free Book New? Start Here ! 
 
 Healthy Eating Tips 
 You are here: Healthy Eating Tips   »   Healthy Eating   »  25 Easy Breakfast Ideas Why You Should Eat Eggs For Breakfast 3 Strange But True Weight Gain Causes 10 Ways To Live Longer And Feel Better Why Am I Fat? Here Are 13 Reasons ISSUE
 187 
25 Easy Breakfast Ideas
 
flickr: pierofix
 
 Breakfast ideas are something that most people don’t think about.

An addiction to cereal and toast is certainly a problem in the west. As is a tendency to hit the snooze button, so that there’s barely enough time to have anything in the morning.

But, having a healthy breakfast is so, so important.

There’s an old saying, which says, “Breakfast like a king, lunch like a prince, and dine like a pauper!” 

The truth is however that most people don’t eat a suitable, healthy breakfast, never mind eating“like a king!”

Healthy breakfast ideas…

Breakfast literally means “ breaking the fast ,” and it helps us to‘restock’or‘refuel’our energy stores, which have been depleting during the overnight fast, giving us energy for the day’s activities.
 
 So, what should a healthy breakfast consist of? Here’s a guideline…

 One serving of a whole grain carbohydrate. One serving of calcium containing food. One serving of fruit. It’s also fine to have a protein serving, for example meat, or an egg, but it’s not necessary for most people. 

When most people think of a healthy breakfast, a small handful of choices (often boring) come to mind. But, it really doesn’t have to be boring at all.

There are heaps of easy breakfast ideas that don’t take up half your morning preparing them, but it’s really important that you have something nutritious, for a number of reasons…

 Note: If you’re serious about mastering how to have and what to eat for an easy healthy breakfast, make sure you visit the healthy breakfast resource.

5 reasons it’s important to consider healthy breakfast ideas…

 It kick starts our metabolism–speeding it up, and therefore burning calories rather than storing them. It boosts our nutrient intake–breakfast eaters have a lower fat intake, a higher fibre intake, and significantly higher intakes of vitamins and minerals, especially calcium, iron and magnesium . It helps prevent binge eating–hunger will be better regulated and therefore less calories are consumed from unhealthy foods . It improves our memory and concentration–people who eat a healthy breakfast concentrate better, are more efficient, and have improved mood, in comparison to those who skip breakfast. Weight maintenance–those who eat breakfast are more likely to maintain a healthy weight. 

So with that out of the way, let’s look at some ideas for breakfast you can try this week…

 Visit the next page to view ALL 25 easy breakfast ideas…Are you ready? 
 
 Pages: 1 2 
 
After reading this, smart people like you read...

 Low Carb Breakfast Ideas 8 Swift and Healthy Breakfast Ideas Breakfast Ideas for When You’ve Got No Time 
 
Keep on track. Health tutorials to your inbox!
Join 14,500 others who get free updates...
 
 
 
 &quot;Great motivational material to absorb!! Thanks!&quot; — Cindy Etier 
 
 About the Author: Melanie is a Registered Dietitian who started Dietriffic in March 2007. Her aim is to make good health attainable and sustainable, without guilt and torture (no wonder people love her). Have you got your copy of her free book yet?
 
 { 102 comments…read them below or add one } 
 1 Tom 
I’m definitely guilty of skipping breakfast. I like the idea of a fruit smoothie though. Fruit is the only thing that I have ever really eaten for breakfast during the week. I definitely need to increase my fruit and vegetable intake, so I think I’ll give the smoothie a try. Thanks for the ideas

 Reply 
 2 Alex 
Oh, nice. Really I can’t eat morning“like a king”my stomach isn’t ready for it. But I like your #3 and #6 breakfast ideas, I’d like to mix them 

 Reply 
 3 Melanie 
Hi Tom,

Yes a smoothie is a great option if you don’t like to eat too much, and it’s a good way of getting in a couple of fruit servings.

Hi Alex,

I used to feel like that in the morning too, now I’ve gotten used to eating at a similar time each day, and I couldn’t go without eating.

 Reply 
 4 Christine 
I am definitely guilty of skipping breakfast. Basically I live on coffee until lunch (not good!). Glad I stumbled upon you, I just got all the ingredients for a healthy fruit smoothie. I just have to get up earlier to make it!

 Reply 
 5 Elaine 
Great post. Tasty, fast and easy breakfast ideas plus you’ve presented 5 compelling reasons to not forgo this important meal. Recently at a dietitians’conference I attended the keynote speaker (himself not a dietitian) stated one of his secrets to losing weight was to add breakfast to his daily routine. The other was to increase his activity by walking more. Just these two practices made a big difference.

I hope you don’t mind if I link back to your blog and this post in particular as part of my Nutrition Month features.

Cheers.
Elaine

 Reply 
 6 ruth 
i LOVE breakfast, so it great to have some different ideas.

 Reply 
 7 Melanie 
Hi Christine,

Thanks for visiting! Do you find you simply can’t face eating in the morning? A smoothie would be a good option if you’re not used to eating first thing.

Hi Elaine,

It’s great to hear about this gentleman’s success. This is what I always say, small changes, big results!

Of course I don’t mind, thank you very much!!

Hi Ruth,

I know, I love breakfast too. I do tend to stick to the same things though, I’ll have to take some of my own advice! 

 Reply 
 8 Failingmemory 
Most of those are pretty high carb. People who are diabetic or insulin resistant could not eat most of those listed. 6, 7, 8, 9, 12, 18, 23, 24 (and number 7 is my favorite breakfast.) Those who are diabetic or insulin resistant *DO* need protein in the morning. ALl the rest are much better choices than sugary cereal and such. The whole wheat bagel I doubt since most often what’s labeled as whole wheat is just white with molasses added to darken it. Opt for whole grain instead. Tastes better anyway.

Like the site so far. Still poking around.

 Reply 
 9 Melanie 
Hi Failing Memory,

They are intended to be suggestions only, it’s not possible to suit everyone’s individual health requirements.

It’s absolutely find for diabetics to have carbs foods, just as long as they moderate their portion size, and choose a high fibre version where possible.

You are right about the whole wheat though, whole grain is a much better choice.

 Reply 
 10 diabetesman 
i know this is very important, thank you for remmaind me

 diabetesman’s last blog post.. Gestational Diabetes–Symptoms And Treatment 

 Reply 
 11 Frankie 
Hey-
My mom is on WeightWatchers. We thought smoothies would be a healthy breakfast. So I started makign smoothies made of milk, frozen berries, a banana, lowfat plain yogurt, and orange juice. We had those for a week and my mom gained like 5 pounds! We found out that smoothies AREN’T as healthy as we thought. She doesn’t have smoothies anymore. I don’t know if it was the way we were making them or if it was my mom. So, I am just saying that smoothies aren’t always healthy so be careful!!

 Reply 
 12 Melanie 
Hey Frankie,
That’s right. As with all foods you need to exercise moderation, obviously all foods have calories, which can lead to weight gain if the portion is too large, or it’s eaten too frequently.

 Reply 
 13 may 
hi~
nice meet you
i’m south korean, call me may(it is my english name)
I chanced upon your blog , search for‘breakfast idea’
i want to tell you about korean breakfast style
many of koreans think that breakfast is very important too as of you
but changed of life style, people used to eat a toast or just cup of coffee.
and many old people eat still‘hanjeongsik / Korean Table d’hote’

i prefer hanjeongsik also, but morning is so busy to eat that.

anyway i’m happy to wrote your bolog.^^

bye

 Reply 
 14 Melanie 
Hi May,
I’m interested in finding out about“hanjeongsik”–what is that?? 

 Reply 
 15 may 
hello ^^
Do you know“South korea”?
“hanjeongsik” is traditional menu in korea.
It’s consist of rice and soup,add to averagely five side dishs.
“hanjeongsik” is balanced diet in short.

 Reply 
 16 Melanie 
Hi May,
Sounds wonderful and very healthy! 

 Reply 
 17 Vanessa 
#22 is perfect! I’ve been looking everywher for a nice breakfast recipe for vegans, and I can’t wait to try this! 

 Reply 
 18 Melanie 
Hey Vanessa,
Hope you enjoy!!

 Reply 
 19 Gail 
stoneage diet- bacon and eggs for breakfast.

 Reply 
 20 Melanie 
Gail,
Do you mean that’s the breakfast you enjoy?

 Reply 
 21 Gail 
Hi Melanie,
Thanks for reply
This is a diet to help CFS.
Dr Sarah Myhill’s website will give you the info.

 Reply 
 22 Zdrowie i uroda 
I have to change my habit and start eating breakfast

 Reply 
 23 Melanie 
Do it…eating breakfast is a great habit to have!! 

 Reply 
 24 alli 
very good ideas!! I was looking at all of the English muffin ideas so I toasted a English Muffin,1 slice of cheese, a a scrambeled egg w/ a glass of milk, very good!!!!! thank you for all the ideas.

 Reply 
 25 Melanie 
That sounds great!!

 Reply 
 26 jemaya 
i feel much better after ur terrific suggestions for breakfast. this had made my life easier other than coffee (my best friend)

 Reply 
 27 justin 
all of these suggestions sounds great and im not a big breakfast person by the way and im pretty active on a daily basis and i was just curious how filling are these meals cause im a large guy 6 6 and 250 alotta of these kinda sound like snacks

 Reply 
 28 melissa 
not that i do not want to eat breakfast, but i do not eat breakfast because i am bored with the usual food choices. thanks to this article, i would like to try these new variety for a change.

 Reply 
 29 Melanie 
I hope these suggestions help, Melissa.

 Reply 
 30 Amy 
I’ve developed two food sensitivities in the last 5 years (gluten–which makes me break out in hives, and lactose–which causes severe gastrointestinal distress if it stays down) and none of these breakfast would do anything short of ruin my day. Guess I’ll stick with coffee and a spoonful of peanut butter.

 Reply 
 31 Melanie 
Hi Amy,
Have you tried something like millet for breakfast? That’s a good alternative to the traditional options.

 Reply 
 32 Ashraf 
Hi Milanie,

Thank you very much for the tips you give for a healthy life…

I would like to know more about how i can sustain a healthy and timely eating and the food i can try daily…

Thanks

 Reply 
 33 Melanie 
Keep reading Dietriffic, Ashraf. I am always updating the site with healthy eating and lifestyle advice!!

 Reply 
 34 Michelle 
I love your healthy breakfast ideas, but for someone with blood sugar issues a little more protein at breakfast is better. I know I am better off all day with protein in the morning. My kids love whole grain mix for porridge in the morning. Rolled oats, spelt and triticale flakes cooked up with a little vanilla tastes great and has more protein in it. The other thing we do is protein shakes. A good quality plant protein shake with a little fruit or banana and almond butter in it is awesome. One brand of shakes we have been using for 4 years now is the AwarenessLife Pure Trim Shakes. They are plant protein, low carb and sugar and have some beneficial herbs in them and tastes great! Smooth and creamy even just with water and ice blended with them.

 Reply 
 35 Melanie 
Hi Michelle,
Thanks for sharing your higher protein breakfast ideas, that’s really helpful 

 Reply 
 36 Tiffany 
Start your day off right with http://www.clearyourcells.com . A natural tea high in antioxidants. Better than Green tea. Try it today you’ll love it!!!

 Reply 
 37 Alex@buffet in kl (40%) 
Your guidelines on healthy breakfast is simply superb! Interesting information on healthy breakfast ideas. Thanks for sharing&amp;do keep posting such wonderful articles. I do agree that taking healthy breakfast helps in maintaining a healthy weight. I have personally experienced it.

 Reply 
 38 carl swank 
I enjoy eating pancakes,both buttermilk and buckwheat. I am considerable good health. I am a 67 male 5’6″. I also eat oatmeal and have a banana,along with orange juice. Sometimes I have 2 eggs. Is this an acceptable breakfast?

I enjoy eating pancakes for breakfast,

‘

 Reply 
 39 Melanie 
Hi Carl,
I occasionally have pancakes for breakfast, too. I think this is fine as long as it’s not too often. Remember, it’s what you do consistently that matters. 

Mixing protein with carbs and a little fat is important for satiety at mealtimes. So just keep that in mind. For example, oatmeal with a little fruit and some crushed nuts and even a dollop of yoghurt would be a good option for breakfast.

 Reply 
 40 Alex@florist kl 
Simply great tips! Thanks for sharing it all. I would like to add that I love taking natural yoghurt mixed with a chopped peach, a handful of berries, and whole grain cereal, served with fresh pineapple juice.
It is really healthy and tasty too!

 Reply 
 41 Melanie 
Hi Alex,
Thanks for sharing your idea, a little handful of nuts or seeds would go great with that too, no?

 Reply 
 42 Melanie 
Hi Alex,
Thanks for sharing your idea, a little handful of nuts or seeds would go great with that too, no?

 Reply 
 43 Albert@@spa in kl 
To make my kids eat healthy breakfast is really very difficult since they always insist on burger and pizzas. I think your idea of eating whole wheat english muffin topped with melted reduced fat cheese, a sliced tomato, and a sliced hard-boiled egg simply sounds great. My kids will surely loved it.

 Reply 
 44 Melanie 
I hope so 

 Reply 
 45 Thor 
Hi, Melanie. I was just wondering if you could give me a good idea on a breakfast that does not exceed 500 calories and gives me all food groups. Thanks 

 Reply 
 46 Albert Lim@car hire kuala lumpur 
Having a healthy breakfast is really essential. It should consist of protein, healthy unrefined carbs and plenty of nutrients. And those who want to get rid of their excess weight will be happy to hear that protein will really help with weight loss. Keep up the good work!

 Reply 
 47 misozi 
Hi Mel
I would like your advise on how i can loose the weight that i gained after giving birth. i must confess i do eat a little bit more because of breast feeding.Please advise on a more nutrition but less calorie diet

 Reply 
 48 Melanie 
Hi Misozi,
I written about a healthy diet for breastfeeding before, which you can find here . I hope it is going well with you, and your baby is healthy and happy.

 Reply 
 49 hannah 
I have to go to school at 6:30 every morning so this cite was a life saver from the all day hunger.

 Reply 
 50 Melanie 
Wow…that is early, Hannah. I’m glad you found this article.

 Reply 
 51 Phillip Schlueter 
Melanie, when will you nutrition experts stop recommending consuming“Soy”? It is poison!! and should not be in our bodies in any but ferminted form! There are plenty of studies to prove this but soy is consistanly being promoted a good and it isn’t!!

Also, calories that you drink should be at a minimum and anything out of a can is suspect for the dreaded BPA’s which are killing us one sip at a time from drinking out of plastic containers and eating foods out of cans lined with plastic (which most are–at least in the U.S.).

 Reply 
 52 Melanie 
Hi Philip,
I appreciate your concern. But, saying it is a poison seems at bit out there, no? I wouldn’t recommend soy morning, noon and night, but I don’t recommend anything in excess. Do you think all soy is bad? What about edamame, miso, tofu and tempeh?

 Reply 
 53 Abbas 
This is a great post ! I was telling my friends couple of days ago about my problems finding good options for breakfast until I stumbled upon your article here ! This is GREAT…keep it up Melanie…by the way, how about raw meat?

 Reply 
 54 :) 
hey i think u r weird

 Reply 
 55 :) 
im only telling the truth

 Reply 
 56 Aria 
Hi Melanie,
Two weeks ago I’ve changed the way I eat and I started exercising everyday(half hour on the treadmill and a ten-minute dance workout) and eating less. I’ve lost a few pounds the first week and the morning I weighed the second week I lost a few too. But that same night I weighed again and it was more. Did I make a mistake about weighing twice for that day or did I not lose any weight in the first place? Please help, some advice would be very well appreciated 

 Reply 
 57 Melanie 
Hi Aria,
I don’t recommend that you weigh more than once per week. Otherwise you will be getting inaccurate readings due to water loss/retention. Try making your measurements on the same day each week, first thing in the morning only, and that will give you a truer picture of how you are doing. I also recommend that you make measurements of your waist using a tape measure once each week too, because these tend to give a good idea of how your body composition is changing overall, which sometimes isn’t reflected using weighing scales.

 Reply 
 58 Devi 
Wow! Your advice is slamming! I didn’t know that these simple and easy to make foods were so easy and delicious! Thanks again….YOU ARE THE BEST BLOGGER EVER!!

 Reply 
 59 Melanie 
lol Devi…I wish!! But thank you.

 Reply 
 60 Kelsey 
Melanie,
I’m trying to lose a few pounds. Before, I would eat 2 or 3 of those microwave pancakes, or a pack of Poptarts. Lately, I’ve been eating things like bananas, yogurts, and whole–wheat toast, but it doesn’t fill me up, and I’m not a big fan of eggs or omelets. Any suggestions?

 Reply 
 61 Melanie 
Hi Kelsey,
Have you tried adding a little natural peanut butter to your toast? You could sprinkle some nuts or seeds on top of your yogurt and fruit. An apple eaten with peanut butter is also good. The idea is to increase the protein content of your breakfast, so that you are feeling fuller without taking in too many calories.

 Reply 
 62 Joe 
Hi Melanie, I’ve been having a helathy hi fibre cereal(Always different mixes) breakfast 7 days a week wih at least 2 cups of water. Even if Im late I just try and push in at least a glass nesquik but i cannot function properly without it. I got into the groove six years ago when i started weight training. I do some variety sometimes with eggs and toasted sandwiches. Ive also used my Meal Replacements shakes for breakfast once in a blue moon but i dont like to to put something so unnatural into my system 1st thing in the morning, it just dont feel right. Great blog sorry if i said too much but too many people out there underestimate the value of this meal.

 Reply 
 63 Elizabeth 
Hey! I just wanted to say I really like your breakfast ideas–they’re quick, easy, and, best of all, healthy! When it comes to breakfast, I’m not like most people. I just CAN’T skip it, and I often find myself guilty of over-eating (sometimes I even have three or four bowls of cereal!). I know this is a habit I need to break, so tomorrow morning I’m going to try one of your recipes, and also try to work on my portions. My biggest problem when it comes to a healthy breakfast is that I hate peanut butter, berries, and any kind of nuts, which is usually what people suggest. Plus, I am in LOVE with CARBS! Anyway, I just wanted to say thanks for the ideas and I’ll be sure to try a couple out–maybe I’ll find one I like even better than cereal! 

 Reply 
 64 Neny Lily 
My way of eating breakfast varies from my daily activities. When I have to stay home, I take light breakfast like toast bread and coffee. but if I have some schedule to attend, I make myself a heavier breakfast like fried rice and egg, and of course with coffee, and make an additional sandwich to carry along. Having read your column, I hope I can get some adjustment to my habit, if there is something that I should add or deduct.Thanks to you, I’ll keep on watch for every issue that you may have.

 Reply 
 65 Melanie 
Thanks for reading and commenting, Neny.

 Reply 
 66 Jae 
Hey um why can’t i find the next page? :s

 Reply 
 67 Melanie 
Hi Jae and Supriya, thanks for pointing that out, the page is sorted now, I’m not sure what happened there.

 Reply 
 68 Supriya 
where is next page

 Reply 
 69 Weird guy 
Cool ideas.

Sometimes I have weetabix and banana

——–
I got twelve inch rims on my chair, that’s how I roll y’all.

 Reply 
 70 Melanie 
lol

 Reply 
 71 Giusi 
whole grain is not a healthy choice

 Reply 
 72 Melanie 
If you are trying to lose weight, yes, but for others, why not?

 Reply 
 73 fiona 
i m a heart patient. what type of breahfast is good. i always drink 1 glass of grapefrit juice is it good.

 Reply 
 74 Melanie 
Hi Fiona,
Most of the breakfast suggestions I’ve made above are a good choice. I would recommend eating 1/2 of a whole grapefruit rather than drinking the juice, however.

 Reply 
 75 Twyla 
I was looking for something different for my kids for breakfast and found your breakfast blobs. I used raisin bran instead of bran flakes because that’s what was in the pantry. I also used my Kitchenaid to mix everything. The cereal was finely crushed and well blended. Using my cookie scoop, the mixture was easily turned into little balls and then refrigerated. Just before serving, I sprinkled with organic cocoa powder. I called them breakfast candy and my kids ate them up! Thanks for a fresh idea for a healthy, EASY breakfast for my kids.

 Reply 
 76 Melanie 
Hi Twyla,
That’s great to hear. I really love your idea of calling it breakfast candy. What a quick and easy breakfast, too Thanks for your comment.

 Reply 
 77 Rixsey 
Hi! I dont have a lot of time in the morning to eat breakfast. I have to eat somthing that will keep me going from 6 AM to 11 AM. I am allergic to bananas and cannot eat mangos,apples,kiwi,peaches,tomatos. I have only 15 minuets to eat. Any sugestions?

 Reply 
 78 Simone 
Hi Melanie,

Your breakfast ideas look great! I was wondering if you have any suggestions on low calorie AND low carb breakfast. The only things I can think of is eggs!? lol

 Reply 
 79 Melanie 
Hi Simone,
Yes, eggs are number one!! Also, what about natural yogurt with crushed nuts and seeds on top? I know you said low calorie, but this is an excellent filling breakfast option, that will keep you going until lunch, and it’s perfect if you’re trying to lose weight.

 Reply 
 80 Deana 
Hey!! Love the ideas!!! My daughter is 12 and insulin resistant. This is difficult for anyone ESP. A child…. Can u come up with some good low carb breakfst ideas and post?? Sometimes she doesn’t eat due to lack of good choice this would be appreciated!! Ty so much…

 Reply 
 81 Melanie 
Hi Deana,
I will try to get that article posted at the beginning of next week. Thanks for asking. I’ll let you know when it’s up.

 Reply 
 82 madiha 
there is no next page:(

 Reply 
 83 madiha 
ups, sorry, i found it

 Reply 
 84 Melanie 
 

 Reply 
 85 Glenn Ryall 
I suffer the same fate when i get up in the morning most of the time, what to eat thanks for making things more clearer.

The reasons of having breakfast were well put up as well loved them as well.

 Reply 
 86 Melanie 
Thanks, Glenn.

 Reply 
 87 Steve 
Hi Melanie,

I try to run in the mornings early, so usually have a green tea and breakfast biscuit, run, then op up on eggs and wholemeal toast before work.

Keeps the hunger pangs away until about 11am, when its banana time. So almost there I’ve tried to get some fruit in at breakfast but I am a bit fan of my protein and stodge 

Steve

 Reply 
 88 Melanie 
Hi Steve, I always find I can go so much longer without needing to eat, when I have eggs for breakfast. Sometimes I have porridge, which is also good, but it doesn’t keep hunger away for as long.

 Reply 
 89 Chino 
Hi Melanie,
I’m a self train chef. Always looking for great info, and yours is an excelent source. I’m working on a new menu for my catering business. Your healthy ideas are great since I caterer to doctors offices and they always asked for healthy choices.
Thanks,
Chino

 Reply 
 90 Melanie 
Hi Chino, Glad you found the info helpful 

 Reply 
 91 Janet 
Hi Melanie I’m always on the go, I have a bussiness me and my husband run were always late so we grab fast food , do you have any articles on healthies fast food ?

 Reply 
 92 Melanie 
Hi Janet, I have this article on making healthier choices at the fast food restaurant. Also, have you tried bringing food with you, so that you don’t need to eat out so much? Is that a possibility? This article on using a snack box may be helpful.

 Reply 
 93 Shammin 
Hi Melanie,

I just stumbled across this website while browsing quick healthy breakfast ideas.
I currently have a messed up sleep schedule (I’m having trouble sleeping at night at the moment), so i end up waking up at midday so i miss breakfast.
My husband finds it difficult to wake up in the morning to go to work, so as a result, he tends to sleep more and miss breakfast (but recently i have made him take breakfast with him).
These breakfast ideas sound really good and quick and i hope to start incorporating breakfast into mine and my husbands diets permanently because i know how important it is.
Thank you for the ideas and hopefully i will gradually make some changes!

 Reply 
 94 Melanie 
Thank you Shammin, I hope these ideas help you both.

 Reply 
 95 Shammin 
Hi Melanie,

I’m happy to say my hubby and I have breakfast every morning now! I started work recently (at a daycare centre) so I wake up early (and as a result I sleep very well because I’m tired from work) and breakfast is a must now! I just need to try to have different things for breakfast! Thank you again for reminding me of the importance of breakfast!

 Reply 
 96 Melanie 
You are welcome, Shammin. I’m glad you found this article.

 Reply 
 97 Elisabeth 
Hi Melanie,

Thanks for these ideas. I’ve been recently diagnosed as reactive hypoglycemic, so I need more protein in my diet than most people, including at breakfast. As much as I like eggs and (Greek) yogurt, it’s nice to have some other options. I can’t wait to try the breakfast blobs! 

 Reply 
 98 Melanie 
I’m so glad this article was useful to you Elisabeth.

 Reply 
 99 fera 
thank you!

 Reply 
 100 Jenna 
These didint help me at all

 Reply 
 101 Melanie 
Any particular reason why?

 Reply 
 102 Emily 
Hi, was just wondering with the fruit smoothie, would 1 banana, 1/3 cup milk and a teaspoon of cinnamon be a healthy breakfast? I used to have them for afternoon tea as a child, so I was wondering if it would be healthy enough for brekky?
Thanks for the ideas!
-Emily

 Reply 
 Cancel reply 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 Please notify me of followup comments via e-mail 

 

 
 
 { 18 trackbacks } 
 
 25 desayunos para empezar bien el día Why Good Lifestyle Choices Can Make You a Fabulous Writer | Nutrition and Dietary Advice Weight Loss for Brides | Nutrition and Dietary Advice easy lunch ideas Exercise on Empty Stomach - Healthy Eating, Diets, and Weight Loss Ideas - Dietriffic.com Weight Loss — Healthy Eating by Dietriffic Food Chemistry FSEM Spring 2010»Breakfast is important Breakfast ideas | ZWear Reasons You&apos;re Fat - Healthy Eating Ideas Cool Resource for Healthful Meal Ideas | My Journey to Lean Foodalicious Friday!«strengthandsweat July, July…Goodbye«strengthandsweat 4 Healthy Breakfast Meal Ideas .:. BlissPlan: Reaching Bliss Through Powerful Information How To Eat A Healthy Breakfast On The Go - Exercise And Depression Help - Exercise And Depression Help, Yes You Can Move On! - Exercise And Depression Help The Juice: Fast and Easy Breakfast Tips from What’s Cooking | Cooking Video Recipes Healthy Eating At Work - Healthy Eating Tips Delicious Healthy Breakfasts for Weight Loss | Weight Loss Critique Meeting 04-19«D3 Highway to Health 
 
Previous post: What Is Coeliac/Celiac Disease? 

Next post: Childhood Obesity: What Can Parents Do? 
 
 
 
 
 Go to the Archives → 

 Join Me: Facebook | Twitter | RSS | Google + LinkedIn | Pinterest 
 
Tutorials
 
 101 Crash Course in Weight Loss 101 Crash Course in Healthy Breakfasts 101 Crash Course in Healthy Snacking 
 
Popular Posts

 Eat More Vegetables: 11 Tips to Help You 30+ Ways to Recession-Proof Your Family Food Budget 25 Low Fat Desserts For Any Occasion How to Easily Double Your Weight Loss How To Become A Runner In Just 10 Weeks 15 Effective Stress Banishing Tips 5 Ingredients or Less: 25 Meals For All Taste Buds 
 Here are just a handful of recommended sites run by some very passionate individuals:
 Faye and Lou · GoodLife Bottles · Diet Blog · Health Castle · Free Fitness Workouts 
 
 
Get Updates (It’s Free)
 
What else is there to say?

Oh yes... if you subscribe for updates today, you&apos;ll also get instant access to my book, &quot;SOAR!&quot; absolutely free!

 In it you&apos;ll discover... 

 The Mental Shift that Changes Goals Into Results How to Banish the Crippling Feeling of Failure Forever The Key to Defeating the Biggest Enemy of Good Health And much, much more! 

Just enter your email below.
Not sure? Read what others are saying .
 
 
 
 
 
Mel’s Mission
 
 She&apos;s been featured in various publications, approached by TV production teams, and in the past 5 years has established herself as one of the foremost dietitians online.

How? Because she&apos;s intensely passionate about educating people on the holistic benefits of good nutrition, as well as exposing diet-related profiteering scams. When it comes to nutrition, this girl means business! 

 Read more about Melanie... 
 
 
Connect with Mel on Facebook , Twitter , Google + , LinkedIn , Pinterest .

Copyright©2007-2012 Dietriffic.com . All rights reserved. Disclaimer . Advertise? 
 Tweet Share 
More in Healthy Eating 
 
 5 Super Ingredients: Are You Missing Out? 

Do you tend to stick with ingredients you know well when cooking? There&apos;s often a...
 Close
	</body>
</document>
