<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008337" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Murray/August-Moon-Chinese-Restaurant_3" time="2012-07-13-01:49" support="5" score="0.031162863879767157" bingtitle="August Moon Chinese Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant Murray, KY" webtitle="August Moon Chinese Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant  Murray, KY">
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>August Moon Chinese Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 506 N 12th St in ... They never have what I order. Takes the wait staff forever just to bring your drinks.</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
August Moon Chinese
Restaurant

 
Average User Rating
 
7
 
Exceptional

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(270) 759-4653

 http://www.augustmoonmurray.com/ 
 KY &gt; Murray &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim August Moon Chinese Restaurant listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by August Moon Chinese Restaurant to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About August Moon Chinese Restaurant
 August Moon Chinese Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 506 N 12th St in Murray, KY . August Moon Chinese Restaurant has been described as an Exceptional Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 7 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American, Chinese Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for August Moon Chinese Restaurant
 
 
 
All Reviews for August Moon Chinese Restaurant

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
7
 
Decor
 
7
 
Service
 
7
 
They never have what I order. Takes the wait staff forever just to bring your drinks. Our waitress was rude and unconcerned with the fact that we were not happy with the food or service. They could not find a manager. Will not ever go back to the Bowie store.
 
Overall Rating
 
7
 
&quot;Exceptional&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about August Moon Chinese Restaurant:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
August Moon Chinese Restaurant News
 Houston, we have marriage problems: Moon Unit Zappa files for divorce from Paul Doucette In August 1836, two real estate entrepreneurs—Augustus Chapman Allen and John Kirby Allen—from New York, purchased of land along ... link downtown buildings containing shops and restaurants, enabling pedestrians to avoid summer heat and ... Top Budget Travel Destinations for 2012 A recent search turned up one-stop flights from New York for $756 (Continental) and from Chicago for $528 (LOT Air), or for $1,010 from Los Angeles (Air New Zealand).   Why in 2012: The arrival in Taiwan of the first mainland Chinese tourists last June ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing New York Restaurants and Dining Guide | NYC.com - Official Site ... New York Restaurant and Dining Guide. NYC.com features detailed reviews of hundreds of top New York restaurants written by our editors and visitors, as well as ... Best Deals and Discounts on the Best Local Restaurants – Save ... Saving money on dining out is easy with Restaurant.com gift certificates. Find restaurants in your area and get $25 restaurant gift certificates for only $10! Start ... New York City Restaurants, New York City Menus, Ratings, Reviews ... What&apos;s a hot menu?Every night we calculate the most-clicked restaurants of the preceding 24 hours and display them here. If a restaurant makes the Hot Menus list for ... Restaurant Ratings | Restaurant Reviews | Zagat Restaurant Guide with Reviews and Ratings for New York, Los Angeles, San Francisco, Philadelphia, Chicago, Boston and Restaurants Everywhere. NYC Restaurants - Ratings and Reviews of NY&apos;s Best Restaurants | Zagat New York Restaurant reviews - Zagat. Trusted reviews of NYC&apos;s top restaurants. Dining guide to help you find the best restaurant for any dining experience. 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 100° 
Fri
 
 68° - 93° 
Sat
 
 66° - 86° 
Sun
 
 66° - 86° 
 
Address
 
August Moon Chinese Restaurant

506 N 12th St

Murray, KY 
 

 
Telephone
 (270) 759-4653 
August Moon Chinese Restaurant
 
 Rating :  7 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
August Moon Chinese Restaurant Photos
 
 Fast Food American Chinese 
 
 Local Places
 
 Huddle House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hong Kong Restaurant Open 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardees 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Johns 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Back Yard Burgers 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Desert Star Banquet Center 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food August Moon Chinese Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Time 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Murray Art Guild 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Area Bank ATM 
Cuisine: ATMs Branch Banking and Trust Company North Carolina 
Cuisine: ATMs Branch Banking and Trust Company North Carolina 
Cuisine: ATMs Branch Banking and Trust Company North Carolina 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Murray Art Museums Galleries 
See all Murray ATMs 
See all Murray Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 August Moon Chinese Restaurant Coupons 

 August Moon Chinese Restaurant Murray 

 August Moon Chinese Restaurant Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Murray Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H J | K | L | M | N | P | Q | R S | T | V | W 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
