<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008195" url="http://www.flickr.com/groups/fast_food_outlets/" time="2012-07-13-01:41" support="1" score="0.0014681431012559928" bingtitle="Flickr: Fast Foods. - Welcome to Flickr - Photo Sharing" webtitle="Flickr:  Fast Foods.">
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>The modern history of fast-food in the United States of America began on 7 July 1912 with the opening of a fast food restaurant called the Automat, a cafeteria with its ...</description>
	<body>
		You aren&apos;t signed in    Sign In    Help 
 Home The Tour Sign Up Explore 
 Explore Home Last 7 Days Interesting Popular Tags Calendar Most Recent Uploads Video on Flickr Galleries Getty Images World Map Places The Commons Creative Commons FlickrBlog code.flickr The App Garden Camera Finder Flickr for mobile 
 Upload 
 
 
Fast Foods.

 Group Pool Discussion 354 Members Map Join This Group 
 
 Share via email Share on Facebook Share on Twitter   Share ▾ 
 

Group Pool 2,705 items  |  Only members can add to the pool. Join? 
 by Patricksm... by Paxton... by Meteorry by Patricksm... by Patricksm... by carl caesar by Meteorry by bruceywan by Patricksm... by Patricksm... by rob_rob2001 by rob_rob2001 
 » More photos 
 Steve-kun (a group admin) says: 
 29 Aug 07 - We are getting some great Photo&apos;s of fast food outlets from around the world. 
 
Discussion 11 posts  | Only members can post. Join? 
 
 Title Author Replies Latest Post Vote, what is the best fast food? Steve-kun 5 33 months ago KFC Steve-kun 1 38 months ago fast food uniforms Steve-kun 1 38 months ago Price of a Pizza Hut Pizza Steve-kun 3 38 months ago Price of a can of Coke in your country? Steve-kun 6 47 months ago Fast food outlets Steve-kun 0 50 months ago 
 
 » More discussions 
 
 
About Fast Foods.

 
 
 
 Create your own visitor map! 
Fast Food outlets ; pictures of what you consider to be fast Food, Corners, Come add your favorite pictures to our group we would love to see them.
Fast food is food that can be prepared and served very quickly. While any meal with low preparation time can be considered to be fast food, such as TV dinners, typically the term refers to food which is cooked in bulk in advance, kept warm or reheated to order, and sold ready-to-eat from an outlet.

Outlets may be stands or kiosks, which may provide no shelter or seating,[1] or fast food restaurants (also known as quick service restaurants). Franchise operations which are part of restaurant chains have standardized foodstuffs shipped to each restaurant from central locations.[2]

The capital requirements to start a fast-food restaurant are relatively small, particularly in areas with non-existent or poorly enforced health codes. Small, individually-owned fast-food restaurants have become common throughout the world. Fast food restaurants with higher sit-in ratios, where customers can sit and have their orders brought to them, are known as fast casual restaurants.
Although fast-food restaurants are often viewed as a representation of modern technology, the concept of&quot;ready-cooked food to go&quot;is as old as cities themselves; unique variations are historical in various cultures. Ancient Roman cities had bread-and-olive stands, East Asian cultures feature noodle shops. Flat bread and falafel are ubiquitous in the Middle East. Popular Indian&quot;fast&quot;food delicacies include Vada pav, Papri Chaat, Bhelpuri, Panipuri and Dahi Vada. In the French-speaking nations of West Africa, meanwhile, roadside stands in and around the larger cities continue to sell- as they have done for generations- a range of ready-to-eat, chargrilled meat sticks known locally as&quot;brochettes&quot;(not to be confused with the bread snack of the same name found in Europe).

The modern history of fast-food in the United States of America began on 7 July 1912 with the opening of a fast food restaurant called the Automat, a cafeteria with its prepared foods behind small glass windows and coin-operated slots, in New York City, created a sensation. Numerous Automat restaurants were quickly built around the country to deal with the demand. Automats remained extremely popular throughout the 1920s and 1930s. The company also popularized the notion of “take-out” food, with their slogan “Less work for Mother”. The American company White Castle is generally credited with opening the second fast-food outlet in Wichita, Kansas in 1921, selling hamburgers for five cents apiece.[3] Among its innovations, the company allowed customers to see the food being prepared. White Castle later added five holes to each beef patty to increase its surface area and speed cooking times. White Castle was successful from its inception and spawned numerous competitors.
 
 
Additional Information

 This is a public group.

 Accepted media types:
 Photos Video 
 Accepted content types:
 Photos / Videos Screenshots / Screencasts Illustration/Art / Animation/CGI 
 Accepted safety levels:
 Safe 
 
 
 Feed –Subscribe to Fast Foods. discussion threads 
 Grab the link 
Here&apos;s a link to this group. Just copy and paste!

 

  show short URL 
 
 About Flickr Who we are Take the tour Flickr blog Jobs Community Community Guidelines Report abuse Help Need help? Start here! Help forum FAQs About Our Ads Apps and the API Flickr for mobile App Garden API documentation Developer blog Developer Guide Follow us Like us 
 Deutsch English Español Français Italiano Português Tiếng Việt Bahasa Indonesia 
 Terms of Use | Your privacy | Yahoo! Safely | Copyright/IP Policy Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
