<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008715" url="http://www.cnineo.com/kitchen-equipment/page_4.html" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="1" score="0.0018079760200181696" bingtitle="Kitchen Equipment,Dish Washing Machine,Counter Top Electric Fryer ..." webtitle="Kitchen Equipment,Dish Washing Machine,Counter Top Electric Fryer Factory,Manufacturer - Guangzhou  INEO Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd.">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>kitchen equipment, dish washing machine, counter top ... Fast Food Restaurant Equipment; Hotel Restaurant Equipment ... Click here to enter your email message</description>
	<body>
		kitchen equipment, dish washing machine, counter top electric fryer, china kitchen equipment,dish washing machine manufacturer, kitchen equipment supplier Guangzhou INEO Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd. 
 
Home
 
About Us
 
Products
 
News
 
Online Order
 
Blog
 
Download
 
Contact Us
 
 All Categories Kitchen Project Kitchen Equipment Kitchen Cooking Equipment Commercial Refrigerator Kitchen Fryer Restaurant Equipment Kitchen Work Table Kitchen Storage Equipment Kitchen Range Hood Bain Marie Food Warmer Dish Washing Equipment Combi Oven Snack Food Equipment Fast Food Restaurant Equipment Hotel Restaurant Equipment Pizza Restaurant Equipment Buffet Restaurant Equipment Hospital Restaurant Equipment School Restaurant Equipment Industrial Restaurant Equipment Others Cake Showcase Ice Cream Showcase Pizza Table Salad Table Vertical Stainless Steel Freezer Cold Room Blast Freezer Wine Refrigerator Mini Refrigerator Food Processing Equipment Meat Slicer Meat Mincer Bone Saws Sausage Filler Filling Mixer Vegetable Cutter Food Cut Up Machines Baking Equipment Bakery Oven Dough Processor Bread Slicer Baking Prover Baking Trolley Home » Products » Kitchen Equipment » Product List 
Kitchen Equipment
 
 
Kitchen Cooking Equipment
 
Kitchen Fryer
 
Kitchen Work Table
 
Kitchen Storage Equipment
 
Kitchen Range Hood
 
Bain Marie
 
Food Warmer
 
Dish Washing Equipment
 
Combi Oven
 
 
Commercial Refrigerator
 
 
Cake Showcase
 
Ice Cream Showcase
 
Pizza Table
 
Salad Table
 
Vertical Stainless Steel Freezer
 
Cold Room
 
Blast Freezer
 
Wine Refrigerator
 
Mini Refrigerator
 
 
Restaurant Equipment
 
 
Fast Food Restaurant Equipment
 
Hotel Restaurant Equipment
 
Pizza Restaurant Equipment
 
Buffet Restaurant Equipment
 
Hospital Restaurant Equipment
 
School Restaurant Equipment
 
Industrial Restaurant Equipment
 
Others
 
 
Snack Food Equipment
 

 
Food Processing Equipment
 
 
Meat Slicer
 
Meat Mincer
 
Bone Saws
 
Sausage Filler
 
Filling Mixer
 
Vegetable Cutter
 
Food Cut Up Machines
 
 
Baking Equipment
 
 
Bakery Oven
 
Dough Processor
 
Bread Slicer
 
Baking Prover
 
Baking Trolley
 
 Guangzhou INEO Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd. 

 B316, Bldg No.1,No.329Yushan W.road,MOCA Creative Industry Park, Panyu Guangzhou,China 511400 86-15018748580 86-20-39292071 86-20-39292498 admin@cnineo.com http://www.cnineo.com 
 
This supplier has been
audited by the b2b tradett.com
 &gt;Add to Company Favorites Products 
Kitchen Equipment
 Total 80 Product(s) We are professional kitchen equipment factory and supplier in China.We can produce kitchen equipment 
 according to your requirements.More types of kitchen equipment wanted,please contact us right now! View: 
 
 
Auto-lift Electric Fryer
 EF-6S . EF-8S Auto-lift Electric Fryer with time setting design for lifting so it no need caretaker,auto control of oil temperature to make sure the food can be cooked evenly. As a commercial kitchen equipment,it enjoy lots of appreciation worldwide. 
 
 
Electric 1 Tank 1 Basket Fryer
 EF-81 As a commercial kitchen, Electric Fryer is widely used in Fast Food Restaurant and other kinds of commercial hotel. Basically, it is using for making delicious fast food such as French Fries , Chicken Wings,Chicken Nuggets etc. Meeting internation hygiene and safety standard so it received CE certificate. 
 
 
Fast Food Electric Fryer
 EF-4L,EF-6L,EF-8L,EF Electric Fryer is general using on Fast Food Restaurant it is very easy to control. It has received CE Approval and multiple capacity eletric fryer for you to choose. 
 
 
Electric 2 Tanks 2 Baskets Fryer
 EF-4L-2,EF-6L-2,EF-8 Electric Fryer is general using on Fast Food Restaurant and it is very easy to control. There are 4 sizes for you to choose and it must be easy fyou to the suitable kitchen equipment among these multiple capacity styles. 
 
 
Freestanding Electric 2 Tanks 2 Baskets Fryer
 EF-85 Freestanding Electric Fryer is made of 304 stainless steel and it is equipped with degreases devices. It is widely used in Fast food restaurant and snack kitchen. 
 
 
Electric Donut Fryer
 EF-T Electric Donut Fryer is made of 304 stainless steel with CE approval. It is widely used on fast food restaurant and snack kitchen. 
 
 
Oil Filter Cart
 LG-20 Oil Filter Cart is using widely on Commerical Kitchen for oil filtering to ensure the cooking oil is healthy and clean.It is equipped with switch protection cover for your security. Wheel device is more convenient for you to move . 
 
 
Knee Operated Hand Washing Sink
 INS-01 The body of this washing sink is 201 stainless steel and the bowl is made of 304 stainless steel. And this washing sink has knee operated design so it will be more convenient to control. 
 
 
Kitchen Worktable
 IN-11 Work Bench With Splashback is made of high quality stainless steel which is very endurable.Quite suitable for using in kitchen preparation area. 
 
 
Mobile Work Bench With 2 Under Shelves
 IN-14 Our clients can avail from us an exquisite range of Mobile Work Bench With 2 Under Shelves overhead Shelves at highly competitive prices. We make sure to check our products, to ensure the delivery of quality assured range of products to our customers. 
 
 
Mobile Work Bench With Under Shelf
 IN-15 We are offering best available quality of Mobile Work Bench With Under Shelfs. These products are developed from effective technology and the top is constructed out of heavy gauge stainless steel with optional splash guard with or without under shelves and optional drawers. 
 
 
Work Bench Under Shelf
 IN-17 Work Bench With Under Shelf is made of high quality stainless steel and it is very endurable and very easy to clean. Quite suitable for commercial kitchen use. 
 
 
Griddle With Cabinet
 ZH-RG,ZH-TG,JZH-RG The upper cooking surface of Griddle With Cabinet is equipped with chromium coating to prevent food getting scorched and the thickness of the stainless steel panel is 20mm . The cabinet below the griddle allow you to have storage. 
 
 
Single Sink Bench
 IN32 We offer Single Sink Bench that are an essential part of every modern and commercial kitchen. It has a stainless steel construction, which ensures its durability and corrosion resistance. The commercial kitchen sink has a chair-type design, which means that users can easily wash various kitchen utensils while standing. 
 
 
Tiple Sink Bench
 IN34 These Tiple Sink Bench are manufactured using high class stainless steel to make sure long life operations and flawless performance. Our products are highly appreciated for its design, which provide versatile applications and take less space. 
 
 
Sliding Doors Bench Cabinet
 DM73 Ineo Kitchen Equipment company can provide you with many kind of kitchen storage equipment. This bench cabinet is made of 304 # stainless steel which is very durable and easy to clean. To supply a better placement for the dish,plate and other kitchenware. so storage cabinet is quite necessary for the commercial kitchen. 
 
 
Kitchen Storage Cabinet
 DM76 Ineo Kitchen Equipment company is the professional supplier who can provide you with high quality kitchen storage equipment. This model is equipped with 3 drawers which allow you to put the different kitchenware inside.Cabinet with sliding door design is very convenient to use.Top area can be used as worktable. 
 
 
Splash Back Worktable Cabinet
 DM97 All the kitchen storage equipment from Ineo Kitchen Equipment company are made of 304# stainless steel which is very endurable and easy to clean. This model is equipped with sliding door for the big cabinet and 4 drawers in side. It is widely used in commercial restaurnt kitchen. 
 
 
Commercial Kitchen Storage Cabinet
 DM77 Ineo Kitchen Equipment company aims to supply the functional and endurable kitchen storage equipment to all the customers. This model is equipped with 3 upper shelves which enlarge the using space to satisfy different client&apos;s requirement.And the top area of the drawers can be used as worktable. 
 
 
Compartment Plastic Rack
 JW-1 INEO Kitchen Equipment company can provide you with many kind of taps for kitchen sinks. A variety of design and construction can satisfy your different requirement. Page 4 of 4 &lt;&lt;Previous 1 2 3 4 Next&gt;&gt; If you didn&apos;t find the product information you want above, you can search more Kitchen Equipment information through here. We are dedicated to provide you more Kitchen Equipment Manufacturer . Anyway, thanks again for your kind patronage! 

 Home | About Us | Products | News | Online Order | Blog | Download | Contact us | Index English German Spanish French Italian Portuguese Japanese Korean Arabic Russian Chinese Copyright©Guangzhou INEO Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd..2011 Links | Site Map | Support By Tradett.com 
 
 America Zone ( North&amp;South America) Ms. Daisy Africa&amp;Mid-East Zone Ms. Sara Asia (exclusive Mid-East)&amp;Pacific Zone Ms. Michelle Australia&amp;New Zealand Zone Mr. David Europe&amp;Russia Zone Andy Juanita 
 
 
 Contact us 
 Click here to enter your email message
	</body>
</document>
