<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008538" url="http://www.pantagraph.com/news/daily-digest/article_1747841b-0e10-5d89-b6f0-6ec370c8a9c9.html" time="2012-07-13-02:00" support="1" score="0.0007656628036130666" bingtitle="Daily Digest - Pantagraph.com | Central Illinois" webtitle="Daily Digest">
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="146"/>
	<description>Supplies, including disposable gloves and trash ... man in the mouth and pushing a woman at a fast food restaurant ... At Heller Ford we offer a complete selection of new ...</description>
	<body>
		Mobile Customer Service ePantagraph Advertise 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 Contribute 
 Article Event Photo Video 
 My Account 
 Edit Profile Logout 
 
 91° Clear 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 92° 68° Saturday 98° 71° Sunday 89° 72° Monday 95° 73° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 All News Local Money Crime &amp; Courts Strange News Illinois National World Weather Archives 
 
The Latest
 
 Documents conflict on when Romney left Bain 

WASHINGTON D.C. — Federal documents filed by Mitt Romney’s former company appear to conflict with the Republican presidential candidate’s stat…
 
 Lawmakers furious over China-made Olympic uniform 

WASHINGTON D.C. — Uniforms for U.S. Olympic athletes are American red, white and blue — but made in China. That has members of Congress fuming.
 
Recent

 Roanoke budget leaves town with $52,000 shortfall Public safety New recordings show Zimmerman’s many police calls Biden paints ominous picture of Romney presidency Fairbury market holds two-week food drive Chicago terror suspect agrees to plead guilty 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 All Sports High School College Professional Recreation Columns Local Scoreboard UPickEm 
 
The Latest
 
 Belters deal another All-Star, set for new look 

NORMAL — Saddled with the Frontier League’s worst record, Normal manager Chad Parker expects to open the second half Friday at Schaumburg with…
 
 Sheppard battling Feger for 3rd-place finish 

In fishing for victories on this year’s grueling 28-race UMP Summer Nationals tour, Central Illinois driver Brandon Sheppard can’t help but th…
 
Recent

 Clinic, parade to precede Shrine game Joe Knows - Thursday 07/12/12 Former Bears&apos; DB Shaun Gayle latest player to sue NFL College sports report 07/11/12 Summer sports report 07/11/12 East tops West in Frontier League All-Star game at the Corn Crib 
 
 Opinion 
 Letters to the Editor Editorials Election Letters Write a Letter Viewpoint Bill Flick Susan Hazlett Blogs &amp; Columns 
 Obituaries Photo Galleries Entertainment 
 Go! Movies Movie Listings Music TV TV Listings Arts Etc. Games Comics Lottery Horoscope Calendar 
 Life 
 Milestones Community Calendar Flying Horse Health Travel Home and Garden Food NIE 
 Get It! 
 Today&apos;s Deal Business Directory Classifieds Coupons Newspaper Ads Contests 
 Classifieds 
 Search All Classifieds Place an ad Services Merchandise Pets Garage Sales Garage Sales Map Legal Notices 
 Homes 
 Homes for Sale Rentals Open Houses Home Market Home Finder 
 Cars 
 Find a vehicle Sell your vehicle Vehicle research Featured Dealers Outdoor Motors 
 Jobs 
 Search for Local Jobs Work for Us Post your Resume For Employers 
 
 
 Hot Topics Unit 5 enrollment Quick contest: Free umbrellas! Inmates on unemployment Video Gambling Uptown Station special section BPD Blotter &apos;Like Us!&apos; for your chance to win $100! Sugar Creek Fest Steve Vogel&apos;s column 
 
 Home / News 
 
Daily Digest
 Print Email 2006-03-23T00:00:00Z Daily Digest pantagraph.com March 23, 2006 12:00 am (0) Comments 
New grade schools superintendent picked

STREATOR - The Ottawa grade school superintendent was picked
Tuesday night as the new superintendent for Streator grade
schools.

Christine Benson replaces Ed Allen, who is retiring at the end
of the school year.

Benson&apos;s resignation from the Ottawa district will be effective
June 30, just before she begins work in Streator. She will be paid
$134,000 a year, including benefits, for the three-year Streator
contract.

Benson&apos;s experience in district finances and her strong
personality were keys in making the decision to hire her, said
Streator grade school board President Dave Conner.

B-N form team for joint cleanup

BLOOMINGTON - Bloomington and Normal will co-sponsor the first
community cleanup week from April 22 to 28. The weeklong event
replaces similar, individual efforts held in both towns.

Residents or groups are encouraged to volunteer throughout the
week to help remove trash and debris from parks, roads and along
Constitution Trail.

Volunteers may request a specific area. If no preference is
given, a location will be assigned. Supplies, including disposable
gloves and trash bags, will be available upon request.

To register, visit www.normal.org or www.cityblm.org or call
(309) 454-9504.

Prairie Air Show unveils &apos;06 dates

PEORIA - Prairie Air Show organizers announced Monday they hope
to raise $250,000 from this summer&apos;s show, WEEK-TV reported.

Proceeds from the River City Air Expo and Prairie Air Show will
benefit the Peoria PlayHouse and the Prairie Aviation Museum and
Challenger Learning Center, both in Bloomington, and the Children&apos;s
Hospital of Illinois.

The air show will be July 21-23 at the Greater Peoria Regional
Airport.

Organizers say it&apos;s too early to say which military acts may
perform, but two civilian aerobatics teams - The Lima Lima Flight
Team and The Goodyear Aerostars - will be there.

Tickets will be on sale April 1 at the Prairie Aviation Museum
and the Junior League of Peoria.

Event for parents here for April

NORMAL - Heartland Community College has been chosen as the site
for a statewide conference for parents of students receiving
special education services.

Explore the Possibilities is offered by Family Matters Parent
Training and Information Centers on April 29. Keynote speaker is
Patrick Schwarz, an associate professor of special education at
National-Louis University in Chicago.

Sessions include positive behavior supports in school, a primer
on basic special education rights, Individualized Education Program
meetings and supporting students using the &quot;least dangerous
assumptions.&quot;

The conference is for both parents and professionals. To
register, visit www.fmptic.org or call (866) 436-7842 before April
19.

Drop-off facility changes its hours

BLOOMINGTON - The Bloomington drop-off facility for bulk and
yard waste will change its hours Monday through May 27 and again
May 30 to Sept. 2.

The facility, 402 S. East St., will be open from 7 a.m. to 6:45
p.m. Monday through Friday and from 9 a.m. to 4:45 p.m. Saturdays,
Monday through May 27.

Hours will be 6 a.m. to 6:45 p.m. Monday through Friday and from
9 a.m. to 4:45 p.m. Saturdays from May 30 to Sept. 2.

The facility is closed Sundays and holidays.

IN COURT

McLean County

Cocaine - A 72-year-old man is accused of selling cocaine to an
undercover police officer three times in July and August.

Lee P. Frye, formerly of the 2300 block of Springfield Road, was
in jail Monday in lieu of $5,000 on charges of unlawful delivery of
a controlled substance. Frye also was listed as living at a
Colorado address in a court file.

Burglary - A Normal man is accused of trying to break into a
house.

Jacob Schmillen, of the 600 block of North Main Street, faces
one count of attempted burglary and is being held in lieu of
$15,000.

According to police, Schmillen, 19, knocked on the back door of
a home and then broke in. When one of the residents saw him, he ran
off. Schmillen later was identified by the resident in a photo
lineup.

Battery - A 51-year-old man is accused of kicking a man and
grabbing a woman at an Interstate 74 rest stop and striking another
man in the mouth and pushing a woman at a fast food restaurant
Saturday.

Joel J. McCormick, of Jefferson City, Tenn., was in jail Monday
in lieu of $1,000 on four counts of aggravated battery.

Cocaine - A Bloomington man is accused of possessing and
intending to deal cocaine and possessing marijuana Sunday.

Rodney R. Holliger, 41, of the 700 block of West Graham Street,
was in jail Monday in lieu of $20,000 on charges of unlawful
possession of a controlled substance with intent to deliver the
drug, unlawful possession of a controlled substance and unlawful
possession of marijuana.

Cocaine - A Decatur man is accused of possessing cocaine and
drug paraphernalia Saturday in Bloomington.

Lawrence L. Porter, 40, was in jail Monday in lieu of $1,000 on
charges of unlawful possession of a controlled substance and
possession of drug paraphernalia.

Cocaine - A Bloomington man is accused of possessing and
intending to deal cocaine and running from and struggling with
police Sunday in Bloomington.

Levar L. Walls, 28, of the 100 block of East Kelsey Street, was
in jail Monday in lieu of $5,000 on charges of unlawful possession
of a controlled substance with intent to deliver the drug, unlawful
possession of a controlled substance, resisting a police officer
and unlawful possession of marijuana.

Marijuana - A Bloomington man is accused of possessing and
intending to sell marijuana Sunday in Bloomington.

Zachary S. Gilmore, 21, of Edgewood Court, was in jail Monday in
lieu of $1,500 on charges of unlawful possession of marijuana with
intent to deliver the drug and unlawful possession of
marijuana.

Controlled substance - An 18-year-old Bloomington man is accused
of illegally possessing clonazepam, a prescription medication
commonly used to control seizures and anxiety.

Ryan Williams, of the 1800 block of East Market Street, was
released on a personal recognizance bond Monday on a charge of
unlawful possession of a controlled substance.

Setting it right

Local

Hotel - The Lincoln Inn in Lincoln, where a swimming pool has
been linked to Legionnaire&apos;s disease that killed an elderly Indiana
woman, is not affiliated with Best Western. A story in Wednesday&apos;s
Pantagraph was incorrect and also gave a wrong name for the hotel.
Both pieces of information were based on incorrect information
provided to the newspaper.
 View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
More News stories
 
 
 Flick: `Real Housewife of NYC&apos; a big hit in B-N, too 
 
 Flick: At movies, it’s big turn-about of the sexes … 
 
 Flick: Snickers goes home, 80,000 points later … 
 
 Flick: Merida, Elinor see themselves at hit movie! 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 pantagraph.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Follow the Pantagraph
 
Facebook
 
Like The Pantagraph on Facebook
 
Twitter
 
Follow The Pantagraph on Twitter
 Follow @pantagraph 
Google+
 
+1 The Pantagraph on Google+
 
Pinterest
 
Follow The Pantagraph on Pinterest
 
Email
 
Get email updates from The Pantagraph

 Email Updates 
 
RSS
 
Follow The Pantagraph via RSS

 RSS Feeds 
 
Latest Local Offers
 More Offers 
 Get a watch battery and installation for ONLY $4.95! 


 
 Open Saturday, July 14th, 1-3 - 3310 Carrington, Bloomington 


 
 Get $2 Off Cordless Phone Batteries! 


 
 The Ultimate GOP Breakfast Special - only $4.75 


 
Most Popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 
 Police: Victims of rollover lied, search for driver called off Owner of Edge, Drive says he wants to buy the Coliseum Two men attacked at Linden St. apartment lot Residents upset about blues festival in their neighborhood Benefit to honor memory of accident victim Dairy Queen damaged in Thursday fire City denies Daddios request for more ‘teen nights’ 4 charged in Constitution trail incident Crime Stoppers: Police search for wanted woman Council nixes jazz cafe, curtails blue fest, questions liquor panel 
 
 Obama has divided American people (97) City denies Daddios request for more ‘teen nights’ (77) Hispanic group protests criminal justice council, Sheriff Emery (75) Residents upset about blues festival in their neighborhood (68) Obamacare taxation with representation (62) Owner of Edge, Drive says he wants to buy the Coliseum (60) Council nixes jazz cafe, curtails blue fest, questions liquor panel (48) Roberts praised for health care vote (46) Parties need to drop drama, find the center (42) Two men attacked at Linden St. apartment lot (40) 
 Latest comments 
Featured Businesses
 More Businesses 
 Buddy&apos;s Ground Maintenance Inc 
 
 Alter Metal Recycling, Central Illinois 
 
 Twin City Home Brewing 
 
 Extreme Motors 
 
 Roanoke Motor Co. 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
 Top Classifieds 

 Jobs Garage Sales Rentals 
 
 Blogs&amp;Columns 

 Flick Fact 7/12/2012 Thursday 7 hours ago Updated: 1:52 pm Joe Knows - Thursday 07/12/12 9 hours ago Craft: Quantum leap -- from Higgs boson to undies quilt 10 hours ago Flick: `Real Housewife of NYC&apos; a big hit in B-N, too 19 hours ago Swiech: Twelfth Run, Martin Luther King Park July 11, 2012 6:29 pm Jenna Smith: Salsa opens door to many possibilities July 11, 2012 1:00 pm Flick Fact 7/11/2012 Wednesday July 11, 2012 12:00 pm Joe Knows - Wednesday 07/11/12 July 11, 2012 10:00 am Flick: At movies, it’s big turn-about of the sexes … July 11, 2012 7:00 am Flick Fact 7/10/2012 Tuesday July 10, 2012 12:00 pm 
 
Get Email Newsletters
 Today&apos;s Deal Special offers Garage Sales Contests&amp;Promotions Email: 
Pantagraph.com Links&amp;Services

 Bloomington Jobs Advertise with us Contact Us About Us Photo Store Customer Service Events Calendar RSS Feeds Bloomington Weather Area Businesses Pantagraph on Facebook Pantagraph on Twitter Bloomington Obituaries Area Classifieds Local&amp;National Sports 

Other Websites

 Today&apos;s Deal Gibson City Courier Woodford County Journal Decatur Herald&amp;Review Mattoon JG-TC 
 ©Copyright 2012, pantagraph.com , 301 W. Washington St. Bloomington, IL | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Bloomington Apartments Bloomington Attorneys Bloomington Auto Dealers Bloomington Auto Parts Bloomington Auto Repair Bloomington Beauty Salons Bloomington Car Rental Bloomington Dentists Bloomington Doctors Bloomington Flowers Bloomington Hotels Bloomington Insurance Bloomington Loans Bloomington Mortgages Bloomington Movers Bloomington Pizza Bloomington Realtors Bloomington Restaurants Bloomington Storage Bloomington Tax Preparation Bloomington Travel More Bloomington… Normal Apartments Normal Attorneys Normal Auto Dealers Normal Auto Parts Normal Auto Repair Normal Beauty Salons Normal Car Rental Normal Dentists Normal Doctors Normal Flowers Normal Hotels Normal Insurance Normal Loans Normal Mortgages Normal Movers Normal Pizza Normal Realtors Normal Restaurants Normal Storage Normal Tax Preparation Normal Travel More Normal… Hudson Apartments Hudson Attorneys Hudson Auto Dealers Hudson Auto Parts Hudson Auto Repair Hudson Beauty Salons Hudson Car Rental Hudson Dentists Hudson Doctors Hudson Flowers Hudson Hotels Hudson Insurance Hudson Loans Hudson Mortgages Hudson Movers Hudson Pizza Hudson Realtors Hudson Restaurants Hudson Storage Hudson Tax Preparation Hudson Travel More Hudson… Mema Apartments Mema Attorneys Mema Auto Dealers Mema Auto Parts Mema Auto Repair Mema Beauty Salons Mema Car Rental Mema Dentists Mema Doctors Mema Flowers Mema Hotels Mema Insurance Mema Loans Mema Mortgages Mema Movers Mema Pizza Mema Realtors Mema Restaurants Mema Storage Mema Tax Preparation Mema Travel More Mema… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing www.pantagraph.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with www.pantagraph.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
