<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008166" url="http://selectivemutismonline.com/blog/sm-friendly-jobs/" time="2012-07-13-01:26" support="2" score="0.0024598933868380177" bingtitle="SM-Friendly Jobs | Selective Mutism Online" webtitle="SM-Friendly Jobs | Selective Mutism Online">
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="108"/>
	<description>Being a cashier anywhere 3. Working at a fast food restaurant 4. Bank teller ... job that demoralizes your spirit, like collecting trash in my ...</description>
	<body>
		Selective Mutism Online 

Selective Mutism Online–Connecting SM Individuals, Family Members, and Friends
 
 Home Page People Signup Forum News and Blogs Videos About 
 Site Map Contact Us Terms of Service 
 
 
 Log In 
 
 Username Password Remember Me 
 Lost your password? 
 
 Forgotten Password Cancel 
 
Recently Online
 
245 Users - Show All 

 
 
Latest Forum Posts

 Re: Hows it going???? Everyone Comment! 
by: mary252525 
 July 5, 2012, 19:32 Re: Not a peep! 
by: admin 
 June 27, 2012, 14:24 New 
by: sosilent 
 June 17, 2012, 01:05 
 
Selective Mutism Posts

 Selective Mutism SM Blogs SM News Articles 
 
Selective Mutism Archives

 July 2012 January 2012 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 
 
Selective Mutism

 Selective Mutism Teacher Advice Sonic Scream: Sarah&apos;s SM Site Child Mind Institute We Have Selective Mutism Raising Smart Girls Diagnosis: Selective Mutism Confessions of a Social Cripple Life with Selective Mutism Selective Mutism Group Opening Closed Doors 
 Learn more about the site here selectivemutismonline@gmail.com 
 SM-Friendly Jobs 

July 24, 2011 in Selective Mutism 
 
 Cary Chessick had selective mutism as a child. Now, as the founder and CEO of Restaurant.com , he spends a lot of time in the spotlight. Read about his story here .

 

For the teen or adult with selective mutism, getting a job may seem like an impossible task. Even if you don’t have selective mutism, getting a job can still be pretty hard. Adults with SM have a tough time finding work because :

1. Interviews can be stressful for anybody, but the prospect of not being able to speak can present another layer of difficulty for someone with SM.
2. If you do get the job, there is still much talking involved while you work.

Kids with social anxiety who are in college sometimes consider tailoring their college major to something that would not involve much social interaction. For example, web programming, accounting, or engineering degrees can allow for a minimal amount of talking.

The good thing about this is that it’s a lot easier to cope with work. There’s not much expectation to speak, which is very nice. The downside is that it’s also very easy to get stuck and not talk to anybody ever. Selective mutism can be overcome slowly, but there has to be a conscious effort and a desire to do so. Some people are fine without speaking and accept it as the will of the universe, and if they prefer it that way, then that’s okay.

Even so, the progress doesn’t necessarily have to take place at work. You can always have a temporary job restocking shelves at a store or something, and work towards reducing anxiety somewhere else (like school).

So one way of looking at what kind of job to get, which I have described above, is where would I have to talk the least . The other way of looking at it is where would I get the most opportunity to practice talking . Last summer I worked as a janitor at a large office building (which I didn’t like at all and quit after three months because trash is gross), and one part of my job was this:

1) Push around a big trash can on wheels
2) Stop at each of the cubicles
3) Empty each of their miniature cubicle trash cans into the bigger trash can.

I started work towards the end of the day when people started to go home, but there were still about 3/4 of the people still working, which might be around 100 different people. Each time I’d arrive at a new cubicle, I had a chance to just say hi or ask how their day was. I didn’t do it every time because I’d get a bout of anxiety every so often, and I got a bit nervous at the thought of going to work, but over time it became less and less of a chore and more of just a habitual friendly gesture.

I learned that the more good social interactions you have, the more confident you will be . One of the reasons why it’s so hard to break out of the circle of anxiety is that it’s self-reinforcing .

 

To break this cycle, you’ve got to have many positive interactions to replace the negative feelings that stems from the anxiety. Most everybody was nice to me, except for maybe one or two people who were having a bad day. But after three months, you get a lot of opportunities to talk, and they add up quickly.

Common jobs that require a lot of talking (probably not a good fit for SM’s, but if you can do it, it will help out loads and help you to think on your feet):
1. Waiting tables
2. Being a cashier anywhere
3. Working at a fast food restaurant
4. Bank teller
5. Tutoring

Some jobs that require a moderate amount of talking:
1. Taxi driver
2. Janitor jobs
3. Mowing lawns
4. Working in a factory
5. Babysitting

Here are some jobs that require only a little bit of speech:
1. Reshelving library books
2. Data entry jobs
3. Photographer
4. Designing web pages
5. A Stockboy/girl at a grocery store
6. Any home business based on the internet
7. Writing books/scripts/articles

One of the most important things to remember is to do something you like . If you’re still in school or just needing a temporary job, then maybe it’s the best option to work somewhere you don’t want to. But thinking long term, a job that demoralizes your spirit, like collecting trash in my case, just isn’t worth it, and it’s better to find a job you like.

-Seth
 
 Tags: anxiety disorders , selective mute , selective mutism , speaking , talking 
 4 Comments» 
 SM-Friendly Jobs 
4 Comments

 
 sonicscream says: July 29, 2011 at 8:33 pm 
also delivering newspapers. that requires almost no talking at all.
 Log in to Reply Seth says: July 30, 2011 at 9:35 pm 
yeah, there are a ton of jobs that are good. being a paperboy/girl is a good one.
 Log in to Reply unpretty125 says: October 26, 2011 at 7:00 pm 
hi. I’m Pamela and I’m new. I just stumbled upon this site today.
 Log in to Reply marcjohng says: October 29, 2011 at 2:09 am 
OH MY GOD! His story almost made me cry! but with joyful tears’cause it’s really inspiring!!! 
 Log in to Reply 
 
 
Leave a Reply

 Click here to cancel reply. 

You must be logged in to post a comment.
 SM-Friendly Jobs 
0 Trackbacks


 
 Selective Mutism Home | Site Map | Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Compensation Disclosure | Contact Us | Sign Up 
2011 Selective Mutism Online
	</body>
</document>
