<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008146" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20081125100122AAjaaUh" time="2012-07-13-01:15" support="1" score="0.000338428330561997" bingtitle="What are some of the causes and effects of popularity of fast food ..." webtitle="What are some of the causes and effects of popularity of fast food restaurants? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>Like Hedy said, people used to make meals and sit around the table ... drives though MD or where ever and throws the bag in the back seat and tells everyone to eat ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Health &gt; Diet&amp;Fitness &gt; Resolved Question 
 Rp-Dk 08 Member since: September 02, 2008 Total points: 1,134 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What are some of the causes and effects of popularity of fast food restaurants?

 4 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 Yea Scarlett your answer had nothing to do with the question... 
 4 years ago 
 by aperki12 Member since: July 24, 2008 Total points: 569 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 I agree with Hedy V. But I bet his answer didn&apos;t really help you. The bad things about FF would be, The food is low quality, loaded with fat and carbs, added perservatives. So obviously it&apos;s unhealthy. You could put in there that even though the cost of FF is so low that all the money you&apos;ll have to spend on diet plans to take off the weight of FF will out weigh the low price.
There is the argument that FF takes away from the family time. Like Hedy said, people used to make meals and sit around the table and talk and share their day. No mom drives though MD or where ever and throws the bag in the back seat and tells everyone to eat while you get all your errands done before bed.
I could make this argument. My husband and I have recently committed to getting out of debt. We have really started planning meals and making a shopping list. We used to just grab something here and there. We never had a plan. We would just drive through Taco Bell and be done with it. Even though you could say that FF is cheap, you end up spending more money than you did b/c you didn&apos;t plan your meals. For instance. We went to Taco Bell the other night. There was just two of us and we spend $14. We didn&apos;t get crazy stuff. Just 2 regular meals and spent $14. Last night we cooked a chicken on the grill cost around $5. We also cooked 2 cans of green beans which cost around $2, and 2 cans of red beans which cost another $2. So our total meal was around $12 with tax. So we ate that for dinner and we had enough left over to take with us to work to eat for lunch. If we would have gone to FF we would have spent $28 for two meals. By cooking we spent $12 for two meals.
Ok, so I know I rambled on, but I was trying to give you some talking points. Hope any of this helped. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Thanks...helped me write my essay for sure. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Hedy V Member since: November 27, 2006 Total points: 214 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 (Either Scarlett is selling this tea or she just wants to brag about losing weight!) Anyway, I&apos;m old enough to remember when the first McDonald&apos;s opened in our town, many years ago. And that was just the first wave of the tsunami of fast food restaurants. Until then, mom stayed home and had dinner on the table at 5 and we all talked about our day. Then, the closest thing we had to fast food was a tv dinner that came in an aluminum tray. No microwaves. We had a garden. Dad and my brothers would go hunting and fishing for entertainment and we would eat their bounty. This was the 50&apos;s and 60&apos;s. Life just got faster. Mom was tired of being the maid and went to work outside the home. Women in society needed a change. They were tired of being labeled and told what to do by the man of the house. The TV show Mad Men is right on the mark. Children&apos;s attitudes were changing too. We didn&apos;t believe our parents or the government. We were breaking out of the mold. It was easier and more fun to grab a burger with your friends, than meet at home. Supply and demand is the basis of the popularity of FF restaurants and great advertising. The effects are terrible. Obesity, illnesses, just to name some of the physical problems. I go to restaurants regularly, but avoid the FF ones. I&apos;ll be interested in other answers and opinions.
 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by kagerous... Member since: April 30, 2007 Total points: 3,338 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Convenience is, I think, the most obvious cause of popularity. People don&apos;t always have time to prepare a meal, but even when we do have time, we enjoy the convenience of not having to. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Diet&amp;Fitness 

 Could someone please point me in the direction of a complete diet plan that I can follow for shredding fat? What is the best way to lose leg and belly fat? Am I a healthy weight? Y do i feel like this? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Health 
 Alternative Medicine Dental Diet&amp;Fitness Diseases&amp;Conditions General Health Care Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Optical Other - Health Women&apos;s Health 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
