<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008711" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?How-to-Design-a-Menu-Board&amp;id=1710699" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="9" score="0.03453645393522566" bingtitle="How to Design a Menu Board - EzineArticles Submission - Submit ..." webtitle="How to Design a Menu Board">
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="29"/>
	<description>A menu board can be the difference between a customer picking you or the restaurant next door. ... seem silly if you serve middle-eastern food and your menu board ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Business » Branding David J Hay 
 Platinum Author |   102 Articles 
 Joined: June 15, 2008 Was this article helpful? 1 0 
How to Design a Menu Board

 By David J Hay 
 
First impressions are important. The first impression can be the last impression for some. A menu board can be the difference between a customer picking you or the restaurant next door. Menu boards can tell the customer a lot about the quality of your product. These days menu boarding in the modern food business, is like a new trade skill. It could prove to be a giant step towards running a successful food franchise someday. There are a number of things you need to keep in mind when designing your menu board. Make sure it compliments your food. It&apos;ll just seem silly if you serve middle-eastern food and your menu board looks like something out of a Halloween party.

There&apos;s nothing worse than for a customer to make his mind up about a particular food item and then find out it isn&apos;t available even though it&apos;s shown prominently on the menu board. Make sure you have only those food items clearly stated which you will not run out of. Add pictures, preferably of the food item that&apos;s most popular, or you think will be, on your menu. They should be large, eye-catching images, put up with the purpose of making customers&apos; and onlookers&apos; mouths watery. Work with the guy who&apos;s taking the photos, it&apos;s as important a task as they come. Use as many colors as possible, keeping in mind what the colors go with the kind of food you serve.

Your best dish is your best bet to land business. Make it the center piece of your menu board giving it as much exposure as you can. The prices and text should be easy to read and in simple language. Some business owners might opt for a foreign language to make the menu look more sophisticated and exotic, in which case it&apos;d be convenient to have a translated one-two word explanation right beside it to avoid confusion for the customer. Having combo deals is always a good option, especially if you&apos;re a fast food joint. Adding a side order of let&apos;s say French fries, Coleslaw and a drink is always going to be popular with your customers, particularly their kids. It will make them think they&apos;re saving money and adding value to their meals.

A menu board consists of a backboard which can be in any shape from a traditional rectangle to a big ice-cream scoop. Several boards can be aligned together to provide an entire menu board arrangement. Graphics can be customized or you can pick one of the default designs. A lot of people now use magnetic border panels, with everything else on the board being magnetic as well. You can mount them on the walls or hang them by the ceiling. They come in various sizes, depending on where you&apos;d like them placed. Menu Boards for Fast food, Hospitals, Railroad stations and airlines will all vary in function and purpose.

Here at the San Diego Company, we create menu boards to suit your personal liking and requirements. Maximum quality guaranteed.
 
BIO: Menu Board Design is offered by 858 Graphics. We will design and print a menu board that will impact your customers.

David Hay is the owner of 858 GRAPHICS in San Diego, California. 858 Graphics designs, builds, prints and installs almost any type of graphics. For all your Trade Show Display, Wall Murals, Outdoor Signs, Poster Printing and Vehicle Wraps needs, please visit http://www.858graphics.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=David_J_Hay 
 Did you find this article helpful? 1 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Business: Branding 
 David J Hay 
 Email Address: Subscribe Branding Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 What Does YOUR Menu Say About You? Menu Boards Are Critical to a Successful Restaurant Primary Components of a Digital Menu Board Menu Development for a Startup Restaurant Menu Engineering&amp;Profitability - The Science Behind the Art How to Customize Your A Board Find the Right Outdoor Enclosed Bulletin Boards for Your Business How to Design a Menu Board in the Right Way How A Digital Menu Boards Template Works Digital Menu Boards for Restaurants 
 
Recent Articles

 Why Your Business Needs Proper Branding 7 Essential Elements of Memorable Branding Clearing The Confusion Around Branding Finding a Brand Name You Can Own Creating Good Karma For Your Personal Brand Why Including White Space In Your Brochure Matters Online Branding - Is It Like Marking Your Cattle or Leaving Your Footprint Behind? A Customer&apos;s Perception - Your Brand Make Your Business Stand Out In The Crowd - Be Unconventional And Imaginative 3 Ways To Brand Your Business 
 
Submitted On November 20, 2008. Viewed 4,255 times. Word count: 504.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Hay, David J. &quot;How to Design a Menu Board.&quot; How to Design a Menu Board .
 20 Nov. 2008 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?How-­to-­Design-­a-­Menu-­Board&amp;id=1710699 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Hay, D. J. (2008, November 20). How to Design a Menu Board .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?How-­to-­Design-­a-­Menu-­Board&amp;id=1710699 Chicago Style Citation: 
Hay, David J. &quot;How to Design a Menu Board.&quot; How to Design a Menu Board EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?How-­to-­Design-­a-­Menu-­Board&amp;id=1710699 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
