<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008290" url="http://rockthetruth2.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="1" score="0.000253829745637284" bingtitle="MSM Monitor" webtitle="MSM Monitor">
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>I wonder who they will pick to be elected this time. ... Protesters attacked the seat of Kano’s state ... University said yesterday that a Chick-fil-A fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		MSM Monitor
 
 This Blog is/was dedicated to exposing the lies of AmeriKa&apos;s Main Stream Media. 
 
 Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 
 British Bellyache 
 I got it from laughing so hard after seeing half of British law enforcement being called out over an E-cigarette on the tube.  

 Of course, the anger turned to rage when the bulls*** started to flow regarding the effective security shield the western intelligence agencies have constructed to protect us and we are told of arrests that have nothing to do with the Olympics , and yet we know they have everything to do with the Olympics and setting that mind-set amongst the British people and world.   I&apos;m sure they are well aware of it , what with the routine vehicle searches and cameras on every corner. Of course, they must have seen V for Vendetta by now. They must know about the FRU its of false flags by now, and I wonder if they have ever met Mr. Aswat or Mr. Khan .  

 Aaaah, the memories:  

&quot;Today is the anniversary of the ICTS associated attack on the London Tube in 2005. They were running security at all the 9/11 airports . They were running security at the London Tube . They were also in place at The Madrid Train Station when that got bombed . Good luck finding links on the internet placing ICTS there. That&apos;s been well scrubbed. The sheer weight of associations between Israel and just about every terror act in recent decades is inarguable. If you&apos;ve got a couple of hours you&apos;ll find lots of heartwarming copy here .

At the London Tube, the claim was made that young Muslims with backpacks filled with explosives were responsible. No one saw this actually happen and the explosions came from beneath the floor of the cars, not in the carriage. So, apparently they magically slipped on to the tracks, under the cars and attached the bombs underneath the cars and then magically slipped back up on to the landing....

-- MORE --&quot;   

 Also see :

 May Day Memories: British Patsies 

 May Day Memories: The U.S. Connection 

 Terror Expert: London Bomber Was Working For MI5 
 
 Israeli Connections to the London Tube Bombs 
   
 How Did Mossad Know the London Bombings Were Going to Happen?   

 Related(?):  

 President Shimon Peres cancels Olympics trip over Shabbat observance 

 IS SHIMON PERES THE TERRORIST MASTERMIND BEHIND 9-11? 

 The FRU flu?  

 Sure hope it doesn&apos;t rain on the games , although I won&apos;t be watching. I don&apos;t even watch Wimbledon anymore. I&apos;ve been trying to scale back the watching of sports so I can blog, but I know you will believe when you see it , readers.  

 So what other British fare is the New England flagship Boston Globe serving up to this New Englander?  

&quot;43-year-old Shawn Sullivan, a dual US-Irish citizen, is accused of raping a 14-year-old girl and sexually molesting two 11-year-olds in Minnesota in the 1990s. He escaped to Ireland as prosecutors prepared to file charges, and while staying there was convicted of sexually assaulting two 12-year-old girls. Authorities finally caught up with him two years ago in London....

-- more --&quot;

 &quot;2 UK hacking suspects plead guilty&quot; June 26, 2012

LONDON—Two British members of the notorious Lulz Security hacking collective pleaded guilty to a slew of computer crimes Monday, the latest blow against online troublemakers whose exploits have grabbed headlines and embarrassed governments around the world.   

 Who are the hackers ?  

 Yeah, turns Lulz, Wikileaks, and the rest are intelligence agency operations. I t&apos;s a net to gather whistleblowers and identify interested citizens. 

Ryan Cleary, 20, and Jake Davis, 19, pleaded guilty to conspiring with other members of LulzSec to attack government, media, and law enforcement websites last year, according to Gryff Waldron, an official at London’s Southwark Crown Court.

LulzSec—an offshoot of the loose-knit computer hacking collective known as Anonymous—has claimed responsibility for attacks against sites run by the CIA, the US Public Broadcasting Service, and Rupert Murdoch ’s News International.   

 They are known as false flag attacks. 

Other targets included media and gaming companies such as Nintendo and Sony, technical security company HBGary, Britain’s National Health Service, and the Arizona State Police.   

 Related :   

 &quot; Leaked emails from data security firm HBGary show the federal government is offering private intelligence companies contracts to create software to manage“fake people”on social media sites , possibly to manipulate public opinion or create the illusion of consensus on controversial issues . &quot; 

 Newspapers no longer getting it done, huh? 

Waldron said two other defendants—Ryan Ackroyd and an unnamed teenager —have pleaded not guilty to the same charges....   

 ????????? 

-- more --&quot;   

 Not related: UK court: Detective must reveal phone hack names 

 Related: Cameron Caught Up in Media Conspiracy 

 You might have to Czech those files again , reader. 

 Also see: Cameron pushes plan to change House of Lords 

 Nice to know some people have plenty of dough.  

 Speaking of dough, it&apos;s about time for me to grab some dinner.  Posted by Rocker at 2:45 PM Links to this post Labels: Afghanistan , Britain , Czech Republic , European Tyranny , Ireland , Prop , Sports , U.S. , Wikileaks 
 Immune to Globe&apos;s Bulger Coverage 
 I&apos;ve already acquitted him, sorry. 

&quot;Bulger says FBI deal gives him immunity &quot; June 25, 2012 | Milton J. Valencia and Travis Andersen 

The notorious gangster James“Whitey”Bulger, speaking for the first time through his lawyers about his scandalous arrangement with the government, said in the court records that he plans to file a motion to dismiss the charges, based on his immunity from prosecution for serving as an FBI informant .

Bulger has requested a hearing and indicated that he may summons US District Court Judge Richard G. Stearns, a former federal prosecutor who is now presiding judge on the case, to testify about what he knew of Bulger’s longstanding agreement with the federal government.

Bulger’s lawyer, J.W. Carney Jr., would not elaborate on the agreement. But he said outside the courthouse and in court records that the government’s refusal to indict Bulger on the murder charges before his relationship with the FBI was exposed in the late 1990s, for instance, demonstrated that he had immunity for his crimes .....

-- more --&quot;    

 I hope you like the staged and scripted show, folks. Here this guy was living blocks away from the local FBI office. They KNEW WHERE HE WAS, folks, they were just WAITING TO SPRING some of these COLD CASES on you so the Fascist Bureau of Instigation would look like they are doing their jobs, tracking down old leads, framing patsies, &apos;er, I mean, busting terror plots and malware schemes and keeping us all safe. 

 Related : US attorney rebuts Bulger claim of immunity 

 Prosecutors oppose Bulger claim of immunity   

 I think I&apos;ll just wait for the movie :

&quot;Mixed feelings as Hub heroes explore movie on its villain; Bulger’s portrayal may be challenge for Damon, Affleck &quot; October 28, 2011 | By Joseph P. Kahn, Globe Staff

Ben Affleck and Matt Damon grew up in Cambridge and have contributed their talents to a string of successful movies set in the Boston area, among them“Good Will Hunting,’’“The Departed,’’and“The Town.’’Collectively these films have established Boston in the minds of moviegoers around the globe.

But their latest venture, a proposed movie about Boston mobster James“Whitey’’Bulger, is already stirring mixed emotions among local people who have known Bulger and who fear it might glamorize a ruthless criminal .

 Yeah, the movies and media never do that (blog editor rolls his eyes skyward). 

 We lionize war criminals and no one seems to have a problem with that. 

“If anyone makes this movie, I’m pleased it’s these two. They’re brilliant,’’said Tommy Donahue, whose father was allegedly killed by Bulger and his henchmen.“But I definitely have mixed emotions about this. Hopefully they can depict Whitey Bulger for what he is. They’ll need to do their homework, though.’’

How Bulger might be portrayed onscreen - Damon has indicated he wants the role - concerns attorney Anthony Cardinale as well. Bulger has been charged with 19 slayings, many shockingly brutal.

“If it’s done honestly, [Damon] will look like an idiot, a treacherous piece of junk. It’ll be a bad career move for him,’’said Cardinale, who represented Francis“Cadillac Frank’’Salemme, then the New England Mafia boss, in a case that helped expose Bulger’s corrupt ties with the FBI.   

 That would be the Fascist Bureau of Instigation for those that don&apos;t know. 

If not done accurately, Cardinale added,“it’s a worse career move.’’

Bulger’s arrest in June and pending trial may yield even more details of gruesome killings and FBI corruption , heightening interest in any dramatization of the mobster’s life and crimes.   

 That is what they are really worried about. 

But along with the interest come questions about how key pieces of the story might be treated or left out .   

 I understand that feeling being a reader of the Boston Globe. 

On the one hand, there is widespread praise for Affleck and Damon as homegrown stars who have never abandoned their roots.   

 Didn&apos;t Damon narrate Inside Job ? 

“As a Bostonian, I’m proud of them,’’said defense attorney Joseph Oteri, a longtime Bulger family friend.

His primary concern is whether their film does“a hatchet job ’’on William Bulger, the former Massachusetts Senate president who is the gangster’s brother, and not how it treats Whitey.“Southie is a state of mind, not a place,’’Oteri said, and Affleck and Damon“know how to capture that mentality.’’

On the other hand, there is worry that a big-budget production built around Damon and Affleck might romanticize Bulger and his gang, or even turn Bulger himself into a sympathetic figure , no matter how dark the film is.

According to Thomas Foley, the former Massachusetts State Police colonel who helped build the criminal case against Bulger, it is critically important that any such movie strives to be more than pure entertainment. It should also, he said, be faithful to what really happened - notably, Bulger’s role as an FBI informant , which began in the 1970s - without“making [Bulger] any more of a celebrity than he is now.’’   

 Rare is the movie that will be faithful to history or the truth, especially coming out of Hollywood. More than likely it never gets made. 

That is a tall order, conceded Foley, who is working on his own book about the Bulger case.“What angle will they take? I don’t know, but this happened over many years. It’s hard to get your arms around all that in a two-hour movie .’’   

 Would you mind if we watched something else , readers? 

-- more --&quot;    

 Who are the criminals again?  

 Btw, she stood by her man. 

 Also see :   

 A Bulging Boston Globe 

 Whitey Makes Me See Red 

 Battle of the Bulger 

 Choppy Bulger Coverage 

 Massachusetts&apos; White Shadow 

 Can only see it at night.   Posted by Rocker at 12:18 PM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , State , U.S. 
 Wednesday, July 11, 2012 
 
 No Day at the Boston Globe Beach 
 I&apos;ll be back tonight, readers. Great day out there, but I have to go work a part-time slave shift.  

 Stinks almost as much as this :

&quot;Invasive seaweed leaves Massachusetts towns, tourism industry helpless&quot; by Martine Powers and Christine Legere | Globe Staff and Globe Correspondent, June 27, 2012

An aggressive red seaweed that hails from Japan has invaded the Massachusetts shoreline , threatening native wildlife, jeopardizing tourism, and causing a stink for beachfront residents.   

 At least we aren&apos;t getting the full flower of radiation like the left coast and Pacific, even though the diluted spew has gone by and continues to go by every day. 

From Cape Ann to Cape Cod, beaches have been blanketed in recent weeks with thickly packed red fibers resembling matted hair, and the odor can at times be overpowering.   

 Related :  Several beaches reopen after bacteria counts are found to be safe 

 Shark spotted off Rye, N.H., beach 

 RI officials: Charlestown beach safe for swimming 

 Reports of gangs lead police to close beach in Conn. 

 I guess I&apos;ll have to go out of state .  

“I wake up with nightmares I’m in a sewer system,”said Beth Bisson, a summertime resident of Manomet, a part of Plymouth.

Local officials are scrambling to clean beaches, spending thousands of dollars for dump trucks and composting fees.

Scientists fear the seaweed could harm the coastal ecosystem by growing over native seaweed, starving it of light and nutrients and damaging a habitat and food source for many marine animals.

“I don’t want to sound dramatic, but it scares the hell out of me ,”said Steven Kenney, the public works director for Manchester-by-the-Sea, adding that he worries the foul smell will discourage visitors.“This might wipe out everything on the coastline, and there’s nothing anyone can do about it.”   

 It&apos;s like the Asian Carp . 

****************************

Meanwhile, towns are trying to find the best way to get rid of the stinky mass .

Collect it in dump trucks? Pay shipping fees to compost it? Leave it to rot? Or use a tractor to push it back into the ocean?

 Ellen Simpson of Manchester-by-the-Sea said a resident used a tractor to plow the seaweed back into the water after it covered the entire beach in a foot of gunk. Town officials said that was not allowed ....

-- more --&quot;

 Related : Great white sighting at Nauset Beach deters few 

 Kayaker’s first foray ends after close shark encounter 

 Think I&apos;ll just stay on the beach:  

&quot;As piping plovers rebound, more of Revere Beach is off limits&quot; by Matt Woolbright | Globe Correspondent, July 03, 2012

Eighteen piping plovers have commandeered some 500 feet of Revere Beach, an­encouraging sign for the birds’champions but an annoyance for some residents.   

 The little sparrow-sized guys have commandeered the beach? 

Growing numbers of the ­endangered birds , which have nested on this beach for years, mean more areas deemed off-limits to beachgoers , riling some residents and potentially deterring some of the beach’s more than 2 million annual visitors.   

 Can&apos;t we all get along? 

“It was at first a small area, and no one objected,”said­Revere city councilor John Powers, who heard resident complaints at a meeting in June.“Ever since it has been growing and growing —they’re going to take over the whole beach , it seems. It just got to be a little too much.”
 
 Well roll me over in the plover!   
***************************** 
Because the piping plovers mostly claim rocky areas with vegetation , they are not in competition with beach-goers , said Mike Pietrello, 46, as he scoured the sand with his metal detector.“Who comes to the beach to lay on piney grass and rocks,”Pietrello said.“Nobody.”   
 Just a bunch of chirping, &apos;eh? 
Gene Giardima, a beach regular, said the southern area where the birds are nesting is usually not sought after .“That’s the last place people would set up,”Giardima, 69, said.... 
Even if the nesting areas are not attractive to beach-goers, restrictions could deter prospective tenants and cost­Revere economically in the long run, Powers said.

“People that are buying a condo are buying because they want access to the water ,”said Powers.“They don’t want to come out and have to walk 400 to 500 feet to get to the water.”   

 Oh, the poor babies would have to walk a few more feet! 

-- more --&quot;   

 Related :

&quot;Beachgoers urged to help protect birds 

Connecticut officials have issued a public plea to beachgoers to beware of vulnerable birds nesting near some busy shoreline parks and islands. Some of the birds, including the piping plover , are endangered or threatened. The state Department of Environmental Protection says beachcombers and sunbathers can accidentally trample the nests. It says eggs and hatchlings will die if the birds abandon the disturbed sites ( AP ).&quot;

 More : See If You Can Swallow This Post 

 Birds Blinded By the Lights 

 Boston Hates Birds   

 A true genocide.   

 Massachusetts&apos; Treasure Island 
   
 Globe Walks Gulf Coast Beaches 

 Also see:  Boston Globe Day at the Beach 

 Boston Globe Beach Patrol 

 Boston Globe Back to the Beach 

 Obama Administration Abandons Beaches     

 No Day at the Beach in France   

 West Bank Day at the Beach 
 
 And don&apos;t go in the river :

&quot;Potentially toxic algae bloom starts early in Charles River&quot; by Carolyn Y. Johnson  | Globe Staff, June 23, 2012
 
A sudden bloom of blue-green algae that has the­ potential to release toxins harmful to people and dogs has turned portions of the lower Charles River a scummy greenish color , and it has started several weeks earlier than in previous years.

People and pets should avoid contact with water that looks green and should not ingest it, state public health officials warned. Toxins that can be produced by the algae may cause skin rashes or stomach problems, and can seriously sicken or kill pets....

 
 A clump of the algae was found near a boat dock not far from the Longfellow Bridge. 
 That looks gross! 

-- more --&quot; 
 Think I&apos;ll just go the pool:  

&quot;New safeguards in place for swimming pools after drowning&quot; by Peter Schworm  | Globe Staff, June 23, 2012

The summer after a Fall River woman drowned in nearly opaque water, state officials have overhauled operations at swimming pools, closing slides, hiring more lifeguards, and filling in deep ends.

With a new swimming season set to begin Saturday, the state’s recreation department has made broad changes to improve safety at its two dozen deepwater pools, following recommendations from a scathing internal review that found“systemic deficiencies”in their management.

Marie Joseph, 36, who could not swim, drowned last June after going down the slide and slipping under the water without notice. Her body lay unseen on the bottom of the Fall River pool’s 12-foot-deep end for two days, shrouded by the cloudy water.   

 Related :   Sunday Swim 

 Body apparently was in state pool 3 days 

 Was it two or three? 

Four state employees, including a regional director and district manager, lost their jobs after­investigators found that water quality flagrantly violated safety guidelines. Two men were sentenced to probation after­being charged with reckless­endangerment....

-- more --&quot;    

 I guess I&apos;ll just see if I can go swimming in the pool of someone I know. 
 

 Made it back to the beach before sunset, too. If you look far enough you can see the wind turbines: 

 &quot;Wind farms on land grow with few critics&quot; by Erin Ailworth  | Globe Staff, July 09, 2012

Despite controversy that has slowed the Cape Wind project in Nantucket Sound, land-based wind farms are expanding rapidly in the region.

One company alone, First Wind Holdings LLC of Boston, has installed enough turbines in the Northeast over the past few years to generate nearly as much power as the long-awaited offshore wind farm. Other companies, too, have developed wind projects in New England states.

Driving this growth are technological advances reducing the cost of wind turbines and increasing their efficiency, making wind power more competitive with traditional power sources—particularly in the Northeast, where electricity costs can run as much as 60 percent above the national average....

 That&apos;s weird because I was told shale was making things cheaper , but whatever....  

-- more --&quot;    

 Hey, that&apos;s where I&apos;m looking for a sunset. 

 Also see: NStar Passes Wind On To Customers 

 That&apos;s rude! Posted by Rocker at 7:59 AM Links to this post Labels: Environment , Japan , State 
 Bankrupt California Post 
 &quot;Calif. city becomes largest in US to file for bankruptcy &quot; June 28, 2012 

STOCKTON, Calif.—In opting to become the nation’s largest city to seek federal bankrupt cy protection, Stockton took a rare financial step of last resort after struggling with the economic downturn, soaring pension costs, and contractual obligations.

Thirteen cities, counties, and other government entities filed for bankruptcy protection last year—the highest annual level in nearly two decades.

Stockton, a river port of 290,000, was the seventh US municipality to file this year and the first California city since Vallejo, which sought protection in 2008, according to James Spiotto, a Chicago bankruptcy attorney who tracks municipal bankruptcies.

‘‘Filing bankruptcy is time-consuming, expensive, and complicated,’’said Spiotto, noting that Vallejo spent millions of dollars alone on attorneys and other bankruptcy professionals.‘‘And you never get the results you desire.’’

 Related : Alabama: Bullies and Bankruptcy 

 Turns out banks are the biggest bullies of all.  

That’s why specialists are divided on whether other financially struggling cities, towns, and government entities will follow Stockton to bankruptcy court. Spiotto said it will be hard and expensive for Stockton to obtain financing.

Others also say bankruptcy comes with non-monetary costs.

‘‘Being in bankruptcy is decimating to your staff and morale,’’said Deborah Lauchner, Vallejo’s finance director....

 Like in Detroit ? 

‘‘Bankruptcy is a huge drain on municipalities, because they have limited ways to create more revenue ,’’said Los Angeles bankruptcy lawyer Karol Denniston.

 Because they have taxed damn near everything -- twice. 

Stockton City Manager Bob Deis said officials were left with little choice but to recommend bankruptcy after failing to hammer out finance deals with creditors to address the city’s $26 million budget shortfall.   

 The banks want to be paid in full now, or let&apos;s just add some more interest if it&apos;s later. 

‘‘Unfortunately, we have no comprehensive set of agreements with our creditors that would eliminate the deficit and avoid insolvency,’’Deis said at the City Council meeting Tuesday night. He said, however, that the city was still negotiating with some creditors and could reach deals with as many as one-third of them.

‘‘We think Chapter 9 protection is the only choice left,’’Deis said.‘‘If we get any agreements, those will be honored in Chapter 9.’’

On Tuesday, the City Council voted 6-1 to adopt a special bankruptcy budget to address Stockton’s $26 million shortfall if the city files for bankruptcy, as expected, by Friday.

The city has been hit hard by high crime and the collapse of the housing market in the past three years. It has also dealt with $90 million in deficits through a series of drastic cuts .

The new budget did not call for additional service cuts beyond those that earlier slashed the police force by one-fourth , the fire department by one-third , and other city employees by 40 percent , along with wages and medical benefits .

The new budget would suspend payments for debts and legal claims ; reduce payments for retiree medical benefits; further cut some pay and benefits; and increase revenue through code enforcement and parking citations .   

 I sure don&apos;t like the cops handing out more tickets stuff; however, I DO LIKE that FIRST ONE! 

-- more --&quot;

 Related:  California Bankruptcies 

 It&apos;s the whole state, not just Stockton.  

 And they approve thi$? 

&quot;California legislators OK high-speed rail line&quot; Associated Press July 08, 2012

SACRAMENTO—California lawmakers gave the green light to start building the nation’s first continuous high-speed rail line, a multibillion dollar project to link Los Angeles and San Francisco. In a 21-to-16 party-line vote Friday, the state Senate approved a $2.6 billion bond issue to fund a 130-mile section of the line. The Assembly has approved the bill, and Governor Jerry Brown has promised to sign it .&quot;    

 So how much interest is going to be tacked on to that? 

 Maybe you ought to bring back the trolley instead. 

 I see Brown is working for the $pecial interests now. What a far cry from 1992. 

 In addition to the fiscal bankruptcy there is moral rot on the left coast :

&quot;Calif. official accused of sex assaults&quot; by Amy Taxin | Associated Press, July 04, 2012

SANTA ANA, Calif.—A Southern California city councilman has been charged with sexually assaulting seven women when he was a high-ranking county executive in what prosecutors said Tuesday was an abuse of power and public trust .

Carlos Bustamante, 47, a former Orange County Public Works administration manager, is facing 12 felony charges ranging from false imprisonment to sex offenses stemming from his work at the county over eight years until he resigned his post in 2011.

Bustamante, a Santa Ana councilman, called female employees to his office under the pretense of discussing work and kissed and grabbed them, and sometimes masturbated in front of them , prosecutors said.   

 What a sickie! 

The women were reluctant to come forward, fearing they would lose their jobs for speaking out against Bustamante, who was considered by some a rising star in Orange County politics.

‘‘This case exemplifies an abuse of power, an abuse of position, abuse of women, and abuse of trust ,’’Orange County District Attorney Tony Rackauckas said.   

 Public servant, right? 

-- more --&quot;    

 Also see : Scott Peterson appeals’04 death sentence 

 Trial starts in wildfire tied to 5 deaths 
 
 Injured Calif. hiker saves rescuer hit by copter blades 

 Sinking of $3.2 million yacht at Tahoe a mystery 

 I&apos;m out of ideas.  Posted by Rocker at 7:51 AM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , U.S. 
 Cambodian Concerns 
 They are every ones! 

&quot;Court frees 13 Cambodian land eviction protesters&quot; by SOPHENG CHEANG | Associated Press, June 28, 2012

PHNOM PENH, Cambodia—A Cambodian appeals court ordered the release Wednesday of 13 women who had been sentenced to 2½years in prison for protesting their eviction from their homes without adequate compensation, in a case that was widely seen as an example of injustice .

 In AmeriKa it is seen as an ashamed fault of oneself. 

The women cheered in the courtroom, their supporters applauded , and observers from foreign embassies, including the United States, smiled in the audience after the judge’s ruling. Local and foreign human rights groups hailed the women’s freedom, but said the court also should have overturned their guilty verdicts....   

 But they don&apos;t take on the banks and their fraudulent foreclosures here! They get a chump-change kickback of a settlement that doesn&apos;t get your home or life back. 

Their joy Wednesday was marred by a clash outside the court between police and the women’s supporters, a reminder of the evictees’prolonged struggle against a government with little tolerance for dissent ....   

 What one is? 

-- more --&quot;

&quot;The investigation of a mystery disease that has killed dozens of children in Cambodia is advancing after the discovery in patient samples of a virus that causes hand, foot, and mouth disease ....

-- more --&quot;

 Related(?) : Fearing Bird Flu Posted by Rocker at 7:46 AM Links to this post Labels: South Asia 
 Canadian Mall Collapse 
 &quot;At least one person is feared dead after a roof collapsed at a shopping mall in northern Ontario, authorities said Sunday....

-- more --&quot;   

&quot;Many residents said the building was much in need of repairs , and officials from the Ontario Ministry of Labor had previously visited the mall because of complaints of water leaks ....   

 I see a lawsuit in the very near future. 

-- more --&quot; 

 Even Canada has gone the way of the U.S. because of banks and wars. 

 Also see : Dunkin’loses in Canadian court 

 I guess Canadians don&apos;t like coffee .  Posted by Rocker at 7:43 AM Links to this post Labels: U.S. 
 Massachusetts Makes Bad Bet 
 We didn&apos;t want casinos in the first place, and now look who is taking a seat at the table : 

&quot;Gambling commission may reach out to Wall Street&quot; by Mark Arsenault  | Globe Staff, July 11, 2012

The state gambling commission may seek to increase competetion (sic) for state casino licenses by reaching out to Wall Street investors and­ encouraging them to provide the capital for­casino companies to make bids in Massachusetts.
   Attracting capital would be an evenhanded way to help potential casino developers, who each must raise more than $500 million to bid for casino development rights in the Bay State, said Stephen Crosby, who chairs the Massachusetts Gaming Commission. Easier access to capital could attract more casino developers to the state, he said.    “It’s selling Massachusetts as a place to­invest ,”Crosby said in an interview following Tuesday’s commission meeting....      We ALREADY PAY ENOUGH DEBT-SERVING INTEREST PAYMENTS each month.     Crosby said reaching out to Wall Street is a new concept for the commission, he said, and the panel will run the idea by the state treasurer and perhaps other officials before deciding whether to follow through.     I hope someone, somewhere, in the bowels of state government says something.   -- more --&quot;      Nah, BAD IDEA! 
 Also see : Commission launches effort to combat problem gambling 

 Antismoking laws could hamstring Mass. casinos 

 PFFFFFFFT!   

 Yeah, we are going to have politically-correct casinos in Massachusetts! 

 Think Wall Street is going to invest in that?   

 (I&apos;m sure they will invent an instrument where they will be able to steal a few dollars) Posted by Rocker at 6:29 AM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , Business , State , State House 
 Clinton Mouths Off in Mongolia 
 I wish she would just shut up. 

&quot;Clinton urges political reforms, free markets in China&quot; by Jane Perlez | New York Times, July 10, 2012

ULAN BATOR, Mongolia—In an unmistakable message to China delivered in a speech from this neighboring country, Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton ’s remarks, couched in unequivocal language at an international forum of democracy advocates, came at a particularly sensitive point in China. A leadership transition at the top of the Communist Party is proving more messy than usual , and criticism against the government has spread from environmental concerns to social issues , such as forced abortion.   

 Yeah, Chinese don&apos;t have to protest wars because they haven&apos;t started any, &apos;murkn. I&apos;ll get to the messy leadership transition a bit lower down in this post, folks.  

‘‘You can’t have economic liberalization without political liberalization eventually,’’she said.‘‘It’s true that clamping down on political expression or maintaining a tight grip on what people read, say or see can create an illusion of security . But illusions fade—because people’s yearning for liberty don’t .’’   

 Well, that second statement is certainly true; however, I wonder how you say hypocrite in Chinese regarding the first because that is what the U.S. government is doing here at home. 

 Related: Googling China 

 Huh? 

Clinton arrived in this mineral-rich nation on the border of China on the second day of an Asia tour.

 Where&apos;s that neo-con world domination map I had lying around here? 

Her appearances are designed to broaden the Obama administration’s renewed focus on the region beyond an early emphasis on US military strength .   

 Translation: We want your resources, and we have the force to back up the threat. 

The administration now wants to stress US interests in economic and social issues , an effort to ease up on drawing a confrontation with China .   

 It&apos;s not easing anything, a**holes. 

Clinton did not mention China , but her target was clear .

‘’Countries that want to be open for business but closed to free expression will find that this approach comes at cost: It kills innovation and discourages entrepreneurship, which are vital for sustainable growth,’’she said, in a particular dig at China as it wrestles with an economic downturn after a decade of double-digit growth .   

 Oh, Americans, the ECONOMY of YOUR DREAMS!! And she is RAPPING IT! 

Clinton is well known to the Chinese as a critic of their model of government, a fact that she recalled Monday by referring to her visit to Beijing 17 years ago when Bill Clinton was president.

 On that occasion, in 1995, she addressed a UN conference on women and created a firestorm when she declared that‘‘human rights are women’s rights—and women’s rights are human rights.’’   

 So when are we going to stop dropping bombs on them, &apos;eh? 

-- more --&quot;     

 You know, I really can&apos;t remember the last time I saw something from Outer Mongolia in my Boston Globe. 

 Related: North Koreans Tell Clinton to Shut Up 

 What is with this woman lately? She is going around the world talking up tensions and war, be it Korea and China or Russia, Syria, Pakistan, Iran, or anywhere!! And she&apos;s headed to Israel and Egypt next!  

 Really trying to get the official WWIII off the ground, huh? 

 &quot;US accuses China of unfair auto trade practices; Asks world trade group to rule on $3b in tariffs&quot; by Matthew Pennington | Associated Press, July 06, 2012

WASHINGTON—The United States launched a trade complaint Thursday against China at the World Trade Organization, accusing Beijing of unfairly imposing duties on more than $3 billion in exports of American-produced automobiles.

 Looks to me like they are just protecting their national interest. 

The announcement came as President Obama hit the campaign trail in the battleground state of Ohio, where automakers have been affected by the tariffs imposed in December. It underscored how America’s trade relations with rising economic power China could color the political debate ahead of the November presidential election....     

 Anything to get your mind of the endless wars and Wall Street looting. 

 Related: The State of Obama&apos;s Campaign 

 Bashing China another fooley like the wealth inequality, the women wedge, the student loans, and all the other campaign issues brought forth by the MSM.  

 What was this guy doing the last four years on all these problems, and why should we believe it won&apos;t be back to business as usual yet again after the false-choice election is over? 

 They EXTENDED the BUSH TAX CUTS for crying out loud, and now Obama is talking about finally letting them expire (nothing Congress can&apos;t fix before the end of the year)?  

China and the United States are at odds over a slew of trade issues .   

 Is this going to make the cost of cheap Chinese s*** go up because that will lose Obama the election. It&apos;s the Walmart vote. 

In March, the United States, the European Union, and Japan brought a trade case against China over its curtailment of exports of rare earth minerals over whose production China has a virtual monopoly . Those minerals are used to manufacture hybrid car batteries, flat-screen televisions, and other high-tech goods . China said curbing rare earth exports is for environmental protection, not intended to help Chinese companies.   

 And they are ALSO USED to &quot;make advanced equipment like guided missiles &quot; that the U.S. needs!!   

 I wonder WHY the REPORT LEFT OUT that item!   

 And WTF you mean the price of a flat-screen just skyrocketed? 

With American manufacturers still struggling to recover from the financial crisis , and unemployment running over 8 percent, the administration is keen to show it is getting tough on discriminatory trade practices by its chief economic rival —also its main foreign creditor — blamed by many in the United States for a loss of American manufacturing jobs .   

 Yeah, American manufaturers are really hurting:   

 &quot; Corporate profits have risen 58 percent since mid- 2009 &quot; and &quot; corporate profits set a post World War II record last year &quot; while big banks are booming and oil companies are awash in profits.    

 It&apos;s because they moved the factories to China. 

-- more --&quot;   

 Related: China has mild response to US autos trade complaint 

 Because the Chinese don&apos;t want a war. 

 So how is that Chinese economy doing? 

 &quot;Developers nationwide have laid off huge numbers of workers as construction sites from the factory cities of Guangdong in the southeast to manufacturing and logistics hubs like Xi’an in the northwest have cut back this year from three shifts working around the clock, seven days a week , to a single daytime shift on weekdays .&quot; 

 Sounds familiar doesn&apos;t it, American.  

 You know who the economic saviors are, right? 

 &quot;China, Europe act to rev up economy&quot; y Binyamin Appelbaum | New York Times, July 06, 2012

WASHINGTON—The actions again cast central bankers in the role of primary responders to the global economic malaise, aiming at the same basic target they have tried to hit repeatedly over the past six years: encouraging people and businesses to borrow and spend and to take greater risks with their investments.

 Oh, it&apos;s a MONEY MOUTHPIECE of a MEDIA, all right!   

 Yes, the DESTROYERS of the WORLD ECONOMY that CREATED the PROBLEMS are the FIRST-RESPONDER HEROES!! 

But Europe is mired in a recession and a political crisis. The United States is faring somewhat better in both respects but is hardly booming .   

 I can&apos;t read this shit anymore. 

 China is suffering what its government has begun to describe as a sharp economic slowdown . And policy makers have not succeeded in restoring public confidence that better days are coming ....

 Sounds familiar doesn&apos;t it, American. 

-- more --&quot;   

 Now about that transition in Chinese leadership :

&quot;Police officials arrested in China investigation; 2 tied to inquiry into corruption&quot; by Edward Wong | New York Times, July 07, 2012

BEIJING—Central investigators have detained at least two senior police officials with close ties to Wang Lijun, the former police chief of Chongqing who set off a national political scandal by confiding suspicions of a murder plot to US officials , according to people with police contacts there.

A third police official also close to Wang has been dismissed. The moves are a sign that the inquiry into Wang could be reaching a critical phase.

The two detained police officials are Tang Jianhua, the city’s deputy police chief, and Wang Pengfei, former department head of the Yubei district. Both were escorted out of Chongqing in June by security officers on the orders of the Central Discipline Inspection Commission, the Communist Party’s anticorruption body and one of the lead agencies in the far-reaching inquiries into Wang Lijun and Bo Xilai, the former party chief of Chongqing and a deposed Politburo member.

 See: Bo Given the Bounce in China 

 The &quot;messiness&quot; is western interference in China&apos;s internal matters, and one thing anyone who has studied history can understand is China&apos;s reaction. Foisted an opium epidemic (drug$ again) and carved them up into spheres of influence a while back if I remember correctly.  

Wang Pengfei, who appears to have no family ties to Wang Lijun, was removed from his post June 25 as head of the Yubei District Police Department, according to Xinhua, the state news agency. The same day, Li Yang, head of the criminal investigations division, was also dismissed.

Wang Pengfei and Li both followed Wang Lijun from the northeast province of Liaoning to take posts in Chongqing after Wang Lijun was appointed police chief of Chongqing by Bo. Together, the men carried out a campaign against what they called at the time organized-crime gangs ; the campaign also involved persecutions of private businesspeople and enemies of Bo and his allies, and is now being widely criticized.

Wang Pengfei is also a wiretapping specialist believed to be involved in a wide-ranging wiretapping campaign run by the police chief and Bo. And he arranged a car in February for the police chief to use in a secret trip to a nearby US consulate , a visit that catalyzed the scandal , say two people with police contacts in Chongqing....   

 Oh, readers, WHAT A STENCH , and it smells like Wang was a CIA asset!! 

-- more --&quot;   

 Globe even had a full article on protests (in China?). 

&quot;China adopts law to crack down on illegal foreign workers&quot; Associated Press, July 01, 2012

BEIJING—China’s national legislature adopted a new law Saturday that will target foreigners who are living and working in China illegally, the official Xinhua News Agency said, adding that the government encourages citizens to inform on suspected illegal workers. The law approved by the National People’s Congress Standing Committee now requires foreigners to obtain valid documents—including employment certificates—to work in China, Xinhua said .&quot;    

 Hey, see something, say something , right? 

 Now can I see your voter ID? 

 Also see: 
 
 Ordination leads to fracturing ties between China and Vatican   

 Actually, the Chinese are looking pretty good in that match-up -- unless there are a bunch of Buddhist monks doing some butt-banging we&apos;ve yet to read about. 

 Mother forced to undergo late-term abortion in China not allowed to leave hospital 

 China to ban shark fin soup at official banquets   

 Yeah, yeah, we know. China is bad for women and other living things . 

 China suspends officials who forced late abortion 

&quot;BACK HOME -- Liu Yang, China&apos;s first female astronaut, exited the Shenzhou 9 spacecraft, which returned to Earth on Friday (Boston Globe June 30 2012).&quot;   

 That photograph only made the printed paper.  

 Related :

&quot;Chinese put female astronaut in space

JIUQUAN- China launched its most ambitious space mission yet Saturday, carrying its first female astronaut and two male colleagues in an attempt to dock with an orbiting module and work on board the craft ( AP ).&quot;   

 Related : China might have woman aboard for space flight 

 China ready to send 1st woman into space 

&quot;China is hoping that around 2020, it will join the United States and Russia as the only countries to send independently maintained space stations into orbit....    

 Just as the U.S. space program has dropped to earth due to lack of funds. 

-- more --&quot;    

 Related: Globe Lost in Space 

 I&apos;m lost trying to figure out what to post next.  Posted by Rocker at 6:00 AM Links to this post Labels: China , Neo-Con Plan , South Asia , U.S. , Women 
 Tuesday, July 10, 2012 
 
 The Globe&apos;s Strobing Streetlights 
 Are they near a garbage can ? 

&quot;Critics of the new lights say they produce so much glare that they can momentarily blind older drivers and reduce depth perception. And some residents complain that the sterile light makes it difficult to sleep and gives their apartments the feel of an operating room ....

 No wonder I&apos;m having so much trouble sleeping. 

-- more --&quot;   

 And it is unfortunately time for me to go to bed. I&apos;ll be back bright and early tomorrow morning, readers. Posted by Rocker at 8:57 PM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , State 
 Colorado Cop is Free Jazz Fatality 
 &quot;A veteran Denver policewoman who was raising her 12-year-old daughter alone was shot and killed during a free jazz festival, police said Monday....

-- more --&quot; Posted by Rocker at 8:34 PM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , U.S. 
 Quick Connecticut Post 
 Took a bit longer than I would have liked, but that&apos;s always the case :

&quot;Central Connecticut State University student accused of faking antigay harassment&quot; Associated Press, July 03, 2012

 A college student who received an outpouring of support after she complained about receiving antigay notes has been charged with writing the messages herself . Central Connecticut State University police say a hidden camera videotape d 19-year-old Alexandra Pennell sliding one of the notes under her own door . She has pleaded not guilty to charges including falsely reporting an incident, fabricating evidence, and making a false statement. Her lawyer declined to comment. Pennell was arrested May 2. Hundreds of students had rallied in her support in March after she reported receiving harassing notes. A spokesman for the university, Mark McLaughlin, said the school remains proud of the campus response to what appeared to be an act of bias .&quot; 

 More the rule than the exception these days. What pathetic souls.  

 Also see :  Canceling Connecticut Post 

 Priest being ousted over porn charges 

 More the rule than the exception these days.  

 Conn. nursing home workers begin strike at five homes 

 More the exception than the rule these days.  

 Connecticut Governor Malloy sees big accomplishments in first 18 months 

 And he&apos;s a Democrat? 

 Next Day Update: Malloy wants Connecticut’s Old State House open on Sundays 

 Review of campaign finds no wrongdoing by Donovan 

 Another Democrat? 

 Conn. Senate candidates address union members 

 Maybe Linda can win it this time after losing to a liar the last time (although the Supreme Court retroactively exonerated him).    

 Next Day Update: Reward offered for info on Conn. bank robbers 

 It&apos;s the guys running it. When can I pick up my reward? 
 Posted by Rocker at 8:33 PM Links to this post Labels: Education , Hoaxes , U.S. 
 Commerce Secretary Crash Cover-Up 
 Related : Commerce secretary takes medical leave after crashes 

&quot;Commerce chief resigns after crashes &quot; June 22, 2012 

NEW YORK—John E. Bryson announced his resignation as President Obama’s commerce secretary Thursday following an episode in which he had a seizure and was involved in a sequence of automobile accidents .

“The work that you do to help America’s entrepreneurs and businesses build our economy and create jobs is more important now than ever, and I have come to the conclusion that I need to step down to prevent distractions from this critical mission,’’Bryson said in a message to department employees.

Bryson offered no further information about his health or the status of the legal case following the episode earlier this month. He had taken a medical leave shortly afterward and left the department in the hands of his deputy, Rebecca M. Blank. In his message to employees Thursday, Bryson said Blank would continue to serve as acting secretary....

Bryson, 68, a longtime California electricity conglomerate executive and founder of the Natural Resources Defense Council , served just eight months in the Cabinet and had kept a low profile in Washington.

But his back-to-back automobile accidents in California on June 9 drew wider attention . Driving a Lexus in suburban San Gabriel, Bryson rolled into the back of a Buick waiting at a train crossing, according to authorities. He got out to offer to give the other driver his information , then got back into his car and hit the Buick again as he was driving off, police said. Just minutes later , he crashed into the rear of another car about 2 miles away.   

 Well, he sure was ACTING DRUNK!! 

Bryson was found unconscious behind the wheel and taken to the hospital.   

 Where they took blood to check the alcohol content, right? 

He was cited for a hit-and-run accident. His department later said he had a seizure, but it was not clear whether he had it before, during, or after the accidents. Officials said it was the first such seizure Bryson had had but declined to provide many more details about his medical history.

 No one involved in the accidents was seriously hurt and the damage to the cars was judged to be fairly minor. Authorities have reported no signs that drugs or alcohol were involved . Bryson has a home in San Marino near the sites of the accident and was there to deliver a commencement address at the private school his four daughters had attended.

 He could have been drinking. 

Obama has not had much luck with his choices to head the Commerce Department. His first choice, Bill Richardson, at the time governor of New Mexico, withdrew from consideration amid a federal investigation into state contracting, an inquiry that did not result in charges against him.   

 Because Bill was involved with a pay-for-play corruption $cam. Never you mind that war criminal stuff. 

Obama’s second choice, Senator Judd Gregg, Republican of New Hampshire, changed his mind about joining a Democratic Cabinet.

Former governor Gary F. Locke of Washington then accepted and was confirmed, serving two years before stepping down to become ambassador to China. Bryson, former chief executive of Edison International in Southern California, was nominated in May 2011 and, after a brief struggle in the Senate, was confirmed in October.

-- more --&quot;     

 Government work is just one big party , huh? Posted by Rocker at 8:33 PM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , Obama , U.S. 
 Cyprus Seeks Bailout 
 No nation is an isla.... oh, yeah. 

&quot;Cyprus will request eurozone bailout aid &quot; June 26, 2012 

LONDON—The eurozone’s sovereign debt crisis took a turn for the worse Monday as Cyprus said it would seek aid from the eurozone’s bailout funds.

“The purpose of the required assistance is to contain the risks to the Cypriot economy, notably those arising from the negative spillover effects through its financial sector , due to its large exposure in the Greek economy,’’the government said in a statement.

Earlier in the day, the ratings agency Fitch downgraded the island nation’s government debt to junk status . Cyprus last year received a three-year, $3.13 billion loan from Russia ....

Even before Cyprus made its request for a bailout, stock markets plunged in Europe and the euro dropped amid doubts that EU leaders will achieve the far-reaching breakthrough needed to resolve the debt crisis.“This will be a decisive week for Europe,’’the German foreign minister, Guido Westerwelle, said Monday at a meeting of EU foreign ministers in Luxembourg.   

 See: Europe&apos;s Answer to Corporate Welfare 

 Wrong. 

On Monday, Spain made a formal request for up to $124 billion in aid for its banks, but how the money is to be disbursed is the subject of negotiation. The Spanish government wants the aid to go directly from European bailout funds to the banks. Eurozone rules now require that the aid be funneled through the government in Madrid, which would add to Spain’s sovereign debt.

 Related: Skipping Through Spain 

 Haven&apos;t seen much on them since they were promised the check. 

European leaders may discuss whether to change those rules at their summit meeting in Brussels, at which they will also debate plans to create an EU banking union , including a system to wind up insolvent banks and the establishment of a central deposit guarantee fund .   

 More centralized banking is NOT the answer either! 

In addition, the European Central Bank would have a bigger supervisory role . Officials say these measures would not require changes to the EU treaty, but they could not be operational until 2013 at the earliest. Bringing about even deeper integration would take longer.

‘‘It is a starting point, it is not an end game ,’’said a European official who spoke on the condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of the discussions.‘‘We are not going to wake up on June 30 and find there is a banking union, a fiscal union, and a political union.’’

 But that&apos;s the goal! 

-- more --&quot;   

 Related : Global markets cheer as Europe’s leaders back rescue plans 

 What did you wake up to?  

 None of that natural gas can be leveraged on behalf of Cyprus? 

&quot;Cyprus has first visit by Israeli leader &quot; February 17, 2012 

NICOSIA, Cyprus - Israel’s prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, paid a historic visit to Cyprus yesterday, aiming to strengthen what he declared to be a“natural relationship’’between the countries in a volatile and quickly changing region.

The visit was the first by an Israeli leader to the nearby island nation, which along with Israel has natural gas interests in the Mediterranean and is coping with rising tensions with Turkey....

Although Cyprus is only a 50-minute flight from Tel Aviv, ties between it and Israel have long been chilly. But Israel’s relations with Turkey have deteriorated over the past three years, while Cyprus has been looking to cement ties with neighbors as a bulwark against Turkey’s growing influence.

Another bridge between Israel and Cyprus has been the discovery of huge natural gas deposits in the Mediterranean Sea. Exploration has found an estimated 25 trillion cubic meters of gas in  Israeli waters and up to 230 billion cubic meters in Cypriot waters.   

 See: Israel Grabs Lebanese Gas 

 Is there anything they don&apos;t steal? 

Turkey opposes any Greek Cypriot oil and gas search that denies breakaway Turkish Cypriots what it says is a rightful claim to gas wealth. And it has dismissed a Cypriot-Israeli deal demarcating maritime borders.

-- more --&quot; Posted by Rocker at 8:30 PM Links to this post Labels: European Tyranny , Greece , Israel , Middle East , Turkey 
 Czeching on Croatia 
 &quot;8 tourists are killed after bus rolls over

ZAGREB—At least eight Czech tourists were killed and 44­injured when a bus crashed and overturned on a major highway in Croatia Saturday, police said. The accident happened around 4 a.m. about 125 miles south of­Zagreb, on a highway connecting the Croatian capital with the central Adriatic coastal city of Split. Croatia’s state television said the bus crashed through metal barriers in the middle of the highway, and overturned in the opposite lane near a tunnel. Witness­reports suggested that the driver fell asleep, officials said ( AP ).&quot; Posted by Rocker at 8:21 PM Links to this post Labels: Czech Republic , European Tyranny 
 Do You Hear a Buzzing Sound? 
 It&apos;s coming from above....  

 Remember way back when bloggers warned the technology being used overseas would soon be brought to the home front and were dismissed?  

 Well.... 

&quot;FAA pressed to allow civilian drone flights in the US; Potential uses raise privacy, safety fears&quot; by Joan Lowy | Associated Press, February 27, 2012

WASHINGTON - Civilian cousins of the military drones that have tracked and killed terrorists abroad are in demand by United States police departments, border patrols, power companies, news organizations, and others wanting a bird’s-eye view that is too impractical or dangerous for conventional planes or helicopters to get.   

 See: Look, Up in the Sky.... 

 Keep looking , readers.  Keep looking ....   

 What a sight , huh? 

Along with the enthusiasm for the unmanned aircraft , though, there are qualms . Drones overhead could invade people’s privacy . The government worries they could collide with passenger planes or crash, concerns that have slowed more widespread adoption of the technology.    

 Whenever I look up at the sky now (or even when I&apos;m outside) I assume they are up there even if I can&apos;t see them. 

Despite that, pressure is building to give drones the same access as manned aircraft to the sky at home.

“It’s going to be the next big revolution in aviation. It’s coming,’’said Dan Elwell, the Aerospace Industries Association’s vice president for civil aviation.   

 Related: Spy Satellite Shit and Rods From God 

 And that was five years ago! 

Some impetus comes from the military , which will bring home drones from Afghanistan and wants room to test and use them ....

The Defense Department says the demand for drones and their expanding missions requires routine and unfettered access to domestic airspace, including around airports and cities....

The possibility of armed police drones someday patrolling the sky disturbs Terri Burke, executive director of the Texas chapter of the American Civil Liberties Union.

“The Constitution is taking a back seat so that boys can play with their toys ,’’Burke said.“It’s kind of scary that they can use a laptop computer to zap people from the air.’’

 In this instance I agree with the ACLU. 

The Electronic Frontier Foundation, which focuses on threats to civil liberties involving new technologies, sued the FAA recently, seeking disclosure of which agencies have been given permission to use drones.

Industry officials said privacy concerns are overblown .

“Today anybody - the paparazzi, anybody - can hire a helicopter or a [small plane] to circle around something that they’re interested in and shoot away with high-powered cameras all they want,’’said Elwell, the aerospace industry spokesman.   

 We are not talking about them, are we? 

Until recently, FAA officials were saying there were too many unresolved safety issues to give drones greater access. Even now the agency is cautious about describing its plans and avoids discussion of deadlines.

“The thing we care about is doing that in an orderly and safe way and finding the appropriate . . . balance of all the users in the system,’’Michael Huerta, FAA’s acting administrator, told a recent industry luncheon in Washington.

Drones come in all sizes, from the high-flying Global Hawk with its 116-foot wingspan to a hummingbird-like drone that can perch on a window ledge to record sound and video.   

 Is that what hit the Pentagon that horrible morning?   

 Also see : Look Up in the Sky! It&apos;s a Bird, it&apos;s a Plane, it&apos;s an... INSECT SPY DRONE? 

 The Terminator Was NOT a Movie 

 And that buzzing you hear around your ear may not be a mosquito!    

 &quot;Radhika Nagpal, an associate professor at Harvard University and a member of the Wyss Institute for Biologically Inspired Engineering, is part of a group working on creating a colony of robotic bees , an effort that received a $10 million economic stimulus grant last year from the National Science Foundation. 

The stimuloot took a 2x4 to a Terminator beehive? 

 The ultimate goal of the project is to create robotic bees that mimic those in nature—a colony that could pollinate crops, emulating bees’ability to hover , fly from flower to flower, and work with others to scout or forage. 

With a LITTLE GOVERNMENT VIDEO CAMERA for a STINGER! 

 The technology will require scientists to develop tiny, lightweight sensors and advanced computer programming to get a bunch of flying robots to coordinate movement .&quot;  

 Like the robot monkeys in &quot; Great Expectations ?&quot; 

The aerospace industry forecasts a worldwide deployment of almost 30,000 drones by 2018, with the United States accounting for half of them.

The hungriest market is the nation’s 19,000 law enforcement agencies. Customs and Border Protection has nine Predator drones mostly in use on the border with Mexico, and plans to expand to 24 by 2016. Officials say the aircraft have helped in the seizure of more than 20 tons of illegal drugs and the arrest of 7,500 people since border patrols began six years ago.

Power companies, farmers, and ranchers also have an interest in using drones.

-- more --&quot;

&quot;As drones spread, privacy issues grow; Inexpensive chips enable a boom&quot; by Marcus Wohlsen | Associated Press, April 02, 2012

BERKELEY, Calif. - Sharp-eyed dog walkers along the San Francisco Bay waterfront may have spotted a strange-looking plane zipping overhead recently that looked strikingly like the US stealth drone captured by Iran in December.   

 See: U.S. Drones Dropping Out of the Skies Like Flies 

A few key differences : The flying wing seen above Berkeley is a fraction of the size of the CIA’s waylaid aircraft. And it is made of plastic foam. But in some ways it is just like a real spy plane ....

Thousands of hobbyists are taking part in what has become a global do-it-yourself drone subculture , a pastime that is thriving as the Federal Aviation Administration seeks to make the skies friendlier to unmanned aircraft of all sizes.   

 Related: Alphabet Agency: It&apos;s Fun Working For the FAA 

 Yes, the only ones not having fun on the flight these days is you passengers! 

The use of drones in the United States by law enforcement and other government agencies has privacy advocates on edge .

At the same time, some DIY drone flyers believe the ease of sending cheap pilotless planes and choppers airborne gives citizens a powerful tool for keeping public servants on the ground honest .

 The tools of tyranny are a double-edged sword. 

Drones are the signature weapon of US wars in the 21st century ....    

 Exhibit A in the war crimes trials. 

Among the groups seeking to take advantage of the steep drop in price of drone technology are journalists who want to attach cameras to aircraft the size of small pizzas and that cost as much to buy - about $400 - as a one-hour helicopter rental for a photographer.

In the San Francisco Bay area, Occupy Wall Street activists built a so-called Occucopter to monitor police action against protesters from the sky.

In Idaho, wildlife biologists started using a drone for counting fish nets after a helicopter crash killed two colleagues and a pilot.

And researchers are developing techniques to use drones equipped with infrared sensors to detect patches of dry ground in orchards.   

 Yeah, tyranny from the air is a good thing.  

Hobbyists say drone prices have been driven down sharply even in the past two or three years primarily by the surge in popularity of smartphones ....

-- more --&quot;

 Also see:  

 Pakistan Post in a New Format   

 Sunday Globe Specials: Up and Down Drones   

 Hit or Mis(take) in Pakistan   

 AmeriKan Missiles Keep Things All in the Family in Yemen   

 Somalia Makes the List   

 So did Iraq and Libya.   

 Yeah, about those war crimes I was mentioning :

 &quot;White House takes lead in deciding target list for drones&quot; Associated Press, May 22, 2012

WASHINGTON - White House counterterrorism chief John Brennan has assumed responsibility for choosing which suspects could be targeted for drone attacks or raids, establishing a new procedure for military and CIA targets.

The effort concentrates power over the use of lethal US force outside war zones within one small team at the White House .

The process, which is about a month old, means Brennan’s staff consults with the State Department and other agencies as to who should go on the target list, making the Pentagon’s role less relevant, according to two current and three former US officials aware of the evolution in how the government goes after suspected terrorists....

-- more --&quot;   

 Related: Obama Campaign Springs a Leak 

 Then he is responsible for them, isn&apos;t he? 

 &quot;US government challenged on drone tactics&quot; by Frank Jordans | Associated Press, June 21, 2012

GENEVA—A UN human rights specialist accused the US government Wednesday of sidestepping his questions on its use of armed drones to carry out targeted killings overseas.

Christof Heyns, the UN’s independent investigator on­ extrajudicial killings , had asked the United States to lay out the legal basis and accountability procedures for the use of armed drones.

He also wants the United States to publish figures on the number of civilians killed in drone strikes against suspected terror leaders in Afghanistan, Pakistan, Yemen, and elsewhere.

After a two-day‘‘interactive dialogue’’with US officials at the United Nations in Geneva, Heyns said he was still waiting for a satisfactory reply ....   

 I wouldn&apos;t hold your breath. 

-- more --&quot;   

 Just wondering why the Globe website lopped this off of my printed version :

&quot;The use of armed drones has provoked anger abroad, particularly in Pakistan, where human rights groups say innocent people have been among the victims of the strikes. The American Civil Liberties Union told the U.N. rights body Wednesday that“the United States has cobbled together its own legal framework for targeted killing .”   

 I can&apos;t imagine why my war paper would want to give that the axe.
  
 Btw, YOUR GOVERNMENT is an OUTLAW , Americans! Posted by Rocker at 6:45 PM Links to this post Labels: American Tyranny , I.E.P. , U.N. , U.S. , War Profiteering Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
About Me
 Rocker All material published for educational purposes under Fair Use Doctrine. 

Warning: Some commentaries may include profanity. I offer my apologies in advance for those who may be offended by the harsh language in response to outrageous lies. View my complete profile 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Must View Truth Websites
 
 Belated Birthday Wish Most Difficult Essay I Have Ever Read Wake the Flock Up What Really Happened Palestine Telegraph Pakalert Press Crimes of the State Catbird Seat EA Against Zionist Israel Europe Existentialist Cowboy Washington&apos;s Blog Injustice Exposed Intel Hub Kenny&apos;s Sideshow Liberal White Boy Lone Star Watchdog Phaedrus Rock the Truth Smoking Mirrors Winter Patriot Zippitty Dodah Desert Peace Divining the News There Are No Sunglasses Truth Rocker Global Research Moon of Alabama Prison Planet Uruknet TV News Lies Wake Up From Your Slumber AmeriKan News Monitor 9/11 Mysteries 9/11 Revisited Architects&amp;Engineers for 9/11 Truth Loose Change Patriots Question 9/11 Pilots For 9/11 Truth Scholars for 9/11 Truth&amp;Justice 
 
Why the Truth?
 Lies come easily. Truth will ultimately win. We are on the winning side!

&quot; This site may contain copyrighted material the use of which has not always been specifically authorized by the copyright owner. We are making such material available in our efforts to advance understanding of criminal justice, political, human rights, economic, democracy, scientific, and social justice issues, etc. We believe this constitutes a &apos;fair use&apos; of any such copyrighted material as provided for in section 107 of the US Copyright Law. In accordance with Title 17 U.S.C. Section 107, the material on this site is distributed without profit to those who have expressed a prior interest in receiving the included information for research and educational purposes. &quot;
 
Subscribe
 Posts Atom Posts All Comments Atom All Comments 
My Blog List
 
 WHAT REALLY HAPPENED Libor Is Not the Only Manipulated Economic Number - The Telegraph noted Monday:

[Bank of England executive] Paul Tucker told MPs that Barclays’abuse of 
the Libor system may be only one part of the banks’... 2 hours ago Intel Hub Whoever Controls the Media Controls the World - *Waking Times* | Perhaps the greatest unknown fact about life on Planet 
Earth concerns the MEDIA, and in particular, the Mainstream Media (MSM). 3 hours ago Therearenosunglasses&apos;s Weblog Supreme Court of Pakistan accused security forces for abductions in 
Balochistan - Supreme Court of Pakistan accused security forces for abductions in 
Balochistan Quetta : The top judge of Pakistan’s highest court on Wednesday 
accused the... 4 hours ago Desertpeace DRONES OVER GAZA - They killed my only child Mamoun Aldam. *“Mum, I am scared because of 
the drones in the sky. There are many of them. I can hear them. I can 
also see... 16 hours ago Smoking Mirrors The Road of Ignominy and the Lord&apos;s of Parsimony. - Dog Poet Transitioning.......

May your noses always be old and wet.

On and on it goes. It flies up your nose. It rips off your clothes, not the 
usual klei... 1 day ago The Existentialist Cowboy The Murder Case Against George H.W. Bush - *by Len Hart, The Existentialist Cowboy*

The CIA never forgave JFK for withdrawing air support at the Bay of Pigs. 
Infamous for his role in Watergate, Howa... 3 days ago Rock The Truth I&apos;m Baaaaaaa..... - 4 days ago kenny&apos;s sideshow Listen to This, You Take That - &quot;Listening to Spell&quot; art by Roberta Serenari 
That was the title of a tune I wrote on the afternoon of July 7, 2005 after 
hearing of the false flag in Lond... 5 days ago Reflections in a Petri Dish These Things too are for the Purpose of Demonstration. - Dog Poet Transmitting.......

May your nose always be cold and wet.

Well, let&apos;s see, there&apos;s this, to the eternal shame of the good old boys, 
who are makin... 5 days ago Truth Rocker Niedermeyer For President - Presidential candidate Mitt Romney was appalled by the antiestablishment 
mood at Stanford University during antiwar protests and, in turn, launched 
count... 2 weeks ago Musings Of A Tired Soul Road to Tantura - by Hala Gabriel

View this fascinating video here!

Work in progress. 20 Min. Please check out my website where you can see 
more clips and interviews that w... 3 months ago Winter Patriot Ten Years Of Murderous Nonsense - WTC6 was hollowed out. What did this? Today marks the tenth anniversary of 
the last happy day of my life.

It was an ignorant sort of happy, but I remember... 10 months ago Divining the News (DTN) Free Meditation download Yoga Nidra - Free digital download, 8 minute meditation, Yoga Nidra means silent or 
psychic meditation, the method is known to be thousands of years old. 4 years ago 
 
Followers
 
Video Bar
 Loading... 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (1375) 
 ▼  July (111) 
 British Bellyache Immune to Globe&apos;s Bulger Coverage No Day at the Boston Globe Beach Bankrupt California Post Cambodian Concerns Canadian Mall Collapse Massachusetts Makes Bad Bet Clinton Mouths Off in Mongolia The Globe&apos;s Strobing Streetlights Colorado Cop is Free Jazz Fatality Quick Connecticut Post Commerce Secretary Crash Cover-Up Cyprus Seeks Bailout Czeching on Croatia Do You Hear a Buzzing Sound? Denying Demjanjuk Dutch Touch Swabbing the Sea For Earhart Massachusetts Community Colleges Suck UMass Stem Cell Lab Runs Short Black Stain on Brown University How Much Is Your School Worth? The Boston Globe&apos;s $ummer $chool 21st-Century Segregation in AmeriKan Schools Massachusetts School Chiefs Cheating Taxpayers Sunday Globe Special: English High Leader Leaving Congress Saved Student Loans Romney&apos;s Report Card Big Job Ahead For Obama Romney&apos;s Summer Trip Romney Will Pilfer Pennsylvania LIBOR Banker Bails on Romney Mitt Hid More Money Romney and the Right Romney&apos;s Reminiscence Romney Romances the Ladies Even the Losers Get Lucky Sometimes Globe Serving You Post Office Hates Newspapers Nuclear Bomb in New Hampshire Gassing Up For Some Campaign Coverage Gone to Globe Well Once Too Often Meet Mr. Morsi Egypt&apos;s Modest First Mom Edwards Affair Over EPA Literally Looking Over Shoulder of Farmers Europe&apos;s Answer to Corporate Welfare Sandusky&apos;s Son Speaks Sunday Globe Special: Scottish Lunch Fires, Floods, and Florida Fearing Bird Flu Phoqueing French Post Greek Post is Garbage Sunday Globe Special: The Softening of Scott Brown... Sunday Globe Special: Stay-at-Home Sermon Sunday Globe Special: Sudanese Sequel Sunday Globe Special: Building Haitians a New Home... Harvard&apos;s Head Racist Taxed by Obamacare Coverage Letting Go of Eric Holder India&apos;s River Refugees Demolishing Indonesian Post Running Through Iran Post Giving Iraq a Rest Blood Gets On Queen&apos;s Dress in Ireland Moving on an Israeli Post The Ivory Coast&apos;s Illegal Immigrants The Globe&apos;s Kashmiri Camera Click Ungracious Exit For Gration Koreans United Against United States The LIBOR is Life Did You See the Fireworks? The Land of Liberty Globe Light on Libya The Boston Globe&apos;s Blind Spot Upper Crust Burns Roof of Mouth Teens Hurry to Get Tan in Massachusetts Meaty Maine Post Mali Goes Islamist Ethiopian Express Capsizes on Lake Malawi Who Gives a Suu Kyi? Mexican Time Machine The Globe&apos;s Michigan Monologue Mississippi Post Aborted Hitchhiker Hoax The Boston Globe&apos;s Full Moon Moroccan Fireworks on the Fourth of July Murray&apos;s Moment Hepatitis Epidemic at Exeter Hospital Knocking in New Jersey College President Ran Prostitution Ring Today&apos;s Boston Globe N-Words Big Gulp From Gotham Bullies on the Bus Too Old For the Cyclone The Silent Streets of New York NYC Cabbies in a Clinch No Boston Globe Scrubs N.Y. Surgeon Commits Suicide $teeled Against Racism in New York Walking a Tightrope on Wallenda Post Going Nuts For a North Carolina Post Not Nuts About Norway Post Kerry on the Case For Obama Obama in Boston Rocker Silenced by Blogger Browser Goodbye, Boston Globe Final Prez Poll? Slow Saturday Special: Occupy Philadelphia an Oppo... One-Stop Ohio Traintracking It Across Oklahoma 
 

 ►  June (238) 

 ►  May (243) 

 ►  April (200) 

 ►  March (134) 

 ►  February (219) 

 ►  January (230) 
 

 ►  2011 (2612) 
 ►  December (184) 

 ►  November (136) 

 ►  October (150) 

 ►  September (229) 

 ►  August (273) 

 ►  July (258) 

 ►  June (405) 

 ►  May (247) 

 ►  April (230) 

 ►  March (96) 

 ►  February (167) 

 ►  January (237) 
 

 ►  2010 (4112) 
 ►  December (144) 

 ►  November (184) 

 ►  October (209) 

 ►  September (397) 

 ►  August (558) 

 ►  July (401) 

 ►  June (447) 

 ►  May (324) 

 ►  April (406) 

 ►  March (260) 

 ►  February (387) 

 ►  January (395) 
 

 ►  2009 (5507) 
 ►  December (292) 

 ►  November (424) 

 ►  October (436) 

 ►  September (458) 

 ►  August (455) 

 ►  July (579) 

 ►  June (358) 

 ►  May (510) 

 ►  April (524) 

 ►  March (580) 

 ►  February (457) 

 ►  January (434) 
 

 ►  2008 (1749) 
 ►  December (575) 

 ►  November (200) 

 ►  October (689) 

 ►  September (285) 
 
 
Labels
 
 9/11 (263) Afghanistan (926) Africa (559) American Tyranny (4606) Animal Cruelty (342) Brazil (84) Britain (397) Bush (279) Business (2963) C.I.P. (202) California Fires (21) Chile (45) China (337) Clunkers (15) Colombia (51) Czech Republic (18) Draft (141) Earmarks (37) Education (725) Egypt (141) Environment (1594) Ethiopia (20) European Tyranny (926) France (205) Fukushima (49) Germany (151) Greece (101) Guinea (15) Gulf Gusher (137) Haiti (138) Health (1205) Hoaxes (60) Honduras (50) I.E.P. (196) India (181) Indonesia (71) Iran (410) Iraq (823) Ireland (80) Islam (200) Israel (1179) Italy (98) Japan (124) JFK (27) Korea (172) Kyrgyzstan (26) Language (15) Lebanon (80) Leftism (40) Libya (93) Life-Affirming (104) Madoff Scandal (86) Massport (50) Mexico (121) Michael Jackson (17) Middle East (336) MSM (3366) Myanmar (48) Neo-Con Plan (1603) Nigeria (69) Norway (7) Obama (1170) Occupy (45) Pakistan (565) Palestine (537) Palin (109) Philippines (53) Plane Crashes (93) Politics (2593) Prop (541) Religion (277) Russia (349) Saudi Arabia (90) Somalia (170) South Africa (72) South America (473) South Asia (342) Spain (74) Sports (368) Sri Lanka (42) State (1398) State House (163) Sudan (80) Swine Flu (98) Syria (108) Thailand (50) Times Square (24) Turkey (106) U.N. (514) U.S. (6536) Underwear Bomber (41) Venezuela (42) Vietnam (50) War Profiteering (356) Wikileaks (69) Women (516) Yemen (101) Zazi (13) Zimbabwe (51) 
 
Favorite Movies and Books
 
 King Kong (1933&amp;2005) Revenge of the Sith Titanic (1997) Gandhi Sicko Avatar Inside Job The International JFK Braveheart Witness Cleopatra My Fair Lady Shut Up and Sing The Last of the Mohicans The Last Samurai Legends of the Fall Letters From Iwo Jima The English Patient The Painted Veil (2006) Planet of the Apes (1968) Blade Runner Jesus Christ Superstar Jaws Brubaker Three Days of the Condor The Candidate Shooter Starman V For Vendetta The Verdict Waterworld The Wizard of Oz Wall Street Flight of the Phoenix (1966) The Ghost and the Darkness Blood Diamond Christian Faith and the Truth Behind 9/11 The New Pearl Harbor Crossing the Rubicon Crossfire: The Plot That Killed Kennedy High Treason The Assassination of Robert F. Kennedy: The Conspiracy and Cover Up The Revolution: A Manifesto Confessions of an Economic Hitman Burning All Illusions On Bended Knee The Secret Team Critical Path Dracula Christine 
 
Labels
 
 9/11 (263) Afghanistan (926) Africa (559) American Tyranny (4606) Animal Cruelty (342) Brazil (84) Britain (397) Bush (279) Business (2963) C.I.P. (202) California Fires (21) Chile (45) China (337) Clunkers (15) Colombia (51) Czech Republic (18) Draft (141) Earmarks (37) Education (725) Egypt (141) Environment (1594) Ethiopia (20) European Tyranny (926) France (205) Fukushima (49) Germany (151) Greece (101) Guinea (15) Gulf Gusher (137) Haiti (138) Health (1205) Hoaxes (60) Honduras (50) I.E.P. (196) India (181) Indonesia (71) Iran (410) Iraq (823) Ireland (80) Islam (200) Israel (1179) Italy (98) Japan (124) JFK (27) Korea (172) Kyrgyzstan (26) Language (15) Lebanon (80) Leftism (40) Libya (93) Life-Affirming (104) Madoff Scandal (86) Massport (50) Mexico (121) Michael Jackson (17) Middle East (336) MSM (3366) Myanmar (48) Neo-Con Plan (1603) Nigeria (69) Norway (7) Obama (1170) Occupy (45) Pakistan (565) Palestine (537) Palin (109) Philippines (53) Plane Crashes (93) Politics (2593) Prop (541) Religion (277) Russia (349) Saudi Arabia (90) Somalia (170) South Africa (72) South America (473) South Asia (342) Spain (74) Sports (368) Sri Lanka (42) State (1398) State House (163) Sudan (80) Swine Flu (98) Syria (108) Thailand (50) Times Square (24) Turkey (106) U.N. (514) U.S. (6536) Underwear Bomber (41) Venezuela (42) Vietnam (50) War Profiteering (356) Wikileaks (69) Women (516) Yemen (101) Zazi (13) Zimbabwe (51)
	</body>
</document>
