<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008919" url="http://www.howcast.com/videos/218345-How-To-Prevent-Seasickness" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="1" score="0.0011738214054966287" bingtitle="How To Prevent Seasickness | Stomach &amp; Digestion | Howcast.com" webtitle="How to Prevent Seasickness">
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>Step 2: Drink plenty of water before you get on the boat ... $15 New era cap $12 Bikini (Ed hardy,polo) $20 accept paypal or credit card and free shipping ...</description>
	<body>
		Howcast 
 Style Food Tech Recreation Fitness Health Home Family Money&amp;Education Relationships Video Games 
 
 Howcast » Health » Digestion&amp;Stomach Problems » How to Prevent Seasickness 
 
How to Prevent Seasickness

 Tweet Embed Video▾ Now playing video 11 of 24 
 Close Embed Code Size X Playback Auto Play Enable full screen player 
Being sick at home is hard; being sick on a boat is unbearable! Keep seasickness from ruining your vacation.
 
Digestion&amp;Stomach Problems
 View Guide 24 videos Auto-play next video ◀ 

 ▶ 
Steps
 
You Will Need

 Motion sickness medication Water Bread and other grains Apples Bananas Hard candy Dry crackers 
 
 Step 1 
Consider preventive medication

Think preventively. Take an over-the-counter antihistamine 1/2 hour prior to boarding the boat or at the first signs of seasickness. You can also consult your doctor for prescription medication.
 Step 2 
Drink plenty of water before you get on the boat

Drink plenty of water prior to boarding. Dehydration can make you dizzy and cause nausea.
 Tip 
Avoid drinking alcohol, which can cause dehydration and nausea.
 Step 3 
Eat right

Eat right before heading out. Bread and other grains, apples, and bananas are all good choices. Avoid anything greasy or acidic.
 Step 4 
Position yourself where motion is less noticeable

Find a spot on board where motion is least noticeable, such as the inner-middle part of the boat.
 Tip 
A window can help put the rocking motion into perspective but can also worsen the feelings of nausea as more objects are moving.
 Step 5 
Stare into the horizon

Focus on the horizon and scenery rather than the water or the movement of the boat. If you feel queasy, stand; sitting or lying down can increase nausea.
 Step 6 
Eat hard candy

Suck on hard candy or eat dry crackers to help keep nausea in check.
 Fact 
Did you know? Some people who take long cruises suffer &quot;landsickness&quot; for a few days after their trip as their body readjusts to being on firm ground.
 
 
Comments
 
Featured Guides

 
How to Have a Healthy Pregnancy

18 videos
 
Personal Security&amp;Self-Defense

15 videos
 
Men&apos;s Health

10 videos
 
 
 Mobile About Us Blog Terms Of Service Privacy Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
