<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008815" url="http://www.mosserdesign.net/checklist.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:16" support="17" score="0.03568756369792791" bingtitle="Building a Restaurant, restaurant design, foodservice consultants ..." webtitle="Building a Restaurant, restaurant  design, foodservice consultants Los Angeles">
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000031" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001459" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001471" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Food Service Consultants. These individuals concern themselves with the kitchen (often ... Good design and planning take a great deal of education, time and ...</description>
	<body>
		OUR FREE ZONE
 RESTAURANT TIPS 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Web Sites and Restaurant Design 
 E-mail 
Los Angeles, CA 
 
 
 
 
 Our Restaurant Portfolio 
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
  
 

 
 

 
[ Check List ] [ ADA ] [ Manuals ]
 
 
 

 
 Are you are thinking about building a restaurant? Heres some information on the Design&amp;Construction process to give you a 
 head-start, and some important promotional ideas after your dream is built. Send this page to a friend. 

 
 Construction Documents 
 Typical Drawings 
 Building Codes 
 Special Agencies 
 Finding Consultants 
 Food Service Consultants 
 Certified (or licensed) Interior Designers 
 Architects 
 Misc. Consultants 
 Equipment Suppliers and Dealers 
 Hiring a General Contractor 
 Hiring a Graphic Artist, Web Designer and Publicist 
 

 
 Construction Documents 

 If youre going to build or remodel a restaurant, your general contractor will need a set of scaled construction documents, often called&quot;working drawings&quot;. These documents can be drawn on a CAD system or by hand and consist of space plans, elevations, schedules and details. These drawings are generally prepared by several design 
 consultants and engineers, integrated into one set for submittal to your local building and health department. The list of design consultants and engineers needed to prepare these drawings follows.

 Typical Drawings 

 Here is a list of typical drawings you&apos;ll need for your building contractor (not in order) 

 Cover Sheet with site and project information Demolition Plan, if applicable Store Front Elevations, if applicable Partition/Construction Plan Floor Plan with FF&amp;E (furniture, fixtures&amp;equipment) Environmental Plans for Health Dept. Finish Plans and Schedules Kitchen Equipment Elevations Wall Elevations Exhaust and Make-up Air Plan Refrigeration and Curb Plans Plumbing and Electrical Rough-in Plans Detail Drawings for custom cabinetry and fixtures Furniture and Equipment Specifications Reflected Ceiling Plan Electrical and Telephone Plans Title 24, California Only Mechanical Plan / HVAC Plan Door, Window and Ceiling Details 

 Top 

 Building Codes 

 All your plans, drawings and specifications should be in compliance with the building and health codes that are applicable to your location. 
 If 
 your project is in California, the governing building codes are Title 24, the Uniform Building Code (UBC), Uniform Mechanical Code (UMC); and Uniform Plumbing Code (UPC). California Health Code governing restaurants is the California Uniform Retail Food Facilities Law (CURFFL). 

 Your drawings, plans, equipment and finish specifications should be approved by the following regulatory agencies: 

 County Health Department Dept. of Building and Safety Fire Marshall 

 Special Agencies 

 Depending on your type of restaurant, equipment and geographical location, you may need approvals from: 

 An air quality board such as the So. Calif. Air Quality Management District (SCAQMD) in Southern California An architectural review board or city planning commission. 

 And please remember, whether you are building new or remodeling, your restaurant must comply with the Americans with 
 Disabilities Act. as overseen by the United States Department of Justice. 

 Top 
  

 Finding Consultants 

 Its a good idea to engage the services of various design professionals and food service consultants to help design and build your 
 restaurant. Their expertise and guidance can help you save a great deal of time and money while also providing an attractive and functional restaurant.  

 As you probably already know, the first rule to hiring anyone is getting referrals from past clients and ask those clients lots of questions! How much experience did the consultant have in planning their type of facility? Did the consultant save the client money? Did they perform in a professional manner? Were they ethical? Did they do the work on time and on budget? Were their design solutions appropriate to the project? Would they hire the consultant again? 

 Food Service Consultants 

 These individuals concern themselves with the kitchen (often referred to as&quot;back of the house&quot;). They will space plan your 
 kitchen and service areas, recommend the best equipment for your menu and budget and give full specifications for the equipment you&apos;ll need. They generally do not sell equipment, so you should be getting an 
 impartial opinion. A good food service consultants plans and specs should give enough information to get your plans approved by the local health department, secure bids from equipment dealers and general 
 contractors. It&apos;s best to seek individuals with experience and a good reputation. Some food service consultants may become members of the Food Service Consultants Society International (FCSI). 

 Certified (or licensed) Interior Designers 

 Certified (or licensed) Interior Designers can plan for any part of your restaurant (for nonstructural work) and can usually submit plans to local building departments for permits. Generally, they perform all the design work your customers see, (also known as&quot;front of the house&quot;). The areas covered are exterior, entry, dining rooms, bars, eating counters and public restrooms. In California, designers certified by the California Council for Interior Design Certification (CCIDC) are the only recognized interior design professionals in the state (as defined in California Business&amp;Professions Code). Seek the services of a Certified or licensed interior designer that has prior restaurant design experience. 

 Top 

 Architects 

 These professionals can plan for any part of your restaurants structural or seismic building elements, usually utilizing the services of a 
 Structural Engineer, and submit plans to the Dept. of Building and Safety. Some architects also do interior design work. In California, check with the Board of Architectural Examiners (BAE) in Sacramento for license 
 verification. Also, ask for references and portfolios for the restaurants they have successfully completed. 

 Misc. Consultants 

 In addition, you may need the services of 

 Electrical Engineers Mechanical Engineers Lighting Consultants Acoustical Consultants Audio Consultants 

 All the above consultants will work together on your behalf to produce a complete set of bid plans to submit to a general contractor, 
 purchasing agent or dealer (prior to construction) so you can get an idea of cost and time involved for the opening of your restaurant. 

 Equipment Suppliers and Dealers 

 These individuals or firms sell just about everything needed for the restaurant kitchen -- from heavy equipment to tabletop goods. Some 
 equipment dealers also offer design and construction (turnkey services). These are valuable services which cost the dealer time and money to produce. Good design and planning take a great deal of education, time and 
 experience. Please beware of deals that sound too good to be true, such as free design with purchase of equipment. You may not get the quality of design and services you need, and may run the risk of paying 
 too much for your kitchen equipment. 

 Top 

 Hiring a General Contractor 

 Be sure you hire a licensed general contractor who has good references and has experience in building restaurants. A residential contractor 
 or one who has built office buildings and has no restaurant experience could cost the restaurant owner in lost time, quality of workmanship and price overruns. 

 If your project is going to be in California, be sure to verify the G.C.&apos;s current active license with the California Contractors State License Board . This Board has published a free booklet entitled&quot;What You Should Know Before You Hire a Contractor&quot;. Please call (800) 321-2752. 

 When hiring a general contractor, also make sure the contractor provides you with certificates of insurance for Workman&apos;s Compensation and 
 General Liability (photocopies should not be accepted. Ask the contractor to have their insurance agent send them directly to you). 

 Hiring Other Professionals 

 When hiring all professionals, be sure to see their portfolios of work; ask for references, discuss their credentials, and 
 be clear on the scope of work you want them to provide you. The following three professionals work can give you lasting value in establishing your public image, distributing your message and promoting your business. 

 Graphic Artist - for your logo, menus, stationery and other miscellaneous printed promotional material. 

 Web Site Designer - Do you really need a web site? 

 Publicist - Youve spent lots of time and money planning and executing your dream. Dont believe the myth, if you build it--they will come. (Well, maybe if you have a prime location and your name is Wolfgang.) Even if your investors are high profile celebrities or your chef does cartwheels in the creme brulee, customers have to be clued into this phenomenon. 

 A publicist will send press releases to newspaper and magazine editors, restaurant critics, radio personalities and related Web sites. 
 She/he will begin the buzz and leave their mouths craving for more. Your customers are continually looking to taste the newest trends or bite into brisket like mama made. 
 A good publicist knows theres more news than whats on the menu. Press releases related to design and construction are sent to related trade publications and overcoming business obstacles and financing are sent to business editors.  Everyone is hungry now .  
 

 
 
 Top      
 
 

 
[ Check List ] [ ADA ] [ Manuals ]
 

 
 

 
[ Home ] [ Restaurants ] [ Web Sites ] [ About Us ] [ Site Map ]
 
  
 Site Design&amp;All Content are Copyrighted by MOSSER DESIGN .
 Copyright 1984-2010. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
