<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008370" url="http://www.appolicious.com/tech/articles/10127-augmented-reality-apps-could-become-a-little-too-real" time="2012-07-13-01:51" support="4" score="0.008696852844279502" bingtitle="Augmented reality apps could become a little too real - iPhone app ..." webtitle="Augmented reality apps could become a little too real - iPhone app article - Dan Kricke  | AppoliciousiPhone and iPad App Directory">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>Now, most of us just want to know the number to the ... reality where I order a cheeseburger at a fast food restaurant ... download the app and then point it at my food, but ...</description>
	<body>
		Appolicious–Find Mobile Apps You&apos;ll Love in association with 
 Trending: action games games adventure games temple run 
 
 Join 
 Sign In with Yahoo! 

 Already a member? Log in 
 
 iPad&amp;iPhone Apps Android Apps Directory Recommended Build your library News Reviews Lists Best apps 
 
 Check out our new games page for in-depth reviews, price cuts and hot apps! 
 Search Appolicious Advisor 
Augmented reality apps could become a little too real

Posted November 6, 2011 4:00pm 
 
 by Dan Kricke Tags: Augmented Reality 
 Apps mentioned: 
 
 Tweet 
 Ever since the Terminator movies (and probably before them, too) man has been obsessed with one goal: to put a lot of additional information on the same dimensional plane as the thing he is looking at directly.

Schwarzenegger’s Terminator could look at you and determine whether you were hostile or not. Now, most of us just want to know the number to the restaurant we’re pointing our iPhones at. But the idea remains the same.

For the most part, this has worked out well in the iPhone age. An app like SkyView – Explore the Universe ($1.99) lets us see the stars over our heads even if the night sky we live under is too bright to broadcast them normally. As a city dweller, I really do appreciate the thought, even if it’s a little like pretending you saw something you can’t actually see.

 Now, Flow Powered by Amazon (free) has been released and I’m feeling slightly nervous. Flow gets awfully close to an information overload that I don’t want any part of. The app lets you pick up an item you could find at Amazon, like a book or video game, and it will show you the price it sells for on Amazon and provide you a link to buy it immediately.

As a stand-alone feature, that’s pretty cool. If you have the patience to wait for something to be shipped to you, you’re likely to save a few bucks on it by not walking out the door with it in your hand. That’s smart.

But where does it stop? How far away am I from a reality where I order a cheeseburger at a fast food restaurant and point my phone at it only to recoil at the nutritional information that pops up on the screen?

I realize this entire thing is a bit of a straw man argument because I’d have to willingly download the app and then point it at my food, but just the idea that I might have a friend who would do exactly that while I’m eating and leave me to deal with the guilt ridden consequences, is enough to unsettle me a bit.

 It’s not just food, either. For every SpyGlass ($0.99), an innocuous AR app that provides real compass directions for you wherever you are, there’s a SpotCrime ($2.99). SpotCrime takes the crime blotters you might read on the web and then overlays those crimes right on the city streets you’re looking at.

I did plenty of research before moving to my home, so I was aware of the general crime that’s expected in the area, but it’s a pretty heady thing to “see” it on your actual block. And as a nosy person, an app like SpotCrime would be a lot harder not to use regularly.

I guess sometimes I just want to be saved from my own neurosis, and the more we get into Terminator territory, the less I’m able to do so. I guess I’ll go drown my fears in a big, greasy cheeseburger. And I’ll leave my iPhone in the other room. You know, just in case.
 Dan Kricke 
 Bio  |  More Articles 
 Apps discussed in this article 
 SkyView - Explore the Universe , Flow Powered by Amazon , Spyglass , SpotCrime 
 Share: Tweet 
 Comments: Leave a comment Email me updates 
 
 nvnusman 
 
Well, it turns out there&apos;s an app for that, the very first app, in fact: Knowledge. It is coded in real-life experience and licensed under the school of hard knocks.

Sorry, it&apos;s not a free app, but it IS crowd-sourced! It costs nothing financially, unless you are really screwing up, then there are legal fees.

System requirements:

A functioning brain, still capable of learning; ears for actually listening; eyes for actually observing, a mute function for an over-eager mouth.

Terabytes of memory, to accommodate the millions of tiny observations made each day.

A sense of humor, to interpret all the stupid things you encounter each day.

Patience, knowing that answers don&apos;t just pop up on Google: You gotta work for them.

And a sense of Realism: Hey, the Rest of Us are looking for the Same Answers!
 Reply to comment Posted November 06, 2011 
 Ask_a_Concierge 
 
Augmented reality is great, we have integrated this functionality in our iPhone App called &quot;Winery Finder&quot; http://econcierges.com. Users love this feature and have made our App quickly shoot up to be the #1 downloaded App for Wine Country. You can use augmented reality to find wineries you.
 
 Associated Apps:   Winery Finder&amp;Tasting Pass Finder: Napa Valley – Sonoma - Wine Country - San Francisco 
 Reply to comment Posted November 07, 2011 Follow us: Facebook and Twitter 
advertisement
 Related Apps 
 SkyView - Explore the Universe Flow Powered by Amazon Spyglass SpotCrime 
 Facebook Activity 
advertisement
 
Connect with Appolicious
 Become a fan on Facebook Follow @appolicious on Twitter 
More from Appolicious

 Android Apps AppVee Appolicious Android app 
 
Advertising Opportunities

Appolicious offers great opportunities for app developers and corporate advertisers. Click here to learn more
 
©2012 Appolicious Inc. All rights reserved. This website is owned and operated by Appolicious Inc. Appolicious collects information you provide on this website. To learn more, please read the Appolicious Privacy Policy .
 
 Discussions Site Map FAQ About Us RSS Directory Questions or Comments Terms&amp;Privacy Media Inquiries Help Yahoo! News Network
	</body>
</document>
