<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008081" url="http://www.hellooperator.com/business_search/?what=Carry%20Out&amp;tag=11247&amp;query=Carry%20Out" time="2012-07-13-01:09" support="1" score="0.0018717503471712283" bingtitle="Results for Carry Out in Jamaica, NY - HelloOperator.com" webtitle="Results for Carry Out in Kassel, 05 - HelloOperator.com">
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>Carry Out Business Listings in Jamaica, NY and ... This Cajun-style fast food restaurant first opened in New Orleans ... I called and placed an order (had to repeat my ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurants | Bars | Spas | Hotels | Shopping 
 
 Search Again Sponsored Results 
Related Products
 ﻿ Kassel 
 Kassel 450Mm Wood Wine Globe On Stand 
 Avg Price: $387.68 3 feet tall 22&quot; in diameter. Lift the lid of the 450mm (17-1/2&quot;) globe and ... Traitor 
 Kassel 80Mm Dark Blue Globe Paper Wt 
 Avg Price: $38.70 Features dark blue crushed mother-of-pearl oceans and semi-precious stone l... Movies: Greatest Hits 
 Avg Price: $7.99 All products are BRAND NEW and factory sealed. Fast shipping and 100% Satis... Madden Men&apos;s M-Kassel Boot,Black Distressed,10.5 M US 
 Avg Price: $70.00 Steve Madden, the company, was founded by Steve Madden, the man, in 1990 in... Testees: The Complete Series 
 Avg Price: $24.98 Peter (Steve Markle) and Ron (Jeff Kassel) are two down-on-their-luck best ... Deltas 
 Kassel Musical Pendulum Clock 
 Kassel Musical Pendulum ClockWeight: 3 GMLength: 10 INWidth: 4 INHeight: 19... Kassel Italian Hand Painted Globe Bar 
 Avg Price: $522.76 Open from its hinged meridian to reveal antique replica fresco inside. Wrap... FREE LISTING HERE Our 
 HelloFrankfurt.com Business Account Register 
Signup for a free account on HelloFrankfurt.com
 
Individual Account

Create your free account on HelloFrankfurt to get a customized experience, upload photos, and more.
 Get Started 
Artist Account

Connect with the thriving art community in Frankfurt. Post your art work and organize by tags you create.
 Get Started 
Business Account

With a local business account you can create a space and share with your patrons on a local favorite, HelloFrankfurt.com
 Get Started 
Band Account

Creating a band page is easy. Share your music, photos and upcoming gigs with all of your fans. Connect with other local musicians.
 Get Started Find Businesses ©HelloOperator.com 2012 | 
 Privacy | Contact
	</body>
</document>
