<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008174" url="http://www.dailyinterestingfacts.com/food/facts-about-nutrition.html" time="2012-07-13-01:39" support="1" score="0.0005017927599006767" bingtitle="10 Interesting Facts About Nutrition | Daily Interesting Facts" webtitle="10 Interesting Facts About Nutrition | Daily Interesting Facts">
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>Meal slow, eat low. Looking for effective diet tips ... producers have increased, the total number is not yet sufficient to balance the dominance of fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Daily Interesting Facts Interesting Facts Around the World 
 Home About Contact Disclaimer Privacy Policy Sitemap 
 
 10 Interesting Facts About Nutrition 
 Posted by admin1 - July 21, 2011 - Posted in: Food 
What we eat is interpreted in our body. We look healthy if we eat good and healthy food, but we will look otherwise if we eat foods with low nutrition. Nutrition is absolutely needed by our body to keep healthy and doing our activities. There are some nutrition facts that perhaps we don’t know. The following is mentioned 10 interesting facts about nutrition.

 1. Healthy food fact 

 

We are required to eat a healthy diet or menu to maintain the condition of the body including the organs remain in good condition. The recommended healthy diet should have a variety of natural colors and non-synthetic. The more bright colors that exist in our food, then the better to consume. It’s also good to include greens, beans, veggies, even chilies in our daily menus.

 2. Junk foods facts 

 

Junk Food is now mostly found almost in over the world. Compared with healthy food, junk food or fast food certainly is not recommended for consumption because of its very low nutrient levels and high calories. Junk food tends to replace other more nutritious foods. When people drinking lots of soda for example, they’re usually not getting plenty of mineral water or other healthful beverages like green tea or orange juice. When they’re snacking on chips or cookies, they’re likely not loading up on fruits and vegetables. However, according to UCLA Center for Human Nutrition research, In USA, 1/3 percent of its total population fuel 47 % of their calories need from fast foods. In other words, 1 out of 4 Americans takes junk foods once per day.

 3. Calorie fact 

 

In nutrition, what we talk of as “calories” are really kilo calories – enough energy to raise the temperature of a kilogram of water by 1°C. The amount of calories needed by people is defferent depends on age, gender, height, weight, goals, body composition and metabolic rate. Compare to Americans who lived in 1985, we are now eating 300 more calories than they are. Compare to kids who live in 1985, our kids consume more cereals compose greater calories or saltier, sweeter, but lesser fibers. Another fact is that we burn more calories while we are sleeping than watching TV.

 4. Unburned Calories 

 

Burning calories needs to happen every day to balance the levels of calories in the body. Calorie is like coal, it will burden us if we do not burn it. If we collect 100 calories surplus every day and we save it one year, what would happen? Those calories will be  10 pounds of  fat in the last date of the year.

 5. Extra benefits of Exercises 

 

Burning calories happens all day and all night long even when you are just breathing. Some activities burn more than other for example exercises. In fact, in addition to burn more calories and make us health and fit, exercises also will make us feel healthier, relax, positive and comfortable. These feeling are rewards from our brain. Doctor says, endorphins that makes it happenwill make us feel healthier, relax, positive and comfortable. These feeling are rewards from our brain. Doctor says, endorphins that makes it happen.

 6. A Benefit of Green Tea 

 

Green tea is one of the benefit plants for our body. By drinking recommended amounts of green tea, the human body is cleansed from toxins that usually cause a lot of health problems. According to Victoria Maizes, an executive director and professor from the University of Arizona College Of Medicine, Arizona, drinking 10 cups of green tea every day account to cancer onrush delay 8.7 years for Japanese women and 3 years for Japanese men.

 7. Meal slow, eat low 

 

Looking for effective diet tips? One of the simplest but also effective diet tips is just eat your meal not too quick and you will eat less meal. Beside, chewing your food properly will benefit your digestive process.

 8. Fresh Food and Junk foods price tag 

 

To be healthy is actually more expensive than fat. Michael Pollan, a Knight Professor of Journalism from University of California said that cost to purchase fresh veggies and fruits has spiked about 40% in the last quarter decade. At the other side, the cost to buy soft drinks has fallen 23%.

 9. Kids Obesity 

 

Today, many children are found in obesity condition. Even the fattest child in the world, Jessica Gaude, is 222 kg at her age of 7. Although the number of organic nutrients and food producers have increased, the total number is not yet sufficient to balance the dominance of fast food restaurant chain with its  massive branding and cheap service.

 10. Most American Basically eat corn, soy and wheat beside meat 

 
 People who live in rural Australia currently consumes more than 800 varieties of food and vegetables. While in America people give priority to eat three variations of foods made from corn, soybeans and wheat. More varieties of healthy nutrition are healthier and many Americans do not realize it  (information from David Heber of the UCLA Center for Human Nutrition). Hopefully, those nutritional facts can play a role in improving your health. If you have other facts about nutrition, I invite you to share in the comment box below. Source: factsofworld.com and many. 
Tag Clouds:
وجبات دايت, food, nutritious food, picture about nutrition, وجبات, fun facts about nutrient, fun facts about nutrition, healthy food pictures, interesting facts about nutrition
 
Tags: 
 ← Previous Next → 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name *
	</body>
</document>
