<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008111" url="http://www.thegrio.com/specials/the-big-issue/black-america-battles-food-addiction.php" time="2012-07-13-01:12" support="2" score="0.0010142576484023303" bingtitle="The Big Issue: Blacks aren&apos;t immune to food addiction" webtitle="The Big Issue: Blacks arent immune to food addiction | theGrio">
			<query id="000447" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>As she scans the contents of her fridge, she picks up a ... For African-Americans that number is even higher at 45 ... Map: Obesity rates vs. fast food restaurant locations</description>
	<body>
		theGrio 

 

 
 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Home Politics Business Living 
 Health Travel and Leisure 
 Inspiration 
 Living Forward Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Music The Dish 
 News 
 Sports Education Black History 
 
 Search 
Living
 
 
 Mr.&apos;Mood Disorder&apos; 
 
 Tyra Banks is back! 
 
 Spike Lee&apos;s MJ joint 
 
 Gary Oldman as R.Kelly 
 
 
The Big Issue: Blacks aren&apos;t immune to food addiction
 by Mara Schiavocampo | September 22, 2011 at 12:00 PM 
 Comments 
 Print 
 “The Big Issue: Addicted to Food”is the first in a new series on TheGrio, taking an in-depth look at issues affecting the African American community. This particular story takes a fresh look at the rates of obesity and weight-related health problems in the black community by focusing on food addiction. New science suggests that when it comes to weight gain, willpower isn’t the only issue, and that food can be as addictive as alcohol, nicotine, or narcotics. 

Iris Williams is redefining her relationship with food. These days the real estate executive and married mom stocks her kitchen with healthy staples like fruits, vegetables and yogurt.

As she scans the contents of her fridge, she picks up a decadent chocolate bar and waves it triumphantly.

“I haven’t even had any of this, which is remarkable,”she says.“It’s like an alcoholic not taking a drink.”

The comparison between alcoholism and Williams’relationship with food isn’t coincidental. She says that for most of her life, she used food as a drug, and in many ways, became addicted. At nine-years old, Williams weighed 130 pounds. By her 42nd birthday, she tipped the scales at 333 pounds.

“I was using [food] to medicate, I was using it not to deal with life, not to get angry,”she notes.“I couldn’t stop at one piece of cake, it would be three pieces of cake.”

It’s a struggle many can relate to. It’s estimated that more than 30 percent of Americans are obese. For African-Americans that number is even higher at 45 percent. Blacks also have the nation’s highest rates of weight-related health problems like diabetes.

 
 TheGrio Web Extras: 


 theGrio: The urban fresh food fight goes national 

 theGrio: Less grease, more greens: Soul food spots shape up 

 Map: Obesity rates vs. fast food restaurant locations 

 Link: Food Addicts In Recovery Anonymous 

 NewsOne: Top 7 Addicting Foods 

 NewsOne: America’s Worst 9 Urban Food Deserts 

 NewsOne: INFOGRAPHIC: The Cost Of Food Addiction 

 NewsOne: QUIZ: Are You A Food Addict? 



 

For years, the prevailing wisdom has been that overeating is caused by a lack of discipline. But now some in the scientific community say there’s evidence that willpower isn’t the only issue.

Dr. Dana Small from the John B. Pierce Laboratory and Yale School of Medicine studies how certain foods affect our brain’s reward centers. She fed obese, overweight, and slender volunteers small amounts of a milkshake through a tube while they rested inside and fMRI scanner.

Dr. Small found that while drinking the shake, heavier subjects showed different responses in their brain’s reward centers than the other volunteers, suggesting that weight gain had actually changed their brain responses, making them more impulsive when it comes to overeating.

“One of the hallmarks of addiction is brain change,”says Dr. Small.

Dr. Small notes that individual genetics plays a big role, as does the specific foods people are eating. Unsurprisingly, people are unlikely to become addicted to things like carrots or apples. The most troublesome treats are highly processed and refined, much like narcotics.

“Just like with addictive drugs, where you refine a plant, a poppy, to produce opium, so too do you do that with food,”says Dr. Small.“Those foods can pack more of a reward punch. And those foods can become to the brain, perhaps on par with addictive drugs.”

So how does one treat an addiction to something we all need to survive? One group thinks they have the answer. Food Addicts in Recovery Anonymous is a 12-step program addressing physical and emotional ties to food. The group, which has more than 4,000 members, says they manage their addiction by avoiding certain foods, and eating only three measure meals each day. Those who work the program swear it works for them.

“Chuck”used to weigh 420 pounds. After eight years in the program he’s down to 180. He says recovery is not just about weight loss, but about learning to think about food the right way.

“I didn’t like how my life was so I used food as a drug to kind of make me check out of my reality. Now I look to food as just fuel, fuel to get me through the day.”

Though Iris Williams has not joined a formal program, she says she has finally regained control of her eating after a painful wake-up call. Five years ago her father died suddenly of weight-related health problems. That encouraged Williams to have gastric bypass surgery. Now 130 pounds lighter, she says he focus isn’t on food, but living.

“I feel alive. I feel alive. When I was at my heaviest I did feel dead.”

Like so many who struggle with food, Williams is looking towards a brighter future, one free from the weight of addiction
 
 Next Story: 
 Less grease, more greens: Soul food spots shape up 
 Previous Story: 
 Map: Obesity by state vs fast food restaurant locations 
 
 Filed in: Health , Living , Video | Related Topics: Food Addiction , Healthy Eating , Michelle Obama , Obesity , Soul Food 
 
Learn about our User Panel
 Read More 
 Top Stories in Living

 Usher’s stepson: Brain death explained ‘Yes, I use the n-word’ Gabrielle Union: Did Dwyane Wade’s divorce hurt her career? 17-year-old dancer defies stereotypes Style Watch: Venus Williams is picture perfect in summer yellow trend Meet the black publisher behind the Kardashian family’s books Slideshow: Beyoncé steps out in short shorts The case for accepting out of wedlock births 
 
 New Stories on theGrio

 Will Smith may bring Biblical story to big screen Beanie Sigel headed to jail Happy 75th birthday Bill Cosby! Report: 8 percent of blacks can’t vote because of felonies Higher education may decrease blood pressure Reggie Jackson says A-Rod comments were ‘inappropriate’ Not-so-Dynomite! Jimmie Walker slams Obama Brazilian artist catalogues skin tones 
 
LIKE TheGrio
 
Hot on Facebook
 
Category Cloud
 Atlanta Black History Business Chicago Detroit Education Entertainment Health Inspiration Living Los Angeles Miami Money Music News New York Opinion Philadelphia Politics Reviews Service and Activism Slideshow Sports TheGrio&apos;s 100 TheGrio&apos;s 100 Women Top Stories Travel and Leisure Video Washington DC 
More from theGrio
 
 
More Stories on theGrio
 
Top News
 
Politics

 
 Report: 8 percent of blacks can&apos;t vote because of felonies 
 
 Not-so-Dynomite! Jimmie Walker slams Obama 
 
 Biden to NAACP: Obama stands by convictions 
 
 Mr.&apos;Mood Disorder&apos; 
 
 »Read More in Politics 
Business

 
 Wells Fargo to pay $175M in lending settlement 
 
 Women with natural hair: Still facing job discrimination? 
 
 Jobless claims lowest in 4 years 
 
 Can GOP campaign on cutting gov&apos;t jobs? 
 
 »Read More in Business 
Living

 
 Higher education may decrease blood pressure 
 
 The best over-the-counter creams for eczema and psoriasis 
 
 Oprah&apos;s father accused of threatening to kill wife 
 
 Kandi and NeNe may get physical on new season of&apos;Housewives&apos; 
 
 »Read More in Living 
Inspiration

 
 Happy 75th birthday Bill Cosby! 
 
 Brazilian artist catalogues skin tones 
 
 Art and fashion help empower orphans in Haiti 
 
 17-year-old dancer defies stereotypes 
 
 »Read More in Inspiration 
Entertainment

 
 Will Smith may bring Biblical story to big screen 
 
 Beanie Sigel headed to jail 
 
 Twitter falsely reports Eddie Murphy died...again 
 
 Drake and Keke Palmer co-star in new&apos;Ice Age&apos;movie 
 
 »Read More in Entertainment 
News

 
 Reggie Jackson says A-Rod comments were&apos;inappropriate&apos; 
 
 FAMU still dealing with hazing death fallout 
 
 Slain NJ cheerleader allegedly knew her killer 
 
 Prep hoops star Jabari Parker names 10 college choices 
 
 »Read More in News 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Politics Business Living Inspiration Entertainment News 
 
 Help Terms of Service Privacy Policy Advertise with TheGrio About 
 ©2012 NBCUniversal Powered by WordPress.com VIP
	</body>
</document>
