<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008294" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/starbucks-coffee-garland-172773" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="2" score="0.002920030620404122" bingtitle="Starbuck&apos;s Coffee - Reviews &amp; Menu - 6075 Broadway Blvd, Garland 75043" webtitle="Starbuck&apos;s Coffee - Reviews&amp;Menu - 6075 Broadway Blvd, Garland 75043">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>... Starbuck&apos;s Coffee is a Coffee &amp; Tea, Breakfast, and Fast Food restaurant ... for the drinks, even five dollars or more. I don’t pay an extra five bucks for pouring a cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 Starbuck&apos;s Coffee Menu 

 Starbuck&apos;s Coffee Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Garland Restaurants » Coffee&amp;Tea » Starbuck&apos;s Coffee Share | 
Starbuck&apos;s Coffee
 
 3.0 star rating           
  3.0 rating over 1 review 
 (972) 303-3723 

 6075 Broadway Blvd ( ) 

 Garland , TX 75043 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (1) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Starbuck&apos;s Coffee is a Coffee&amp;Tea , Breakfast , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go , paid less than $10 , and tipped less than 15% . Tags: Coffee&amp;Tea, Breakfast, Fast Food, Delivery, American, Coffee, and Tea Stats: 
 351 dishes entered by diners at Starbuck&apos;s Coffee 
 Tips: 
 Purchase a Starbucks customer card and use it to receive fun rewards, like a free tall beverage when you buy a pound of coffee beans. The Starbucks logo, a two-tailed mermaid, was based on a 16th century Norse woodcut, and supposed to be as seductive as coffee itself. 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Starbuck&apos;s Coffee? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Starbuck&apos;s Coffee
 Write a review 
 1 review First reviewed by FordF150STX 
 
 0 helpful votes over 1 review 
 FordF150STX 
 1 Restaurant Review 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Starbuck&apos;s Coffee FordF150STX 
 May 9, 2011 
 3.0 
 3.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Drive thru Tips
 
Good guest service, good drinks, but I feel like I get robbed every time I go there, the teller almost always try to keep my change for the drinks, even five dollars or more. I don’t pay an extra five bucks for pouring a cup of coffee.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Coffee of the Day
 
 3.0 star rating           
 
A little bitter, but strong coffee.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
Best Dishes at Starbuck&apos;s Coffee

These dishes from the Starbuck&apos;s Coffee menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
Caramel Frappuccino® Light Blended Coffee
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Caramel Apple Cider
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Iced Tazo® Green Tea Latte
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Walgreens 
 1 review 1.0 star B&amp;S Guns 
 31 reviews 2.5 stars Castleglen Treehouse Learning Bike World Don Johle&apos;s 
 5 reviews 4.5 stars Rent-A-Center Best Western Lakeview Inn La Quinta Inn&amp;Suites Garland - Harbor Point Crossland Economy Studios Dallas - Mesquite Jazzercise Garland Audubon Recreation Center Broadway Vacuum 
 4 reviews 4.5 stars 
 Starbuck&apos;s Coffee is located near the cities of Scott, Rowlett, Sachse, Minneapolis, and Richardson. People found this by searching for: Starbucks 75043, Area Director Of Starbucks 75043, Coffee Bean Garland, Starbuck Garland Texas, Coffeebean Garland, How To Make Garland Out Of Coffee Beans, 75043 Reviews, Reviews On Starbucks In Garland, Tx 75043, and Starbuck Broadway Garland Tx. 
Featured in Garland
 
 5.0 star rating           
 Maxine&apos;s Chinese Restaurant 
 3.0 star rating           
 Pappadeaux Seafood 
 3.5 star rating           
 Pappasito&apos;s Cantina 
 2.5 star rating           
 Olive Garden 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 172 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Donut Palace Little Caesar&apos;s Pizza Papa John&apos;s Pizza China City Restaurant Subway 
Link to Starbuck&apos;s Coffee
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
