<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008428" url="http://www.ldonline.org/xarbb/printtopic/3173?theme=print" time="2012-07-13-01:54" support="5" score="0.00444427619538374" bingtitle="money in math - LD OnLine: The world&apos;s leading website on learning ..." webtitle="money in math">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>... time with learning to count money or give change. ... girl said when I worked at a fast food restaurant I could never make change. ... the LMB &quot;On Cloud Nine&quot; number line ...</description>
	<body>
		money in math 
 Author Message Anonymous Posted: Wed, 12 February 2003 10:51:58
 Subject:
money in math
 
My son is having a difficult time with learning to count money or give change. The school uses awful plastic coins, but at home we use real coins. This makes a difference because he was confusing plastic nickels and quarters but doesn&apos;t have that problem with real coins. The largest problem that he is having is counting up mixed coins beginning with quarters, such as, 1 quarter, 1 dime, 2 nickels. He will start guessing at numbers from twenty eight to whatever he thinks of. He can&apos;t seem to begin with 25 and count up. Quarters in general give him trouble. He is still trying to remember 2 quarters = 50, and 3 quarters = 75. He can count by tens and fives, but has problems when switching from counting by 10&apos;s to counting by 5&apos;s. He doesn&apos;t have a problem switching from counting dimes to adding in the pennies. (or counting nickels and adding in pennies)
Any tried and true secrets out there that helped your child or students work through learning money? Also, he loves to go in to stores and buy things but it doesn&apos;t seemed to have helped with learning. I have asked for him to give me the money when going through the drive-thru, he enjoys getting the change ready to hand me.
 Anonymous Posted: Wed, 12 February 2003 15:16:05
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
I think it is a lot to keep track of-which coin is worth what and then counting by 5s or 10s.

I would break it down and have him just add the quarters, write it down;just the dimes, write it down. Then add up the numbers. Obviously at some point he has to get past this but maybe it would be a good intermediate step

Asking what comes after 25, before 73-general postional things with numbers under 100 would be a good car activity game. My son can usually recite the alphabet correctly but asking him to start at K or something similar??? Yikes. By 11, this should be a piece of cake but it isnt and Im guessing your son is similar(mine had trouble with quarters as well)

I also wonder if cutting circles that look like the coins size and colorwise and actually writing 10, 25, etc on them would be an aid-take one step out of it for now
 Anonymous Posted: Thu, 13 February 2003 14:42:11
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
My child had the same problem. We went over and over what is a quarter plus a quarter.We wrote out .25 + .25 = .50. We also spent money in vending machines that only took 50 cents to help her realize how much it is.We spent many nights with me holding up a quarter asking how much it worth and having her write it down before we did her homework.Now I should probably ask her again to make sure she retained it.-
 Anonymous Posted: Fri, 14 February 2003 09:11:32
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
Does your child get an allowance or have the opportunity to earn money at home? My LD child learned money long before other math because he was interested in money. I think it was the emotional investment--he saw it as important because he could buy things while other things were not.

Anyway, if he does not have his own money, that would be my suggestion.

Beth
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 11:02:48
 Subject:
This works
 
Here is how I do teach money and I have had good success.

I tell them to start with quarters. I don&apos;t use 50 cent pieces or dollar coins until the end.

First I have them practice with only nickels and dimes counting by 5&apos;s touching the dime two times on each side of the dime and the nickel once. When the child gets this down pat I begin with the big mix.

I chant, 25, 50, 75, 100 many, many times before starting and as a warm up. I start by having the child pick out the quarters, count up. When they get to the magic number (25, 50, 75, 100,) I day ding , ding, ding, like a bell.I have this paper with 25, 50, 75, 100 circled on a mat in front of the child to see visually as well.
I tell them to next pick out any other silver coin (nickel or dime). I teach them to only, only , only count by 5&apos;s. The child touches a nickel once and a dime twice. So by now the child has counted the quarters and other silver. Then the child counts by ones.

I don&apos;t know why, but the ding ding ding like a game show sound has been the trick. I have high school kids come over to tutor my 6th graders. I showed them how to help my students do this making change but the other way up. The high school girl said when I worked at a fast food restaurant I could never make change. Now that you showed me this I can do it. lol.

So making change to a dollar it almost the same. The child starts by saying what the cost of the item is.....the child uses 4 or less pennied to get to the nearest 5.....then uses either a dime or nickel to count up to the magic 25, 50, 75, or dollar saying ding, ding, ding, like a game show bell. PRESTO. With practice they get it. Once the child gets to the magic number, he can only use quarters up to a dollar, or what ever bill used is.

Michelle

Good luck.
Michelle
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 11:07:57
 Subject:
Re: This works
 
oops, I meant to say they chant...25, 50, 75, a dollar, over and over. 25, 50, 75, a dollar. on the above post. I wrote it but somehow it says &quot;protective mom&quot; wrote it. OOPS.
Michelle
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 13:24:58
 Subject:
Re: This works
 
I have my kids do that very same chant, but I&apos;ve never tried the &quot;ding, ding, ding&quot; - I&apos;m going to do that starting this week. I just always start them off at every session with a series of skip counting chants. Once our session is finished, I make sure they chant once again. It takes many, many, many repetitions for it to stick with some kids.

I sometimes have the kids do their chanting with movement. Sometimes it just means that as we&apos;re walking down the hall together, we chant to the rhythm of our walking (I do this with skip counting too). I&apos;ve had two kids chant while jumping on a little trampoline.

For other money work, we play &quot;the penny game&quot;. Have a bunch of pennies, nickels, dimes, quarters, and one dollar bill available along with a pair of dice. Roll the dice. Take that amount of change. You must, each time you take the change, exchange it &quot;up&quot; so that you always have the least number of coins possible. Ex: trade 5 pennies for a nickel, two nickels for a dime, etc. Continue along this way till someone&apos;s able to trade their dollar of change to a $1 bill. That&apos;s the winner.

I like this game because there&apos;s so much opportunity to teach. Kids get to skip count by 5&apos;s and 10&apos;s. I also teach them to just know automatically that, for instance, a quarter, a nickel, and a dime equal $.40. I think it&apos;s important to not only show HOW that&apos;s arrived but also to get them to memorize that combo and many of the others. Through this game, you can also teach many other concepts. You can teach kids to skip count by 10&apos;s starting with any number, 23, 33, 43, etc. I usually have available little cards showing the numbers. When a child is stumped, I show them the number, say 13, then show that to add 10 to the number 13, we increase the 1 to a 2.

Meanwhile, I&apos;ve been doing lots of other place value work so this game is yet another chance to practice that. For kids really struggling, I also have the LMB &quot;On Cloud Nine&quot; number line (it goes from 1-100) laid out so they can refer to that too. Eventually they&apos;re weaned off that need because they can picture the number line in their heads.
 Anonymous Posted: Mon, 24 February 2003 19:09:44
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
Have you tried touch math. Check out there website www.touchmath.com They have a system similiar for the money. You don&apos;t even really need to buy the set. Just put dots on REAL change in increments of 5&apos;s. For example a nickel would be one dot, a dime two dots, a quarter 5 dots etc. And then the child would count the dots and easily transition into the different change. This worked magic on my son. Once he learned the system then he didn&apos;t need the dots. He could visualize them with no problem.

Good luck
 Anonymous Posted: Wed, 12 February 2003 15:16:05
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
I think it is a lot to keep track of-which coin is worth what and then counting by 5s or 10s.

I would break it down and have him just add the quarters, write it down;just the dimes, write it down. Then add up the numbers. Obviously at some point he has to get past this but maybe it would be a good intermediate step

Asking what comes after 25, before 73-general postional things with numbers under 100 would be a good car activity game. My son can usually recite the alphabet correctly but asking him to start at K or something similar??? Yikes. By 11, this should be a piece of cake but it isnt and Im guessing your son is similar(mine had trouble with quarters as well)

I also wonder if cutting circles that look like the coins size and colorwise and actually writing 10, 25, etc on them would be an aid-take one step out of it for now
 Anonymous Posted: Thu, 13 February 2003 14:42:11
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
My child had the same problem. We went over and over what is a quarter plus a quarter.We wrote out .25 + .25 = .50. We also spent money in vending machines that only took 50 cents to help her realize how much it is.We spent many nights with me holding up a quarter asking how much it worth and having her write it down before we did her homework.Now I should probably ask her again to make sure she retained it.-
 Anonymous Posted: Fri, 14 February 2003 09:11:32
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
Does your child get an allowance or have the opportunity to earn money at home? My LD child learned money long before other math because he was interested in money. I think it was the emotional investment--he saw it as important because he could buy things while other things were not.

Anyway, if he does not have his own money, that would be my suggestion.

Beth
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 11:02:48
 Subject:
This works
 
Here is how I do teach money and I have had good success.

I tell them to start with quarters. I don&apos;t use 50 cent pieces or dollar coins until the end.

First I have them practice with only nickels and dimes counting by 5&apos;s touching the dime two times on each side of the dime and the nickel once. When the child gets this down pat I begin with the big mix.

I chant, 25, 50, 75, 100 many, many times before starting and as a warm up. I start by having the child pick out the quarters, count up. When they get to the magic number (25, 50, 75, 100,) I day ding , ding, ding, like a bell.I have this paper with 25, 50, 75, 100 circled on a mat in front of the child to see visually as well.
I tell them to next pick out any other silver coin (nickel or dime). I teach them to only, only , only count by 5&apos;s. The child touches a nickel once and a dime twice. So by now the child has counted the quarters and other silver. Then the child counts by ones.

I don&apos;t know why, but the ding ding ding like a game show sound has been the trick. I have high school kids come over to tutor my 6th graders. I showed them how to help my students do this making change but the other way up. The high school girl said when I worked at a fast food restaurant I could never make change. Now that you showed me this I can do it. lol.

So making change to a dollar it almost the same. The child starts by saying what the cost of the item is.....the child uses 4 or less pennied to get to the nearest 5.....then uses either a dime or nickel to count up to the magic 25, 50, 75, or dollar saying ding, ding, ding, like a game show bell. PRESTO. With practice they get it. Once the child gets to the magic number, he can only use quarters up to a dollar, or what ever bill used is.

Michelle

Good luck.
Michelle
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 11:07:57
 Subject:
Re: This works
 
oops, I meant to say they chant...25, 50, 75, a dollar, over and over. 25, 50, 75, a dollar. on the above post. I wrote it but somehow it says &quot;protective mom&quot; wrote it. OOPS.
Michelle
 Anonymous Posted: Sun, 16 February 2003 13:24:58
 Subject:
Re: This works
 
I have my kids do that very same chant, but I&apos;ve never tried the &quot;ding, ding, ding&quot; - I&apos;m going to do that starting this week. I just always start them off at every session with a series of skip counting chants. Once our session is finished, I make sure they chant once again. It takes many, many, many repetitions for it to stick with some kids.

I sometimes have the kids do their chanting with movement. Sometimes it just means that as we&apos;re walking down the hall together, we chant to the rhythm of our walking (I do this with skip counting too). I&apos;ve had two kids chant while jumping on a little trampoline.

For other money work, we play &quot;the penny game&quot;. Have a bunch of pennies, nickels, dimes, quarters, and one dollar bill available along with a pair of dice. Roll the dice. Take that amount of change. You must, each time you take the change, exchange it &quot;up&quot; so that you always have the least number of coins possible. Ex: trade 5 pennies for a nickel, two nickels for a dime, etc. Continue along this way till someone&apos;s able to trade their dollar of change to a $1 bill. That&apos;s the winner.

I like this game because there&apos;s so much opportunity to teach. Kids get to skip count by 5&apos;s and 10&apos;s. I also teach them to just know automatically that, for instance, a quarter, a nickel, and a dime equal $.40. I think it&apos;s important to not only show HOW that&apos;s arrived but also to get them to memorize that combo and many of the others. Through this game, you can also teach many other concepts. You can teach kids to skip count by 10&apos;s starting with any number, 23, 33, 43, etc. I usually have available little cards showing the numbers. When a child is stumped, I show them the number, say 13, then show that to add 10 to the number 13, we increase the 1 to a 2.

Meanwhile, I&apos;ve been doing lots of other place value work so this game is yet another chance to practice that. For kids really struggling, I also have the LMB &quot;On Cloud Nine&quot; number line (it goes from 1-100) laid out so they can refer to that too. Eventually they&apos;re weaned off that need because they can picture the number line in their heads.
 Anonymous Posted: Mon, 24 February 2003 19:09:44
 Subject:
Re: money in math
 
Have you tried touch math. Check out there website www.touchmath.com They have a system similiar for the money. You don&apos;t even really need to buy the set. Just put dots on REAL change in increments of 5&apos;s. For example a nickel would be one dot, a dime two dots, a quarter 5 dots etc. And then the child would count the dots and easily transition into the different change. This worked magic on my son. Once he learned the system then he didn&apos;t need the dots. He could visualize them with no problem.

Good luck
 
 
http://www.ldonline.org/xarbb/printtopic/3173?theme=print
 
©2008 WETA. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
