<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008264" url="https://litigation-essentials.lexisnexis.com/webcd/app?action=DocumentDisplay&amp;crawlid=1&amp;doctype=cite&amp;docid=70+Tenn.+L.+Rev.+1095&amp;srctype=smi&amp;srcid=3B15&amp;key=d03c14248f304db0e73abe776136433f" time="2012-07-13-01:45" support="1" score="0.00045207267635335443" bingtitle="DESCRIPTIVE TRADEMARKS AND THE FIRST AMENDMENT" webtitle="DESCRIPTIVE TRADEMARKS AND THE FIRST AMENDMENT">
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>... symbol ( ) include &quot;We Don&apos;t Make It &apos;Til You Order It&quot; for Jack in the Box&apos;s fast-food restaurant ... to labels, signs, prints, packages, wrappers, receptacles or ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip over navigation Browse Law Reviews and Treatises Skip over navigation Sign in with your lexis.com® ID to access the full text of this article.   -OR- Order the full text of this article if you do not have a lexis.com® ID.   Price:  US $15.00 (+ tax) Yahoo!®Currency Converter     Subject to Terms&amp;Conditions 
Copyright (c) 2003 Tennessee Law Review Association, Inc.
Tennessee Law Review

DESCRIPTIVE TRADEMARKS AND THE FIRST AMENDMENT



Summer, 2003

70 Tenn. L. Rev. 1095

Author
 Lisa P. Ramsey * 
Excerpt
 

I. Introduction



First Amendment challenges to trademark laws are increasingly common. Scholars have generally expressed concern that the&quot;propertization&quot;of trademark law 1- the increasing tendency to treat trademarks as property-may stifle speech in various respects. 2 Commentators question whether trademark actions based on a theory of dilution violate the First Amendment&apos;s right of free expression. 3 Defendants contend their use of another&apos;s distinctive mark as part of a parody or film title is constitutionally protected expression rather than infringement or dilution. 4 Yet, no one has raised or addressed the basic question of whether the protection of exclusive rights in descriptive trademarks is an unconstitutional restriction of speech under the First Amendment. 5 



A descriptive mark is a word, name, or symbol used to indicate a brand of product or service that also describes the qualities or characteristics of the product or service sold under that mark. The Federal Trademark Act of 1946, 6 more commonly known as the Lanham Act, presently allows applicants to register marks that are&quot;distinctive&quot;of the applicant&apos;s goods or services in commerce, including descriptive marks that have&quot;become distinctive.&quot; 7 For example, the Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) has allowed Fox News Network to register the descriptive phrase&quot;Fair&amp;Balanced&quot;for news-reporting services. 8 The Lanham Act also grants exclusive rights in distinctive marks and permits broad enforcement of these rights against domain name registrants, competitors, and others who use the same descriptive term ...     If you are interested in obtaining a lexis.com® ID and Password, please contact us at 1-(800)-227-4908 or visit us at http://www.lexisnexis.com/ . Search Documents   eg., Environmental Insurance Coverage Under the Comprehensive General Liability Policy See Related Content   Lexis®Web - Beta       
Lexis®Web - The only search engine that delivers free web content specifically from legal sites validated by LexisNexis®attorney editors and includes tools for faster research and more relevant results.
   
 
 
 
   LexisNexis®Products   
 LexisNexis®Services at www.lexis.com LexisNexis®Store LexisNexis®Web Communities 
     Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | Copyright ©2012 LexisNexis, a division of Reed Elsevier, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
