<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008562" url="http://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health/public/heart/obesity/lose_wt/dine_out.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:01" support="8" score="0.03927243435437611" bingtitle="Healthy Eating - NIH Heart, Lung and Blood Institute" webtitle="Healthy Eating">
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000846" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>Tipsheet: Eating Healthy When Dining Out. Regardless of whether you&apos;re trying to lose ... Select foods that are: Steamed in their own juice (au jus) Broiled ; Baked ; Roasted</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content past banner and navigation links 
 U.S. Department of Health&amp;Human Services National Institutes of Health 

 Contact Us Get Email Alerts Font Size 
 
 Accessible Search Form           Advanced Search 
 Search the NHLBI, use the drop down list to select: the entire site, the Health Topics section only, or the News and Resources section. 
 
 NHLBI Entire Site 
 NHLBI Entire Site 1 Health Topics 2 News&amp;Resources 3 
 
 Home » Eat Right » Tips for Healthy Eating On the Go or At Home »Tipsheet: Eating Healthy When Dining Out 
 
 Home Assessing Your Weight and Health Risk Control Your Weight Eat Right 
 Healthy Eating Plan Menus and Menu Planner Food Exchange Lists Shopping Tips Portion Distortion Recipes Daily Food and
Activity Diary Tip Sheets 
 Be Physically Active Healthy Weight Tools Key Recommendations Healthy Weight Resources
for Parents/Families
( We Can! ) Health Professional Resources 
 

 
Tipsheet: Eating Healthy When Dining Out

Regardless of whether you&apos;re trying to lose weight, you
 can eat healthy when dining out, if you know how.

So, if you&apos;re treating yourself to a meal out, here are some tips
 to help make it a dining experience that is both tasty and good for you.

ASK!
 Will the restaurant: 
 Serve margarine rather than butter with the meal? Serve fat-free (skim) milk rather than whole milk or cream? Trim visible fat from poultry or meat? Leave all butter, gravy, or cream sauces off a dish? Serve salad dressing on the side? Accommodate special requests? Use less cooking oil when cooking? 


ACT!
 Select foods that are: 


 Steamed in their own juice (au jus) Broiled Baked Roasted Poached Lightly sauteed 

 

 
 
Healthy Weight Tip

Ask your server how the menu items are prepared. Healthy substitutions like using a red sauce instead of an Alfredo (white, creamy) sauce in Italian dishes are easy to make.
 
Looking for tips on how to order healthy foods when dining out?

 The Aim for a Healthy Weight Pocket Guide to Eating Healthy on the Go features tips on ordering at a variety of American and ethnic restaurants. Its portable size makes it easy to carry in a purse or bag. 
 
 
 

 Twitter         Facebook         YouTube SEARCH | ACCESSIBILITY | READERS&amp;PLAYERS | SITE INDEX | OTHER SITES | PRIVACY STATEMENT | FOIA | CONTACT US | OIG 

 National Institutes of Health    Department of Health and Human Services    USA.gov
	</body>
</document>
