<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008140" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/786136" time="2012-07-13-01:14" support="4" score="0.0073770173857923204" bingtitle="Manresa - a short review - San Francisco Bay Area - Chowhound" webtitle="Manresa - a short review - San Francisco Bay Area - Chowhound">
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>... the missing amuse which i watched nearby tables receive ... to a big party, I was tempted to grab the tray ... they get you out earlier or have gone to a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; San Francisco Bay Area Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
Manresa - a short review
 
We were a few minutes early for our 6:00 res, and thus sat in the sun in their beautiful courtyard with comfy chairs. It would have been a nice place to drink some champagne before dinner, but unfortunately I had to hang on to sobriety for my trip to the airport a couple of hours later. We told the maitre d&apos; we needed to be gone by 8:30 to make the plane, and they alerted our waiter as well.

We ordered the 5 course and the waiter told us we would begin with&quot;a series of snacks and amuse bouche&quot;followed by the bread service as the courses began. There was 1 amuse (a delicious little leaf of crispy kale and a fritter) which I don&apos;t think qualifies as a&quot;series&quot;. I was disappointed.

The bread service consisted of an olive batton - delicious, a salt-topped-brioche - INCREDIBLY buttery, very good hearty sourdough, and a dark multigrain.

I had a glass of Peay Chardonnay from Sonoma, they were out of the Santa Cruz Mountain selection. I&apos;m not a huge Chard fan, but it was the closest white to local. I was disappointed that on my whole trip to Big Sur/Carmel/Monterey I never got any wine more local than Sonoma. $17 for about 4 oz.

We both had the asparagus starter, covered in sesame seeds...it was delicious. I had never had fried mussels before. My husband was convinced they were bad, i think the flavor just changes when you cook them, just like oysters.

My Into the Garden salad was spectacular. I beleive each leaf was a different lettuce or herb and there were TINY radishes, turnips, leeks, etc. The dressing was foam...possibly the best use of the mandatory foam I have seen.

My Tidal Pool was also fabulous. Uni followed by foie....i had to control myself to avoid eye-rolling and simpering like Rachel Ray. The broth was also fabulous. there was abalone as well.

My Spring lamb dish had some very interesting pickled tongue, a delicious piece of loin, and a&quot;confit&quot;of what I took to be leg that was not good, IMO. If I had cooked that, I would have been displeased. My husband&apos;s porcelet I like even less, although he really liked pork loin part of it...neither of us get the appeal of pork belly and fat back.

At this point we recieved a very nice little taste of sorbet/granita prior to dessert. My chocolate dessert w/ chocolate rice krispies was tasty as was my husband&apos;s strawberry affair w/ a cheesecake bite. While perfectly fine, neither of these desserts yelled out&quot;2 Michelin Stars&quot;to me. Oddly, before dessert, the waiter offered me coffee, saying&quot;but I know you have to get to the airport&quot;. I took that to mean if I wanted coffee, it wouldn&apos;t come w/ dessert but would require another 10 minute wait between courses. I thought the pacing was too slow throughout the whole meal.

We were given cookies and salted caramels as parting gifts.

The verdict: It was a very nice meal. It cost just under $300 w/ only one glass of wine and before tip. when I compare it to the last grand meal I had at L20 in Chicago last fall, it falls short. Although it was all quite correct (well except for the missing amuse which i watched nearby tables receive) and everything (except that lamb leg) tasted good...sometimes very good, I didn&apos;t feel any brilliance, no genius, no flavor-burst moments that make you think, oh there&apos;s something special going on in the kitchen.

-----
Manresa Restaurant
320 Village Lane, Los Gatos, CA 95030
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 09:32 AM 
Updated on May 24, 2011

 16 Replies 
 
 
The&quot;Into the garden ...&quot;was spectacular and maybe the best use of foam you&apos;ve seen, but nothing special was going on in the kitchen? That&apos;s the dish that makes me want to go back.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Robert Lauriston on May 23, 2011 09:37 AM 
 re: Robert Lauriston 
yeah, perhaps that&apos;s not the best wording...&quot;special&quot;isn&apos;t a strong enough descriptor. no&quot;magic&quot;perhaps describes my thought? It was a lovely salad, and likely arranged w/ tweezers. I might have come away with a better final verdict if the meal had stoped after the garden and the pool, but the last two courses made me start thinking I&apos;ve had better. But don&apos;t get me wrong...it&apos;s a very nice restaurant, and if I lived in LG and money were no object, I&apos;d go back.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 10:01 AM 
 re: danna 
You just proved my&quot;if dessert is great, nothing else matters&quot;theory. When I read the reports on my tasting menus the desserts always sound kind of pedestrian -- I wonder why? Thanks for the report.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Ruth Lafler on May 23, 2011 10:08 AM 

 re: danna 
Perhaps, is it possible that a certain unavoidable anticipation about having to deal with the SFO and TSA nonsense and a flight schedule could have affected your receptivity, particularly for the later courses?

Myself, I certainly would not back a great restaurant or a play or an opera up against having to get to and through the airport indignities for a red-eye flight.

It would be really great to see a comparison of the great new (since I left there 8 years ago) Chicago restaurant scene with Manresa and others around SF. Putting Manresa aside, I suspect Chicago might come out ahead at the&quot;grand meal&quot;level. I think the next level down is where the Bay Area is shining these days.

-----
Manresa Restaurant
320 Village Lane, Los Gatos, CA 95030
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Thomas Nash on May 23, 2011 11:17 AM 
 re: Thomas Nash 
oh, i think it&apos;s possible that anticipation played a part...but just that I was really psyched about Manresa...sometimes it&apos;s hard to live up to inflated expectations. But no, I was about to fly out of San Jose, not SFO, and it was pretty mellow. I guess I&apos;m one of those crazy people who don&apos;t really mind the TSA, I&apos;m happy to throw my shoes in a box and pose for the camera.

I imagine you&apos;re right about&quot;next level down&quot;, which is what I might have been happier with. Passionate cooking in a relaxed atmosphere is hard to beat. Honestly, I had become a bit weary of multi-course extravaganzas until the above mentioned L2O meal, when I became a fan again.

But really, I don&apos;t want to make too much of my small criticisms. It&apos;s just at those prices I reserve the right to critique w/ a hard eye. We had a nice meal and a nice evening. Manresa is obviously a very fine restaurant.

-----
Manresa Restaurant
320 Village Lane, Los Gatos, CA 95030
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 11:37 AM 
 re: danna 
You didn&apos;t get the egg? That&apos;s one of their signature dishes and certainly one that people rave about.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By 512window on May 23, 2011 11:48 AM 
 re: 512window 
no egg. maybe on the full tasting? do tell...what do they do with egg?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 12:14 PM 
 re: danna 
The Arpege egg is an amuse. If you ask a restaurant to fit a three-plus-hour menu into two and a half hours, it seems likely that they&apos;ll skip some of the off-menu items to make sure the timing isn&apos;t off.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Robert Lauriston on May 23, 2011 02:09 PM 

 re: danna 
egg poached @57C, Vermont maple syrup, chives, whipped cream, sea salt.

It&apos;s served in the egg shell, you eat it with a little spoon. I hate poached eggs. This was fantastic, so good that later in the evening when I encountered a waiter with a tray of twelve of these on his way to a big party, I was tempted to grab the tray and high tail it out the back door.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By 512window on May 23, 2011 05:08 PM 



 
 re: Thomas Nash 
Expectations can kill a meal before it starts. Had expectations throw some buzzkill on a meal at the TFL the first time.

I haven&apos;t had the a la carte menu at Manresa but the tasting menu is excellent...and you might lose something not getting it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ML8000 on May 23, 2011 12:50 PM 

 
 
 re: Robert Lauriston 
My Tidal Pool was also fabulous. Uni followed by foie....i had to control myself to avoid eye-rolling and simpering like Rachel Ray. The broth was also fabulous. there was abalone as well.

=============
Sounded like this dish was pretty magical too.

2 genius dishes out of 5 ain&apos;t bad. No restaurant I&apos;ve been two has done 12/12 genius dishes...not even Pierre Gagnaire. Then again, I have not been to L2O or Alinea.

Manresa remains one of my favorite restaurants anywhere.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Porthos on May 23, 2011 03:11 PM 
 re: Porthos 
Oh, Lord, I still feel full when someone mentions Pierre Gagnaire...I think that may have been when I first started to think maybe i shouldn&apos;t get the biggest tasting...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 07:04 PM 

 
 
 
Did they deliver to get you out by 8:30 as you requested?
If you thought the pace was slow you should have requested they get you out earlier or have gone to a fast food restaurant, or should have dinner whit someone you like :)
I don&apos;t think the veggies in&quot;into the garden&quot;have any&quot;dressing&quot;, the foam are the natural juices of the cooked vegetables in that dish.
I think that is one of the best vegetable dishes I have ever had, an endless parade of vegetables displayed in various forms, a contrast of temperatures, textures, colors, respecting the flavors of each component by not adding a dressing, I think that&apos;s brilliant and genius.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Dumbfoodie on May 23, 2011 03:02 PM 
 re: Dumbfoodie 
As matter of fact, they got me out at 8:00, and that after making me wait 10-15 minutes past my reservation time even though I arrived 10 min early.

You can parse the semantics as you like, but something liquid-y and flavorful, on greens, is&quot;dressing&quot;in my book.

I&apos;m impressed by the passionate dedication of the fans of Manresa, give the amount of umbrage that&apos;s been taken to my exceedingly mild criticisms.

-----
Manresa Restaurant
320 Village Lane, Los Gatos, CA 95030
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danna on May 23, 2011 07:11 PM 
 re: danna 
Manresa could have slipped. That said, I&apos;ve been to TFL a few times and other 2 and 3 star places and Manresa was the most interesting and best executed of any by far.

Had the chef&apos;s tasting menu. Totally off the dial and from left field...molten foie gras cube, tidal pool, aged New York with potato roasted in hay and pine needle ice cream...yes, pine needle ice cream.

Here&apos;s my report: http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/491377 

Regarding service, it&apos;s definitely in the California mode which as a Californian I appreciate very much. I dislike overstuffed French service.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ML8000 on May 23, 2011 07:39 PM 

 re: danna 
Danna, Manresa&apos;s definitely a darling of the board. I went when they first opened and thought it was great. I&apos;ve been back 3 times since (at friend&apos;s requests) and never been impressed. I think it&apos;s slid pretty significantly in the last couple years.

-----
Manresa Restaurant
320 Village Lane, Los Gatos, CA 95030
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By openhelix on May 24, 2011 10:57 AM 

 
 
 
 «Back to the San Francisco Bay Area Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 Manresa [trip report] (7 replies) 1 The Three Best Things I Ate at Manresa [Los Gatos] (6 replies) 2 After Manresa and French Laundry (37 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 10 

 Best place to buy whole lobsters... 

1 minute ago
 
 14 

 4 Hour Layover in San Fran 

4 minutes ago
 
 9 

 Eating at the Bar: Cyrus in... 

5 minutes ago
 
 4 

 Anyone been to the new Second... 

41 minutes ago
 
 12 

 One night in town at the Hyatt... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 2 

 Best Tasting Menu Around $100? 

about 2 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 Easy Dinner Party Dishes See All 36 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » Supertaster Daily: Vegemite » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Campfire Breakfast Toad in the Hole 
 
 »Blogs » Quirky in Queens: Panorama of My Silence-Heart Café » All&apos;Angolo: Tasty Italian Pasta in LA&apos;s Koreatown » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County 
 
 »Discussion » 4 Hour Layover in San Fran » Chicken broth vs stock Info?? » Eating at the Bar: Cyrus in Healdsburg » Best Mediterranean/Middle East in the Valley (Encino, Tarzana, Sherman Oaks) » Christopher&apos;s » Ice Cream Sandwiches in LA? 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;Manresa - a short review&quot;
	</body>
</document>
