<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008532" url="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2011-11-06/k-on-by-the-numbers/sales-of-phenomenon-outlined" time="2012-07-13-01:59" support="2" score="0.0015979257592978" bingtitle="K-ON! by the Numbers: Sales of &apos;Phenomenon&apos; Outlined - News ..." webtitle="K-ON! by the Numbers: Sales of &apos;Phenomenon&apos; Outlined - News - Anime News Network">
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="29"/>
	<description>Number of different tie-in items: Over 1,050; Among ... of 9,000 convenience stores, the Lotteria fast-food restaurant ... prices (again) and that Youth Ordinance Bill ...</description>
	<body>
		USA UK AUSTRALIA MAGAZINE TWITTER FACEBOOK encyclopedia » forum » Login Register 
 » Today&apos;s news » Press Releases » News Archive » Convention reports » Newsfeed 
 
 » Summer 2012 Anime Spotlight / Archives » Upcoming Anime List » Summer 2012 Preview Guide / Archives » Upcoming DVD&amp;Blu-Ray , Manga 
 
 » Features » Hey Answerman! » Shelf Life » The Mike Toole Show » Interviews » Anime News Nina » Astro Toy » House Of 1000 Manga » Reviews » RIGHT TURN ONLY!! » The X Button » ANNCast     and more... 
 
 » Anime ( Top 10 ) » People » Search » Manga ( Top 10 ) » Companies » Compare » Releases » Lexicon    and more... 
 
 » Anime » ANNtv » Trailers » Premium 
 
 Log in Search Register FAQ Usergroups 
 
 » My Anime » Surveys » Chat » My Manga » Contests » Skins » Subscription 
 
 News K-ON! by the Numbers: Sales of &apos;Phenomenon&apos; Outlined
 posted on 2011-11-06 14:25 EST 1.1 million BD/DVDs despite this year&apos;s dip; over 1,050 different items made 
 With the consent of the magazine&apos;s editors, the news site Narinari.com outlined Nikkei Entertainment magazine&apos;s report on &quot;Understanding the K-ON! Phenomenon&quot; on Saturday. Before Nikkei Entertainment&apos;s December issue shipped with the report on Friday, Nikkei already revealed that goods tied to the slice-of-life manga and anime franchise have surpassed 15 billion yen (about US$192 million) in sales:

 Copies of the 39 CDs tied to the two anime seasons sold: 2.8 million Copies of Blu-ray Discs and DVDs sold: 1.1 million Copies of kakifly &apos;s original manga volumes sold: 2.5 million Number of different tie-in items: Over 1,050 

Among the companies that are collaborating with the December 3 opening of the K-ON film are the LAWSON chain of 9,000 convenience stores, the Lotteria fast-food restaurant chain , the Denny&apos;s family restaurant chain, the Universal Studios Japan amusement park , and the Lumine department stores .
Despite the earlier high sales for K-ON , the television broadcaster TBS said in its second-quarter (July-September) earnings report that revenues from the K-ON anime are taking a step back during the current fiscal year, which will end next March. TBS reported that revenues from all anime franchises from the current fiscal year&apos;s first half were 1.022 billion yen (about US$13 million), a drop of 164 million yen (US$2.1 million) from the same period last year.
 TBS did note that the &quot; K-ON! Live Event ~Come with Me!!~&quot; moved over 60,000 DVDs and Blu-ray Discs, and it projects that the K-ON! film will have a positive impact in the second half.
In addition to covering the film&apos;s opening and the overall phenomenon, the current Nikkei Entertainment issue published pieces on the making of the music, the production of the anime itself with the director and writer, and the main voice actresses. Nikkei Entertainment interviewed all five voice actresses — Aki Toyosaki (Yui Hirasawa), Yōko Hikasa (Mio Akiyama), Satomi Satou (Ritsu Tainaka), Minako Kotobuki (Tsumugi Kotobuki), and Ayana Taketatsu (Azusa Nakano). The issue also ran a feature about the current state of anime with interviews with SKE48 idol group member Rena Matsui and the &quot;queen of anime songs&quot; Nana Mizuki .
 Source: Narinari.com via Uri-Sure Matome+ , animeanime.biz 
 discuss this in the forum (14 posts) | bookmark/share with: http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2011-11-06/k-on-by-the-numbers/sales-of-phenomenon-outlined K-ON! by the Numbers: Sales of &apos;Phenomenon&apos; Outlined 
   
 Robert&apos;s Anime Corner Store AAA Anime Distribution Visit AniplexUSA.com Anime Castle 
 Recent Articles The Summer 2012 Anime Preview Guide
 The Summer 2012 Anime Preview Guide is here! Check back every day for previews of all the new shows premiering.
Available now: Utakoi ep 2 - Joshiraku - Tari Tari ep 2 - Lagrange Season 2 - Total Eclipse ep 2 - The Ambition of Oda Nobuna - Arcana Famiglia ep 2 - Humanity has Declined ep 2 - Kokoro Connect - Sword Art Online - Kono Naka ni Hitori, Imōto ga Iru! - Campione! - Moyashimon Returns - Koi to Senkyo to Chocolate - Natsuyuki Rendezvous - Yuruyuri♪♪ - and much more! 2012-07-04 The X Button - Remastered
 Todd gets all prickly about upcoming classic reissues! Then it&apos;s on to Tales of Xillia, Phantasy Star Online 2, and a new game for JoJo&apos;s Consistently Bizarre Adventure. 2012-07-11 Japan : One Year Later
 Rebecca Silverman discusses French publisher Kaze&apos;s anthology of manga stories about last year&apos;s devastating earthquake and tsunami in Japan, with an interview from the fine folks who are publishing it. 2012-07-10 Shelf Life - The Abyss Stares Back
 Erin ponders the void with Tales of the Abyss, takes another crack shot with Golgo and tries very hard to pronounce &apos;Towa no quon&apos;.
Tales of the Abyss 3- 4
Towanoquon Complete Collection
Golgo 13 Collection 4 2012-07-09 more features &amp; columns ... ∨advertisement∨ Recent Press Releases Jul 12 AnimeFest 2012 Guest Announcement: Dai Sato Jul 12 Otakon Welcomes Back Masao Maruyama for 2012 Jul 12 Shin Sasaki to Appear at Otakon 2012 Jul 12 Viz Media Invites Young Fans For Kids Day At 2012 Comic-Con International Jul 11 Section23 Films Announces October Slate more press releases... Recent Reviews Gravity Rush
 Gravity Rush isn&apos;t a smooth trip. At its most intense, it&apos;s chaotic and acutely frustrating. Yet it remains a marvelous, standard- setting creation, and the proof is only a button- press away. A Certain Magical Index Episodes 15- 24 Streaming
 A stretch of episodes that feels a lot more like the slightly padded middle of a series than a big finish. Not that it isn&apos;t still loads of fun. Theatrhythm Final Fantasy
 And Theatrhythm feels so right. These songs, some of which are older than an entire generation of gamers, stoke the fires of such fond memories that any frustration over niggling issues becomes insignificant. That&apos;s nostalgia, yes, but nostalgia has its place. Ōkami- san&amp;Her Seven Companions Blu- Ray + DVD
 The first half is definitely stronger than the second, but if you&apos;re looking for a good laugh and a little escapism, put on your red hood and pop this in the DVD or Blu- Ray player. Fate/ Zero
 Magic- using Masters use Servants in the form of legendary figures to battle one another for the Holy Grail in this Fate/ stay night prequel. Despite some flaws, the series does an excellent, visually impressive job of both telling its own story and setting up what follows. Lupin III: The Woman Called Fujiko Mine
 If you&apos;re going into this expecting wacky hijinks or crazy exploits, you will be disappointed. Lupin the Third: The Woman Called Fujiko Mine is a mature, slightly dark take on the franchise, and it succeeds in bringing new life to it while still remaining faithful to Monkey Punch&apos;s original. Occult Academy Sub.Blu- Ray 1
 A cowardly time traveler and the cynical daughter of an occult- focused academy&apos;s founder team up to try to stop an upcoming alien invasion in this silly, eclectic 2010 comedy/ romance/ horror series. Though usually entertaining, it struggles to find a good balance. Shiki LE Blu- Ray + DVD 1
 A show that, in its first 12 episodes, homes in on the essence of the vampire legend: humankind&apos;s universal, primal fear of death. Shiki is pure, classic horror, and that&apos;s all it needs to be. A Certain Magical Index Episodes 1- 14 Streaming
 Index doesn&apos;t work because it&apos;s new or unique; it works because it&apos;s, well, good . tsuritama Episodes 1- 6 Streaming
 If you took an old- fashioned youth drama, hitched it to a campy 50s sci- fi romp and filtered it through the hipster sensibilities of an indie comedy it might come out looking something like this. more reviews... Random Fun Knights of Ramune - Blast Off!
     
All material Copyright ©1998-2012 Anime News Network. All rights reserved.
 FAQ | Contact us | Staff | Staff openings | Advertise with ANN | Privacy policy 
 @moeka
	</body>
</document>
