<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008763" url="http://thenaturalstep.org/" time="2012-07-13-02:13" support="3" score="0.008326649247730303" bingtitle="The Natural Step" webtitle="The Natural Step">
			<query id="001222" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>In late 2008, a fast-food burger restaurant in Sweden received an odd complaint ... only wanted the fries and toys, she said, and she was annoyed at having to throw the boxes ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Navigation 
 Home 
 Australia Brazil Canada France Italy Japan New Zealand South Africa Sweden United Kingdom USA 
 
 
 Our Solutions 
 Solutions for Business Solutions for Communities Our Programmes and Partners Our Certificate Courses Free Sustainability Toolkits Our Projects 
 Our Approach 
 Applying the Framework Our Research FAQs Glossary 
 Get Involved 
 eLearning Events Global network 
 News&amp;Media 
 Videos In the News Blog Archive Newsletters Media Contact 
 Resources 
 Free Sustainability Toolkits 
 About Us 
 Our Story Our People Join Our Team Contact Us 
 
 
LATEST NEWS
 
 Sans langage commun, il est plus difficile pour les collectivités de planifier efficacement vers la durabilité Thursday, 12 July 2012 | Submitted by Alexandre Magnin 
 

Le terme«développement durable»est beaucoup utiliséde nos jours. Mais quel est cetétat de durabilitéqu’un mode de développement durable permet d’atteindre? Comment reconnaitrions-nous une entreprise ou une collectivitédurable si l’on en voyait une? Comment mettre enœuvre un mode de«développement durable»ensemble lorsque certains intervenants comprennent«environnement», d’autres«vert», d’autres«écologie», d’autres«social»? L’absence d’un langage commun peut poser un défi particulièrement difficile pour les collectivités qui doivent rassembler et faire travailler ensemble des acteurs multiples et variés.
 read more Want policy changes? Sound the fire alarm Monday, 09 July 2012 | Submitted by Regina Hauser 
 

Bob Willard, author of“ The Sustainability Advantage ”and several other books on business and sustainability, is a shrewd observer of human nature.

In a full conference room Willard suggested that people consider moving to the conference room next door–it had the same amenities as this one, but with a little more comfort. No one moved. He then went on to suggest that if he said a $5 bill was sitting on each chair, some people would move, but not everyone. However, if a fire were to break out in the room, people would finally move.
 read more National Post/Mediaplanet: Green Innovations, Making Canada a Green World Leader - Panel of Experts interview with Chad Park Thursday, 28 June 2012 | Submitted by Chad Park 
 

 The following interview with  Chad Park , Executive Director of The Natural Step Canada, appeared in the Mediaplanet Special Report on Green Innovations in the National Post on June 27, 2012.
 

 What is the future of green innovation in canada? 

With increasing demand on natural systems and resources, combined with an eroding capacity of natural systems to provide these resources, the opportunities for green innovation can only increase. The challenge for Canadian society will be how to create the conditions for more organizations to realize and grasp the opportunities. This will require creative approaches to collaboration; organizations that don’t typically work together to do so need to find new ways to overcome barriers or identify opportunity. 
 read more “Humans should not be outsmarted by cockroaches.” Reflections from The Natural Step’s Level 1 Sustainability Course Friday, 22 June 2012 | Submitted by Neil McCallum 
 A full house greeted Karen Miller and Brendan Seale , Sustainability Advisors with The Natural Step Canada, on Tuesday 12th June. They were leading The Natural Step Level 1 Sustainability Course: Foundations in Strategy at the Evergreen Brickworks in Toronto. Attending were 35 students and one storyteller. They ranged in age from newly graduated Millenials to a retired perennial (me). There were ring-bearing engineers and NGO representatives, management consultants and motivational speakers, all wanting to know more about The Natural Step Framework for Strategic Sustainable Development , and how to apply it.
 read more 
 more news Latest news and events 
 
 

 
Events
 
 IMPACT! Sustainability Champions Training Program for Emerging Leaders (Ottawa, ON) Thursday, August 16, 2012 Last week to apply for&quot;not to miss&quot;opportunity: The Natural Step Canada’s MBA Sustainability Leadership Bootcamp (Toronto, ON) Monday, August 27, 2012 Course: Innovation for Sustainability (in Gothenburg) Tuesday, August 28, 2012 FREE Introduction to Strategic Sustainability for Business in Canada (Webinar) Wednesday, September 12, 2012 IMPACT! Sustainability Champions Training Program for Emerging Leaders (Montreal, QC) Thursday, September 13, 2012 IMPACT! Sustainability Champions Training Program for Emerging Leaders (Vancouver, BC) Thursday, September 27, 2012 IMPACT! Sustainability Champions Training Program for Emerging Leaders (Guelph, ON) Saturday, November 03, 2012 
 
 



 CONTACT   CHANGE COUNTRY   SITE MAP Some rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
