<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008154" url="http://www.restaurantica.com/on/streetsville/osmows-grill/23016462/" time="2012-07-13-01:15" support="14" score="0.050778119086880166" bingtitle="Osmow&apos;s Grill: Streetsville, ON | Restaurant Reviews &amp; Menus ..." webtitle="Osmow&apos;s Grill: Streetsville, ON | Restaurant ReviewsMenus | Restaurantica.com">
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000985" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>Well, it&apos;s a FAST FOOD restaurant! Do you go to McDonald to ask for a glass of wine? ... Not a place to sit down comfortably as it is very small but really good for a cheap ...</description>
	<body>
		What? Where? Join Restaurantica  Sign Up 
 Your Page 
 
 Register Login Français Help 
 
 Home Ontario Restaurants Streetsville Restaurants Osmow&apos;s Grill 
 Be the first to add a photo! Upload 
 
Osmow&apos;s Grill
 3.5 stars ( 48 reviews, average rating: 2.9/5) Cuisines: Grill (905) 826-6021 251 Queen Street South Streetsville , ON L5M 1L7 Neighbourhoods: Streetville 
 
 Write a Review Map it! 
 
 Yes No 
 Recommend Restaurant? 46 people have voted 85% of voters recommend Bloglink! If you&apos;ve reviewed this place on your blog, Add your review to this page! Restaurant Details Price range $$ ($11-$25) Are you the owner? 
 Claim this restaurant now! Incorrect business info? Let us know! 
 Restaurant Reviews 48 Himself 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 next 
 10 Reviews 2011/06/17 
 If anyone knows shawarma, Osmow&apos;s does Reviewed by CharlesSuChinChen Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 4.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 1 
 
I&apos;ve visited Osmow&apos;s since grade 9 and 8 years later it&apos;s still the same place with the same food that you can rely on to be absolutely fabulous. The only time I&apos;ve tried better shawarmas are homemade shawarmas. Yes, I understand the restaurant is small, but it&apos;s Streetsville! Why are we asking for so much? Service is bad? Well, it&apos;s a FAST FOOD restaurant! Do you go to McDonald to ask for a glass of wine? No.
 Order: Chicken Shawarma 
   Comment (0) 4 Reviews 2011/05/20 
 Been going for many years now Reviewed by Flukej Overall 3.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 3.0 stars Atmosphere 3.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 5 
 
Been frequenting Osmow&apos;s Grill since the first week it opened up. It has changed a lot over the past several years. The service has improved over the last year although you must choose wisely when you are going. Not a place to sit down comfortably as it is very small but really good for a cheap/quick meal. Their hot sauce is very good and the shawarmas are definately one of the best in the area.
 Order: Chicken Shawarma, Philly Cheesesteak 
   Comment (0) Presented by Nearby Restaurants: 
 The Curve 
 905-804-9582 55 City Centre Dr, Mississauga, ON, L5B1M3 
 Barber House Restaurant 
 4.0 stars 2 reviews 905-858-7570 5155 Mississauga Rd, Mississauga, ON, L5M2L9 
 
 6 Reviews 2011/04/25 
 Good Food Reviewed by OmyG Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 3.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 1 
 
I&apos;ve been going to Osmows for years when I was living in Mississauga. The shawarmas are always good. Their hot sauce is probably the best out their. I&apos;ve been to that other place down the street pita nuty (nutso) can&apos;t remember but their hot sauce is like spicy ketchup lol. Anyways I would recommend Osmows over any shawarma places. If your in a rush just call ahead and order your food. Instead of 30 minutes wait time it will be like 10-15. Enjoy.
 Order: Shawarma 
   Comment (0) 13 Reviews 2011/01/23 
 Nothing Great Reviewed by cuddles Overall 2.0 stars 
 Food 3.0 stars Services 2.0 stars Atmosphere 2.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Maybe Party Size: 2 
 
I go to John Fraser Secondary School, located a few minutes from Osmow&apos;s. The school is predominantly East Indian and Middle Eastern, and a lot of my friends recommended Osmow&apos;s to satisfy my shawarma craving. So I went with a buddy into Streetsville and we opted to try Osmow&apos;s. We walked in to find a fairly dirty, cramped atmosphere, but were quite hungry so we ordered our shawarmas. The wait time was somewhat long, but that could be due to the fact that it was this past summer and people were watching the Fifa World Cup. Anyway, we managed to get a small table and sat down to our lunch. I ordered a regular size medium shawarma and my friend ordered a regular size hot falafel (he&apos;s a vegetarian). The first few bites were quite good, but I found as I worked my way down the sandwich it just seemed to lose its flavour, instead becoming a blend of unpleasant spices. On top of this, my shawarma was not properly wrapped and despite my best effort food kept dropping out of it. It got to a point where I couldn&apos;t even finish; I was too full in a bad way. My friend didn&apos;t like his falafel either and we hastily left the restaurant. Overall, our Osmow&apos;s experience was not what we expected. The next time we craved shawarmas we decided to try Pita Nutso. Way better place. Wider, cleaner restaurant, friendly staff, and much better food. We have had Pita Nutso several times and enjoy it very much. Unfortunately Osmow&apos;s just doesn&apos;t measure up.
 Order: medium chicken shawarma, veggie falafel 
   Comment (1) 2011/06/17 
 Recent Comment by : CharlesSuChinChen 
 
&quot;As you work your way down&quot;, you said it yourself, thats how food like this works! Every cylinder shaped food with sauce inside will follow the law of physics &quot;Gravity&quot;!
 see all comments 1 Review 2010/09/15 
 Extremely unprofessional, bad customer service!! Reviewed by AG18 Overall 1.0 star 
 Food 2.0 stars Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 1.0 star 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 5 
 
The lady at the cash register is extremely unprofessional, rude and has no clue about anything in the restaurant. They constantly overcharge customers and cant explain why. Food is sub-par and service is at unacceptable levels. Do yourself a favour and avoid this place!
 Order: Shawaramas 
   Comment (0) 2 Reviews 2010/05/07 
 WONDERFUL SERVICES!! Reviewed by MississaugaFoodie953 Overall 5.0 stars 
 Food 5.0 stars Services 5.0 stars Atmosphere 5.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 9 or more 
 
Who gives a s -- H -- I - - T if the food is halal, if you want&quot;halal&quot;go back to your country, this is CANADA, besides almost all restaurant that say they sell&quot;halal&quot;is a lie, only you arab and indians believe in that hahahaha, as I said go back to your country!! All of you are cheap b astar ds, don&apos;t even want to pay $5 for a meal.

FU CK YOU B ITC HES!!!!!! (ARABS, INDIANS, AND m MUSLIS, AND DI RTY CHINESES!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!)
 Order: SHAWARMA 
   Comment (2) 2011/04/03 
 Recent Comment by : MississaugaFoodie642 
 
Fa g got mississauga is our country, your the f ucking immigrant. Go to alberta MO FO.

LI CK IT BI TCH
 see all comments 2 Reviews 2010/02/23 
 I ate at Osmows and that was it the service suk... Reviewed by samh Overall 1.0 star 
 Food 1.0 star Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 1.0 star 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 1 
 
I ate at Osmows and that was it the service suk, the hospitality has no place there, the food discusting, the owner sheets you with 3 OZ of chicken if he is generous at that time because he is not selling that much, all workers are depressed, over all I will never ever eat there not to mention how dirty that Restaurant is ,,,and to have a sandwich you have to wait 30 minutes it is not even to wait a minute in that restaurant
 Order: Shawarma 
   Comment (0) 1 Review 2010/02/06 
 The owner of Osmow’s grill and all employees say... Reviewed by shk Overall 1.0 star 
 Food 1.0 star Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 2.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 2 
 
The owner of Osmow’s grill and all employees say the food is Halal but they have not taken the initiative to put it on the board outside, or on the menu, nor do they have a Halal certificate.

I’m not sure if this restaurant is a Halal restaurant obviously because there is no proof.
 Order: nothing 
   Comment (2) 2011/04/03 
 Recent Comment by : MississaugaFoodie642 
 
Samh probably has been licking too many pita &quot;nuts&quot;. Listen buddy, get a life and please dont bash osmos. Your resturant is way too clean for us immigrants we like it down and dirty at osmos.
 see all comments 4 Reviews 2009/12/30 
 Not a good place to dine in, very small and... Reviewed by anam Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 5.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 2.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 2 
 
Not a good place to dine in, very small and doesnt look too clean but the food is AMAZING! definitely worth trying. the proportions are good as well so youll definitely be full after your meal.
 Order: chicken shawarma 
   Comment (0) 2 Reviews 2009/11/08 
 The food is amazinggggg, I absolutely love it... Reviewed by Chicita Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 5.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 4.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 5 
 
The food is amazinggggg, I absolutely love it!!! Totally addicted to it. Really tasty and something I definitely crave now and then. Not only the shawerma, I&apos;ve had a few of their menu items. Excellent! The mixed grill is A LOT OF FOOD for a fairly low price! Wow!

The service is adequate, I mean the people treat you well and everything but it may take a little bit of time to get your order and if you ask me, I say it&apos;s wayyy worth it!!

The atmosphere is fine, cute little restaurant, very nice decor.
 Order: I&apos;ve had almost everything there! Yummmmyy 
   Comment (1) 2010/02/24 
 Recent Comment by : samh 
 
you must have no brains or no value taste of what you eat,,,to say that the food at Osmows is good oh my God help this person to realise what he is eating for your information one client suffers from small crushed glass in his sandwich and he went...
 see all comments 
 1 2 3 4 5 next 
 Nearby restaurants Tapas De Espana 
 3.5 stars &lt;½ km De La Crepe 
 3.0 stars &lt;½ km The Franklin Pourhouse 
 3.5 stars &lt;½ km more nearby Streetsville Restaurants: A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z Quick Links to USA Cities 
 Arlington Charleston Charlotte Denver 

 Detroit Las Vegas Milwaukee Minneapolis 

 Nashville Orlando Pittsburgh Portland (OR) 

 Sacramento Salt Lake City Seattle Springfield (IL) 

 Toledo Tucson Tulsa All Cities 
 Quick Links to Canadian Cities 
 Burnaby Calgary Charlottetown Halifax 

 Hamilton Kelowna Kitchener Mississauga 

 Montréal Ottawa Québec City Regina 

 Saint John Saskatoon Surrey Toronto 

 Vancouver Victoria Winnipeg All Cities 
 
 Advertisers Advertise with us Add a Restaurant Restaurant Owners 

 About Us About Us Careers Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions Bookmark Us 

 Quick links Your page Invite a Friend Help and FAQ 

 Mobile and tools Mobile Apps Blog Link to Us 

 Partners Yellowpages.ca AutoTrader.ca Buysell.com Canada411.ca CanadaPlus.ca Autos.ca 

   Deal of the Day HomeTrader.ca PriceCanada.com RedFlagDeals.com Restaurantica.ca 
 

 
© Copyright Restaurantica 2008-2011. Neighbourhood data

© 2009 Urban Mapping Inc. Yellow Pages Group and the Walking Fingers&amp;Design are trademarks of Yellow Pages Group Co. in Canada.
 
 Best Results 
 No Results 
 Popular Cities 
 Las Vegas, Nevada New York, New York San Francisco, California
	</body>
</document>
