<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008730" url="http://internationalguy.wordpress.com/2012/03/25/junk-food/" time="2012-07-13-02:11" support="2" score="0.0014785856416102985" bingtitle="Junk Food « Internationalguy&apos;s Blog" webtitle="Junk FoodInternationalguys Blog">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... began to see the Mexican fast food restaurant “Del Taco” everywhere. I was curious so I bought a meal. While eating it ... Masterpiece Theater and trash TV ...</description>
	<body>
		Internationalguy&apos;s Blog 
 A variety of politically incorrect musings 
 Home About 
   
Junk Food
 
A few years ago I developed a taste for Taco Bell´s 7 layer Burrito.  It seemed reasonably healthy with vegetarian ingredients, it was cheap and I like Mexican food.  Soon however after eating it I began to develop cravings for the burritos, and would sometimes rush over and order 5-6 burritos and eat them right away.  At first I attributed it to the good taste, but while abroad I thought about it and something inside me both unconsciously and consciously told me that this was not normal to develop these types of cravings.  When I went back to the US there was a Taco Bell nearby but I passed.

I did not realize it at the time, but surely the burritos must have been loaded with MSG, which was creating hunger and addiction.  Fortunately my mother raised me on healthy meals so I am used to eating good food, and have never really liked junk food.  When people eat junk food all the time the body becomes used to the toxins and it all begins to seem very normal, but when the body is used to eating real food, it notices the difference when a junk food meal is eaten.  It is like the habitual smoker who loves the feeling of smoke in his lungs, and the non smoker who naturally finds inhaling cigarettes to be toxic and unpleasant.

Between parents, school lunches and constant junk eateries available, we are raising a generation that thinks that junk food is normal.  They have become so addicted to the stuff, that when given healthy meals they reject them. They want the crap food.

A few years ago I was visiting my parents, and I began to see the Mexican fast food restaurant “Del Taco” everywhere.  I was curious so I bought a meal.  While eating it, it was unpleasantly obvious to me that this was low quality food, and I did not like it.  Since I had been used to quality food, this junk food tasted junky to me.  But for those habituated (often from a young age) to junk food, I am sure that the crap tastes just great, and quality food is unpalatable.

Basically fast food manufactures take sugar, fat, caffeine, salt, MSG, Aspartame, etc. (all the addictive substances that we naturally find hard to control) and jack them up.  They know which buttons to push to get us to consume more.  The food is designed to be addictive and promote greater appetites, which means that they sell more, the diet industry profits, and the medical cartel really reaps in the big time profits treating all of the lifestyle diseases (diabetes, cancer, obesity, etc.).

Quality food is different in taste.  It is more subtle, and complex and less scrumptious.  I think that it is much more satisfying, but it takes are more sophisticated palette to enjoy it.  It is like the difference between Masterpiece Theater and trash TV, all hyped up, full of immediate gratification, but ultimately shallow and empty.

If you have not done so, learn to appreciate quality foods.  Then the transition will be easier, and you body and mind will thank you for it.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
 This entry was posted on Sunday, March 25th, 2012 at 12:14 am and is filed under Economic Issues , Environment , Health , Politics . You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed.
 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 
Post navigation
 «Previous Post Next Post» 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 August 2010 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 December 2008 
 
Categories

 Economic Issues Education Energy Crisis Entertainment Environment Fiscal Policy Health Immigration Infrastructure Politically In correct Politics Population Religion Uncategorized 
 
 
Theme: Contempt by Vault9 .
 Blog at WordPress.com .
 Follow 
 Follow“Internationalguy&apos;s Blog” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 33 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
