<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008502" url="http://www.skyscrapercity.com/archive/index.php/t-216053.html" time="2012-07-13-01:58" support="1" score="0.0011860848604542328" bingtitle="Burgers...best chain in Canada?/Carl&apos;s Jr. coming to Canada ..." webtitle="Burgers...best chain in Canada?/Carl&apos;s Jr. coming to Canada [Archive]  - SkyscraperCity">
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... Fatbuger or other sandwich with a wide selection of ... up front, and it took over 5 minutes to get my order ... Locals are more likely to choose a local fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		SkyscraperCity &gt; Continental Forums &gt; North American Skyscrapers Forum &gt; Canada &gt; Canada Urban Issues &gt;Burgers...best chain in Canada?/Carl&apos;s Jr. coming to Canada PDA 
View Full Version : Burgers...best chain in Canada?/Carl&apos;s Jr. coming to Canada 
 Pages : [ 1 ] 2 samsonyuen May 23rd, 2005, 10:23 PM Carl&apos;s Jr. has announced its intention to enter Canada (first via BC, AB, and ON). For those who don&apos;t know this chain (and its sister Hardee&apos;s), it&apos;s famous for its Thickburger amongst other not too-good-for-you things...Paris Hilton is in its most recent Spicy Thickburger commercials.
http://www.smh.com.au/ffximage/2004/11/18/th_monsterburger.jpg
_______________________________
Can Carl&apos;s do a Quiznos?
By RICHARD BLOOM
Monday, May 23, 2005 Updated at 12:21 PM EDT
From Monday&apos;s Globe and Mail

&quot;The $7.59 Burger&quot;doesn&apos;t quite roll off the tongue but that&apos;s not stopping American fast-food chain Carl&apos;s Jr. -- famous for its mammoth Six Dollar Burger in the United States -- from entering the Canadian market.

Carpinteria, Calif.-based CKE Restaurants Inc. is planning to bring its Carl&apos;s Jr. chain to this country -- currently searching for franchisees, regional developers and possibly someone to hold the entire Canadian master franchise.

&quot;We&apos;ve always had an eye on the Canadian market . . . it&apos;s really our No. 1 priority [internationally],&quot;Ned Lyerly, CKE&apos;s vice-president of international operations, said in an interview.

The company will first focus on urban areas in British Columbia, Alberta and Ontario, and hopes to start opening stores within 18 months. It&quot;makes sense logistically&quot;to have the bulk of its locations in the Western provinces because most of the chain&apos;s 3,200 American restaurants are peppered across the U.S. Southwest, Mr. Lyerly said.

Advertisements








&quot;We think that our burger platform and our positioning as a premium-quality burger chain . . . certainly has a place, and we&apos;re looking forward to serving some young, hungry burger lovers out there.&quot;

Founded as a hot-dog cart operator by Carl Karcher in Los Angeles in the 1940s -- about 10 years before Ray Kroc opened his first McDonald&apos;s restaurant in Des Plains, Ill. -- CKE boomed in post-war California, transforming itself into a drive-in burger seller. Sixty years later, CKE has annual sales of $1.5-billion (U.S.) and 30,000 employees working under the Carl&apos;s Jr., Hardee&apos;s, Green Burrito and La Salsa Fresh Mexican Grill banners.

Canadians are expected to spend almost $14-billion (Canadian) at fast-food restaurants this year. Of that tally, 32 per cent will be spent at burger joints, according to market research firm NPD Group Canada.

Figures also reveal that while customer visits to fast-food eateries increased 2 per cent over the past year, servings of hamburgers declined 2 per cent.

&quot;It&apos;s a tight marketplace right now, we&apos;re not seeing any gains in traffic,&quot;NPD vice-president Jim Robinson said. It will be interesting to see how McDonald&apos;s Restaurants of Canada Ltd. -- the largest burger seller in the land -- responds to Carl&apos;s Jr.&apos;s entrance, he said.

&quot;The question will be, can Carl&apos;s do a Quiznos? Because everyone thought Subway was invincible and nobody could eat more sandwiches, until Quiznos came in and introduced an upscale sandwich at a higher price point,&quot;he said.

&quot;Are people willing to pay for a bigger burger in quick service? That is the key question.&quot;

As chains like McDonald&apos;s and Wendy&apos;s International Inc. have altered menus to include healthier items like salads, yogurt parfaits and grilled chicken sandwiches, CKE trumpets heftier products.

Carl&apos;s Jr.&apos;s flagship sandwich is called The Six Dollar Burger -- a half-pound beef patty with cheese and mayonnaise. It also sells a double version of that burger that has one pound of beef. The burger will have a different name in Canada, Mr. Lyerly said, adding&quot;we&apos;ve got something up our sleeve . . . [but] it won&apos;t be The $7.50 burger.&quot;

Last year, CKE&apos;s Hardee&apos;s chain rolled out the Monster Thickburger, which includes two 1/3-pound patties of beef, four strips of bacon, three slices of cheese and mayonnaise on a buttered bun.

The chain is also known for racy advertising campaigns that target 18- to 34-year-old men -- the key burger-eating demographic.

CKE made waves in the U.S. advertising industry last week with a commercial starring Paris Hilton. With a rock version of I Love Paris in the Summer in the background, the ad features Ms. Hilton in a revealing black swimsuit, seductively washing a black Rolls Royce and biting into the chain&apos;s spicy new burger.

In 2003, Carl&apos;s aired a commercial with Playboy founder Hugh Hefner surrounded by scantily clad models. At the end, the announcer says:&quot;Because some guys don&apos;t like the same thing night after night.&quot;

This isn&apos;t the first time CKE has done business in Canada. In 1997, the company paid Montreal&apos;s Imasco Ltd. $457-million for the Hardee&apos;s burger chain. Hardee&apos;s, however, is not allowed in Canada because of possible patent infringement with Cara Operations Ltd.&apos;s Harvey&apos;s chain. Westcoast604 May 23rd, 2005, 10:29 PM Fatburger, popular in SoCal&amp;Las Vegas recently opened their first location outside the U.S. here in Vancouver.

http://www.fatburger.net/w.holly.small.jpeg


VANCOUVER, B.C., CANADA, May 2005 -- Vancouver&apos;s vibrant West End community will soon be home to the very first Fatburger restaurant in Canada, and the first location outside of the United States for the fast-growing hamburger chain founded in Los Angeles, California in 1952. Plans call for the new Fatburger restaurant to open on May 9 in a 1600-square-foot facility located at 1101 Denman Street, situated conveniently near the beach at popular English Bay and shopping on nearby Robson Street.

The restaurant will feature Fatburger&apos;s signature 1950&apos;s retro-style dcor with neon lighting, open kitchen and counter seating. Music and sports memorabilia, including items commemorating British Columbia&apos;s BC Lions of the Canadian Football League, will be on display.

A garage-style door can be opened up to provide diners with a full view of Denman Street and to entice pedestrians into the burger stand. Approximately 35 staffers will be employed at the site, which can conveniently seat up to 48 guests inside.

The franchisee for Fatburger in Canada is Frank Di Benedetto of Frankie&apos;s Burger Enterprises, a self-proclaimed hamburger and hotdog fanatic who heard about Fatburger through his long-standing career in the restaurant industry.

&quot;Growing up with a passion for the burger business, I knew I had to find out more about a burger place that dared to call itself Fatburger,&quot;joked Di Benedetto. What I learned made me want to become a franchisee. Now I&apos;m thrilled to give other burger-loving Canadians a chance to try a Fatburger, too.&quot;

Plans are on the drawing board for Di Benedetto to open at least 20 Fatburger restaurants throughout Canada in the next few years.

As it opens in new markets, Fatburger continues to build a loyal following with its huge, great-tasting, homemade-style burgers that are freshly prepared to order. Fatburger restaurants have recently been opened in Georgia, Louisiana and New York.

With Fatburger&apos;s arrival in Canada, another important step in the company&apos;s 50-plus-year history will be achieved.&quot;There are really no borders when it comes to great-tasting hamburgers,&quot;said Elaine Patel, director of marketing for Fatburger North America, Inc.&quot;We&apos;re delighted to introduce Fatburger to a whole new country!&quot;

To ensure customer satisfaction, each Fatburger, Turkeyburger and Chicken Sandwich is grilled immediately after it is ordered. Customers may garnish their Fatbuger or other sandwich with a wide selection of toppings, including cheese, bacon, a fried egg, and chili.

In addition to the trademark 1/3 lb. Fatburger, made with fresh USDA lean beef, guests may also select from a menu that features chili dogs, homemade onion rings, and&quot;fat&quot;or&quot;skinny&quot;fries. Milkshakes made with real hand-dipped ice cream top the list of beverages that includes an assortment of soft drinks. worldwide May 23rd, 2005, 10:34 PM tim hortons!

but seriously i think wendys is good Skybean May 23rd, 2005, 10:52 PM :drool: :drool: crazyjoeda May 24th, 2005, 12:15 AM I heard about Fatburgar opening in Langely for this year but not downtown. BTW I hear one is still scheduled to open later this year in Langley. mumbojumbo May 24th, 2005, 12:25 AM That burger looks amazing.... But Harvey&apos;s is my favourite nonetheless.

Btw, Tim Hortons isn&apos;t a burger chain. But it is a coffee/donut/muffin/soup/sub chain... KillBill May 24th, 2005, 12:25 AM Don&apos;t tell me you guys don&apos;t have In N&apos; Out s. Man, I have not been any other burger place other than In N&apos; Out in the last 12 years. Fyi, I ain&apos;t no fat, I just go maybe once a month.

Best of US for sure. Hopefully, Canada will also experience it one day. Then you will understand that all Carls, Wendies, Fatburgers blah blah are just nonsense.

Regards, touraccuracy May 24th, 2005, 12:43 AM WHITE SPOT Ashok May 24th, 2005, 12:57 AM i like Wendy&apos;s Jaybird May 24th, 2005, 01:03 AM Oh dear God, I was hoping they would never come to this country, now I have seen everything... I hope it&apos;s more short-lived than Krispy Kreme was in Canada. I am now sick to my stomach even as I speak. But for the best burger chain, it&apos;s definitely Harvey&apos;s. Because I have no access to a Lick&apos;s. EdZed May 24th, 2005, 01:10 AM WHITE SPOT

I agree too bad there is a lack of them in Alberta. But in BC there everywhere, I believe in Chevron Stations. Buster May 24th, 2005, 01:34 AM Lick&apos;s owns the burger-chain category in southern Ontario.

Wimpy&apos;s is another tasty chain.

But my new favourite is Dangerous Dan&apos;s. I&apos;m working up to their coronary burger. Mmmmm. . . fat soaked paradise. :drool: :drool: :drool: Booyashako May 24th, 2005, 01:42 AM I prefer Harvey&apos;s (even over White Spot and In n out) rt_0891 May 24th, 2005, 02:37 AM I prefer Harvey&apos;s (even over White Spot and In n out)

Me too:D

Too bad the US will never get a taste of it, lol. :) KGB May 24th, 2005, 03:03 AM I had a rare hanker&apos;n for some crap chain burger the other day, and I couldn&apos;t recall which chain had the better one, so I popped into a Burger King, cause it was the first one I came across and ordered a Whopper/cheez.

The people working there were exceedingly slow and dim-witted. I was only the second person in line, with three people working up front, and it took over 5 minutes to get my order taken.

I knew things weren&apos;t good when I could see them&quot;making&quot;it (reconstituting it, whatever they do to it). They slid it into this thing that kinda looked like an Easy bake Oven for a little while.

So, I figure WTF, and I take my warm little package and my $8&quot;small&quot;root beer to a window seat to watch Yonge St go by...that and a greasy burger and an overly sweet artificially flavoured carbonated beverage...what more could you ask for if you feel like slumming it?

I opened the package...and holy shit...what a sad looking burger...the bottom half of the&quot;bun&quot;was so thin and soggy, my fingers went through it!!! I&apos;ve seen healthier&quot;meat&quot;on that 4000 year old mummy they thawed out in the Andies!!

I took a few bites and just threw it out and left...I figured complaining was a waste of time...this is what they sell, and people buy it.

I have no idea why Burger King is in business...the shit they sell is so disgusting....and I don&apos;t mean in the unhealthy, fatty, indulgent, decadent sense...it&apos;s just plain tasteless, garbage.

I already knew McDonalds was like that (I hadn&apos;t even considered them), but I had no idea BK was that bad. I&apos;ve had some nasty streetmeat in the wee hours before, but this is the worse thing I&apos;ve ever had.

Yes, Licks makes a pretty good burger...when I&apos;m spending the day in the Beach, I always treat myself.





KGB DanfromTO May 24th, 2005, 03:04 AM Man, i havent eaten in like 6 hours and this thread is making me remarkably hungry
personally-i eat a load of fast food, but for some unknown reason im underweight, possibly because of exercise
im a big fan of mcdonalds marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:05 AM LOL.

Burger King is, if possible, worse than McDonalds. At least McDonalds doesn&apos;t make like their fare is anything more than what it is.

Of the choices, I had to go with Wendy&apos;s. Harvey&apos;s seems to be winning, but I&apos;ve never heard of it... Steeltown May 24th, 2005, 03:26 AM For the best chickenburger I have to go with Wendy&apos;s...mmmmm spicy chicken burger.

But for the best regular burger I have to go with Harvey&apos;s.

I usually always pick a chickenburger over a hamburger. Westcoast604 May 24th, 2005, 03:28 AM Burger King is by far the worst food on the planet. The last time I had a burger from there it was yellowy green, and looked like it had been mauled by an animal . KGB May 24th, 2005, 03:36 AM &quot;At least McDonalds doesn&apos;t make like their fare is anything more than what it is.&quot;


Excactly...I can appreciate McPuke for what it is...a paradoy of itself...people sue them for stupid things...people make movies about them...they are the lowest form of pop culture...they take the booby prize...they are like the huge joke...and we are the punch-line. They&apos;ve earned their right to kill us (or at least make us sick...give us cancer...whatever).

But Burger King...they haven&apos;t earned their right to do any of this....they just fly under the radar...they just stick themselves out there with nothing but crap, knowing simply by the chance of probability, they will make a buck....and don&apos;t have to give anything in return...not decent food...no cool toys...no cool commercials...nothing to take away from the agony of their product.

And the proverbial icing on the cake, is that everything there is EXPENSIVE!!! I mean, if they charged like 59 cents or something for that crap, I could understand them having a place in the wacky world of fast food...people don&apos;t mind paying less for crap...but they don&apos;t...at least mcPuke has a daily sandwich special for under a buck.

So I have no idea why people go there...bad food, bad service, bad environment and high prices. Come to think of it, there weren&apos;t but a few people in there...I don&apos;t wanna seem like an elitist asswipe (even though I am)...but everybody in there was a loser....some 17 year-old girl, with her 8 month old baby in a stroller...and a group of 4 American kids (can&apos;t miss that Michigan accent), who obviously found themselves in the wilds of Non-America, and panicked and went to the first food name they recognized (god forbid they actually might want to pop into one of the many noodle joints that line Yonge St...which i should have done).

Oh well....I&apos;ll just chalk it up to another urban experiment gone awry.









KGB marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:41 AM I don&apos;t wanna seem like an elitist asswipe (even though I am)...

Might as well go with what you know...LOL Plumber73 May 24th, 2005, 03:45 AM WHITE SPOTYES! I will die because of them. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 03:47 AM Oh well....I&apos;ll just chalk it up to another urban experiment gone awry.

KGB

Going to Burger King is an urban experiment? Geeeeez.

I don&apos;t think Burger King is that bad. Anyway, if you really want to experiment and you&apos;re in White Castle territory, go there after 2 AM. I guarantee you&apos;ll have a story to tell your grandchildren, and it won&apos;t be about the burgers. marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:48 AM Anyway, if you really want to experiment and you&apos;re in White Castle territory, go there after 2 AM. I guarantee you&apos;ll have a story to tell your grandchildren, and it won&apos;t be about the burgers.

No need to go there anymore. You can buy those in the grocery store... The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 03:50 AM No need to go there anymore. You can buy those in the grocery store...

But that&apos;s no fun. Microwaving them at your house isn&apos;t the same. The frozen burgers at the store don&apos;t come with the late night freak show. marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:50 AM But that&apos;s no fun. Microwaving them at your house isn&apos;t the same. The frozen burgers at the store don&apos;t come with the late night freak show.

Microwaving them? That never even occurred to me...

And I&apos;m too old and ornery to get a kick out of the freak show anymore... Yankee BOY May 24th, 2005, 03:56 AM Ok ok ok I got a reallly good question. When I lived in California Carls Jr was called Carls Jr but when I moved south its called Hardees. Why? Same logo and everything. marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:57 AM Ok ok ok I got a reallly good question. When I lived in California Carls Jr was called Carls Jr but when I moved south its called Hardees. Why? Same logo and everything.

It&apos;s Hardee&apos;s in the midwet too. It happens. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 03:57 AM Microwaving them? That never even occurred to me...

And I&apos;m too old and ornery to get a kick out of the freak show anymore...

You&apos;re no fun then. Come on, it&apos;s more than just the burger, it&apos;s the entertainment, the bum eating french fries out of the garbage, the lady with her bare feet propped up on the table getting a foot rub in the booth across from you, the cops laughing at it all in the corner booth, and the smell of onions....ahhh, the smell of onions. marathon May 24th, 2005, 03:58 AM You&apos;re no fun then. Come on, it&apos;s more than just the burger, it&apos;s the entertainment, the bum eating french fries out of the garbage, the lady with her feet proped up on the table getting a foot rub in the booth across from you, the cops laughing at it all in the corner booth, and the smell of onions....ahhh, the smell of onions.

Suburban life cleansed me of all appreciation for such spectacle! :) CrazyCanuck May 24th, 2005, 05:24 AM Licks is the best. Also, just what we need, another fat ass American food chain. KGB May 24th, 2005, 05:36 AM &quot;Going to Burger King is an urban experiment? Geeeeez.&quot;


In a city where the choices aren&apos;t limited to 5 similar american fast-food chains...yea. To you, it&apos;s everyday home-cook&apos;n...to me, it&apos;s exotic. And something I won&apos;t be getting all risky about again....I&apos;ll stick to everyday, tried and true fast-food stuff like roti, pho, banh mi, or falafel.







&quot;I don&apos;t think Burger King is that bad.&quot;

Either there is an enormous inconsistancy in quality, or you can kiss your carreer as a food critic goodbye.








&quot;if you really want to experiment and you&apos;re in White Castle territory, go there after 2 AM. I guarantee you&apos;ll have a story to tell your grandchildren, and it won&apos;t be about the burgers.&quot;


Dude...it&apos;s Yonge St...ya don&apos;t have to wait for 2 AM for the freakshow to start.





KGB DrJoe May 24th, 2005, 05:43 AM Hmmmm i&apos;ll go with Wendys.

McDonalds is crap, but its cheap and you know what you&apos;re going to get...they dont f*ck around, they know you know its crap.
Burger King is brutal, gross, expensive, trys to hard to be upscale McDonalds or something. Wendy&apos;s is the most real food like so they win, I havent been to the others enough to comment. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 05:46 AM &quot;Going to Burger King is an urban experiment? Geeeeez.&quot;


In a city where the choices aren&apos;t limited to 5 similar american fast-food chains...yea. To you, it&apos;s everyday home-cook&apos;n...to me, it&apos;s exotic. And something I won&apos;t be getting all risky about again....I&apos;ll stick to everyday, tried and true fast-food stuff like roti, pho, banh mi, or falafel.


There are more choices in Minneapolis that 5 fast food chains. I know you were probably trying to exaggerate, but that&apos;s beyond exaggeration. My point was that Burger King is not exotic, not even in Canada. I find it hard to believe that was the first time you&apos;ve tried Burger King. If I&apos;m supposed to be impressed that you find roti, pho, banh mi, and falafel&quot;everyday fast food&quot;, I&apos;m not. Believe it or not, Minneapolis has Indian, Vietnamese, and Greek food too.

Either there is an enormous inconsistancy in quality, or you can kiss your carreer as a food critic goodbye.

What I&apos;m saying is that is Burger King really that much worse than any other fast food Burger joint? I don&apos;t think so. DrJoe May 24th, 2005, 05:50 AM I just badmouthed BK, but one thing they do have going for them is the poutine IMO.

http://www.burgerking.ca/imagelibrary/menus/poutine.jpg Westcoast604 May 24th, 2005, 05:54 AM As if it ever looks like that rt_0891 May 24th, 2005, 05:55 AM I tried Mcdonald&apos;s poutine before, and it made my tummy growl. :cry:

BTW, I have never been to a BK, and never intend to go.

....I&apos;ll stick to everyday, tried and true fast-food stuff like roti, pho, banh mi, or falafel.

Definitely. When there&apos;s so many choices at hand, there&apos;s no need for the burger. Sushi is also a fast-food favourite for me. doady May 24th, 2005, 06:02 AM Harvey&apos;s is by far the best fast food chain. I think A&amp;W&apos;s is pretty good too. Nowadays though, the only fast food I eat is sushi or teriyaki. Tastes better and it&apos;s healthier too. KGB May 24th, 2005, 07:36 AM &quot;There are more choices in Minneapolis that 5 fast food chains. I know you were probably trying to exaggerate, but that&apos;s beyond exaggeration.&quot;


I&apos;ll bet you the top 5 fast-food chains in Minn account for 98% of the market.






&quot;My point was that Burger King is not exotic, not even in Canada.&quot;

And my point was.....well...basically a joke. I guess they don&apos;t serve a side of humour along with the fries in Minn.







&quot;Believe it or not, Minneapolis has Indian, Vietnamese, and Greek food too.&quot;

Yea, and I&apos;m sure all 18 vietnamese people in Minn keep it in business too....Minneapolis being the huge cornucopia of international cuisine and all. LOL

Dude..there is a slight difference between how many people eat&quot;ethnic&quot;food in Toronto and Minneapolis. I&apos;m not trying to&quot;impress&quot;anything on you, except that there is much better fast food to be had, than the big chains, and that lots of people in Toronto actually eat a lot of alternative fast food.








&quot;What I&apos;m saying is that is Burger King really that much worse than any other fast food Burger joint? I don&apos;t think so.&quot;


Do you own stock or something?

Hey...if you find it yummy...then hat&apos;s off to you...have another Whopper!!







&quot;but one thing they do have going for them is the poutine IMO.&quot;


Yea, I can just imagine how fantastic it is???

I had real poutine once at the top of the ski hill at Mount St Anne once. Quebec should sue Burger King for bastardizing such a fine french tradition. LOL







&quot;Nowadays though, the only fast food I eat is sushi or teriyaki. Tastes better and it&apos;s healthier too.&quot;


Sushi is great, but I have to be in a certain mood for it....and it&apos;s not all that cheap for the amount you get.

teriyaki is great...simple...but tasty and reasonably healthy I guess. And hey, in the same food court, for the same money...why would you eat that pap at Burger King, when next door, those teriyaki places make it for you on the spot?

When you are stuck with a food-court as your only source of food (really...why are you there anyway...ok, if you are working in PATH), there are always better alternatives...my favorite is Jimmy The Greek....1/4 roasted chicked...roasted mini-potatoes, rice and greek salad...big portion, wholesome and filling and tasty...and it costs the same as whatever it was Burger King was trying to poison me with.







KGB KGB May 24th, 2005, 07:41 AM Burgers 1,000 ways
By STEVEN DAVEY

THE YELLOW GRIFFIN (2202 Bloor West, at Runnymede, 416-763-3365) Open daily 11:30 am to 2 am.

Swansea, that affluent semi-retired burg that runs west from High Park to Bloor West Village, comes new to al fresco caf society. Hogtown&apos;s last booze-free zone, it&apos;s only in the past five years that the area has embraced drinking in public, let alone on a patio in full view of the neighbours.

The Yellow Griffin is typical of Swansea, a small Guinness-slinging pub with a six-table curbside veranda where the biggest attractions are Thursday&apos;s poker night and Friday&apos;s 80s disco. But, like most local bars and restos, business has been down.

&quot;First SARS, then the anti-smoking bylaw. We had to do something!&quot;says the Griffin&apos;s Maria Lutkiewicz who, with her son Oliver , decided to think big and offer 1,470 variations of hamburgers, topping combos and side dishes.

That&apos;s six different patties ground beef, lamb or turkey, chicken breast, pork escalope and Yves&apos;s veggie 35 styles of fixin&apos;s from the Kung Fu ($8.85), with scallion, peanut and Kung Pao sauce, to the Skippy Dipper ($8.45), with crunchy peanut butter and strawberry jam. Sides go seven ways: sweet potato and Belgian-style fries, breaded onion rings, two types of coleslaw, tart curried potato salad with bacon, apple and raisins, and superbly crisp waffled potato gaufrette.

Some burgers are just plain weird: the St. Peter&apos;s ($11.45) on chicken breast with fishy roe and a smashed shrimp I think not. But others, like the Bollywood ($8.95), lamb with mango chutney and tandoori yogurt sauce, or the Cubana Libre ($10.25), pork with peameal bacon, Swiss cheese and gherkins (hold the hot dog mustard), are keepers.



More patty picks:

The Drake (see listing, page 90) has one of the best burgers in town, patio or otherwise. Served with frites so crisp they make Jamie Kennedy&apos;s acclaimed spuds seem like limp noodles, the patty topped with oka &apos;n&apos; caramelized onion and sandwiched between slices of Fred&apos;s brioche is so thick and jus-squirting that it requires a chopstick skewer to hold it together ($14). No less an authority than the Globe&apos;s Joanne Kates called the Pilot &apos;s (see listing, page 99) namesake charbroiled 6-ouncer ($8.50)&quot;the king of burgers.&quot;Who knew they had Whoppers way back then? Things have certainly changed since the early 60s. Still others swear by Mark McEwan &apos;s bombastic Bymark (see listing, page 95) burger, 8 ounces of hand-chopped USDA prime layered with foie gras, mango jam and mustard aoli, a mere snip at $36.95. dtx03 May 24th, 2005, 07:49 AM Lick&apos;s owns the burger-chain category in southern Ontario.

Wimpy&apos;s is another tasty chain.

But my new favourite is Dangerous Dan&apos;s. I&apos;m working up to their coronary burger. Mmmmm. . . fat soaked paradise. :drool: :drool: :drool:

hmmmmm...burgers.... dangerous dan&apos;s is tha joint!!!
other burger jointz of choice in T.O...

johnny&apos;s, vesta, and sizzler.. great for late night eats, when you know you won&apos;t have time for breakfast in the morn... but you get the lovely mornin stale burger breath (lol)!! samsonyuen May 24th, 2005, 11:20 AM Burger King is my least favorite chain. Its poutine is even gross, the gravy&apos;s orange and the cheese is rubbery. I&apos;d go with Harvey&apos;s again for best poutine. I forgot to include A&amp;W. Their onion rings are awesome! I wish In-N-Out was in Toronto (same as Jack in the Box), it&apos;s only in the western US. What&apos;s White Spot? I haven&apos;t seen them in Central Canada, but then again, we don&apos;t have Chevron stations either. THE BUCKET May 24th, 2005, 04:22 PM My&quot;beef&quot;with Burger King stems from the fact that they go out of their way to make their food taste as if it were severly burnt, which I find really f&apos;d up...BK&apos;s gimmick that it seems to be pushing is that&quot;flame grilled&quot;dealy, which in practice just means either burning the shit out of your food or adding some sort of chemical additive that makes it taste as though the patty lost a fight with a bag of charcoal. THE BUCKET May 24th, 2005, 04:26 PM Burger King is my least favorite chain. Its poutine is even gross, the gravy&apos;s orange and the cheese is rubbery. I&apos;d go with Harvey&apos;s again for best poutine. I forgot to include A&amp;W. Their onion rings are awesome! I wish In-N-Out was in Toronto (same as Jack in the Box), it&apos;s only in the western US. What&apos;s White Spot? I haven&apos;t seen them in Central Canada, but then again, we don&apos;t have Chevron stations either.

To my knowledge, White Spot only exists in BC, at least in Canada. I&apos;d heard they&apos;d opened a few in Hong Kong and were looking elsewhere in Asia (can&apos;t remember where I read this)...I think they had a few in Washington state for a while but I&apos;m not too sure if they stuck around or not. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 04:40 PM &quot;There are more choices in Minneapolis that 5 fast food chains. I know you were probably trying to exaggerate, but that&apos;s beyond exaggeration.&quot;


I&apos;ll bet you the top 5 fast-food chains in Minn account for 98% of the market.

In outstate Minnesota, sure. I&apos;m sure it&apos;s the same thing in bumfuck Ontario. I live and work in Minneapolis though. There are about 20 fast food restaurants in my immediate area (one skyway away in any direction) and none of them are McDonalds, Burger King, Wendys, etc. Just in my building and adjacent buildings there is French, Thai, Cantonese, Mexican (not Taco Bell, real Mexican), Japanese, Chicago style hot dogs, and Greek choices for fast food. Yeah, French fast food. If you want big chain fast food, there&apos;s Cousins, Taco Bell, Subway, and Taco Johns. That&apos;s just 2 blocks of downtown, and it&apos;s not in a food court.

Yea, and I&apos;m sure all 18 vietnamese people in Minn keep it in business too....Minneapolis being the huge cornucopia of international cuisine and all. LOL.

You don&apos;t know much about Minneapolis or St. Paul and you love being a jackass, don&apos;t you? There is a fairly large asian population here, mainly Hmong, Vietnamese, and Laotians. Not as big as Toronto, but Toronto is a bigger city.

Dude..there is a slight difference between how many people eat&quot;ethnic&quot;food in Toronto and Minneapolis.

There is a slight difference in population too. algonquin May 24th, 2005, 05:11 PM I&apos;m sure it&apos;s the same thing in bumfuck Ontario.

I grew up in Bumfuck, ON. We had no fast-food.

Unless you count the TH on every corner. KGB May 24th, 2005, 06:46 PM &quot;you love being a jackass, don&apos;t you?&quot;


Is that what they&apos;re calling people who eat at Jack in the Box too much??

Come now...you antagonize me and then call me a jackass?? mm hmm







&quot;Yeah, French fast food.&quot;

You mean Freedom fast food?






&quot;There is a fairly large asian population here, mainly Hmong, Vietnamese, and Laotians. Not as big as Toronto, but Toronto is a bigger city.&quot;


Of course the population is bigger...because of immigrants (who probably eat&quot;ethnic food he he). But measuring size has little to do with it....the Twin Cities have less than 100,000 immigrants, which would have to include those asians...this can&apos;t touch suburban Toronto cities, let alone Toronto...Mississauga is the same size as the Twin Cities (population and land size), and has 3 times the immigrants. Forget Mississauga...Markham has more asians than the Twin Cities, and it&apos;s 1/3 the population.










&quot;We had no fast-food. Unless you count the TH on every corner.&quot;


Yes...Tim&apos;s has managed to somehow jump the fast-food world and has become some kind of national treasure. Nice one...but it&apos;s still a fast food joint...we didn&apos;t even flinch when they started freezing their doughnuts, and it&apos;s now majority controlled by an American company....bad omen. And they have actually managed to unseat McPuke as the largest fast-food chain in the country. For fast-food, i guess it&apos;s reasonably good.






KGB vid May 24th, 2005, 06:55 PM Harvey&apos;s makes good hamburgers, but htey can&apos;t beat the local fast food places.

Thunder Bay has over alot of chinese and vietnamese restaurants for a city this size (they&apos;re everywhere) we also have quite a few greek, scandinavian, and other oriental style fast food restaurants, that aren&apos;t big multinational corperatios. As for big fast food companies, Burger King is all but gone, McCraps is scrambling for new customers, and Wendy&apos;s.. Is doing okay, actually. The fitness trend is starting to kick in. WE&apos;re entering the era of the salad :O

@The-anti-cheesehead and KGB: You look like children! now, kiss and make up. Or else. ;) The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 07:39 PM Of course the population is bigger...because of immigrants (who probably eat&quot;ethnic food he he). But measuring size has little to do with it....the Twin Cities have less than 100,000 immigrants, which would have to include those asians...this can&apos;t touch suburban Toronto cities, let alone Toronto...Mississauga is the same size as the Twin Cities (population and land size), and has 3 times the immigrants. Forget Mississauga...Markham has more asians than the Twin Cities, and it&apos;s 1/3 the population.

KGB

Come on, you said&quot;In a city where the choices aren&apos;t limited to 5 similar american fast-food chains&quot;and&quot;and I&apos;m sure all 18 vietnamese people in Minn keep it in business too&quot;. You may not know much about the Twin Cities, but I&apos;m pretty sure you know what you said is complete B.S. and you know you were being a jackass. The whole&quot;18 vietnamese people&quot;in the Twin Cities is way, way off base. There are quite a bit more than 18 Vietnamese people here and St. Paul has the largest Hmong population in the United States. There is also a good chunk of Laotians and Cambodians too. Many of these Asians are second and third generation, so they aren&apos;t counted in the immigrant population. We all know Toronto is diverse and has a lot of ethnic restuarants but that doesn&apos;t mean you have put down another city to try to make a point. DrJoe May 24th, 2005, 07:47 PM How did a thread about hamburgers turn so controversial, lol. KGB May 24th, 2005, 08:31 PM &quot;The whole&quot;18 vietnamese people&quot;in the Twin Cities is way, way off base. There are quite a bit more than 18 Vietnamese people here&quot;


Really?? maybe you should count them...I&apos;m pretty sure there are only 18.






&quot;you know you were being a jackass.&quot;

Look dude...if all you can do is troll threads, and not understand humour, then maybe you should buzz off (or go eat some of that world-famous Twin Cities french food).

You&apos;re the one who came in here and picked a fight with me...so don&apos;t dish it if you can&apos;t take it.








KGB rt_0891 May 24th, 2005, 09:03 PM The Americans are invading the Canadian threads, lol. :D We&apos;ll scare them off with our quick wit and our tin-can army. marathon May 24th, 2005, 09:33 PM Of course the population is bigger...because of immigrants (who probably eat&quot;ethnic food he he). But measuring size has little to do with it....the Twin Cities have less than 100,000 immigrants, which would have to include those asians...this can&apos;t touch suburban Toronto cities, let alone Toronto...Mississauga is the same size as the Twin Cities (population and land size), and has 3 times the immigrants. Forget Mississauga...Markham has more asians than the Twin Cities, and it&apos;s 1/3 the population.



Alright, that Toronto has more than MSP is a given, and the Mississauga assertion is likely true as well, but when you jumped to Markham...I&apos;m not buying into that...

At least you didn&apos;t go the full route and jump to Halton Hills next...so you do have some restraint TooFar May 24th, 2005, 10:14 PM For the best chickenburger I have to go with Wendy&apos;s...mmmmm spicy chicken burger.

But for the best regular burger I have to go with Harvey&apos;s.

I usually always pick a chickenburger over a hamburger.

I agree with all of this^ samsonyuen May 24th, 2005, 10:35 PM I read an article maybe two years ago that ten years ago from then, the top 3 burger chains in terms of sales in Canada were McDonald&apos;s, Harvey&apos;s, and A&amp;W. Now it&apos;s the same as in the US, McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, and Wendy&apos;s. There are so many Wendy&apos;s popping up alongside Tim Horton&apos;s now! I wonder if the #4 US chain (Hardee&apos;s/Carl&apos;s Jr.) will make as great inroads. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 10:51 PM You&apos;re the one who came in here and picked a fight with me...so don&apos;t dish it if you can&apos;t take it.

KGB

If questioning that a trip to Burger King is an urban experiment, then I guess I&apos;m guilty of picking a fight. The anti-cheesehead May 24th, 2005, 10:53 PM The Americans are invading the Canadian threads, lol. :D We&apos;ll scare them off with our quick wit and our tin-can army.

It was just by chance that I saw this thread when I clicked on the North American threads. I&apos;m American and when I see the word&quot;Burgers...&quot;I just can&apos;t help but check it out. Buster May 24th, 2005, 10:57 PM Has anyone tried the Yellow Griffin burger in Swansea? Heard many good things from many people and it looks like there&apos;s an article on this thread that backs this assertion.

How about Kobe beef burgers? rt_0891 May 24th, 2005, 11:13 PM It was just by chance that I saw this thread when I clicked on the North American threads. I&apos;m American and when I see the word&quot;Burgers...&quot;I just can&apos;t help but check it out.

You take things too seriously, lol. Loosen up. :banana: philosopher May 28th, 2005, 08:12 AM LA BELLE PROVINCE. You know this one is tipicaly from Quebec. samsonyuen May 28th, 2005, 12:01 PM Don&apos;t forget Au Coq, I love that name, or Au Vieux Duluth (which is in Eastern Ontario too). -IAMQUBECOIS- May 29th, 2005, 12:47 AM LA BELLE PROVINCE. You know this one is tipicaly from Quebec.

Ouais esti! spongeg February 11th, 2009, 11:33 PM Carl&apos;s jr is opening in Surrey this year sometime - construction is underway now :) Huhu February 11th, 2009, 11:46 PM ^^ Hooray for greasy food! Still waiting for In and Out to get up here. :| Spoolmak February 12th, 2009, 01:11 AM In &apos;n Out is by far the BEST fast food I have ever eaten. I also thought Burger King was good until Kamloops&apos; franchise went under and I had it in Kelowna. The only thing I tasted on the whopper w/ cheese was the mayo. Spoolmak February 12th, 2009, 01:13 AM My last name is Harvey, and I have never eaten at a Harveys. I really should one day! Kamloops doesn&apos;t have one:( isaidso February 12th, 2009, 01:29 AM On that list Lick&apos;s is by far my favourite, but they&apos;re not a national chain. Same goes for Hero Burgers. Of the national chains, Harvey&apos;s is the only one I&apos;ll go to. spongeg February 12th, 2009, 02:13 AM i didn&apos;t like in n out - it wasn&apos;t that great

i thought fat burger in Langley was better PacificMetropolis February 12th, 2009, 05:08 AM Carl&apos;s jr is opening in Surrey this year sometime - construction is underway now :)

Wow they took their time! this is an ancient thread from 2005. Spoolmak February 12th, 2009, 05:22 AM i didn&apos;t like in n out - it wasn&apos;t that great

i thought fat burger in Langley was better

Im from Kamloops. I dont get much variety remember:cheers::lol: spongeg February 12th, 2009, 07:27 AM Wow they took their time! this is an ancient thread from 2005.

they have finally started to open up
took them a few years :nuts: Xelebes February 12th, 2009, 08:50 AM I like Burger Baron&apos;s mushroom burgers. CrazyCanuck February 12th, 2009, 09:01 AM Licks bar none. Gerrad February 12th, 2009, 03:14 PM Licks bar none.

I liked Licks at one time but haven&apos;t gone back since the drunken night about 2 decades ago when I found a curly hair in my fries. Taller, Better February 12th, 2009, 03:25 PM I liked Licks at one time but haven&apos;t gone back since the drunken night about 2 decades ago when I found a curly hair in my fries.

Are you sure you didn&apos;t find a curly fry in your hair? :D salvius February 12th, 2009, 04:28 PM Whoa. A dead thread revival. Apparently I already voted for Harvey&apos;s, though I think Lick&apos;s is actually the best. They also happen to be the only two chains where I can actually get something to eat... Riise February 12th, 2009, 06:09 PM Carl&apos;s jr is opening in Surrey this year sometime - construction is underway now :)

Blood hell!!! They are so going to break ground on a Calgary location the day I move to the U.K., I can fell the impending injustice. Canadian Chocho February 13th, 2009, 05:07 AM Hero&apos;s=WIN!!! Quall February 13th, 2009, 06:35 PM Maccas!

DQ actually has some pretty good burgers. spongeg February 15th, 2009, 11:29 PM do they still yell at Licks?

I had a friend who worked there and we would laugh when he had to yell

ho ho ho ho homeburger Spoolmak February 16th, 2009, 01:50 AM What is Licks? I have never heard of it? Is it just out of Ontario? If so then I think Triple O&apos;s should be on the poll if were allowing local fast food restaurants, but I don&apos;t think Local Fast Food Restaurants should be polled because Locals are more likely to choose a local fast food restaurant than a mass chain spongeg February 16th, 2009, 03:17 AM you can buy licks burgers frozen at urban fare - maybe save-on foods too

http://www.lickshomeburgers.com/products/homeburgerbox.jpg Spoolmak February 17th, 2009, 02:21 AM Man does that ever look good... Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 02:28 AM Licks burgers are pretty amazing. So thick and juicy. Rumors February 17th, 2009, 02:34 AM I like my Whoppers. :) Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 02:44 AM For big chains I still prefer Wendys! :eat:

But I have not had a hamburger at a chain since the summer. Rumors February 17th, 2009, 03:04 AM I like Wendy&apos;s too, Harvey&apos;s put fillers in their burgers. :ohno: Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 03:09 AM I like the concept of Harvey&apos;s, and I like the&quot;fixins&quot;, but the meat always tastes&quot;odd&quot;to me. I almost prefer their veggie burger. Their Black Angus burger is ok, but not a lot different than the regular one. They have very good onion rings and pretty good milkshakes. McDonald&apos;s, for all its faults, makes a wicked Oreo McFlurry. Has anyone ever gagged down one of those ghastly breakfast burritos at McD&apos;s? Rumors February 17th, 2009, 03:24 AM I like the concept of Harvey&apos;s, and I like the&quot;fixins&quot;, but the meat always tastes&quot;odd&quot;to me. I almost prefer their veggie burger. Their Black Angus burger is ok, but not a lot different than the regular one. They have very good onion rings and pretty good milkshakes. McDonald&apos;s, for all its faults, makes a wicked Oreo McFlurry. Has anyone ever gagged down one of those ghastly breakfast burritos at McD&apos;s?

Not me. :lol: Spoolmak February 17th, 2009, 04:53 AM I like egg McMuffins. I mean what could they possibly do to their eggs? :P Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 05:07 AM A Sausage McMuffin with Egg is total hangover food! Loads of grease and salt! :lol:
sort of a morning equivalent of 3 am poutine! hehe Spoolmak February 17th, 2009, 05:47 AM I got arrested one Halloween enjoying a 3 am poutine from A&amp;W. Another fast food restaurant that should be polled. SPQR February 17th, 2009, 05:50 AM lol, I love it, the only thing I miss about mexico when I&apos;m in canada are tacos and carl&apos;s jr, now if they could open a whataburger in montreal I&apos;ll be happy forever. Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 05:54 AM I got arrested one Halloween enjoying a 3 am poutine from A&amp;W. Another fast food restaurant that should be polled.

Were you arrested for unhealthy food choice? LOL!
Poutine is the ultimate junk food. Spoolmak February 17th, 2009, 05:54 AM Well open up for poutine and Whale blubber! Spoolmak February 17th, 2009, 05:58 AM Were you arrested for unhealthy food choice? LOL!
Poutine is the ultimate junk food.

LOL no, if that were the case I would probably be in maximum security prison 25 to life.:lol:That reminded me of that Wendy&apos;s commercial where the two guys are saying that if&quot;loving bacon is a crime then lock me up!&quot; Taller, Better February 17th, 2009, 06:00 AM Peameal bacon sandwiches at St Lawrence Market are an old Toronto standby. You have not lived till you sink your teeth into a thick succulent pile of hot Peameal bacon on a crusty Kaiser roll! Mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm

http://i82.photobucket.com/albums/j251/dawnd_01/WINTER%202008/Winter%20Part%20Two%202009/oct3105OinkonabunStLawrenceMarketi.jpg vid February 17th, 2009, 06:54 AM Harvey&apos;s is coming back to Thunder Bay. About ten years ago the only one here was turned into a Tim Horton&apos;s. I&apos;ve never been there, at least that I can remember. spongeg March 5th, 2009, 08:35 AM you must be on pins and needles thomyorke26 March 5th, 2009, 09:15 AM Does anyone knows if Carl&apos;s Jr is Planning to Open in Quebec, i Mean in Montreal?

I love Carl&apos;s Jr, and i love my Whoopers also from BK.

what about applebee&apos;s?,

I think the best chain in Burgers is BK and Applebee&apos;s.

Why the state of Quebec Doesn&apos;t have this kind of chains, we don&apos;t have applebee&apos;s, carl&apos;s jr, TGI Fridays, etc, it is unfair, we must to get this kind of chains.

anyway. Taller, Better March 5th, 2009, 06:02 PM I think some of those are in the West only. I don&apos;t recall seeing a Carl&apos;s jr, TGI or Applebees here either, but I haven&apos;t really been looking.
Jack Astor&apos;s has been expanding like crazy this past year. I think it is mostly a Toronto chain, but they are also moving into some States and
one in Quebec, I believe. CrazyCanuck March 5th, 2009, 08:20 PM Come to the burbs Taller, plenty of Applebee&apos;s. I live about 5 minutes from one. Taller, Better March 5th, 2009, 08:23 PM Can you picture Taller, Better on his trusty old bicycle whizzing up to Markham? :lol: CrazyCanuck March 5th, 2009, 11:08 PM I can lol. Applebees is actually one of my favourite chain restuarants. Taller, Better March 6th, 2009, 07:09 AM What kind of food is it? thomyorke26 March 6th, 2009, 07:31 AM I think some of those are in the West only. I don&apos;t recall seeing a Carl&apos;s jr, TGI or Applebees here either, but I haven&apos;t really been looking.
Jack Astor&apos;s has been expanding like crazy this past year. I think it is mostly a Toronto chain, but they are also moving into some States and
one in Quebec, I believe.


Well, actually i saw one TGI Fridays and one Apleebee&apos;s in Niagara Falls, that&apos;s why i&apos;m asking you guys if you know about the chains getting into Quebec State?

anyway, i love applebee&apos;s.


Taller,Better, you can check on the link below.

http://www.applebees.com/MenuLandingStatic.aspx isaidso March 6th, 2009, 09:35 AM What kind of food is it?

My first introduction to Applebee&apos;s was on a trip to Grand Rapids, Minnesota in 2007. They serve typical Canadian fare and plaster local sports memorabilia all over the place. It&apos;s a bit of a sensory over load, but not obnoxious in the way that East Side Mario&apos;s is.

One great characteristic was the mini desserts they offer for $1.99! I never have room for dessert, so it&apos;s the only restaurant I&apos;ve been to where I can order a dessert that will get finished. Usually, I only have room for one or two bites which is about the size of their mini desserts. Sold!

I never visit chains like Applebee&apos;s or Boston Pizza, but they are unavoidable in the boonies or suburbia. Choices are severely limited way out there. When I was in the north and drive through places like Barrie, places like this that I&apos;d normally not bother with, become a welcome sight. Taller, Better March 6th, 2009, 06:15 PM Ah! Thanks for the info, Thom and isaidso. I knew I had seen an Applebees and a TG its Friday signs somewhere, and I&apos;ll bet it was in Niagara Falls. They also have a Rainforest Cafe, which is kitchy but probably very fun for kids. I ordered the ribs platter and it was quite possibly the best ribs I have had in many years. But seriously we could have shared one platter between the two of us and still been very full... it was like a massive Fred Flintstone meal on an oval plate about a foot and a half wide, with the big slab of ribs hanging over either end. Meat Fest! :D HipHopCanada March 6th, 2009, 09:36 PM Harveys.. and where&apos;s A&amp;W?! vid March 7th, 2009, 12:12 AM Applebee&apos;s is disgusting. They&apos;re like Swiss Chalet.&quot;We&apos;re supposed to COOK the chicken?!!1WTFBBQ1!&quot;

The vicinity of our Applebee&apos;s smells like burning. thomyorke26 March 7th, 2009, 01:14 AM Harveys.. and where&apos;s A&amp;W?!

We got some A&amp;W here in Montreal, Probably one of the best burgers i have ever eaten, but i realize they are over the country. vid March 7th, 2009, 01:27 AM A&amp;W rivals McDonald&apos;s in Northern Ontario. Many communities here have A&amp;W but not McDonald&apos;s. I think Thunder Bay is the only city where McDonald&apos;s outnumbers them. When you compare the two, McDonald&apos;s hamburger is like a piece a cardboard soaked in hamburger fat. thomyorke26 March 7th, 2009, 02:41 AM ^^^^I Did not know A&amp;W was a Rival of Mcdonald&apos;s, we Have a lot of Mcdonald&apos;s Here in Montreal, in each corner you can find one of them, i&apos;m kidding, but the number of Mcdonald&apos;s here is absolutely tremendous, even more than A&amp;W. Taller, Better March 7th, 2009, 07:08 PM I love A&amp;W because when I was young it was one of the few fast food outlets. I still love a TeenBurger with onion rings and Root Beer!! :D

Winnipegger&apos;s will also be familiar with The Salisbury House (one of the first fast food type restaurants in Canada) which I always visit when I go there, for a Mr Big Nip with fried onions. The gravy for their fries is like thick grey-brown Elmer&apos;s Safety Glue! CrazyCanuck March 7th, 2009, 07:19 PM My first introduction to Applebee&apos;s was on a trip to Grand Rapids, Minnesota in 2007. They serve typical Canadian fare and plaster local sports memorabilia all over the place. It&apos;s a bit of a sensory over load, but not obnoxious in the way that East Side Mario&apos;s is.

One great characteristic was the mini desserts they offer for $1.99! I never have room for dessert, so it&apos;s the only restaurant I&apos;ve been to where I can order a dessert that will get finished. Usually, I only have room for one or two bites which is about the size of their mini desserts. Sold!

I never visit chains like Applebee&apos;s or Boston Pizza, but they are unavoidable in the boonies or suburbia. Choices are severely limited way out there. When I was in the north and drive through places like Barrie, places like this that I&apos;d normally not bother with, become a welcome sight.



I live in a place where the concentration of chain restaurants is amazingly high. Applebees, Boston Pizza, Casey&apos;s, Kelesy&apos;s, Montana&apos;s,the Keg, used to be East Side Mario&apos;s and Shoeless Joes but they closed down. Nickles owned by Celine Dion, but that closed down too. As well as a Wendy&apos;s, Tim Horton(4), KFC, Harvey&apos;s, McDonald&apos;s, Pizza Pizza(2), Spoolmak March 8th, 2009, 12:40 AM I chose other for A&amp;W. rockin&apos;.baltimorean March 8th, 2009, 05:43 AM mickey d&apos;s, baby!!:okay: vid March 8th, 2009, 08:39 AM I Did not know A&amp;W was a Rival of Mcdonald&apos;s

A&amp;W is quite big in small town markets. If a community in Northwestern Ontario has a fast food outlet, it&apos;s either Subway or A&amp;W. Mcdonald&apos;s and Pizza Hut are secondary. (The subway is only there with Mac&apos;s, which is everywhere since they keep buying all the local convenience store chains.) isaidso March 8th, 2009, 05:26 PM I live in a place where the concentration of chain restaurants is amazingly high. Applebees, Boston Pizza, Casey&apos;s, Kelesy&apos;s, Montana&apos;s,the Keg, used to be East Side Mario&apos;s and Shoeless Joes but they closed down. Nickles owned by Celine Dion, but that closed down too. As well as a Wendy&apos;s, Tim Horton(4), KFC, Harvey&apos;s, McDonald&apos;s, Pizza Pizza(2),

Out of that list I&apos;ve been to Applebee&apos;s twice, and Boston Pizza three times. Been to Wendy&apos;s probably 10 times, KFC only when I was a kid, McDonald&apos;s may be three times in the past 20 years, Pizza Pizza a handful of times, and Tim&apos;s too many times to count.

East Side Mario&apos;s, Montana&apos;s, the Keg, Shoeless Joe&apos;s, Kelsey&apos;s, and Casey&apos;s? Never been to any of them. Taller, Better March 8th, 2009, 07:25 PM The Keg is excellent value for the money. Especially the Keg Mansion on Jarvis Street, which is really a pleasure to dine in. I doubt a person could get a juicy big rib eye steak with the sides that come with it, at any other restaurant for the money spent. Give it a whirl! :) isaidso March 8th, 2009, 07:31 PM Thanks for the advice. I just got out of jaw surgery 2 weeks ago and have been on a liquid diet for 2 and a half weeks because my jaws are wired shut. I plan to gorge on a mighty feast as soon as the wires come off.

A fat juicy rib eye steak sounds very good to me. Cripes, a timbit sounds great at this point.

:cry: Taller, Better March 8th, 2009, 07:54 PM Thanks for the advice. I just got out of jaw surgery 2 weeks ago and have been on a liquid diet for 2 and a half weeks because my jaws are wired shut. I plan to gorge on a mighty feast as soon as the wires come off.

A fat juicy rib eye steak sounds very good to me. Cripes, a timbit sounds great at this point.

:cry:

Also give Sambucca&apos;s on Church Street a whirl. They have a $25 prix fixe that is astounding. Choice of Ceaser salad or soup of the day, and the main course choice has about 12 items. I always choose the veal chop or the steak. Then creme brulee or Kaluha Timisu (the best one) all for $25. A true bargain!
The Keg rib eye is a better steak, however. isaidso March 9th, 2009, 03:33 AM Perhaps, I&apos;ll eat at the Keg, then Sambucca&apos;s. Rumors March 9th, 2009, 03:49 AM The Keg is excellent value for the money. Especially the Keg Mansion on Jarvis Street, which is really a pleasure to dine in. I doubt a person could get a juicy big rib eye steak with the sides that come with it, at any other restaurant for the money spent. Give it a whirl! :)

I ate at the one on airport road many times, I always stay at the Marriott hotel when I fly into Toronto for business. I got really trashed in a few of those hotel bars, also the Marriott has an awesome buffet restaurant. I like that area of TO .:) Taller, Better March 9th, 2009, 06:52 AM I ate at the one on airport road many times, I always stay at the Marriott hotel when I fly into Toronto for business. I got really trashed in a few of those hotel bars, also the Marriott has an awesome buffet restaurant. I like that area of TO .:)

LOL! I&apos;ve never really been in the airport area other than to catch a plane! If I did I would be tempted to dash across that busy highway and get blotto at one of those trashy strip joints! hehe....
Your company is cruel, but not unusual, for making you stay out at the airport. Huhu March 10th, 2009, 01:15 AM Thanks for the advice. I just got out of jaw surgery 2 weeks ago and have been on a liquid diet for 2 and a half weeks because my jaws are wired shut. I plan to gorge on a mighty feast as soon as the wires come off.

A fat juicy rib eye steak sounds very good to me. Cripes, a timbit sounds great at this point.

:cry:
Ouch I had jaw surgery a few years ago and was on a liquid diet for a couple months. I lost like 10-15 pounds lol. Of course my first day back from the hospital my family eats a big feast of fried chicken right in front of me. Gee thanks guys... isaidso March 10th, 2009, 02:34 AM Ouch I had jaw surgery a few years ago and was on a liquid diet for a couple months. I lost like 10-15 pounds lol. Of course my first day back from the hospital my family eats a big feast of fried chicken right in front of me. Gee thanks guys...

A couple months? OMG, I&apos;m at my wits end. I keep thinking I&apos;m almost there, then my specialist tells me he&apos;s keeping it all fastened shut. I don&apos;t have 10lbs to lose. I don&apos;t have 1lb to lose.
:cry:
The jaw looks great, so I&apos;m happy about that. Taller, Better March 10th, 2009, 06:48 AM OMG a liquid diet for two weeks.. that is horrible. Was the jaw out of alignment? Huhu March 10th, 2009, 08:53 AM A couple months? OMG, I&apos;m at my wits end. I keep thinking I&apos;m almost there, then my specialist tells me he&apos;s keeping it all fastened shut. I don&apos;t have 10lbs to lose. I don&apos;t have 1lb to lose.
:cry:
The jaw looks great, so I&apos;m happy about that.
Yeah it&apos;s worth it in the end but the first few weeks are hell. I had a serious under-bite that needed to be fixed. They shortened my bottom jaw and also cut loose my upper jaw and moved it forward. My face was the size of a basketball out of surgery. I have screws and plates in my face permanently but I don&apos;t feel them. isaidso March 10th, 2009, 09:38 PM Yeah it&apos;s worth it in the end but the first few weeks are hell. I had a serious under-bite that needed to be fixed. They shortened my bottom jaw and also cut loose my upper jaw and moved it forward. My face was the size of a basketball out of surgery. I have screws and plates in my face permanently but I don&apos;t feel them.

I didn&apos;t have to have my upper jaw moved, but I did have my chin tilted in addition to my lower jaw re-alignment. Despite the pain and discomfort, I&apos;m really happy with the result. I&apos;ve stopped taking pain killers, and it looks really good. I have permanent screws and plates as well. I&apos;ll admit I was a little worried whether I was going to be a pretty boy after all this work.

OMG a liquid diet for two weeks.. that is horrible. Was the jaw out of alignment?

Yes, my lower jaw was about 4 mm back or what&apos;s commonly called an &apos;overbite&apos;. I&apos;ve been wearing braces for 1.5 years, so now that my teeth are straight, they didn&apos;t meet up any more. My lower jaw was moved forward 4mm.

I was on morpheine for a day and a half, and Tylenol 3&apos;s for the past 2.5 weeks. All I&apos;ve had to eat since then is strained Cream of Wheat, juice, strained soup, smashed up jello, apple sauce, and meal replacement drinks. I even had to consume everything using a syringe for 10 days straight. Smashed up pills mixed with juice went in the syringe as well. Thankfully, now I can drink out of a mug.

MMMMMM BURGERS!!!! isaidso March 10th, 2009, 10:03 PM I&apos;ve certainly been obsessed with food the past 3 weeks. So much so that I went online to find out what the largest Canadian fast food chains are by number of outlets. I was going to post it in the &apos;Canadian Business&apos; thread, but this is as good a place as any.

Keep in mind that this these are numbers I pulled off the net. They may not be fully up to date, and I may have missed some Canadian fast food chains. I omitted Manchu Wok because they are owned by a Hong Kong company and I&apos;m not sure if they are managed from Canada any more.

The biggest surprise was how many countries Yogen Fruz operates in. Other surprises: the expansion of Coffee Time into Greece, Poland, and China; New York Fries in the UAE, South Korea, and China; Pizza Nova in Cuba; and the availability of Tim Horton&apos;s products in the UK and Ireland.

CANADA&apos;S TOP 20! All the chains operate only in Canada unless indicated otherwise.

1. Tim Horton&apos;s 3,437: USA, Ireland*, UK*, Afghanistan*
2. Yogen Fruz 1,100: 23 countries**
3. A&amp;W*** 683
4. Pizza Pizza 650
5. Country Style 505

6. Mr. Sub 450
7. Boston Pizza 314
8. Coffee Time 300: Greece, Poland, China
9. Harvey&apos;s 286
10. Robin&apos;s Donuts 240

11. Pita Pit 220: USA
12. New York Fries 201: United Arab Emirates, South Korea, China, USA
13. Swiss Chalet 200: USA
14. Pizza Delight 180
15. Panago 175

16. Greco Pizza 170
17. Extreme Pita 150: USA
18. La Belle Province 125
19. Pizza Nova 120: USA, Cuba
20. St-Hubert 97

*The Tim Horton&apos;s outlets in Ireland and the UK aren&apos;t full outlets while the outlet in Afghanistan services US, UK, and Canadian troops in Kandahar.
**Yogen Fruz operates in Canada, Bolivia, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, China, Dominican Republic, El Salvador, France, Guatemala, Honduras, Indonesia, Japan, Poland, Puerto Rico, Saudi Arabia, Singapore, Thailand, United Kingdom, Venezuela, the USA, Greece, and the Ukraine.
***A&amp;W was originally part of the US chain called A&amp;W, but no longer has any connection to that chain. It&apos;s an independent Canadian based fast food company. isaidso March 10th, 2009, 10:47 PM As a point of interest, here are the number of outlets for a few of the big foreign chains that operate in Canada:

1. Subway 2,403
2. McDonald&apos;s 1,375
3. Dairy Queen 479
4. Quiznos 430
5. KFC 370
6. Wendy&apos;s 370
7. Burger King 345
8. Dominos Pizza 300
9. Burger King 180
10. Taco Bel 175 Huhu March 10th, 2009, 11:23 PM Great work, I didn&apos;t even realize that New York Fries and Boston Pizza are Canadian companies. What about coffee shops like Blenz?

Since you&apos;re obsessed with food, here&apos;s a pic of a burger:
http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_I8SyiXYp9zc/SEiYGiHXHPI/AAAAAAAAAuM/zlEgrfy7QdU/s400/a%26w%2BTeen.bmp vid March 10th, 2009, 11:57 PM I have an underbite but I didn&apos;t get no sissy surgery to fix it. I&quot;deal&quot;. Ts&apos;how it goes.

That burger is crap, btw. Know why? White onions. Those have no place on a burger. You put RED onion on burgers. It&apos;s more flavorful. isaidso March 11th, 2009, 12:26 AM I have an underbite but I didn&apos;t get no sissy surgery to fix it. I&quot;deal&quot;. Ts&apos;how it goes.


Some people want to have nice teeth. If you&apos;re going to go through the trouble, you may as well do it right. There were other issues to consider as well. The possibility of developing arthritis in my jaw due to my malocclusion certainly helped in my decision. Better physical symmetry was a nice bonus. I guess you&apos;re a tougher cookie than I, but sissy? I realize you&apos;re being obnoxious which is sort of cute, but I was in the army and this was procedure wasn&apos;t exactly a cake walk. Sissy? OK, I&apos;m a sissy.

Great work, I didn&apos;t even realize that New York Fries and Boston Pizza are Canadian companies. What about coffee shops like Blenz?

Since you&apos;re obsessed with food, here&apos;s a pic of a burger:
http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_I8SyiXYp9zc/SEiYGiHXHPI/AAAAAAAAAuM/zlEgrfy7QdU/s400/a%26w%2BTeen.bmp

Thanks. I do a lot of research on Canadiana, be it history, sports, trivia, geography, culture, etc. New York Fries was started by 2 Brantford brothers who discovered a small french fry stand in New York. They liked them so much they bought it and started a company based on it. Despite the company name, there are no locations in New York City, or in the United States as of October 4, 2008.

Boston Pizza has nothing to do with pizza from Boston. This Canadian eatery that was named by its Edmonton founder after his favourite NHL team, the Boston Bruins. It&apos;s headquarters are now in Richmond, BC.

Blenz? They&apos;re a Canadian chain with 82 locations in Canada, the Philippines, the United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, China, and Japan. I believe they&apos;re the most international of Canada&apos;s coffee chains, but I didn&apos;t include coffee chains in my list, only fast food chains. Granted, some of the donut chains I listed are only barely passable as fast food, but I did attempt to differentiate between the two.

I suppose the other big coffee chains would be Second Cup, Timothy&apos;s, Lettieri&apos;s, and A.L. Van Houtte. Thank you for the burger pic. I&apos;ll pretend that I&apos;m eating it when I go to sleep tonight. vid March 11th, 2009, 12:32 AM Fries with the skin left on them is how every locally owned fast food place up here makes them, they&apos;re better that way. IIRC, that&apos;s how New York Fries makes them. That&apos;s why they&apos;re so good. isaidso March 11th, 2009, 12:53 AM Fries with the skin left on them is how every locally owned fast food place up here makes them, they&apos;re better that way. IIRC, that&apos;s how New York Fries makes them. That&apos;s why they&apos;re so good.

Perhaps, you should start your own Thunder Bay based french fry company and give New York Fries a run for their money? Thunder Bay could certainly do with a successful home grown multi national and the money would buy you as many airline tickets to where ever you wanted to go.

French fry company may not be your dream job, but it would open up a lot of doors for you. You&apos;re a smart boy. I&apos;m sure you could pull it off. Robin&apos;s Donuts was founded in Thunder Bay, so it proves you don&apos;t need to be in a big city to succeed. Robin&apos;s Donuts is #10 on that list above and was sold for $30 million back in 2000. vid March 11th, 2009, 01:14 AM I could buy on the confectioneries and turn them into one company and go global! spongeg March 11th, 2009, 01:51 AM belle frites on davie street is really good

i can&apos;t remember if they have skin on or not hmmm

another burger pic... (white spot)

http://johnwang.smugmug.com/photos/469616274_VoaEh-M.jpg
http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3061/2697828728_cf729e93fa.jpg?v=0 Huhu March 11th, 2009, 01:52 AM I have an underbite but I didn&apos;t get no sissy surgery to fix it. I&quot;deal&quot;. Ts&apos;how it goes.

That burger is crap, btw. Know why? White onions. Those have no place on a burger. You put RED onion on burgers. It&apos;s more flavorful.
I was born with cleft lip and palate, along with a misaligned jaw with an under-bite. In and out of surgery for twenty years. Believe me, I would have rather avoided all of it if I could have.

And I agree with the red onion thing but I&apos;ve never seen it on a fast food burger, only in real restaurants. Shallots would work good too IMO. :colgate: isaidso March 11th, 2009, 02:10 AM I could buy on the confectioneries and turn them into one company and go global!

That&apos;s right. Conquer the world, obliterate the competition.... oh yeah, provide great jobs for Thunder Bay people.

OK, I must be really bored because I&apos;ve just compiled the coffee shop chain version of my previous list. I didn&apos;t include donut chains like Tim&apos;s, Coffee Time, Country Style, and Robin&apos;s Donuts. They&apos;re in the other list.

Top Canadian coffee house chains by number of outlets

1. Second Cup 375: *11 countries
2. Timothy&apos;s World Coffee 141: South Korea
3. Blenz 82: Japan, China, United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, Philippines
4. A.L. Van Houtte** 70
5. Coffee Culture 31: USA
6. Nebur-King Coffee*** 29: China
7. Lettieri&apos;s 14
8. Waves Coffee House 13
8. Caffe Artigiano 13
10. Bridgehead 9
10. Java Express 9


* Besides Canada, Second Cup operates in the USA, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, Lebanon, Turkey, Jordan, Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, and Syria.
** A.L. Van Houtte is actually the largest company of the lot. Coffee retailing is only a small part of their coffee empire. The bulk of their business is selling coffee and coffee machines to 71,000 offices around north America and A.L. Van Houtte branded coffee to grocery chains. They also sell to cafeterias, restaurants, convenience stores, and hotels. They are the largest such coffee company on the continent. They were bought by a private US equity firm in 2007 for $600 milllion, but continue to be based and operated out of Montreal as an independent firm under their own brand.
*** Nebur-King Coffee is rapidly expanding in China and is also diversifying. spongeg March 11th, 2009, 02:11 AM Onions of any kind are gross on a burger

I always ask for them without Huhu March 11th, 2009, 02:19 AM Great list. What&apos;s Timothy&apos;s World Coffee? Never heard of it but it looks like it&apos;s pretty big.

Maybe you should also add Waves Coffee House, which has 13 locations around Metro Vancouver. isaidso March 11th, 2009, 02:27 AM Great list. What&apos;s Timothy&apos;s World Coffee? Never heard of it but it looks like it&apos;s pretty big.
Maybe you should also add Waves Coffee House, which has 13 locations around Metro Vancouver.

Timothy&apos;s World Coffee is a Toronto based chain, and the 3rd largest Canadian owned chain after Tim Horton&apos;s and Second Cup. In the late 1990s, Timothy&apos;s expanded into the United States, concentrating in New York City. Other stores were located in Boston, Washington, and Philadelphia. At one point, it was New York City&apos;s second-largest coffeehouse chain, after Starbucks. The US business never performed well. After 9/11 the company closed its American operations and the company refocused on the Canadian market.

Timothy&apos;s opened its first overseas store in Seoul, Republic of South Korea on May 19, 2007. Timothy&apos;s Korea plans to open more than 50 Timothy&apos;s World Coffee stores in the South Korean Market over the next several years.

Timothy&apos;s bought out the Grabbajabba and Mmmuffins chains a number of years ago. Mmmufins still operates separately, but I believe Grabbajabba was incorporated into Timothy&apos;s. I&apos;ll add Waves Coffee House to the list above. Thanks for the information.


A true Canadian original, the bison burger. It&apos;s become a very trendy Canadian food choice of late in New York and show signs of catching on in Paris too.

Brico Restaurant, Calmar, Alberta
http://www.bricco.ca/images/BisonBurger.jpg
http://www.bricco.ca/images/BisonBurger.jpg

Another variation on the bision burger
http://www.blogcdn.com/www.slashfood.com/media/2009/02/bison020409.jpg
http://www.blogcdn.com/www.slashfood.com/media/2009/02/bison020409.jpg Spoolmak March 11th, 2009, 02:28 AM what does IIRC stand for :D spongeg March 11th, 2009, 07:51 AM That&apos;s right. Conquer the world, obliterate the competition.... oh yeah, provide great jobs for Thunder Bay people.

OK, I must be really bored because I&apos;ve just compiled the coffee shop chain version of my previous list. I didn&apos;t include donut chains like Tim&apos;s, Coffee Time, Country Style, and Robin&apos;s Donuts. They&apos;re in the other list.

Top Canadian coffee house chains by number of outlets

1. Second Cup 375: *11 countries
2. Timothy&apos;s World Coffee 141: South Korea
3. Blenz 82: Japan, China, United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, Philippines
4. A.L. Van Houtte** 70
5. Coffee Culture 31: USA
6. Nebur-King Coffee*** 29: China
7. Lettieri&apos;s 14
8. Waves Coffee House 13
9. Bridgehead 9

* Besides Canada, Second Cup operates in the USA, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, Lebanon, Turkey, Jordan, Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, and Syria.
** A.L. Van Houtte is actually the largest company of the lot. Coffee retailing is only a small part of their coffee empire. The bulk of their business is selling coffee and coffee machines to 71,000 offices around north America and A.L. Van Houtte branded coffee to grocery chains. They also sell to cafeterias, restaurants, convenience stores, and hotels. They are the largest such coffee company on the continent. They were bought by a private US equity firm in 2007 for $600 milllion, but continue to be based and operated out of Montreal as an independent firm under their own brand.
*** Nebur-King Coffee is rapidly expanding in China and is also diversifying.

what about Cafe Artigiano? - it has 13 locations in BC and Alberta

from the coffee lovers I know they all say it is the best coffee hands down

I have to believe them since I hate coffee

http://caffeartigiano.com/images/banner/CafeArtigianoBanner_01.png

http://vancouvercoffee.files.wordpress.com/2007/07/artigiano03.jpg

they are not a place to go for free internet but for good coffee... Taller, Better March 11th, 2009, 07:59 AM I am not a true coffee aficionado, or amateur barista by any stretch of the imagination, but Timothy&apos;s is my IDEAL coffee. I buy a pound of their Kona blend ($13 and change) every two weeks and it is, to me, dreamy. I just revel in it every single morning! PLUS their hot chocolate mixes are very good (banana; hazelnut). My friends from England stock up on those hot chocolate mixes when they go home, and also they go crazy for Icy Capps at Tim Hortons. They are strangely delicious ( I guess sugar and cream will do that ;) ) and are as addictive as crack.

I used to be a Second Cup fan, but switched allegiance to Timothy&apos;s. I do not drink Starbucks coffee as I find the dark roast horribly strong, and I also find the whole Lactose-intolerant-skinnny-Lawtay-Grawnday thing to be anal and pretentious.

My favourite coffee house is Balzac&apos;s at the Distillery District. The smell of the roasting green beans is worth the bicycle ride over, but again the roast is a bit
dark for me. My god that coffee has flavour, though. Mill Street uses it in their Coffee Porter beer. Yum. :cheers: Huhu March 11th, 2009, 08:05 AM There&apos;s also Java Express with 9 locations in 3 provinces.

I&apos;m sure there&apos;s a few more small chains based out of Vancouver and Toronto kicking around. vid March 11th, 2009, 02:51 PM There is a place outside of Thunder Bay that has been serving Bison burgers for years. They&apos;re good.

I don&apos;t understand how one can have a hamburger without onion. Much of the time the only thing on my burger is onions and coney sauce. Taller, Better March 11th, 2009, 06:10 PM I think the domestically raised Bison in Canada is an animal that is half Buffalo and half cattle... but I could be wrong. To me it tastes just like beef only a bit drier. The meat is very lean. My favourite burgers are the ones made with Prime Rib. Those melt in your mouth.
I remember bison being served probably 30 years ago; a lot of them were raised in Manitoba. isaidso March 11th, 2009, 06:31 PM Spongeg and Huhu: thanks for the info. I will update the list.


I don&apos;t understand how one can have a hamburger without onion. Much of the time the only thing on my burger is onions and coney sauce.

What&apos;s coney sauce?

I think the domestically raised Bison in Canada is an animal that is half Buffalo and half cattle... but I could be wrong. To me it tastes just like beef only a bit drier. The meat is very lean. My favourite burgers are the ones made with Prime Rib. Those melt in your mouth.
I remember bison being served probably 30 years ago; a lot of them were raised in Manitoba.

A bison/buffalo sighting was one of the highlights of my Manitoba trip. The animal nearly became extinct, so it was good to see them thriving once again on the Great Plains. You&apos;re right about how lean and delicious they are. If you&apos;re ever on College check out the bison burger at Utopia in Little Italy. I dare you to finish the whole thing!

Referring back to your earlier post, is Balzac that coffee house with the 20 foot celings? The room is almost as high as it is wide and in a very old building. I believe you posted a photo of it in your &apos;Hot off the Press&apos; photo thread. Free ranging herds can still be found in America. 1 is in northern Mexico, 2 are in the USA, and 2 in Canada. By the way, according to wikipedia, the American buffalo and the bison is the same animal.

&quot;Buffalo&quot;is somewhat of a misnomer for this animal, as it is only distantly related to either of the two&quot;true buffaloes&quot;, the Asian buffalo (or&quot;water buffalo&quot;) and the African buffalo. However,&quot;bison&quot;is a Greek word meaning ox-like animal, while&quot;buffalo&quot;originated with the French fur trappers who called these massive beasts boeufs, meaning ox or bullock. So both names,&quot;bison&quot;and&quot;buffalo,&quot;have a similar meaning.

The bison once inhabited the Grasslands of North America and Asia in massive herds, ranging from the Great Slave Lake in Canada&apos;s far north, through the United States to Mexico in the south, and from eastern Oregon almost to the Atlantic Ocean, taking its subspecies into account. Its two subspecies are the Plains Bison, distinguished by its smaller size and more rounded hump, and the Wood Bison, distinguished by its larger size and taller square hump. Wood Bison are one of the largest species of cattle in the world, surpassed in size only by the massive Asian gaur and Wild Asian Water Buffalo, both of which are found mainly in India and Southeast Asia. It is also the largest extant land animal in North America.

Bison/Buffalo
http://www.bbqblog.ca/Bison.jpg
http://www.bbqblog.ca/Bison.jpg Taller, Better March 11th, 2009, 06:52 PM Bison and Buffalo might be the same animal, but I think they breed them with cattle for commercial raising in Canada. At least they used to.
I think the Coney sauce is probably a sauce used traditional on Coney Island in New York for hamburgers or hot dogs. isaidso March 11th, 2009, 07:17 PM I don&apos;t know enough about it to know for sure, but from what I read, 95% are privately owned and bred to exaggerate certain genetic features. This is much like we do with cows. Some are bred for milk, some for meat. The remaining 5% are free ranging herds where natural selection occurs. Taller, Better March 11th, 2009, 07:37 PM I was just going by what farmers said when I was younger, about the domestically raised bison not being full blood bison, but a mixed breed. Maybe it is different today.
You were probably thinking of Balzac&apos;s coffee house in the Distillery District... it is absolutely fantastic and I urge you to visit it this spring or summer. vid March 11th, 2009, 10:11 PM I think the domestically raised Bison in Canada is an animal that is half Buffalo and half cattle... but I could be wrong.

When I explained it like that you said I was wrong, so you must be too.

Coney Sauce is a topping on hamburgers that is extremely common here. It&apos;s composition varies, but it usually has onions and tomato paste in it. New York style has ground beef and some places will include that. (Carrie&apos;s Corner in PA does, and their burgers are HUGE.) There is also mustard and spices and sometimes things like mayonnaise, HP sauce, I think there are a couple places that use the hamburger grease as a base and make it a sort of hamburger fat-mustard-tomato-onion gravy. It really varies and you have to go around and find what you like.

Another common food here is hamburger nip, which is a hamburger (or cheese burger or whatever) with fries and gravy on everything, eaten with a knife and fork. Hot hamburger sandwich is the same thing but served on bread. CanadianCentaur March 12th, 2009, 01:24 AM Bison and Buffalo might be the same animal, but I think they breed them with cattle for commercial raising in Canada. At least they used to.


Buffalo and bison refer to the same animal here in North America.

I&apos;ve heard of buffalo being crossbred with cattle, though that&apos;s not done too often probably due to fertility problems and the fact that bison can be difficult to deal with (You don&apos;t want to get too close to a buffalo on hormones!). Such a hybrid is known as a&quot;beefalo&quot;.

However, people do have buffalo farms. I&apos;ve seen few of them in Northern Alberta, especially in the Peace. A relative of my sister in law runs a buffalo farm north of Grande Prairie.

A&amp;W rivals McDonald&apos;s in Northern Ontario. Many communities here have A&amp;W but not McDonald&apos;s. I think Thunder Bay is the only city where McDonald&apos;s outnumbers them. When you compare the two, McDonald&apos;s hamburger is like a piece a cardboard soaked in hamburger fat.

I see much the same situation in Northern Alberta and BC, too.

A&amp;W tends to have some of the best burgers of any fast food chain, IMO. Especially the Mozza and the Double Mozza, even though they can get a bit greasy. spongeg March 12th, 2009, 01:46 AM coney sauce is an Ontario thing - I remember when i moved there wondering what the heck it was and why people would want it

there was a place where I grew up called Buffalo Bills - it served buffalo meat - I don&apos;t know how long it lasted never tried it and moved soon after it opened isaidso March 12th, 2009, 06:30 AM coney sauce is an Ontario thing - I remember when i moved there wondering what the heck it was and why people would want it

So, it has nothing to do with Coney Island then?


Another common food here is hamburger nip, which is a hamburger (or cheese burger or whatever) with fries and gravy on everything, eaten with a knife and fork. Hot hamburger sandwich is the same thing but served on bread.

I first encountered a nip when I was in Winnipeg at Salisbury Steakhouse. I guess it&apos;s a northwest Ontario-Manitoba thing as I&apos;ve never heard mention of it anywhere else. I must add that I was surprised to see how big A&amp;W was as I don&apos;t see very many in southern Ontario or Quebec. I would have thought that Harvey&apos;s was bigger, but it goes to show that the prevalence of some chains isn&apos;t consistent across Canada. Some chains are completely regional. Take Greco Pizza, for instance. They&apos;re #1 in Atlantic Canada, but non existent elsewhere.

Two chains I wish there were more of is Mary Brown&apos;s and St-Hubert. They&apos;re both chicken restaurants. The first is out of Newfoundland and their fries are cooked in peanut oil. They&apos;re so tasty, but a heart attack in a box. St-Hubert is usually only found in Quebec, but I remember liking their chicken too. spongeg March 12th, 2009, 08:41 AM It might be named after coney island - I don&apos;t know

All I know is i&apos;ve never heard of it or seen it offered here in BC

When I lived in ontario a coupel years I remember seeing it at a lot of places and my room mate used to love it and I was like - what is it?

I think St hubert was in ontario in the early 90&apos;s I remember seeing one in 1992 when I arrived there and than I think it shut down soon after isaidso March 12th, 2009, 09:11 AM It may be an Ontario concoction named after the US amusement area.

St-Hubert retreated to Quebec. They used to have restaurants in Halifax, but they closed a long time ago. giallo March 12th, 2009, 09:43 AM It&apos;s kind of funny, but my wife&apos;s (who&apos;s quite the burger connoisseur, yet skinny...go figure) favorite burgers (from a chain restaurant) while visiting Vancouver were Triple Os and A&amp;Ws. We went to every burger chain be it McDanks, Burger King, DQ, Wendy&apos;s etc. and those came up heads above anything else in her opinion. The only other burger joint that made an impact was Fatburger, but that chain is imported from California. Huhu March 12th, 2009, 10:47 AM It&apos;s kind of funny, but my wife&apos;s (who&apos;s quite the burger connoisseur, yet skinny...go figure) favorite burgers (from a chain restaurant) while visiting Vancouver were Triple Os and A&amp;Ws. We went to every burger chain be it McDanks, Burger King, DQ, Wendy&apos;s etc. and those came up heads above anything else in her opinion. The only other burger joint that made an impact was Fatburger, but that chain is imported from California.
Fatburger is supposed to be good, but I was disappointed by it when I went. There&apos;s also Vera&apos;s Burgers but I haven&apos;t tried it yet. isaidso March 12th, 2009, 10:55 AM Triple Os is only in BC? Is White Spot and Triple Os 2 separate things? I&apos;ve never been to BC, so I&apos;ve never had Triple Os, but of the rest, A&amp;W, Harvey&apos;s, and Lick&apos;s would top my list. I&apos;m still trying to get to Hero.

I can&apos;t stomach McDonald&apos;s, Wendy&apos;s, or Burger Thing. A&amp;W in the US is a separate company from A&amp;W in Canada. Does that mean that A&amp;W can&apos;t expand overseas unless they go by a different name in those markets? I imagine the US version has the rights to that name in most markets around the world except Canada. giallo March 12th, 2009, 11:06 AM White Spot and Triple Os are sort of the same. WS is a sit down restaurant with a full menu while Triple Os is the fast food equivalent of it. Burgers are pretty much the same at both places ie: delicious!
It should be noted that Triple Os is the only form of the White Spot franchise that I&apos;ve seen outside of BC. Apparently, the only other Canadian province that has Triple Os is Alberta (Am I right, Albertans?). Other than that, you can find it in Hong Kong, Thailand and South Korea.

I always make a special effort to go to Triple Os when in HK. There used to be only one there, but now there are about 5 or 6. Taller, Better March 12th, 2009, 04:33 PM So, it has nothing to do with Coney Island then?



I first encountered a nip when I was in Winnipeg at Salisbury Steakhouse. I guess it&apos;s a northwest Ontario-Manitoba thing as I&apos;ve never heard mention of it anywhere else. I must add that I was surprised to see how big A&amp;W was as I don&apos;t see very many in southern Ontario or Quebec. I would have thought that Harvey&apos;s was bigger, but it goes to show that the prevalence of some chains isn&apos;t consistent across Canada. Some chains are completely regional. Take Greco Pizza, for instance. They&apos;re #1 in Atlantic Canada, but non existent elsewhere.

Two chains I wish there were more of is Mary Brown&apos;s and St-Hubert. They&apos;re both chicken restaurants. The first is out of Newfoundland and their fries are cooked in peanut oil. They&apos;re so tasty, but a heart attack in a box. St-Hubert is usually only found in Quebec, but I remember liking their chicken too.

I have never heard of Coney sauce, but my guess is the origin of the name is Coney Island in New York. I&apos;ve heard of Coney Dogs before, which are a type of hot dog. Wikipedia explains that a true Coney Dog is a white sausage ( I assume veal), called a&quot;White Hot&quot;. The Coney Dogs with chili dumped on them apparently comes from Detroit. Because of the proximity of Detroit to Ontario, my guess is that&quot;Coney Sauce&quot;is some sort of chili sauce, but vid can tell us.
The only reference to&quot;nip&quot;I have heard is from Salisbury House, and is just their term for a hamburger. They started in Winnipeg in 1931, and pretty much introduced the idea of hamburgers to the city. Their motto always was:&quot;We put the nip in Winnipeg!&quot;. I&apos;ve not heard of it used in reference to gravy and fries on top of a burger. There was a place in Winnipeg called Juniors, and their speciality was a burger with chili dumped all over it. Tasted much as it sounds.
St-Hubert was in Toronto, but to be very honest to my taste it seemed very similar to Swiss Chalet. I&apos;ve eaten at both, and neither chain is really my cup of tea. To make a long story short, I believe SC tried to pierce the Quebec market, and SH tried to pierce the Ontario market, and I don&apos;t think either was successful. Both chains began in the late 40&apos;s/early 50&apos;s and seem pretty much geared to the same type of market. But each of the chains has its fans.
I tried the new Jack Astors at Yonge and Bloor to use the $10 off coupon, and was surprised how much fun we had. We had a great Aussie waitress, and the food was very good! I was expecting the place to have a suburban vibe, but it didn&apos;t. I had the prime rib bacon cheese burger and my b/f had a smallish steak with amazing garlic mashed potatoes and excellent fresh green beans. The beer is ice cold and served in frosted mugs, which is a bonus in my eyes.
The bill was very low and we will go back. isaidso March 12th, 2009, 05:42 PM I was under the impression that it would be suburban Canadian tackiness like East Coast Mario&apos;s, but I&apos;ll give it a try. Taller, Better March 12th, 2009, 07:16 PM LOL! It is suburban tacky, of course (sans the suburbanites and parking lot). All of those&quot;roadhouses&quot;are similar (Montana&apos;s, etc....) and I doubt if any of them could be considered tasteful or one of a kind, but that doesn&apos;t bother me if the food is good and the service is friendly. I think if a person is expecting a cosy pub type place, or a unique dining experience, they will be disappointed in Jack Astor&apos;s... it is a good roadhouse, but a roadhouse nonetheless.
If I want cosy or unique I go to a neighbourhood pub, like Local 4 on Dundonald, or The Artful Dodger. Local 4 has a huge selection of board games for people to use, which can be very fun for groups of friends.

In Winnipeg a good chain is Earl&apos;s. Probably one small notch above Jack Astor&apos;s. vid March 12th, 2009, 08:27 PM So, it has nothing to do with Coney Island then?

Looking at Wikipedia articles, it apparently originated as a type of hot dog in New York called Red Hots, was imported to Michigan where it got the name coney dog (named after where it came from) and the sauce was probably used on more things when it came to Ontario. Here it&apos;s mostly on burgers. The recipe has probably changed as it has moved from place to place, coney sauce here is probably different from other parts of the province and could be unrecognizable to what you get in Coney Island. It probably came to Canada from New York via Michigan. The sauce recipe given for the coney island variety is very close to the sauce used here, so they are probably related somehow.

Ah, the etymology of foodstuffs. :)

I first encountered a nip when I was in Winnipeg at Salisbury Steakhouse. I guess it&apos;s a northwest Ontario-Manitoba thing as I&apos;ve never heard mention of it anywhere else.

Sal&apos;s calls all of their burgers nips. Here, a&quot;hamburger nip&quot;(nip by itself has no real meaning) is a burger and fries, with everything covered in gravy.

Mary Brown&apos;s ... is out of Newfoundland and their fries are cooked in peanut oil. They&apos;re so tasty, but a heart attack in a box.

We had one here, but it closed about a year ago. There is a restaurant in Westfort called Coney Island Burger and they cook their fries in peanut oil, which is very popular. Greco Roman March 12th, 2009, 11:42 PM Carl&apos;s Jr. has announced its intention to enter Canada (first via BC, AB, and ON). For those who don&apos;t know this chain (and its sister Hardee&apos;s), it&apos;s famous for its Thickburger amongst other not too-good-for-you things...Paris Hilton is in its most recent Spicy Thickburger commercials.
http://www.smh.com.au/ffximage/2004/11/18/th_monsterburger.jpg


I don&apos;t know why anyone would want to eat something who&apos;s inner parts look like it just came out of you five minutes ago :uh:

BTW, I&apos;ve never noticed any Carl&apos;s Jr. places in Alberta or BC. Spoolmak March 13th, 2009, 12:35 AM One In BC is opening in Surrey pretty soon. Taller, Better March 13th, 2009, 08:23 AM I must be kind of hungry, because that burger was looking pretty good.... all that bacon hanging down with the cheese...:eat:

Instead I had a bunch of grapes and a Mineola orange (the very best type). Yellow Fever March 13th, 2009, 09:13 AM The only burger I like is the &apos;fillet o fish&apos; from McDonald and their fries and coffee are the best. hellospank25 March 13th, 2009, 09:53 AM Do you have TGI Friday&apos;s in Canada?

I took a pic of a delicious burger i had there

http://i43.tinypic.com/2a5aeme.jpg Huhu March 13th, 2009, 11:35 AM ^^ Yes TGI&apos;s is around. A bit expensive IMO. Evan March 14th, 2009, 12:49 PM TGI Friday&apos;s is one of the better full service chains, IMHO. Far better than Ruby Tuesdays, if they even have those in Canada. If not, you really aren&apos;t missing anything. spongeg March 15th, 2009, 06:56 AM vancouver just lost its last TGIF

I find the burgers at Red Robin pretty good

http://static.seekingalpha.com/wp-content/seekingalpha/images/redrobin.jpg Taller, Better March 15th, 2009, 04:55 PM I have a recipe for meatless burgers that is AMAZING. Made with Quaker rolled oats, sunflower seeds, a bit of brewers yeast, eggs, milk or tomato juice, chopped onions, garlic powder, rosemary, thyme, and salt/pepper. Great on the barbecue! vid March 15th, 2009, 06:29 PM My family uses oats in homemade hamburger patties in place of bread crumbs quite often. It&apos;s a good way to stretch out a limited supply of meat. :) We made them with maple and brown sugar flavour once, it was actually really good. isaidso March 15th, 2009, 08:11 PM What&apos;s that stuff beneath the meat in that Robins burger? Taller, Better March 15th, 2009, 08:37 PM ^^ looks like onion rings

My family uses oats in homemade hamburger patties in place of bread crumbs quite often. It&apos;s a good way to stretch out a limited supply of meat. :) We made them with maple and brown sugar flavour once, it was actually really good.


It is so easy to make good hamburger patties that I wonder why people buy those ghastly frozen blocks of them. spongeg March 15th, 2009, 10:31 PM yes its like this onion crispy thing

tasty Huhu March 16th, 2009, 12:50 AM vancouver just lost its last TGIF
I thought there was still one in Metrotown. spongeg March 17th, 2009, 12:22 AM it shut down two weeks ago?

apparently all the staff got laid off two fridays ago and the place shut down vid March 17th, 2009, 03:04 AM It is so easy to make good hamburger patties that I wonder why people buy those ghastly frozen blocks of them.

Some people aren&apos;t particularly fond of touching the raw hamburger and eggs required to make them. I did buy frozen patties before the price went up. (4.98 to 6.98 for 12. They&apos;re 8.98 now. This is over the course of one month. I&apos;ve had to change my diet quite a bit due to rising prices lately.) Each of those hamburgers had about 40 grams of fat. I did the math, and figured out that if you ate a 200 gram bag of potato chips, except for the sodium, that would be less unhealthy. :ohno: I don&apos;t miss them. They usually gave me diarrhoea. I lived on such things when I was living with my dad a few years ago. Thin frozen hamburgers for singledailylowincomemeal (with no bun), maybe a microwaved potato to go with it, and a fudgicle (the really, really cheap kind) for desert. Water to drink. I refer to that year as&quot;the dark period&quot;.

The PC Blue Menu Angus Burgers, a 6 pack, went on sale for 4.99 once and those were good, and relatively healthy. They&apos;re 12.99 now, so I don&apos;t buy them. (With three people, that could work out as only one meal, if nothing else is made to go with them.) Not much fat but very tasty. Anything from PC Blue menu is worth it. Not as good as making something from scratch yourself but if you want to eat processed food (God knows why you would do such a stupid thing) that&apos;s the brand to go with, at least from Superstore. Probably the only thing they&apos;ve done right.

I think they should tax unhealthy food to lower prices on unhealthy food. People would be more likely to buy the healthier food, they would be healthier and health care costs would go down. isaidso March 17th, 2009, 03:13 AM If you know how to cook, you can eat healthy, tasty, nutritious meals for the same price as those cost saving alternatives you mention. It takes a little researching and some work, but it&apos;s doable. Buy fresh produce, learn about spices, and value purchases like legumes, and cut out all processed or pre-packaged food items always.

It&apos;s far easier to buy 12 frozen burgers for $5 than to make a big pot of healthy chili from scratch for the same money. Convenience or health? You may not like chili, but there are usually options that are satisfying. Taller, Better March 17th, 2009, 04:06 AM Some people aren&apos;t particularly fond of touching the raw hamburger and eggs required to make them. .

? You&apos;ve never heard of rubber gloves? :eek2:

Mind you, home cooking from scratch involves a fair amount of planning and work and that is generally the part that some people are not particularly fond of. Johnny Blade March 17th, 2009, 04:29 AM http://www.cheesebuerger.de/images/smilie/nahrung/h020.gif I tend to stay away form the big greasy chains so usually I&apos;ll go to a few Pubs I know of that makes great homemade burgers with real cheese...yummy! spongeg March 17th, 2009, 04:33 AM i heard a food nutrionist say if you stay to the outside of a grocery store and avoid the aisles you should eat better - cause thats where the fresh meat, produce, dairy, bread etc is

the aisles are full of the bad processed foods vid March 17th, 2009, 04:50 AM It&apos;s far easier to buy 12 frozen burgers for $5 than to make a big pot of healthy chili from scratch for the same money. Convenience or health? You may not like chili, but there are usually options that are satisfying.

You actually mentioned the one meal that I do take the time to prepare. Last time my mom and I made chili we put hours into it. It was fantastic. Used some extra sauce and meat from a lasagna we made the day before and put in lots of peppers. (Not the cheapest fruit but they&apos;re loaded with flavour.)

And while vegetables are cheap (I do eat those occasionally) fruit isn&apos;t. For the price of 6 ounces of raspberries I can get a kilogram of chips. You know what&apos;s really good? Get peaches and let them sit until they start to get soft. They get really really sweet. When I was little we&apos;d just go into the bush and get fruit but we don&apos;t do that anymore. No way to get out there and most of the fruit in this area has been crappy since the late 1990s for some reason. Taller, Better March 17th, 2009, 05:15 AM There are some types of imported fruit that are surprisingly cheap-oranges, bananas... but most, like raspberries are way too expensive. Keep an eye out for sales. Rabba had clamshell strawberries on last week for a buck a container. Apples are good and healthy, and really cheap. A watermelon cut into pieces lasts a number of days.
All better for you than chips. vid March 17th, 2009, 06:32 AM I hate watermelon. It makes me noxious, because I can&apos;t spell nauseous.

Bananas are 1.29 a pound here. I got a lot of those last summer but there are only so many you can eat before it drives you insane. Oranges are too sticky and at Superstore, they all look like shit. Taller, Better March 17th, 2009, 06:54 AM I don&apos;t particularly like fruit... I much prefer vegetables. But I remember to buy it now and then simply for health. Mineolas are amazing oranges, and I love watermelon. But the real treat is fresh fruit in the summertime, Ontario grown. Strawberries, peaches, pears, grapes, etc..
When I was young, the only fruit we had in winter were oranges, apples, bananas and fruit my mother put into sealers (saskatoons, raspberries, etc...) from the summer. Also we had canned fruit. I still don&apos;t mind canned fruit cocktail packed in water once in a blue moon! Reminds me of my youth... a very big treat was to have it over ice cream! :) vid March 17th, 2009, 07:07 AM Canned fruit cocktail on ice cream is always desert up here. That or pistachio pudding, for some reason. I have lots of canned fruit but I don&apos;t really like it, and it&apos;s from the food hamper so it&apos;s from China and expired.. I also have some apricot jam&quot;Whith Friut&quot;.

In 2005, my christmas hamper had a can of Campbells Mushroom Soup that offered me tickets to the Winter Olympics if I won.

Which winter Olympics?

The ones in Calgary.

The soup expired two years before I was born.

I know people like to think they&apos;re doing good things when they donate food but make sure it isn&apos;t expired! A third of the donations to a charity I volunteered for a year ago was expired, some of it was in foreign packaging and we couldn&apos;t identify it, some was just rice in zip bags. You can&apos;t give that kind of thing out. Taller, Better March 17th, 2009, 07:26 AM OMG that is disgusting. You are right, donating old food is not doing anyone any favours. You have to be careful and read the labels on your hamper foods. vid March 17th, 2009, 07:57 AM Well when I was volunteering I went through everything and weeded all the expired and bizarre food out. I did that a lot when I worked at Safeway, went through the entire department and got several boxes full of old food, some as much as a year old. It was a real problem this year though, the food hamper distribution was really badly handled and some people got almost nothing but expired food. The food distribution organization told people that if they&apos;re not going to check their food for expiry dates to not even bother donating anything, though they said that money was better anyway, lots of independent grocers give charities and schools discounts so they can get more for the money than if it was donated. It might be ok to eat, but at the same time, it might not. It&apos;s better not to risk it. Taller, Better March 17th, 2009, 04:34 PM I wouldn&apos;t take a chance eating an expired can of food... it isn&apos;t worth it. Especially if it is 20 years old. I used to like it at Dominion when they sold those plastic bags full of suitable food for donation (peanut butter, cereal, pasta, beans, rice, etc...). You could buy it and then deposit them into a big bin just past the cashier. So simple. vid March 17th, 2009, 08:02 PM Lots of grocery stores here do that, you just give them ten dollars and they put it toward the charity. Superstore has a collection bin beside the exit for food for the food bank, and there is locally owned grocer downtown that will give you a little chip to donate ten cents to any of three charities for each reusable bag you bring. I usually bring a handful of them so I can be extra charitable. :)

Haven&apos;t used a plastic bag since early 2006. spongeg March 18th, 2009, 01:57 AM when i worked at dennys we used to use the frozen burger pattys for the ground beef in other dishes... Taller, Better March 18th, 2009, 06:38 AM ewwwwwwwww... that is wacko. Surely it is cheaper to buy the ground beef bulk. isaidso March 18th, 2009, 07:47 AM You actually mentioned the one meal that I do take the time to prepare. Last time my mom and I made chili we put hours into it. It was fantastic. Used some extra sauce and meat from a lasagna we made the day before and put in lots of peppers. (Not the cheapest fruit but they&apos;re loaded with flavour.)

And while vegetables are cheap (I do eat those occasionally) fruit isn&apos;t. For the price of 6 ounces of raspberries I can get a kilogram of chips. You know what&apos;s really good? Get peaches and let them sit until they start to get soft. They get really really sweet. When I was little we&apos;d just go into the bush and get fruit but we don&apos;t do that anymore. No way to get out there and most of the fruit in this area has been crappy since the late 1990s for some reason.

Chili is awesome. Nothing like a hot bowl of it in the winter time. Healthy, delicious, nutritious, and not expensive. You&apos;re right about the cost of fruit in northern Ontario too. If I lived there, I&apos;d think twice about buying a lot of it. My diet is about 40% fresh fruit, but I&apos;d have to pay 2-3 times the price in Thunder Bay that I pay here in Toronto.

Cheap fruit in many of the small markets is one of the surprising deals to be had in this city. Some of it is so cheap, I just pile mountains of it into my cart with no thought to the price. 5 kiwis for $1, 3 grapefruit for a $1, 10 oranges for $2, 2 trays of strawberries for $3, mangoes for 50 cents. These are in season prices, but even in off season, fruit is cheaper than a lot of the junk food.

When I went to Safeway in northern Ontario, I went into sticker price shock. I needed to buy groceries, but ended up buying practically nothing because I couldn&apos;t bring myself to pay the prices they were charging. After a few days, you pay it because you don&apos;t have a choice.

Also we had canned fruit. I still don&apos;t mind canned fruit cocktail packed in water once in a blue moon! Reminds me of my youth... a very big treat was to have it over ice cream! :)

OMG, that&apos;s so ghetto! I shoudn&apos;t talk. I get cravings for Kraft Dinner sometimes. Taller, Better March 18th, 2009, 06:12 PM We all have our dirty little ghetto food secrets! hehe.....
One thing we never ate was Kraft Dinner, though. I don&apos;t think my mother
believed in it.
You can eat nutritionally at a surprisingly cheap cost, but it involves a lot of
legwork and shopping about. The real trouble is nutritious food without a lot of
variation becomes boring fast. I can&apos;t eat rice and beans every night, yet my b/f
from Brazil was raised on it, and could quite happily munch them down every meal.
I love a variety of food and fortunately am now in a position when I can afford it,
but I have gone through phases of my life when I really had to watch every penny. isaidso March 19th, 2009, 08:56 AM I grew up with rice too, but not beans. I could eat rice 5 times a week and not get bored of it. Everyone has their staple food. I suppose for many people, it&apos;s potatoes.

Thankfully, I like it all. As long as it&apos;s fresh, good quality, and appropriately spiced, I&apos;m happy. I really should eat more meat than I do though. vid March 20th, 2009, 03:42 AM My dad lives on Kraft Dinner. I can&apos;t eat it, it&apos;s disgusting. I can eat macaroni noodles with butter and lemon pepper, or mixed with real cheese, but and Kraft Dinner or knockoff of it I can&apos;t eat. (Although PC&apos;s white cheddar Macaroni and Cheese is very good.) isaidso March 21st, 2009, 10:41 AM The PC white cheddar one is better. My interest in regular Kraft Dinner is mostly psychological. I ate a lot of it in grade school. Parents were at work, so at lunch we made what ever was easy and quick. For a 14 year old who didn&apos;t know much about cooking, Kraft Dinner got made quite often. I get cravings for it occasionally as an adult because I associate it with memories of youth.

It&apos;s crappy, but I&apos;ll probably always eat it from time to time for those reasons. vid March 21st, 2009, 11:34 PM Kraft Dinner was too hard for me, you had to strain to water out. My&quot;made this myself!&quot;pasta dinner was Lipton Sidekicks.

I was too young to enjoy the microwavable variety, though not having a microwave for three years now I&apos;ve come to appreciate real food and really don&apos;t like what comes out of the things. Real cooking appliances are far superior to a little radiation box that turns everything into rubber. spongeg March 22nd, 2009, 07:13 AM i love kraft dinner but i never eat it

my mom used to make it&quot;fancy&quot;and i always hated it the way she did it and I just wanted it plain

she would take the plain stuff than put in a dish grate cheese all over the top and put slices of tomato and more cheese and than bake it in the oven till the cheese got all crusty and melted

and i would kill for some of it now - but at the time I always hated it done that way CrazyCanuck March 22nd, 2009, 07:24 AM I&apos;m never without a bunch of boxes at home. I eat it at least once a week. Huhu March 22nd, 2009, 07:30 AM Kraft dinner is just carbs with some processed gunk and chemicals as a sauce. I usually throw in some fresh veg and ham or sausage to make it more appetizing. isaidso March 22nd, 2009, 08:33 AM So, what&apos;s the best mac&amp;cheese around Canada? Home made is best, with different types of cheese, then baked in the oven so the top is crispy. Taller, Better March 22nd, 2009, 05:46 PM I once knew a chef who make scrumptious mac and cheese for kids. It was so creamy and delicious, and I asked her what her secret was. The answer? Velveeta. Actually beat the versions I have tasted made with $20 worth of Fontina, Gruyre and Asiago. Sometimes when it comes to junky foods, the down and dirty one tastes better. spongeg March 22nd, 2009, 10:23 PM i never eat it - i do like the presidents choice though - i have a box at home

i don&apos;t really ever eat pasta though - can&apos;t say i like any form of it - i will eat it if i have to Spoolmak March 23rd, 2009, 01:00 AM After u stirred in the powdered cheese, throw in a little block of cheddar cheese, let it melt and stir it in. It is fucking amazing, excuse my french. Taller, Better March 23rd, 2009, 07:25 PM After u stirred in the powdered cheese, throw in a little block of cheddar cheese, let it melt and stir it in. It is fucking amazing, excuse my french.

I should say so. :nono:&quot;You&quot;is spelt like this, not&quot;u&quot;!





:) Spoolmak March 24th, 2009, 01:15 AM It&apos;s from all that text messaging, I swear it is ruining my grammar!:cheers: Rhino March 24th, 2009, 01:26 AM A&amp;W !! vid March 24th, 2009, 02:37 AM Someone else taunted me with A&amp;W just a little while ago. :(

They also have good onion rings. spongeg March 24th, 2009, 05:46 AM except when the onion is too chewy and it all comes out of the batter :( Taller, Better March 25th, 2009, 06:35 PM Cripes @ Velveeta! I&apos;ll have to try that one. Anyone been to Gourmet Burger in Cabbagetown? I am dying to try it.



I know!! Who would buy Velveeta? It is right down there with Cheez Whiz and Squeeze-A-Snak. But my god it tastes good in Mac and Cheese.

OMG ... the Gremlins have put my post above yours, isaidso! This server time synch thing is bad today. isaidso March 25th, 2009, 06:35 PM I once knew a chef who make scrumptious mac and cheese for kids. It was so creamy and delicious, and I asked her what her secret was. The answer? Velveeta. Actually beat the versions I have tasted made with $20 worth of Fontina, Gruyre and Asiago. Sometimes when it comes to junky foods, the down and dirty one tastes better.

Cripes @ Velveeta! I&apos;ll have to try that one. Anyone been to Gourmet Burger in Cabbagetown? I am dying to try it. vid March 25th, 2009, 07:24 PM Cripes! :lol: I thought it was a little wee bear!! :rofl: spongeg March 25th, 2009, 11:57 PM http://www.dirtysouthwine.com/.a/6a00e55144008488340111684d90df970c-400wi Taller, Better March 26th, 2009, 08:48 AM ^^ Well, whadda ya know... the old gal was right! My, but she does look eager to please
when they come. isaidso March 26th, 2009, 09:23 AM Is it true that Velveeta is actually grey before they add the cheese colour into it? I&apos;ve heard that repeated, but no one can verify it. I know they paint many types of food like salmon from fish farms because they&apos;re grey, but grey Velvetta? Surely, it&apos;s beige, or some dirty white colour before they add some orange-yellow dye? Taller, Better March 26th, 2009, 06:06 PM Is it true that Velveeta is actually grey before they add the cheese colour into it? I&apos;ve heard that repeated, but no one can verify it. I know they paint many types of food like salmon from fish farms because they&apos;re grey, but grey Velvetta? Surely, it&apos;s beige, or some dirty white colour before they add some orange-yellow dye?

No cheese is naturally orange. Dyes are used to give it that colour, even in very expensive aged cheddar. I have no idea about Velveeta, but natural coloured cheese is usually anything from white to pale cream colour. isaidso March 26th, 2009, 09:04 PM No cheese is naturally orange. Dyes are used to give it that colour, even in very expensive aged cheddar. I have no idea about Velveeta, but natural coloured cheese is usually anything from white to pale cream colour.

I was under the impression that Velveeta wasn&apos;t technically cheese. Isn&apos;t it just sludge made to resemble cheese sauce? vid March 27th, 2009, 07:02 AM I&apos;m pretty sure it is. Most&quot;American cheese&quot;(Cheese whiz, No Name singles, etc) isn&apos;t really cheese. If you leave cheese out it gets mouldy. Leave&quot;American cheese&quot;out and it petrifies. DENTROBATE54 March 27th, 2009, 07:55 AM That powdered shit in the macaroni packets is 100% not cheese. I always have to add in a shredded blend of mozzarella, provolone and cheddar to my Kraft dinner to give my meals actual favour. I also find grocery-store processed sliced cheese to be too waxy and salty in texture for human consumption. Many a sandwich of mine&apos;s been ruined by plastic-tasting cheese. Yuck! :puke: vid March 27th, 2009, 09:23 AM When you&apos;re poor, the shitty taste doesn&apos;t matter. Actual cheese is a luxury for me. Although we buy Parmesan on a weekly basis and that is more expensive? Parmesan is good with anything, though. spongeg March 27th, 2009, 10:49 AM parmesan in a block or in a can? vid March 27th, 2009, 11:12 AM In a can. Block is too expensive. :( Evan March 27th, 2009, 11:54 AM The powdered parmesan from Kraft smells like feet. :( vid March 27th, 2009, 12:03 PM As opposed to real Parmesan, which smells like feet dipped in farts and left in the sun for too long. :)

Or blue cheese, which smells like rotting human flesh!! It tastes good but only in small amounts. Too much overpowers you and knocks you out cold.

Last summer one of my Flickr contacts, who is a newspaper report in a small Minnesota town, published a recipe for blue cheese burgers. Sort of like a chicken Kyiv but with ground beef and blue cheese. I got mom to make the recipe, but she was going to use mozzarella because that was the only actual cheese we had. But when I was at Quality Market that day, I saw blue cheese on sale, for only 2.88 for 4 ounces, which would have been (and was) more than enough for the burgers.

She put the cheese on as if it was mozzarella, and I couldn&apos;t eat them. :( I finished one and a half of three, the rest was thrown out. The first one tasted pretty good, the second went from ok to intolerable in a matter of minutes. I kept the blue cheese in the fridge until a few days ago, when I cleaned the whole thing out and it was thrown away. Along with an unopened half litre of milk from October, 2007, which was solid. Evan March 27th, 2009, 12:06 PM I think the canned stuff smells more like feet, but yeah, the block is stinky too. I always wondered what kept the poor people in the Kraft factory from passing out. I&apos;ll just jump in here with my support for mac and cheese in a box as well. If you put enough extra stuff in it and add a little real cheese, it&apos;s not bad. Especially on drunk nights. :D I must also say that American cheese is an abomination and should be banned from the marketplace! Taller, Better March 27th, 2009, 06:23 PM What exactly is American cheese? I saw a tourist reaming out a waiter once because he wanted American cheese on his burger and the guy told him all they had was cheddar.

I&apos;d never heard of the stuff before that. Evan March 27th, 2009, 06:45 PM What exactly is American cheese? I saw a tourist reaming out a waiter once because he wanted American cheese on his burger and the guy told him all they had was cheddar.

I&apos;d never heard of the stuff before that.

It&apos;s neon yellow colored processed funk. It&apos;s about as close to real cheese as nuclear waste is, and the nuclear waste is probably better for you. Originally I think it had some real cheese in it, but that was replaced with processed garbage years ago.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_cheese

We do actually make fantastic cheese in this country, but that shit up there isn&apos;t one of them. DENTROBATE54 March 27th, 2009, 07:01 PM Yup, most disturbing line from the wiki article:

&quot;It... meets the legal definition of cheese.&quot;:shifty:

What the heck are manufacturers having us consume? What&apos;s going into our bodies? So many carcinogens and obesity-causing additives can be traced back to the processed foods people living under our present economic climate have no choice but to subsist on. :ohno: Evan March 27th, 2009, 07:15 PM Yup, most disturbing line from the wiki article:

&quot;It... meets the legal definition of cheese.&quot;:shifty:

What the heck are manufacturers having us consume? What&apos;s going into our bodies? So many carcinogens and obesity-causing additives can be traced back to the processed foods people living under our present economic climate have no choice but to subsist on. :ohno:

Yep, I do my best, note the emphasis on best, to eat as little processed food as possible, but I find myself doing it on occasion. The main problem with it is, it&apos;s cheap, easy to make, and here is where they get you... not ALL of it tastes like ass. :( I think the biggest issue in the US is, people want convenience and they want it fast. Nutrition frequently takes a back seat to all of that, and I&apos;m sorry to say, it shows in many of my fellow countrymen. Evan March 27th, 2009, 07:24 PM Um, I didn&apos;t mean to turn this into a shitty US food thread. Don&apos;t hate me. Taller, Better March 27th, 2009, 07:57 PM Great strides have been made in Central Canada in the past two decades in the area of cheese production, especially in Quebec. Unsurprisingly Quebec cheeses are mostly modelled on traditional French cheeses, and Ontario&apos;s are modelled on traditional British cheeses. As our industries mature, I hope our artisinal cheese
producers create more uniquely distinctive Canadian varieties.. (also the same for packaging). Luis80 March 29th, 2009, 05:14 AM when i lived in MTL i pigged out alot on&quot;belle provence&apos; burgers....

Other fast food i miss from mtl is the bbq chicken joints,&quot;bbq cote-st-luc&quot;and&quot;chalet bbq&quot;both pretty good at what they do.:cheers: vid March 29th, 2009, 05:20 AM Thunder Oak Cheese Farm on the edge of Thunder Bay is Ontario&apos;s only Gouda cheese maker. Their product is fantastic, and inexpensive compared to other cheeses. They make one with peppers in it which is one of my favourite cheeses.

http://www.cheesefarm.ca/

Processed foods aren&apos;t really cheaper, it&apos;s just that to get fresh food you have to buy more for it to match the price. I can pay $1.98 for a 380g bag of salad, or I can spend $5 on enough vegetables to make more than a kilogram of salad. I can buy a box of two Chicken Kjiv&apos;s made of processed chicken for $4.49, or I can spend $16 on 8 chicken breasts and maybe 25 cents on some parsley and make it myself. The latter is cheaper, but the former appears cheaper because the net price is lower. That&apos;s why low income people eat more processed food. It isn&apos;t less expensive, it only appears so. It&apos;s also easier to eat. That box of Chicken Kjiv comes out of the box and plastic wrapper, goes into the oven for 35 minutes and its done. With the home made variety, you have to handle the raw chicken, fillet it, fill it with the butter and herbs, close it up, put it in. It could take an hour to cook it that way.

As for chips and pop, well, they&apos;re cheap and taste good. Also, a lot of processed fruit juices are actually less healthy than soft drinks. Five Alive has more sugar than pop and no vitamins (I was surprised when I noticed it too!) and the concentrating and pasteurization process many processed juices go through destroys all of their nutrients. Those little cans of frozen juice syrup are the worst. My doctor told me last year that I have to cut down on soft drinks but he also warned me about juices. They are quite deceiving.

And if you want a juice that is unprocessed and healthy? They cost 2 to 12 times what pop does. Superstore sells a brand that costs 5.99 for 500ml. You can get 4,260ml of Pepsi for little more than half that when it&apos;s not on sale. (Though I have tried those expensive juices and let me tell you, they are worth it if you have the money to spend on them.) Taller, Better March 29th, 2009, 08:57 AM when i lived in MTL i pigged out alot on&quot;belle provence&apos; burgers....


LOL! Memories of La Belle Province..late at night in the gay village it is at least open after the bars close. Late night munchies... but hold the soggy choucroute. Hot dogs are something like 99 cents. :D Luis80 March 29th, 2009, 07:25 PM ^^yeah some of their locations had good hours. At one job i had, i had to be there at 6 in the morning and belle provence was the only place nearby that was open. That one served breakfast and their breakfasts are actually not bad ...I always enjoyed the free refills on the coffee:nuts: spongeg March 29th, 2009, 11:22 PM It&apos;s neon yellow colored processed funk. It&apos;s about as close to real cheese as nuclear waste is, and the nuclear waste is probably better for you. Originally I think it had some real cheese in it, but that was replaced with processed garbage years ago.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_cheese

We do actually make fantastic cheese in this country, but that shit up there isn&apos;t one of them.

american cheese contains all the ingredients other cheese has (plus fillers) but its processed differently and i think it skips a process&quot;cheese&quot;goes through and ends up the way it does spongeg March 29th, 2009, 11:23 PM do you ever notice ice cream is not really ice cream?

its usually modified milk ingredients and not actual&quot;cream&quot;as it should be

you can get real ice cream but you pay a lot more for it DENTROBATE54 March 29th, 2009, 11:54 PM ^^ Gelatos are the purest, most real form of ice cream there is. :yes: Just milk/cream, thickening agent, crushed ice and favourings (usually fruit syrups or chocolate) prepared fresh.

Yep, I do my best, note the emphasis on best, to eat as little processed food as possible, but I find myself doing it on occasion. The main problem with it is, it&apos;s cheap, easy to make, and here is where they get you... not ALL of it tastes like ass. :( I think the biggest issue in the US is, people want convenience and they want it fast. Nutrition frequently takes a back seat to all of that, and I&apos;m sorry to say, it shows in many of my fellow countrymen.

Yeah, if only there was a way to make health food cheaper, tastier and easier to prepare. My fave fast food chain Subway at least delivers on all 3 of those concerns. Why have a burger when a sub at least keeps you full for 2 hours and it&apos;s upto you just how much you decide to binge out on toppings? Avoiding white bread and opting for fat-free dressing and lots of veggies is my defintion of a nutritious lunch on the go. ;) vid March 30th, 2009, 10:06 AM You might opt for healthier ingredients, but most don&apos;t and their basic menu items are no better than those at McDonalds. Evan March 30th, 2009, 12:54 PM It&apos;s hard for me to go into one of those places and order from their very tiny healthy menu. The second I walk in and the smell of meatballs hits me in the face, it&apos;s all over. Taller, Better March 30th, 2009, 04:03 PM I&apos;m still addicted to Korean pork bone soup. When I go in the restaurant I have coached myself that I will order something different for a change, but when I smell that soup it is all over and I have to order it! :D
Tonight we are going to an Italian restaurant. vid March 30th, 2009, 11:31 PM Oh, an Italian restaurant!!

Mediterranean food is healthier my ass. You order spaghetti and you get a fucking farm on a plate. 
 vBulletinv3.8.7, Copyright2000-2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
