<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008916" url="http://weekendbackpacker.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="8" score="0.012057109420844078" bingtitle="Weekend Backpacker" webtitle="Weekend Backpacker">
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... the one and only stall that made it forgot my order. ... look at a freshly-cooked lechon in styrofoam trays ... email address to subscribe to this blog and receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Main menu Skip to content 
 About Me Climb Record 
 Weekend Backpacker Backpacking the weekend on a road less travelled. ← Older posts 
 The Ancient Capital of Udong 
 Posted on June 4, 2012 by Earl 
 

This is a really late blog post  as this trip was made last January right after New Year’s Eve.  Nevertheless, here it is as I think the place deserves some mention.
 
Stairway to Nirvana
 
 
 
The temples at Udong are living breathing ones and worshippers troop to its shrines to light incense and pray.
 
 

 Udong made for a wonderful day trip from Phnom Pehn.   I’m a temple guy and I don’t easily get temple fatigued especially if they’re ancient and have interesting stories to tell.  I have been to Siem Reap before and on this trip, I had not been to any temples yet having spent the earlier part of my trip to Cambodia in Ratanakiri so a visit to Udong was just perfect.  I had heared about the temple from Jon, the London-based Columbian photographer I had met in Banlung.  He showed me really nice pictures of a white-washed temple gleaming in the morning light.  He had forgotten the name but referred to it as“the place near to (sic)  Phnom Pehn.”Matti, the Finnish guy I had hiked with,  recognized the pictures and said it was the ancient capital.  A little read through on Lonely Planet’s section“Around Phnom Pehn”yielded the name Udong.

 

A car hire from one of the many tour stalls along the main road cost $40 including waiting time.  It was kinda steep but fortunately,  U-Chen, a Malaysian Chinese I had met through Couchsurfing was coming along so I had someone split the cost with.

The next morning we made our way out of the capital along the national highway past small towns.  We made quick stop to buy some num pang , the Cambodian equivalent of the Vietnamese bahn mi , and some drinks at a stall under a flyover in the city.

About an hour after we had left the city, we reached the turn-off to the base of the mountain.  The dirt road led past villages  where children played on front yards and chickens crossed the road.  It was a dramatic change of scenery and life.

We arrived at the base of the temples and the driver found a shady place on a temple courtyard to park the car.    Apparently, not too many non-locals make it to Udong.  There was hardly anyone there as we made our way up the concrete steps to the stuppa .

 

The view from the top was immense making you realize how flat this part of Cambodia was.

Elephants figure prominently in bas reliefs on the facade of the gleaming white stuppa .

A bridge way led to another stuppa that seemed much older and had bas reliefs of elephants like the ones in the Terrace of the Elephants in Siem Reap.

 



This second one would seem more at home in Angkor with its crumbling walls and reliefs faded and worn-out by the elements.  It was very atmospheric walking along the narrow dirt paths in between the walls.

 


 
The inlaid ceramic pieces that decorate the“stuppa”remind me of a favorite Thai temple,“Wat Arun.”
 
This temple seemed more“used”as the small shrine at the entrance fronting the connecting bridgeway has used incense sticks while colorful cloth bunting festooned the sandstone walls.  Fallen leaves from the trees littered the floors lending an abandoned feel to the place. It was a stark contrast from the squeaky clean newer temple on the other side with its shiny tiles.

 



 

We only spent about an hour in the temples not knowing that there was another one up the road from where the car had parked. The driver didn’t say anything about it either.  He was probably keen on getting back to Phnom Pehn right away.  I should have brought my Lonely Planet book.  Udong made a nice day-out from Phnom Pehn.  It may not have the splendor of the temples at Angkor but it does have one important thing Angkor doesn’t have—peace and tranquility.



 
 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Uncategorized | Leave a comment 
 Flying Budget While Keeping Your Sanity (and your trip) Intact 
 Posted on May 28, 2012 by Earl 
Yeah. I’m a sucker for budget airlines. Name it—Cebu Pacific, Air Philippines, Zest Air, Tiger Airways, Jet Star, Air Asia—I’m on their mailing list. I’m the type who have my flights booked 10 months in advanced courtesy of a seat sale.  And yes I do spend a large part of the day trying to get through the internet traffic when there’s on online seat sale. On the precious flights when no budget airline served the route and I have to dole out a little more moolah, the comfort of a wide leg room, in-flight snacks and movies, and other amenities make me say,“Ahhh…I’ll never fly budget again.”That is until the next seat sale comes along.

Lots of people have had unpleasant experiences with budget airlines.   I’ve been lucky as I have had nothing worse than a couple of hours of delayed flights and just one cancellation.  Or maybe I kinda like hanging out at airports.

Anyway, if you’re like me and fancy himself as a Nat Geo explorer or a Lonely Planet author always in search of the next great adventure but without the corresponding finances, budget airlines are the way to go.  It’s not all that bad contrary to what your envious office mate (who probably only took one flight in his/her entire sedentary life) or the frustrated I’m-gonna-blog-you-I’m-a-big-shot-tourist say.  Flying budget is a great way to save your money for things that would matter most during your vacation.  Shit does happen and it can happen again.  How you deal with it is all up to you. You can either laugh about it and treat it as part of your travel experience or be exasperated and feel like shit.  Your choice, really.  In the meantime, here are few things you need to know to keep you sane.

 This Is Your Fate 

 You’re  poor.  So Shut-up. 

 If you want the wide leg room, the meals in aluminum trays, flight attendants in smart uniforms, and the over-all feeling of snootiness because you’re off on vacation while leaving the rest of humanity in slavery, go ahead and spend about $100 more.  If you can afford it.  If you can’t…. take a deep breath, swallow your pride, and repeat after me….“I get what I paid for…. I get what I paid for…”

You’re not willing to pay for more so why expect the airlines to give you more?  You skimp on you trip.  They skimp on you.  Enough said.

Beggars can’t be choosy.

 Surviving Your Fate 

 Sit Smart 

Because the fares are cheap, budget airlines try to squeeze in as many people the aircraft can hold.  Almost non-existent leg rooms and 90 degree seat pitches are the norm.  So unless your petite you’ll be squeezed tight and literally rubbing elbows with your seatmate.  Woe to anyone on the center seat.  On the other hand, you can follow the advice of some fast-food joints and“Share a Seat, Win a Friend.”In this case, you can“Share a Space, and Win a Friend.”Engaging your seatmate in light conversation will help you while away the time.  Just make sure turbulence doesn’t make you jittery.  Having your voice rise an octave above when the plane suddenly drops a few feet will belie your relative lack of air travel experience.
 
“I can’t fit,”heaved a hefy Russina behind me on an HCMC-bound Cebu Pacific flight.
 
If you’re on a red-eye flight, dont’even attempt to start a conversation.  Sleeping is always preferred to talking.

 

A neck pillow really comes in handy for your winks.   If you’re lucky and the flight isn’t full (and I’ve had this twice on a BKK-MNL Cebu Pacific flight), there will be whole empty rows.  Cast your eye on it to claim it as yours and give the evil eye to whoever attempts to take it away from you.  As soon as the flight attendant shuts the door, unbuckle your seatbelt and skeddadle to the nearest empty row.  Stay at the CENTER so nobody takes the other seats.  After take-off and when the seat belt signs goes off, fling the arm rests up, lie flat, and enjoy .
 
Spare the extra cash and reserve a nice seat. You’ll be glad you did.
 
If you really must have a nice and comfortable seat, then go and buy yourself one.  Budget airlines nowadays try to make additional revenue by selling seat allocations.  If you don’t get one, the system randomly assigns a seat. Forget about checking-in early and asking the guy at the counter to give you seat 8F.  Most online systems assign seats as it makes check-in faster and easier. If leg room or a window is important to you, spare the additional hundred bucks for your preferred seat.  Air Asia and Cebu Pacific have premium seats that are double the rate.  These seats are usually in front and on emergency rows.  I’m fine with getting seat 1A or 1F for a measly Php 100.
 
The best seats in Air Asia are the red ones which cost more.
 
 

 

 

 Tandoori in the Sky. 

Do you really need to have something on a 4-hour flight?  Does being in high-altitude and breathing pressurized air still make you hungry?  Are you really that much of a glutton?  What were you doing while waiting for your boarding call?

I like airline food. Honestly. I’m usually not very hungry during flights as I prefer to sleep but on rare occasions, such as on a PP-KL AirAsia flight, I hadn’t had lunch so I ordered a Chicken Masala.  I liked it so much I was tempted to order another one Air Asia has cheap meals and they have promos when you order your meal online when you book your flight or do web check-in.

 

If you’re  a social-climbing snooty, you can add this to your Snooty Tips.  Having a Chicken Tandoori with Biryani Rice while the rest of your seatmates try to ignore you makes you look . . . well . . .“moneyed.”Hahahaha.  It screams—”I have money.  I can buy airline food.”If you’re just gonna have a cup of instant noodles, forget it.

Should you bring baon ?  Why not?  I sometimes bring a chocolate bar with me and I always have a bottle of water.

 Getting to the Point. 

Budget airlines are point-to-point carriers. That means they ferry you from your point or origin to your destination as indicated in your ticket.  While checking-in for my home-bound flight at KL, an exasperated French man with a young child in tow was exasperatedly screaming his head off as his flight from KL to Singapore was leaving in less than two hours and he had yet to look for his check-in counter.  He had just arrived from Paris and had expected that since he had booked all flights with Air Asia, there would be no need to go through immigrations, retrieve his luggage, and check-in again.  WRONG! Those were two separate flights.  Anyway, Air Asia has since launched its Fly Through program that spares  passengers on multiple flights the hassles of luggage claims and check-ins.

If you’re flying in and flying out on the same day, LEAVE ENOUGH TIME in between the arrival of one and the departure of another.  It’s more pleasant to wait than to rush off the plane and on another one while at the same time cursing yourself for thinking there might be no flight delay or your luggage will be the first one on the carousel.

 Where’s my luggage? 

Airlines really have the right to offload luggage for safety reasons. Some really small airports such as those in islands have short runaways which means less“momentum”time for the aircraft to prepare itself to lift off from the runway.  They do need to tell you  in advanced though that they’re not putting your luggage on  your flight.  Whenever I’m checking-in luggage, I always have my essentials on my carry-on.  I can lose my clothes but not my medication and other stuff really important to me.

 

 If you’re delayed or cancelled . . . 

Nothing much you can do about it really especially if the cause of the delay or cancellation is congested airways and weather conditions.  Inhale.  Exhale.  If you are in danger of missing another flight, scroll up and read“Getting to the point.”Can you ask for some sort of compensation such as flight vouchers or free meals?  As indicated in the terms of carriage, airlines are not obliged to compensate passengers for delays and cancellations over which they have no control.  The fancy term for this situation is force majeur which translates into“superior force.”It’s a fancy way of saying,“Sorry but it’s not our fault and we couldn’t do anything to avoid it.”

Do take note that budget airlines operate with limited fleets which means that their aircraft are always up in the sky somewhere.  So don’t expect a  spare aircraft lying  somewhere on a hangar waiting to be put to use.

 

 Budget Airlines. Budget Terminals. 

One of the reasons these airlines manage to keep their costs down is the low fees they need to pay the terminals which like them, are also budget.  Some cities have a single terminal for international flights such as  Bangkok’s Suvrnabhumi, but most have a separate terminal that’s as no frills as the airlines (even Bangkok has Dong Muang to service other domestic budget airlins).

Expect to be walking to your plane.  Be lucky if there’s a shuttle.  Inside the terminal, expect little amenities.  If you’re planning to sleep in the airport to catch an early morning or late night flight, good luck.  Most budget terminals are not 24 hours which means they shut-down.  If you’re really on a budget and don’t want the additional expense to head to the city and get a room, take a shuttle to the main airport which would most probably be 24-hours and stay there.

Hongkong, Malaysia, and Singapore all have their budget, or to use the more proper term, low-cost terminals.    In Europe, Paris has Orly and Londonw has Gatwick.  The Philippines is an exception.  The budget airlines all operate out of the newer and better Terminal 3 instead of the ageing Terminal 1.

 

 Shit happens. 

 Relax.  Think back of all the great travelers of the past and the inconveniences they suffered—- broken wheels, missing train tracks, bad-tempered horses, the list can go on.  You can scream, shout, kick, cry, and name drop all you want but it’s not gonna change.  The airline will go on with its business and while you can’t go on with yours.  You might have lost a day from your trip but you still have the rest of the days.  Lost luggage?  If you packed light (and you should have), then there’s nothing in there to make you lose sleep.

Some people swear-off budget airlines.  Good for them if they have the money.  But I don’t and I love to travel.  I accept these airlines for what they are.  Sure, it could be better and I hope they do make it better.  In the meantime, I have to admit it I’m stuck with them.  And if you can’t beat‘em, join‘em.


 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Uncategorized | Tags: cebu pacific air philippines , transportation , travel , vacation | Leave a comment 
 Chaotic GenSan and the Search for the Maranao Market 
 Posted on April 30, 2012 by Earl 
After the lake and the forests, the culture and the people, it was disconcerting to be in GenSan .  It was like my trips to Sagada before when upon arriving in Baguio City, the first thing I wanted to do was leave right away. I might as well go back straight to Manila.  Nothing in the city that had been listed in internet sites interested me. Those that did such as Mt. Matutum and Kalajia Karsts needed more time.  With just the afternoon to spend as I was returning to Manila tomorrow morning , the only thing I planned to do was head to the Maranao shops across the public market which I had read so much about. I actually left Lake Sebu early so I would have enough time to browse the shops and hopefully find something.



 The Case of the Missing Maranaos 

The multi-cab dropped me at Dolores Hotel which I had called a week before to reserve a single room.  It was located in a busy thoroughfare and was just a stone’s throw away from the public market.  There was a large lobby and a small business center.  Php 550/night got me a large room with a double bed, a small tv, and ensuite toilet and bath.  It was good value for its price and was clean at least.  It was mid-afternoon so I just showered a bit then headed out to the public market just around the corner to look for the Maranao souvenir shops.  Stuff here was reportedly being sold there at a much lower price than Davao.

I circled the entire block of the public market, did it again for another time, and then again, asked the security guard at the hotel, used Google Maps and the GPS in my Blackberry device, checked out the internet posts, but THERE WAS NO MARANAO SOUVENIR SHOPS!  Sure there were plenty  Maranaos and plenty Maranao shops selling sundry goods but where were the colorful malongs and the shiny brassware ?  The latest internet post about the souvenir shops were just a little over a year old but the time period between then and now must have been enough for changes to have taken place.  Like an archaeologist out to find a hidden city buried underneath centuries of rubble, I went back to its reputed site and other possible sites.  There was no trace of the market.  The hotel guard had mentioned“TLJ”but it was just a small general merchandise store.  Defeated, I went back to my hotel.


 The Case of the Missing Sauce 

So what does the vanquished do?  Eat!  Blogs had mentioned Kanto Grill which supposedly serve the freshest seafood on top of which was their secret sauce which was to die-for.  The hotel staff didn’t know about it.  Bad sign.  They asked other guests. Negative.  Hmmmm. A lady who had just walked in and overheard the entire thing chimed in that Kanto Grill had already closed at its location had been taken-over by SM.  Another defeat.  I had come to look forward to GenSan for only two things—- the Maranao shops and Kanto Grill’s secret sauce and both had been reduced to nothingness. Frustration is a small word to describe how I felt at that moment.  Not willing to put my faith and trust in a dated blogpost, I turned to the friendly female receptionist and asked,“Where can I eat?”She suggested I take a multi-cab and tell the driver to head to the barbecue places in San Pedro Lagao.

The driver didn’t seem to get it at first but I repeatedly kept-up the mantra,“Barbecue…barbecue…”either he was afraid I’d roast him over a charcoal pit or he had a sudden memory jolt but he did deliver me to a row of simple barbecue stalls with attached restaurants.  I went to the one at the far end on the right side which had two tables full of happy diners.

I chose two chorizoes and five sticks of pork barbecue.  Four days of eating nothing but tilapia had turned me into a ravenous carnivore.  Everyone else can have GenSan’s freshest seafood and tuna.  I want bits of sinewy muscle and soft fat.
 
No tilapia here! Only meat! Meat! Meat!
 
My order soon arrived together with a liter of Coke and two packets of rice in banana leaves.  What is it with Mindanao that it does barbecue so well?  The meat was tender and whatever marinade they used tasted very well.  It had just the right sweetness that went well with the smokey flavor imparted by the charcoal.  Extra two packets of rice please.

Done with dinner.  Now for dessert.  I took a trike to KCC Mall which I had passed by en route to the barbecue place.  It looked just like any mall with all the usual brands and a large food court and grocery in the basement.  Maybe because it was a holiday the next day that’s why the place was quite packed with people.  I didn’t find anything there to tickle my sweet tooth so I just headed back to my hotel.

Street peddlers had set-up shop selling second hand clothes at the street surrounding the hotel.  The public market was closed and in its place was an evening market along the road that sold cheap goods from China.  Nothing really special.

 

I only spent half a day in GenSan and didn’t go out much. From what I experienced in my very brief stay, I can’t say much about it.  There was nothing there to hold my interest plus I found the streets to be quite chaotic with all the multi-cabs.  Oh.  There was one thing I liked about GenSan, though.  In spite of  its population being largely Christian, Muslim presence was obvious here compared to other Mindanao cities such as Davao and Cagayan de Oro.  I chanced on a group of Muslim men in their white caps and gowns getting on a small jeep while the shiny minaret of a mosque loomed from behind.  The sight of that alone made me feel I was truly in Mindanao.  Mt. Matutum also makes an impressive sight as it looms over the city.



 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: GenSan | Tags: Dolores Hotel , GenSan | Leave a comment 
 Lake Sebu Day 4: Back to GenSan 
 Posted on April 30, 2012 by Earl 
There was nothing more to do in the morning except to pack my stuff hoping everything would fit.  I have become an expert in packing musical instruments from all my trips abroad.  It’s easy if you’re packing stuff and heading straight to the airport.  Getting on land transportation is a little more tricky as it means less space and more carelessness in handling and stowing luggage.  Double all that when you need to get on a beat-up mini-van with about a dozen more people than it normally carries.

I had brought my Lowe Alpine 75+15 backpack which is quite huge but stashing my klutang there was out of the question.  In came the two sludoy wrapped in my used shirts.  I had already marked and removed the frets  so there would be less chances of the fragile strings snapping should it something heavy be placed on top of my pack.  The kumbin g and sloli were wrapped in the tubao and placed between the sludoy .  I had brought my overnight bag as back-up bag in case the pack becomes too heavy and I go beyond the 15kg limit.  The klutang was wrapped in used straw sacks.  Mel had assured me when I called her that it wouldn’t be illegal to be transporting a small piece of wood.  I had become apprehensive that the DENR might call my attention to it as it seems just like any piece of cut wood. I would have to go through the entire process of explaining that it was in fact a musical instrument and why I have it.
 
Goodbye Lake Sebu!
 
I had an early lunch of what else… sugba na tilapia and instant pancit. When I asked for my bill, Elmer said I need not pay as they owners who dropped by yesterday and who I chatted with had told them to feed me as I were their first guest.  The couple who owned the Green Box, a doctor-wife and an engineer-husband who are based in Insulan, Sultan Kudarat, were really nice and gracious.  If only for that, I’d give a 5-star rating to Green Box and would stay again and even recommend it to others.  Sometimes you can forgive not-so-good facilities for really wonderful hosts.

The van to Surallah passed by past 12 noon already and fortunately there was still an available seat and the luggage space behind the last row of seats wasn’t full.  I was really lucky to have taken that seat as I was to discover on later in the trip as passengers hopped on and off, they really did fill it beyond its capacity as even the space where the engine was is used for seats!  When the entire van was full, the conductor road outside hanging dangerously at the back.

Surallah was a mere thirty minutes away and we finally let out at the bus station.  A Marbel-bound bus was pulling out just as I arrived at the bus bay so I got on an empty bus that filled in about 15 minutes.  There was no air-con but the cloudy weather made everything.

As I sat by the window looking at the gorgeous countryside of rolling hills and flat plains, the conductor swang by to collect my fare.  I gave him a twenty-peso bill and four one-peso coins.  He looked at me puzzedly and said something in Ilonggo which I of course, could not understand.“Tagalog,”I told him.  He was asking how much I had given him.“Twenty-four,”I answered. He moved on.  He must have forgotten the twenty-peso bill I gave him.

The middle-aged man seated beside me struck up a conversation  (translated in English here).

“Is this your first time here?”

“Yes.”

“Where are you from?

“Manila.”

“Didn’t you get scared coming here?”

“(smiling) No.”

I was surprised with this.  But he must have been more surprised at me traveling alone in this part of Mindanao.  I didn’t feel nor see anything out of the ordinary as to invite fear during my entire course of travel here.  I felt I was just like in any other provincial town.  He  introduced himself as pastor who was heading to Marbel with his wife for some errands. They were both very nice and we talked until we reached the Yellow Bus Line terminal.

I loved how the bus connections were all so easy and quick.  There was a waiting a/c bus at the bay and I took an aisle seat beside a young guy in office uniform.  I had an hour to get a some shut-eye.

The multi-cab chocked streets of GenSan greeted us as we pulled into the bus terminal.  I already missed Lake Sebu.  I must have had a sign on my forehead reading:“I’m new here”as porters and trike drivers swarmed around me.  One particular brusque porter kept grabbing my bag and was about to carry it off to the trike I had negotiated Php 70 to bring me to the hotel in the city proper. I let out at loud yell and he took off.

I had truly come back to realty.


 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: GenSan , Lake Sebu | Tags: GenSan , Lake Sebu | Leave a comment 
 Lake Sebu Day 3 (evening): An Evening with the T’boli 
 Posted on April 29, 2012 by Earl 
I had come to Lake Sebu not to seek out the lake but the people whose home it is.  I have been fascinated with the T’boli since I was in high-school and saw a documentary on the T’boli made by the Sta. Cruz Mission.  Resplendent in their traditional garb of handwoven textiles and colorful plastic beads and brass bangles, they caught my imagination.  Their dances using the tubular cloth which hang from their necks as they whirled feverishly around in circles while their feet lightly tapped the ground was amazing.  Their lute, the hegalong, had also taken on iconic status for me.  I knew that one day I would make this trip.  It did take decades before I finally set foot in the ancestral domain of the T’boli.  Progress has inevitably altered their lives and lifestyle and outside the tourist industry, finding their culture was quite difficult.  I was really lucky to have met Oyog.  She not only got me the instruments I needed but more importantly, she allowed me to set foot to glimpse their world of dance and music.

 

Returning from the trip to the falls and the T’boli Museum, Oyog had  dropped me at the Green Box to rest while she went to a village to seek out Joel.  She assured me that he was one of the best musicians and he could make me a dwege y, a sloli , and a t’nonggong .  About an hour later, she returned to tell me that she had gone to him in the fields where he was working on a ploughing machine and that he would come in the evening to make me the instruments and to play!  I was really excited about it as I have never seen a“living”example of a dwegey before.  She also assured me that in the evening there would be dancing.  The moto driver would fetch Joel at around 4.

I had more than ample time to go back to Kehelingan as I was interested in the t’nonggong I had seen the previous day.  The doors were closed to the main shop but someone in the restaurant called a plumped middle-aged lady that could pass-off as anyone’s gracious mother.  She opened the doors and we went in.  She was Nida Bacalang who was head of the foundation which was an umbrella organization of different craft-making associations.  She was very patient and answered all my questions and even let me try the different blouses and vests on display.  They were really beautiful and could cost up to Php 7,000 depending on the intricacy of the designs and the beadwork.  One of the simplest ones cost Php 800.  I tried on a big one and it fit me though it hang half-way up my torso.  If it had been long enough, I would have bought it even if it was a woman’s blouse.  A complete T’boli outfit consisting of a blouse, skirt, and all the accessories including head gear costs Php 7,000!

I bought one of the sludoy on display for Php 250.  I could have gladly bought the bigger and heavier one which was only  Php 100 more but I didn’t think I’d have space for it.  The instruments looked like the real thing and didn’t seem to have been made for the tourist market which most of the souvenir shops had.  I couldn’t help taking my eyes off the red square fabric hanging on the wall. It was a head gear worn by T’boli women minus the frame.  The fabric alone cost Php 500.  Attached to the frame so it could be worn properly on the head, it cost Php 800.  With beads hanging down from the edges, it costs Php 1,000.  She got one hanging from the restaurant and showed it to me.  I manage to persuade her to give it to me for Php 500 as it was quit dirty having been on display outside the restaurant’s dining area.

I spent the rest of the afternoon packing my stuff as I was leaving the next day. The instruments would have to be packed the next morning as they needed more time to dry out under the heat of the sun.

The moto driver came knocking on my door past at around 5 to say that Joel had arrived!  I quickly shuffled to Oyog’s house and there he was, cutting the bamboo to be used for the dwegey while his teen-aged son was removing the meat from the coconut which was to be used as resonator.  It was dusk and there wasn’t any light on Oyog’s tribal house. I had to make do with the flashlight on my Blackberry just so I could continue documenting his crafting of the instrument and also of that of the sloli .  Upstairs, Oyog’s youngest daughter was practicing on the t’nonggong. 

 

With her younger cousin, a cute little boy, they practiced the warrior dance while another girl beat out some rhythms on the drum.  It was fascinating and really fun to watch them as they were really intent on their dancing and playing. I was really taken-in by Oyog’s daughter and her natural love for the arts.  After retrieving my flashlight from my room, I chanced upon her practicing on the bamboo tubes which her cousin held upright.  She was continuously exhorting the others to play and play and play.

 

Night had fallen and a couple of young girls, students of Oyog, had arrived in T’boli garb.  They were fully made up and looked so pretty.  Oyog had told me earlier that there would be dancing and they would be in their traditional wear.  Seeing the young girls, I knew the evening would be really special.

A bonfire had been built in the center of the tribal house.  By now, Joel had finished making the dwegey and the sloli .   I would have to wait until my next visit for the t’nonggong as deer skin was unavailable.  He did bring his own drum which he would play later.  Oyog had wrapped some rice and the left-over fish we had for lunch in the leaves of the lemenge tree which she distributed to everyone.  The dinner of clams which I had asked Green Box to cook for me was brought over together with the tilapia chicharon I ordered from the nearby eatery.  We squatted on the floor with the food parcels before us and ate with our fingers.  We washed it all down with orange juice.
 
Communal dinner by bonfire
 

 


After clearing the dishes, the performance started.  And boy, did I have a fantastic time watching them dance and play.  Oyog annotated the performances and during the dances she would coach the three girls.  Joel was a true master musician who showed excellent playing of the t’nonggong . It was captivating to watch him coax vibrant sounds from such a small drum.  One playing style consisted of him flinging his left hand in the air after a few strikes.  At times, he would also touch the floor.  His son had apparently also taken after him as the boy also played the drum very well.

Accompanying Joel   was Oyog  on a flat slab of bamboo which had been attached to a small low wooden bench.  This substituted for the floor.  The special“instrument”had been made as a portable floor which could be brought anywhere there were performances, especially abroad.
 
Joel playing the“sloli”
 
 Madal tahu, one of the most difficult dances due to its fast rhythm was performed by Oyog who told me that whenever Joel plays the drum one can’t help but dance.  It really was true.

I felt so privileged to have been treated to such a performance.  I could not thank Joel enough for his time and the instruments he had made for me.  Shyly, he asked for just Php 200!  I gave him double that as it was too low.  I also gave him an advance of Php 500 to make me t’nonggong and a tambul. Deep in my heart, I knew he would not renege on his promise.
 
Playing the“kumbing”
 
It was past 10 when the performance ended.  Joel packed his stuff and bade good bye as he had to walk back home there being no motos available.  I stayed to just chat with Oyog but had to leave when her sister-in-law came by to say that her brother had been rushed to the hospital due to difficulty in breathing which didn’t seem to be such a big problem basing it on their conversation.

That evening as I lay down on my room I knew I had found my thesis to finally complete my MA.   Lake Sebu would be my“home”and the T’boli my“people.”

 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Lake Sebu | Tags: Lake Sebu , T&apos;boli , T&apos;boli dance , T&apos;boli music | Leave a comment 
 Lake Sebu Day 3 (morning): The House on Top of the Hill and the Water from the Top of the Mountains 
 Posted on April 29, 2012 by Earl 
Oyog begged off in the morning as it was Sunday and she was going to church.  I had made arrangements with our moto driver to go boating in the lake and hike all the way up the hill in the biggest island.

Around 8 in the morning, he came promptly down from the hill where Oyog lived bringing with him the klutang that Ma Fil had delivered.  The wood hadn’t fully dried yet so I  left it underneath the sun.  The nylon cord had also been replaced with abaca.

We hired a large traditional dug-out canoe for Php 200 with the moto driver rowing.  Come to think of it, I never even knew his name.  Punta Isla had motorized outrigger boats that take tourists around the lake.  It had a cover to keep the sun out and life jackets.  My canoe was powered by the strong arms of the driver who paddled slowly across the tranquil lake as I sat on a really low wooden bench.  There was no cover but I welcomed the sun’s warmth.  I would take the canoe anytime.  Not only is it more environmentally friendly but it really is the traditional way to go around the lake.

 

I had asked for a large canoe as seeing the smaller ones made me doubt my ability to balance in such narrow boats.  I marvel at the T’boli’s skill in being able to sit precariously on the edge of the small boats as they cast their nets on the water.

Our canoe skimmed the water and we went quietly past water lilies and fish pens to the middle of the lake.  If it were not for that radio or videoke blasting from one of the resorts, it would have been oh so still.  A few were already up and casting nets on the lake while others had water jugs with them presumably to fetch water somewhere.

 

Out in the center of the lake, life seemed so far remove from that of the mainland.  I was surpised how large the lake truly was.  It did  smell very fish though maybe because of all those fish pens.  Such a pity.

According to my moto driver/boatman, a canoe that size costs around Php 3,500 (cheap!) and could fit up to eight people.  I said I wanted to watch the boat builders and have one made. For that, he said, I would have to go to the mountains where the T’bolis who live there make them.

We reached the shore of Isla Tebowol and disembarked.  My little day pack partially fell into the water as I had failed to wear one of the shoulder straps.  Fortunately, my stuff inside didn’t get wet.

Someone was preaching in a small shack where about a couple of dozens of locals listened.  The trail was muddy and quite steep especially near the top.  Fortunately, steps had been carved out of the hill in the last few steep portions.  I was a little sweaty as we made it to the row of corns planted on top.  The small patch of land and the little hut was owned by the driver’s brother who was nowhere to be found.  The hut stood quietly empty as the corn leaves fluttered in the morning breeze.

 

 The House on the Hill 

Past the rows of corn, we exited to a patch of newly-tilled land.  This was the hill that we could see from the mainland.  On top, referred to by the T’boli as telutot , was a small shack with sacks as walls.  A couple were tilling the land while children played.  They were also related to my driver.

 

The view was amazing from where I stood.  The lake shone below while the famous“three fingers”contour formed by land that jutted out from the mainland.  It was really very beautiful and it was not surprising that other visitors who had come had expressed a desire to stay and perhaps spend the night on the hill.  But amidst the natural beauty was the depressing poverty of the family that lived there.

 

Their only means of livelihood was to plant corn on the small patch of land where they lived.  The harvest would be sold for about Php 30/kilo in Surallah.  Their last harvest only yielded 15 sacks.  The rest of the hilly field were planted with root crops for their own consumption.

 

Of the five kids, four went to school as one of them had been born with a non-functioning right arm that hand limply from his body.  To confound the problem was the young boy’s inability to speak.  It was so sad because he had a really cheerful disposition and smiled and posed gamely when I motioned to him that I wanted to take his photograph.

 

The eldest boy was an incoming third year high-school student but he was too short for his age.  He had gone through a lot to put himself to school, having worked in his school canteen in GenSan.  Asked where they get their drinking water, he pointed to an opposite island.  They take a steep path down the hill, cross by boat, and get water from a spring storing them in plastic gallons and return the same way.  Their living conditions were really deplorable.  But amidst all these, they welcomed me with warm smiles and even apologized for their condition as they were embarrassed with their shack.  I told them I would buy the kids school supplies and they could go pick them up at my driver’s place.  It was the least I could do for them.

My driver found me a long bamboo pole to use as a trekking pole as I didn’t wanna risk slipping on the steep trail on my way down.

As I made my way across the lake back to the mainland, I couldn’t help but think of the kids and their hard life.  I wished kids who had more in life would realize that there were other kids who were not so lucky.

 

Back at the mainland, we went to a general supplies store in Poblacion to get some notebooks, pad papers, pencils, and crayons for the kids.  While my driver brought them back to his home for safekeeping, I went to withdraw at the atm at the local bank beside KDatu Souvenirs.  Wonder of wonders, the atm worked!  One of the most magical moments in traveling is when you’re in an area where you least expect an atm and you find one and it actually dispenses money!  This was one of those moments.  I’ve had similar ones in Sagada and in Sapa.

My driver had returned and we motored back to the Green Box to wait for Oyog who still had not returned from church.  Maybe the sermon was long, I told my driver.  To kill time, I headed to the Kehulingan Craft Foundation a few meters down the road beside a restaurant that apparently was affiliated to the store.  The spacious store had beautiful T’boli wear for sale and other crafts such as baskets and a few musical instruments including a drum with a torn skin.
 
I want this drum!
 
I could have easily spotted any of the small items such as the beads because no one was there.  Fortunately for them, I wasn’t that kind of person.  I took photographs instead of the pages of a small book on T’boli music published by the Summer Institute of Linguistics.  On the small store out on the side of the road were small t’nonggong on display but whoever was in charge was probably busy at the restaurant as there were some people lunching there.

It was almost twelve so I decided to just head to one of the restaurants (if you could call it that) where I had dinner the previous night and ordered a tilapia chicharon.  Oyog and the driver soon arrived so I just told the server who was already cleaning the freshly-caught tilapia to just reserve it for dinner later in the evening.

Oyog had not yet lunched so we decided to just eat at the waterfalls even if it was way past lunchtime.  I had some bananas and junk food at Green Box so I wasn’t really hungry.

 Waterfalls 


 A stone-and-gravel road led up to the hills where the falls were.  It was a little bumpy but we managed to hold on to the moto.  The second falls could actually be glimpsed on one section of the road.  We chose to go to the second waterfalls first as it will be easier to go down the 700+ cemented steps leading to the first falls rather than hiking up. 

 
The First Falls: Hikung Alu
 
 Past the registration area where I got in for free courtesy of Oyog, a cemented pathways  led to the first falls known by its T’boli name: Hikung Alu which means“passageway.”Is it because it led to some netherworld that only the T’boli who first glimpsed know about?  To get up close and personal with the falls, I took the short trail leading to it but stopped short just before it as it was quite slippery.  Bathing in Hikunh Alu isn’t allowed probably because of the strong current.  Oyog joined me on the short walk back going down the banks to try to get some small clams to show me but there were none.”Maybe because the water is too strong,”she explained. 

 

 We took the 700+ concrete steps that led to the second falls.  It gently spiraled down through the forest and made for a nice albeit knee-tiring walk.  We heard the falls before we saw it.  It really was spectacular.  It was  high and cascaded in torrents down below.  So powerful was the water that a perennial spray of water hang around the swimming hole where the water plunged down.  It was really beautiful. 

 

 I’m always mesmerized with waterfalls.  The volumes of water that drop over the cliff face look so magical and it is awe-inspiring when you think of how powerful that water is.  I’ve always considered waterfalls as one of the most potent symbols of the majesty of God’s creation and that of nature.  It must have been even more awesome when the surroundings were in its natural state—no infrastructure, no pathways, no nothing.  Just the falls and nature.  I wonder how the first T’bolis who stumbled on those falls felt the moment they laid eyes on the crashing water. 

 


The falls were really beautiful and it’s just right that they be promoted in a big way as one of the natural attractions in Lake Sebu.  I just wished they were better managed and had more upkeep.  The cottages really looked old and quite dilapidated and there were some litter on the trails.

 The eateries surrounding the parking lot were without food anymore as it was way past lunch time so we just headed to one of the eateries overlooking Lake Seloton for tilapia chicharon and sugba .  Judging by how many vehicles stopped to buy the live tilapia swimming in wooden rectangular tanks, you’d really think that people love their tilapia in this part of the world.  The eatery we were at even ran out of the fish when a truckload of people stopped and bought kilos of fish. 
 
A truckload of tilapia enthusiasts
 
 
“Hey that’s my tilapia!”“Noooo! That’s mine!!”
 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Lake Sebu | Tags: boating in Lake Sebu , Lake Sebu , Seven Falls | 2 Comments 
 Lake Sebu Day 2: T’boli Crafts and Music 
 Posted on April 28, 2012 by Earl 
At around 6 in the morning, with the mist still hovering over the hills surrounding the lake, Oyog and I made our way to the slew of huts we had visited earlier.  It had rained in the wee hours of the morning so the trail was a little wet with a few slippery parts.  Nobody stirred as we passed quiet huts.  Only dogs came out to greet us with their barks.  I hurried down the trail on the heels of Oyog as I didn’t want any dog following me around.

 

As we turned a corner, up on a low hill, we espied the family of brass casters who were all up and at work on their little kiln.  The molds had already been baked and they were just waiting for the melted metal to heat up at the right temperature before it could be poured.  It was hot as smoke rose from the bonfire where the metal was heating-up to a fiery orange color.  Finally, the man who had made my bell the previous day, using a long iron tong, lifted the container and poured it on the molds.  I understood why they went to work so early in the morning.  The smoldering heat of the kiln would have made work unbearably hot in the middle of the day.

 


About fifteen minutes later, with the metal finally cooled and set, he broke the a flat mold apart revealing a shiny belt buckle.  The rest of the molds were cone-shaped revealing beautiful bells with filigreed designs.  They all glinted in the rays of the morning sun.
 
Molds waiting for hot melted metal to be poured
 


 

In the meantime, the women chiseled newly minted little bells using small metal chisels which they pounded with to remove excess metal bits.  Children milled around helping around.

On the other side were a group of women who were also chiseling little bells.  One of them brought out a basin of bells and said they had been ordered by somebody.

It was so early in the morning and yet these people were hard at work already.

Back at the Green Box, I slept a bit as there was still a bit of time for some shut-eye before heading to our next destination—- a village to visit a musician.

I was really excited about this day as we were heading to the house of Ma Fil, a master musician who was going to make me some instruments.  We hired a moto and a driver for the day (Php 500).  The bike had none of the seat extension like what the other motos regularly used for commuting had so the three of us were squished together with me between Oyog and the driver.  I was literally breathing down his neck especially downhill when we would all slide forward.  I was quite worried that with all the weight forward the moto would topple.  Core training was put to good use.

 

The ride was on the main road that followed the ridge overlooking the lake.  Parts of the lake that didn’t have any tilapia cages andresorts were quite pretty.  Small souvenir stalls with woven baskets and beads hanging out front were picturesque.  From the turn-off to the village, the road had become rocky but it was all very manageable.  I understood why Oyog had wanted to hire a moto driver she knew as a lot of the motos were just wheezing pass us at almost breakneck speeds.  An accident was the last thing we needed in this part of the world.

Leaving the main road behind, we entered a world of green with verdant mountains and hills and undulating fields.

 

We finally stopped at a small clearing where we parked the moto.  We went up some steps carved onto the compact soil and up a small plateau where a large traditional T’boli house stood.

 Ma Fil the Musician 

The view was gorgeous as we could see the other side of the lake and fields as far as the eyes could see.  A few kids were playing basketball on the small dusty field on the far right of which stood two small huts.

It was very cool and shady in the T’boli house.  Solid logs held the house aloft which was accessed by a short flight of stairs.  It was one big open space inside.  The stove was on near the right corner of the house while on one corner right by the doorway were folded mattresses and blankets.  Bamboo slats as flooring made everything very cool.

 

 

Ma Fil, the owner of the house and my reason for coming soon arrived.  Hanging on a beam above the stove was a sludoy , a 5-stringed bamboo zither.  He took it and began playing.  Soft sounds emanated from the instruments as his fingers deftly plucked the strips of bamboo that had been cut and raised to serve as strings.  He played a few more pieces for me.

 

It was in the hegalong , the iconic T’boli 2-stringed lute that his mastery as a musician truly shined.  Laying the instrument he himself had put together and designed, horizontally on his lap, his right pointer finger played the strings with a plectrum while the fingers of his left hand went up and down the neck of the lute on the frets.

 

One piece imitated the sounds of a wood pecker.  In this one, Oyog struckthe strings with a pair of very thin almost straw-like sticks which resulted in some sounds being damped.  It was a really unique way of playing a lute, something I have not seen before.

It was a magical moment sitting on the floors of the house as the sound of the hegalong embraced me.  This is what I had come to Lake Sebu for.

The performance ended and Ma Fil went off to get a node of bamboo to make a sludoy for me.  I was willing to wait the whole day just to watch him make the instrument.  A lot of people can play but few can make instruments and one of the signs of a master musician is his ability to craft instruments.  I was going to seize this opportunity.

He returned with a newly-cut node of bamboo which he smoked on the stove to dry it out.  He put it out under the searing heat of the sun as he wove rattan strips to make a ring around both ends of the bamboo.  Retrieving the now dried bamboo, he put the woven rattan ring and then with a sharp knife, carefully cut out strip of the skin which would be the strings.  Small flat pieces of bamboo were wedged to raise the strings.  A small hole was also cut out on both ends to allow the sound to resonate from the instrument.

Ma Fil constantly shaved the strings until it was the desired thinness.  He then returned the instruments to the stove to smoke it some more.  Another round of plucking and listening to the strings.  Apparently dissatisfied with one, he broke it and made another one.  Testing the sludoy again, it became obvious it had passed his quality control when he finally started playing.


By this time, the little boys he had sent out to bring a trunk of a lemenge tree had returned.  Ma Fil then proceeded outside to cut and remove the bark from the wood until its pale white flesh showed.  He cut shallow notches on both ends to which he tied black nylon strings he had found and taken from a used coal sack.  The notch would prevent the string from sliding off the instrument when hanged and played.  He was soon done and getting two bamboo poles, he stuck on them ground to which he hanged the log of wood.  Taking two short sticks he had also cut from the one of the branches, he began playing.  The klutang was done!

 


 
My“klutang”and“sludoy”drying in the sun
 
While waiting for the klutangtod dry under the sun together with the sludoy , he still had enough energy left as he took a discarded piece of wood and started carving a mini hegalong for me.“Sample,”he told me with a grin.  It was wonderful how he was able to carve out the graceful curves of the lute from the wood.
 
Ma Fil making a mini“hegalong”
 
It was way past lunch and we had not brought any food for us as we had not anticipated the long time we would be spending with Ma Fil.  My stomach was grumbling but I wasn’t complaining.  I was too much engrossed on what I had been watching, listening, and learning.

I paid Ma Fil Php 500 for the sludoy and klutang he had made.  It was a small price to pay for his efforts.  Oyog later told me that Ma Fil had been working in the fields to which he was being paid a measly Php 100 per day!  His son had told him to hurry-up with what he was doing as he needed to return to his work in the fields.  Php 100 matters a lot to a family with no other source of income to feed them.  But Ma Fil had told his son that he had to finish making the instrument as I might want to buy it.  I think instrument-makers like him should be encouraged to make instruments to keep his craft going.  As the tourist market gets flooded with imitation instruments that look good as display pieces only, real music instruments from real makers should be patronized.  He used to play at Punta Isla before but being paid only Php 150 per day with no meals and no transpo allowance, he has since stopped as it wasn’t enough.

I was shocked to hear this as the resort could have at least given him free meals.  Transpo to and from his place to the Poblacion costs Php 80 per day already, so what would be left wouldn’t even be enough to buy a kilo of rice.

We only brought the sludoy back with us as it was impossible to bring the klutang .  I just gave Ma Fil 50 bucks to get a moto and bring it to the Green Box.

We motored back to the main road and went to one of the roadside eateries for a lunch of what else…. tilapia!  The chicharon tilapia was very good but even better was the lagpang .  It was charcoal-roasted tilapia that had been cooked in a sourish soup. It was tasty and good.

 

 

Next stop was Lang Dulay, the dream weaver.

 The Weavers 

Located in a small village past the area where the recent cyclone wreaked havoc, we reached the small school established by National Living Treasure, Lang Dulay, where she teaches the younger generation the ancient art of t’nalak weaving.

 

I first came across Lang Dulay in the Dreamweavers video and I have since been fascinated with her and her craft.  Unfortunately, I had come at the wrong time.  It was a weekend and the school was closed and the grand old lady, now in her 80s and no longer weaving, was in Poblacion.

 

We went up and took a look around the school was just a wide area in the stilted house where t’nalak was i the various staged of weaving.  Soon, some of her students arrived.  They were all very nice and answered all my questions.

Apparently, due to her age, Lang Dulay, fondly referred to by her students as“Lola”no longer weaves.  She still teaches, though, and at present has 16 active students, all female as it is taboo for men to weave t’nalak .  The women are all involved in the process of making the cloth from the dyeing to the knotting and the weaving. They say that the weaving is actually not very difficult.  It is the process of dyeing the threads and tying the knots that take a lot of time.

 

All the designs are done by Lang Dulay as she is the only one who knows up to a hundred designs, all coming from her dreams as the T’boli believe that the designs of this precious and almost sacred cloth must come from dreams.  Lang Dulay starts the initial knots for the first set of designs which are then continued by the students.  For an entire bolt of t’nalak that had been personally tied by Lang Dulay herself from top to bottom, the cost would be Php 1,500/meter. The actual weaving is done by one of her students though.  A bolt of cloth done by one of the students is priced much lower from Php 600-700/meter depending on the design.

Unlike the cheaper ones at Php 350/meter sold at the souvenir shops, those from the school of Lang Dulay only uses natural dyes which means a more permanent coloring and the designs are truly beautiful. Only the traditional colors of red, brown, and natural are also only used. Those knotted by Lang Dulay bear her signature woven at the end of the bolt.  Also, it is only Lang Dulay who makes cloth with as much as four different designs in a single bolt.

 

I could only afford a 2.5 meter bolt woven by one of her students.  It was a keepsake well worth the price.

Storm clouds had again gathered and we made a quick exit to beat the rain.  We arrived back at the Green Box just as the clouds let loose with a torrent of rain.

 Travel Tips 

1. T’nalak cloth is generally sold in bolts of 5 meters unless they were made in bolts lesser than that such as 2.5 meters.  Because of the designs, you cannot simply ask them to cut.  The bolts would have a“blank”edge between the designs to signify the end of one entire bolt measuring for example, 5 meters.  It is only at those“blanks”that the cloth could be cut.

2.  Bring cash of course.  Don’t expect to pay with a card.

3.  You can order a bolt and have them sent via LBC to you.

4.  The school is open Monday to Friday only.  But the people are nice enough to open it and talk to you if you wanna look around.  At the very least, buy some cloth for their effort.
 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Lake Sebu | Tags: ethnic music , hegalong , Lake Sebu , sludoy , T&apos;boli , T&apos;boli crafts , T&apos;boli music | Leave a comment 
 Lake Sebu Day 1: Getting there is a an adventure 
 Posted on April 27, 2012 by Earl 

 
 

After the narrow Airbus A320 of budget airlines and the even  narrower seats and non-existent leg room, the economy class of PAL’s Airbus 330 (YES!!!!) seemed like first-class.  Wide seats, lots of leg room, and 2-seat configuration on the sides.  Pure bliss!  It was enought to make me want to ditch budget airlines altogether.  Making it even better was not having a seat-mate and because the plane was nearly half-empty, acrosss me was an entire middle row begging for occupancy! As soon as the plane had cleared take-off and the seat-belt sign had gone out,  I skedaddled to the empty row, pulled-up the arm rests, inflated my pillow, and promptly lied down and fell asleep.
 
PAL you are my pal!
 
I woke-up about a half-way into the flight to GenSan with my snacks of packaged biscuits and peanuts on the tray table.  As the plane started its initial approach, I munched them down, asked for a glass of water from the smiley and nice flight attendant, and tried to go back to sleep again.  I loved this flight!
 
See the seats?
 
Touchdown was smooth and the weather was fair.  The small arrivals area was crammed as we crowded on the conveyor belt waiting for our luggage.  I had brought my large Vietnam-made (you know what that means) Lowe Alpine 75+15 backpack as I knew I was gonna bring home some musical instruments.  That meant having to wait for my luggage with the rest of the sweating crowd.  Unfortunately, mine was one of the last to come out.

As soon as I exited, I was swarmed with touts offering transpo to the  city center.  The moto driver with a Php 150 ride to the Yellow Bus Line terminal edged out the cab driver who was offering Php 350.  Getting on a waiting multi-cab was a lot cheaper at just Php 50 but that meant waiting for it to fill-up with passengers.  Anyway, I kinda missed hopping on the back of a moto.

The driver was engaging enough and pointed out certain places of interests such as Pacquiao’s house (big but looked quite ordinary) and the fish port.

At the Yellow Bus Terminal, a Marbel-bound a/c bus was ready to depart in a couple of minutes. My backpack went  in the luggage compartment and I  boarded the clean and comfortable bus and snagged a nice window seat (again!) in the middle of the bus.  It soon filled-up and we left at around 10:30am.

Marbel or Koronadal as it is officially known is just an hour away. I woke-up from my nap just as the bus pulled-in at the Marbel bus station. Yellow Bus Line or YBL as the local refer it seems to be the major bus company here. It’s what Victory Liner is to Baguio.  The moto driver had told me earlier that there was van going straight to Lake Sebu which was a better option to getting on the YBL to Surallah, thirty minutes away, then a 15-minute van ride to Lake Sebu. On inquiry, I was told by the security guard that the vans were on another terminal and I had to take a trike there.  It was just a couple of hundreds of meters and cost Php me 10.
 
Not going to Lake Sebu? How about heading to Surallah, Tacurong, Isulan, or Maitum? These vans go there as well.
 
Whether it would have been faster if I had taken the Surallah-Lake Sebu route, I don’t know.  But it seemed like forever before the van finally took off. When I arrived at the van terminal, a white L300 sat waiting there.  The seats beside the driver had already been reserved by two girls.   A big guy in a red sport shirt emblazoned with an embroidered logo was  seated on the first passenger seat row.   He told me to just sit beside him as it was cooler there.   He was all sweaty but I did realize that the row also had the widest leg room.    I asked him to reserve the seat for me and went to the store just behind the van. My backpack went to the small luggage space behind the last row of seats.  On my count, there were five passengers already.  It was going to be a long wait knowing that rural vans won’t leave without it overflowing with passengers.
 
Look for this signboard on parked L300s at the terminal. Pick your seat, leave something non-valuable like a jack to mark it, then wait and wait and wait outside.
 
Someone came along shouting,“lechon!”She was selling lechon in small plastic packages at Php 50 per pack.  I was tempted to buy one but figured it might not taste good or worst, might upset my stomach.  The van beside ours had already filled-up and was getting ready to leave for Maitum.  There was nothing to do but watch the world go by and wait.

I was digging into a pack of Oishi Baconnetes and sipping a bottle of Sprite when the barker motioned to me what we were ready to go.  I had been waiting to close for an hour already.  It was almost 12 noon and a couple of more passengers had boarded.  The open windows let in some breeze as we made our way along the sealed highway.  People got on and off the van as it also functioned like a jeepney ferrying passengers to nearby stops along the main road.  At Surallah, we passed by the newish and modern-looking bus station where some kind of toll fee was paid by the driver to a small wooden booth by the side of the road.  By the time we started climbing the curving roads to Lake Sebu, there were just about four of us including my seat mate.  The weather had grown noticeably cooler and flat dusty plains gave way to rolling hills.  The lake soon came into view and signboards of the resorts dotted the highway. The van dropped us at Poblacion which was the center of town.

 Don’t wanna make punta 

 to Punta Isla 

My stomach was grumbling so I hopped on a moto and sped to Punta Isla for late lunch.  I had heard a lot about this place—that the food was good, that you could eat by the lake, and that it was the only lake-side accommodation. From the main road, we turned left to a stoney unpaved road, passed the T’boli Museuam and the COWHED shop, until we reached the end of the line.  Cars lined the small parking area and as soon as I entered the open-air restaurant on the left , I knew I had entered into a tourist trap.

Perusing the menu, it was clear that I was going to have tilapia during my entire stay at Lake Sebu.  Servings were for four people as each dish was about a kilo of tilapia. That meant having to eat the entire 1 kilo of tilapia chicharon all by my lonesome self with no one to share it and the cost (Php 190) with.“You can have the rest wrapped to eat later,”the helpful waitress suggested.

While waiting for lunch, I went down to the floating restaurants.  Though picturesque, it quite frankly smelled like one big giant fishpond.  A fishpond full of tilapia.  What would have otherwise been a quiet tranquil lake was marred by the sight of so many fish pens. It was really really ugly.

 

Punta Isla itself was ugly.  This was one resort that really stuck-out like a sore thumb.  I was sure glad I wasn’t staying there.  Concrete hulking structures, noisy tourists, and a general look and feel of tackiness and wanton crass commercialism.  The only thing interesting was a small zip line that carried stuff in a basket from the kitchen to the lake.  A couple of T’boli girls were in full regalia seated at a bench probably waiting for their dance number for the mandatory cultural show to the guests.

Lunch was ready by the time I returned to my table with a view of the lake.  More local tourists had come in and the place was threatening to have the look and sound of Tagaytay on weekends.   I was expecting a videoke to start blasting soon.

The serving was really plentiful as a kilo of tilapia was equal to two big fishes. I nearly chocked with all that deep-fried tilapia meat.  The meat had been filleted and cut into bite-sized pieces which were deep fried to a crisp.  It was really good though especially the bones which were cooked intact.  As Colonel Sanders would say: it was finger lickin’good.
 
The start of the tilapia diet.
 
I made a quick look-see at the souvenir shop which was selling a kulintan g set for Php 15,000 and a used Dream Weavers documentary VHS for Php 550.  I was tempted to buy the latter  but since it was a used copy, I wasn’t sure if it was gonna play.  I wished the CCP would re-issue it as I lost my copy.

Out of Punta Isla on board another moto and on to Green Box pharmacy.  Maria, whom I had contacted through the internet, had texted me that I was to stay at the guesthouse at Green Box just opposite her house.  Her tribal house had fallen in disrepair and could not accommodate me so she booked me there instead.  The arrangement suited me.

 Living in the Green Box 

The Green Box pharmacy was on the side of the road overlooking a small patch of greenery, a cluster of huts, and of course, the lake.
 
There are more than medicines in this pharmacy.
 
It looked really neat and tidy.  Aside from medicines, there was a whole lot of other stuff being sold such as junk food, canned and bottled drinks, instant noodles, and other things you might suddenly need such as a pink headband or a plastic bracelet with letters you can arrange to form a message.

The attached open dining area was very breezy and looked like an inviting place to just lounge around.

 

A short flight of steep stairs by the side of the dining area led to the four small guest rooms that faced a slope.  A few meters away was the common bathroom.  The place  had barely been open a month and a lot of things still needed work.  The bathroom wasn’t tiled yet and construction stuff littered the slope.

My room was very clean though and smelled of fresh paint.  It was large and had a queen-sized bed and a night stand.  The staff, led by Elmer, who also stays in one of the rooms were very accommodating.  I was to learn later on that they were quite worried about my arrival as they were totally unprepared to accept anyone.  Maria, who also goes by her T’boli name of Oyog, had been unable to accept me in her homestay as her tribal house needed repairing.  Fortunately, there was Green Box and she managed to persuade them to accept me their very first guest!

The room was Php 550/night which included breakfast.  Since I had brought my stash of cereal drinks, I asked if I could just convert my breakfasts to dinners to which they agreed.  They asked me what I wanted to have for that evening.  I couldn’t think of anything to request.  They said I could ask for anything as long as it was in their capacity to cook it.  After all that fish for lunch, the only thing I could think of was vegetables.  I took-up their suggestion of pakbet. 

Across the road and up a small hill was Maria’s office and house opposite of which was SIKAT, the school of indigenous knowledge for T’boli children.  I had found Maria through the internet and learned that she was a cultural worker and ran homestays.  I knew she was going to be a minefield of information and could lead me to what I wanted to see and do.    No, the zipline wasn’t in my bucket list though I had a mild interest to see the famous waterfalls.   What I wanted most was to meet musicians and dancers and experience the culture.   Taling to her and seeing  pictures of her and even a plaque showing her participation in a Smithsonian festival, I knew I had met the right person.
 
Oyog’s office and the SIKAT school just across the road
 



 Hear the ringing of the bells . . . 

It was mid-afternoon so there was still time for a boat ride across the lake to the biggest island from where we could go all the way up and see the sun set.  We headed down the road and to a small pathway to a small slew of huts by the lake’s edge.  It had began to rain by then and we sought refuge in a small house.  It was obvious that there would be no boating.  When the rain stopped, we headed instead to some houses to see some beadwork being done.  The T’boli were master bead makers and it had become a home industry to them to created beaded necklaces and belts to be sold to the tourist market.

We walked past some rows of houses and on to a small cluster of huts where a family of brass casters lived.  Work was over for the day and they were just lounging around with a few kids playing.  About a dozen newly casted bells sat on the ground waiting for the tiny bell inside to be attached.  I bought one for Php 150 and they promptly went to work cleaning the bell while a woman started hacking off the newly-casted small bells.  It was hard work watching her as she set about hamming the clumps of small bells so they could all be separated from each other. The small bells cost Php 5.00 each while the bigger one was Php 15.
 
Brass casting is a family affair
 
A couple of minutes later, my newly-made bell was ready all shining and gleaming.  Maria, whom I shall now refer to as Oyog, said that their family came from a far-off village that was famous for brass casting. My bell was really nice and light and had a pure ringing sound compared to the bells I bought a decade back in Aldevinco in Davao.  Edgar Allan Poe would be proud of the sound of the bells.
 
This woman is making tiny small bells used in accessories. The T’boli cast bells, belt buckles, and other items using the lost-wax method.
 
These kids are playing with newly minted bells. Young as they are, they know how to tap the bells to remove any soil and debris left-over during the minting.
 
We were going back the next day at 6 in the morning which was the time they work on their casting.

There wasn’t much to do after dinner.  I was all alone and the two girls who were running the pharmacy had gone home.  Only Elmer and I were left so we just sat around and told stories.  I had a really nice vibe about the place even with its minor inconveniences.

There was nothing really remarkable about this day.  I admit I was a bit disappointed with Lake Sebu as I envisioned a really tranquil lake where you could just by the shore and do nothing.  But the sight of all those tilapia cages totally shattered any illusion.  Add to that the blast of the videoke from the lakeside restaurants.

 

But I had come to Lake Sebu more for the T’boli people and their culture.  Though it became obvious as soon as I got off the van at Poblacion that it wasn’t really going to be easy to find it.  The T’boli look no different from you and me.  Their colorful wear and accessories are reserved for important occasions or when going to church (Yes! They’re either Catholic or Christian nowadays).
 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Lake Sebu | Tags: Lake Sebu , transportation to Lake Sebu | Leave a comment 
 Hiking in Kubah National Park 
 Posted on April 18, 2012 by Earl 
 

This is a really late post of my trip to Kubah during the Lenten break.  But better late than never.  I really enjoyed my time at Kubah, albeit a really short one, and the trip deserves its own post.

Thank to the good roads and lack of a crowd, I managed to visit the longhouses at Benuk and Annah Rais in the morning with enough time for a quick hike at Kubah National Park .  Or perhaps the short time spent at the longhouses were due more to the general lack of anything to really do except walk along the bamboo boardwalks with a goofy smile on the face and nodding to the bored residents like it was a secret code that allowed you access to their lives.  I wonder how it feels to have crowds of strangers trampling on your front yard every single day of your life?

Day 2 in Kuching and the threat of thunderstorms made me forgo my planned excursion to Bako National Park.  The RM 230 cab hire definitely did not figure in my budget but what the heck, I might as well take in whatever experience I could.  Tour groups?  I’m quite allergic to them.

 

Kubah is the most accessible national park from Kuching.  Unfortunately, there are no regular buses to the park so you either take a mini van, a cab, or a your own vehicle.  From the main road, we followed the sign to the Matang Family Park and followed the road past it until we reached the national park entrance.  The lady manning the small office was very cheerful and suggested I do a 3 hour loop to the waterfall.  I opted to do the Selang trail which would take me to the viewpoint using the sealed road to the summit then hanging a right to the Rayu Trail which would later meet the Selang trail.  It was a much better route she said as it would mean descending the steep parts of the Selang rather than ascending it.  The 6 hour return hike on a sealed road to the summit of the mountain was out of the question as it would mean getting back down in the dark.  She colored the route for me on a simple hand-drawn map and I was off to the trail after a quick stop at the comfort room.

 

The sun was out and it was really really hot as I made my way up the steep sealed road.  At times I would walk backwards just to relieve the pressure on my quads.  Give me a forest trail anytime.  Sealed roads are more jarring to both knees and feet not to mention the heat it gives off.  It reminded my of the road up the jump-off point in Gulugod Baboy.  This one was thankfully less steeper.  A slowly made my way up wishing I had not listened to the lady and had taken the jungle trail instead.  I went pass by a middle-aged couple who were taking photographs of a lizard on a tree by the side of the road.

 


 
An orange mark for the Rayu Trail
 

The road finally leveled off and I took a break at the leafy frog pond.  Frogs are nocturnal animals so there wasn’t a single one croaking on the muddy pond singed by boardwalks.  It was cool and quiet place to seek shelter from the heat and to catch my breath.  I would have stayed longer if I had more time in the park.

A few meters from the pond, I veered right to the sign post marking the start of the Rayu Trail .    I was told to simply follow the color coding of the trails which were marked on the trees.  Orange for Rayu and yellow for Selang.  I made a conscious effort to look for the painted barks on the trees just to make sure I was on the right trail.  Last year, the small group I was  hiking with at Taman Negara in West Malaysia had missed the trail and we had gone deeper into the jungle rather than out of it.  We had not bothered to carefully look at the map nor taken heed of the color coding.  I was not going to take chances this time as I was all alone  and didn’t have a lot of sun time.

 

All alone on the trail, I was dwarfed by ancient trees that soared to the sky almost blotting it out.   It was very cool and leafy and the only sound was that of insects buzzing.  So peaceful it was on the trail, it was almost meditative.  With nary an elevation and clear trail sounds, I took my time to breathe in the surroundings.  There was no summit to assault and no campsite to set-up.  This was a just a short hike and I was going to savor it.

What it lacks in wildlife Kubah makes up for it in vegetation, particularly palms.  There were lots and lots of wild palms and some of them were really big you can pick one off (of course I didn’t do that) and use it as an umbrella.  I grew up with palms as we had several pots of them that my mom used to decorate the corners of the house with. Dead spaces suddenly came to life with these fan-like wonders.  In the wild, they were even more beautiful.  Like beautiful forest flowers, they stood out among the bushes and trees.

 

The Rayu Trail eventually linked-up with the Selang Trail which led to the viewpoint, my final destination.  The high wooden platform was set in a small clearing and reached by a short steep ladder.  The views of the valley and the small villages were magnificent.

I took in the scene while  snacking on the leftover kek lapis I had bought the other day .  I still had not bumped on a single soul on the trail and the viewpoint and the view was all mine.  I could have sat there for ever but I had to make my way back and be at the headquarters by 4pm.  From the viewpoint, the trail suddenly became steeper with some sections having ropes to make it easier.  As I slowly made my way down, I now understood why the lady at the headquarters advised me to take the sealed road so as to the stepper part on the descent.  Ascending it would take the wind out of anyone.  There were carved steps and some parts had wooden slabs to keep anyone from slipping all the way down. Nothing treacherous but definitely difficult.

I finally reached the Main Trail that led to the camp grounds and eventually to the park headquarters.  All in all, it took me less than two hours to do the entire loop.

 

 Trip Tips 

1.  You can take a van and asked to be let-off at the turn-off to Matang Family Park then walk to the park entrance from there.  As for getting back to Kuching . . . I supposed you could wait by the side of the road.

2.  There are many walking trails and it all depends on how much time you’ve got. The Summit Trail is a sealed road that goes all the way up to the summit.  Yes, it it is sealed but it doesn’t mean you can take a vehicle.  Walk.

3.  There are cottages, chalets, and dorms if you wanna sleep over. You gotta book through the Sarawak Forestry Department.  There’s also a canteen.

4.  There’s a simple hand-drawn map which is easy to follow and includes the hiking time.

5.  The lady manning the little office at the start of the Summit Trail is very very friendly and helpful.



 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: Kubah National Park , Sarawak | Tags: Hiking in Malaysia , Kubah , Malaysia , Malaysia national park | Leave a comment 
 A Queen in the Universe? 
 Posted on April 16, 2012 by Earl 
 
I am what I am
 
The controversy over Miss Canada Universe contestant, 25-year old transgender Jenna Talakova, and her subsequentdisqualification and later reinstatement, have had people doing a Sushmita Sen, asking themselves and others,“What is the essence of a woman?”The Miss Universe, in their landmark decision, has reinstated Ms. Talackova and has since paved the way for transgenders to join what is probably the world’s most famous and most popular pageant by 2013.

In the 7,107 islands (at low tide)  of the Philippines, beauty pageant-crazy Filipinos can’t help being drawn to the issue  especially with the announcement of Bb. Pilipinas Charities, local franchise holder of the Ms. Universe, that they were following the lead office’s decision thereby paving the way for transgenders to compete.

Make no mistake about it. It is the dream of a lot of gay men, not just transgenders, to be Miss Universe.  Even that 200-lb bench pressing guy at your nearest Gold’s Gym hiding underneath the veneer of heterosexuality in basketball shorts and a loose shirt, has at least once in his lifetime, took to some obscure corner in his room, hairbrush on one hand, and with all the courage he could muster, uttered the sacred invocation—–“Mabuhay!  I am Maria Antonia de la Reyna from the 7,101 islands of the Philiiiipppppiiiinnnnnneeesss!”

Like all good Filipinos, I admittedly grew-up with the Ms. Universe pageant.  Time stood still in our household as we all tuned to the television set and with bated breath waited for Ms. Philippines to take to the stage during the Parade of Nations and in what would probably be her only moment of glory in the pageant, cry out,“from the Philippiiiiines!”With even deeper breaths, we waited for her name to be called among the semi-finalists.  Of course, we were disappointed a lot of times.

I think I finally lost the Ms. Universe habit and with beauty pageants in general mid-college.  I don’t know why.  Somehow, I just lost interest.  I think the last pageant I fully watched was the one when Sushmita Sen of India took the crown.  When the pageant came to Manila and the entire nation burdened Charlene Gonzales with the role of championing Filipino pride and glory,  I didn’t pay much attention to it except the famous the interview portion and to notice that she looked like an old-fashioned debutant in her twill gown.  Beauty queens have since come and gone with a few Pinays managing to inch themselves closer to the crown than the others.  There have been a few mildly interesting news such as Miriam Quiambao and Venus Raj almost taking the crown and Ms. Angola, being the first black to win the pageant but I have since loss interest until now.
 
Who is the fairest of them all?
 
So should transgenders be allowed to compete in the Ms. Universe?

No.  I’ll say it again. No.  I have nothing against transgenders as I sincerely believe they are as human as you and me and deserve equal respect and love at the same level as all others.  However, being equal does not necessarily equate to being able to have everything you ask for.  Certain doors are open to everyone while some remain closed to some.  And it doesn’t necessarily mean inequality.  It just is because life is just is. We have to accept the fact that life has certain appropriations.  In the case of the Ms. Universe, it has been appropriated to women.  Real women.

The Ms.  Universe has always been about women both in the sex and gender sense of what being a woman is.  In the sex sense, Ms. Universe as a pageant celebrates female beauty not withstanding that contestants from a certain South American country reportedly undergo a series of reconstructions to make them more beautiful.  In the gender sense, the Ms. Universe pageant celebrates  what it means to be a woman in this ever changing world even if it includes parading in a swim suit.

I would like to believe that each and every woman who competes in the pageant brings with her the courage and the experience of her womanhood.  It  includes her transformation from a gawky adolescent to a shimmering beauty queen.  It includes  her determination to succeed as a career woman or a genius who can both be mentally and physically attractive.  It includes all the ups and downs of life just because she is a woman as determined by her chromosomes and her culture.  Her being a woman is a result of her gendered experiences.  And let me say this.  A woman who has always aspired to be beautiful, to be admired and loved for her beauty, and in doing so has opted to celebrate herself in a beauty pageant doesn’t make her any less than a woman who aspires to win the Math Olympiad. They’re just both women.  Period.

Transgenders, no matter their emotional and psychological make-up,  have none of these.  A new sex can be surgically placed but a new gender cannot.  Whatever desires, yearnings, and experiences they may have as a woman trapped in a man’s body all remain in the locus of their being a transgender.  They may find emotional and physical release in hormone injections and plastic surgery but it does not release them from their gender of a man transformed into a woman.  If chromosomes, the most basic unit of biological assignation of sex cannot even preclude gender, what more with plastic surgery?  Where will be the shared experience with women across all ethnicities and across all generations?  Some in the gay movement may argue that the road to civil rights, equality, and social transformation is equally shared by all“minorities.”Yes, there are shared experience but no equal experiences.

As gay activism continues to battle for civil rights and equal opportunities and transgenders take their own special places in society and in its culture, both have to be cognizant of the fact that in the area of gender, there are appropriated spaces.  To recognize one’s gender is to recognize other genders as well.  To claim your place in society is to respect the place of others.

The place of a woman, a biologically and culturally determined woman, in a beauty pageant is the Ms. Universe just as the place of a transgendered, also biologically and culturally determined, is the Ms.  Tiffany.  I wonder if the very same gay movements who hail the decision of the Ms. Universe pageant would be as accepting if lesbians start clamoring for their right to join  Mr. Gay World?

If the Ms. Universe organizers and owner, Donald Trump, think of the pageant as a mere parade of beauties rather than a parade of women, then perhaps its acceptance of transgenders to compete alongside with women is justified.  After all, in a contest where the only question that matters is,“Who is the fairest of them all?”physical beauty, whether courtesy of  chromosomes or plastic surgery, takes precedence over gendered experiences.  In such a scenario, the Ms. Universe then would be beauty pageant in the truest sense of the word.  That being the case, then it is justifiable why I have since lost interest in  beauty pageants of any kind.

 12.879721 121.774017 Categories: THICK THOUGHTS | Tags: Ms. Universe | Leave a comment ← Older posts Search for: 
Recent Posts

 The Ancient Capital of Udong Flying Budget While Keeping Your Sanity (and your trip) Intact Chaotic GenSan and the Search for the Maranao Market Lake Sebu Day 4: Back to GenSan Lake Sebu Day 3 (evening): An Evening with the T’boli 
 
Pages

 About Me Climb Record 
 
Border Crossings
 
 Cambodia China Indonesia Malaysia Sabah Sarawak Thailand Vietnam USA 
 
Mountain Summits
 
 Ampacao Arayat Asog Batulao Buntis Cristobal Gulugod Baboy Hibok-Hibok Kabunian Kalisungan Kinabalu Lobo Maculot Malindig Manabu Manalmon Pico de Loro Pinatubo Pulag Romelo Tagapo Talamitam Tapulao Tayak Ugo 
 
Outdoor Adventures
 
 Aurora Coast Cameron Highlands Kinabatangan Kubah National Park Sagada Caves Taman Negara 
 
Trippin the Philippines
 
 Bacolod Banaue Baguio Bataan Boracay Bukidnon Cagayan de Oro Casiguran Cebu Davao GenSan La Union Lake Sebu Sagada Tagaytay Vigan 
 
Manila, My Manila
 
 THIS CITY CALLED HOME 
 
Seeing The Sea
 
 Bataan Boracay Casiguran 
 
Cook, Eat, and Burp
 
 China Indonesia Philippines Malaysia Thailand Vietnam USA 
 
Staying and Sleeping
 
 Cambodia China Indonesia Malaysia Philippines Thailand USA Vietnam 
 
Thick Thoughts
 
 THICK THOUGHTS 
 
Itineraries
 
 Asian Itineraries 
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 July 2009 June 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 1,225 other followers

 

 
 
Pages

 About Me Climb Record 
 
Tags
 Baba Nonya Baba Nonya cuisine Baba Nonya food Banlung Cambodia Cebu Central Market Cheong Fatt Tze mansion China Chocolate Boutique desserts eating in Georgetown eating in KL GenSan Georgetown Hangzhou Khao San Road KL Kratie Lake Sebu Lhasa Cove Malaybalay Malaysia Melaka otak-otak Penang Penang Mansion Peranakan cuisine Precious restaurant Ratanakiri Red Garden Sarawak Shanghai Sony&apos;s Garden Suzhou T&apos;boli T&apos;boli music Tagaytay Taman Negara Tapulao Typhoon Vietnam West Lake where to eat in Cebu where to stay in Melaka 
Recent Comments

 Earl on Mt. Buntis: On the Trail of… dada aytin on Mt. Buntis: On the Trail of… Earl on Lake Sebu Day 3 (morning): The… newagequixotic on Lake Sebu Day 3 (morning): The… Earl on To Be Talaandig 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Adventure Journal by Contexture International .
 Follow 
 Follow“Weekend Backpacker” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 1,225 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
