<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008478" url="http://inkwatu.com/2009/02/21/green-chili-indian-bistro/" time="2012-07-13-01:56" support="2" score="0.004273296122307472" bingtitle="Green Chili Indian Bistro - Inkwatu — DELIGHTS, NEAR AND FAR" webtitle="Green Chili Indian Bistro">
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>... restaurant (well, new to me, at least) is almost a fast-food restaurant (order at the counter, limited menu, plastic plates and cutlery, paper napkins, bus your own trays ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Hilton Tampa Bay Blogroll Archive favorite articles 
 
 Inkwatu 

DELIGHTS, NEAR AND FAR
 
Green Chili Indian Bistro

by Hilton Kean Jones on February 21, 2009 

in Florida , FOOD , Indian food , restaurants , St. Petersburg 
 
 
 click here for larger image
COMBO #3 (CHICKEN CURRY, SAG PANEER, RICE, NAN)
and a side of VEGETABLE SAMOSA,
plus a TAJ IMPORTED BEER 

 

Newly opened downtown is the Green Chili Indian Bistro (310 Central Ave., St. Petersburg, FL 33701; 727-898-2873). This is the second restaurant of this new breed I’ve covered. The first was Zeko’s a Mediterranean grill. The Green Chili is, as the name states, an Indian bistro. This new breed of restaurant (well, new to me, at least) is almost a fast-food restaurant (order at the counter, limited menu, plastic plates and cutlery, paper napkins, bus your own trays), but the food is 100% authentic of some ethnic variety (note the two above: Mediterranean and Indian) and the restaurants are locally owned and operated. It really is a good niche restaurant idea. I hope other ethnic, almost fast-food restaurants open.

I don’t review restaurants that I can’t recommend in some way. This is one I can definitely recommend. Now, it what it is…it isn’t a go-out-of-your-way-to-eat-there kind of place. But, if you’re downtown at lunchtime and you’d like a fast, great tasting , ethnic, good-value-for-your-money meal, don’t hesitate: consider the Green Chili Indian Bistro. I think you’ll be pleased.

I had Combo #3 which is basmati rice , bread ( nan ), 1 veggie dish and 1 non-veggie entree; drink extra. It’s a steam table with about eight different dishes. The chicken curry was as good as I’ve had anywhere. The sag paneer (spinach with cheese cubes) was extremely good. (Actually, I could live on sag paneer, so I’m inclined to like that, regardless.) I also got an imported beer and a samosa (veggie pastry). The whole works was only $11.44. It’s not an all-you-can-eat buffet, which many have come to expect at Indian luncheries, but the portions are adequate and the prices are appropriate for single servings.

The owner is charming and is offering private Indian cooking classes for $40. She supplies everything and you get to eat what the class cooks. They are a two-hour class on Saturdays at noon, by appointment; just call the number above. Another nice feature of this restaurant is that it’s a fast, tasty source for a vegetarian lunch, something that’s not always easy to find. Scattered about the restaurant are various Indian cooking items for sale, such as spices. As I was leaving, the restaurant was quickly filling up with folks walking there from their offices for the noon hour. I predict this will be a long-running and popular lunch place downtown. It’s definitely worth a try. I’ll be going back for a weekday lunch when I’m in the neighborhood.

 
 click here for larger image
GREEN CHILI INDIAN BISTRO EXTERIOR 
 
 Most images link to larger images.
click on larger image for closeup 
 

Tagged as: Florida , FOOD , Indian food , restaurants , St. Petersburg 
 
 { 14 comments…read them below or add one } 
 Brenda February 28, 2009 at 10:12 am 
My husband and I lunched at Green Chili’s on Central Ave. this week and were disappointed. Maybe if we’d known ahead that its a cafetaria style, fast food type place that would’ve prepared us. For some reason (our own fault), we’d assumed it would be a buffet arrangement like AJANTA (at the Ramada Inn, Rte 19) which we always thoroughly enjoy, and will continue to frequent. We found the food lukewarm, and skimpy (not nearly a full plate as shown in the photo here!!) even though we too added the samosa (side dish). But do agree that it is good to have an ethnic eating place downtown, offering something different for office workers in a hurry.We had the luxury of time, so didn’t need a place with plastic tableware (etc.). No doubt it is a niche place for those it is intended for. We’ll try RAGA in Clearwater sometime…We know and love Indian food, and will go out of way for it.

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones February 28, 2009 at 10:16 am 
Yes, it’s definitely not Ajanta, which I love.“It is what it is”as the kids say: a nice ethnic alternative for a quick lunch downtown. I wish India Grill had not closed. I enjoyed them very much. It’s my understanding they intend to reopen in a different location. I hope it’s downtown.

 Reply 
 tara July 28, 2009 at 11:18 am 
Green Chili is now offering a daily lunch buffet.

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones July 28, 2009 at 11:21 am 
That is very good to know! Thank you for alerting us.

 Reply 
 Diane D July 28, 2009 at 12:21 pm 
I just tried the new buffet today. I think it was $7.95, and a drink is extra. You can try all the different dishes, which is good, and eat as much as you want, which is not so good, since I’m trying to cut down on eating! It’s delicious, casual, and the service is fast and friendly. I highly recommend this place.

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones July 28, 2009 at 1:59 pm 
Thanks, Diane. I gotta try it. I noticed, also, a couple blocks to the west, that India Grill is going to reopen in the place that used to be The Kitchen. I always enjoyed India Grill at its old location, but parking was such a problem there. At the new location, there shouldn’t be.

 Reply 
 Joel Schaffer March 24, 2010 at 4:31 pm 
Ajanta is TERRIBLE now. My family&amp;I had LOVED Ajanta from 2002–2009 but alas the kitchen is no longer run by the long time chef&amp;the new regime is terrible. The quality of the food has dropped tremendously. All sauce, no substance. Even the Naan is watered down to the point that it is almost see-through…more like a cracker than bread. A major let down. Not even close to the Ajanta most people think of for lunch, dinner brunch on Sunday. I wish I knew where the former chef moved onto. We used to drive close to 45 minutes almost every Sunday for brunch at Ajanta, we are all so disappointed about this. Truly good Indian food is SOOOOO hard to find.

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones March 26, 2010 at 8:49 am 
I’m very sorry to hear this. It’s been some time since I’ve been to Ajanta. It used to be very high quality. I tend to go to the new location of India Grill in downtown St. Pete. I haven’t had a chance to write it up yet. It’s a good, serviceable Indian buffet, reasonably priced, nice atmosphere, convenient parking, downtown. As I said, Ajanta used to be great; sorry to hear these reports that it’s declined. I need to go back to taste for myself.

 Reply 
 Joel Schaffer March 26, 2010 at 9:17 am 
It’s a real shame, Ajanta was some of the best Indian food we ever ate. In this area or anywhere. The former chef has great recipes, with India being as large a country as it is the recipes vary by geographic location. We really hope to run into the former chef again or another chef from that specific region….we are very spoiled by that specific type of Indian food. Especially some of the items Ajanta featured on their Sunday Brunch menu, items we have never had anywhere else, ever.

“Hope Springs Eternal”

 Reply 
 Joel Schaffer March 26, 2010 at 9:21 am 
Hilton,

Did you ever have the“good fortune”to eat at Satay House on Seminole Blvd.? Across from the old Orange Blossom Groves? It’s been closed since 2006 but was superb Indian / Malaysian / Chinese food. Very authentic.

Ajanta’s decline reminds us of when Satay closed….something that was great while it lasted but once it’s gone it’s gone.

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones March 26, 2010 at 9:35 am 
No, never got to Satay. I wish I had. I absolutely love Malaysian food. I didn’t know there was one here once. There’s not another one around is there? If there is, please let me know! I’ll be there in a heartbeat.

 Reply 
 Joel Schaffer March 26, 2010 at 11:18 am 
None that I am aware of but I am always looking. As a vegetarian Beef Rendang is a guilty pleasure of mine…one of the few items I go off my vegetarian diet for….I read about one in Dunedin off of Main street but it has TERRIBLE reviews so I chose not to get my hopes up only to be let down…..

 Reply 
 Margaret Juul Ammann December 7, 2011 at 11:00 am 
Green Chili Indian Bistro- bland and overpriced

I am a connoisseur of Indian food. I love it! No matter where I travel, I am always in search for the best local Indian Restaurant in town.

Having said that…

My husband and I purchased a Groupon for Green Chili Indian Bistro in downtown Saint Petersburg. The deal was $57 dollar’s worth of food for $27. It was the only Indian restaurant in Tampa Bay that we had not frequented. We were excited to use our Groupon on our wedding anniversary, which happened to be yesterday.

My husband made reservations, as requested. Needless to say, when we arrived there was no need for it. Granted, it was a Tuesday night.

The menu was limited so I asked the waitress, a non- Indian, if they could make my favorite- Malai Kofta. She hadn’t heard of it. She went to the chef and came back with a no. There are standard dishes I always order when I try a new Indian restaurant for the first time. They are- something curry (usually shrimp), Biryani and Malai Kofta, with Naan bread of course…these meals are always a testament on how good the chef is.

The Groupon deal was for two drinks, an appetizer, Naan bread and two entrée’s, which we were going to share.

First, we each ordered a glass of Chardonnay. What arrived was a 4oz pour divided in two glasses. Okay, so we were going to start lite on the wine…then we ordered our appetizer, Vegetable Pakoras. We were quickly presented with a bowl containing two small Pakoras. They were hot and flaky, yet had no flavor.

Our entrée’s soon arrived, Vegetable Biryani and Shrimp Curry with Basmati rice. I asked for our Biryani mild and our Shrimp Curry to be spiced medium. Depending on location, medium can be a mouth burning experience…so, this being our first meal here I thought we would play it safe. More spices are usually offered, which unfortunately here they were not. The Biryani portion was most likely a half cup of rice with spices and a sparing mix of vegetables. Other than the fresh Cilantro, there was not much flavor. No potatoes, raisins or nuts. These ingredients are not always included, but more than likely are.

The Shrimp Curry with Basmati was even more disappointing. The curry sauce was thin and soupy. In the bowl contained six properly cooked shrimp, which was the best part of the meal. There was about a half cup of plain Basmati rice included on the side. The one, very thin piece of Naan bread sliced in half could not soak up anything. It was that thin. The curry sauce dribbled off the rice. The only way for the sauce to be eaten was with the serving spoon. Which brings me to the other issue…we were only given one fork a piece and one napkin. No spoons, no knife. The place setting was very minimal to say the least.

We were never asked if we would like another glass of wine, nor were we offered dessert- which we would have gladly paid extra for. It was one of the fastest meals to be served on record. Our ‘check’ was presented with the tip for $12 and change…like we were not going to tip our waitress and waiter- and delivered with not so much as a smile. So much for our romantic anniversary dinner.

The décor was lovely, but minimal. They did play Indian music, which is always a plus.

We left hungry and moved on to Beak’s for another drink and dessert, where we were greeted by a friendly staff.

All in all, if this is someone’s first Indian food experience I feel sorry for you. Please look further! The India Grill across the street on Central Avenue is much better. If you are able to drive to the two other better Indian restaurants in Tampa Bay… try Deeya in Tri City or Bombay Masala on Waters Avenue in Tampa. At those locations, you will be greeted with a smile, have large dished out delicious portions and revel the culinary masterpiece which, in my opinion, is Indian food.

Do not waste time or your hard earned money at Green Chili Indian Bistro. C-

 Reply 
 Hilton Kean Jones December 7, 2011 at 11:06 am 
Sorry you had a disappointing experience. When I went and wrote my review, it had just opened. At that time, the only Indian restaurant downtown had just closed. This new place wasn’t the best Indian restaurant I’d ever eaten in, but when I went it was more than passable and I was quite happy.

 Reply 
 Cancel reply 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail. You can also subscribe without commenting. 
 
Previous post: Sunken Gardens 

Next post: Arbors Records 
 
 Hilton 
 
 INKWATU 
 Delights, Near and Far 
photos and descriptions of what makes our world a pleasure ~
emphasis on Florida and the Tampa Bay area but also far beyond
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Subscribe…it’s free!!!
 Subscribe in a reader. 
 Subscribe by Email 
Search
 
 
 Enter your search terms 
 Web inkwatu.com 
 Submit search form 
 
Categories
 Select Category ACTIVITIES  (59)    attractions  (18)    boats  (6)    crafts  (3)    dance  (1)    events  (11)    fine arts  (10)    fishing  (5)    fountains  (1)    galleries  (2)    lighthouses  (2)    museums  (8)    piers  (4)    theater  (1)    zoos  (2) B&amp;W  (11) BOOKS  (13)    book reviews  (4)    bookstores  (3) ETC  (13)    announcement  (10)    charities  (2)    health  (1) favorite articles  (65) FOOD  (133)    African food  (1)    Asian food  (30)    bakeries  (10)    barbeque  (1)    bars  (1)    Chinese food  (4)    chocolate  (2)    coffee shops  (5)    dim sum  (2)    English food  (1)    farms  (1)    German food  (3)    Greek food  (3)    ice cream  (3)    Indian food  (2)    Irish food  (2)    Italian food  (1)    Jewish food  (2)    Korean food  (5)    low carb  (1)    markets  (21)    Mediterranean  (2)    Mexican food  (5)    pizza  (1)    Polish food  (1)    pubs  (1)    recipes  (15)    restaurants  (56)    seafood  (13)    sushi  (1)    Thai food  (7)    Vegetarian  (11)    Vietnamese food  (5) HISTORIC  (28)    antiques  (2)    cemeteries  (1)    Floridiana  (7)    postcards  (3)    vintage  (7) HOLIDAYS  (28) LOCATIONS  (234)    Austria  (2)       Salzburg  (1)    California  (1)       Monterey  (1)    China  (3)       Beijing  (1)       Tibet  (1)    England  (2)       London  (2)    Florida  (184)       Anna Maria  (1)       Bradenton  (1)       Cassadaga  (2)       Clearwater  (2)       Gulfport  (12)       Indian Rocks Beach  (1)       Mount Dora  (4)       Pass-a-grille  (2)       Pinellas Park  (1)       Redington Shores  (1)       St. Pete Beach  (2)       St. Petersburg  (120)       Tampa  (30)    France  (1)    Georgia  (11)       Atlanta  (10)    Hawaii  (5)       Kona  (1)    Italy  (9)       Assisi  (4)       Rome  (4)    Louisiana  (3)       New Orleans  (3)    Mississippi  (4)       Biloxi  (1)    New York  (11)       New York City  (11)    Texas  (3)       Fort Worth/Dallas  (3)    Thailand  (2)       Bangkok  (1) MUSIC  (16)    jazz  (2) NATURE  (58)    beaches  (15)    birds  (4)    dogs  (1)    flowers  (12)    gardens  (3)    lakes  (1)    parks  (7)    plants  (3)    rainbows  (1)    seascapes  (2)    sunsets  (1)    trees  (14)    wildlife  (4) SHOPPING  (11)    flowers  (4)    gifts  (4)    shops  (5) SINGLE PHOTOS  (59) SPIRITUAL  (12)    Buddhist  (9) SUBJECT  (40)    buildings  (10)    churches&amp;temples  (4)    cityscapes  (6)    construction materials  (1)    doors  (2)    jewelry  (2)    landscapes  (2)    people  (2)    repitition  (1)    rivers&amp;streams  (1)    signs  (2)    statues  (3)    still life  (3)    transportation  (3)    weathered  (5) 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 (2) April 2012 (1) March 2012 (2) January 2012 (1) December 2011 (6) November 2011 (1) August 2011 (3) June 2011 (1) May 2011 (3) April 2011 (1) March 2011 (1) February 2011 (3) January 2011 (1) December 2010 (1) November 2010 (4) October 2010 (2) August 2010 (13) July 2010 (4) June 2010 (1) May 2010 (3) April 2010 (6) March 2010 (14) February 2010 (10) January 2010 (20) December 2009 (12) November 2009 (11) October 2009 (5) September 2009 (3) August 2009 (6) July 2009 (4) June 2009 (5) May 2009 (9) April 2009 (9) March 2009 (8) February 2009 (8) January 2009 (10) December 2008 (11) November 2008 (10) October 2008 (9) September 2008 (9) August 2008 (10) July 2008 (9) June 2008 (8) May 2008 (12) April 2008 (8) March 2008 (6) 
Recent Posts

 Avocado improvisation Casita Taqueria The Starboard Sea (review) Patak’s Biryani Paste with Cauliflower and Yogurt My First Steak Iconic memory Year’round Holiday decorations Homegrown lettuce from a neighborhood garden Happy Holidays! Variation on a Butternut Squash Soup Zack Shack recipe Blogroll updates Microwaved Acorn Squash with Maple Syrup Cheese and Brussels Sprouts Casserole Biloxi, Mississippi Trees and picnic table in an Atlanta park 
 
Recent Comments

 Libby P. on Hilton wondu gizaw on The Queen of Sheba Ethiopian Restaurant, Tampa, FL Breanna Fingall on Lake Vista Park Angela Wayne on Lake Vista Park Karen Frioli on Ted Peters Famous Smoked Fish Mary Clark on Lake Vista Park Free Flower Bulbs on Crape Myrtle Hilton Kean Jones on Orchid Tree, Jacaranda, Royal Poinciana, and Tamarind grace on Orchid Tree, Jacaranda, Royal Poinciana, and Tamarind Lucy on Casita Taqueria Frank on Adam’s Nursery&amp;Water Gardens Laura on Orchid Tree, Jacaranda, Royal Poinciana, and Tamarind Joanne Wilson on Jo-El’s kosher deli Jennifer Haynes on Vintage Sheet Music Covers raj shah on Wat Mongkolratanaram—Palm River Thai Temple 
  
 If you love photos, visit my photoblog, Zhong Heting .
	</body>
</document>
