<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008334" url="http://www.proteinpower.com/forum/archive/index.php/t-2050.html" time="2012-07-13-01:49" support="1" score="0.001541996221129652" bingtitle="bk low carb options [Archive] - Protein Power Forums" webtitle="bk low carb options [Archive]  - Protein Power Forums">
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="168"/>
	<description>... carb options now, there are so many things to eat ... I like to know what&apos;s in my food items, so I cook ... Sorry, but I can&apos;t go NEAR any fast food restaurant, especially BK ...</description>
	<body>
		Protein Power Forums &gt; Protein Power Living &gt; The Protein Power Life Style &gt;bk low carb options PDA 
View Full Version : bk low carb options 
 
 moe0204&apos;schild 01-03-2007, 08:44 PM so i had no idea, but burger king offers low carb options now, there are so many things to eat there. i&apos;m so excited! now i dont have to stress out and plan every single meal. if i&apos;m in a crunch i can go to burger king. here&apos;s the link to my findings
http://www.bk.com/Nutrition/PDFs/Low%20Carb%20handout%204-3-06.pdf


enjoy!! moe0204&apos;schild 01-03-2007, 08:45 PM if there are any other resturants that people know of that have low carb options please post them. i&apos;m new to this, and just discovering this new stuff on my own. thanks! Missy 01-04-2007, 08:06 AM McDonalds does the same. It works in a pinch. :D But, I don&apos;t want to rely on it too often, or it feels too much like the&quot;old&quot;days. :rolleyes: cmcole 01-04-2007, 09:03 AM With careful planning, you can get items from nearly anywhere.
It&apos;s just not the best thought, in my opinion.
I like to know what&apos;s in my food items, so I cook extra and take leftovers for my lunch, usually.

In a pinch, a can of seasoned tuna, sardines, smoked oysters/mussels or similar items are always in my desk, so I don&apos;t have to rely on a fast food establishment. ladydoc442 01-04-2007, 02:58 PM Sorry, but I can&apos;t go NEAR any fast food restaurant, especially BK - my french fry addiction has never been cured :) . Just the smell of those fries cooking can make me turn my car right into the closest drive-thru ... so I just stay away and avoid the temptation altogether .. hee hee ..

Interesting bit of info, though! arc 01-04-2007, 03:03 PM When we are on the road and stop at a BK, I usually get the Angus Burger with no bun and a side salad. Really good and pretty filling.

DQ&apos;s Grillburgers are good without a bun, though I don&apos;t think they have salads, and it&apos;s tough to resist the Blizzards. :D Carl&apos;s Jr has the Low Carb Burger and side salads that are pretty good. maxlharris 01-04-2007, 03:09 PM so i had no idea, but burger king offers low carb options now, there are so many things to eat there. i&apos;m so excited! now i dont have to stress out and plan every single meal. if i&apos;m in a crunch i can go to burger king. here&apos;s the link to my findings
http://www.bk.com/Nutrition/PDFs/Low%20Carb%20handout%204-3-06.pdf


enjoy!!

Hardees does LC Thickburgers, very nice. But eating on the run is part of what got me here in the first place. It&apos;s good for a pinch (driving cross country, stuck between work and a Dr. Appointment) but let&apos;s just say you are probably better off (health wise and cost wise) eating self-prepped lunches/left overs.

Quick thought: I am a very picky eater. I cannot count how many times I have asked for a burger, plain, with cheese and bacon, and gotten something with mayonaise (hate), ketchup (not a fan) or pickles (these ruin anything for me). Honest, it is beyond counting. Lord knows how many times I maybe swilled a sugar coke when I asked for diet or vice versa. Medium coke at a fast food restaurant is 32 ounces, 86G of carb, all in sugar, mostly in HFCS. Let&apos;s suggest that this would be very counter productive.

Mileage varies, etc. But, I&apos;d think pretty long and hard about fast food options. Old habits and all. Hard without fries. Viking Dan 01-04-2007, 05:54 PM Tossing the bun is an easy approach although its messy on the road.

The chicken salads are usually not so bad depending on the dressing you choose. mepc06 01-05-2007, 09:29 PM I couldn&apos;t pull up the link for BK....POS computer.
I walk by Burger King every day when I walk during my lunch break. For a long time I was addicted to the Breakfast Croissanwiches. I would eat them daily. When I started PPLP, I quit, cold turkey. Then started getting the craving back for them. I went in one day in December and ordered just the egg and sausage, hold the croissant. A real treat, with all the flavor I remembered and very satisfying.
I rarely eat fast food anymore, simply because my choices are so limited. When I go out now, it&apos;s usually a sit down place that I have more freedom to pick and choose what I can and want to eat. But there are still mornings when I am rushed, or simply just want it and will stop at BK for just the eggs and sausage.

Michelle miralin 01-06-2007, 01:30 AM In-n-Out does a pretty good protein wrap - which is a burger wrapped in lettuce, no bun. And as mentioned, Carl&apos;s Jr has several options as well. Powered by vBulletin®Version 4.1.11 Copyright©2012 vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
