<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008042" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/what-is-the-catch-phrase-to-wendy%27s-fast-food-restaurant" time="2012-07-13-01:06" support="1" score="0.0021537405715686833" bingtitle="What is the catch phrase to wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? | ChaCha" webtitle="What is the catch phrase to wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? | ChaCha">
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>What is the catch phrase to wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? ChaCha Answer: Wendy&apos;s ... Please make a valid selection!</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
What is the catch phrase to wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? 

In: Business › Corporate Info 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Wendy&apos;s newest slogan is&quot;It&apos;s Way Better than Fast Food, It&apos;s Wendy&apos;s&quot;. Thanks for using ChaCha! Have a good day! 
 Answered

 
 - 7 days ago at 9:26pm on Jul 04 2012 
Related Questions for Corporate Info 

 
 What are some Pharmacist catch phrases? 

Here is a great catch phrase my pharmacist told...

in Advertising&amp;Marketing | 2 hr 32 min ago via sms text 
 
 How many minutes are you suppose to play catch phrase for? 

In the game of Catch Phrase, your team&apos;s turn i...

in Games | 4 hr 18 min ago via Android app 
 
 What is catch phrase of BK show company? 

The catch phrase for the BK show company is the...

in Corporate Info | 7 hr 23 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What was walter cronkite&apos;s catch phrase on the news? 

Walter Cronkite&apos;s catchphrase at the end of eve...

in TV&amp;Radio | 16 hr 45 min ago via web 
 
 What is the funniest catch phrase? 

&quot;I&apos;m Larry, this is my brother Darryl ...&quot;(Lar...

in Relationships&amp;Dating | 17 hr 1 min ago via sms text 
 
 What is Oprah&apos;s catch phrase? 

Oprah Winfrey (born Orpah Gail Winfrey; January...

in TV&amp;Radio | 21 hr 4 min ago via web 
 
 What does the 22 in the phrase&quot;catch 22&quot;mean? 

It is from a military regulation in a novel of ...

in Definitions | 21 hr 7 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the cutest catch phrase for me to say to my girlfriend? 

For a moment I thought I had died and gone to h...

in Relationships&amp;Dating | 21 hr 14 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the Natural Ice beer catch phrase? 

Natural Light is an economy brand 4.2% abv redu...

in Advertising&amp;Marketing | 21 hr 48 min ago via Android app 
 
 Whats taco bell&apos;s catch phrase? 

Taco Bell&apos;s catch phrase is&quot;Think Outside the ...

in Corporate Info | 21 hr 58 min ago via sms text 
 
 What is the catch phrase for sketchers? 

I can&apos;t find a catch phrase for sketchers. But ...

in Conversational | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 What are some catch phrases? 

&quot;Two thumbs up&quot;(Siskel&amp;Ebert,&quot;Siskel&amp;Eber...

in Entertainment&amp;Arts | 1 day ago via iPhone app 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Galleries for Corporate Info 

 
 
 
 Shopkick: The Mobile Shopper&apos;s Savings App 
 Viewed 77 times 
 
 
 
 A 90s Kid&apos;s Christmas List 
 Viewed 1137793 times 
 
 
 
 Fun Facts About Apple Inc. 
 Viewed 1344 times 
 
 
 
 The Best Of: Will It Blend? 
 Viewed 56 times 
 
 
 
 Yahoo Cuts 2,000 Jobs 
 
 
 
 Google Charged with Deceptive Ads 
 Viewed 28 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Quizzes for Corporate Info 

 
 
 
 Is Your Boss a Jerk? 
 Viewed 2023 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Recognize These Famous Logos? 
 Viewed 583274 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Recognize That 90&apos;s Logo? 
 Viewed 8127 times 
 
 
 
 How Much Do You Really Know About Facebook? 
 Viewed 15061 times 
 
 
 
 Can You Match the Insurance Company to its Slogan? 
 Viewed 5790 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Company Slogans? 
 Viewed 16333 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Corporate Info 

 Bell Coupons» 
 
Top Trends in Business 

 Job Application» Savings» Rent» ATM» Resume» Brands» Work Permit» Visa» Bankruptcy» Interest Rate» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Ford» Hurt» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Business › Corporate Info 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
