<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008201" url="http://www.millenniumseating.com/wood-booths.html" time="2012-07-13-01:41" support="5" score="0.028813424522688338" bingtitle="Wooden Restaurant Booths, Wood Booth Seating, Wood Booths" webtitle="Wooden Restaurant Booths, Wood Booth Seating, Wood Booths">
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>Availability: Build to Order Ships in 3-4 Weeks ... with their meal, and dining establishments that place ... Whereas table-and-chair setups require extra room for ...</description>
	<body>
		Wooden Restaurant Booths, Wood Booth Seating, Wood Booths
 TOLL FREE: (866) 379-8422 
 Mon - Fri, 9am - 5pm EST My Account | Quote Cart 
 
 
 Restaurant Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Cafeteria Seating Breakroom Seating Outdoor Furniture 
 
 PRODUCTS Cluster Seating Restaurant Benches Waste&amp;Trash Receptacles Outdoor Restaurant Furniture Restaurant Booths Restaurant Booths Contour Booths Upholstered Booths Wood Restaurant Booths Retro Diner Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Chairs Metal Restaurant Chairs Wooden Restaurant Chairs Stacking Restaurant Chairs Retro Diner Chairs Outdoor Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Restaurant Tables Table Bases Laminate Table Tops Wood Table Tops Retro Diner Tables Commercial Bar Stools Commercial Bar Stools Metal Bar Stools Wood Bar Stools Retro Bar Stools Outdoor Bar Stools Diner Furniture Diner Furniture Diner Booths Diner Chairs Diner Stools Diner Tables Customer Service Have Questions? 

 (866) 379-8422 
Mon-Fri 8-5 EST

» Send an email Home &gt; Restaurant Furniture &gt; Restaurant Booths &gt; Wood Booths 
Wood Booths
 Like 
 Show 24 Per Page 48 Per Page 72 Per Page 96 Per Page 120 Per Page 
 &lt; Prev 
 1 2 
 Next &gt; 
 Wood Booths Products 1-24 of 33 
 Old Towne 862 Single Wood Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $847.00 Price: $423.99 
 See options. Old Towne 862 Double Wood Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,341.00 Price: $670.99 
 See options. Irish Pub Series 872 Single Wood Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,197.00 Price: $589.99 
 See options. Irish Pub Series 872 Double Wood Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,692.00 Price: $845.99 
 See options.
	</body>
</document>
