<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008793" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100528233105AAIiqV9" time="2012-07-13-02:15" support="3" score="0.0009674549934160059" bingtitle="Help With Precalculus Worksheet? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="Help With Precalculus Worksheet? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="120"/>
	<description>a) A small fast – food restaurant invest $5000 to produce a new ... week in order to make the straight commission ... row, 18 seats in the second row, 21 seats in ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Science&amp;Mathematics &gt; Mathematics &gt; Resolved Question 
 Jesus Member since: December 17, 2008 Total points: 401 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Help With Precalculus Worksheet?
 2. Solve the following:
a) A small fast – food restaurant invest $5000 to produce a new food item that will sell for $3.49. Each iterm can
be produced for $2.16.
i) How many items must be sold to break even ?
ii) How many items must be sold to make a profit of $8500?
b) You are offered two jobs selling dental supplies. One company offers a straight commission of 6% of sales.
The other company offers a salary of $350 per week plus 3% of sales. How much would you have to sell in a
week in order to make the straight commission offer better?
c) At a local high school city championship basketball game, 1435 tickets were sold. A student admission ticket
cost $1.50 and an adult admission ticket cost $5.00. The total ticket receipts for the basketball game were
$3552.50. How many of each type of ticket were sold?
d) A small corporation borrowed $775,000 to expand its clothing line. Some of the money was borrowed at 8%,
some at 9%, and some at 10%. How much was borrowed at each rate if the annual interest owed was $67,500
and the amount borrowed at 8% was four times the amount borrowed at 10%

6. a) A triangular brick wall is made by cutting some bricks in half to use in the first column of every row.
The wall has 28 rows. The top row is one – half brick wide and the bottom row is 14 bricks wide.
How many bricks are used in the finished wall?
b) Determine the seating capacity of an auditorium with 36 rows of seats if there are 15 seats in the first
row, 18 seats in the second row, 21 seats in the third row, and so on.


c) An object with negligible air resistance is dropped from the top of the Petronas Toweers in Malaysia at
a height of 1483 feet. During the first second of the fall, the object falls 4.9 feet, during the second
second, it falls 14.7 feet, during the third second, it falls 34.3 feet. If this arithmetic pattern continues,
how many feet will the object fall in 17 seconds?


9. a) A tool and die company buys a machine for $135,000 and it depreciates at a rate of 30% per year. (In
other words, at the end of each year the depreciated value is 70% of what it was at the beginning of the
year.) Find the depreciated value of the machine after 5 full years.
b) A rubber ball is dropped from a height of 60 feet. If it rebounds approximately two – thirds the
distance after each fall, use an infinite geometric series to approximate the total distance the ball
travels. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Ingeniou... Member since: August 04, 2006 Total points: 42,702 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 wrong section for this - business finance (accounting to be precise)

2 a) i) b/e = fc/(sp-vc) = 5000/(3.49-2.16) = 5000/1.33 = 3759.40 i.e. 3760 items
ii) b/e + fixed profit = (fc + profit)/(sp-vc) = (5000+8500)/(3.49-2.16) = 13500/1.33 = 10150.38 i.e. 10151 items

b) let x = quantity sold
350 + 0.03x = 0.06x
350 = 0.03x; x = $11666.67

c) 3552.50 = 1.5s + 5a
s +a = 1435

using the substitution method, s = 1435 - a
3552.50 = 1.5(1435-a) +5a
3552.50 = 2152.50 - 1.5a + 5a
3552.50 = 2152.50 + 3.5a
1400 = 3.5a; a = 400 adult tickets
s = 1435 -a
s = 1435 - 400 = 1035 student tickets

d) 0.08x + 0.09y + 0.10z = 67500
x+y+z = 775000
4z = x

0.08*4z + 0.09y + 0.10z = 67500
0.42z + 0.09y = 67500

z + y + 4z = 775000
5z + y = 775000
y = 775000 - 5z

0.42z + 0.09(775000 -5z) = 67500
0.42z + 69750 - 0.45z = 67500
-0.03z + 69750 = 67500
-0.03z = -2250; z = 75000
as 4z = x; x = 300000
y = 775000 - 5z = 775000 - 5*75000 = 400000

6) a) trapezium = (1/2)(a+b)h = (1/2)*(14+0.5)*28 = 14*14.5 = 203 bricks
b) tn = 12 + 3n; at row = 36; tn = 12 + 36*3 = 12 + 108 = 120
trapezium = (1/2)(15+120)*36 = 18*135 = 2430 seats
c) s = a + b(t -1); s = additional distance, a = 4.9, b = 9.8, t = time
s = 4.9 + 9.8*(17-1) = 4.9 + 156.8 = 161.7 ft
total distance fell using trapezium rule: (1/2)(4.9+161.7)*17 = 83.3*17 = 1416.1ft

9) a) presuming we are using a reducing balance (i.e. the depreciation is compounded and is not straight line), $135000*0.7^5 = 135000*0.16807 = $22689.45 remaining
b) requires a bit of thinking on this one...
if the ball falls 60ft, it rebounds (2/3) of this distance back up but falls the same distance on the way down. on the second time it rebounds (2/3) of the prior distance back up but falls the same distance back down and so on. You are looking at 2 of the same distance travelled everytime the ball rebounds after the first drop
ball rebounds at a*2/3, so distance = a(2/3)^(n-1); geometric sum = a/(1- 2/3) = 60/(1/3) = 180
however the fall of the ball needs to be considered. This is at the rate ar^(n-2) where a = 40; geometric sum = 40/(1/3) = 120
total distance travelled is 180 for the rebounds and 120 for the falls which gives a total of 300ft

Hope this helps 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: thanks. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Mathematics 

 The perimeter of a rectangle is 20 yards. Its area is 24 sq.yds. Find the dimensions of the rectangle.? Is it true that if a≠0 then a³&gt;a²? Can you please help me with math? Find the perimeter of a square whose area = 175 sq km (Give the exact answer then round to nearest thousandths? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Science&amp;Mathematics 
 Agriculture Alternative Astronomy&amp;Space Biology Botany Chemistry Earth Sciences&amp;Geology Engineering Geography Mathematics Medicine Other - Science Physics Weather Zoology 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
