<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008857" url="http://www.movoto.com/real-estate/homes-for-sale/FL/Winter-Haven/5-Bridgewater-Dr-431_P4616503.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:17" support="1" score="0.0017472814922287003" bingtitle="5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL 33884 MLS# P4616503" webtitle="5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL 33884 MLS# P4616503">
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>Master suite offers plush carpeting, tray ceiling ... Life Skills Center Polk County East: 7500 Cypress Gardens ... Properties near 5 Bridgewater Dr, have a median listing ...</description>
	<body>
		Call Us! 888-766-8686 Sign In | Register | Contact Us | Call us toll-free: 888-766-8686 Call Us! 888-766-8686 Sign In | Register | Contact Us | Call us toll-free: 888-766-8686 Search 
 Find Homes Map Search 
 Property Search 
 MLS # Search 
 Open Houses 
 Rentals Winter Haven Homes for Sale 
 Winter Haven Open Houses 33884 Homes for Sale 
 Bridgewater, Winter Haven Real Estate Our Agents Agent Search 
 Meet an Agent 
 About Movoto 
 Real Estate Tools 
 Work with Movoto 
 Buying Make an Offer 
 School Information 
 Demographics 
 Buyer Tips Selling Sell Your House 
 Free Home Value 
 Professional Home Value 
 Real Estate Market Statisitcs 
 Blog My Movoto Sign In / Register 
 Favorites and Saved Searches 
 
 Loading... Movoto Real
 Estate » Florida » Winter Haven » 5 Bridgewater Dr Prev  |  Next Back to Search 
5 Bridgewater Dr,
 Winter Haven,
 FL
 33884 
 
 Photo: &lt;&lt;   1    2    3    4    5    6    7    8    &gt;&gt;   All 
 
 Price: $309,000 Loan Payment: $1,076/mo Bedrooms: 3 Bathrooms: 3 Size: - $/Sqft: -/sqft Type: Single Family House Year Built: 1994 Lot Size: 13,421 Days on Movoto: 415
 days Neighborhood: Bridgewater MLS#: P4616503 Status: Active 
 Go See This Home Make an Offer Timeless design is evident with this exceptional pool home in established family community. Circular driveway and grand entrance opens to this spacious 3 bedrooms, 3 bathrooms (2,534 sf), floor plan with formal dining room, large family room and office.Features include: Elegant designer decorated interior, beautiful hardwood flooring, fireplace in family room, French doors, crown molding, window shutters, high ceilings, upgraded light fixtures and fans, breakfast bar in kitchen and closet pantry. Breakfast nook overlooking pool. Master suite offers plush carpeting, tray ceiling, garden tub, separate shower and twin vanities with recess lighting. Attractive screened pool with lanai, outdoor fans, surrounded by tropical landscaping.   
Schedule a Viewing of 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven
 
 Name
 Phone
   Email
 Comments
 Please have a Movoto specialist contact me to schedule a viewing of 5 Bridgewater Dr in Winter Haven. Or Call Toll-Free 888-766-8686 
 Privacy Policy    Terms of Use Go 
 Have a question?
Want to see it in person?

Fill out this form to
have a Movoto specialist
contact you today!   
House Features for 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven
 
 Feature Description Parking 2 Property Type Single Family Home, Residential Homestead Yes Floor Plan Utility room, Foyer, Open floor plan, Attic, Living Room/Great Room, Breakfast Room Separate, Split Bedroom, Den/Library/Office, Breakfast Room Separate Lot Description Oak Trees, Staked lot, Dock - Slip Deeded Off-Site, Private Boat Ramp, Dock - Slip 1st Come, Street Lights Architecture Contemporary Kitchen Microwave oven, Disposal, Refrigerator, Dishwasher, Breakfast bar, Pantry Dining Room Formal Dining Room Separate Bathroom Tub and separate shower Master Bathroom Garden Bath Attic Attic Appliances Refrigerator, Hot Water Electric Flooring Wood, Ceramic Tile, Carpet Garage/Parking Automatic garage door, 2 car garage, Attached, Side Rear Entry Yard/Ground Mature Landscaping Access Lake - Chain of Lakes Miscellaneous Gutters / Downspouts Amenities Smoke Alarm(s), Wet Bar, Cable Available, Crown Moulding, Walk In Closet, Ceiling Fan(s) Fireplace Living room fireplace Cooling Central Heating Central heat, Fuel - Electric Patio Patio/Porch/Deck Screened Pool In-ground swimming pool, Gunite/Concrete, Yes Pets Pets Permitted Exterior Stucco, Block Roof Shingle roof New Construction No Foundation Slab Utilities Electric, Fire Hydrant Sewer Private Sewer Water Supply City Water Community Amenities Dock, Deed Restrictions, Fees Required Sq Ft Source Public Records HOA Required Homeowners Association Fees 250.00 Annually 
 Listing courtesy of
MICHAEL NORRIS
 of 
NORRIS&amp;COMPANY REALTY, LLC
   
Price History for 
 5 Bridgewater Dr
 
 Date Status Price Price Change Source 05/31/2011 Active $309,000 --- Mid-Florida Regional (#P4616503) 05/25/2011 Off Market $309,000 --- Mid-Florida Regional (#P4616503) 05/24/2011 Active $309,000 --- Mid-Florida Regional (#P4616503) Register or Login to view the sale history.  Why is this required? 
   
Map of 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven
 Map Satellite Street   
Schools near
 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven
 School District: Polk County School District 
 School Name Type Distance (mi) MSR Elementary Schools Chain Of Lakes Elementary School Primary 1.64 Hope Creative School Elementary 2.03 Garden Grove Elementary School Primary 2.13 High Schools Life Skills Center Polk County East High 2.71 Winter Haven Senior High School High 3.04 Lake Region High School High 3.29 
 View More Schools Movoto computes a school rank for each school in FL. The rank is based on each school&apos;s most recent performance in each of the state-defined exams that appear on Movoto. Schools are ranked against all other schools of the same type (Elementary, Middle, or High School).   
Nearby Points of Interest for

 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven
 
 Name Address Distance (mi) Restaurants Perkins 6005 Cypress Gardens Blvd,Cypress Gardens 1.07 Hungry Howies Pizza&amp;Subs 3007 Cypress Gardens Rd,Cypress Gardens 1.51 Cypress Cafe 3055 Cypress Gardens Rd,Cypress Gardens 1.52 Harry&apos;s Old Place 3751 Cypress Gardens Rd,Winter Haven 1.79 Add or edit a restaurant. It&apos;s open data powered by Factual . 
   
5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL Market Statistics
 Median List Price Inventory (Single Family Homes and Condos for Sale) Price Changes Complete
 Winter Haven, Statistics Profile   
Property Listings and Communities Nearby
 5 Bridgewater Dr
 
 2606 Wyndsor Oaks Ct, Winter Haven, FL 
4
 Beds,
 3&amp;1/2
 Baths,
 $499,000 
 
 Winter Haven Homes for Sale Homeland Homes for Sale Miami Homes for Sale Orlando Homes for Sale Tampa Homes for Sale 
 This 3 bedroom, 3 baths house located at 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL has approximately - square feet. It is currently listed for $309,000 and has a price per sqft of -. Properties near 5 Bridgewater Dr, have a median listing price of $109,900 and a median price per sqft of $49. This home is currently Active under the MLS#: P4616503. It is listed by MICHAEL NORRIS of NORRIS&amp;COMPANY REALTY, LLC.

5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven was built in 1994. It has 2 parking spots in a Automatic garage door, 2 car garage, Attached, Side Rear Entry. The kitchen includes Microwave oven, Disposal, Refrigerator, Dishwasher, Breakfast bar, Pantry. The homeowners association fees are 250.00 Annually.

5 Bridgewater Dr is part of the Bridgewater neighborhood located in 33884 and is part of the Polk County School District school district. The closest school is Chain Of Lakes Elementary School in Winter Haven, FL. 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL has been on the market for 415 days and the median days on market for a property in the area is 118. Please contact one of Movoto&apos;s top-rated agents to see Winter Haven market statistics and to help you get the best deal for 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL. 
More Options

 Email a Friend Rentals/Apartments Add to Favorites Meet an Agent Get Listing Alerts Tweet this House Take a Virtual Tour 
 
My Notes
 SAVE NOTE Awesome Similar Homes Real Estate listings near 5 Bridgewater Dr , Winter Haven, FL $354,900 
 Beds: 3 
Baths: 2&amp;1/2 
Sqft: 4311 
DOM: 24 12 , Winter Haven, FL $384,900 
 Beds: 3 
Baths: 2 
Sqft: 4240 
DOM: 64 12 142 Wyndham Dr, Winter Haven, FL $479,000 
 Beds: 3 
Baths: 3 
Sqft: 3927 
DOM: 92 1 37 Berna Cir, Winter Haven, FL $34,950 
 Beds: 2 
Baths: 2 
Sqft: 1248 
DOM: 582 12 148 Sweet Cir, Winter Haven, FL $34,950 
 Beds: 2 
Baths: 2 
Sqft: 1248 
DOM: 582 12 Request More Information for 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven, FL 

 Name:
 Email:
 Phone:
 Comments:
 Please contact me to schedule a viewing of this home. Or Call Total-Free 888-766-8686 Privacy Policy   Terms of Use 
 Go 
 Neighborhood Demographics Full demographics profile available for 5 Bridgewater Dr Winter Haven Crime Index Population By Education Level in ZIP code 33884 Household Income Distribution in ZIP code 33884 5 Bridgewater Dr, Winter Haven_-81.691642_27.975474_309000_300_300_-_13,421_431_0 Movoto Site Map 
 Contact
 Us 
 About Us 
 Blog 
 Feedback Popular States California (Northern) Real Estate 
 California (Southern) Real Estate 
 Colorado Real Estate 
 DC/Maryland/Virginia Real Estate 
 Florida Real Estate 
 Illinois Real Estate 
 Massachuessets Real Estate 
 New Jersey Real Estate 
 New York Real Estate 
 Texas Real Estate Search Search Popular Cities Boston Homes For Sale 
 Boulder Homes For Sale 
 Charlotte Homes For Sale 
 Chicago Homes For Sale 
 Denver Homes For Sale 
 Franklin Homes For Sale 
 Houston Homes For Sale 
 Los Angeles Homes For Sale 
 Miami Homes For Sale 
 Miami Beach Homes For Sale 
 Nashville Homes For Sale 
 Ocean City Homes For Sale 
 Palm Desert Homes For Sale 
 Palm Springs Homes For Sale 
 Philadelphia Homes For Sale 
 Portland Homes For Sale 
 San Diego Homes For Sale 
 San Francisco Homes For Sale 
 Sarasota Homes For Sale 
 Scottsdale Homes For Sale 
 See All Popular Cities Change Language English 
 Español 
 简体中文 Social 
 Listing information courtesy of NORRIS&amp;COMPANY REALTY, LLC. All listing information is deemed reliable but not guaranteed and should be independently verified through personal inspection by appropriate professionals. Listings displayed on this website may be subject to prior sale or removal from sale; availability of any listing should always be independently verified.
Listing information is provided for consumer personal, non-commercial use, solely to identify potential properties for potential purchase; all other use is strictly prohibited and may violate relevant federal and state law.
Listing information updated daily. This listing was retrieved on 07/12/2012 15:00:00. 
 Copyright©2004 - 2012 Movoto LLC.  All rights reserved. 
 Alabama 
 Arizona 
 California (Northern) 
 California (Southern) 
 Colorado 
 DC/Maryland/Virginia 
 Delaware 
 Florida 
 Georgia 
 Illinois 
 Indiana 
 Louisiana 
 Massachusetts 
 Michigan 
 Minnesota 
 Missouri 
 Nevada 
 New Jersey 
 New York 
 North Carolina 
 Ohio 
 Oregon 
 Pennsylvania 
 Rhode Island 
 South Carolina 
 Tennessee 
 Texas 
 Utah 
 Washington 
 Wisconsin
	</body>
</document>
