<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008306" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/quiznos-fast-food-franchise-review-north-oklahoma-3427468.html" time="2012-07-13-01:47" support="2" score="0.0029912182269991754" bingtitle="Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City ..." webtitle="Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Individual plastic cups with lids are available for condiments. I am delighted Quizno&apos;s offers ... Bay - Ya-Ya&apos;s Flame-Broiled Chicken Review of Ya-Ya&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City

Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City
 Deborah Oakes, NPS , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
May 31, 2009 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food Franchising quizno&apos;s 
 Flag Close Post a comment Quizno&apos;s Neighborhood: Quail Springs
Oklahoma City , OK 73134
United States of America Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City 
It had been several years since I dined at Quizno&apos;s because I didn&apos;t care for their greasy sandwiches. Since I had Quiznos coupons, I decided to try their new Torpedo Sub sandwiches. Find out here how this fast food franchise stacks up.

 Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City 

It was late one evening and I didn&apos;t feel like fixing dinner. I remembered my Quiznos coupons, so I decided to try their new Torpedo Sub sandwiches since I know Quizno&apos;s offers a sandwich bar . I called the store to make sure of the location. Unfortunately, the employee gave me ridiculous directions but I finally found it.

I entered the fast food franchise and walked to the counter where three employees and a manager stood to greet me. The next thing I knew, I was hurried through my ordering although I was the only customer there. The manager made things worse because she was trying to do two things at once. She trained an employee as she helped the employee helping me.

Anyway, we finally got things figured out and I proceeded to the sandwich bar while they prepared my sub sandwiches. I really like the offerings at the sandwich bar. There is wine vinaigrette dressing, creamy horseradish, pickles, jalapeños, banana peppers, bar-b-que sauce and napkins.

Individual plastic cups with lids are available for condiments. I am delighted Quizno&apos;s offers SoBe drinks. These are available at health food stores so I feel good about drinking one. My sub sandwiches were finished just about the same time the condiments were ready.

I ordered a Turkey Pesto Torpedo sub sandwich. I thought there should be a little more meat but with the condiments, it tasted good. Except, I could taste the grease the bun is warmed with and I still don&apos;t care for the taste.

After all these years, I hoped Quizno&apos;s sub sanwiches would taste good again. I&apos;ll have to remember to ask for a plain bun, no heating it up. The tomato basil soup is good although I won&apos;t order it again. I noticed their menu had details about healthy fast food, so I&apos;ll give this Quizno&apos;s fast food franchise an 8 out of 10 points.

 Click here for a review of McDonald&apos;s one block North.

Quizno&apos;s at Quail Springs Market Place
2150 W. Memorial Rd.
OKC, OK 73134
405.751.4700

Source:
Author&apos;s Experience: Fast Food Franchise, Quizno&apos;s

Quizno&apos;s: Fast Food Franchise Review for North Oklahoma City copyright 2009.
 
Published by Deborah Oakes, NPS 

Certified National Product Specialist, Author: &quot;H1N1 Threat Reduced Using Natural Healthcare&quot; and &quot;Home&amp;Hearth Recipes.&quot;  View profile 
 
 Benefits&amp;Drawbacks to Purchasing a Fast Food Franchise Advice and tips from the owners of three top fast food franchises in the Houston area. Should you purchase a restaurant franchise? Find out the benefits and drawbacks. Healthy Fast Food in Tampa Bay - Ya-Ya&apos;s Flame-Broiled Chicken Review of Ya-Ya&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant Healthy Fast Food Alternatives in Las Vegas, Nevada You may think that the dollar menu is the answer to your prayers but especially when times get tough it&apos;s important to live as healthy as possible. In the end, poor health will cost more than spending a little extra o... Healthier Fast Food Options...They Really Do Exist Using the Weight Watchers Points Plan takes the guesswork out of what not to eat at a fast food restaurant. It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant Think you have to order 1,000 calorie meals just because you are eating at a Fast Food Restaurant ? Think Again , there are ways to work the menu to your advantage. 

 Make Your Own Fast Food with No... Healthy Fast Food Menu Worst Non-Fast Food Menu Items 
 
 &quot;Healthy&quot; Fast Food: America&apos;s Biggest Oxymoron Healthy Fast Food Choices Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Fast Food Failures Can You Really Eat Healthy Fast Food? How to Have a Healthy, Fast-Food Breakfast Is There Really Such a Thing as Healthy Fast Food? 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.quiznos.com/ en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SoBe en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quail_Springs_Mall 
 
9 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Cathy A Montville 6/6/2009 
We finally have a Quiznos here, well about a half-hour away, and I go there every now and then and love their food! The service is decent as well!
 jayanti raman 6/5/2009 
Great work,thanks Typing for Food
 Jennifer Wagner 6/3/2009 
I really love Quiznos. I know it&apos;s just a sub, but it tastes better than other places.
 Dina Quirion 6/3/2009 
I agree with Jennifer, LOL. That commercial cracks me up... :o)
 Jennifer Waite 6/2/2009 
Sounds yummy! I just can&apos;t get past the commercial! &quot;Put it in me, Scott!&quot;
 Dan Reveal 6/2/2009 
Thanks for this review about Quizno&apos;s. I keep seeing their commercials about great-looking food..
 Kofi Bofah 6/1/2009 
What in the world was going on with you on 5/31? You must have been really motivated around that time...
 Shirley Mandel 6/1/2009 
This is a very honest, well written, interesting review. Quite entertaining.
 Hally Z. 6/1/2009 
I love Quizno&apos;s, except that the stuff is usually too salty for me. It&apos;s weird that they hussled your order through like that. You may prefer Potbelly if you can&apos;t stand the grease at Quizno&apos;s.
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Travel. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
