<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008013" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20120107033958AAVeVhu" time="2012-07-13-01:05" support="2" score="0.008770812137917063" bingtitle="How long can you have a dog travel in the car with you? - Yahoo!7 ..." webtitle="How long can you have a dog travel in the car with you? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000704" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>... even if its only on the grass by a fast food restaurant on ... stop at a fast food venue for a meal, park your car ... Lock your car doors, and order your food to ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Pets &gt; Dogs &gt; Resolved Question 
 Patricia Member since: 07 January 2012 Total points: 79 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How long can you have a dog travel in the car with you?
 I know you NEVER keep a dog in a car by itself but in terms of travelling with you - if you go on a long drive (ie 5 - 8 hours) can you have a dog with you? How often should you have breaks, water, etc.

Also should you always have a window wound down or is air con in the car alright while travelling? (Thinking of a short drive here - I&apos;ve always had all four windows wound down and just wanted to check that I&apos;m doing the right thing).

Thanks! 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 by kelly Member since: 22 January 2010 Total points: 11,871 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Yes you can Some dogs fly in aeroplanes in the cargo hold for hours on end ! I have driven 5+ hours with my dogs while visiting family In Liverpool, which is a five hour drive .My dogs enjoy riding in the car however , and after a while fall asleep and i dont hear a peep from them ! Make sure you toilet them before you leave , if they are potty trained they should let you know when they need to go through out the journey . Take water to drink when you stop - as for food as long as you feed them before you leave and when you arrive there should be no need to feed whilst you travel .Unless of course your are driving for a whole day or more .
You dont need all windows would down - unless you are leaving the dog unattended in the car and its a hot day . Then wind a few down - but of course not all the way .
If your are comfortable than your dogs should be do . They do have a higher body Temperature than humans so make sure they dont over heat , by giving then plenty to drink . The air con will help , but a blast of fresh air every now and again will do the dogs good also 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Thanks - great answer good tips and experience. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; How long can you hav… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Jessi Member since: 14 June 2006 Total points: 27,509 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 We&apos;ve taken our dog with us on a 9-10 hr trip in a car. He was in a travel crate in the back of our SUV and we pretty much stopped at every rest area to let him walk around and have potty time. We used a bunny bottle that attached to the crate so he could have water whenever he wanted it. When we stopped for food, we fed him as well.

As for windows down or up...it was summer so we had them down. AC is fine as long as you know that it is cooling the area where your dog will be. 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 by Afinity Member since: 30 May 2006 Total points: 2,391 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Some dogs live in the car! Truckers have dogs who sleep in the cab with them and go for weeks. You should stop every 3-5 hours for a potty breaks or exercise. I once drove my dog 30 hours from the west coast to the east coast and she was fine. GIVEN she loves the car, if your dog doesn&apos;t like the car, it might not be a good idea. 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by ♋™இ™☠ ㊉NE TRlCK P㊉NY ☠™இ™♋ Member since: 15 January 2008 Total points: 112,099 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 Same break schedula that humans are recommended to follow; stop every 2-3 hours and have a good stretch and a pee.

Windows down no more than a few inches to keep the dog from getting through. And it&apos;s a good idea to have a dog harness attached to the seat belt anchor. 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 by MamaBas Member since: 16 August 2008 Total points: 147,735 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 It&apos;s more about frequency of stops than how long. For instance when we were showing, we were on the road, often for quite long trips, and we even took a b itch from Toronto down to Pennsylvania to be mated once - that took all of 12 hours by the time we&apos;d stopped, etc.etc. If you have a/c in the car, and he&apos;s not sitting in the full sun either, there should be no need to wind windows down (that will increase drag, and your fuel consumption alarmingly!!).

I&apos;d recommend you travel your dog in a crate - it&apos;s far safer, and he&apos;ll be less constricted than using a car harness which I&apos;d never consider appropriate, for my hounds in any case.

I&apos;d plan on stopping just as you would, at which time you water them - although there are non-spill bowls you could put in a crate while travelling, if necessary. If your dog pants a lot, he will need to be kept hydrated as he&apos;ll loose hydration lots via panting. My experience of travelling is that once on a freeway/motorway, dogs settle down for a snooze - it&apos;s normally only on side roads, with stopping and starting that they don&apos;t travel as well and although Bassets are notorious for not being good travellers, we&apos;ve had most who have enjoyed, or not been phased, by being with us in the car. 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 by Basketba... Member since: 20 June 2008 Total points: 308 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Remember safety first, if you don&apos;t have a large window boot in your car, your dog will have to travel on a seat. Purchase a dog safety seat and it will be safer and more comfortable for your dog if your turn or stop the car suddenly.


If you do have a large window boot, put up a wire grid to stop your dog jumping over the back of the seats, most cars have a wire grid already installed.



Line the boot with dog blankets or place his bed in the corner so he can nap comfortably on the journey. Most dogs find sleeping an easy way to cope with motion sickness.



Let a puppy or new pet become accustomed to riding in a car gradually. Begin by allowing your dog to wander around your car with the motor off. Then start with short trips until you and your dog become familiar with traveling by car together.



Do not feed your dog just before the trip. Feed him at least a few hours before. You don&apos;t want to make your dog car sick.




Place a few chew toys in the back with your dog to keep your dog occupied. It is better not to give him a bone or food treats because if he feels sick he will vomit it back up. Squeaky toys are also undesirable as they will drive you crazy.




Ensure your pet does cannot roam around the vehicle, consider purchasing a pet safety belt (e.g., BatziBelt). These belts ensure that should an accident occur your pet is not thrown from the vehicle or into other passengers.


Keep your dog&apos;s collar and dog tags on whenever you are driving. There&apos;s always a chance - no matter how well behaved your dog may be - that your dog will get out of the car and away from you.


Be aware of how quickly a dog can get heat stroke in a parked car. never leave your dog unattended in your car in warm weather for any length of time.


Make sure that you stop every hour or so and go for a quick walk, even if its only on the grass by a fast food restaurant on the highway. This lets your dog use the toilet, so you can also give him some water around now. Taking him on short walks is important as it means that he can stretch his legs and stops him going crazy from being bored. If you stop by the highway your dog MUST be on a leash for his own safety.


Pack appropriate supplies for your dog when taking a long car trip. Bring water, treats, his collar and leash, some of your dogs favorite chew toys, and plastic bags for waste.


If your journey is more than a few hours, (about four hours is your average dogs absolute limit for driving without a longer break then what is described above), Make sure you stop somewhere grassy and relatively quiet (not right by the road), lock your car, feed your dog some food and water, and take him for a walk so he can let off some of his excess energy.


Consult your veterinarian if your dog shows signs of car sickness. Never medicate your dog with Dramamine or any other medication without the guidance of your vet.

If you are traveling a long distance (example: dog show, moving, or ride longer than 1 hour), you may consider getting a dog crate. make sure it is secured either between seats or on the floor. Make sure it is VERY secure to prevent injuries).
If you have a crate, get the crate essentials. Get a dog crate waterer (no mater what, for health and to prevent dehydration you NEED THIS! To train the dog how to use a crate waterer, dab a little honey on the opening and show it to your dog). If it is roasting hot or even a little warm (dogs get over-heated very easily), get a crate fan. You can buy one from www.elitek9.com for only $9.95 or a different brand for $12.95. Both are great.


If your dog has hyperactivity problems, contact your vet and see if a MILD sedative is available and safe, especially if it is a long journey. Follow the instructions carefully.


If you stop at a fast food venue for a meal, park your car in the shade, and let the windows down about an inch each to let cool air in, put a bowl of cool water in the car for your dog and unbuckle him if he is in a dog seat. Lock your car doors, and order your food to go. Try to spend no more than five minutes MAX waiting in line if it is a warm day, as you don&apos;t want your dog to overheat. If there is a large line, tie your dog to a post either just inside the front door or just outside in a place where you can see him. At least he will be out of the heat while you wait. Make sure to tie him with secure knots so he doesn&apos;t escape onto the road. Tight knots will also mean it will be less likely for someone to steal your dog. Eat your food with your dog so he has company. It is also a good time for you to feed him HIS lunch. Go for a walk afterwards.


Make your first few trips in the car to somewhere fun for your dog, like a park or a field so they associate a car ride with something good rather than just trips to the vet. 
Source(s):
 wikihow 
 6 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Dogs 

 Would you own this dog? Middle name for my dog? Is it possible to have a dog and still maintain a good lawn? Potty training a 12 week puppy? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Pets 
 Birds Cats Dogs Fish Horses Other - Pets Reptiles Rodents 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
