<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008249" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/09/ketchup_way_more_than_you_need.php" time="2012-07-13-01:44" support="3" score="0.02091333559181344" bingtitle="Ketchup: Way More Than You Need To Know About It - Miami ..." webtitle="Ketchup: Way More Than You Need To Know About It - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000597" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>... maybe the baked beans), as do all of the condiments ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ... Voice Places. Discover restaurants, nightlife ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Food Facts 
Ketchup: Way More Than You Need To Know About It
 By Lee Klein Fri., Sep. 2 2011 at 8:44 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 Lee Klein Ketchup didn&apos;t start out with tomatoes. 
​ Labor Day weekend brings hamburgers, hot dogs, barbecued chicken, cole slaw, some baked beans, chips and salsa (and perhaps guacamole), ice cream, beer, lemonade ... well, we can go on quite awhile with this list. Every one of these foods has a fascinating history (except for maybe the baked beans), as do all of the condiments used -- like, say, ketchup, which 97% of American kitchens are stocked with. Each one of us, in fact, consumes on average three bottles of the stuff a year.

Did you know that, like wines, there are good and bad ketchup years determined by the tomato harvest? Neither did I, but now that I do, I think it&apos;s high time someone introduced vintage ketchup with the year printed on the label.

Even though you&apos;re all very familiar with ketchup, there&apos;s probably a whole lot you don&apos;t know about it.
 
Ketchup comes from kê-chiap , a spicy, pickled, anchovy-based fish sauce popular in China in the 17th-century. From there it spread to the Malay states, which is where British seamen discovered it, brought it home, and Anglicized the name to ketchup . It wasn&apos;t until the late 1700s that someone in New England thought to add tomatoes to the recipe. In those days, Americans were suspicious of tomatoes -- many thought they were poisonous. But by 1876, when the F.&amp;J. Heinz Company of Pennsylvania processed and infused the tomatoes with vinegar, spices, and sweetener and sold it in bottles, folks were more apt to try it.

&quot;Blessed relief for Mother and the other women in the household!&quot; blared the original Heinz slogan, which referenced the laborious process necessary for making it at home. Ketchup became popular in 19th century American homes, but it was the banning of sodium benzoate in the early 20th century that likely propelled the condiment to its present iconic status. Commercial ketchups in the early years were culled from unripe tomatoes low in pectin, so it was a thinner sauce and relied on sodium benzoate as a preservative.

​Harvey W. Wiley, known as &quot;the father of the Food and Drug Administration,&quot; challenged the safety of the preservative, which led to its banning in the 1906 Pure Food and Drug Act. Heinz and fellow ketchup entrepreneurs started using ripe tomatoes and pickling them to a greater extent, which eliminated the need for sodium benzoate and also greatly improved the taste. By 1907, Heinz was selling 12 million bottles of ketchup per year. Nowadays the company sells some 650 million bottles a year.

Perhaps the lowest point in this condiment&apos;s history came in October 2000, when Heinz rolled out a line of artificially colored EZ Squirt ketchups in green, pink, purple, blue, orange, and teal. By 2006 they were gone.

Other fun facts:


 Heinz sells 11 billion single serve packets of ketchup per year. That averages out to two packets for every person on the planet. Ketchup falls from a Heinz glass bottle at .028 miles per hour. According to the Heinz website , the best way to release the ketchup faster is to &quot;apply a firm tap to the sweet spot on the neck of the bottle -- the &apos;57&apos;.&quot; The company also slyly notes that only 11% of the public know this trick. The acid in ketchup purportedly makes it effective for removing tarnish from copper pots. 

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Heinz Tomato Ketchup Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Wow Lee!  I love the copper pot tip. Finally a use for ketchup...
 

TotalComments: 1
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Tobacco Road
 View Ad | View Site 
Flip Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
Trio on the Bay
 View Ad | View Site 
Gordon Biersch
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 The Next Rendition of the Harding Dinner Series; Menu for Balloo and Zapata &quot;Dinner With Friends&quot; Developer Gil Dezer To Knock Down a Miami Institution Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
