<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008959" url="http://www.androidpit.com/en/android/market/apps/app/com.mqdp.foodfinder/Food-Finder" time="2012-07-13-02:23" support="1" score="0.00038193390775845525" bingtitle="Support AndroidPIT" webtitle="Food Finder - Android Apps and Tests - AndroidPIT">
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>... fast food finder,food restaurant finder,fast food restaurant ... As a logged in user, you can also change the order ... Support AndroidPIT. Do you enjoy AndroidPIT? We?re ...</description>
	<body>
		/ [ Deutsch | English | Español |
  Русский | Português | Français |
  Italiano | Türkçe ]   
 
 Register now »Login «Login 
 E-mail address Password 

 

 Remember me Forgotten your password? 
 
 Home   News   App Center Apps Reviews   Forum   Developers   Community 
 You are here: All Android Apps » Social »Food Finder Add to my profile Add to my watchlist Post on Facebook Link to this app Report comparable or similar apps Developer&apos;s website (2,768) 
Food Finder

 Michael Quach 
 This app has been removed from the Market. INSTALL About this app: Show more LATEST VERSION 1.4.0 VERSION FROM Dec 5, 2010 UPDATED ON Dec 21, 2010 ANDROID VERSION 1.5 and up CATEGORY Social INSTALLATIONS &gt;250,000 SIZE 183,730 Bytes: PRICE FREE 
Top 5 Apps
 Hotel Search HRS-250000 Hotels HRS Hotel Reservation Service (2,335) free AIVC (Alice) YourApp24 (14,610) free SwiftKey 3 Keyboard SwiftKey (62,251) EUR 3.87
 AlarmDroid Fabian Lueghausen (27,913) free OfficeSuite Pro 6 + (PDF&amp;HD) Mobile Systems (4,610) EUR 12.56
 
 Overview User reviews (2,768) Review Permissions 
 
Description
Best Food Finder App!

Get turn-by-turn directions to the nearest restaurant of your choice!

This handy app helps you find great dining and show you where to eat locally.

KW:food,restaurant,food finder,fast food finder,food restaurant finder,fast food restaurant finder,food fast food finder,local restaurant fast food

Recent changes:
Thank you for using this app. Hope you enjoy it! 
App Screenshots
 
User Reviews
 Average rating 4.0 (2,768) Your rating: 
Latest Community Comments
 Write new comment: 
You must log in or register now ,
to submit a comment!

As a logged in user, you can also change the order of the comments.
 
User Reviews
 Average rating 4.0 (2,768) Your rating: 
 All reports Market only Community only 
 Language: German English Spanish Russian Portuguese French Italian Turkish All languages   Sort order: Latest first Oldest first 
alani 
 Dec 23, 2010 12:05:15 PM 
If anyone is trying to find hot girls or guys in your area check out DroidSingles.Info I meet someone new to hang out with on there every night!
 
Michael 
 Dec 23, 2010 11:10:33 AM 
Great app. Finds restaurants other apps miss.
 
Thiam Hooi 
 Dec 22, 2010 5:19:19 PM 
Would be better if the distance is showing in kilometres
 
Bill 
 Dec 21, 2010 9:54:04 PM 
Fast, specific. Good, potentially great application, but their particular ads suck. I&apos;d rather pay. I still use it, but worst ads on a free app.
 
susie 
 Dec 21, 2010 12:17:58 PM 
If anyone is try to find hot girls or guys in your area check out DroidSingles.Info I meet someone new to hang out with on there every night!
 
mike 
 Dec 21, 2010 1:49:40 AM 
Google maps does the same thing. Droid x
 
steve 
 Dec 21, 2010 1:17:12 AM 
Excellent!
 
kat 
 Dec 14, 2010 6:31:14 PM 
Nd step by step directions on how to get there. .exit number, etc.. got me lost on my way outta nyc
 
April 
 Dec 14, 2010 6:08:14 PM 
I&apos;m in arlington, tx and this app can&apos;t locate me after 4 min. Dev needs to add ability to enter zipcode. Uninstall.
 
Jacks 
 Dec 11, 2010 3:18:51 AM 
Good only for big cities.
 
 Go to page: 1 2 3 ... 38 » 
 Language: German English Spanish Russian Portuguese French Italian Turkish All languages   Sort order: Latest first Oldest first 
alani 
 Dec 23, 2010 12:05:15 PM 
If anyone is trying to find hot girls or guys in your area check out DroidSingles.Info I meet someone new to hang out with on there every night!
 
Michael 
 Dec 23, 2010 11:10:33 AM 
Great app. Finds restaurants other apps miss.
 
Thiam Hooi 
 Dec 22, 2010 5:19:19 PM 
Would be better if the distance is showing in kilometres
 
Bill 
 Dec 21, 2010 9:54:04 PM 
Fast, specific. Good, potentially great application, but their particular ads suck. I&apos;d rather pay. I still use it, but worst ads on a free app.
 
susie 
 Dec 21, 2010 12:17:58 PM 
If anyone is try to find hot girls or guys in your area check out DroidSingles.Info I meet someone new to hang out with on there every night!
 
mike 
 Dec 21, 2010 1:49:40 AM 
Google maps does the same thing. Droid x
 
steve 
 Dec 21, 2010 1:17:12 AM 
Excellent!
 
kat 
 Dec 14, 2010 6:31:14 PM 
Nd step by step directions on how to get there. .exit number, etc.. got me lost on my way outta nyc
 
April 
 Dec 14, 2010 6:08:14 PM 
I&apos;m in arlington, tx and this app can&apos;t locate me after 4 min. Dev needs to add ability to enter zipcode. Uninstall.
 
Jacks 
 Dec 11, 2010 3:18:51 AM 
Good only for big cities.
 
 Go to page: 1 2 3 ... 38 » 
 Language: German English Spanish Russian Portuguese French Italian Turkish All languages   Sort order: Latest first Oldest first 
Test review and rating
We havenʼt tested this Android app yet.
 Request a test report now! 
The application has access to the following:

Network communication
 full Internet access Allows an application to create network sockets. 
Your location
 coarse (network-based) location Access coarse location sources such as the cellular network database to determine an approximate phone location, where available. Malicious applications can use this to determine approximately where you are. fine (GPS) location Access fine location sources such as the Global Positioning System on the phone, where available. Malicious applications can use this to determine where you are, and may consume additional battery power. You are here: All Android Apps » Social »Food Finder [X] Link to this app 
 Link To This App At AndroidPIT 

Thank you for your interest in putting a link to this app at AndroidPIT on your website. The HTML code below creates a button that will lead your visitors directly to this app&apos;s details page.

Option 1 (green button):
 
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidpit.com/en/android/market/apps/app/com.mqdp.foodfinder/Food-Finder&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://st01.androidpit.info/img/dev/get_it_at_androidpit_gr.png&quot;alt=&quot;Food Finder - Android Market&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 

Option 2 (black button):
 
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidpit.com/en/android/market/apps/app/com.mqdp.foodfinder/Food-Finder&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://st01.androidpit.info/img/dev/get_it_at_androidpit_bl.png&quot;alt=&quot;Food Finder - Android Market&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
Simply insert the specified code at the appropriate area of your website&apos;s HTML code. 
Support AndroidPIT

Do you enjoy AndroidPIT? We?re thrilled to have your support! How does it work? Just click on the links below.

 Advertise on AndroidPIT » App Seller - Give your app a boost! » Request a test report » 
 
Recommend to Others

Enjoy AndroidPIT? Then please let other people know about us!
 

 
 Your name: 

 Your e-mail: 

 Friendʼs e-mail: 
 
 
 
Questions / Help

Do you have questions about AndroidPIT or simply want to learn more about us? Then you might find the following links helpful.
 
 FAQ» Privacy policy» Contact form» Info for developers» Affiliate Program» 
 
Search Keywords

 PDF Search keyword Whatsapp Youtube adobe android market angry angry birds facebook flash player free free games fruit ninja games google google play instagram market netflix office opera skype temple run tv twitter 
 
Bookmarks
   
 Home Affiliate Program About us Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy RSS Feeds Contact us 
 You are reading: Food Finder - Android Apps and Tests - AndroidPIT.
All times are UTC+02:00. The time now is 2:23 AM.
	</body>
</document>
