<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008597" url="http://www.nutritionalsteps.com/about.html" time="2012-07-13-02:03" support="3" score="0.0071125312084955195" bingtitle="About - Nutritional Steps" webtitle="About - Nutritional Steps">
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>Prior to founding Nutritional Steps, LLC, I gained my food ... and beverages sold to the growing trend of upscale fast food restaurant chains, but also watched how high end ...</description>
	<body>
		Nutritional Steps 
 Home Nutrition by age 
 Infant - Preschooler 

 Elementary K - 5 

 Grade 6 - 11 

 
 Get started 
 Private consultations 

 Cooking workshops 

 Monthly coffee&amp;questions 

 
 Food bytes About Contact 
 
 About 
 Don’t hide the butter from me - I eat butter!&apos;  says Georgette.
 
Georgette Blake
B.A. (hons), Dip. C.A., Dip. C.N., Cert. P.P.A.N.
Nutritional Steps, LLC
 
 As a consumer, a classically trained chef and home cook, with over 10 years of experience working in the food industry, I couldn’t believe how unprepared I was when the time came to introduce my daughter to food. I was overwhelmed by the wealth of food choices made available to parents today and the abundance of, and often controversial, information on nutrition. It was only when I had completed a Diploma in Comprehensive Nutrition and a Certificate in Pregnancy, Pediatric and Adolescent Nutrition that I fully understood how and what I should do to nourish my daughter in order for her to grow and develop properly and to enhance her protection against the future development of many of today’s major diseases. I can now confidently and happily say that my daughter is thriving.
 
 Passionate about sharing my knowledge and extensive experience with young parents, I founded Nutritional Steps, LLC in the summer of 2009. My mission is to package what I have learnt in a simple, practical and applicable format and give busy parents the knowledge and tools to promote optimum health and good eating habits that will survive into their children’s adulthood.
 
 Prior to founding Nutritional Steps, LLC, I gained my food, nutrition and business knowledge by following a career in the food industry.
 
 Raised in England and France, I graduated from Brooke’s University, England with a Bachelor of Arts Combined Honors Degree in German Language, Literature and Contemporary Studies. I have subsequently earned a Diploma in French Cuisine from L’Ecole de Cuisine Francaise de Mirbeck, England, a Diploma in Comprehensive Nutrition and a Certificate in Pregnancy, Pediatric and Adolescent Nutrition from the Huntington College of Health Sciences, Tennessee.
 
 My career began in England in the specialty cheese industry as an Assistant Cheese Buyer where I rapidly grew my knowledge of cheese manufacturing, importing, processing and distribution. My fluency in French and German enabled me to travel to Europe as the company’s representative at International Trade Fairs and to interpret during buying negotiations and quality control inspections of international cheese and dairy manufacturers.
 
 After marrying a Canadian, I immigrated to Ottawa, Canada and continued to focus my career in the food industry. This time I worked as a Product Category Manager for a foodservice distributor, where I not only gained knowledge of the types of foods and beverages sold to the growing trend of upscale fast food restaurant chains, but also watched how high end restaurateurs started to add prepared foods to their purchase orders to reduce both food and labor costs.
 
 After three years my husband and I moved to Toronto, Canada where I worked as a Senior Buyer for a major retail and foodservice importer and distributor of gourmet national and international foods. My language skills, my ever increasing food knowledge and my well trained eye to growing consumer food trends, specifically to those of natural and organic foods, allowed me to focus on product development and assist suppliers in creating and designing Canadian specific food labels.
 
 My desire to diversify into the area of nutrition was precipitated in January 2003, by the publishing of Health Canada’s new nutrition labeling regulations, forcing the entire Canadian food industry to provide nutritional information in a mandatory“Nutrition Facts”table. I assisted the company in spearheading this project to ensure that it would be able to successfully comply within the given timeline.
 
 Having worked closely with the Suppliers’food scientists on this project, moving to the States with my husband and figuring out how to raise a well nourished child, my obvious next stage of career development was to enroll myself into a nutrition program. By combining my extensive food knowledge with a comprehensive education in the importance of nutrition and diet, I soon realized I had become unknowingly entangled in a quagmire of the modern food industry and therefore made it my passion to free myself and others from such confusion over food and daily nourishment.
 
 I currently live in Washington DC with my family. Find out about the coaching and support Georgette offers - Click here.   
 Charlotte - my inspiration 
 My inspiration several years on. First steps, little morsels. 

 
 Your personal food trainer 
 Join Georgette for a coffee morning. Click above Pantry and refrigerator appraisal? Click above 
 Cooking and prep lessons? Click above
	</body>
</document>
