<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008719" url="http://www.grubgrade.com/2010/12/22/fast-food-review-tater-tots-from-sonic/" time="2012-07-13-02:11" support="5" score="0.01926979156468398" bingtitle="GrubGrade | Fast Food Review: Tater Tots from Sonic" webtitle="GrubGrade | Fast Food Review: Tater Tots from Sonic">
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000758" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>I liked how they were remarkably clean on the ... Even the fact that my order took forever to come out ... And considering no other nationwide fast food restaurant makes ...</description>
	<body>
		GrubGrade 
 We Make You Hungry 
 Home About Contact GrubGrading Privacy Policy Reviews While I’m Out 
 
 Fast Food Review: Tater Tots from Sonic 

 December 22, 2010 By: Adam Category: Fries/Rings/Sides , Reviews 
 
 
 Given my incredibly open mind for trying off-the-wall food items , it may come as a shock to you that I was once the most selective of eaters. I was so selective (one might even call it ‘picky) that for my entire elementary, middle and high school education I not once purchased lunch from school. Even when I ended up forgetting my brown bag and was issued one of those county mandated “billed” lunches, I straight up refused to put anything from a hair-netted woman into my mouth, in the processes risking malnutrition and extreme hypoglycemia during recess four-square.
 
I was a&quot;never ever&quot;
 
Yup. I was that kid.

The quintessential “bringer,” I was so closed minded I didn’t even engage in trading. To me, cafeteria food was just a fear I couldn’t conquer, and even as I got older and the choices increased, it wasn’t until my freshmen year of college that I stopped relying on my mommy to pack my lunch.  And why not? Mom knew what I liked, and besides, those mushy chicken fingers and that square “pizza” thing on the beige, 1970 hospital trays of Rockburn Elementary just looked, well inedible (the food that is, obviously the trays were inedible.)
 
The only thing better than a random tot is a random tot in my mouth
 
And while I feel myself ultimately saved from a future of poor taste and potential health problems from my decision to forgo the lunch line, I do regret one thing: that I never had the pleasure of eating a real live, honest-to-God tater tot.

Until now.

 

Thanks to my first ever trip to Sonic, my worldview has not only been shocked, but 12 years of culinary isolation have been called into question. Yes, I am here to tell you that Sonics tater tots are just that good, and are in fact the best tater tots I have ever eaten.
 
 
 Pop some of these crispy little potato pieces in your mouth and you’ll never think of a spud the same way again. Top them with chili and cheese, or get them plain. They’re SONIC® good no matter how you eat them. 
Never mind that they were the first and only tater tots I’ve ever eaten. Forget the stunning devolution of my sophisticated palette. Just know that thanks to my friend “Q” at Brand Eating and a recent Sonic giveaway, a changed man stands before you today.

 

As one of the world’s leading experts on potato chips and French fries, it really amazes me that I didn’t realize I would like tater tots sooner in life. I mean, it’s potato + fat + salt dipped in ketchup. What the heck is there not to like? Yet unlike French fries, which very widely in consistently and can be found everywhere, there’s something incredibly unique and hypnotizing about the perfect tot. It’s that culinary “X” factor born from nostalgia and simplicity, taking us back to a time when life was simpler and the hour you got between a hard days of napping and addition problems was to be savored.

 

Yet I never got to savor those days, but thanks to Sonic, I am now. The medium container is well filled with warm, crispy potato pieces with tiny ridges and bumps on the exterior. I liked how they were remarkably clean on the outside – crispy and not oily, with the nooks and crannies you don’t get with fries. The insides were moist but not mushy, and did a great job of soaking up ketchup.
 
How did those little buggers get in there?
 
My goodness these little buggers were delicious. Even the fact that my order took forever to come out by the annoying drive through hop or the fact that a few stray fries ended up in my box couldn’t ruin this ethereal tasting experience for me. Words fail me, to the point where description becomes impossible. So I can simply say that these are the best tots ever – that is, until I try others to compare.

And considering no other nationwide fast food restaurant makes tater tots (at least to my knowledge, but let me know if I’m off here) I think it’s safe to say that my conception of the golden brown standard of tater goodness is safe for at least the immediate future.

(As a side note, a medium order of these things is listed at  ridiculously low 200 calories and 2.5 grams of saturated fat. Considering I’m now willing to replace all my carbohydrates with Sonics tater tots, this seems completely within the acceptable limits of nutritional mindfulness.)

 Pros : Nostalgia for memories never realized. Warm, crispy loveliness. Somewhere between“ethereal”and“OMG YES AWESOME” Cons : Hypoglycemia at recess. 22 years of missing out. 

 Taste: 9.50/10
 

 Value: 8.00/10 

 Grubbing on the Go: 9.00/10 

———————————

 GrubGrade : 9.50/10 ( GrubGrade Hall of Fame ) 
 

 (Overall GrubGrade is not an average) 

 Price: $1.59 for medium order 

 www.Sonic.com 

 Nutrition Info – Onion Rings (Medium Size)
 
Calories – 203

Fat – 12.9 grams

Saturated Fat – 2.4 grams

Cholesterol – 1 milligram

Sodium – 440 milligrams

Carbs – 20 grams

Sugars – 2 grams

Protein – 2 grams
 
 
 
 Tags: Sonic , Sonic Drive-Thru , Sonic Tater Tots , Sonic Tater Tots Review , tater tots 
23 Comments to“Fast Food Review: Tater Tots from Sonic”
 

 maxchain says: December 22, 2010 at 8:55 pm 
HAHAHAHAHAHA. Nobody’s going to confuse those mushy, salty
cylinders they serve(d) in school cafeterias with actual tater
tots–you didn’t miss anything. Heck, I was convinced I hated tater
tots as a whole until I tried them at Sonic. You should get‘em
with cheese sometime!
 1 Reply skippymom says: December 22, 2010 at 9:30 pm 
You know I never realized it–but you are so right–tater
tots do not vary in consistency as french fries can. We love tater
tots and have them when we make sandwiches and burgers. Try the
ore-ida brand and just bake them in the oven–they are awesome! 
[that is when you can&apos;t get to Sonic. Love Sonic!]
 2 Reply tracylee says: December 22, 2010 at 9:54 pm 
The posted Nutrition Info is for Onion Rings?
 3 Reply Anne Marie says: December 22, 2010 at 11:33 pm 
I normally don’t order things with cheese, but cheese tater
tots at Sonic are awesome. Try them 
 4 Reply Scott says: December 23, 2010 at 8:50 am 
Adam, please expound; I don’t think you were clear in your
message. Did you like them or not?
 5 Reply 
 Adam says: December 23, 2010 at 9:22 am 
Loved em
 6 Reply 
 jay says: December 23, 2010 at 9:41 am 
Fact: everything fried at sonic tastes like french toast
and is disgusting
 7 Reply 
 John says: December 23, 2010 at 10:12 pm 
Fact: What you just wrote is NOT A FACT.
 8 Reply 
 Atleye says: December 23, 2010 at 10:11 am 
Adam: I look at the extra fries as I do with extra fries in a fast food onion ring order…extra awesomeness. How can a little extra fried food be bad?
 9 Reply 
 Adam says: December 23, 2010 at 10:49 am 
Good point!
 10 Reply 
 IBeAnonymous says: December 23, 2010 at 11:40 am 
1. Try dipping in ranch.
2. Try with cheese. But not the sonic cheese, its pretty flavorless.

Honestly though, Sonic’s tot’s aren’t even the best tots around! Nonetheless, they are pretty good!
 11 Reply GrubGradeFan says: December 23, 2010 at 1:23 pm 
I was def. a“never ever”kid in elementary school, but once I got into middle school the lunches drasitcally changed.

In my school district we were offered Taco Bell, Pizza Hut, and a local mexican chain, Miguels Jr. ( http://miguelsjr.com ), as our daily menu. Of course there was still a line that had all the typical, nasty items.

My question is, did anybody else have these choices or is this extremely rare?

PS. We didnt have full menus

Taco Bell: Hard Tacos, Soft Tacos, Bean Burritos, Chillitos, and the Cinnamon Twists.

Pizza Hut: Pepp. and Chesse Pizza by the slice

Miguels: Bean&amp;Cheese Burritos and BR&amp;C Burritos
*Check the website. Homemade Mexican fast-food that will blow your mind. Very few locations in a condensed area.
 12 Reply 
 Adam says: December 24, 2010 at 9:09 am 
Dude, that is maybe standard at a college, but a middle school? LOL No way. Reminds me of that scene in Richie Rich.

“YOU HAVE YOUR OWN MCDONALDS!”
 13 Reply 
 GrubGradeFan says: December 29, 2010 at 5:26 am 
hahaha. This was at a public school too. Im not gonna
downplay the fact that I did live in a nice area, but this def.
wasnt some fancy private or prep school. I had this menu from
7th-12th grade. Guess I should feel blessed.
 14 Reply 
 
 Jessica says: December 23, 2010 at 2:51 pm 
Arby’s has potato cakes which taste like tater tots. Jack
In the Box has hashbrown sticks that get pretty close. BK has
crispy crowns as their breakfast potato offering. They are not very
tasty. But I LOVE me some Arby’s Tater Cakes!!!
 15 Reply mattitude says: December 23, 2010 at 11:00 pm 
I have to disagree with all,since I have lived in the south most of my life,Sonic and it’s food are just tasty and the tots especially with chili and cheese–are a heart stopping delicious thing!
 16 Reply Q says: December 24, 2010 at 4:02 am 
Haha, I don’t know if I would go so far as to put them in the GrubGrade Hall of Fame but you’re welcome! ;D
 17 Reply popeyes fried biscuit says: December 24, 2010 at 8:14 am 
Taco Time has the best tater tots(mexi nuggets) of all times, ALL TIMES*Kanye voice*
 18 Reply Tony jaguar says: December 24, 2010 at 5:43 pm 
GrubGradeFan that explains lots about the IE.
 19 Reply 
 GrubGradeFan says: December 29, 2010 at 5:32 am 
. . .and what exactly would that be? We got kick ass
lunches?
 20 Reply 
 Zachary Jacob Zblewski says: December 28, 2010 at 2:23 pm 
Make sure to put Taco John’s Potato Ole’s on your list to try!

 http://tacojohns.com/food4-SideOrders1-Potato_Oles.asp 
 21 Reply jesika says: December 29, 2010 at 12:48 pm 
tater tots are indeed awesome, especially when the outside
is really crispy and salty. sonic’s cheese tots are frigging
awesome as well, and served with ranch. taco john’s potato oles are
pretty much tots with seasoning salt, and AS ADDICTING AS CRACK.
perfect plain, or with sour cream, taco sauce or guac. most of the
best tots ive had are from local joints here in minnesota. i think
mayslacks in st paul has the best ones ive ever had. oh man, the
crispy outside, the fluffy potatoy interior, always consistant…i
definately prefer tots to fries!
 22 Reply Steve says: July 23, 2011 at 12:08 pm 
They are soooo good because they do not have onion in them unlike most to those famous brands found in food stores. The onion over powers the taters makeing the onion tot inferior in taste to the Sonic tater tots. Wish I could find some in the store without onion.
 23 Reply 
 

 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 

 Notify me of follow-up comments by email. 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
   ← Fast Food Review: New Beefy Crunch Burrito from Taco Bell Food News: Hand-Breaded Chicken Tender Wrappers from Hardee’s → 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (14) June 2012 (49) May 2012 (45) April 2012 (45) March 2012 (49) February 2012 (56) January 2012 (44) December 2011 (35) November 2011 (47) October 2011 (47) September 2011 (55) August 2011 (55) July 2011 (39) June 2011 (35) May 2011 (39) April 2011 (35) March 2011 (38) February 2011 (40) January 2011 (42) December 2010 (38) November 2010 (37) October 2010 (41) September 2010 (34) August 2010 (35) July 2010 (49) June 2010 (38) May 2010 (45) April 2010 (35) March 2010 (36) February 2010 (31) January 2010 (38) December 2009 (40) November 2009 (36) October 2009 (39) September 2009 (53) August 2009 (68) July 2009 (75) June 2009 (73) May 2009 (76) April 2009 (81) March 2009 (61) February 2009 (24) 
Categories
 Select Category Celebrity Grubbers  (18) Discussion  (19) Featured Restaurant  (50) First Impressions  (50) Food for Thought  (6) Food News  (904) From the Editor  (66) GG Contests  (120) GG Videos  (104) GrubGrade Site Update  (12) Hitting the Road  (48) Homemade  (45) In My Pantry  (12) Jealous  (17) Observations  (56) Polls  (38) RememBear This  (24) Reviews  (506)    Breakfast  (75)    Burgers  (66)    Chicken  (92)    Desserts  (39)    Drinks  (16)    Fries/Rings/Sides  (27)    Hot Dogs  (8)    Mexican  (37)    Pizza  (19)    Salads  (17)    Sandwiches  (121)    Seafood  (18)    Snacks  (91)    Soup  (1)    Wraps  (12) Uncategorized  (9) 
 GrubGrade on Twitter 

 RT @EatBitchBlog : Just read about new, fun food tours in #Frederick #Maryland by @TasteFrederick Check it out: http://t.co/KRjftmBr 5 hours ago Tipsy Texan and Friends @Franklinbbq http://t.co/2tQtNODF 6 hours ago The line @franklinbbq Austin http://t.co/q2a78NpA 8 hours ago 
 
Recent Comments

 metric89 on A Look at Family Meal in Frederick, Maryland jenne on Son of Baconator Joins the Wendy’s Menu jenne on A Look at Family Meal in Frederick, Maryland stevenp on Review: Cantina Bell Menu from Taco Bell 
 
 
 
Check Us Out On...

 GrubGrade on Facebook GrubGrade on Tumblr GrubGrade on Twitter The GrubGrade Channel 
 
Other Blogs

 EJ Eats Food Junk Freezer Burns On Second Scoop Option Pitch&amp;Waffle Crisp Rodzilla Reviews San Diego Sugar Serious Eats Snack Snoop So Good Blog The Impulsive Buy Would I Buy It Again? Yum Yucky 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
 
 GrubGrade ©2007 - 2012 All Rights Reserved. Using WordPress 3.4 Engine
 Entries and Comments .

 Prosumer ver. 1.9 design by WP GPL 

 
 Page optimized by WP Minify WordPress Plugin 

 Featuring Recent Posts WordPress Widget development by YD
	</body>
</document>
