<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008826" url="http://rlmather.com/" time="2012-07-13-02:16" support="4" score="0.01318309329319525" bingtitle="Kitchen, Dining and Bar Layout and Design for Commercial Restaurants" webtitle="Kitchen, Dining and Bar Layout and Design for Commercial Restaurants">
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Customers are looking for a good restaurant experience from the moment they walk in the door until the time they leave. Our commercial layout and design ...</description>
	<body>
		bob@rlmather.com 
Phone: 952-941-2271 

 Site Map 
 
 


 
 
 
Kitchen, Dining&amp;Bar Layout
&amp;Design for Commercial Restaurants
 
 
Layout&amp;Design
Good restaurant layout and interior design can help position your restaurant in the marketplace. 
 Customers are looking for a good restaurant experience from the moment they walk in the door until the time 
 they leave. Our commercial layout and design concepts are all part of creating that enjoyable 
 experience. We utilize AutoCAD and specialized commercial kitchen equipment software to professionally plan, layout, 
 and design the public spaces for everything from chain restaurants to trendy eating spots. 
 
Layout&amp;Design from Concept to Completion
Whether new construction or 
 remodeling, from concept to completion we layout and design the interior of commercial kitchens, restaurants, 
 bars and night clubs, cafeterias, coffee shops, and much more. Our restaurant layout and design services 
 are provided for reasonable layout and design fees. Contact us to meet with 
 us and receive your customized layout and interior design cost estimate. We can accomplish work within your budget 
 needs and in a timely manner.


Full Service Layout&amp;Design
As a full service, commercial kitchen layout and design company,
 we can offer you everything you need: professional plans that meet the requirements of the Health Department, 
 Architects, Engineers, and Contractors. We work closely with electrical and mechanical engineers, plumbers, 
 contractors, equipment dealers and interior designers to complete your commercial kitchen layout on schedule.
 Visit our Services page to view just what we are able to layout and design for your
 commercial kitchen or restaurant.

 

 
 
 Home  |  Services  |  Biography  |  Contact 


 
Copyright©2000-2011 RL Mather Kitchen, Dining and Bar Layout and Design. All rights reserved.
Web design by The Literate Letter® .
	</body>
</document>
