<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008220" url="http://dinehere.ca/vancouver/rasoee-robson" time="2012-07-13-01:42" support="6" score="0.011740483010498627" bingtitle="Rasoee (Robson) | Vancouver" webtitle="Rasoee (Robson) | Vancouver">
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000502" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001252" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>... with a few more side veggies, throw in a small slice of Naan into the container ... I waited under ten minutes for my food ... The atmosphere of the &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant really ...</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt;&gt; Metro Vancouver Login or Register 
 Metro Vancouver Bowen Island Burnaby Coquitlam Delta Langley Maple Ridge New Westminster North Vancouver 

 Pitt Meadows Port Coquitlam Port Moody Richmond Surrey Vancouver West Vancouver White Rock 

 Abbotsford Brampton Burlington Calgary Chilliwack Duncan Edmonton Halifax Hamilton Kamloops Kelowna Kitchener Ladysmith 

 London Mission Mississauga Montreal Nanaimo Niagara Falls Oakville Oshawa Ottawa Parksville Saskatoon Scarborough Squamish 

 St. Catharines Tofino Toronto Vaughan Waterloo Welland Whistler Whitby Windsor 

 Greater Victoria Sidney Sooke Victoria 
 Do a search below using the city or postal code search box if your city is not listed above. 
 
 Follow us on Facebook and Twitter 

 Get dining news including restaurant closures and qualify for giveaways.
 Search: Location: Locations Locations: 
 Vancouver Burnaby Coquitlam Maple Ridge White Rock Pitt Meadows Richmond North Vancouver New Westminster West Vancouver Port Moody Bowen Island Surrey Langley Delta Port Coquitlam     
 Tip: To view neighbourhoods, click on a city above or change the default location to a specific city (top left of website). Cuisines Cuisines: 
 Afghan Cambodian European International Pakistani Soup African Canadian Family Irish Pasta Southern American Caribbean Fast food Israeli Persian Southwestern Asian Chicken Filipino Italian Peruvian Spanish Australian Chilean Fish&amp;chips Izakaya Pho Steaks Austrian Chinese French Jamaican Pita Sushi Bagels Coffee Fusion Japanese Pizza Swiss Bakery Contemporary Game Juice Polish Szechuan Bar Continental Gelato Korean Portuguese Taiwanese Barbeque Creole German Kosher Poutine Tapas Belgian Crepes Greek Latin American Pub Tea house Bistro Cuban Halal Lebanese Ramen Tex-Mex Brazilian Deli Hawaiian Malaysian Regional Thai Brewery Dessert Healthy Mediterranean Romanian Tibetan British Dim sum Hot dogs Mexican Russian Tunisian Bubble tea Diner Hot pot Middle Eastern Salad Turkish Burgers Doughnuts Hungarian Mongolian Sandwiches Ukrainian Cafe Dutch Ice cream Moroccan Seafood Vegetarian Cafeteria Eastern European Indian Organic Shanghainese Vietnamese Cajun Eclectic Indigenous Pacific northwest Singaporean Wine bar California Ethiopian Indonesian Pacific rim     
 Options Price: $ ($15 or less) $$ ($15 - $30) $$$ ($30 - $45) $$$$ ($45 or more) Features: 
 Ocean Wise View Dinner Banquet Wheelchair accessible Patio Lunch Delivery Live entertainment All day breakfast Breakfast Takeout Romantic Catering Weekend brunch Cheap eats Television Late night Buffet Fine dining 
 Sort: A-Z Popularity Rating - Food - Service - Value - Ambiance Z-A # Reviews Created Updated Min: 0 Reviews 1 Reviews 2 Reviews 3 Reviews 5 Reviews 10 Reviews 15 Reviews 20 Reviews 25 Reviews Results: 10 20 50 Offer: None Deals -- Group buys -- Coupons Order online Reserve online Gift cards Status: Open Opening soon Renovation Closed Fast food 
 Food Service Value Ambiance Reviews 5 
   Add to favourites Add to try 
 Vancouver › Indian 

Rasoee
 320 Robson Street 
 Vancouver , BC V6B6M2 Tel: (604) 568-9023 Order Online 
 Neighbourhood: Downtown 
 Cuisine: Indian Price: $ ($15 or less) Service: Takeout , Delivery , Catering Meals: Lunch , Dinner Features: Cheap eats , Wheelchair accessible Hours: Mon - Sun: 11AM - 10PM 
Rasoee serves fresh, fast and modern Indian cuisine. Eat-in, Take-out or FREE Delivery available! Rasoee also offers a comprehensive catering menu, everything from cocktail appetizers to full buffets (large and small). We&apos;ll bring the right ingredients to help Spice Up your meeting or event!
 

 Web site Order online Twitter Facebook Inspection reports 
 
 Submit review Upload image Edit restaurant 
 
 Reviews Images Tips Twitter 
 
Reviews
 Displaying 1 - 5 of 5 Reviews Found Sort: Useful | Helpful | Reviews | Date Great service - Food on the Shy side By MoneyPenny of Vancouver (2 Reviews) Submitted Saturday, March 17, 2012 - 8:33am [Take-out] 
Fist time trying to find something in this area that wasn&apos;t totally fast-food for lunch. Walked in, very clean, small seating area, lovely bhangra-trance music playing (not too loud which was great and added a little ambiance), counter attendant was very friendly, smiling and recommended the Be Green Curry, take out order was delivered by another staff person who came out from the back and handed me the bag, (nice service touch). The food was okay, could have used a few more vegetables in it, the Curry is this seemed to be a combo of one part Chicken Saag (spinach puree) and one part Butter Chicken (cream tomato sauce), which was placed side by side, I would recommended to keep the Saag by itself, touch it up with a few more side veggies, throw in a small slice of Naan into the container as well. Taste wise, it was okay, not the greatest, but certainly not the worst either. Would love to see this place develop a little more in the food area, however I can say I was impressed with the cleanliness and the staff. I think too that the price is a little steep but if they added more to it, it would be fine for a quick lunch.
 
 Food Service Value 
 Was this review helpful?
 2 / 3 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Food Score = 2 out of 10 By ksuleman of Yaletown (10 Reviews) Submitted Wednesday, October 27, 2010 - 10:11pm [Take-out] 
This is a new funky progressive fast food Indian eatery right in the hub of where there must now be some 8+ other smaller restaurants. Being an Indian, I walked by this restaurant several times enroute to my son&apos;s daycare and I finally made a stop for a takeout. I asked the server what is the most flavorful menu item and I was informed the Butter Chicken and the Bhiryani, so I ordered the Butter Chicken. If you have had Indian food before then you will be dearly disappointed with this Butter Chicken, no flavor and very bland. Not to mention, there seemed more rice than butter chicken. If you are looking for great butter chicken, go to Atithi&apos;s on Burrard.
 
 Food Service Value 
 Was this review helpful?
 10 / 12 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
&lt; More reviews below advertisement &gt;
 low quantity By sagarr of VANCOUVER, ROBSON STREET (1 Review) Submitted Sunday, June 5, 2011 - 5:33pm [Take-out] 
I went in to this restaurant after picking up my wife after her job. we ate about 7 difffernt dishes and i should say over all it was ok . But the quantity of food they provided was too low.i am satisfied with their service.I would like it if they increase the quantity of food.
 
 Food Service Value 
 Was this review helpful?
 85 / 86 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Give It a Try By Love2Eat_VanCity of Vancouver (downtown) (1 Review) Submitted Sunday, November 14, 2010 - 2:00pm [Dine in] 
I work downtown and I was walking by the Library one day when I walked past this new restaurant I had never heard of before called Rasoee&apos;s. There was a girl outside giving free samples of their naan bread along with a menu. I took a menu and a sample and I quite liked the taste of their sample naan. I looked through their menu and decided I would give it a try when I was off work. When I arrived I was greeted by their friendly staff that offered to answer any questions I may have about the menu. I ended up getting the curry spiced chicken combo with naan bread and some water. I waited under ten minutes for my food and when it came I was pleased with the portion size. It came with rice and the curry on top and my naan bread on the side. I was pleasantly surprised by how good everything tasted too. At the end of my meal I was quite satisfied and had decided that this was a place I would come back to in the future. I have since been back a few times and have never been disappointed with the service or the food. I recommend it to people that want to try something a little bit out of the ordinary that is still delicious.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 4 / 8 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Awesome new Indian fusion restaurant By yummy mummy of Vancouver (downtown) (1 Review) Submitted Friday, October 22, 2010 - 9:20pm [Dine in] 
The atmosphere of the &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant really impressed me. The decor was very chic and welcoming. I loved the colors and comfy feel of the place. The service was incredible, they were so friendly and helpful. I had the butter chicken with Naan and my husband had the tandoori chicken and fries. The kids even enjoyed their dishes as well. It was very delicious and a good value, we would definitely go back there again.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 2 / 7 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
Images
 Displaying 1 - 2 of 2 Images Found 
Tips
 Displaying 2 Foursquare Tips 
 Chris R. : ...but it is not bad for Canadian pizza. 1 year 13 weeks ago Chris R. : Worst pizza ever lol 1 year 13 weeks ago 
 
Twitter
 Displaying 50 Relevant Tweets 
 Rasoee Are you an Art Student who would love to showcase their art? Contact @ Rasoee for info about providing you space at our #UBC location :-) 5 hours 2 min ago Rasoee Come join us today and tomorrow for the Grand Opening of @ Rasoee on 1680 Robson St. Live entertainment&amp;prizes to be given away #RGO1680 6 hours 42 min ago Rasoee THE FIRST 100 PEOPLE @ Rasoee Grand Opening today will receive a #FREE YOGA CLASS to @ YYoga &apos;s NEW Location in Kits! #RGO1680 #Vancouver 6 hours 43 min ago chocoaeggie @ HealthCastleIan @ Rasoee it was delicious!! Had it for dinner but I believe their menu is available all day! ^-^ 7 hours 11 min ago HealthCastleIan @ chocoaeggie Hey, looks good. Was that lunch? @ Rasoee 7 hours 41 min ago Rasoee @ wwong17 @ bombaybrowbar Great shot! You&apos;ve been entered - good luck and Curry ON! #RGO1680 7 hours 52 min ago vanfoodies West end location at Bidwell...RT @ DianneChow Celebrate @ Rasoee Grand Opening on Robson from July 11-13: t.co/DKbjQQbZ 8 hours 41 sec ago Rasoee Day 1 of #RGO1680 complete. Looking forward to Day 2 of the 1680 Robson St Grand Opening of Rasoee. Don&apos;t miss out on the fun tomorrow :) 19 hours 12 min ago wwong17 @ Rasoee @ bombaybrowbar Keep Calm&amp;Curry On!! #currylove t.co/EJnbVHqh 19 hours 48 min ago Rasoee Thank you! Would love to catch up soon xo &quot;@ SocialBites : @ Rasoee will def stop by soon! Very excited for u!!&quot; 20 hours 9 sec ago SocialBites @ Rasoee will def stop by soon! Very excited for u!! 20 hours 1 min ago Rasoee @ SocialBites Thanks Annika! Hope to see you there this week :-) #RGO1680 #Vancouver 20 hours 4 min ago SocialBites Congrats to our supporter @ Rasoee for opening another yummy curry location on Robson in the Westend! Grand opening until Fri! 20 hours 7 min ago indulgendance Congrats to our supporter @ Rasoee for opening another yummy curry location on Robson in the Westend! Grand opening until Fri! 20 hours 7 min ago chocoaeggie Grand Opening- my 2nd time today @ Rasoee !! :p Yummyyyy~♡ @ Rasoee t.co/mjDZVbFk 21 hours 46 min ago Rasoee @ Rasoee at 1680 Robson is preparing some yummy samples of Sweet Pea and Butter Chicken! #RGO1680 #Vancouver t.co/oi9orwlo 22 hours 51 min ago chocoaeggie Rasoee&apos;s West End Grand Opening goodies! Thank you @ Rasoee ! ^-^☆ #RGO1680 t.co/CyL9UP48 23 hours 47 min ago Rasoee @ eventlikevancty We&apos;re sampling our menu during the Grand Opening! Come down and get your curry groove on! #RGO1680 1 day 23 min ago VancouverPicks Latest buzz for Rasoee: t.co/59aYRPEf - RT @ eventlikevancty The new @ Rasoee Restaurant at 1680 Robson St is now open! Looks like ... 1 day 29 min ago Rasoee Feel free to call and ask when we open in August :-)&quot;@ GaelenN : @ rasoee Had to ask. your new west station store is about a 10 minute drive&quot; 1 day 29 min ago GaelenN @ rasoee Had to ask. your new west station store is about a 10 minute drive, but sometimes I just like delivery haha 1 day 42 min ago Rasoee @ GaelenN Not at this time. We&apos;re always expanding...so stay tuned, you never know. 1 day 44 min ago eventlikevancty The new @ Rasoee Restaurant at 1680 Robson St is now open! Looks like a place we will have to check out! 1 day 50 min ago GaelenN @ rasoee do you deliver to #coquitlam? 1 day 1 hour ago Rasoee Treat yourself to a relaxing night in by ordering @ Rasoee to your doorstep after 5pm. Visit t.co/5IG6TDN3 for the menu. #currylove 1 day 1 hour ago chocoaeggie Grand opening fun! @ Rasoee (@ Rasoee) [pic]: t.co/vVpsn84I 1 day 3 hours ago Rasoee Don&apos;t forget to snap a picture of yourself at the @ Rasoee #westend Grand Opening today in order to enter to win a @ Bombaybrowbar gift card 1 day 3 hours ago Rasoee It&apos;s @ Rasoee GO so curry of course! :-) &quot;@ VANEATSca : Whats everyone eating for lunch today?&quot; 1 day 4 hours ago Rasoee @ 24hoursvan @ MetroVancouver @ CTVBC @ CBCCommunity Check out @ Rasoee 1680 Grand Opening!#RGO1680 t.co/q9ReWX7q t.co/kGzewPAq 1 day 4 hours ago supervancouver The @ Rasoee Indian Kitchen grand opening party with music and prizes is at 1680 Robson in Vancouver now t.co/d3oJ55L2 1 day 4 hours ago Rasoee Ha! That&apos;s awesome...#MiniCooper is the new high bar for hotness! &quot;@ danudey : @ Rasoee @ MINIYaletown I&apos;d hit it.&quot; 1 day 4 hours ago erin_ireland let the @ rasoee robson street grand opening party begin! nice mini coopers t.co/EfZgdyj9 1 day 4 hours ago danudey @ Rasoee @ MINIYaletown I&apos;d hit it. 1 day 4 hours ago Rasoee See you then :-)&quot;@ wwong17 : Congrats! Coming by after work! RT @ Rasoee &apos;s 1680 Robson St Grand Opening today. Drop by for live entertainment&quot; 1 day 4 hours ago Rasoee Okay one more...have you seen how sexy the new #2012MiniCoppers are?!? HOT @ MINIYaletown #RGO1680 #Vancouver t.co/AHSGic1R 1 day 4 hours ago Rasoee Whooot! #RGO1680 #Vancouver @ Rasoee t.co/39Ip664t 1 day 5 hours ago Rasoee @ Rasoee loves @ MINIYaletown !!! #RGO1680 #Vancouver Let the party begin! t.co/SXZdE7NF 1 day 5 hours ago Rasoee Enter to #Win this gorgeous silk arrangement from Heather&apos;s Flowershop! @ Rasoee Grand Opening 1680 Robson #Vancouver t.co/l45ZsqW3 1 day 5 hours ago MINIYaletown @ Rasoee - check out the all new 2012 #MINI Cooper S Coupè at the new Rasoee Red location grand opening all day today! t.co/xCtOpUqF 1 day 5 hours ago wwong17 Congrats! Coming by after work! RT @ Rasoee &apos;s 1680 Robson St Grand Opening today. Drop by for live entertainment and hundreds of prizes :) 1 day 5 hours ago SpudShackca @ weskoop @ stickers66 Thanks, #Rasoee 1 day 5 hours ago Rasoee #Vancouver wait till you see what @ MINIYaletown has created for @ Rasoee Grand Opening! The party starts in 30 minutes 1680 Robson. #RGO1680 1 day 6 hours ago Rasoee Spreading the #currylove @ Rasoee &apos;s 1680 Robson St Grand Opening today. Drop by for live entertainment and hundreds of prizes :) 1 day 6 hours ago JACKSONMICKAEL Chhoda Jaai Rasoee Mein | Mazaa Bas Raat Mein Aave - Bhojpuri Video Song...: t.co/Krla1jwp via @ youtube 1 day 9 hours ago Apples1Oranges @ Rasoee Let&apos;s keep the party and spotlight going with a @ tiktok deal! We&apos;re partying with you! #Vancouver 1 day 14 hours ago Rasoee Lovely to have you! Curry ON :)&quot;@ EatWhatWhere : Going to try @ Rasoee for the first time. I&apos;ve heard very good things. Details to follow.&quot; 1 day 21 hours ago Rasoee Our 1680 Robson St Grand Opening kicks off tomorrow. Enjoy live entertainment, hundreds of prizes :) #currylove #RGO1680 1 day 21 hours ago EatWhatWhere Going to try @ Rasoee for the first time. I&apos;ve heard very good things. Details to follow. 1 day 22 hours ago Rasoee Don&apos;t forget to tweet a picture of yourself @ Rasoee &apos;s #westend Grand Opening tomorrow to enter to win a gift card from @ Bombaybrowbar ;) 2 days 12 min ago tiktok @ rasoee We got your flyer! Let&apos;s &apos;tok&apos; TikTok. @ MarleyHolowach has some even better ways to get your offers out...and it&apos;s all free! 2 days 30 min ago 
   Map and directions 
 Vancouver Entertainment Book 
 Up to $26 off when you buy the new 2012 Vancouver Entertainment Book. Free Shipping. 
Other Locations
 
 1. Gastown (650 m) 2. West 8th Ave (1.7 km) 3. Robson&amp;Bidwell (1.8 km) 4. UBC (9.4 km) 5. 100 SE Anderson Road (670.5 km) 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 
 1. Wraps Plus (20 m) 2. Wrap Plus (21 m) 3. Blenz Coffee (25 m) 4. McDonald&apos;s (26 m) 5. Salad Loop (27 m) 6. Flying Wedge Pizza Co. (27 m) 7. Kamiya Japanese Restaurant (28 m) 8. Gutenberg&apos;s Cafe (28 m) 9. Amore Pizza (32 m) 10. Rosie&apos;s on Robson (32 m) 
   
 Restaurants Opening Soon New Restaurants Updated Restaurants 

 Support Review Guide FAQ News 

 Socialize Facebook Twitter Google + 

 Corporate Contact Advertise 
 Copyright©2004-2011
	</body>
</document>
