<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008425" url="http://www.dnanpa.com/dnanpa/VideoList.php?selection=21" time="2012-07-13-01:53" support="1" score="0.0005512351935473196" bingtitle="Video List - This Web site coming soon" webtitle="Video List">
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>If there are more than 100 videos in your selection ... Remember when you had a radio controlled car and ... transit, giving away gifts, and eating at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Nanpa&apos;s Place - The Source for Videos from the Orient

 
 
 Videos | How to Order | FAQ | Customer Reviews | Release Form | Video Classifications | Home 
 
In the following table, the symbol indicates that this video is one of Nanpa&apos;s favorites and the symbol indicates that the master copy of the video is on DVD assuring you of the highest video quality. All of the videos delivered to you will be in DVD format.

If there are more than 100 videos in your selection, navigation symbols appear before and after the table that you can use to see more pages.
 
 


 
 
 

 Video Cost Description R-903 Best of Vibrators in Public Was $45 Now on sale for $40 The economy is a bit soft in Japan lately as well, so many producers are simply putting out &quot;best-of&quot; videos. This one features a number of ladies who are vibrated/dildoed into incredibly wet orgasism in very public places. First are somes pretty OL who straps on a huge remote control vibrator strapped to their pussy and are sent out in the busy streets and shops of Tokyo. Their orgasisms are intense! Then there are some scenes of a woman whose head is outside of a van traveling through the streets of Tokyo. She is blasting out some advertising gut inside the van, one guy is going to town with her &quot;nether&quot; regions. Next up, the ladies drop their panties and take a seat in a wheel chair with a hidden dildo. As the wheel chair moves, the dildo goes up and down. Finally some scenes with a lady DJ doing some radio from a street booth while (not too surprising at this point) she is completely exposed from the waist down. The use of hidden camera make this video superb. [Soft on Demand - SDMT-136](240 minutes) R-832 Nopan/Nobra Waitress Was $40 Now on sale for $35 In Japan, to be Nopan means to be commando - no panties. In this video, a 20 year old waitress who is in need of her job is bullied by her boss - first to get a blow job but then to serve her customers in increasingly humiliating clothing, eventually ending up nopan. We first see her as a waitress in a traditional Japanese restaurant. People it on the floor at low tables. The waitress is wearing a non-descript pants and blouse. Her bosses first demand is that she insert a remote control vibrator which he controls from a hidden location. If that wasn&apos;t hard enough, her boss next takes a scissor to her pants cutting out the bottom to fully expose her panties. Now she has to try to maneuver around the room so that her back is never to a customer. (Of course, the vibrator is still humming.) Cusotmers keep arriving, men and women and she is running out of places to keep her back hidden. Next, her boss insists that she removes her pants, then her panties leaving her with only her blouse and apron covering her. Next, he gives her back her pants (but not the panties) and sends her back to work. By this point, one of the customers is pretty drunk so she accompanies him to the mens room and provides some &quot;full service&quot; there. Another customer is too far gone to make it to the men&apos;s room, so she is ordered to help him out at the table. She has to service him while trying to hide her bottom which is sticking out the back of her pants and visible to other customers. The whole situation is then repeated with another waitress wannabe, but this time, her boss cuts out big circles in her blouse, exposing her nipples. Eventually, she also loses her pants and panties. Women&apos;s work is never done! A good video if you have ever had any fantasies about your waitress! [Hunter - Hunt-208](135 minutes) R-786 Embarassed Clerk Was $40 Now on sale for $35 One of my favorite fantasy stories from the net is &quot;Ted&apos;s Revenge&quot; which has a scene where a lady is stripped from the waist down while acting as a clerk at a 7-11 type of store. This video is a bit similar - not as much as I had hoped, but still quite good. There are two similar scenes. It starts with a young (20 years old) lady being interviewed for the clerks job. She must be pretty desperate for a job, because she gives the owner a quick hand/blow job. Next we see her working at the store wearing a smock and jeans when the owner arrives and insists that she insert a remote control vibrator while kneeling behind the counter. He then torments her while she does her best to do her job. The owner decides that she needs a bit more humiliation and so goes to work on her jeans with a scissor, cutting out the seat and one leg and makes her continue to serve customers in that state. Next, he makes her strip off her own jeans, and then he strips her of her panties.My favorite parts of the video are when her customers ask her to get a pack of cigarettes which forces her to back away from the counter and expose that she is bottomless. He further humiliates her by cutting out holes in her smock that permit her nipples to poke out, and then makes her give him another blow job behind the counter.[Hunter - HUNT-157](135 minutes) R-773 Naked in the Game Center Was $40 Now on sale for $35 If you&apos;ve been to Japan, you have certainly run across the neighborhood pachinko parlor which now also has a number of other video games. What is particularly striking is the zombie-like state that all of the people there are in as they play their games. A naked woman could be in there and nobody would notice -or would they? In this video a few ladies are brought into such a place to test this. The first lady walks through wearing a cut off jeans that expose her panties and gets no reaction. Next, they insert a remote contol vibrating dildo and she sits down between two guys to play a gmae. Will they notice an orgasming woman next to them? Well, one guy detects something and moves to another seat. The other guy is oblivious, so our lady decides to get a bit more aggressive with him and while he plays away, she gropes him a bit and gets scolded for it. Next, she puts on a see-through body suit walks through and gets no reaction. Finally, she finds a businessman who will permit her to give him a hand job. How considerate! Finally, she strips down and plays a game buck naked. This time she is again successful in dragging a guy away from his games and gives him a blow job. A second lady goes through a similar trial. [Hunter - HUNT-141](120 minutes) R-772 Dissolving Bikinis in a Pool Was $40 Now on sale for $35 Lately there have been a number of videos featuring clothing that disolves in water. As this video opens, we find the braintrust of Soft on Demand experimenting with that material, timing how long it takes to dissolve and designing new bikinis based upon it. Then they hire three ladies to model their designs (no dressing rooms in the labs!) and we are set to make a video. 4 ladies are offered the opportunity to wear this new bikini to an indoor public pool in Japan and each are given &quot;missions&quot; to perform in the pool. In the first case, they have to callenge a guy to a playful sumo-type matc, then with their bikini vanishing have to ask someone to put on some tanning oil. Finally, she has to ride the water slide to the middle of the pool. By the time she is done, the only thing left of the bikini is the outline of the strings that held the cloth up! This all takes place in a very public venue. Her run to the dressing room is very embarrassing. She is really turned on by this and is talked into putting on yet another bikini (a real one), but this time has to insert a dildo like vibrator (radio controlled of course) before heading back out to the pool where she has to perform a number of normal tasks (ordering and eating some food) while trying to maintain her dignity in such a public place. The other 3 ladies go through similar trials. There is no sex in this video - just a lot of delightfully embarassing scenes. [Soft on Demand - SDMS-503](140 minutes) R-754 Domination Date - Greeting the Delivery Men Was $40 Now on sale for $35 This is an interesting video, but one that is hard to describe. It begins with a woman being talked into following a guy home and once there, is talked into performing some pretty strange dares. First, she changes from her regular clothes (in full view of the camera) into a see through (and poke through) leotard. Next, she phones for the landlord to come and fix her door and while waiting for hime, the guy fools around with a remote control vibrator.When the landlord arrives, she has to greet him and hang about dressed in her filmy outfit and trying to put up with the vibator, She tries to offer him some sex as payment for his work, but the guy refuses. Next, she is convinced to change out of her leotard and exchange it for a towel the can barely cover her front. Yet, even then her companion is not satisfied and shortens it with a scissor. A delivery man arrives and she answers the door with only the towel for cover. She owes on the package and tries to fetch the payment from her pocket book and sign for the package while holding onto the towel. For his trouble, he is rewarded with a hand job. Finally, she exhanges her towel for a frying pan. (I told you it was hard to explain!) Once more, she has to answer the door, dressed in her birthday suit and a frying pan to accept a food delivery. The tip this time is a blow job. A sequence involving the domination of another woman follow involving a bit less treats for the delivery men, but an equal amount of sex and exposure. Very interesting. [Hunter - HUNT-126](150 minutes) R-738 Naked at the Laundromat Was $40 Now on sale for $35 Here is another odd video from those crazy people in Japan. It begins with a lady showing up for a job interview at an adult video producer. She is told what is expected of her for the day and then has a quick audition consisting of giving a guy a quick blow job. It happens so quickly that she doesn&apos;t even undress - which is a bit of a problem since the guy spews all over her blouse, so we take a trip to the local landromat. There, the director convinces her to toss all of her clothes into the washing machine. He gives her a t-shirt and jeans to wear while her regular clothes are being cleaned, but we do see her take off her outer clothing in a public place. She then slips off her bra from beneath a tight t-shirt and the director converts her tight jeans into a very tiny miniskirt with a scissor. He then decides that her t-shirt would look a bit better if he cut off the bottom half. Just to make the lady feel a bit more uncomfortable, he gives her a remote controlled vibrator to put into her panties. Finally, she gets to start the washing machine, but at the same time another patron has entered the laundry. She is faced with the embarrassment of being quit exposed and having the vibrator randomly turned on from outside the laundry. After that patron leaves, the director returns and makes the lady strip out of all of her clothes - panties and all and change into a nearly transparent leotard. Another patron enters and she has to stand there in a rather exposing outfit. By telephone, she is ordered to offer the guy a hand job which is is happy to accept - oops more soiled clothing! The leotard comes off and she gets a towel to wear instead, but that seems to be way too modest, so the director steals that, leaving her naked. Yet another patron arrives and enjoys the benefit of having a naked lady trying to hide behind the transparent door of a drier. With only her hands for cover, she waits for the washer to finally finish and to help pass the time, she offers a blow job. Then the whole scene repeats with another attractive lady who ends up going all the way. A very unique and interesting video! [Hunter - HUNT-114](150 minutes) R-715 Blackmail! Was $40 Now on sale for $35 This is an odd little video (which ones aren&apos;t?). Many young ladies participate in some adult videos - especially like the ones on this site that may involve stripping or nudity, but not necessarily a lot of sex. After doing a video or two, they leave the business and go off to do other things with their life. While there is no strict societal stigma attached to acting in an adult video, it probably isn&apos;t something you&apos;d like all of your co-workers to know. In this video 4 loyal SOD customers select a lady that they liked in an earlier video and show up at her new job with a copy of the video. When the lady sees the video, she is pretty much sure to do whatever the guys asks to keep it quiet. The first guy finds his favorite working in as a hair stylist. He makes an appointment with her, and when he springs the blackmail and gets the lady to do his shampoo and cut while he controls a remote control vibrator. (Something I don&apos;t think I&apos;d ever want to try.) The second guy finds his favorite lady working as a nurses assistant at a health care facility. He gets her to wear the vibrator while she is assiting elderly people at the facility (peeing and bathing - how nice it much be in Japan to get old and have chicks help you our with the essentials.) The last guy finds his favorite lady working at a men&apos;s clothing store. In all three cases, they get together after work for some non-vibrator assisted fun. [Soft on Demand - SDMS-513](140 minutes) R-678 Remote Vibrator Challege Was $40 Now on sale for $35 It has been a while since a good vibrator challenge video has been added. Here three of attractive ladies have been challenged to strip down, have a remote control vibrator of some sort placed on/in them and then they have to get dressed again and go out in a public area where they have to walk a couple of blocks to a store and back. In the first case, the lady is wearing a long skirt and no panties when she goes out and not only has the vibrator strapped in her, but has a video camera strapped to the inside of her thigh, pointing directly up. There are a few cameramen on the street and she is carrying a stuffed animal with a camera inside to capture close-ups of her face when the vibrator is turned on. When she makes it back to the studio, she is so horny, that sex with the producer is a sure thing. The next two ladies go through similar challenges, but without the thigh camera. There can be little doubt that all of the ladies are brought to multiple, often noisy climaxes on the busy streets of Tokyo. [Soft on Demand - SMDS-438](135 minutes) R-662 Towel Dares Was $45 Now on sale for $40 I have a number of videos on this site featuring ladies wearing only very thin towels in a hot spring bath - of course it is a men&apos;s bath ;-) - but the ladies feel a bit comfortable because it is the appropriate clothing to wear at a hot spring. Things are different in this Soft on Demand extravaganza. Once again, it starts in the workplace where we find the SOD staff hard at work planning their next video releases. But, 6 of the ladies are called away from their desks and get that sinking feeling when they find Myu and some cameramen waiting for them. This time, the ladies have to strip down in full view, with only the thinnest of towels for cover. Next, they have to strap on remote control vibrators and try to hide from a bunch of guys who are searching for them in the building. When they are found - anything goes. After about 2 hours, another video seems to start up - a celebration of some sort within the company. Lots of people drinking and getting drunk. Inhibitions are lowered, some silly games are played (separating ladies from their clothes) and once again, anything goes. Sometimes it seems to me as if SOD simply turns on the video camera, records what happens at work and sells the result for the next month. These people are insatiable! [Soft on Demand - SDMS-404](270 minutes) R-654 The Invisible Man (Part 7) Was $40 Now on sale for $35 After the lovely ladies, what I love most about Japanese AV is how inventive they are. Sure there is enough of the old in and out, but they enjoy setting up fun and interesting scenes. This video features 4 scenes involving &quot;invisible men&quot;. Actually, guy who are completely covered (well almost completely covered) in a white body suit that has been used for hundreds of years to indicate ghosts and other invisibiel creatures in Japanese theater. The first scene finds us at a ski resort in Japan. Two guys are trying (and failing) to ski take a break at a vending machine where they find a drink they have never seen before. When they drink it - they notice that they have become invisible! They spy two ladies who are also taking a break and they harrass the ladies both by groping them and by having things they are holding move without any visible cause. It quickly escalates and they take full advantage of them. In the next scene, a plumber is fixing the kitchen sink in a Japanese home. When he is done, the housewife thanks him and he is very attracted to her. He stops for a snack at the local vending machine, finds the same potion and he heads back to the apartment for some R&amp;R;, enjoying the pleasures of the miniskirted lady as she tries to get her housework done. The third scene takes place at a local bar, where two somewhat drunk ladies try to play darts when they are attacked by an invisible force. In the final scene, four ladies are heading to school when the invisible man catches up to them in the street, and enjoys some gropes, some skirt lifting, At school, there are 3 more invisible men waiting to sample the goods. The teacher walks in to find 4 of her students seemingly felating nothing. She sends them off to the nurses office and so is left alone with the 4 invisible men. You&apos;ve got to love this stuff! [V&amp;R;VSPDS-318](116 minutes) R-439 Radio Controlled Girls Was $40 Now on sale for $35 Remember when you had a radio controlled car and you would day dream about being able to control everything in the world - bullies, teachers, ... pretty girls? Well here is the movie to capture the fantasy. A couple of guys in the R/C club at school discover that their control console works through head phones and permits them to control whoever is wearing them. First, a classmate is &quot;forced&quot; to pull up the teachers skirt (much to her surprise). Then a lady walking her dog is he next victim, the servos used to have her strip off her panties in the park, lift her leg and take a wiz just like her dog would. Next, a student in a sailor suit is made to flash her panties in the park and jill off much to the delight of some onlookers. Next, a food delivery lady is made to strip and ride around the city in her undies and then really provide some customer satisfaction! Finally, my favorite part - a young lady who was about to use a public bath (separated by gender) has the headphones put on and suddenly finds herself forced into the men&apos;s section! There, she is forced to strip down, bathe, was the guy&apos;s backs. Then our hero finds a few more headphones and takes control of the women&apos;s side of the bath as well, getting 3 ladies to not only race like his car, but also make him very, very happy. Later, back in school, the R/C club continues with their hi jinks. A triumph! [V&amp;R;VSPDS-181](120 minutes) R-419 Remote Control Vibrator Office Was $30 Now on sale for $25 This video has the feel of a theatrical release. Two young ladies work in an office in fairly typical jobs for young ladies in Japan - &quot;office flowers&quot;. One of the ladies appears to be a sex addict, working in a massage parlor after her normal working hours. Her boy friend seems to have a powerful control over her, and orders her to purchase a remote control vibrator, insert it on the street in broad daylight and leave the control unit for the boyfriend. She later recruits her coworkers into the world of remote control vibration. There are a few terrific scenes as one is vibrated while practicing at a driving range, and then together in a bar. [Flower Works - RRR-05](75 minutes) R-325 Remote Control Vibrator Club Going Was $30 Now on sale for $25 Actually, in Japan when they say going, they mean &quot;coming&quot;. This video features 6 very perky ladies. Each gets to pick her vibrator of choice, then they all head out for a little adventure. The hang out near a train exit, restaurant entrance and other very busy places, then each lady in turn is set out with a mission - get someone to take a picture of them. They also attend a funeral and a job interview - in all cases the various vibrators are randomly turned on and off requiring the ladies to try to do their best to maintain some composure. [Soft on Demand - SDDM-553](90 minutes) R-295 Remote Control Vibrators at the Cabaret Was $40 Now on sale for $35 Cabarets in Japan are like nothing in the world. The typical one is staffed by a number of ladies of all ages, but they are all dressed nicely and are focused on keeping their patrons happy. Men go there after work and expect to drink a little, and flirt with the ladies. And the ladies go along with everything - lighting the guy&apos;s cigarettes, keeping their drink full, laughing at their jokes, commiserating with the men on the problems they have with their wife etc. So it is not very odd for the patrons to ask them to try out a new remote control vibrator. After the ladies agree, they find out that this isn&apos;t your ordinary vibrator, but rather the deluxe edition that consists of a base and a dildo for maximum arousal. With the ladies dripping wet and horny, things progress as you might expect. (Next 11 - VNDS-1054)(120 minutes) R-93 Remote Control Vibrators 2 Was $40 Now on sale for $35 This tape features many ladies, one at a time who are outfitted with remote control vibrators in their panties and taken for a walk and out to lunch while their guy randomly turns on the vibrator when they least expect it. Kind of cute idea. [Shuttle Japan TB-01, TB-02](120 minutes) R-84 Remote Control Vibrators Was $40 Now on sale for $35 This is a two tape set. A dozen or so ladies are hired to be &quot;campaign girls&quot;. These are girls that you find in every major Japanese city who stand on the streets and hand out free cigarettes, beer, tissues, etc. all with a little advertising on it. They are generally very attractive and dressed in mini skirts and heels. In this tape, which was shot in real time in the course of an afternoon, the girls are also wearing panties that have a remote control vibrator inside. After a day of riding public transit, giving away gifts, and eating at a fast food restaurant, every now and then having the little hummer go off right outside the gates to heaven, these ladies are really horny! [Obtain Future REM-001, REM-002](180 minutes) 
 
 


 
 
 Videos | How to Order | FAQ | Customer Reviews | Release Form | Video Classifications | Home
	</body>
</document>
