<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008407" url="http://louises.com/catering.html" time="2012-07-13-01:53" support="1" score="0.004271819766251171" bingtitle="Louise&apos;s Trattoria Catering" webtitle="Louise&apos;s Trattoria Catering">
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>Food is not the only thing we do, it’s just the ... Sign up for Louise&apos;s Insider&apos;s E-Club to receive emails ... The Classic Catering Menu | Go to the Classic Catering ...</description>
	<body>
		Corey Lawson (310) 475-5575 
Louise’s Director of Catering Services 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
For over 30 years now, Louise’s Trattoria has been a Los Angeles tradition for Italian food. Respected by our private and corporate clientele alike, it’s no wonder we are considered one of L.A.’s leading caterers. Our first name may be Italian, but you will find that our cuisine has a Californian flare!

Food is not the only thing we do, it’s just the beginning! Our special events and catering department offers a variety of services including corporate catering, private parties, as well as full service catering, from birthdays to weddings. Service, great food and ambiance are our goals every time, whether it’s a simple delivery for 10 guests or an event for 10,000.

You can call or email us with any questions that you have about your upcoming event. Or simply click on the link below to fill out our Event Inquiry Form and we will promptly get back to you. We would love to put together your custom quote!

 TELL US ABOUT YOUR EVENT 

 Check out our reviews on WeddingWire.com 
 
 Sign up for Louise&apos;s Insider&apos;s E-Club to receive emails with special offers! 
 ©Louise&apos;s Trattoria. All Rights Reserved. | Legal Notice | Site by Tornado Design 
 The Classic Catering Menu | Go to the Classic Catering Menu 
Our full Restaurant menu available in larger quantities. With over 10,000 of these orders delivered annually, Louise&apos;s Classic Catering Menu is always sure to please the crowd and make the host look great!

 Louise’s Business Catering | Go to Business Catering 
The backbone of our Catering operation. Serving lunch and dinner daily to offices across LA, Louise’s provides great food, in the right quantities, at amazingly reasonable prices.

 Formal Affairs | Go to Formal Affairs 
Another of our core Catering services with which we are well experienced! Weddings, Bar Mitzvahs, Sweet 16’s, Quinceañera, and Memorial Services hold a very special importance to our clients, so we treat you with the respect that you deserve!

 Pharmaceutical Representatives 
You’ve found a home! We understand the unique needs of your business. Give our friendly catering staff a call at (310) 475-5575 and find out what we can offer you and your clients.
Or fill out our contact form and we&apos;ll get back to you with more info.

 House Accounts | Go to House Accounts 
Very popular with businesses that require food on site often. The convenience of Louise’s service, great tasting food, priority delivery status, and standardized monthly billing provide you the luxury of knowing that your needs will always be met, just the way you want it!
	</body>
</document>
