<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008922" url="http://www.thefreelibrary.com/Living+large%3a+the+scoop+on+ice+cream+shops.+(Cover+Story).-a0106471691" time="2012-07-13-02:20" support="2" score="0.0023809424089130432" bingtitle="Living large: the scoop on ice cream shops. (Cover Story). - Free ..." webtitle="Living large: the scoop on ice cream shops. (Cover Story). - Free Online Library">
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>Free Online Library: Living large: the scoop on ice cream shops. (Cover Story). by &quot;Nutrition ... also known as DQ) is an ice-cream shop and fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Printer Friendly 
19,791,913 articles and books Periodicals Literature Keyword Title Author Topic 
 Member login User name    Password     Remember me 
 Join us   Forgot password? 
 The Free Library &gt; Health&gt;  Food/cooking/nutrition &gt;  Nutrition Action Healthletter &gt;  July 1, 2003 The Free Library &gt;  Date &gt;  2003 &gt;  July &gt;  1 &gt;  Nutrition Action Healthletter 
 
Living large: the scoop on ice cream shops. (Cover Story).

In 1904, at the St. Louis World&apos;s Fair world&apos;s fair:  see exposition. world&apos;s fair 

Specially constructed attraction showcasing the science, technology, and culture of participating countries and enterprises. , an ice cream vendor
ran out of dishes. Ernest Hamwi, a Syrian concessionaire next door,
rolled one of his wafer-like waffles into a cone shape and offered it to
his neighbor.

A century later, you don&apos;t have to wait for a World&apos;s
Fair to buy ice cream cones An ice cream cone or cornet is a cone-shaped pastry, usually made of a wafer similar in texture to a waffle, in which ice cream is served, allowing it to be eaten without a bowl or spoon. . Every shopping mall, amusement park amusement park,  a commercially operated park offering various forms of entertainment, such as arcade games, carousels, roller coasters, and performers, as well as food, drink, and souvenirs. ,
airport terminal, and neighborhood features at least one &quot;scoop
shop.&quot; And the dazzling larger-than-life-size dishes displayed on
menus, countertops, and posters make a single-scoop cone look puny pu·ny  
 adj. pu·ni·er , pu·ni·est 
 1. Of inferior size, strength, or significance; weak: a puny physique; puny excuses. 

 2. Chiefly Southern U.S. Sickly; ill. .

What used to be a 150-calorie treat has mutated into a
500-to-1,200-calorie indulgence indulgence,  in the Roman Catholic Church, the pardon of temporal punishment due for sin. It is to be distinguished from absolution and the forgiveness of guilt. The church grants indulgences out of the Treasury of Merit won for the church by Christ and the saints. . Saturated fat saturated fat,  any solid fat that is an ester of glycerol and a saturated fatty acid. The molecules of a saturated fat have only single bonds between carbon atoms; if double bonds are present in the fatty acid portion of the molecule, the fat is said to be ? Don&apos;t ask.

If your freezer is like those in 90 percent of American households,
it&apos;s got ice cream or another frozen dessert wedged wedged - 1. To be stuck, incapable of proceeding without help. This is different from having crashed. If the system has crashed, it has become totally non-functioning. If the system is wedged, it is trying to do something but cannot make progress; it may be capable of doing a few  between the OJ
concentrate and the frozen vegetables Frozen vegatables (also freeze-dried vegetables ) are commercially packaged vegetables that are sold in the frozen section of the store, usually packaged in either rectangular boxes or plastic bags. .

But more than six out of every ten dollars spent on ice cream are
spent away from home, much of it at chains like Baskin-Robbins and
Haagen-Dazs or at vestiges of 1950s ice cream parlors Ice cream parlors are places that sell ice cream and frozen yogurt to consumers. Ice cream is normally sold in two varieties in these stores: soft-serve ice cream (normally with just chocolate, vanilla, and &quot;twist&quot;, a mix of the two), and hard-packed, which has an assortment of  like
Friendly&apos;s or Swensen&apos;s. And as cones, shakes, and sundaes
grow, so do the people who eat them.

In the race to outdo their competitors, ice-cream-sellers
can&apos;t resist the temptation to build bigger belly traps. It&apos;s
not just regular ice cream, but super-premium, not just one scoop, but
two or three. It&apos;s not just a cone, but a chocolate-dipped waffle See WAFL.  cone. It&apos;s not just hot fudge Hot Fudge , a.k.a. The Hot Fudge Show , was an American children&apos;s television series that aired in syndication from 1976 to 1980. The series was produced in Detroit at WXYZ-TV. , nuts, and whipped cream, but every imaginable i·mag·i·na·ble  
 adj. 
Conceivable in the imagination: imaginable exploits. 

 
 i·mag  variety of cookie cookie 

File or part of a file put on a Web user&apos;s hard disk by a Web site. Cookies are used to store registration data, to make it possible to customize information for visitors to a Web site, to target Web advertising, and to keep track of the products a user wishes to , candy, and chocolate, from gummy bears For the show based on the candy, see .

A Gummy bear is a small, rubbery-textured confectionery, roughly 1 centimeter long, shaped in the form of a bear. History  to Reese&apos;s Pieces Reese&apos;s Pieces are a peanut butter-flavored candy manufactured by The Hershey Company. They are circular in shape, and covered in candy shells that are colored yellow, orange, or brown.  to M&amp;M&apos;s, Heath Bars The Heath Bar is an American candy bar made of English-style toffee. A thin hard slab with a milk chocolate coating, the toffee originally contained sugar, butter, and almonds, and was a small squarish bar weighing 1 ounce. , and Oreos.

It&apos;s a horserace Horserace 
Derby

classic annual race at Epsom Downs. [Br. Cult.: Brewer Dictionary , 276]

Kentucky Derby

classic annual race in Louisville. [Am. Cult.  that will leave many customers limping under
the stress of excess flab. The catch: With no in-store nutrition labels,
customers have no idea what they&apos;re getting. Do they think
it&apos;s diet food? No. But they sure aren&apos;t expecting the
equivalent of two or three Quarter Pounders The Quarter Pounder is a sandwich sold by international fast food chain McDonald&apos;s. Along with the Big Mac, it is one of McDonald&apos;s two signature products. Product description .

&quot;With ice cream portions like these, it&apos;s no wonder that
two out of three Americans are overweight, diabetes rates are rising,
and heart disease is our leading cause of death,&quot; says Marion
Nestle Marion Nestle , Ph.D., M.P.H., is the Paulette Goddard Professor of Nutrition, Food Studies, and Public Health at New York University, in the department that she chaired from 1988 through 2003. Her degrees include a Ph.D. in molecular biology and an M.P.H. , chair of the nutrition and food studies department at New York
University New York University,  mainly in New York City; coeducational; chartered 1831, opened 1832 as the Univ. of the City of New York, renamed 1896. It comprises 13 schools and colleges, maintaining 4 main centers (including the Medical Center) in the city, as well as the .

Most of our numbers come from the companies, but we analyzed 13
items that the chains didn&apos;t tell us about. We also estimated added
sugar--which companies didn&apos;t divulge--at about four teaspoons per
half cup (4 fl. oz.) of most flavors and about six teaspoons per half
cup of sundaes, shakes, etc.

With or without sugar numbers, the results will knock your
sprinkles off. THE COST OF A SPLURGE

 Saturated Fat
 (grams)

 Haagen-Dazs
 Sorbet (1 scoop) 120 calories

 Baskin-Robbins
 Vanilla Ice Cream
 (2 scoops) 500 calories

 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s
 Brownie Special 1,020 calories

 Cold Stone Creamery
 Mud Pie Mojo (regular) 1,180 calories

 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s Chunky Monkey
(reg.) in a chocolate-dipped
 waffle cone 820 calories

 TCBY Toffee Coffee
 Cappuccino Chiller (large) 1,200 calories

 Baskin-Robbins
 Vanilla Milk Shake (large) 1,070 calories

 Haagen-Dazs
 Mint Chip Dazzler 1,270 calories

Looking for a splurge? Most of these items deliver at least a day&apos;s
worth of saturated fat (20 grams) and more than 1,000 calories. Stick
with the sorbet (or a low-fat ice cream, frozen yogurt, or sherbet).

Note: Table made from bar graph. 

Baskin 31 Robbins

With 4,600 units across the country, Baskin-Robbins is the second
largest ice cream chain (we didn&apos;t look at ice cream sold at No. 1 Dairy Queen Dairy Queen (also known as DQ ) is an ice-cream shop and fast-food restaurant franchise based in the United States and founded in 1940.

For many years the franchise&apos;s slogan was &quot;We treat you right!&quot; In recent years, it has been changed to &quot;DQ something different.  or other fast-food chains). Stick with a low-fat single
scoop in a cup and you can get away with roughly 100 to 200 calories and
no more than three grams of saturated fat. (Add 60 calories for a sugar
cone.) Low-fat means sorbet, ices, frozen yogurt yogurt:  see fermented milk. yogurt 

Semisolid, fermented, often flavoured milk food. Yogurt is known and consumed in almost all parts of the world. , sherbet sher·bet  
 n. 
 1. also sher·bert A frozen dessert made primarily of fruit juice, sugar, and water, and also containing milk, egg white, or gelatin.

 2. Chiefly British A beverage made of sweetened diluted fruit juice. , or low-fat
ice cream.

A scoop of Baskin-Robbins&apos; regular ice cream goes from about
250 to 300 calories and eight to 12 grams of sat fat--about half a
day&apos;s worth. That&apos;s bad enough. But double or triple scoops,
toppings, and beverages make it much worse.

A large Chocolate Blast, for example, hits 780 calories and 15
grams of sat fat (thanks to its chocolate ice cream, chocolate syrup syrup  /syr·up/ ( sir´up ) a concentrated solution of a sugar, such as sucrose, in water or other aqueous liquid, sometimes with a medicinal agent added; usually used as a flavored vehicle for drugs. ,
and whipped cream). That&apos;s as bad as an overstuffed o·ver·stuff  
 tr.v. o·ver·stuffed , o·ver·stuff·ing , over·stuffs 
 1. To stuff too much into: overstuff a suitcase. 

 2. To upholster (an armchair, for example) deeply and thickly.  corned beef
sandwich. But it&apos;s small potatoes small potatoes 
 pl.n. Informal 
 1. A person or thing regarded as unimportant.

 2. An insignificant amount or sum.  compared to the milk shakes milk shake

a solution of sodium bicarbonate administered to racehorses by stomach tube 4 to 6 hours before racing to produce a metabolic acidosis. Promoted as a means of producing relief from tying-up and delaying the onset of fatigue by producing additional buffering to counteract ,
which aren&apos;t diluted di·lute  
 tr.v. di·lut·ed , di·lut·ing , di·lutes 
 1. To make thinner or less concentrated by adding a liquid such as water.

 2. To lessen the force, strength, purity, or brilliance of, especially by admixture.  with coffee and ice. A large Vanilla vanilla,  a plant of the genus Vanilla of the family Orchidaceae (orchid family). Vines of hot, damp climates, most are indigenous to Central and South America, especially Mexico, but are now cultivated in other tropical regions.  Shake,
for example, packs 1,070 calories and 32 grams of sat fat. It&apos;s
worse for your heart than drinking three Quarter Pounders. Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams of saturated
fat. Worst Bites have at least 10 grams of sat fat. (The company
didn&apos;t provide numbers for toppings.)

Ice Cream, Frozen Yogurt,
Sherbet,&amp;Sorbet Total Fat Sat Fat
(1 scoop--4 oz.--unless noted) Calories (grams) (grams)

[check] Chocolate Soft Serve Frozen
 Yogurt (small, 5 oz.) 110 0 0
[check] Daiquiri Ice 130 0 0
[check] Sorbet (1) 140 0 0
[check] Rainbow Sherbet 160 2 1
[check] Maui Brownie Madness Yogurt
 Gone Crazy 200 4 2
[check] Lowfat Ice Cream (1) 210 4 2
[check] Lowfat Ice Cream, No Sugar
 Added (1),(2) 150 3 3
 Vanilla Ice Cream (kid&apos;s
 scoop, 2.5 oz.) 150 10 7
 Pralines &apos;n Cream Ice Cream 270 13 8
 Mint Chocolate Chip or
 Chocolate Chip Ice Cream 260 14 9
 Old Fashioned Butter Pecan
 Ice Cream 260 18 9
 x Chocolate or Vanilla Ice
 Cream (3) 280 17 12
 x Vanilla Ice Cream
 (2 scoops, 8 oz.) 500 32 21
 x Vanilla Ice Cream
 (3 scoops, 12 oz.) 740 48 32

Frozen Drinks

 Cappuccino Blast (regular,
 16 fl. oz.) 310 12 7
 x Chocolate Blast (regular,
 16 fl. oz.) 520 17 10
 x Cappuccino Blast (large,
 24 fl. oz.) 470 18 11
 x Chocolate Blast (large,
 24 fl. oz.) 780 26 15
 x Chocolate Milk Shake
 (regular, 16 fl. oz.) 650 33 21
 x Vanilla Milk Shake
 (regular, 16 fl. oz.) 710 33 21
 x Chocolate Milk Shake
 (large, 24 fl. oz.) 980 50 32
 x Vanilla Milk Shake (large,
 24 fl. oz.) 1,070 50 32

Cones

 Sugar Cone 60 0 0
 Waffle Cone 120 2 0

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors.

(2) Contains the artificial sweetener aspartame (NutraSweet).

(3) Average of the flavors listed.

Daily Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

Haagen-Dazs

You won&apos;t feel deprived with a scoop of Haagen-Dazs sorbet,
frozen yogurt, or low-fat ice cream. But just about anything else means
&quot;the usual&quot;--250 to 300 calories and eight to 12 grams of
saturated fat. (The Gelato ge·la·to  
 n. pl. ge·la·ti 
An Italian ice cream or ice.

 
[Italian, from past participle of gelare , to freeze ; see gelatin .]  has just four grams.)

And that&apos;s just the beginning. Posters push the Bailey&apos;s Irish Cream For the novel of the same name, see .
 Irish Cream is a cream liqueur based on Irish whiskey, coffee, cream, and other ingredients. Well known brands include Baileys Irish Cream, which was the first Irish Cream, Carolans and St. Brendan&apos;s.  Shake (Bailey&apos;s Irish Cream ice cream, whole milk, chocolate crunchies Chocolate Crunchies, sometimes abbreviated Crunchies, are commonly used to make up a layer of ice cream cake. The layer of Chocolate Crunchies is generally sandwiched in between two layers of ice cream. , and whipped cream). They don&apos;t mention the 960
calories and 32 grams of sat fat we found--not unlike a Burger King
Double Whopper Whopper - WarGames  with Cheese.

Similar numbers belong on glossy posters of the Banana Split. Each
comes with three scoops of ice cream (we chose chocolate, vanilla, and
strawberry), three syrups syrups, 
 n a medicinal preparation in which herbal infusions or decoctions are mixed with glycerin, honey, or sugar.  (we picked hot fudge, caramel, and
strawberry), and two toppings (we went with peanuts pea·nut  
 n. 
 1. A prostrate southern Brazilian plant (Arachis hypogaea) widely cultivated in tropical and warm temperate regions, having yellow flowers on stalks that bend over so that the seed pods ripen underground.

 2.  and chocolate
crunchies). Would it taste as good if you knew it had 1,100 calories?

At most Haagen-Dazs outlets, the Banana Splits For the dessert, see .
 The Banana Splits Adventure Hour , syndicated as The Banana Splits and Friends Show , was an hour-long package television program featuring both live action and animated segments, that ran for 31 episodes on NBC Saturday mornings from  are overshadowed by
the Dazzlers (&quot;portable versions of classic sundaes&quot;), which
are made with three scoops of ice cream, syrup, whipped cream, and at
least one other topping, all packed into a shake-like cup.

And the Dazzlers&apos; numbers are indeed dazzling. A Dulce Split
( dulce de leche Dulce de leche in Spanish, dolç de llet in Catalan, or doce de leite in Portuguese (&quot;milk candy&quot;), is a milk-based syrup.

Found as both a sauce and a caramel-like candy, it is popular in Argentina.  ice cream, bananas ba·nan·as  
 adj. Slang 
Crazy: &quot;That&apos;s the horrible thing when you&apos;re bananas , caramel, and whipped cream) weighs
in at nearly 1,200 calories and 22 grams of saturated fat. A Mint Chip
(mint chip ice cream, hot fudge, Oreos, chocolate sprinkles, and whipped
cream) approaches 1,300 calories and 38 grams of sat fat. Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams of saturated
fat. Worst Bites have at least 10 grams of sat fat. (The company
didn&apos;t provide numbers for cones or toppings.)

Ice Cream, Frozen Yogurt,&amp;Sorbet Total Fat Sat Fat
(1 scoop--4 oz.--unless noted) Calories (grams) (grams)

[check] Soft Serve Non Fat Frozen
 Yogurt (1) or Sorbet (1) 120 0 0
[check] Low Fat Ice Cream (1) 170 3 2
[check] Soft Serve Coffee Frozen 140 4 3
 Yogurt Gelato (1) 250 9 4
 x Bailey&apos;s Irish Cream Ice Cream 270 17 10
 x Dulce de Leche Ice Cream 290 17 10
 x Cookies&amp;Cream Ice Cream 270 17 11
 x Chocolate or Vanilla Ice Cream 270 18 11
 x Mint Chip Ice Cream 290 19 12
 x Vanilla Ice Cream (2 scoops,
 8 oz.) 540 36 22
 x Vanilla Ice Cream (3 scoops,
 12 oz.) 810 54 33

Dazzlers, etc.
 x Dulce Split Dazzler (16 oz.) 1,180 35 22
 x Banana Split (16 oz.) 1,110 50 29
 x Bailey&apos;s Irish Cream Shake
 (16 fl. oz.) 960 53 32
 x Mint Chip Dazzler (14 oz.) 1,270 62 38

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors. Numbers for
items in italics are from CSPI&apos;s independent laboratory analyses.

Daily Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

 COLD STONE CREAMERY Cold Stone Creamery is an ice cream parlor chain based in Scottsdale, Arizona, United States. [1] History 
The company was co-founded in 1988 by Susan and Donald Sutherland (unrelated to actor Donald Sutherland), who sought ice cream that was neither hard-packed 

This up-and-coming West Coast chain, with more than 300 outlets, is
headed east. Its claim to fame: &quot;When you choose your size and
flavor, it is placed on our frozen granite stone ... and the fun begins!
We add your tasty Mix-Ins and toppings by hand, to make your very own
&apos;one-in-a-million&apos; custom creation.&quot; Translation: Watch
out.

A small (six-ounce) sweet cream ice cream (the base of all the
non-chocolate flavors) will cost you 380 calories and 15 grams of
saturated fat. For another 50 cents you can get a regular (ten ounces)
with 640 calories and 25 grams of sat fat. And two more quarters buy you
a 14-ounce large. That&apos;s 890 calories and 35 grams of sat fat (more
than 1 1/2 days&apos; worth). Would you like your porterhouse steak in a
cone or a cup?

Of course, few people visit Cold Stone Creamery for plain ice
cream. They&apos;re there to watch the servers use their paddles to mix
in some combination of the 40+ candies, cookies, syrups, and nuts.
Except for fruit, you can pretty much count on 100 to 150 calories for
each Mix-In (200 for the cookie dough Cookie dough refers to a blend of cookie ingredients which has been mixed into a solid yet malleable form but has not yet been hardened by heat. The dough is often then separated and the portions baked to individual cookies, or eaten as is.  and the peanut butter). Then
there&apos;s the 160-calorie waffle bowl or cone, which leaps to 330
calories--and 12 grams of saturated fat--if it&apos;s dipped in
chocolate.

That brings, say, a regular sweet cream ice cream with a
Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter Cup, roasted almonds, and hot fudge in a
chocolate-dipped waffle cone to 1,400 calories and two days&apos; sat
fat. Is Cold Stone trying to boost obesity rates?

Of course not. Just giving people a chance to indulge.

To make indulging even easier, Cold Stone offers a selection of
&quot;Creations&quot; that mix-and-match for you. We analyzed a handful
in regular sizes. The Strawberry Shortcake This article refers to the character; for the dessert, see shortcake. 

 Strawberry Shortcake is a licensed character owned by American Greetings, originally used in greeting cards and expanded to include dolls, posters, and other products.   Serenade serenade  [Ital. sera =evening], term used to designate several types of musical composition. Opera and song literature yield numerous examples of the serenade sung or played by a lover at night beneath his beloved&apos;s window; outstanding is  (sweet cream ice
cream, strawberries, sponge cake, and whipped topping Whipped topping is a non dairy product made to resemble the taste, texture, and look of whipped cream. Whipped Topping normally contains some mixture of partially hydrogenated oil, sweeteners, and other ingredients. ) registered 740
calories and 23 grams of sat fat. (Think a one-pound order of BBQ BBQ  barbecue  baby
back ribs.) The Founder&apos;s Favorite (sweet cream ice cream, caramel, fudge 1. fudge - To perform in an incomplete but marginally acceptable way, particularly with respect to the writing of a program. &quot;I didn&apos;t feel like going through that pain and suffering, so I fudged it - I&apos;ll fix it later.&quot;
 2. fudge - The resulting code. , pecans, and brownies) brought the calories up to 970 and the sat
fat down to just 3/4 of a day&apos;s worth (16 grams)--about what
you&apos;d get in two Quarter Pounders.

If you&apos;re looking to put on weight, you might want to consider
the Germanchokolatekake (chocolate ice cream, brownies, caramel, coconut coconut,  fruit of the coco palm ( Cocos nucifera ), a tree widely distributed through tropical regions. The seed is peculiarly adapted to dispersal by water because the large pod holding the nut is buoyant and impervious to moisture. , and pecans). Its 1,110 calories come with 21 grams of sat fat.
Tough to beat ... unless you get the Mud Pie Mojo (coffee ice cream,
roasted almonds, fudge, Oreos, peanut butter, and whipped topping). How
do 1,180 calories and 26 grams of sat fat grab you? About the same way
two Pizza Hut Personal Pan Pepperoni Pizzas would.

Cold Stone does have one item for people who know what happens when
they eat a small tub of ice cream, candy, and fudge: a small Italian
Sorbet, with 170 fat-free calories. According to according to 
 prep. 
 1. As stated or indicated by; on the authority of: according to historians. 

 2. In keeping with: according to instructions. 

 3.  the company, a small
sweet cream yogurt has 220 calories and no fat, so it also seems like a
good deal. But our lab analysis showed otherwise.

We ordered a small Berry Berry Berry Good (sweet cream ice cream
plus strawberries, blueberries, and raspberries) off the
&quot;Creations&quot; menu. But instead of ice cream, we asked for
(supposedly fat-free) sweet cream frozen yogurt. Yet the dish registered
340 calories and 11 grams of fat--seven of them saturated. That&apos;s
half the fat of the sweet cream ice cream, but it&apos;s worse than a
scoop of nearly any ice cream at any other chain. Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams of saturated
fat (the only topping worth a Best Bite is fruit). Worst Bites have
at least 10 grams of sat fat.

 Total Fat Sat Fat
Ice Cream&amp;Sorbet Calories (grams) (grams)

[check] Italian Sorbet (small, 170 0 0
 6 oz.) (1)
 Italian Sorbet (regular, 280 0 0
 10 oz.) (1)
 x Sweet Cream Ice Cream 380 24 15
 (small, 6 oz.)
 x Chocolate Ice Cream 610 40 25
 (regular, 10 oz.)
 x Sweet Cream Ice Cream 640 40 25
 (regular, 10 oz.)
 x Sweet Cream Ice Cream 890 56 35
 (large, 14 oz.)

Creations

 Berry Berry Berry Good,
 made with Sweet Cream 340 11 7
 Frozen Yogurt (small,
 9 oz.)
 x Founder&apos;s Favorite 970 37 16
 (regular, 11 oz.)
 x Germanchokolatekake 1,110 43 21
 (regular, 12 oz.)
 x Strawberry Shortcake 740 37 23
 Serenade (reg., 11 oz.)
 x Mud Pie Mojo (regular, 1,180 60 26
 12 oz.)

Mix-Ins (2)

[check] Berries (3 Tbs.) (1) 20 0 0
 Fat-Free Caramel or Fudge 100 0 0
 (2 Tbs.) (3)
 Oreos (2 cookies) 110 5 1
 Caramel or Fudge 140 4 1
 (2 Tbs.) (3)
 Nuts (3 Tbs.) (1) 150 15 2
 Brownie (2&quot; square, 1 oz.) 160 5 2
 Rainbow Sprinkles (3 Tbs.) 170 5 2
 Candy Bars (1/2 bar or 120 6 3
 2 Tbs. pieces) (1)
 Peanut Butter (2 Tbs.) 190 15 3
 Whipped Topping (4 Tbs.) 50 4 4
 Coconut (2 Tbs.) 70 5 4
 Cookie Dough (1 cookie) 200 10 4
 Chips, Chocolate or White 170 8 6
 (3 Tbs.) (3)

Cones

 Waffle Cone or Bowl, 160 4 1
 undipped
 x Waffle Cone or Bowl, 330 16 12
 chocolate-dipped (2)

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors.

(2) Numbers are CSPI estimates.

(3) Average of the items listed. Numbers for items in italics are
from CSPI&apos;s independent laboratory analyses.

Daily Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

Friendly&apos;s[R]

If there are no Friendly&apos;s in your neighborhood, you probably
have someplace some·place  
 adv. &amp;n. 
Somewhere: &quot;I didn&apos;t care where I was from so long as it was someplace else&quot;   Garrison Keillor.  See Usage Note at everyplace.  similar. The New England-based ice cream parlor chain
offers the same kinds of sundaes, shakes, and banana splits that
you&apos;ll see at Swensen&apos;s--which wouldn&apos;t give us nutrition
information. Friendly&apos;s, on the other hand, offered numbers for
much of its menu (guess it&apos;s not called &quot;friendly&quot; for
nothing).

Like most chains, Friendly&apos;s does offer at least one low-fat
ice cream, frozen yogurt, or sherbet, though the chain&apos;s generous
portions put their calories in the 220 to 280 range. And while you can
order your shake, sundae, split, or frozen drink with low-fat ice cream
or frozen yogurt, it&apos;s still a splurge.

An Orange Sherbet Slammer A worm that caused a billion dollars worth of damage on the Internet on January 25, 2003. Slammer infected computers all over the Internet by generating random IP addresses and causing the computer&apos;s buffer to overflow with its own instructions that replicate itself and start the process  (sherbet blended with sparkling seltzer),
for example, has only three grams of saturated fat. But it will weigh
you down with 510 calories. A Reduced Fat Vanilla Milk Vanilla Milk is Milk with vanilla in it. The vanilla is sometimes artificial, although other times it is real vanilla. Since vanilla contains alchohol, putting too much vanilla in the milk can make it an achoholic beverage.  Shake has eight
grams of sat fat and 620 calories. While that&apos;s not great,
it&apos;s better than any of the Fribbles (&quot;the shakes that made
Friendly&apos;s famous&quot;), with 680 calories and 12 grams of sat
fat. And the Fribbles look good next to the Double Thick Milk Shakes. A
Double Thick Chocolate will set you back 800 calories and 21 grams of
sat fat. Not exactly spa food.

Thinking about a sundae? Don&apos;t. You&apos;ll blow 1,000
calories on the Caramel Fudge Brownie brownie,  in Celtic folklore, household spirit associated with farmsteads. Brownies help with chores, but, if criticized, they will make mischief, such as spoiling crops. If payment other than food is offered a brownie, he vanishes from a farm forever.  or any of the other Oven Fresh
Sundaes. And you&apos;ll need a prescription for cholesterol-lowering statin drugs Noun 1. statin drug - a medicine that lowers blood cholesterol levels by inhibiting HMG-CoA reductase
lipid-lowering medication, lipid-lowering medicine, statin  to cope with their saturated fat (20 to 30 grams).

For the seriously underweight Underweight

An situation where a portfolio does not hold a sufficient amount of securities to satisfy the accepted benchmark of the portfolio&apos;s asset allocation strategy.

Notes:  (or self-destructive),
Friendly&apos;s offers Super (five-scoop) versions of its Original
(three-scoop) Classic, Double Deluxe de·luxe  also de luxe 
 adj. 
Particularly elegant and luxurious; sumptuous: deluxe accommodations; a de luxe automobile. 

 adv. , and Candy Shop Sundaes. Take a
Super Candy Shop Reese&apos;s Pieces (creamy peanut butter sauce, hot
fudge, marshmallows, whipped topping, sprinkles, and Reese&apos;s Pieces
candy on top of vanilla ice Robert Matthew Van Winkle (born October 31, 1968), better known as Vanilla Ice , is a Grammy Award nominated, American Music Award winning American rapper and actor known mostly for the 1990 single &quot;Ice Ice Baby.  cream). You&apos;re talking 1,300 calories
and 39 grams of sat fat. That&apos;s two 12-ounce New York strip Noun 1. New York strip - steak from upper part of the short loin
strip steak

beefsteak - a beef steak usually cooked by broiling  steaks.
But who&apos;s counting? Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams of saturated
fat. Worst Bites have at least 10 grams of sat fat. (The company
didn&apos;t provide numbers for toppings.)

 Total
 Calo- Fat Sat Fat
Ice Cream, Frozen Yogurt,&amp;Sherbet ries (grams) (grams)

[check] Vanilla Fat-Free Frozen Yogurt
 (single, 8 oz.) 220 0 0
 Vanilla Fat-Free Frozen Yogurt
 (double, 10 oz.) 280 0 0
 Sherbet (single, 8 oz.) (1) 280 4 2
[check] Vanilla Low-Fat Ice Cream
 (single, 8 oz.) 240 5 3
 Vanilla Low-Fat Ice Cream
 (double, 10 oz.) 300 6 4
 Soft Serve (single, 6 oz.) (1) 280 9 6
 x Vanilla Ice Cream (single, 8 oz.) 300 16 10
 x Vanilla Ice Cream (double, 10 oz.) 380 20 13

Shakes, etc.

 Orange Sherbet Slammer (11 oz.) 510 5 3
 Watermelon Sherbet Slammer (11 oz.) 590 6 4
 Strawberry Banana Cyclone
 (small, 12 oz.) 440 12 7
 Reduced Fat Vanilla Milk Shake
 (15 oz.) 620 12 8
 x Classic Root Beer Float (20 oz.) 440 17 10
 x M&amp;M&apos;s or Oreo Cyclone (small,
 12 oz.) (2) 750 23 10
 x Orange Creme (18 oz.) 710 18 11
 x Fribble Shake (18 oz.) (1) 680 18 12
 x Fudge Brownie Cyclone (small,
 12 oz.) 790 25 14
 x Oreo Freeze (20 oz.) 850 28 15
 x Double Thick Strawberry Milk Shake
 (15 oz.) 660 26 17
 x M&amp;M&apos;s or Oreo Cyclone (large,
 20 oz.) (2) 1,250 38 17
 x Iced Cappuccino (12 oz.) 620 22 18
 x Strawberry Ice Cream Soda (15 oz.) 540 30 19
 x Double Thick Vanilla Milk Shake
 (15 oz.) 720 31 19
 x Double Thick Coffee Milk Shake
 (15 oz.) 690 31 20
 x Coffee Ice Cream Soda (15 oz.) 550 32 21
 x Chocolate Ice Cream Soda (15 oz.) 730 35 21
 x Double Thick Chocolate Milk Shake
 (15 oz.) 800 33 21
 x Fudge Brownie Cyclone (large, 20
 oz.) 1,320 42 23
 x Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter Cup Cyclone
 (large, 20 oz.) 1,470 72 28

Sundaes, etc. (3 scoops unless noted)

 x Double Deluxe Swiss Chocolate
 Almond 660 29 14
 x Double Deluxe Caramel Fudge Blast 700 30 18
 x Fabulous Royal Banana Split 940 37 19
 x Candy Shop Satisfaction Snickers 810 35 20
 x Oven Fresh Strawberry Shortcake 980 46 20
 x Double Deluxe Beyond Chocolate 650 31 21
 x Oven Fresh Apple or Triple Berry
 Pie (2 scoops) (2) 1,060 61 21
 x Candy Shop Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter
 Cup 930 54 23
 x Oven Fresh Caramel Fudge Brownie 1,060 46 23
 x Classic Hot Fudge Vanilla 650 34 24
 x Fabulous Jim Dandy Banana Split
 (5 scoops) 1,130 48 25
 x Candy Shop Reese&apos;s Pieces 930 52 27
 x Oven Fresh Mud Pie Madness
 (2 scoops) 1,180 52 30
 x Classic Hot Fudge Vanilla
 (5 scoops) 1,130 55 38
 x Candy Shop Reese&apos;s Pieces
 (5 scoops) 1,310 71 39

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors.

(2) Average of the items listed.

Daily Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

All Natural BEN&amp;JERRY&apos;S VERMONT&apos;S FINEST

It&apos;s hard not to love the two guys who started this
big-hearted, environmentally friendly Environmentally friendly , also referred to as nature friendly , is a term used to refer to goods and services considered to inflict minimal harm on the environment. [1]  company (which is now owned by
corporate giant Unilever). But if you&apos;re not careful, those big
hearts can lead you to a big belly and a bypassed heart.

Like most other chains, Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s offers a limited
selection of sorbets and frozen yogurts with 150 to 200 calories and no
more than two grams of saturated fat in a small (four ounces). But
don&apos;t expect more than a few flavors on any given day.

In contrast, you&apos;ll find fatty ice creams galore. Now
you&apos;re talking anywhere from 230 calories and eight grams of
saturated fat (Strawberry) to 340 calories and 14 grams of sat fat
(Coconut Almond almond,  name for a small tree ( Prunus amygdalus ) of the family Rosaceae (rose family) and for the nutlike, edible seed of its drupe fruit. The &quot;nuts&quot; of sweet-almond varieties are eaten raw or roasted and are pressed to obtain almond oil.  Fudge Chip).

But not everyone gets a small at Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s. A regular
(six ounces) will run you 350 to 530 calories. For around a dollar more,
you can jump to a large (nine ounces) with its 540 to 800 calories and
at least a day&apos;s worth of sat fat. Thanks for the incentive, guys.

And why stop with a 60-calorie sugar cone when you can get a
fresh-baked 160-calorie waffle cone? If you don&apos;t mind 320 calories
(and your arteries don&apos;t mind 12 grams of sat fat) you can get your
waffle cone dipped in chocolate. That brings a regular ice cream up to
650 to 800 calories. Are we having fun yet?

B&amp;J offers ready-made concoctions for those who don&apos;t want
to make their own creations. The company had no numbers, so we analyzed
a few.

The Cappachillo Cooler (ice cream, milk, coffee, and whipped cream)
will chill your efforts to look good in a swimsuit. With 720 calories
and 19 grams of sat fat, it&apos;s about equal to the Waffle Cone Sundae
(vanilla ice cream, peanuts, hot fudge, and whipped cream). Replace the
waffle cone with a brownie and you&apos;ve got yourself a Brownie
Special, complete with its special 1,020 calories and 22 grams of sat
fat. It&apos;s a Philly cheese steak sub plus an order of french fries French fry 
 n. 
A thin strip of potato fried in deep fat. Often used in the plural.  that you can conveniently drink between meals. Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams
of saturated fat. Worst Bites have at least 10 grams of
sat fat. (The company didn&apos;t provide numbers for toppings.)

 Total
Ice Cream, Frozen Yogurt,&amp;Sorbet Calo- Fat Sat Fat
(small--4 oz.--unless noted) ries (grams) (grams)

[check] Sorbet (1) 130 0 0
[check] Low Fat Frozen Yogurt (1) 180 2 2
 Vanilla For A Change Ice Cream
 (kid&apos;s, 2 oz.) 130 8 6
 Strawberry Ice Cream 230 12 8
 Chocolate Fudge Brownie Ice Cream 300 14 9
 x Phish Food Ice Cream 300 16 10
 x Chocolate Chip Cookie Dough Ice
 Cream 310 17 10
 x Vanilla For A Change Ice Cream 260 17 12
 x Cherry Garcia Ice Cream 270 16 12
 x Chunky Monkey Ice Cream 330 21 12
 x New York Super Fudge Chunk Ice
 Cream 340 22 12
 x Peanut Butter Cup Ice Cream 350 23 13
 x Coffee Coffee BuzzBuzzBuzz Ice
 Cream 300 20 14
 x Mint Chocolate Chunk Ice Cream 310 21 14
 x Coconut Almond Fudge Chip Ice Cream 340 23 14
 x Vanilla For A Change Ice Cream
 (regular, 6 oz.) 390 25 18
 x Vanilla For A Change Ice Cream
 (large, 9 oz.) 580 38 26

Sundaes, etc.

 x Cappachillo Cooler (16 fl. oz.) 720 31 19
 x Waffle Cone Sundae, undipped cone
 (8 oz.) 740 32 20
 x Brownie Special (10 oz.) 1,020 40 22

Cones

 Sugar Cone 60 0 0
 Waffle Cone, undipped 160 4 1
 x Waffle Cone, chocolate-dipped (2) 320 16 12

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors.

(2) Numbers are CSPI estimates. Numbers for items in italics
are from CSPI&apos;s independent laboratory analyses.

Daily Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

&quot; TCBY TCBY The Country&apos;s Best Yogurt
TCBY This Can&apos;t Be Yogurt (original name) 
TCBY Taking Care of Business, Ya&apos;ll [R]&quot;

TCBY--The Country&apos;s Best Yogurt--is an oasis for arteries that
want to stay young and vibrant ... but only if the arteries are attached
to clear-headed brains.

TCBY&apos;s Nonfat non·fat 
 adj. 
Lacking fat solids or having the fat content removed.  Frozen Yogurt is a freebie free·bie  also free·bee 
 n. Slang 
An article or service given free: &quot;such freebies as subway and bus maps&quot;   New York.  for blood vessels Blood vessels 

Tubular channels for blood transport, of which there are three principal types: arteries, capillaries, and veins. Only the larger arteries and veins in the body bear distinct names. ,
but not for hips and thighs. A small registers 220 calories, a regular
290, and a large 350. But get the 96% Fat Free Frozen Yogurt and the
freebie vanishes. Depending on the size, you end up with 270 to 420
calories and four to six grams of sat fat. Calling a food &quot;96% Fat
Free&quot; when it&apos;s not even low-fat is deceptive de·cep·tive  
 adj. 
Deceptive or tending to deceive.

 
 de·cep tive·ness n.  (and would be
illegal on a food label). Even regular ice cream is about 90% fat-free.
Premium is 85% fat-free.

And TCBY is happy to sell you premium ice cream--made by Mrs.
Fields Mrs. Fields Cookies is a chain of bakeries, located mostly in the United States, founded by Debbi Fields (b. 1956, Park City, Utah). Mrs. Fields and her husband started their business in the late 1970s, opening the first of many retail bakeries in Palo Alto, California, selling . A small dispatches 390 to 570 calories and 13 to 20 grams of sat
fat to your hips and heart. It&apos;s worse than Haagen-Dazs or Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s, because a small has four ounces at those chains but
seven at TCBY. A regular Mrs. Fields means 500 to 730 calories, while a
large ranges from 610 to 900 ... for about 50 cents more than the
regular.

The frozen-yogurt concoctions are no better. The Supreme Hot Fudge
Sundae (non-fat frozen yogurt, hot fudge, mixed nuts, and whipped
topping) that we analyzed clocked in at 580 calories and eight grams of
sat fat. It&apos;s not a Haagen-Dazs Dazzler, but it&apos;s not a cup of
non-fat frozen yogurt, either.

TCBY ratchets up the stakes with its Shivers--frozen yogurt blended
with topping. A small Fruit Shiver shiver

involuntary shaking of the body, as with cold. It is caused by contraction or twitching of the muscles, and is a physiological method of heat production in all animals.  will cost you 470 calories and seven
grams of sat fat. A regular ups the ante to 580 calories and nine grams
of sat fat. That&apos;s close to a Big Mac. A large Heath The Large Heath ( Coenonympha tullia ) is a butterfly in the family Nymphalidae. References 

 Emmet, A.M., J. Heath et al. (Ed.), 1990. The Butterflies of Great Britain and Ireland. The Moths and Butterflies of Great Britain and Ireland Vol.
  Shiver has
1,070 calories, 26 grams of sat fat, and 35 teaspoons of added sugar.

TCBY&apos;s Cappuccino cap·puc·ci·no  
 n. pl. cap·puc·ci·nos 
Espresso coffee mixed or topped with steamed milk or cream.

 
[Italian,  Chillers (frozen yogurt, milk, coffee
flavoring, and whipped topping) should be called &quot;Fillers,&quot;
given their potential to fill out your figure. Even a small ranges from
410 calories (no extra topping) to 780 calories (for Oreo Joe). The
large Toffee Coffee Cappuccino Noun 1. coffee cappuccino - equal parts of espresso and hot milk topped with cinnamon and nutmeg and usually whipped cream
cappuccino, cappuccino coffee

coffee, java - a beverage consisting of an infusion of ground coffee beans; &quot;he ordered a cup of coffee&quot;  packs 1,200 calories and 30 grams of
saturated fat. It may look like a milk shake, but it&apos;s closer to
two pork chops Pork Chop

An arrangement on the floor of the NYSE whereby clerks cover the booth of a floor broker and accept orders, phone calls, and associated tasks.

Notes:
The clerks in charge of maintaining the booths are directly compensated by the floor brokers who own them.  plus a Caesar salad caesar salad 
 n. 
A tossed salad of greens, anchovies, croutons, and grated cheese with a dressing of olive oil, lemon juice, and a raw or coddled egg.  and a buttered baked potato. Best Bites have no more than 250 calories and 3 grams of saturated
fat (the only topping worth a Best Bite is fruit). Worst Bites have
at least 10 grams of sat fat.

 Total
 Calo- Fat Sat Fat
Frozen Yogurt&amp;Sorbet ries (grams) (grams)

[check] Nonfat Frozen Yogurt, no sugar
 added (small, 7 oz.) (1),(2) 170 0 0
[check] Sorbet (small, 7 oz.) (1) 200 0 0
[check] Nonfat Frozen Yoqurt, no sugar
 added (regular, 9 oz.) (1),(2) 210 0 0
[check] Nonfat Frozen Yogurt (small,
 7 oz.) (1) 220 0 0
 Sorbet (regular, 9 oz.) (1) 260 0 0
 Nonfat Frozen Yogurt (regular,
 9 oz.) (1) 290 0 0
 Nonfat Frozen Yogurt (large, 11
 oz.) (1) 350 0 0
 96% Fat Free Frozen Yogurt (small,
 7 oz.) (1) 270 6 4
 96% Fat Free Frozen Yogurt
 (regular, 9 oz.) (1) 340 8 5
 96% Fat Free Frozen Yogurt (large,
 11 oz.) (1) 420 10 6

Mrs. Fields Ice Cream (small--7 oz.--unless noted)

 x Cotton Candy or Rainbow Cream 390 23 13
 x Cookies&amp;Cream 490 26 15
 x Vanilla Bean 460 28 18
 x Butter Pecan 570 44 18
 x Mint Chocolate 500 33 20
 x Vanilla Bean (regular, 9 oz.) 590 36 22
 x Vanilla Bean (large, 11 oz.) 720 45 28

Shivers, Sundaes,&amp;Chillers (made with frozen yogurt)

 Fruit Shiver (small, 16 fl. oz.) 470 11 7
 Supreme Hot Fudge Sundae (10 oz.) 580 18 8
 Fruit Shiver (regular, 20 fl. oz.) 580 14 9
 Oreo Shiver (small, 16 fl. oz.) 660 20 9
 x Cappuccino Chiller (small, 16 fl.
 oz.) 410 17 11
 x Oreo Shiver (regular, 20 fl. oz.) 840 26 11
 x Cappuccino Chiller (regular, 20 fl.
 oz.) 590 23 14
 x Oreo Joe Cappuccino Chiller (small,
 16 fl. oz.) 780 29 15
 x Heath Shiver (regular, 20 fl. oz.) 880 33 21
 x Heath Shiver (large, 24 fl. oz.) 1,070 41 26
 x Toffee Coffee Cappuccino Chiller
 (lg., 24 fl. oz.) 1,200 47 30

Toppings (1 scoop, unless noted)

[check] Fruit (1) 10 0 0
 Hot Caramel 90 0 0
 Chocolate Chip Cookie Dough or
 Sprinkles (3) 70 3 1
 Heath or Snickers pieces (3) 70 4 1
 Almonds, Mixed Nuts, or Pecans (3) 80 6 1
 Walnuts in Syrup 160 10 1
 Whipped Topping (4 Tbs.) 30 3 3
 Butterfingers, M&amp;M&apos;s, or Reese&apos;s
 Pieces (3) 110 5 3
 Hot Fudge 140 7 3
 Coconut 60 5 4
 Peanut Butter Topping 210 19 4

Cones

 Cake Cone 20 0 0
 Sugar Cone or Junior Waffle Cone 70 1 0
 Waffle Cone 110 2 1

[check] Best Bite. x Worst Bite.

(1) Average of all flavors.

(2) Contains the artificial sweetener aspartame (NutraSweet).

(3) Average of items listed. Numbers for items in italics are
from CSPI&apos;s independent laboratory analyses.

Dally Values (daily limits for a 2,000-calorie diet):
Total Fat: 65 grams. Saturated Fat: 20 grams. 

The information for this article was compiled by Tamar Genger, Heather Jones Heather Jones (born October 8, 1970 in Edmonton, Alberta) is a former field hockey player from Canada, who represented her native country at the 1992 Summer Olympics in Barcelona, Spain. There she ended up in seventh place with the Canadian National Women&apos;s Team. , and Sarah Wade. Composites of equal portions of dishes
purchased at six ice cream shops in Atlanta, Chicago, Los Angeles Los Angeles   (lôsăn`jələs, lŏs,ăn`jəlēz&apos;) , city (1990 pop. 3,485,398), seat of Los Angeles co., S Calif.; inc. 1850. ,
and/or Washington, D.C., were sent to an independent lab. The use of
information from this article for commercial purposes is strictly
prohibited without written permission from CSPI CSPI Center for Science in the Public Interest
CSPI Corporate Service Price Index
CSPI Cumulative Schedule Performance Index . COPYRIGHT 2003 Center for Science in the Public Interest
No portion of this article can be reproduced without the express written permission from the copyright holder. Copyright 2003, Gale Group. All rights reserved. Gale Group is a Thomson Corporation Company. 
 Reader Opinion
 Title:
 
Comment:
 

 
   
 
 Article Details Printer friendly Cite/link Email Feedback Author: Liebman, Bonnie Publication: Nutrition Action Healthletter Date: Jul 1, 2003 Words: 4905 Previous Article: Bar none. . Next Article: FDA: the gutless tiger. (On the Web: www.cspinet.org). Topics: Ice cream Ice cream, ices, etc. 




 Related Articles BEHOLD, GLORY EASY DESSERTS CAN ENTERTAIN AS WELL AS LET YOU ENJOY TODAY. 31 LICKS IN SWEET RIVALRY BASKIN-ROBBINS JOINS FREEBIE FRAY. Ice cream man. (Food chemistry: states of matter). Lacto-Licious. Be creamed! Young essay writer scoops competition. GOOD TASTES. Three scoops of success. 
 
 
 Publications by Name Publications by Date Authors Literature A-D E-O P-T U-Z before 1995 1995-1999 
 2000-2004 2005-2009 2010- A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 

 Terms of use |
Copyright©2012 Farlex, Inc. | Feedback | For webmasters | Submit articles
	</body>
</document>
