<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008949" url="http://www.shopwiki.com/l/promotional-plastic-cup" time="2012-07-13-02:22" support="31" score="0.06060422245034221" bingtitle="promotional plastic cup" webtitle="promotional plastic cup">
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001245" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000515" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="55"/>
	<description>... 16 oz. tumbler is made from hard plastic, and is insulated in order ... Tumbler 16 oz. Bulk(100) This custom imprinted Everyday Plastic Cup Tumbler has a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		ShopWiki Homepage Buying Guides▼ | Save with Coupons | Approved Store Program | Follow on Pinterest Close 
 Accessories   Arts and Crafts   Automotive 
 Babies&amp;Toddlers 
 Books , Movies , &amp;Music 
 Clothing Collectibles 
 Computers&amp;Software 
 Electronics 
 Food&amp;Beverages 
 
 
 Green Guide 
 
 Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden 
 
 Jewelry&amp;Watches 
 
 Kids 
 
 Office 
 
 
 Pets 
 
 
 Sports&amp;Recreation 
 
 Toys&amp;Games 
 
 Video Games 
 
 Weddings   GIFT GUIDES 
         SEE MORE GUIDES 
 promotional plastic cup /l/promotional-plastic-cup promotional plastic cup Home and Garden 
 57 results for &quot; promotional plastic cup &quot; between $0.00 and $100.00 

promotional plastic cup
 Tweet 57 promotional plastic cup $0.00 $100.00 /l/promotional-plastic-cup Search instead for: promotional plastic stadium cup translucent promotional plastic cup promotional color plastic cup promotional clear plastic cup promotional plastic cold cup promotional plastic drink cup 
 22 oz. Promotional Plastic Stadium Cup 
 Product Description The 22 oz. Promotional Plastic Stadium Cup comes in 8 different colors to help with any company or organization&apos;s branding needs. For extra functionality, purchasers can also add a lid and straw to this lightweight plastic drinkware item.24-hr or Same Day service is available at no extra charge Lids and Straws available, sold separately Metallic Gold, Silver, and Copper imprint colors are an extra 0.05 run charge per piece 
 Show More 
 Covalence 1 oz. Plastic Shot Glass 2500/Box SOLO Cup Company Guildware Heavyweight Plastic Forks, Black, 1000/Carton ZIPLOC 2 GALLON STORA E BAGS 100/1.7 - DRK94603 Ziploc® Windex Glass Cleaner, Trigger Bottle, Nonaerosol, 32oz. DRA90135 Plastic Portion Cups Translucent 4.5 Oz. - Case 
 $0.48 pinnaclepromotions.com pinnaclepromotions.com Go to Store Top stores pinnaclepromotions.com $0.48 Promotional 10 oz. Clear Plastic Cup 
 &quot;The opportunity to see before you buy, to place a logo on an item and instantly see how it will look - right from your browser - effectively takes the mystery out of what the actual product will look like.&quot;- BRAND MARKETING MAGAZINE 
 Show More 
 ISI North America - Clear Flexible Silicone Four Cup Measuring Cup Vertex Ventana Undecorated China Dixie Wax Treated Cold Drink Cup (B000XTM0BU) Round Cocktail Table leather Raspberry Filled Mini Dark Chocolate Cups: 8LBS 
 $0.46 branders.com branders.com Go to Store Top stores branders.com $0.46 See 9 Stores &gt; Promotional 7 oz. Clear Plastic Cup 
 To use a graphic located on your local computer, click on the “Upload Now” button on the “Step 1: Get Your Artwork” page of the design studio. This will lead you to a new page. Click the “Browse” button and look for the file on your computer. [+] 
 Show More 
 baking cups paper Plastic spice jars Flaunt Mid Back Brown Micro Fiber Managers Chair Rhinestone Accented Champagne Glasses and Cake Server Set Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1101) 
 $0.46 branders.com branders.com Go to Store Top stores branders.com $0.46 See 8 Stores &gt; Promotional 4 Colors/1 Side - Quick Ship Ten Ounce Eco-friendly Soft Sided Plastic Compostable Cup 
 Promotional 4 Colors/1 Side - Quick Ship Ten Ounce Eco-friendly Soft Sided Plastic Compostable Cup . 
 Show More 
 Midnight Dreary 9 oz. Paper Cups (18 count) Plastic Pink Ribbon Cups Dixie Crystal Clear Plastic Cup small plates *Drive Deluxe Seat Lift Chair Overbed Table - Right Side Table 
 $2.66 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $2.66 Promotional 4 Colors - Sixteen Ounce White Plastic Cold Drink Stadium Cup 
 Promotional 4 Colors - Sixteen Ounce White Plastic Cold Drink Stadium Cup . 
 Show More 
 Clear Sauce Cup 25oz Sofa Throw Blanket By Ashley Furniture Emtek Products 2102US26 Privacy Pocket Lock Sliding Door Hardware Plastic Cups 9 Ounce Translucent RPI solo plastic cups 
 $0.49 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $0.49 17 oz. Fluted Promotional Plastic Stadium Cup 
 Product Description This 17 oz. Fluted Promotional Plastic Stadium Cup is a must-have for your next stadium event. Sports fans can stay hydrated while also boosting awareness for your marketing message. Also, the 17 oz. Fluted Promotional Plastic Stadium Cup is top rack dishwasher safe, making it a practical choice for kids and adults alike.Made in the USA. Recyclable. Made from FDA approved materials. Price includes a Two Sided Imprint. Dishwasher Safe (top rack). 
 Show More 
 Shepherd Hardware Rigid Plate Caster (9484) Hibiscus Flower Plastic Tumblers Fabri-Kal Greenware Clear Souffle Cup - 2oz CLEAR PRODUCE TRAY 5-CELL WITH DIP CUP 13X3.14 Durango Mens Brown Leather Harness Boots - Round Toe 
 $0.44 pinnaclepromotions.com pinnaclepromotions.com Go to Store Top stores pinnaclepromotions.com $0.44 Promotional Collapsible Plastic Cup With Internal Pill Box 
 Branders offers different shipping methods to suit your budget and event date. We quote the most economical shipping method available for an order, unless otherwise specified. Contact us about oversized, very large or heavy shipments. 
 Show More 
 Dignity Briefmates Extra Absorbent Pad by Whitestone John Deere Hot/Cold Paper Cups (8) Twin or Full Metal Bed Frame with Glides Dixie Clear Plastic Cup 10 oz Screen Back Task Chair with Vinyl Seat 
 $0.84 branders.com branders.com Go to Store Top stores branders.com $0.84 Hi-Def WHite Plastic Cups, Promotional Hi-Def WHite Plastic Cups by 
 Promotional Plastic 12 oz. Hi-Def Cups are beatiful keepsakes for after the holidays. Full four color process imprint on enitre cup &amp;roomk for your custom logo/message. Top shelf dishwasher safe. Also available in .17oz&amp;.22oz. .10 cents more per piece will be added. 
 Show More 
 ZIPLOC SANDWICH BAG 500/1.2MIL (B0002V3Y8M) Frosted Cookies - Halloween Black Cat Cookies - Merlino Baking - 12 Pack Grafton Orange Sofa Throw Blanket By Ashley Furniture Work Smart Screen Back Chair with Leather Seat - 599402 Plastic 9 OZ Ultra Clear Cup 
 $1.59 bizpen.com bizpen.com Go to Store Top stores bizpen.com $1.59 Promotional 16 oz. Carnival Cup with Acrylic Straw | Customized Plastic Cups | Promotional Plastic Cups 
 16 oz. Double Wall BPA Free acrylic construction with a twist on Lid and Acrylic BPA Free Plastic Straw. 
 Show More 
 Cold Cup AvantiInfinity 44 Oz Garden District Bronze/Gold Scroll Blanket Rack By Powell Furniture Dry Measure Cups GSI Mini Expresso Cups 1.75 Oz SpongeBob Buddies Cups - 8 Count (9 oz.) 
 $4.59 theexecutiveadvertising.com theexecutiveadvertising.com Go to Store Top stores theexecutiveadvertising.com $4.59 Promotional 500 Line - Clear Plastic 9 Oz. Old Fashioned Cup 
 Can you&quot;pray-tell&quot;the benefits of adding a custom imprint to this 9 oz. old-fashioned cup ? This recyclable promotional product is ideal for virtually any business, fundraiser or special event! Conveniently designed to hold your favorite beverages it would be a great way to promote concert venues, outdoor festivals and cafe&apos;s. Proudly made in the USA and BPA free, these classic items can help build brand awareness with each sip. 2 imprint colors! 
 Show More 
 Big Cup Three-Compartment Supply Organizer, Plastic, Clear Margarita ( 5-pc. nesting doll set ) Red Paper Cups Post-it Super Sticky Self-stick Easel Pads Antique Dresden Bouillon Cups&amp;Saucers Desserts Hand Painted Exquisite 
 $0.79 usimprints.com usimprints.com Go to Store Top stores usimprints.com $0.79 Promotional Same 1 Color 1 Or 2 Sides - Quick Ship 32 Oz. Colored Plastic Cold Drink Stadium Cup 
 Promotional Same 1 Color 1 Or 2 Sides - Quick Ship 32 Oz. Colored Plastic Cold Drink Stadium Cup . 
 Show More 
 slipstick foot good cup Flaunt Camel Micro Fiber Guest Chair Glass measuring cup Plastic Portion Cup Lids Clear - Case 
 $0.97 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $0.97 Promotional 7 Working Days - Plastic - Patented Car Flag With 3.25&quot;Suction Cup And 20&quot;Pole 
 Get your company logo outdoors or on the road with these marketing flags. Customize these branded promotional products a with a logo of your choosing.7 working days - Plastic - Patented car flag with 3.25&quot;suction cup and 20&quot;pole. Incredibly versatile sticks anywhere. No damage to window seals! Goes on hood, roof, windows or trunk of any vehicle. Great for Schools, fund raisers, car dealers, parades, tailgating parties and pop 
 Show More 
 10 OZ Stock White Squat Hot Cup Base Emtek Products Brass Arch Style Screen Door Lock (2290) John B Taylor Harvest Cup and Saucer Flat, Fine China Fabri-Kal Kal-Clear 7oz Clear Plastic Cold Drinking Cup Nomad Women&apos;s Bomba - Brown Webbing 
 $9.97 usimprints.com usimprints.com Go to Store Top stores usimprints.com $9.97 See 2 Stores &gt; Promotional 500 Line Colorware - 5 Working Days - Colored, 16 Oz. Plastic Cup 
 5 working days - Refresh your current marketing campaign by adding a custom imprint to a promotional product that&apos;s ideal for virtually any business, fundraiser or special event! This 16 oz. colored plastic cup is conveniently designed to hold your favorite beverages; making it a great promotion for concert venues, outdoor festivals and cafe&apos;s. Proudly made in the USA and BPA free, these everyday items can help build brand awareness with each sip! 
 Show More 
 nose cut out cups Chocolate Peanut Butter Cups, 1.6 oz, 24 count 10 OZ Bella Tazza Hot Cup Base Hurricane Disposable Cups for Bomb Shots 500 Count RPI Russell Round Black Leather Ottoman&amp;Tray Table 
 $0.86 usimprints.com usimprints.com Go to Store Top stores usimprints.com $0.86 See 6 Stores &gt; 12 oz. Translucent Plastic cup 
 High Speed Off-Set Printed: Translucent soft sided plastic cup . This personalized soft sided plastic cup is economical and disposable. A popular promotional product for concerts and other one-time events. Great for outdoor patios and drinks on the go. 
 Show More 
 Cambro 9.7 Oz Plastic Colorware Tumbler, Slate Blue 713015 Floor protection glides Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1171) Ziploc Brand Resealable Freezer Bags - 2-Gallon (SHR-DRK94605) german shepherd screen savers 
 $0.13 anypromo.com anypromo.com Go to Store Top stores anypromo.com $0.13 12 oz. Full Color Plastic Cups 
 12 oz. Full Color Plastic Stadium Cup made of recyclable plastic . These unique cups are great for vivid full color logos or photos. Never before has a plastic cup been able to promote your image with such detail and clarity. Hi-Definition graphics increase the initial impact of your promotion. Plus, you&apos;ll get added exposure when our reusable plastic cups are taken home and used again and again. Here are a few promotional ideas using cups: promote people, promote places and events. Call for more... 
 Show More 
 Glad ForceFlex Tall Kitchen Bags, 13 Gallon (120 Bags) Clear Vintage Glass Candle Holder (cup design) Villeroy and Boch cereal bowls 16 OZ Bella Tazza Hot Cup Base Clear Rigid Tall Plastic Tumblers - 10 Oz 
 $50.00 adcomarketing.com adcomarketing.com Go to Store Top stores adcomarketing.com $50.00 See 4 Stores &gt; Personalized Plastic Cup -12 oz. Smooth 
 Catch the&quot;Mood&quot;with the varying colors of this promotional plastic mug. What a promotion product for almost any event or 
 Show More 
 Global Elements Felt Bag w/ Polka Dots Brown - Leather Handbags 14 OZ Catering Plastic Tumbler Light Up Margarita Glass Inner Lip Partitioned Plate ziploc container 
 $0.49 promotional-items-inc.com promotional-items-inc.com Go to Store Top stores promotional-items-inc.com $0.49 Min Qty 100 10 oz. Clear Plastic Cup (Screen Printed) 
 These disposable plastic cups are convenient economical and made of high quality durable clear hard plastic . Promotional Plastic Tumblers are great for events tradeshows restaurants and pubs. 
 Show More 
 Cup Plastic Clear 16oz ziploc cups Sahalie Women&apos;s Earth Glides Coffee cups and saucers jumbo baking cups 
 $51.00 PrintGlobe Go to Store Top stores PrintGlobe $51.00 32oz White Plastic Stadium Cups 
 32oz White Plastic Stadium Cups with large imprint area. Custom printed stadium cups for promotional events, business events and sporting events. Reusable, recyclable and made in the US 
 Show More 
 Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1641) Dignity Regular Duty Pads by Humanicare - Case of 384 - 026954 colorful stunning baking cups Boardwalk 12oz Translucent Plastic Cups 1000ct Reese&apos;s Cups Mini - 5 lb. Bulk 
 $0.89 customglassware.com customglassware.com Go to Store Top stores customglassware.com $0.89 Plastic Stadium Cups 
 New are now have promotional stadium cups for your event or wedding or any occasion. we have a limited stock at this time with more due in two weeks. Custom printing can be done on lots of 250 or more please email for more information. 
 Show More 
 Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1381) Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1231) Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1161) Ringed base - 925 Silver Kiddush cup 3 /4 Bucket Bar Stool Glide 
 $0.29 cheaptotes.com cheaptotes.com Go to Store Top stores cheaptotes.com $0.29 Fast Custom Plastic Cups: 16oz Stadium Cup : 103526 
 Classic, durable personalized cups for all of your casual events! * Durable, 16-oz. plastic tumbler. * Made in the U.S.A. * A perfect imprinted promotional item for trade show giveaways * This cup is classified as recycle code #2. * 2-day service is available for order quantities up to 2,500. Call for larger quantities. Size: 16-oz., fluted 4 1/4&quot;H. Setup charge: $45. Imprint area: 3 3/4&quot;W x 2&quot;H or 8 1/2&quot;(Wrap). Production time: 2 working days (Does not include payment, art prep, or shipping... 
 Show More 
 Bailey Rug Brown Leather 77&quot; Round Wilton Elmo Standard Baking Cups Curtain Call Breakfast Cup by Barbara Barry Virco 2000 Series 12&quot;&quot; Stacking Chair with Nylon Glides 2012 8 Oz Bistro Paper Poly Lined Hot Cups 
 $215.00 crestline.com crestline.com Go to Store Top stores crestline.com $215.00 See 4 Stores &gt; Lumina Translucent Rolled Rim Plastic 5 oz. Cold Drink Cup 
 Made of translucent plastic , Lumina Translucent Rolled Rim Plastic 5 oz. cold drink cups are an economical alternative for parties and events. Imprint these cups with your name, logo or other message. Great for coffee shops or restaurants, these promotional translucent cups are an easy way to get your brand noticed. Lumina plastic cups provide the convenience youre looking for, and come with sidewall ridges for added strength. 
 Show More 
 Emtek Products Non-Keyed, Thumbturn Inside, Patio Door Hardware (1443) Square Table Unit 8 Seat egg server Slipstick CB420 Carpet Caster Cup Clear Large bed tray non slip 
 $60.32 Round Eye Supply Round Eye Supply Go to Store Top stores Round Eye Supply $60.32 24 oz. Translucent Plastic Cup 
 High Speed Off-Set Printed: Translucent soft sided plastic cup . This personalized soft sided plastic cup is economical and disposable. A popular promotional product for concerts and other one-time events. Great for outdoor patios and drinks on the go. 
 Show More 
 OXO 3-pc. Good Grips Angled Measuring Cups Latte Harvest Design Cups&amp;Saucers - Set of 2 Dignity Briefmates Beltless Undergarments by Whitestone Fabri-Kal 2oz Plastic Translucent Souffle Cup Mens Timex Round Brown Leather Strap #T2M489 
 $0.33 anypromo.com anypromo.com Go to Store Top stores anypromo.com $0.33 Plastic Hoop Custom Plastic Cups - 16 oz 
 This clear promotional 16 oz. custom plastic cup has a hoop built on and is great for sports fan and ballers alike. Each mug features an orange handle and imprinted white plastic backboard with orange stripes. Purchase also includes 2&quot;orange Styrofoam basketball for added fun. Intended for use with cold drinks only! 
 Show More 
 Peppermint Filled Mini Dark Chocolate Cups: 8LBS Emtek Products Non-Keyed, Thumbturn Inside, Patio Door Hardware (1693) Easy Glide Slide Cutter Film 18 Inch X 2000 Ft 24 OZ Gourmet Design Hot Cup Base Sage Design Hot Paper Cups with Fold-Out Handles 
 $3.48 epromos.com epromos.com Go to Store Top stores epromos.com $3.48 Vintage Orphan Annie Plastic Ovaltine Cup , 1930s/1940s 
 This promotional cup stands 3 inches tall with cream color body and full-color decal of Sandy&amp;Annie. Marked&quot;Beetleware&quot;. Excellent condition through out. 
 Show More 
 plastic beer cups Brown Felt on Felt Rings Pillow plastic disposable cup Eco-Products 16oz Compostable Corn Clear Plastic Cups 1000ct Godiva Creme Brulee Single-Serve Coffee Pods, 16 Count, 3.66 Ounce Bags (Pack of 6) 
 $18.00 dowahdiddy.com dowahdiddy.com Go to Store Top stores dowahdiddy.com $18.00 Custom Plastic Cups: 24oz Stadium Cup : 101013 90A 
 Your message or logo will look simply radiant on this glow-in-the-dark cup ! * Durable 24-oz. plastic tumbler. * Glow additive is blended directly into plastic for a long-lasting glow. * Available in a variety of promotional cup styles. * Made in the U.S.A. Size: 6 1/2&quot;H. Setup charge: $49. Imprint area: 3&quot;W x 4 3/4&quot;H. Production time: 10 working days (Does not include payment, art prep, or shipping time. Click here for details) Need It Fast? Also Available in 2-Day Production! (#104728 90A) 
 Show More 
 Emtek Products Non-Keyed, Thumbturn Inside, Patio Door Hardware (1603) Glad Tall Kitchen, Quick-Tie, 13 Gallon, 35 ea CrestWare Bouillon Cups Ziploc Freezer Bags - 1 Gallon RPI Dignity Briefmates Super Guards by Humanicare - Case of 120 - 30074 
 $237.50 crestline.com crestline.com Go to Store Top stores crestline.com $237.50 Min Qty 126 Plastic Yard Cup , 24 oz. 
 Get your logo noticed at your next big event with the Plastic Yard Cup . It is available in 4 fantastic colors and is ideal for parties outdoor promotions tradeshows and more. Get outstanding exposure with your logo showcased on the Promotional Yard Cup ! 
 Show More 
 Tulip Personalized Champagne Glasses and Cake Server Set Sabrina Scarlet Sofa Throw Blanket By Ashley Furniture Brown Leaf - Felt Coasters Emtek Products Keyed Patio Door Hardware (1131) ZIPLOC 2 GALLON FREEZE R BAGS 100/2.7MI - DRK94605 
 $321.30 PrintGlobe Go to Store Top stores PrintGlobe $321.30 3 Color / 1 Side - Quick Ship 16 Oz. White Plastic Cold Drink Stadium Cup 
 3 Color / 1 Side - Quick Ship 16 oz. white plastic cold drink stadium cup . The material of this promotional product is Plastic . Add your logo by Pad Print. This is available in White. 
 Show More 
 leveling glides Mini Milk Choc Peanut Butter Cups: 25 LBS Silicone Baking Mats, Fits Full-size Sheet Pan Bratz Fashion Pixiez 9 oz. Paper Cups (8 count) Bratz Cups - 8 Count (9 oz.) 
 $1.97 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $1.97 Plastic Frost-Flex - Frosted Polypropylene Souvenir Stadium Cup , 16 Oz 
 Plastic Frost-Flex - Frosted polypropylene souvenir stadium cup , 16 oz. You can imprint your logo by Silkscreen decoration method. This promotional product is made of Plastic . Get yours in Frosted. 
 Show More 
 Halo Cup - Wide Base Stability - Stackable (B0002DLCFC) coffee mug Pink Paper Cups ziploc com Chefs Select Parchment Baking Cups Set of 54 
 $0.95 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $0.95 Sweda 16oz Everyday Plastic Cup Tumbler 
 The Sweda 16oz Everyday Plastic Cup Tumbler is a pratical cup you can use for anything and not worry about spills. The Promotional Plastic Cup is a double wall acrylic cup that is available in multiple bright colors and has a matching color screw top lid and sip straw. The MG112 is BPA free and has a large imprint area with one color imprint and one setup included, multiple color imprints are available, call or chat for details. Microwave and dishwashers are not considered safe for this item. 
 Show More 
 Ziploc Sandwich Bags - Foodservice Grade Under The Sea Hot/Cold Cups (8/pkg) Emtek Products Non-Keyed, Thumbturn Inside, Patio Door Hardware (1503) Salisbury Pewter Cup - Easton Cross w/Handle - 5oz. ClearLight Clear Plastic Cup - 9.5 oz 
 $4.54 promomanagers.com promomanagers.com Go to Store Top stores promomanagers.com $4.54 Promotional Measuring Cups: Measure Mate: 106485 
 This handy kitchen tool features four measuring spoon sizes in one piece! * Made of rugged, dishwasher safe, ABS plastic . * Bright, polished finish shows off your logo or message. * Measures 1/4 teaspoon, 1/2 teaspoon, 1 teaspoon, and 1 tablespoon. Size: 7/8&quot;H x 4 1/2&quot;W x 1 1/4&quot;D. Setup charge: $42. Imprint area: 1 3/8&quot;W x 1/2&quot;H. Production time: 7 working days (Does not include payment, art prep, or shipping time. Click here for details). 
 Show More 
 Tulsa Golden Hurricane 10-Pack 16oz. Team Slogan Foam Cups Office Star Screen Back Adjustable Chair With Mesh Seat - Black 3 oz plastic cups margarita glasses plastic Wilton Silicone Baking Cups 
 $259.00 crestline.com crestline.com Go to Store Top stores crestline.com $259.00 Promotional Melamine Cup , 8 Oz 
 Melamine cup makes great kids tumbler. Melamine, a form of high compression plastic , is terrific in so many ways. The parts are decorated with full color graphics using custom decals that are added during the molding cycle, actually embedding them into the material. Dishwasher safe. Not intended for microwave use. All of our melamine products are completely FDA compliant for direct food contact. 
 Show More 
 12 OZ Bella Tazza Hot Cup Base Emtek Products Dummy Pair, Patio Door Hardware (1675) Clear Standard Cup 69 oz White Peanut Butter Cups - Wrapped: 24 Count Rosanna Caffe Italia Set of 4 Espresso Cups and Saucers, Gift-boxed 
 $4.44 usimprints.com usimprints.com Go to Store Top stores usimprints.com $4.44 Promotional Melamine Cup , 10 Oz 
 Melamine cup makes perfect kid tumbler. Melamine, a form of high compression plastic , is terrific in so many ways. The parts are decorated with full color graphics using custom decals that are added during the molding cycle, actually embedding them into the material. Dishwasher safe. Not intended for microwave use. All of our melamine products are completely FDA compliant for direct food contact. 
 Show More 
 Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle Cups - 8 Count Greenware Clear Cold Cup 16oz Ziploc Zip &apos;n Steam, Steam Cooking Bags, Medium, 10 ea Igloo with Santa and Penguins Silicone Baking Pan Wade Ceramics Dignity One Handled Cup in Green 80207/GN 
 $5.00 usimprints.com usimprints.com Go to Store Top stores usimprints.com $5.00 Custom Cup Tumblers, Acrylic Tumblers, Plastic Insulated Tumblers, Acrylic Cups With Straws 
 Custom print these 16 oz. Clear Cup Insulated Tumblers with your logo or brand artwork. With 16 oz. of capacity, these BPA Free plastic tumblers can hold a lot of liquid and are made to be sturdy and durable for everyday use. The attached sipper straw and screw on lid add functionality and utility to this promotional product. 
 Show More 
 Carlisle 16oz Plastic Tumbler Clear - 24pk Ziploc Divided Container, Rectangle, 2 ea Nomad Women&apos;s Hancho - Brown Webbing Cute Animals Print Disposable Paper Party Cups Four Vetro Silver Handled Glass Cup And Saucers 
 $2.99 silkletter.com silkletter.com Go to Store Top stores silkletter.com $2.99 Rush Promotional Cups: Stadium Glow Cup : 104726 90A 
 Your message or logo will look simply radiant on this glow-in-the-dark cup ! * Durable 12-oz. plastic tumbler. * Glow additive is blended directly into plastic for a long-lasting glow. * Made in the U.S.A. * 2-day service is available for order quantities up to 2,500. Call for larger quantities. Size: 4 1/4&quot;H. Setup charge: $49. Imprint area: 3 1/4&quot;W x 2 1/2&quot;H. Production time: 2 working days (Does not include payment, art prep, or shipping time. Click here for details). 2-Day Service: Order... 
 Show More 
 CLEAR SOUFFLE CUP LID - 2oz mini baking pans Magazine Cup, Plastic, Red Magazine Cup, Plastic, Red Disney Fairytale Princess Cups 8 Count 9 oz Fostoria Alexis (Stem 1630, Heavy) Handled Custard Cup 
 $227.50 crestline.com crestline.com Go to Store Top stores crestline.com $227.50 Sampler/Portion Cup - Plastic Squat, Clear Rigid Disposable Plastic /glass Sampling Tumbler 
 Sampler/Portion Cup - Plastic squat, clear rigid disposable plastic /glass sampling tumbler. The material of this promotional item is Plastic . Silkscreen imprint method is available. This item is available in Clear. 
 Show More 
 Polypropylene Clear Plastic Cup 18 Oz. - Case china villeroy and boch Ghirardelli Semisweet Chocolate Baking Bar: 12 Count L&apos;Oreal Lineur Intense Felt Tip Liquid Eyeliner Houndstooth Brown Forever Glides 036665 
 $0.86 promopeddler.com promopeddler.com Go to Store Top stores promopeddler.com $0.86 
 Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for? Flag this search Thank you! This search has been flagged. 
 1 2 Next 
 Recommended Reading Sports and Recreation &gt; Team Sports &gt; Soccer Accessories &gt; Bags Home and Garden &gt; Kitchen and Dining &gt; Kitchen and Dining Brands &gt; Fiestaware Home and Garden &gt; Kitchen and Dining &gt; Kitchen and Dining Brands Home and Garden &gt; Food Storage Narrow by price 
 See All Prices $0 – $1 $1 – $5 $5 – $10 $10 – $25 &gt;$50 
 Set Your Range: $ – $ By Stores 
 usimprints.com branders.com promopeddler.com anypromo.com PrintGlobe crestline.com Round Eye Supply cheaptotes.com epromos.com theexecutiveadvert... 
 Show More▼ Show Fewer▲ By Brands 
 ASI Gildan CRESTLINE DART Durable Oregon Adobe Old Fashioned Rim 
 Show More▼ Show Fewer▲ Featured Products No Image Related Buying Guides 
 Baking Cups Bouillon Cups Furniture Pads and Cups 

 Coffee Cups and Saucers Measuring Cups and Spoons Paper and Plastic Food Storage Fine Dinnerware Breakfast Cups Villeroy and Boch Egg Cups and Plates Eating and Drinking Aids Cups and Glasses Toys and Games Party Supplies Tableware Cups Household Supplies Paper and Plastic Cups and Straws Home and Garden Dining Tableware Cups Mugs and Saucers Household Supplies Paper and Plastic Cups and Straws Cups Sports and Outdoors Fan Gear Kitchen and Bath Mugs and Cups Travel Mugs Cups Plastic Balls World Cup Soccer Spill Proof Cups Plastic Bag Holders Plastic Mixing Bowls 
 Show More&gt; Home and Garden Deal Alerts Sign-Up for Deal Alert Emails: (See sample) Submit We respect your privacy. Or Follow Us to See Deals: Twitter Facebook 
Thank you for subscribing!

You will receive a &quot;Welcome Email&quot; from us momentarily
 
Unsubscribe text here
 
 About Us | Help/FAQ | Privacy | User Agreement | Buying Guide Directory | Shopper Deals | Our Partner Stores 
 Copyright©, 2006-2012 ShopWiki Corp. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
