<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008887" url="http://www.gulfcoastnews.com/RT2007ChevKodiak4500.htm" time="2012-07-13-02:19" support="3" score="0.0007702615215674133" bingtitle="2007 Chevrolet Kodiak - Gulf Coast News - Your Mississippi Coast ..." webtitle="2007 Chevrolet Kodiak">
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>You can also order yours with back seat captain&apos;s chairs,each with its own seat ... drive-throughs, whether at the bank or your favorite fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		2007 Chevrolet Kodiak
 When You Need a Really Big Pickup, This is It 

 By Keith Burton 

So you are big truck enthusiast that feels the need 
 for size. Well, if a Chevrolet 3500 Silverado isn&apos;t big enough for your 
 needs, we have something you will want to have. How about the big boy of 
 pickups, the 2007 Chevrolet Kodiak 4500. Not familiar with that truck? You 
 are, but usually this medium duty heavy truck is more commonly configured 
 as dump trucks, school buses and moving vans. But the folks at Monroe Truck Equipment 
 Company have teamed up with Chevy to build the Kodiak 4500 pickup, 
 which can be ordered at your neighborhood Chevrolet dealer.

Our Kodiak came equipped with a wealth of options. The crew-cab C4500&apos;s base price is 
 around $34,086, but 
 ours came equipped with the Duramax turbo-diesel and Allison transmission 
 altogether with numerous other options upped the price to just over 
 $70,000.

Our truck had an 8-foot pickup bed (a standard 
 one-ton dualie bed with a few modifications) with a 30,000-pound-rated 
 pop-up gooseneck hitch hidden underneath. In addition, the truck had the 
 Ultra Ride air suspension, which replaces the rear leaf springs with two 
 frame-located airbags supposedly improves the empty ride of the truck and 
 increase overall carrying capacity.
 
 
 Key Points: 

 The real full size pickup larger than the 
 biggest typical quadcab pickup Big rig towing capability with a 30,000 
 pound-rated popup gooseneck hitch Somewhat better ride with air suspension for cab 
 and seats, but still jolting at times Easy to drive considering its size Luxurious appointed with leather heated seats and 
 wood trim dash Remarkable smooth transmission gear shifts 
 without any jarring 350 horsepower Duramax 6600 Diesel Engine with 605 
 ft.lbs of torque. Can haul in excess of 20,000 pounds Can be built to your specifications, consider it 
 a custom truck Everyone in a pickup looks at it more stares 
 than a Ferrari would get. 
 
 

But that ride improvement is a relative term, which we will talk more of 
 later. Out truck was also equipped with fully air-suspended seats, 
 offering a full six inches of shock-absorbing travel. Monroe also 
 installed a separate cab air suspension, which includes two additional 
 airbags under the cab, along with two shock absorbers. We also had a nifty 
 navigation system that included three, count them, three exterior video 
 cameras to watch what was out back and to the right and left. The display was integrated into the navigation monitor on 
 the dash. What was cool was that you could set the monitor to display the 
 nav screen and all three of the cameras. While that made the pictures 
 small, when you made a left or right signal, or placed the vehicle in 
 reverse, the display would drop the other pictures and show a full screen 
 of what the camera viewed.

Our truck also had onboard a forest of 
 simulated and real wood. On the dash, on the doors, on the headliner, 
 attractive wood panels were almost everywhere. But if you don&apos;t like wood, 
 you can order it without, or choose some other simulated stuff, like fake 
 carbon fiber. Monroe replaced the front seats with 
 two air-suspended fully bolstered leather captain&apos;s chairs with a 
 solid-oak center console. In back, the three-passenger leather bench seat 
 can be electronically controlled and reclines and even folds flat at the touch of 
 a button. With the seats laid flat, the rear area is converted into a bed 
 large enough for two children to stretch out and sleep, or two adults 
 could cozy up back there. You can also order yours with back seat 
 captain&apos;s chairs,each with its own seat heater. A big-screen DVD player is 
 also available.

At the heart of the Kodiak is the Duramax 
 6600 diesel and Allison six-speed transmission (with PTO) that is found in 
 the Silverado and Sierra 
 HD trucks. And while versions of the Duramax can be tuned to 350 
 horsepower and 650 pound-feet of torque, the medium-duty versions such as 
 what&apos;s in the Kodiak are not. 
 The Kodiak power totals 300 horses and 605 pound-feet of torque, which 
 provide plenty of grunt for getting around town and towing. At highway 
 speeds, the Kodiak loafs along at under 2,000 rpm. But being a very large 
 vehicle, you do not accelerate with anything close to regular truck 
 speeds. Momentum gathers more locomotive-like. The Allision transmission 
 though is remarkably smooth-shifting, seamlessly snicking off gears 
 without any jerks to the chassis.

You have to remember that this is not a regular 
 pickup truck and it doesn&apos;t ride like one. The ride can often be brutal 
 over rough roads when the truck is not loaded. Even with the air 
 suspension and cushioned seats, sharp bumps set off a cacophony of motions with the driver&apos;s seat rocking back and forth, the 
 chassis shuddering and the cab itself moving to quell the disruption. It 
 makes for a ride that would feel at home at Six Flags.

Then there is the size issue. On regular 
 neighborhood streets, which are not often as wide as city boulevards, you 
 will be looking out for trees, telephone poles and mail boxes to keep from 
 knocking off the Kodiak&apos;s huge mirrors. These mirrors extend, wing-like 
 far from the cab and offer no position to move them closer when you are 
 not towing a trailer.

Steering and braking are quite good for such a 
 huge vehicle, but its home is clearly the open road. You will need about 
 four regular parking lots to visit your local Wal-Mart, and drive-throughs, 
 whether at the bank or your favorite fast food restaurant, are really out 
 of the question unless you like to spend a lot of cash for repairing 
 buildings.

What you do get though is a truck that draws 
 admiring stares from the folks in most travel trailer parks and from 
 almost everyone else. I have driven exotic cars that do not get the stares 
 the Kodiak gets. It is clearly not a truck that the&quot;greens&quot;would 
 approve. Drivers of hybrid Prius&apos;s gave us disconcerting looks.

But if you are someone that has the need for a 
 serious tow vehicle, with the power and weight to get almost the biggest 
 consumer trailer down the road, the Kodiak 4500 pickup is your vehicle. 

 Overview Models: 2006 Chevrolet Kodiak C4500/C5500 Body style / driveline: 2-3 passenger Regular Cab Pickup, 5-6 passenger Crew 
 Cab pickup; front-engine, rear-wheel drive, four-wheel drive EPA vehicle class: Class 5: C4500 available with 17,500-pound GVWR and 
 C5500 available with 19,500-pound GVWR Manufacturing location: Flint, Mich. Key competitor: Ford SuperDuty 

   Engines   Vortec 8100 (L18) Duramax 6600 (LLY) Application: C4500 or C5500 C4500 or C5500 Type: OHV gas V-8 OHV turbodiesel V-8 Displacement (cu in / cc): 496 / 8128 403 / 6599 Bore&amp;stroke (in / mm): 4.25 x 4.37 / 107.95 x 111.0 4.06 x 3.90 / 103 x 99 Block material: cast iron cast iron Cylinder head material: cast iron aluminum Valve train: OHV, 2 valves per cylinder OHV, 4 valves per cylinder Fuel delivery: sequential fuel injection (coil-near-plug) turbocharged, intercooled direct injection via 
 high-pressure common rail Compression ratio: 9.1:1 17.5:1 
Horsepower (hp / kw @ rpm): 

LRW: 325 / 242 @ 4000 LRX: 300 / 224 @ 3100
LPD: 300 / 224 @ 3100 Torque (lb-ft / Nm @ rpm): 
450 / 603 @ 2800 LRX: 520 / 705 @ 1600
LPD: 605 / 820 @ 1600 Recommended fuel: unleaded 87 octane (minimum) No. 2 diesel Maximum engine
speed (rpm): 5000 3250   Transmission   Allison 1000 (M74)   Type: 5-speed automatic   First: 3.10   Second: 1.81   Third: 1.41   Fourth: 1.00   Fifth: 0.71   Reverse: 4.49   PTO (optional): 6-bolt SAE   Final drive (axle) ratio: 4.88 / 5.13   

   Chassis/Suspension Front: solid beam axle (7,000-lb w/C4500; 7,000-lb w/C5500; 
 8,000-lb on 4x4 models), single-stage parabolic tapered-leaf springs 
 with 34-mm square-tube stabilizer bar, 35-mm shock absorbers Rear: full floating axle (13,500-lb w/C4500, 13,500-lb 
 w/C5500), multileaf springs with 35-mm shock absorbers, 44.5-mm 
 stabilizer bar Steering type: Integral power steering Steering ratio: variable, 16.1:1 to 19.6:1 Turning circle,
curb-to-curb (ft / m): Regular Cab: 38.4 / 11.7
Crew Cab: 46.7 / 14.2   Brakes Type: 4-wheel disc, 4-channel ABS, Hydro-Max Disc diameter (in / mm): front: 15 / 381
rear: 15 / 381   Wheels/Tires Base wheel: hub-piloted steel, 8-hole, 19.5 inch x 6.75 inch Tire: 225/70R19.5F (4x2)
245/70R19.5GOn/Off Road (4x4)   Dimensions   Exterior Wheelbase (in / mm): Regular Cab: 128 / 3251
Crew Cab: 169 / 4293 Overall length (in / mm): Regular Cab: 205.5 / 5220
Crew Cab: 246 / 6248 Overall width (in / mm): 95.8 / 2433 (114.9 / 2918 with mirrors) Overall height (in / mm): Regular Cab (RWD): 90.6 / 2301
Crew Cab (RWD): 91.2 / 2316
Regular Cab (4WD): 94.6 / 2402
Crew Cab (4WD): 95.2 / 2418 Step-in height (in / mm): RWD: 19.0 / 483
4WD: 23.0 / 584 Frame width (in / mm): 33.5 / 851 (C4500: 80,000 psi; C5500: 80,000 psi) Approach / departure angle (deg): Regular Cab (RWD): 28.1 / 23
Crew Cab (RWD): 19.9
Regular Cab (4WD): 35.5 / 18.9
Crew Cab (4WD): 35.5 / 18.9 Track (in / mm): front: 79.6 / 2022
rear: 73.1 / 1857 Minimum ground clearance
(in / mm): Regular Cab (RWD): 8.4 / 213
Crew Cab (RWD): 8.3 / 210
Regular Cab (4WD): 9.4 / 239
Crew Cab (4WD): 9.3 / 236 GVWR (lb / kg): C4500: 17,500 / 6531
C5500: 19,500 / 7278 GCWR (lb / kg): C4500&amp;C5500: 26,000 / 9704   Interior Head room (in / mm): 4.6 / 117 (minimum head clearance) Legroom (in / mm): front: 39.9 / 1014
rear: 39.4 / 1001 Shoulder room (in / mm): front: 68.8 / 1748
rear: 67.4 / 1712 Mirrors, surface area (sq in / sq cm): 120 / 774 (outside-mounted mirrors only)   Capacities Fuel tank (gal / L): 32 / 121 (single, behind rear axle)
40 / 151 (dual, 25 midship; 15 behind rear axle) 

   Overall Wheelbase and Frame Dimensions Wheelbase Cab-to-Axle (CA) Cab-to-End of Frame (CE) Conventional Cab Chassis (in / mm): 128 / 3251
  60 / 1524
  95.9 / 2436
  Crew Cab (in / mm): 169 / 4293
  60 / 1524
  121.3 / 3081
  

Note: Information shown is current at time of publication.
	</body>
</document>
