<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008703" url="http://tag.wonderhowto.com/make-frozen-yogurt-without-an-ice-cream-maker/" time="2012-07-13-02:10" support="3" score="0.0021831136977551635" bingtitle="Make frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker" webtitle="Make Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream MakerWonder How To">
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>How To Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant. Whether you&apos;re eating on-the-go, on a budget ... homemade ice cream served up at old world ice cream parlors in a real glass cup ...</description>
	<body>
		WonderHowTo Login | Signup   Worlds: 
 Minecraft Smartphones Hacks, Mods&amp;Circuitry Photoshop The Secret Yumiverse More Worlds » 
 Explore All Worlds How-To » How-To Topics » Make frozen » Make Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream Maker 
 Make Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream Maker 
 How to Make homemade frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker Frozen yogurt is delicious but it can be expensive to buy. Luckily in this how-to video we show you how to make frozen yogurt at home. You don&apos;t need a fancy ice cream maker for his recipe. Grab your favorite yogurt, a plastic bag, and your favorite toppings. Chill the yogurt in the plastic bag, attach a pastry tip and dispense into a bowl. Enjoy... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make homemade frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker 
 Cookbooks for two ages Look at the banner for this Books world and you&apos;ll see books of all kinds, including cookbooks. Can you spot the two of them in the banner? One of them is pretty obvious, Betty Crocker&apos;s Cookbook. The other is actually right beside it, The Anti-Aging Plan. What&apos;s interesting about these two is that they&apos;re actually from two different periods of my life.
I bought Betty Crocker&apos;s Cookbook during my ... 0 books »Inspiration 
 Cookbooks for two ages 
 How to Spend Less on Dairy Products Dairy products are becoming increasingly expensive in some countries or regions. Rather than foregoing having them in your well-rounded diet, there are some good ways to cut the costs on dairy and still enjoy it in your daily fare. Prefer stronger flavoured cheese. Cheese that has a stronger flavour goes further. For example, choose Parmesan or Pecorino cheese and grate lesser amounts of these typ... 0 cheese »How-To 
 How to Spend Less on Dairy Products 
 How to Go Canoe Camping While camping from a canoe is similar to car camping, it also shares many similarities with backpacking . This article will provide the information that you need to make your first trip successful. Select a river. When choosing a river, it&apos;s a good idea to find one that has a reputation as a good camping river. Many rivers are unsuitable for camping as the flood plains tend to be uneven and have h... 0 camp »How-To 
 How to Go Canoe Camping 
 How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant Whether you&apos;re eating on-the-go, on a budget, or with friends who couldn&apos;t care less about their diets , you&apos;ll probably end up eating at a fast food restaurant despite your best efforts to avoid them. They&apos;re everywhere, they&apos;re cheap, and they&apos;re convenient -- so what&apos;s a dieter to do? Take the following steps to minimize the impact of fast food on your diet. Read the nutrition pamphlet . If the... 0 nutrition »How-To 
 How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant 
 How to Make a delicious homemade cherry ice cream Everyone craves ice cream every now and then, except for those lactose-intolerant folks (we feel sorry for them). But nothing in the grocery store freezers will compare to a delicious homemade ice cream, so try to make some yourself, and start with this cherry ice cream recipe.

Cherries are not only delicious but they&apos;re loaded with vitamin C and fiber. Their growing season is short, so you could... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make a delicious homemade cherry ice cream 
 How to Make homemade strawberry and basil flavored ice cream Ice cream doesn&apos;t have to stop at vanilla. There&apos;s a whole world of ice cream flavors out there, but one you wouldn&apos;t expect to try out is basil ice cream, but not just plain basil, basil with ice cream. Lynne Viera, ice cream enthusiast, creates a dessert inspired by the Strawberry-Basil Cocktail from Cuchi Cuchi in Cambridge, MA. Fresh, local strawberries are macerated with sugar, lime zest and ... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make homemade strawberry and basil flavored ice cream 
 How to Make homemade spiced pumpkin ice cream If the version with beer sauce was too much for you, then this spiced pumpkin ice cream should be the perfect Halloween dessert for you. The colors and flavors of Fall are waiting for you in this delicious dessert dish. Whip up a batch of pumpkin, cinnamon, nutmeg and clove-flavored custard with a touch of bourbon. Give it a quick chill in your ice cream maker, then freeze for at least four hours ... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make homemade spiced pumpkin ice cream 
 How to Make (Wheeler Del Torro) vegan peanut butter ice cream In this tutorial, we learn how to make vegan peanut butter ice cream. To make this, you will need: 2 c soy milk, 3/4 c peanut butter, 1/2 c brown sugar, and 1 tbsp vanilla extract. First, place a saucepan over high heat and add in soy milk, brown sugar, and peanut butter. Heat until it&apos;s boiled, then remove and add in the vanilla extract. Combine everything together until well mixed together and p... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make (Wheeler Del Torro) vegan peanut butter ice cream 
 How to Make lemon and cranberry flavored Italian ice with only four ingredients There&apos;s nothing better to cool those hot summer days that a deliciously fruit Italian ice. Italian ice is one of the best desserts to beat the heat, right alongside frozen yogurt and ice cream! And you probably didn&apos;t realize how easy Italian ice is to make at home. Robin Benzle of Chow Time will show you how with her lemon-cranberry version. There&apos;s only four ingredients: lemons, cranberries, wat... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make lemon and cranberry flavored Italian ice with only four ingredients 
 How to Make Sure Your Dinner Party Is a Success Holiday dinners can be the same every year, but many are starting to switch it up, making new traditions and getting a new dining experience for everyone at the table. It’s not unusual to see sweet potatoes on an Easter dinner menu or lamb at Thanksgiving dinner.

Some people are set in their ways when it comes to a holiday entrée on the table, but switching up the side dishes can make it a new di... 0 spices-and-garnish »How-To 
 How to Make Sure Your Dinner Party Is a Success 
 How to Dominate the New York Times Crossword Puzzle First off, don&apos;t be frustrated. YOU CAN DO IT!

Contrary to the message in the image above, it&apos;s NOT over. It&apos;s just beginning. And when it comes to solving the New York Times crossword puzzle, the old cliche does apply: practice makes perfect.

I&apos;ve read quite a few books and articles on solving crosswords. Many of them have useful information, some of it obvious, some of it not. This article is ... 0 puzzles »How-To 
 How to Dominate the New York Times Crossword Puzzle 
 How to Make ice cream Everyone loves ice cream, no matter what age they are. So why not try making a little homemade ice cream instead of hitting up Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s? You&apos;ll enjoy it, and most of all, you&apos;re kids will love it. With this recipe and an ice cream maker, you can create your own sundaes, shakes and ice cream cones at home.

You Will Need
* 1 qt. half and half
* 1 c. granulated sugar
* Pinch of salt
* 2 vanilla... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make ice cream 
 How to Make an Italian-style mango gelato ice cream Attention all ice cream lovers — drop the ice cream and pick up the gelato! You won&apos;t regret it. At least, not with this fantastic recipe for a really simple mango gelato. The tropical fruit is the key to this mouth-watering gelato. Sweet and juicy mango is puréed and added to a smooth custard of eggs, sugar, milk and heavy cream. Pastry Chef Meghann Osmon of BINA restaurant effortlessly takes us ... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make an Italian-style mango gelato ice cream 
 How to Make yummy chocolate peanut butter ice cream Love chocolate? Can&apos;t live without peanut butter? Then we think this yummy chocolate peanut butter ice cream recipe was heaven sent for your taste buds.

After all, this ice cream tastes like a frozen Reese&apos;s peanut butter cup. So without further ado, check out this video to learn the recipe.

Makes approximately 5 cups of ice cream... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make yummy chocolate peanut butter ice cream 
 How to Make ice cream in a bag with your children You don&apos;t need an expensive ice cream maker to make your own ice cream! All you need is a sandwich bag or Ziploc bag, milk, sugar and vanilla flavoring. Once you&apos;ve put your ingredients in the bag, mix it up and then freeze it!... 0 kids-activities »How-To 
 How to Make ice cream in a bag with your children 
 How to Make a frozen iced cappucino Spending too much money on those expensive coffee concoctions? Get your fix at home for a fraction of the price. You will need strong coffee, sugar, ice, milk, whipped cream, a spoon, a blender, a coffee maker, a large glass, a straw, and a flavored syrup. Watch this video beverage-making tutorial and learn how to mix up a frozen iced capuccino.... 0 beverage-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make a frozen iced cappucino 
 How to Make yogurt ice lollys These easy frozen snacks have all the great taste of regular ice cream but only a fraction of the fat. It is the perfect choice for a hot Summer&apos;s day. Make yogurt ice lollys.
Click through to watch this video on videojug.com... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make yogurt ice lollys 
 How to Make multiple delicious smoothies Chef Merlin teaches us how to make multiple delicious smoothies in this video. To make a tropicolada, add ice, 3/8 tsp coconut cream, 3 tbsp yogurt, fresh pineapple (however much you would like) and pieces of a banana. Then, put the top on and blend this until everything is combined. For the next smoothie, add in milk and ice to the bottom of the blender, then add in yogurt, honey, and a banana. N... 0 beverage-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make multiple delicious smoothies 
 How to Make old world homemade strawberry ice cream Ever yearn for the days of homemade ice cream served up at old world ice cream parlors in a real glass cup with a non-plastic spoon? Don&apos;t settle for the mass-produced stuff in the frozen aisle and learn how to make your own ice cream instead.

In this home made strawberry ice cream video, Rita shows you how to make a simple strawberry ice cream in 20 minutes flat using a home ice cream maker. We ... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make old world homemade strawberry ice cream 
 How to Make margartias in an ice cream machine She begins the video by telling us that this is a great way to finish off that Mexican dinner. She gives a list of the ingredients and begins to mix. In your cream bucket pour a quarter cup of triple sec, a bottle of beer, half a liter of tequila, two cans of frozen limeade and one large can of frozen lemonade, and a few splashes of Roses lime juice. Add twelve cups of water and reassemble your ic... 0 tequila-mixed-drinks »How-To 
 How to Make margartias in an ice cream machine 
 How to Make Crab Salad with Savory Basil Sherbet This is a refreshing and light crab salad with a savory basil lemon sherbet on top. I know it sounds weird, but it&apos;s perfect for summer and helps you cool off from the heat.

For the salad:

1 corn on the cob, sliced off the cob after it&apos;s been grilled
1/2 of an avocado
juice of 1 lemon
2 tablespoons olive oil
2-3 pinches of salt
1 package of mixed greens

For the lemon basil savory sorbet:

1 cup... 0 lxrcuisine »How-To 
 How to Make Crab Salad with Savory Basil Sherbet 
 How to Make homemade matcha green tea ice cream You&apos;ve heard of a great cup of matcha green tea, well how about a great green tea dessert. In this HowTo video we show you a delicious recipe for matcha green tea ice cream.

Ingredients for matcha green tea ice cream:
* Matcha Mixture: 60g, or 8-10g of Pure Matcha + 50g of Sugar
* Sugar: 50g
* Milk: 20cl
* Cream: 20cl
* Yolks: 4

The method

1. Beat yolks on the boiling water (double-boil).
2. Ad... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make homemade matcha green tea ice cream 
 How to Make a fig, goat cheese and walnut gelato Italian-style ice cream If you haven&apos;t tried a gelato, you need to drop the ice cream and try out this delicious dessert recipe. It&apos;s a fig, goat cheese&amp;walnut gelato. Interesting, huh? What&apos;s even more interesting is how good this is!

This is delicious, subtle tang from goat cheese that&apos;s whisked into a creamy custard base. Meghann Osmon of BiNA restaurant also adds buttermilk to balance the fat content of the egg yo... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make a fig, goat cheese and walnut gelato Italian-style ice cream 
 How to Make healthy after school snacks your kids will love When kids get home from school they go straight for the snacks, don&apos;t they? So, why not have some healthier options available, rather than fatty chips and cookies? Now, we know kids don&apos;t always like what&apos;s good for them, so check out this tutorial and start making snacks that are delicious AND healthy! Your kids won&apos;t even know how good for them these snacks are because they are so tasty!

Step 1... 0 parenting »How-To 
 How to Make healthy after school snacks your kids will love 
 How to Prepare Strawberry Ice Cream Milkshake A strawberry ice cream milkshake is an ideal beverage in a hot afternoon. It&apos;s easy to prepare and highly nutritious. Ingredients 250g of fresh strawberries (serving for 2 persons) 2 tablespoonful of plain yogurt (approx 70g) 1 table spoonful of sugar syrup (according to your own preference) 200ml of full cream milk Strawberry syrup Vanilla ice cream Cut the strawberries into cubes, and place them... 0 beverage-recipes »How-To 
 How to Prepare Strawberry Ice Cream Milkshake 
 How to Make Ice Cream We&apos;ve all had really bad cravings for ice cream. But, instead of running down to the store for an ice cream fix, check your cupboards. If you have access to things like salt, ice, milk, sugar, and plastic bags, consider making it yourself. This article will cover several different methods for making ice cream at home. This is also a great activity to do with children of any age and makes for an en... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make Ice Cream 
 How to Eat a Banana As difficult as it might be to realize that not everyone has eaten a banana, there are people who haven&apos;t. Bananas are full of potassium and are extremely healthy. Perhaps after reading this article, everyone will at least try a banana, and enjoy it, because now they will know how to eat one. Look for a banana that is yellow in color and lightly speckled with small brown or black speckles. Large b... 0 fruit-recipes »How-To 
 How to Eat a Banana 
 How to Winterize a Home Whether you&apos;re closing up a summer vacation home or leaving your own home during winter for an extended period, it&apos;s important to close up for the season. So what should you do to ensure that when your family returns months (or even a year) later, you won’t find a nightmare waiting? Turn off the water at the main supply point. If you don&apos;t know how to do this, find out where the main (inside) shut... 0 home-building »How-To 
 How to Winterize a Home 
 How to Get Naturally Beautiful Skin Here I will show you how to get great skin without falling for all the myths that large expensive beauty stores tell you. The best way to getting glowing healthy skin is to use completely natural products . STEAMING AND FREEZING TECHNIQUE Steam your face over a pan of boiling water so your pores are extremely open. Massage baking soda all over the face to get rid of black heads. Rinse with cool wa... 0 skincare »How-To 
 How to Get Naturally Beautiful Skin 
 How to Veganize Recipes If you are a vegan, you may be wondering if it is possible to&quot;veganize&quot;your existing recipes. Even recipe books with meat and fish recipes can be converted to a vegan recipe with some imagination and some know-how. Here are some ways to help you to achieve this. Look through your recipe books and choose a recipe that appeals to you. Check off all the items in the ingredients list that are not ve... 0 grains-nuts-soy »How-To 
 How to Veganize Recipes 
 How to Stop Brain Freeze Nothing ruins the refreshing consumption of a cold substance on a hot day like a painful brain freeze , also know as an ice cream headache and medically as Spheno Palatine Gangleoneuralgia (the pronouncing of which can give a headache as well). Fortunately, if you are a victim of brain freeze, you aren&apos;t completely helpless in the matter. Understand what causes brain freeze. When the cold object t... 0 home-remedies »How-To 
 How to Stop Brain Freeze 
 How to Pack a Waste Free Lunch This is a very easy change you can make for the environment. By carrying your lunch this way, you also avoid trips to restaurants or the cafeteria and you can eat better. Try packing a lunch without any trash left. Use a re-useable lunch box, not a disposable bag. Choose something durable that you can use for a long time. Many good, insulated models exist. Freeze your ice pack the night before. If... 0 canning »How-To 
 How to Pack a Waste Free Lunch 
 How to Do Once a Month Cooking Cooking once a month can save both time and money. Not only do you take advantage of sales by buying in bulk, but you also give yourself more free time on a daily basis by cooking in bulk. And if you&apos;re creative enough, you can fit thirty meals in a standard freezer. So put on your apron, play your favorite music, and clear the kitchen--once a month, you&apos;re a lean, mean cooking machine. Make a men... 0 snacks »How-To 
 How to Do Once a Month Cooking 
 How to Make Waffles As long as you have a waffle iron, there&apos;s nothing too complicated about making them yourself. Waffles are baked using a waffle iron. Waffle irons are typically electric although older waffle irons were used to bake atop gas stoves. Some older irons were even used in the fireplace. The waffle fable says an armored knight sat down on pancake batter forming the familiar grid. The waffle was born. Wa... 0 bread »How-To 
 How to Make Waffles 
 How to Swallow a Pill While it seems like an easy task, swallowing a pill is something that many adults as well as children have great difficulty doing. The fear of gagging can cause the throat to tighten up so that pill stays in your mouth until you spit it out. Fortunately, there are various ways to approach the problem so that you can relax, overcome the fear of choking, and just let the pill easily slide down. It&apos;s... 0 pharamceuticals »How-To 
 How to Swallow a Pill 
 How to Pick Dewberries Dewberries are a common wild berry that grows in many parts of North America, with several close relatives in many European countries. Related to raspberries , boysenberries, and blackberries , they are smaller and less prolific, but for what they lack in size, they make up for in flavor. Here are some steps to help you harvest these delicious berries successfully. Determine when the berries will ... 0 camp »How-To 
 How to Pick Dewberries 
 How to Host a Kid&apos;s Ice Cream Party Ice cream is appreciated globally , and in nearly every city there is a local flavor or custom relating to the sweet treat. That&apos;s why throwing this kind of party for your child makes perfect sense, especially during these troubled economic times - an ice cream party is inexpensive to hold, and has a mass appeal that cannot be duplicated. Simply put, an ice cream party is a great way for your chil... 0 themed-parties »How-To 
 How to Host a Kid&apos;s Ice Cream Party 
 How to Make Jam In today&apos;s world of all-night supermarkets and ready-made everything, it&apos;s easy to forget that jam didn&apos;t always come from the store. Homemade jam tastes fresher than store-bought stuff and it makes a great (and increasingly rare) gift . Ingredients Fruit or fruit juice according to the pectin package insert. **This demonstration uses 5 3/4 cups of crushed strawberries, equivalent to about 4 pints... 0 jelly-jam-preserves »How-To 
 How to Make Jam 
 How to Make a Schedule for Moving Moving can be costly and stressful. There are many steps in planning and preparing for a move, and it doesn&apos;t happen over night. However, with a little patience and a well thought out plan, moving cost can be reduced and and the process less of a hassle. Here are a few steps that are spread out over several weeks to ensure an affordable and easy paced schedule to a safe move with less stress. 8 We... 0 housekeeping »How-To 
 How to Make a Schedule for Moving 
 Previous Next 
 Community 
 ZachVivs published New, Is This How I Get Registered or Started? Esteban Felix commented on Shieldston What&apos;s your tax rate, since you include free healthcare :P? Physics Anonymous published What We Should&apos;nt Do in Iran and Syria Thacher Shields commented on Shieldston And one more thing: is the erecting of Shieldston (a prosperous rising city) worthy of a rank-up? Austin Sirkin commented on Rebuilt NPC Village, Simple Defenses and Advanced Defenses What a great post! I loved every part of it, the build as well as the narration.

It was a pleasure to read! Austin Sirkin commented on DUO Competition Winners! Hey, Pmags. You can get underscores (instead of italics) by typing two in a row. Just FYI. =)

Meanwhile, is there a new redstone challenge coming soon? I can&apos;t wait to see what it is! 
 Arts 
 Arts&amp;Crafts Beauty&amp;Style Dance Fine Art Music&amp;Instruments 
 Science&amp;Tech 
 Autos, Motorcycles&amp;Planes Computers&amp;Programming Disaster Preparation Education Electronics Film&amp;Theater Software Weapons 
 Lifestyle 
 Alcohol Business&amp;Money Dating&amp;Relationships Diet&amp;Health Family Fitness Food Home&amp;Garden Hosting&amp;Entertaining Language Motivation&amp;Self Help Outdoor Recreation Pets&amp;Animals Pranks&amp;Cons Spirituality Sports Travel 
 Gaming 
 Gambling Games Hobbies&amp;Toys Magic&amp;Parlor Tricks Video Games 
 
 
 About Us Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Conditions
	</body>
</document>
