<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0008263" url="http://factory.dhgate.com/other-home-appliance-parts/adjustable-cup-dispenser-fast-food-equipment-p46253393.html" time="2012-07-13-01:45" support="5" score="0.003541749128599519" bingtitle="Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment, Cup Dispenser ..." webtitle="Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment, Cup Dispenser, Paper Cup Dispenser | DHgate Factory">
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>1 Piece/Pieces sample order is ... Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment Item Code : ... 3 very suitable for fast food restaurant Commodity:Cup dispenser</description>
	<body>
		DHgate Factory 
 Home Products Suppliers 
    Go to DHgate Gold Zone Stock in US/UK Spring Sale Promotions Electronics Tablet PC Hot New Trends Wedding&amp;Prom Factory &gt; Home Appliances &gt; Home Appliance Parts &gt; Other Home Appliance Parts &gt;Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment Share    
Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment
 Price&amp;Payment;: US $25 - 35 / PieceT/T,Western Union MOQ : 1 Piece/Pieces sample order is accepted Productivity : 1000 Piece/Pieces per Week Packaging : Carton packing Delivery time: 7-15 days after receiving the payment 
Quick Details
 Product Name : Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment Item Code : 46253393 Category: Other Home Appliance Parts Keywords : cup dispenser ,paper cup dispenser ,kitchen equipment Port: Guangzhou color: silver white Type: Other Home Appliance Parts 
Specifications
 
 cup dispenser 
1 All stainless steel body
2 adjustable diameter from 70 to 99mm.
3 very suitable for fast food restaurant

Commodity:Cup dispenser 

This cup dispenser is used in the Mcdonald&apos;s or fast food restaurant.



 There are three dimensions 

ADJ-21 Adjusted diameter from 70-79mm

ADJ-31 Adjusted diameter from 79-89mm

ADJ-81 Adjusted diameter from 89-99mm
 
You might want to know...
 This Other Home Appliance Parts wholesaler is wholly responsible for Adjustable Cup Dispenser - Fast Food Equipment listing and contents.
 DHgate is a fast trading wholesale marketplace which supports purchase order transactions. DHgate Factory is born to target traditional offline global trading markets, and to make them more efficient for you. On DHgate Factory, you will be able to browse millions of products from Chinese factories and contact manufacturers and suppliers directly to get the best deal. 
Supplier Details
 
 Guangzhou Jieguan Western Kitchen Equipment Factory [Guangdong,China ] Business Type: Manufacturer See Factory Store 
 More products from this company 
Related products
 Cup dispenser cup dispenser,It can be used in offices, families, schools and other public places. cup dispenser,It can be used in offices, families, schools and other public places Cup Dispenser For Water Dispenser Cup Dispenser 
1)The most ideal companion 
2)Suitable for most public and private places 
3)It could hold out 25pcs of ... cups from 6.5 to 9 ounce 
6) Dexterous design to avoid any damage for the cup Cup Dispenser Guangdong Shunde ShenTop Trading Co., Ltd 
Cup Dispenser 
Name: Cup Dispenser 
Model: HWC-3,HWC-4 Cup Dispenser We are the professional supplier of cup dispenser . 
Products Name : Cup Dispenser 
Item No : Pirlo-CS1136 
Item Number ... (diameter) Capacity : 25-30pcs paper cups Packing: 40pcs/ctn Meas: 63*47.5*56cm cup dispenser holder Our cup dispenser: 
1.Good design for steel clip. 
2. Suitable for water dispenser. 
3. With screw to install 
Features ... pull 
8.Can be mounted onto water dispenser by screws 
9.PC transparent body cup dispenser cup dispenser/cup dispenser for water dispenser 
cup dispenser 
make in PC 
can fill in 50 pcs paper cup cup dispenser* OEM offer 
cup dispenser,cup dispenser for water dispenser,water dispenser accessories 
strong stainless steel body ... and restaurants, snack shops, fast food shops, parties and other occasions. stainless steel cup dispenser Cup Dispenser: 
--Material:stainless steel 304 
--Size:82x650 mm,92x650 mm,102x650 mm and so on. 
Stainless Steel Cup ... be adjusted to hold different size cups, eg. 7oz /8oz/ 9oz/ 12oz/ 32oz, etc. Cup Dispenser with Ice Storage All Stainless Steel Body 
Cup Dispenser with Cabinet with Ice Storage 
Deluxe Outlook 
Convenience and Easy to Use 
OEM ... Description: HWC-836 Cup Dispenser with Ice Storage 
Dimension: 1500*760*800 +More Back to Search Results Return to top 
Send your message to this supplier
 
 Related Searches&amp;Catalogs 
 
 paper cup dispenser plastic cup dispenser bathroom paper cup dispenser drinking cup dispensers coffee cups dispenser water dispenser beer dispenser cup dispenser holder fuel dispenser soap dispenser 
 
 Wholesale | About Us | Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | 供应商登录 | Gold Zone 

Copyright Notice © 2004 - 2012 DHgate.com All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
